Speaker 1: Hey, it's Tuesday December 9th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We talk about the board game, Agricola Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I took tomorrow off work for the sole Reason of I want to go skiing and I don't want to pay a lot of money to go on the weekend.
Speaker 0: See if I had all these days off.
Speaker 0: I would not be using them You know like on these Wednesdays and things I would pile them up right up against the holidays and get like this gigantic Vacation which is what I'm doing I'm getting.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna have the final like two weeks of the year off and not going.
Speaker 0: basically next week I'm going to work and then after that I'm not going to work again until January 5th.
Speaker 1: Well, you see the only reason I'm doing it this way is that I forgot how many extra vacation days I had.
Speaker 1: So by the time it was okay, I got to spend all these other people already took all the good days Mm-hmm, but I worked it out.
Speaker 1: I'm taking the whole week before New Year's off and all the time like right around Christmas off and you know all that business.
Speaker 1: And then of course, I'm taking like a month off next year, maybe two.
Speaker 0: so it all works out - I don't know Anyone will give you two months.
Speaker 1: Well, I got 30 vacation days.
Speaker 1: Well, that's not - that's a month and a half.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not two months.
Speaker 1: It's a month and a half and if I take a little bit of leave of absence, there we go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wish I could do leave of absence.
Speaker 0: I'll do leave of absence for a whole year.
Speaker 1: I thought that they just won't pay you.
Speaker 1: you want to live a year without getting paid.
Speaker 0: Well, leave of absence is cool because it means I can sort of leave the job But then go back to it as soon as I need money.
Speaker 0: Yes, you know, it's like quitting but you're not quitting You're just you know, it's like guaranteed job if you want it again, but you can leave it for now.
Speaker 1: See one guy at my work Apparently a while sometime a long time ago took a sabbatical a long one to be a professional chef for a while And then he came back to do our stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see it's like if I could just like take six months off and you know I wouldn't care if I didn't get paid because I got money saved up enough for six months.
Speaker 0: Then I could just live for six months and try to do something else.
Speaker 0: And if I fail Guaranteed go back.
Speaker 1: No problem, but it's been busy at work lately I haven't had the opportunity to wander around and go for like those super long lunches.
Speaker 1: I used to go on but I wandered over today to Bryan Park to check out the ice skating and it was Surprisingly bustling even at lunchtime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the ice skating over there is kinda it's kind of weak compared to the Rockefeller Center ice skating.
Speaker 0: the thing is the Rockefeller Center is much fancier and You know shinier and all that to anyone who's never been to New York City.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you see that place You know, it's really small.
Speaker 1: you see that place on TV or in the critic with all those flags and it's like this gigantic.
Speaker 1: There's always like the two protagonists of a movies like ice skating by themselves at night.
Speaker 1: Now there's an hour-long line and the rink is like the size of our house.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the rink is the Bryant Park rink is also pretty small.
Speaker 1: It's bigger than last year.
Speaker 0: It is but the ice is still not the greatest.
Speaker 0: It's not the greatest ice.
Speaker 1: They built that gigantic like winter village around it.
Speaker 0: Well, they always do that to sell like holiday gifts.
Speaker 1: They got the same thing in Union Square, but it like giant gift thing, but this year They got this two-story like heated building you can go into and hang out.
Speaker 1: It's weird.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's kind of where you let.
Speaker 0: they usually just do like, you know the booths.
Speaker 0: it looks like Oh, they're like fully enclosed looks like a dealer's room at a convention only Christmas.
Speaker 1: now They're like fully enclosed buildings.
Speaker 1: and then they built this two-story like building of Buildings among and they got all those trucks providing the electricity and shit.
Speaker 1: No, they got like structures and buildings providing all that.
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 1: You got to go see it.
Speaker 1: It's kind of weird.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've seen it, you know, like two or three years in a row.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but they've.
Speaker 1: they've upped the ante.
Speaker 1: so I went and got Belgian waffles covered in ice cream.
Speaker 0: Belgian waffles there.
Speaker 1: Yes shit for lunch.
Speaker 1: That was the baby lunch.
Speaker 0: ever have lunch tomorrow.
Speaker 1: They're tomorrow My Thursday, maybe That's all I got.
Speaker 1: I guess I should have a gaming anecdote or something.
Speaker 1: I've been I've been playing and s left for dead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm playing video games.
Speaker 1: I have order ecclesia.
Speaker 1: I have played it.
Speaker 1: It's awesome.
Speaker 1: It might be the best Castlevania game ever.
Speaker 1: I can't say that for sure just ever.
Speaker 0: I don't know I can't.
Speaker 0: I haven't played it, but I don't know Might might as in as in.
Speaker 1: you know How when you look at a team like in football and there's two games left and they're undefeated up to this point and you know They might go undefeated.
Speaker 1: This is beyond that.
Speaker 1: This is like, alright, the Lions won a game.
Speaker 1: They might win another game.
Speaker 1: Okay, but it might be.
Speaker 1: there's a chance.
Speaker 1: I'll give the game that it's fantastic.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I played on the way.
Speaker 0: how much different could it be from just other Castlevania's?
Speaker 0: Just polish.
Speaker 1: polish counts for a lot.
Speaker 0: It's just more of the same.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly but polish.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I could be playing that but after I finished the book I was reading it I didn't play that.
Speaker 1: I in fact took that out of my DS Put advance wars in good job and turned three of my the last A's I have into S's.
Speaker 1: All right, and that was somehow Greatly gratifying perhaps more so than Castlevania.
Speaker 1: Am I getting stuck in gay?
Speaker 1: Am I like a gaming rut?
Speaker 1: Is that the reason I'm only playing?
Speaker 0: and as no you're in a gaming, right?
Speaker 0: You've been playing anything?
Speaker 1: No, no a rut means you're doing the same thing over and over and over again.
Speaker 1: a lull means I'm not playing at all.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: I think I'm in a rut.
Speaker 0: Alright you and your rut lulls.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: What can I do about it?
Speaker 1: I guess I could play mirrors edge.
Speaker 0: you do it all for the lulls.
Speaker 1: I Want to play new games but a lot of times new games disappoint me so profoundly that and I looked at like the upcoming games for DS list we.
Speaker 0: There's like nothing.
Speaker 0: it's like Dragon Quest 5.
Speaker 0: It's like I'm actually almost considering a stupid level up RPG just because there's nothing else.
Speaker 0: I mean Chrono Trigger came out recently, but I'm talking about the future.
Speaker 0: This is the DS is not looking like anything.
Speaker 0: Where's the fire emblem?
Speaker 0: Come on.
Speaker 0: What the fuck?
Speaker 1: I'm waiting another advance Wars.
Speaker 1: That's like printing money.
Speaker 0: Where's like new Super Mario Brothers -
Speaker 1: yeah, seriously We had that 2d side scroll in original style platformer Mario on the DS and while it was
Speaker 0: always like Kirby's Canvas curse again Like when the DS first came out at least they were trying shit even when it didn't work.
Speaker 0: So well now it's like they've given up and they just bring it out.
Speaker 1: You know, I'm gonna say something funny.
Speaker 1: Where's another 3d Metroid game with FPS and where is no?
Speaker 0: where's a 2d Metroid game true dad?
Speaker 0: They got in the Castlevania is they're almost the same exact thing, but you know Metroid is something else.
Speaker 1: I Don't know really what's going on.
Speaker 1: I mean, I felt I don't know.
Speaker 1: I feel like the cycle has been broken in some way.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess my whole life I've been used to this sort of ebb and flow of Games come in games go out games come in games go out and the DS for a long time has had like the same flow.
Speaker 1: And just as I was getting to the point where I wouldn't pull my DS out anymore a game would come along and like it Was this perfect timing.
Speaker 0: but suddenly they were like doing Phoenix, right?
Speaker 0: They throw out some hotel does?
Speaker 0: there was all this You know weird, you know the stuff coming out and now it's just nothing.
Speaker 0: Anyone if anyone knows a DS game that's coming out.
Speaker 0: That's worth paying attention to now.
Speaker 1: No I'm not one that's already out and one that is up worth paying attention to.
Speaker 1: that is the important part there because There are a lot of games for the DS and the GBA Not worth paying attention to now.
Speaker 0: Actually, I was playing a GBA game recently.
Speaker 0: I went out and I got Zelda 3 Aka Link to the past and because I don't have a news.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna talk about it.
Speaker 0: some People may not realize something that's sort of freaky.
Speaker 0: Alright, there was all the one in Zelda 2.
Speaker 0: Zelda 3 was for the Super Nintendo and came out in 91.
Speaker 0: The Game Boy Zelda came out in 93 Which is totally blows my mind that the Game Boy one came after the Super Nintendo one.
Speaker 1: Well, I just I mean Zelda 1 and Zelda 2 had that flimsy like contiguous plot.
Speaker 1: I mean there weren't that many Zelda games back then.
Speaker 1: There was the Legend of Zelda and then actually the BS Zelda plot Which I just recently learned of is more contiguous a little bit Yeah, but I'm talking about the the well-known Nintendo canon.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we got you know, Zelda 1 Zelda 2 Contiguous in that the instruction book told you they were contiguous.
Speaker 1: Yeah They both had a Zelda and a link and an Impa and it kind of made sense.
Speaker 0: There was no input in Zelda 1.
Speaker 1: now, I guess there was old man.
Speaker 0: There was a woman and old woman.
Speaker 1: I like to think that old woman was impas in the instruction book is all the two Not in Zelda 1.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure now are you okay?
Speaker 0: You can go investigate.
Speaker 0: Well, it's pretty sure right over there.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure she's not in these all the one instruction book.
Speaker 1: Anyway, is this gonna be a sword situation?
Speaker 1: Perhaps Scott and I got into an argument at RIT.
Speaker 1: This lasted like an hour with and everyone in the room was wasn't RIT was here.
Speaker 1: No, it was alright It wasn't.
Speaker 1: it was definitely at RIT.
Speaker 1: Yes, because I I still had all those remember that Lego bin full of instruction manuals that I've.
Speaker 0: you still had the instruction to Zelda instruction manuals out in the hallway where it is now.
Speaker 1: Yes, but this argument happened at RIT.
Speaker 0: I know it didn't happened here.
Speaker 1: All right, I don't understand why you're making up something like that.
Speaker 0: Why are you making up something or remembering incorrectly and refuse to distrust your memory?
Speaker 1: because I remember very clearly Whose memory wins.
Speaker 1: In the past it has been mine.
Speaker 0: No, Jessica.
Speaker 0: Someone else agrees with your memory does not mean your memory is correct.
Speaker 1: I can get people to say yeah Scott is this gonna be one of those situations where you tried to convince me that I was in Rochester in the theater with you idiots watching the second second matrix movie when in fact I was living in Poughkeepsie?
Speaker 0: Well, there is the perfect example in which you know, I had people agreeing with my memory yet.
Speaker 0: Somehow we were wrong.
Speaker 0: now This is a situation where people may agree with your memory, but you can still be wrong.
Speaker 1: I point out that I think you're just hedging your bet there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this definitely happened at RIT.
Speaker 0: It definitely did not.
Speaker 1: the pertinent part here is that there have often been Arguments in the crew where For reasons of entertainment.
Speaker 1: No one will actually look anything up or in any way try to bring evidence.
Speaker 1: We'll just well.
Speaker 0: when we do things happen usually relating to berries.
Speaker 1: Oh my god the berries.
Speaker 0: This happens kind of look and learn.
Speaker 0: you learn your lesson.
Speaker 0: Don't look shit up when you're arguing because everyone will be wrong.
Speaker 1: all I want to say is we argued for over an hour about berries and We realized then that we didn't know what berries were.
Speaker 1: and you might think that's stupid But now look online.
Speaker 1: We didn't know what berries were.
Speaker 1: Our argument was bullshit after an hour.
Speaker 0: Everyone's argument was bullshit.
Speaker 1: It was fantastic.
Speaker 0: Don't look anything up.
Speaker 0: You'll learn things You don't want to know.
Speaker 1: but at the point when we were having this argument Which I still insist was at RIT in colony because I was sitting in my computer chair.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I still insist it was not because you're sitting in this room.
Speaker 1: I said that it was the red sword and I said it was the wood Sword and I I was pretty sure it was the red sword.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it'd be wooden.
Speaker 1: So it's pretty red.
Speaker 0: Yeah red because it's made of wood.
Speaker 1: if it was made of wood.
Speaker 0: It's also the.
Speaker 0: she is the shittiest sword Which is why it is it of course.
Speaker 0: Wait.
Speaker 0: Wait, it's reddish brown.
Speaker 0: First of all, right?
Speaker 1: The second sword is the white sword.
Speaker 1: therefore it follows that they have color names until you hit the master sword.
Speaker 0: It's actually so a magic sword.
Speaker 0: I just said that would white and magic.
Speaker 0: No, it's red white and actually no we're both wrong.
Speaker 1: Yes, it was sword.
Speaker 0: that the first sword in Zelda 1 is just sword.
Speaker 0: It is not red.
Speaker 0: It is not wooden It is just sword.
Speaker 0: However, I contend that sword is made of wood.
Speaker 1: There is nothing.
Speaker 0: Why else would it be red quite so fantastic and wooden and brown?
Speaker 1: after having an hour-long argument with many different people taking many different sides everyone strongly full of conviction and Then the luminary from on high comes down with proof evidence of the truth.
Speaker 1: The evidence is presented and it turns out that every single person in the argument was equally wrong and no one in any way had anything even resembling truth.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I played Zelda 3 again.
Speaker 0: I played the GBA version which is pretty interesting because it also has four swords in it.
Speaker 0: But I'm not sure if that four swords is the same four swords that the GameCube has.
Speaker 0: If it's a different four swords, then I have to play it.
Speaker 0: if the same four swords I don't.
Speaker 0: but actually I'm thinking maybe I should play it because if you beat the four swords in the GBA version Then you get an extra dungeon in the single-player version like the hero dungeon or some shit like that.
Speaker 0: anyway Zelda 3 is sorta.
Speaker 0: It's a very strange Zelda game and it's like.
Speaker 0: I wish the newer Zelda games are more like it.
Speaker 1: You know, I feel like Zelda 3 set one of those precedents that should have been followed like, you know It was followed in Zelda 64, but then it was never followed again.
Speaker 1: Yes, but that's the thing.
Speaker 1: They didn't keep following I mean when the square boss president was set.
Speaker 1: Square bosses were everywhere from that point on like that.
Speaker 0: It was obvious you expected them Yeah and in a way that Diluted the power of it yet at the same time not having one felt even less so.
Speaker 1: it created a ritual and the loss of The power of the square boss was kind of balanced by the fact that you added this ritual of gaming.
Speaker 1: the.
Speaker 1: I know it's Coming I beat you and now I beat you Mr.
Speaker 1: behind the scenes.
Speaker 1: but Zelda 3 Set the precedent of you play a little game and do some dungeons and then holy shit The actual game is like 80 percent.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you start the game by beating like this opening dungeon, right?
Speaker 0: then you get like three medals and then you do the castle thing again and Then suddenly there's seven more dungeons and then another castle seven Which is actually which is actually sort of sad.
Speaker 0: I wish they were eight and then another castle.
Speaker 0: that way it's sort of like the original Zelda Whereas eight dungeons and then nine is the boss.
Speaker 1: I do feel like Zelda 3 was probably the ultimate of the old style Zelda game.
Speaker 0: The other thing about it is that it has like so many items like oh my god.
Speaker 0: And some of the items like you don't even get them in dungeons like the Cape.
Speaker 0: You get the Cape like somewhere that's not in a dungeon at all.
Speaker 0: You could actually completely miss the Cape and never find it if you don't know what you're doing.
Speaker 0: and if you don't have the Cape some of the game is just stupidly hard like You'll not like.
Speaker 0: the Cape allows you to get some other items, too.
Speaker 0: So if you don't get the Cape like you won't get all the pieces of heart and you oh, it's terrible.
Speaker 1: But I guess like compared to ages and seasons which were not I don't know They weren't as fun as hell to three to me.
Speaker 1: or convert a minish cap, which was trivial Yeah, it's all.
Speaker 0: the three was like the business and Zelda 64 was just like Zelda 3 and had just as many items.
Speaker 0: It also had two different worlds to go between.
Speaker 0: You know the young world young link and old link world versus.
Speaker 0: you know Link to the past had the golden world in the regular world.
Speaker 1: Of course, it wasn't the same kind of game from a purely mechanical stand.
Speaker 0: Well, it was a 3d game and a 2d game.
Speaker 0: But otherwise, it was like the same, you know made from the same mold.
Speaker 1: But just I'm saying in terms of pure mechanics like in terms of the kind of game you play on a straight up.
Speaker 1: How like how do I interact with this game way?
Speaker 1: Zelda 3 was kind of like the ultimate of the top-down 2d hit stuff with your sword and solve complicated.
Speaker 1: Sometimes time-based puzzles game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the other 2d Zelda's, you know, even though they did just weren't as grand as all the three.
Speaker 0: It's like they kept making 2d Zelda's minish cap, you know Gameboy But why?
Speaker 0: or just seasons?
Speaker 0: and while those are great except for minish cap, they weren't as big.
Speaker 0: I mean I beat ages and I beat it and I was like what that was, you know It's like they should just make another 2d Zelda for the DS.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: There was another 2d Zelda for the DS also not as big as all the three Nah, and they should just make it just like Zelda 3 only even bigger.
Speaker 0: be like, yeah There's three over worlds and 25 dungeons and that would be the business right there.
Speaker 0: That's all you got to do.
Speaker 1: that game was just so good and the dungeons were so varied I mean minish cap and even a lot of the others Top down Zelda's.
Speaker 1: the dungeons were all the same just skin differently or like there'd be one game or like eat.
Speaker 0: Yeah the dungeon would have like one gimmick to it and they'd be really short and small and it would just be that gimmick to the Dungeon.
Speaker 1: Zelda 3 like every dungeon was so different?
Speaker 0: Yeah And pretty big too and dangerous like it actually counted at the end.
Speaker 0: it tells you how many times you died.
Speaker 0: I think I died 14 times.
Speaker 0: That's about right.
Speaker 1: something like that for a seasoned player.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Just you haven't played.
Speaker 0: Zelda 3 probably plays all the three and the thing is all the three is actually like.
Speaker 0: It's weird because the overworld even though there's two over worlds as the golden world in the regular world is actually pretty small.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: Zelda 1 feels like it has a bigger overworld than Zelda 3 like it actually, you know It's like I could get from one end of the map to the other like in no time Without even using the magic flute or anything, but it's the not so magic flute.
Speaker 1: actually Zelda 1 had.
Speaker 1: Don't start that argument again, but the argument about whether it was the flute of the magic flute.
Speaker 0: Well in Zelda 1 the flute was obviously magical.
Speaker 0: in Zelda 3 the flute had no magical powers whatsoever.
Speaker 0: How about Zelda 2?
Speaker 0: Now that to the flute.
Speaker 1: What did it do?
Speaker 1: Do you remember what it did?
Speaker 0: You blew the flute and it.
Speaker 1: it did something.
Speaker 0: Made bad guys do stuff.
Speaker 1: It only was usable on the overworld map.
Speaker 0: I know I know you used it on the overworld map Twice.
Speaker 0: well, maybe three they like make something appear.
Speaker 0: That was invisible.
Speaker 1: It made a castle appear.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was invisible and that's a magic flute then.
Speaker 1: and it made a spider run away.
Speaker 0: Oh, right, right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's definitely a magic flute.
Speaker 0: But the Zelda 3 flute was non-magical.
Speaker 0: All it did was I guess I would say this bird come and carry you away.
Speaker 1: It amazes me.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of gamers who they played like all the modern Zelda games.
Speaker 1: They love Twilight Princess and all this stuff But they've never played any of the original Zelda's like 1 2 3 6.
Speaker 0: Well, that's like the people who played Final Fantasy 7.
Speaker 0: They're like, oh my god, if I'm a super Final Fantasy guy They haven't played Final Fantasy 6.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like or 1 2 3 4 5.
Speaker 1: if you're gonna play one of the original Zelda's for context and you're not really a gamer You don't really want to like.
Speaker 1: be hardcore about it.
Speaker 0: I think Zelda 3 is the best one because Zelda 3 combines the epicness and but also the hardness like Zelda 64 is.
Speaker 0: Actually while it's as big and epic as all the three it's easy.
Speaker 0: So how?
Speaker 0: the three is actually kind of hard in places.
Speaker 0: I mean you can always go to the fortune teller to figure out what you need to do, which I did not do.
Speaker 0: but You know, it's it's still places in.
Speaker 0: it are freaking hard.
Speaker 0: Some of the bosses was to own you.
Speaker 1: I think Zelda 2 Probably was harder, but it was only a.
Speaker 0: very well the two is definitely harder.
Speaker 0: But Zelda 3 actually had difficulty.
Speaker 0: a lot of the other Zelda's, you know, even the Gameboy Zelda just doesn't have difficulty Even though it's the same kind of game.
Speaker 1: I mean Zelda 1. a lot of the difficulty was just you don't know where stuff is and you got a bomb every wall.
Speaker 0: The other thing is like getting your head like a lot of the other games that allow you to travel between two worlds.
Speaker 0: Right, like.
Speaker 0: the way that works is either.
Speaker 0: it's like there are portals and you can go to them and that's it.
Speaker 0: Zelda 3 the way you travel between the two worlds is actually sort of tricky and and difficult.
Speaker 0: It's like you as soon as you beat the first half of the game, right?
Speaker 0: Well, here's how.
Speaker 0: here's how it works.
Speaker 0: I'll explain it to you.
Speaker 0: right you start out in the good overworld, right?
Speaker 0: The good overworld has portals to the dark world, right?
Speaker 0: There's also the magic mirror.
Speaker 0: if you have the magic mirror and you're in the dark world.
Speaker 0: You can use it at any time to go to the good world.
Speaker 0: So the magic mirror is actually one way it goes from dark world to good world.
Speaker 1: But the thing is what's brilliant is one the way that the way they set it up to bring you back Which from a game design standpoint was probably primarily to prevent you from getting to places You shouldn't get to or breaking the game
Speaker 0: exactly when you use the magic mirror to go from the good world From the bad world to the good world.
Speaker 0: one way it leaves these sparkles lying there, right?
Speaker 0: And that means you can go back to the bad world through the sparkles But you won't be able to go back to the bad world at a different spot.
Speaker 0: So where you can only go.
Speaker 0: it basically prevents you from going to places in the.
Speaker 0: you'll be able to go anywhere in the good World because you can go everywhere in the good world, but it prevents you from going to places in the dark world.
Speaker 0: they don't want you to go yet.
Speaker 0: and what happens is as you Expand more in the dark world right by getting new items like the hammer and such right that let you go to new places in the dark world.
Speaker 0: You you can still go everywhere in the good world, but there are portals in The good world to the dark world that you have to find in tricky spots.
Speaker 0: So it's like there's some places in the dark world like the bottom left.
Speaker 0: You just can't get there.
Speaker 0: But eventually you'll get the hammer and when you get the hammer You can go someplace in the good world and then use the mirror.
Speaker 0: It's it is or no?
Speaker 0: you then use the port.
Speaker 1: yes other way or anywhere.
Speaker 0: See how confusing it is to explain but it totally.
Speaker 0: it's really clever.
Speaker 0: They can actually make a whole game just out of that.
Speaker 1: one game design of Zelda 3 is so perfect and polished It's.
Speaker 1: it's an amazing game.
Speaker 1: It's one of the best games ever made.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely all right.
Speaker 0: a Lot of people haven't played Zelda 3.
Speaker 0: I played it again recently and beat the whole thing and got every item.
Speaker 0: so Other people gotta be paying attention to that.
Speaker 1: so speaking of upcoming DS games I had a segue here if you hadn't jumped in but I'll go back like this didn't happen.
Speaker 1: There is an upcoming DS game that you'll probably all want to play at least a little bit What the great Gianna sisters is actually an assistant getting a legitimate release?
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: It was always legitimate.
Speaker 1: Well, no it was taken off the shelves pretty much immediately And I think I don't know was my cousin's had a copy?
Speaker 0: was you could buy it?
Speaker 0: everyone had it.
Speaker 0: anyone I come to have 64 had.
Speaker 1: Gianna says yes, but Dean intended it was taken off of shelves everywhere.
Speaker 1: There are lots of lawsuits and stuff around it.
Speaker 0: I know is that everyone I knew had a Commodore 64 also had Gianna sisters.
Speaker 0: So if it was taken off the shelves it was taken off the shelves way late Meaning after everyone bought it.
Speaker 1: well not everyone had it.
Speaker 0: I mean no one not everyone, but a lot of people.
Speaker 1: anyway this game I don't know how this is reported on Kotaku But someone has sorted out all the rights because the game Was basically a lot of work sorting out the rights to an old game.
Speaker 1: the game was basically just a straight-up Clone of Mario.
Speaker 0: it wasn't an exact clone.
Speaker 1: It was 90% the same game.
Speaker 1: Oh jumping hitting.
Speaker 1: you jump and hit star blocks to get your power-ups.
Speaker 0: Well in every run level one looks a lot like Mario 1 1 But the other levels start.
Speaker 0: you know in the second world is an underground world, and there's a lot of similarities.
Speaker 0: But it's actually really different.
Speaker 0: you can shoot things, and they don't shoot like fireballs.
Speaker 0: They shoot sort of straightforward.
Speaker 0: I think and You know there's this it's it's different enough for Mario 1 that I would say it is not a ripoff even though in those days You know a platforming game where you hit blocks with your head.
Speaker 1: Well the thing is if you look through the game there are a whole bunch of spots that are exactly tile for tile.
Speaker 0: There are many spots, but there are not entire things.
Speaker 1: But there are so many spots that the game clearly had to have been drawn primarily from it.
Speaker 0: There was there is indeed an obvious drawing from.
Speaker 1: also the girl's name was Maria.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Maria, Giana.
Speaker 1: Yes, Maria Mario one Maria Maria Giana.
Speaker 1: yes one letter.
Speaker 1: There is no way.
Speaker 0: Well, you know if it was really a ripoff.
Speaker 0: She would have been named Giana, Giana.
Speaker 1: How many Mario's are there between you?
Speaker 0: Three.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to play this game plus got mushrooms and blocks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who comes up with that?
Speaker 1: out of nowhere?
Speaker 0: the bad the bosses were different.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those bosses were what.
Speaker 1: what bosses were there in Mario 1 other than King Koopa?
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: King Koopa wasn't there there was like these other things.
Speaker 0: They were actually more like the bosses from Super Mario Land for the game boy.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the game was trouble and somehow now it's coming out on the DS, and I can't imagine that this will sell to anyone except people who remember the original and Have their old-school credentials on the line.
Speaker 0: next had really good music.
Speaker 0: that was nothing like tomorrow day.
Speaker 1: the game had fantastic music.
Speaker 1: That's why there's so many remixes.
Speaker 1: Normally, I'd say things of the day right here But Scott informed me that he thinks it's stupid to say things of the day And that we should just I guess assume that people will figure it out.
Speaker 0: I think it's pretty corny at least the way you say things of the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so how should I say it?
Speaker 1: Just be like hey time for things of the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, totally lame.
Speaker 0: so at least it's not things of the day.
Speaker 0: Corny.
Speaker 0: things of the day things of the day Yeah, and you don't sound like a person you know with a mental problem, so what do you got?
Speaker 1: Oh, so check this out, but are things of the day lame.
Speaker 0: No just you saying it.
Speaker 1: Okay, so why don't you say it then?
Speaker 1: Like I offered that you could say it right now, and you refused.
Speaker 0: yeah, cuz we should have a you know like a Thing.
Speaker 1: what kind of thing like someone saying things of the day?
Speaker 0: Maybe not in a corny way It's an encore.
Speaker 1: give me an example of a non corny way, how would you say it?
Speaker 1: How would you record that that thing for posterity?
Speaker 0: I don't have a robot do it.
Speaker 1: Okay, so we get the Stephen Hawking voice.
Speaker 0: doesn't have to be Stephen Hawking be better robot than that.
Speaker 1: there aren't that many better robots.
Speaker 0: I think there are anyway.
Speaker 0: What do you got like a Godzilla anyway?
Speaker 0: That sounds good.
Speaker 0: So this dude went to the monster truck rally Bitchin and you know what he brought with him a monster truck a camera.
Speaker 0: You know what he put on that camera?
Speaker 0: No now a tilt shift lens.
Speaker 0: Aha, you know what that is.
Speaker 1: I've no idea.
Speaker 0: I had no idea either.
Speaker 0: and you know what else he did with that camera.
Speaker 0: took pictures besides that more specifically broke it.
Speaker 0: stop-motion the stop-motion tilt shift lens and Monster truck rally, you know what the result is a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: the whole monster truck rally.
Speaker 0: It looks like matchbox cars and all the people look like toy people.
Speaker 0: And he made a video of this because it's stop-motion and he put this cool song on.
Speaker 0: it called metal heart and he aimed the Video after the song metal heart.
Speaker 0: and it's pretty cool because like there's like a little demolition derby with all these matchbox cars.
Speaker 0: It's Just a pretty hilarious video all around.
Speaker 1: Oh, I see how it works.
Speaker 1: There's a good Wikipedia thing that explains tilt shifting.
Speaker 0: Yes, it you tilt every shit.
Speaker 1: Well it reduced by doing that because you're taking everything at the angle.
Speaker 1: It reduces the depth of field.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Anyway, everything looks tiny like it's a toy and it's awesome and you should watch it.
Speaker 0: All right, especially when the Robotic, you know monster thing comes out.
Speaker 1: So we've been playing Left 4 Dead and of course, it's fun, but we haven't really Messed around with the game a lot yet.
Speaker 1: I mean a lot of people.
Speaker 1: when I was younger and a game like this was out I would be looking for glitches and then exploiting those glitches for hilarity and all that instead.
Speaker 0: now I watch other people explain the glitches on YouTube and I just play normal like.
Speaker 1: yes now I have not Attempted this and I don't know if valve is fixed it because they tend to be very vague when they release updates to Left 4 Dead like a lot of the updates say fixed a glitch or Fixed the exploits that we're not going to better than
Speaker 0: Apple Saying bug fixes,
Speaker 1: but I suspected something like this and we're gonna try to experimentally verify the behavior here.
Speaker 1: but it appears that if you just abandon your team and just move through the map as fast as possible You can stay ahead of I guess where the AI director is deciding what to do and most of the zombies will spawn behind you.
Speaker 1: all the swarms if they spawn at all will spawn behind you and Any boss zombies that spawn in front of you will be glitched and stupid will probably run backwards.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if everyone runs together It doesn't work because then you've got everyone together and it's gonna try to get you.
Speaker 0: But if you've got three people falling way back and one person way ahead It's gonna keep attacking the three people and not the one person.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna have to experiment with this and then possibly run ahead.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz I've thought about running ahead a few times but I never ran ahead that far.
Speaker 0: and in this video some girl just starts running Way far ahead everyone else and then this other guy says oh, I thought we were gonna play seriously.
Speaker 0: I guess not.
Speaker 0: so he starts running and the other two people stay behind and die and The girl makes it the safe room and then the guy eventually shows up at the safe room She lets him in and that's over.
Speaker 1: though in general I gotta say I can only play left for dead with good people anymore because I want to move fast and people just like hunker down and waste all their ammo and their time in their life like Hiding from every zombie swarm instead of just fighting their way through it and moving on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely, you know if the team sits in one spot too long It's no good.
Speaker 0: And I think the last versus game we played was was the awesome.
Speaker 1: That was such a close game until the very end.
Speaker 0: when my it's like It's like at first.
Speaker 0: I join in right seven geek nights.
Speaker 0: people already there including rim and rims You know gets on a team with some people I recognize the names of so I'm like shit among the team of people I don't recognize the names of.
Speaker 0: is this gonna be a bad team?
Speaker 0: as I knows At least two people on the other team rim and classic are good.
Speaker 0: are the people on this team good?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: this could turn out to be bad for me.
Speaker 1: They won the first round by like 40 points that we won the first round by like almost nothing And then we won the second round.
Speaker 0: So in the end we were like they were ahead by like five points.
Speaker 0: It was this incredibly tiny margin and I was like, ah, I was like, alright guys We got to win this and then in the third round.
Speaker 1: We just destroy.
Speaker 0: it was total ownage.
Speaker 1: and in the fourth round It was total ownage again and we wrecked them, but I can't say one thing if you watch this video Times I have played this game with good people.
Speaker 1: the team of four has moved almost this quickly.
Speaker 1: So it is possible.
Speaker 1: Don't hide in the back.
Speaker 1: I feel like this should be something like the the rallying cry of shoot the medic not the heavy.
Speaker 1: move fast not slow Yeah, just freaking.
Speaker 0: go go go go go.
Speaker 0: go.
Speaker 1: 180 miles an hour.
Speaker 0: Yeah Stop when you have to but then as soon as there's an opening go like as soon as it's quiet go Soon as elevator opens get in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's been a long time since there has been a two or three player board game.
Speaker 0: Oh wait hit before we start is an idea.
Speaker 0: You know how when people like running a mile or something or like, you know in in the Olympics and such They have like people who are just there to like set the pace, you know It's like they'll go fast and you just one guy keeps up with them But then they drop behind
Speaker 1: nominate one person on the team to be the pace setter, right?
Speaker 0: Someone is the pace setter and it's like everyone else.
Speaker 0: just keep up with me, you know, and I'll be the leader.
Speaker 1: Well, you go one step further and you the pace setter is also the point mmm.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess theoretically if you're coordinated the pace setter should be the rear guard but that's very hard to pull off unless you're really Good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's like everyone.
Speaker 0: shit You know, there's someone in front and everyone just keep up with that guy in front.
Speaker 0: everyone Just do it, you know and guy in front just keep going as fast as you.
Speaker 1: well as we've proven if you apply even rudimentary tactical Thinking and predefined strategy to left for dead The game ends.
Speaker 1: you just wait.
Speaker 0: Well, we haven't played an expert yet.
Speaker 0: So what to say?
Speaker 1: Well inverses at least.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, definitely.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so we've had this trouble where there aren't good two or three player board games.
Speaker 1: I mean By the way game theory is a versus three player game will either devolve into solitaire You know non interactive solitaire or weekly interactive solitaire or it'll devolve into Two people gang up and have a chance of winning Thereby increasing their odds of winning to 50% while the third person is marginalized has no reason to continue.
Speaker 0: Yep, because there are games where you can hurt the other players.
Speaker 0: For example a war game, right?
Speaker 0: I can just attack rim or attack Alex right and in that kind of game you'll end up where You can't.
Speaker 0: not everyone is just going to attack the person to their right and be attacked by the person on their left.
Speaker 0: It's not going to work out that way.
Speaker 0: Someone's.
Speaker 0: whoever goes down first is down and the other two people is.
Speaker 0: Whoever gets the spoils is probably gonna win in a three-player game.
Speaker 1: There is no incentive to play evenly.
Speaker 1: you want to Crush one other player.
Speaker 1: So basically as soon as bus increasing your chances of winning from one out of three to one out of Two so as soon as any one player is weak everyone else well everyone else the other two people should pounce on them.
Speaker 1: and When it's me Scott and Alex playing that always happens because that's the optimal strategy doing anything.
Speaker 1: In fact, it's at the point where if you if that didn't happen We'd almost be disappointed because then clearly someone is playing sub optimally and stupidly.
Speaker 0: Yep, someone's either like just holding out and then not attacking or you know Something like that.
Speaker 0: two-player games, you know if you do that, right then it becomes two two-player games.
Speaker 0: But the second two-player game one person is double power because they have the spoils from the first two-player game and two-player games either boil down to paper rock scissors, yep, or Indirect solitaire.
Speaker 1: Yep So we've had trouble because it's not often we'll get you know The five people we need to play like the optimal set of all the good games we own Pretty much four or five or six people.
Speaker 1: we can play awesome games two or three not happening.
Speaker 1: So finally a game appeared that has provided Two and three player play that does not immediately break down.
Speaker 0: Not immediately, but it'll break down.
Speaker 1: but it has not yet and doesn't look like it will anytime soon.
Speaker 0: And as soon as it does, well, it's sufficiently complex that it's not gonna.
Speaker 1: as soon as the game does break down It's definitely going to turn into one of those really good four and five player games.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I mean the game is is Agricola?
Speaker 0: I think is the correct pronunciation The pronunciation should be Agricola.
Speaker 0: Well, that's what we say.
Speaker 1: No, that's not just what we say.
Speaker 1: That is what the dude what speaks Latin at my office said.
Speaker 0: it should be pronounced as oh, whatever It's like you and your Herakles.
Speaker 1: Well, the the name in Greek was Herakles.
Speaker 0: Are you Greek?
Speaker 1: Well, if you're saying that are you Greek?
Speaker 0: if you're saying the name, are you Greek?
Speaker 1: But so the Scott.
Speaker 1: by that logic, I mean do you ever translate names?
Speaker 0: Do you say?
Speaker 0: Schedule.
Speaker 1: No, I'm not saying everyone should say Herakles.
Speaker 1: I'm saying the name of the person as he called himself.
Speaker 1: Did he exist or as he was spoken of?
Speaker 1: I mean when you read the Count of Monte Cristo and someone's name is Etienne Do you want to translate it to Steve?
Speaker 0: Doesn't really matter.
Speaker 1: or do you just leave it as Etienne?
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: you leave it as Herakles or do you change it to Hercules anyway in Greek?
Speaker 1: It's Herakles.
Speaker 1: It was romanized to Hercules doesn't matter Doesn't matter at all.
Speaker 1: the point is Agricola is a word in Latin.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so Agricola is what I'll say.
Speaker 0: either way because that is our funny mispronunciation or in rims case correct Latin pronunciation.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: It is a simulation.
Speaker 1: We've talked about this.
Speaker 1: We don't have to talk about what the game is about.
Speaker 1: We've already.
Speaker 0: it's a farming game.
Speaker 0: you farm.
Speaker 1: it simulates Freeholder farmers or farm families in the end of the Middle Ages beginning of the Renaissance times in Europe.
Speaker 0: Yep, you grow your crops you bake your bread you care for your animals you make babies You take care tell you.
Speaker 1: making babies is necessary and costly.
Speaker 0: indeed It's pretty much the whole point of the game is to make babies and you got to feed the babies.
Speaker 0: That's the hard part And that's it.
Speaker 0: I mean.
Speaker 0: it reminds me a lot of Calus in that you sort of have these Board of open actions and when one person takes the action, no one else can take the action that turn.
Speaker 0: It also reminds me of like a few games I've played online like.
Speaker 0: there was this one flash game That was like a poverty simulator and it's like each turn You pick what you want each person in your family to do and you just try to get by without starving.
Speaker 0: You know the same sort of mechanic goes on there.
Speaker 1: Well, the game is a basically a resource optimization game.
Speaker 1: straight up You're trying to you start with a very very limited set of resources and among your resources are the you know The things on the board that you acquire and your actions which are your people that you get to spend to do things.
Speaker 0: Actions is the most viable resource.
Speaker 1: Well, yes, but that basically you take these actions and you try to Use them to acquire more goods and more resources in order to spend those resources to get more resources Optimizing your growth and then having the optimal set of resources at the end of the game to get the most points.
Speaker 0: Yep, and the thing about the game is like the way the scoring goes is it's it's not one of those games.
Speaker 0: You want to get a whole bunch of one thing?
Speaker 0: But then again, you don't want to get a little bit of everything either.
Speaker 0: you want to get a whole lot of everything In order to get the most points.
Speaker 1: Well, the game has a certain mechanism designed to where the obvious strategies of these other games They're like this tend to not work.
Speaker 1: the I'll pick one thing and hammer it and optimize it and make this Perfectly working machine that just takes in sheep and spits out victory points.
Speaker 1: You can't do anything like that in this game.
Speaker 0: Well what the game does really well is at the same time as you're trying to get victory points You're also trying to feed your family right and get a bigger family Which means you have to feed them more in order to carry on.
Speaker 0: if you ever fail to feed your family You're fucked.
Speaker 1: you're basically done.
Speaker 0: So and the way to age of steam mechanic, right?
Speaker 0: So early on in the game You're just trying to get this food Machine rolling so that you can get enough food to feed a bigger family to get more food to feed the bigger family.
Speaker 0: And then I'm doing so awesome.
Speaker 0: I can make so much extra stuff that even though I'm also feeding my family I can also get victory points, right?
Speaker 0: but the way to most early on.
Speaker 0: you want to feed the family efficiently.
Speaker 0: you want to get that food as quickly as possible and The way to do that is to pick one thing and go for it.
Speaker 0: Right, if you try to spread out early on, you know a little bit of sheep a little bit of grain a little bit of vegetable A little bit of baking a little bit of cooking.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna get the food early enough.
Speaker 1: Actually, that's how I've won both of the games that I won.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 1: by spreading out a lot early on and not hammering anything?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you're not gonna get the food as quickly, you know, I didn't need it.
Speaker 1: I got plenty I got enough food to feed my feet and that's that's the trick there.
Speaker 0: Right is is you want to get the food more efficiently?
Speaker 0: you target in so you have this instinct to target in on one thing.
Speaker 0: But really, you know, you can get enough food without the targeting even though it's less efficient on the food getting.
Speaker 1: but anyway the deal with this game.
Speaker 1: the reason is notable at all because From all we've said it's just a solitaire game.
Speaker 1: It doesn't break or fix any of the problems of two or three player games and sounds a little bit of non solid.
Speaker 1: This is the point I'm making right now because it all that appears from this to just be a solitary.
Speaker 0: You can actually play it.
Speaker 0: solitaire comes which is for one player lame.
Speaker 1: But at the same time that's probably a good way to practice and just.
Speaker 1: it's an easy way to do All the math to solve the game without having to actually do the math.
Speaker 1: it's much more intuitive to play the game single player than it is to sit down with a pen and paper and actually calculate the odds and calculate the patterns and all that.
Speaker 1: but Solitaire games suck and I hate them.
Speaker 1: They're just they're not fun because you're not really.
Speaker 1: it's kind of like playing.
Speaker 1: I play a tower defense game and you play a tower defense game and then you know We keep playing it and see who has the highest score and that's it and there's no interaction at all There's.
Speaker 1: so it's an entirely strategic and not at all tactical game.
Speaker 1: This game while it is highly strategic is also highly tactical because there is a Commons.
Speaker 1: the Commons from which you get resources is Extremely limited.
Speaker 1: every round if you take an action and every action is unique No one else can take that action at all.
Speaker 0: Not that round.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so for example if I take wood this round No one else can take wood And in fact, I've emptied the wood bin and the wood bin will fill up slowly.
Speaker 0: Well relatively slowly but at the same time.
Speaker 1: to the other cool thing that while this is so limited The rules in terms of what you can do with the resources you spend Unlike most other German board games and most other games are not fiddly and not arbitrarily limited.
Speaker 1: If you take the build action you can build as many things as you can possibly afford in whatever configuration you want and a lot of times when you build something it'll Give you an.
Speaker 0: and/or.
Speaker 0: it's like yeah build part pieces for your build rooms in your hut and or build stables.
Speaker 0: We don't care.
Speaker 0: build as many stables and hut rooms as you want go nuts.
Speaker 0: It's like wow two different things.
Speaker 0: You can do it like so fields as many as you want and bake bread as many as you want at the same time.
Speaker 0: It's like so.
Speaker 1: there's definitely this desire to one.
Speaker 1: Tactically, you might want to take a suboptimal action to prevent your opponent from taking an extremely example.
Speaker 0: You might want to sew without baking bread just to prevent your opponent from sewing and baking bread But at the same because then you'll you'll starve them and then they're age of steamed.
Speaker 1: It's over Yep, but at the same time you have this instinct, which is probably a good one to build up resources and build up resources.
Speaker 1: this is also I think why the extremely powerful nature of taking an action does.
Speaker 1: denying it to everyone else doesn't break the game.
Speaker 1: if You save up your resources in an optimal configuration Then you can take that action later and have the same effect because you can spend all the resources you've gathered up to this point.
Speaker 1: while The other person took the action earlier They spent all the resources they had but they didn't get as much out of the taking of the build action.
Speaker 1: Yep, so basically the game's resource mechanics are Very enough and fiddly enough.
Speaker 1: I mean building materials.
Speaker 1: There's wood and there's reeds and there's stone.
Speaker 1: There's a whole bunch of different kinds of animals and you have two pastures for all of them and stables and all that business.
Speaker 1: There's different kinds of crops.
Speaker 1: There's different buildings.
Speaker 1: There's specialists.
Speaker 1: There's so many things in the game that they skirt the line between so many, you know good game design solely through obscurity and Obscurity.
Speaker 1: that makes the game good and challenging and intellectually stimulating.
Speaker 0: It also skirts the line between just randomness going on But also, you know some sort of you know complex and varied controls that are somehow equal.
Speaker 1: But luckily the game does a fantastic job of having a lot of randomness the randomness thus preventing Set strategies like Puerto Rico.
Speaker 1: The only randomness is the plantations and at least in the three-player game It's pretty much a solved on deal and there's no there really isn't any effective randomness.
Speaker 1: because you can you can as a player mitigate the randomness so much and The amount of randomness that is there is so little that the game will still break down.
Speaker 0: Yep, but in Agricola.
Speaker 0: right you get at the beginning of the game every player gets seven minor improvement cards and seven occupation cards.
Speaker 0: There are also is a tray with I think ten or twelve major Improvement cards that are available to everyone.
Speaker 0: and these all these cards are basically sort of like buildings in Puerto Rico.
Speaker 0: Right you you you find some way to play them in front of you by you know paying the cost the appropriate cost and then They you know give you new abilities or powers.
Speaker 0: And there's a lot of them and they all have different powers.
Speaker 0: and in some ways if you draw better ones or better Combination of them at the beginning of the game because you can never draw anymore.
Speaker 0: That's it That's the 14 cards you get that's it.
Speaker 0: never know more, right?
Speaker 1: well, there are some things that change that but we don't have to get into that but
Speaker 0: You know they if you draw better cards, maybe you'll have an advantage Maybe you won't you will be different from the other players,
Speaker 1: but the brilliance of this game This is I think what stands out in the game more than anything and it wasn't obvious to us right away And it probably wouldn't be obvious to you if you just played the game sight unseen.
Speaker 1: But early on one of the first games Scott played He you know he has all these professions the people because one thing you can do is play these people and they all have these different effects.
Speaker 1: You feel like you like you can make all these combos like wow if I get all four of these guys and play like they're All great, and you feel like you want to use them all.
Speaker 1: and Scott tried to use a lot of them.
Speaker 1: But looking at the game you probably unless you're playing a very specific strategy will only ever play maybe two of them.
Speaker 1: the majority of the cards you have in your hand both improvements and Professions will go unplayed and are expected to go on played.
Speaker 1: It's not that you're supposed to use them all and bring them all out at the right time It's that you are given all these tactical and strategic options.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like a randomized draft.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the thing is right with the cards.
Speaker 0: let's say there's a card that says four ears a card I I know actually right.
Speaker 0: it says If you have this card in front of you And you build the fourth room in your house you automatically get the fifth room in your house.
Speaker 0: Right so think about this you have to spend an action to play this card.
Speaker 0: Then you have to spend another action to build the fourth room in your house And then you automatically get the fifth room in your house, right?
Speaker 0: What does that get you?
Speaker 0: well you spent two actions?
Speaker 0: And you saved the resources.
Speaker 0: it costs normally to build a house room.
Speaker 0: So it's like how much does it cost to build a house room like five?
Speaker 0: Resources in or five wooden to read something like that.
Speaker 0: so basically the card saves you five wooden to read.
Speaker 0: If you know you had an extra read lying around and there's five wood lying on a wood spot.
Speaker 0: You could spend two actions to take the wood and then build the fourth room in your house and thus you're still spending two actions and Still getting the fifth room in the house You know at the same cost of resources and actions.
Speaker 0: so the card didn't actually save you anything Except now you have a card in front of you that might get you points.
Speaker 0: You know if it has points associated with it Or if another card allows you to get points based on cards.
Speaker 0: So if a card doesn't save you an action or save you Resources that you couldn't have gotten with one action Then it's really sort of no difference if you use the card or don't.
Speaker 0: the only difference it makes is Well for the other players you're either going to block up the play card action or block up the get resource action.
Speaker 0: So it basically just gives you a most of the time a different way to do the same thing Except for the rare cases where it actually saves you an action, which is when you definitely want to do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it doesn't save you an action.
Speaker 0: doing it is sort of yes No Maybe
Speaker 1: but the kind of the randomized draft coupled with the fact that you get it gives you all these kind of tactical and strategic Options, I mean you see all your cards at the beginning and you can make your strategy based on that.
Speaker 0: You're not drawing the cards throughout the game.
Speaker 0: You know, you're it's all the beginning and then you make a plan based on it.
Speaker 1: Yes, and you can definitely have a very very clear strategy a very precise strategy, but at the same time you have to be tactically agile and able to react to what the other players are doing and be able to anticipate what the other players will do.
Speaker 1: and these factors more so than the complexity of the math of the game are Probably what are going to give it the longer play time that it otherwise might not have worn.
Speaker 0: The other things about the game that are that are interesting to note is that number one If you play with different numbers of players the game actually changes drastically.
Speaker 0: like all these new actions come out and all these new cards come out and the game is completely different.
Speaker 0: so It scales very well.
Speaker 0: I mean this thing is from one to six players.
Speaker 1: It also has There are multiple decks of cards.
Speaker 0: Well that there's two.
Speaker 0: there's two things going on here, right?
Speaker 0: There's you get a lot of cards with the game Right and the cards are minor improvements and occupations of the two kinds of cards in each deck.
Speaker 0: Right, there is the complex deck the interactive deck the basic deck and the Z man.
Speaker 0: Who's the US publisher expansion deck?
Speaker 0: so you can mix up the cards any which way you want.
Speaker 0: if you think a card is?
Speaker 0: Unbalanced get it out of there.
Speaker 0: Right if you think a card is too weak get it out of there, you know You can just mix and match the cards to make any deck you want.
Speaker 0: as long as there are at least seven cards of each Kind per player everyone will get enough cards.
Speaker 0: so it doesn't matter which cards you have in there.
Speaker 0: as long as you think they're fair put them in.
Speaker 0: if you think they're Unfair take them out.
Speaker 0: and if you want a game that's more interactive just use the interactive deck.
Speaker 0: If you think one again is more complex use just the complex deck.
Speaker 0: if you want a game That's random shuffle all the cards together and go nuts.
Speaker 0: You know plus a lot of the cards are like this card is only for three and up player games.
Speaker 0: This card is only for four and up player games.
Speaker 0: So you won't put those cards in when there's like two players because they won't mess up Really break the game or they won't work because other things change in the two-player game.
Speaker 0: The card won't make sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah now the one thing I guess my enjoyment in this game one thing that really stands out is that you know like the difference between Age of steam and railroad tycoon was that you feel like you're accomplishing something and Few games like this have ever instilled in me a sense of accomplishment like this game does but at the same time have Hit me so hard and made me feel at times Simultaneously like I was accomplishing so little.
Speaker 0: yes Like you start out with Jack and she start with the meager ist of crap.
Speaker 0: You got like two people in a hut.
Speaker 1: You start with nothing and all of the option.
Speaker 1: like the things you do.
Speaker 1: the options you have are pitiful.
Speaker 0: It's like one grain.
Speaker 1: take a tiny bit of stuff put out plow one field And they're the first like.
Speaker 1: you'll go through the whole.
Speaker 1: like the game actually plays really quickly Except for the time people spend thinking and the whole like first set of the game.
Speaker 1: You're making very important very heady decisions But yet the fruits of your labor do not come into play.
Speaker 0: for you know five or six turns Yeah And you have to feed your people.
Speaker 1: like the harvest comes quickly you have to set in motion Events in turn one that will come into fruition in turn five and be ready for that.
Speaker 1: Then the whole.
Speaker 0: if you don't have enough food you will starve and then you basically just lose if you can't feed your people.
Speaker 0: All right, it's basically just you're out.
Speaker 0: the thing I've always wondered right and that no one's tried yet is Consider this the the begging strategy.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: The game is specifically designed to prevent that.
Speaker 0: is it really?
Speaker 1: Yes, because remember you take more begging if you have if your food deficit is greater.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: But if you didn't then the obvious strategy is at one point in the game Beg produce zero food and just go crazy with the victory points.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, here's my.
Speaker 0: here's the strategy I'm thinking of.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: Let's say per chance.
Speaker 0: You didn't have enough food.
Speaker 0: Maybe you had some food, but not enough.
Speaker 0: There was a move you could make.
Speaker 0: you could write.
Speaker 0: someone else in the game needs one particular action to get enough food instead of feeding yourself with another action.
Speaker 0: Instead block them and forcing both of you to beg right and or maybe multiple players to beg and in that way the begging didn't matter because Everyone begged.
Speaker 1: Yes, that is definitely a strategy But I feel like the situation would have to like arise perfectly.
Speaker 0: I feel like moons would have to line up in a straight row.
Speaker 1: I get the impression that if you ever beg you've done fucked.
Speaker 1: I also I get the impression that if you beg you fucked up, of course I did pull a somewhat fantastic coup against Scott and Alex the most recent.
Speaker 1: well,
Speaker 0: you forgot you had the car that lets you eat wood,
Speaker 1: but simultaneously I basically pointed out that I could not win the game and I had a lot of Math to back me up by not pointing out the card I had that let my people eat wood because they both also forgot about it despite the fact that I made a big deal about it way in the beginning of the game and I basically convinced them both that I had lost the game totally and there was no way I could win And I was like I shouldn't even play anymore.
Speaker 1: Let's just get this game done with go go go.
Speaker 1: and then they ignored me the rest of the game And then I won by one point.
Speaker 0: Well, we were ignore you.
Speaker 0: we were just be all he did.
Speaker 0: really it didn't change my game strategically.
Speaker 0: what he changed was basically we were.
Speaker 0: it realized there is a flaw in the game and that if Let's say Rin didn't have that card He was in a position Where he fucked up and there's no way he could win because he would been forced to beg and it was close to the end Of the game and he couldn't have won.
Speaker 1: Yes, there's that.
Speaker 0: if that situation arises Why should he keep playing?
Speaker 0: and that's frustrating for the other players?
Speaker 0: Cuz it's like well if I was in his shoes, I agree.
Speaker 0: Why should I keep playing?
Speaker 0: I can't win but being one of the other players who can win.
Speaker 0: Now my game is ruined if he decides to stop playing because now I'm not gonna find out who wins.
Speaker 0: Cuz the game's over.
Speaker 1: some games deal with this very elegantly in that you still like railroad tycoon Even if you can't win if the game is fun enough and you can accomplish enough in your turn To where the end of the game is enjoyable.
Speaker 0: other games have rules that are awesome like quitting without fucking up the game.
Speaker 1: do this Yep, or age of steam.
Speaker 1: Well, you fucked up.
Speaker 1: You're done out of the game.
Speaker 1: You're out bankrupt zero leave.
Speaker 1: Yep But this game.
Speaker 1: I can foresee Players getting into that situation and there's especially bad players against good players.
Speaker 0: It's gonna easily happen where they get in a situation where it's obvious They cannot win no matter what even if they were allowed to do whatever they wanted to.
Speaker 1: there's no.
Speaker 1: I mean I can think of a few hackish ways out, but there's no elegant way out.
Speaker 0: No, unless you have like miracle cards in your hand or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's one of the biggest failings of the game.
Speaker 1: that and the fact that it worries me how powerful an extra child is and the fact that Basically One player in a three-player game It is very easy for one player to be denied an extra child For so long that it might be impossible for them to win.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much you can just keep you know Depending on the card that comes up that lets you make babies comes up someone immediately gets on it.
Speaker 0: Okay, the next round no one else can get on it, right?
Speaker 0: So that person has a baby before everyone else.
Speaker 0: the next round they use their baby Someone else immediately jumps on and gets the second baby or the same person does it or see?
Speaker 1: I think the problem is in a two-player game.
Speaker 1: is he is kind of even out.
Speaker 1: in a four-player game More likely one person gets a little boost instead of one person getting kicked down.
Speaker 1: Yeah in three-player I feel like there's this specific condition Whereby a player can be marginalized Completely out of the game through no fault of their third person doesn't get the baby Right.
Speaker 0: the third person to get the baby is sort of way down there because this harvest comes before and then There's sort of a step behind everyone.
Speaker 1: now this happened to me, but I saved it.
Speaker 1: I salvaged it, but I could foresee a situation where it's on.
Speaker 1: so don't have the wood eating card Yes, but even if I didn't have the wood eating card of course my whole strategy would have been different.
Speaker 1: But still there remains that there could be situations whereby you could lose a game through no fault of your own.
Speaker 1: But I'm not sure yet.
Speaker 1: hmm the game needs a lot more play.
Speaker 0: It does it does, but that's the one thing it hasn't gotten bored.
Speaker 0: yet another thing about this game.
Speaker 0: Right is a lot of times I'll play games that have like where you put a lot of cards out in front of you right even something like magic the gathering.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: you put a bunch of cards out that have like permanent effects, and I'll always be like ah shit I forgot about this card.
Speaker 0: I had I didn't do what it said.
Speaker 0: crap you know.
Speaker 0: I can try to remember what game that happens to me in a lot.
Speaker 0: I can't think of one right now, but it's always like you play special powers in front of you and then later It's like oh, I forgot to use this even though.
Speaker 0: I had it crap.
Speaker 1: well in La Chita I remember a number of times all of us would forget to count one of our cities.
Speaker 0: But yeah stuff like that, but that game's just hard to score.
Speaker 0: like you know I'll have a card in front of me that says take an extra victory point.
Speaker 0: if this happens Then that will happen like three times, and I'll be like oh, I forgot to take the extra victory point.
Speaker 0: shit You know I could have had three points, but now I forgot crap in a Greek Allah.
Speaker 0: That doesn't really happen.
Speaker 0: I seem to remember every card.
Speaker 0: I have in front of me and use them all at every appropriate opportunity Which is I don't know what about something about the design of the game?
Speaker 0: You know what it is me from forgetting the cards and whatever it is I don't know what it is is good The game is so there's so little actually going on.
Speaker 1: the decisions you make as complex and horrible as they are to make are Simple to enact and are limited in number on an absolute scale.
Speaker 1: so the kids you'll spend most of your time Reading all your cards over and over again and forming very complex strategies and very complex like.
Speaker 1: I'll do this on turn two So that in turn five because he won't need this and he won't need this I'll be able to take this action, and then this action
Speaker 0: Yeah I think also part of it though with the cards is sort of like San Juan where San Juan has all these cards and you look at them You're like man.
Speaker 0: if I can get the well and the steeple and the something else then I could get like a bajillion Resources with like one play.
Speaker 0: the thing is you're better off just getting a whole bunch of silver mines Right?
Speaker 0: so I feel like in Agricola.
Speaker 0: Maybe you're better off just getting a whole bunch of big Obvious like major improvements and forgetting all the little cards that add up and combo together.
Speaker 1: because well don't combo That's the thing you can't combo.
Speaker 1: you can't expect to play all these things at the same time.
Speaker 1: You just have to have a strategy.
Speaker 1: And I think the reason we don't forget to use cards is that cards not only have a very specific purpose But the cost of playing a card is Enormous, so if you play a card you had a fucking good reason to play it And you're not gonna forget about.
Speaker 0: yeah, you're gonna.
Speaker 0: You know when you play a card you're gonna use it at least twice.
Speaker 0: otherwise that was stupid Because you wasted a whole action.
Speaker 0: if you're only gonna use it once you probably could have just did a different action and got an Equivalent you know effect for it, but uh in I guess in conclusion This game is fantastic.
Speaker 1: if you're a board game fan.
Speaker 1: Just buy it.
Speaker 1: don't even worry about.
Speaker 0: yeah This is pretty much the game right now.
Speaker 0: It's very it's.
Speaker 0: it's got a lot of things in common with a lot of other games like Kayla's and things like that.
Speaker 0: But it's different enough from other games and it combines elements from many different games that it is something unique that stands alone and Even if it's eventually solved it has a lot of replay value.
Speaker 0: and for most people who aren't as crazy as us about solving games You'll probably be entertained by this like times a hajillion.
Speaker 1: and also you know crazy at us.
Speaker 1: You know we always laugh like yeah settlers of Catan is a completely worthless game if you've solved it.
Speaker 1: It took us years to solve it
Speaker 0: and the vast majority of people will never solve it and they will always find settlers of Catan to be awesome and That vast majority of people will find Agricola to be awesome forever probably But
Speaker 1: I guess not to sound like we're conceited about that the only reason we solve games like settlers or three-player boarders.
Speaker 1: We're crazy.
Speaker 1: We play them.
Speaker 0: We play them too much.
Speaker 0: most people play them like once in a blue moon.
Speaker 1: We would play settlers every day in college.
Speaker 1: We would play Puerto Rico like three or four times a day over the summer.
Speaker 1: Yep It's crazy.
Speaker 0: people mostly will be happy to play settlers once a week or once a month.
Speaker 1: Yeah And I mean I guess the number of times we played it Makes sense if you don't say if you play a game that many times you haven't solved it something's wrong.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right I think we're done.
Speaker 1: Agricola is great.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front road crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.