Speaker 1: It's Monday January 7th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek knives tonight.
Speaker 1: Love sex and robots.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: You think in New York City that the you know big one of the most important cities in the world if not the most important.
Speaker 0: You could get a decent internet connection.
Speaker 1: But no Well, uh, I would wager that while New York City is one of the most important cities in the world Your company is not one of the most important companies in the way.
Speaker 0: So it's nothing to do with our company has to do with the building.
Speaker 0: You see you when you're in New York City, you don't own a building.
Speaker 0: I mean if you do own a building then your company is a company that owns buildings and doesn't do anything else, right?
Speaker 1: You know, I can't really make fun of this too much because I've actually been having similar issues at my company.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like we're sitting around.
Speaker 1: we're like, alright How can we get better wires into our business?
Speaker 1: and the answer was well How much you're willing to pay?
Speaker 1: and the answer to that was anything Anything.
Speaker 1: we just want it to be better and there's no way.
Speaker 0: nope Cuz you're at the mercy of the building.
Speaker 1: so and it's not that you can't get it technologically.
Speaker 1: It's that the people who run the buildings in New York City You just don't know jack all about technology and not only are we at the mercy of the building.
Speaker 0: We're also at the mercy of Verizon.
Speaker 0: In
Speaker 1: In all my life I've discovered that Verizon is the least shitty of the people you have to call if you've got like a t1 down or something
Speaker 0: and that's why they can afford to sell t1s and but also lease out their copper to other people to sell t1s on because you can buy a t1 from someone else who leases Verizon's copper and then sells it to you at a lower price and you save money that way.
Speaker 0: or you can buy a t1 from Verizon.
Speaker 0: but you know what if you pay for a t1 from the people actually own the copper things are usually better for you.
Speaker 0: It's a racket It works out.
Speaker 0: But anyway We have some like Ethernet loops to this company down the road and it went out once and it went out twice and now it Went out again.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: I think you've done this opening bit before Maybe talking about your internet being down at work.
Speaker 1: now you couldn't do anything.
Speaker 0: But anyway, there's like there's one of those companies that lets you aim a dish at their you know To do the might the direct link thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah But the the building won't.
Speaker 0: let us put a dish on the roof Even though we already have a direct TV dish up there because the building doesn't allow cable.
Speaker 0: There's no cable in the building.
Speaker 1: tell them it's another direct TV dish and paint it to look like one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they're also doing like construction up this they don't want anyway But also it just.
Speaker 0: they're just being a huge pain in the ass and there's nobody that we can get fast internet from in that Building even though this shit tons of bandwidth all around.
Speaker 0: We can't get it in that building because I tell you what if we ever?
Speaker 1: That's the one thing if we like, you know Go pro with this or whatever and we end up just having some sort of computer shop here in Beacon We can get some pretty damn fast internet.
Speaker 1: It'll probably be pretty damn awesome fucking fiber or something.
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 0: no can't get any fiber or anything.
Speaker 0: It's horrendous man.
Speaker 1: Still bothers me that the FiOS is like right there down the road.
Speaker 1: Yep, like I can walk to where the FiOS I'd get it in a second But in other news because I feel like we've talked about this before when your company's internet goes down Scott and I once again ran afoul of a fat and dignit lady.
Speaker 0: You're talking about me talking about an opening bit that we've done before and now you're talking about a fat and dignit lady.
Speaker 1: That might have been intentional.
Speaker 1: I don't know maybe But seriously, it was like we're up the road pretty much.
Speaker 1: I think this is the last time we're gonna go up the road.
Speaker 0: You know a long time at least.
Speaker 1: we always say up the road and basically live in Beacon.
Speaker 1: Everything we need is in Beacon or on the internet, but there's residual things that except for groceries which are in Vishal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well they exist in Beacon, but I would not consider that to be a grocery store more.
Speaker 0: I don't consider anything nearby to be a grocery store.
Speaker 1: Well, something could be nearby and be a grocery store.
Speaker 1: However, what is nearby is not a grocery store and smells.
Speaker 1: Yes So, uh, I I mean the last time I drove to the mall was I tried to get some glasses during a blizzard and I discovered that Who doesn't go out during the blizzard?
Speaker 0: opticians opticians?
Speaker 1: So I show up and there's the doctor like yeah, you can buy glasses, but you can't get a checkup.
Speaker 1: There's no doctors.
Speaker 1: So I paid four times more to just deal with it in the city.
Speaker 1: But then again, I didn't pay anything.
Speaker 1: I didn't care Yeah, but uh, so we went up that road pretty much for the last time and we went beyond the mall All the way up the road to the gaming store which had nothing.
Speaker 1: yeah, we went in.
Speaker 1: we're like, oh wow Yeah, this place hasn't changed much.
Speaker 0: Wow, actually it changed a lot, but they didn't have anything for us.
Speaker 1: Remember we used to come here every month and play games with those guys.
Speaker 1: What if they're still alive?
Speaker 0: No, they're probably still alive.
Speaker 0: But I think they're game organized.
Speaker 0: gaming days are over.
Speaker 1: Yeah kind of sad.
Speaker 0: Well, probably see them at that gaming for hope.
Speaker 1: maybe yeah, but we know we pretty much did everything we could do up the road Craft store to buy stuff to build a clock decided it was worth it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got there and we're like, where's the clock shit?
Speaker 1: Where's the clock shit?
Speaker 1: We found the clock stuff like alright All we have to do is buy the mechanisms and we can make our custom fuck it.
Speaker 1: and then we left.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those are not the kind of mechanisms I was looking for.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, uh, we're in this parking lot And you know, I'm gonna leave and go back home.
Speaker 1: I got I didn't buy a ski jacket.
Speaker 1: and Thank you internet, you know I go to EMS.
Speaker 1: I buy a ski mask buying Maljean.
Speaker 1: buy all this winter hat.
Speaker 1: cuz I realized.
Speaker 0: EMS a good store.
Speaker 1: I don't own a winter hat.
Speaker 1: I haven't owned a winter hat years.
Speaker 0: Are you ears cold?
Speaker 0: No, why not?
Speaker 1: Cuz I don't know they just don't get cold.
Speaker 1: So, uh, all right.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna buy a ski jacket cheapest one.
Speaker 1: They got 300 bucks.
Speaker 0: I bought mine.
Speaker 0: There wasn't 300 bucks wasn't a ski jacket.
Speaker 1: Oh So, uh, all right, I go online.
Speaker 1: I decide not to buy it.
Speaker 1: I look online.
Speaker 1: I can buy that exact same ski jacket for 200 bucks on the internet.
Speaker 0: Go.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Thank you internet retail stores Not so useful anymore granted.
Speaker 1: The worst thing is I'm there right now.
Speaker 1: I'm playing.
Speaker 1: I was gonna go skiing this coming weekend.
Speaker 1: I was all set to go skiing.
Speaker 1: I haven't skied in like slow warm to go ski.
Speaker 1: Well, you see yeah That's this thing now.
Speaker 1: It's like 70 degrees.
Speaker 1: So uh Skiing might not happen fund but on the way out in the parking lot narrow parking lot I was parked in a parking space.
Speaker 1: We get in the car and there's this fat woman sitting in the car next to us Suv by the way, and she's.
Speaker 1: she keeps like talking at us.
Speaker 0: Well, she talked at me and she was like blabbity blabbity blah and I was just like what.
Speaker 0: and she's like I had to crawl in through the passenger seat.
Speaker 0: cuz you know, I couldn't get in this way and What I should have said was well, maybe if you weren't fat and driving an SUV would never problem I can get in this car just fine.
Speaker 1: But instead Scott gets in the car.
Speaker 0: He said I'm just like talk to him I'm not driving and he gets to.
Speaker 1: the car is like that lady wants you and like what?
Speaker 1: so I like open my door and I stand up and I look to the right and I'm like Hello, and she's like you parked too close to me.
Speaker 1: I couldn't get into my car.
Speaker 1: There wasn't enough space.
Speaker 1: I had to get in from the other side.
Speaker 1: So I look at her for a second and I'm about to just like drive away cuz I don't care and she says it again Basically, so I stopped and I look now.
Speaker 0: keep in mind this parking lot.
Speaker 0: The spots were really close together like this parking lot was obviously old and not designed for large video.
Speaker 0: No, these were tiny parking space very tiny and close together parking spaces.
Speaker 1: So what I do is I just said alright and I look on both sides of my car and I walk around my car And I go, huh?
Speaker 1: I turned to her and I say well, I'm parked fully within the lines I'm no closer to your car than I am to the car on the other side of me.
Speaker 1: so it's obviously not my problem.
Speaker 1: and I go to get back in the car and I can see her getting angry and her face starts turning.
Speaker 0: I think she was angry before we even showed up.
Speaker 1: I think she was waiting for us to come back to try to yell at us.
Speaker 1: She was definitely waiting for us to come and she must've been waiting a while though cuz we had lunch and we wandered around.
Speaker 1: But so we're sitting there.
Speaker 0: We had lunch after that.
Speaker 1: Oh, we don't.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we did.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I weren't in there that long.
Speaker 1: then we just failed to buy clocks.
Speaker 0: Yep, and We succeeded in getting paper.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which we kind of needed.
Speaker 0: We really needed.
Speaker 1: so alright, so I just ignore her at this point.
Speaker 1: I go to get back in the car and she says well blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: people could be polite blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: I hope that someone does this to you.
Speaker 1: so blah blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: and she's getting louder and louder.
Speaker 1: as I'm Slowly like getting in the car ignoring her and closing the door and I could see her still talking as I was driving away.
Speaker 1: That woman was the third most indignant person.
Speaker 1: I have ever personally dealt with.
Speaker 0: I've dealt with a lot more indignant.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she was a fat indignant lady.
Speaker 1: the most indignant person I ever dealt with was waiting in line to go over the Lewiston bridge into Canada.
Speaker 1: That was the most indignant I've ever seen a human being.
Speaker 0: what about That lady who blocked the hallway?
Speaker 1: that lady was indignant But at the same time she was so furious when that guy said well Maybe you could lose some weights that she chooses.
Speaker 1: She was just standing there seething and she went from indignant into hilarious.
Speaker 0: Dignity is hilarious.
Speaker 1: I Think that's the point.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So what do you got in the news?
Speaker 0: What happened the news?
Speaker 0: Okay, so what happened?
Speaker 1: CES can talk about CES.
Speaker 0: Well, basically, there's so much new technology.
Speaker 0: It's sort of impossible to talk about anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm gonna buy unless he did the whole show on it.
Speaker 0: I mean we could just go down look go to Engadget.
Speaker 0: There's more stories posted on Engadget in the last two days.
Speaker 0: There have been like the last two months and every story is like new HDTV new phone new HDTV new phone new New this new that new this.
Speaker 0: do that.
Speaker 0: It isn't that and a lot of it's cool.
Speaker 0: A lot of its kind of.
Speaker 0: Bill Gates made his last keynote not so exciting.
Speaker 1: I heard it was a pretty good speech.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess you know for Bill Gates normal, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's not the best speaker.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean basically it's like, you know It really all I care about is the new technology like a lot of people reporting on the show itself.
Speaker 0: It's like come on.
Speaker 1: It's not like an anime con where cool things happen at the convention.
Speaker 0: Yeah at the show tell me about the thing that things themselves and some of the things that are going on there.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 1: granted if Steve Somehow started choking on the new iPhone that I might care about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Apple doesn't do too much at CES.
Speaker 0: No, they do their Mac worlds in there their personal things and they're hey the Apple stores down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something's happening.
Speaker 0: Knows we can't make a website that updates seamlessly without going down.
Speaker 1: I think they do that on purpose to generate buzz.
Speaker 0: I think they also do it to make it easier.
Speaker 0: Cuz Amazon doesn't even have a problem.
Speaker 0: They don't need to take their site down to update it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the one thing about not work like when I worked at IBM was like, oh we can't ever take anything down But anytime you have a server that only has to be accessed during business hours.
Speaker 1: It is so great to just take that fucker down and do something.
Speaker 1: today cherries like alright I can update the database.
Speaker 1: Well, the database is now read locked.
Speaker 1: The database is now down.
Speaker 1: the database is back up.
Speaker 1: Yep, as opposed to a shit someone connected.
Speaker 1: now everything went to hell.
Speaker 0: Yep So, yeah that Like.
Speaker 0: I thought that this week is be full of CES news and you know what?
Speaker 0: I think that as soon as the news starts to simmer down, you know It will boil and sediment and the most important bits of news will arise to the top and then we can discuss them.
Speaker 0: but right now it's just.
Speaker 0: This is this is this is this and this and this and this and this is this and if you actually care you can go Reading gadget or something.
Speaker 1: All I can really say is I think I found the laptop I am going to purchase unless it unless a very small power book comes out MacBook Pro.
Speaker 0: Well, what is?
Speaker 0: the Mac world is pretty soon the Mac world?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna hold out until Mac world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's in a little while and pretty much if what I want comes out of Apple I'm buying that.
Speaker 1: if it doesn't I'm buying that other laptop.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so here's a news ready.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, okay I'm wait.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Now I am.
Speaker 0: Okay this guy he came from Canada to Vermont I think.
Speaker 0: well, obviously Not all the details of what happened here are listed.
Speaker 0: So I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: maybe I read the news already But maybe I don't have all the details of this news But I have the the most important parts that they're relevant.
Speaker 0: The guy crossed the US Canadian border in some way and in some way it involves Vermont.
Speaker 0: He was suspected of having the child prawns on the computer.
Speaker 0: I guess they had warrants to you know, search his business and all that right and so they did search his business and whatever.
Speaker 0: But I guess they didn't have enough evidence.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: and this guy, you know, if he is having the child prawns It's not cool and I don't condone that.
Speaker 0: but he was smart enough to use the PGP encryption to encrypt his stuff So that they couldn't you know decrypt his drive and see what he had on there.
Speaker 1: All right, great.
Speaker 1: So the police get the computer and say hey you've got.
Speaker 1: well I'm surprised the police got to the point of realizing there was encryption in place.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's pretty.
Speaker 1: he probably has that like PGP Disk encryptor that encrypts the whole disk.
Speaker 1: You have to put a password into boot.
Speaker 1: Maybe he's otherwise there's no way.
Speaker 0: they'd know It's got to be something like that or they hired.
Speaker 1: a forensics guy like Katsu can do that stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But anyway, there was a subpoena from a grand jury that directed him to provide any passwords used with the laptop, right?
Speaker 0: Which sort of?
Speaker 0: and the judge right?
Speaker 0: So he goes hey, I'm not telling you the passwords.
Speaker 0: He can't make me.
Speaker 0: So the judge had to decide Does he have to give up the passwords or not?
Speaker 0: And of course if you don't give up the passwords and the judge says you have to you know what that is That's the Fifth Amendment contempt.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but the judge said no You don't have to give the passwords now because of the Fifth Amendment Exactly.
Speaker 0: You don't have to incriminate yourself, right?
Speaker 0: So I think it's pretty interesting and that when if I let's say I have in my house Something illegal drugs.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't have drugs in the house except Tylenol, I guess.
Speaker 0: but let's pretend I do okay, and The police are have reasonable suspicion enough to get a warrant from a judge and they want to search my house and have a warrant.
Speaker 0: They're allowed to search my house with a warrant.
Speaker 0: if I don't give them the key to my house They can either force me to give them the key or bust the door down and just search my house.
Speaker 0: There's nothing that's that's legal.
Speaker 0: now
Speaker 1: Luckily for this guy busting the door down to PGP is a little more difficult than busting down that shoddy-ass like hollow metal frame door you've got
Speaker 0: right now if the Basically this guy they had a warrant to search his computer and they did search his computer as much as they could But the door on his computer was not opened by a physical object and could not be opened.
Speaker 0: I guess it could be opened by force which if they did that that would be fine.
Speaker 1: But I have a feeling the statute of limitations would run out long before they decrypted his drive exactly.
Speaker 0: It's so difficult to open by force that it's effectively unopenable right unless they get incredibly lucky.
Speaker 1: You know, there was a Superman about.
Speaker 0: that was there way back.
Speaker 1: I remember watching this where some guy Committed some crime and what he did is he locked himself in an impenetrable box until the statute of limitations ran out.
Speaker 0: How do you know this?
Speaker 1: So they tried to.
Speaker 1: Superman tried to bust in right because they had this clock and they're like, all right The statute of limitations runs up in like 12 hours.
Speaker 1: Superman Bust in there and get this guy and Superman couldn't bust in.
Speaker 1: so we talked to some guy I don't know what you this guy was who taught him about Adams and how we could Faze through matter by making this Adams dodge the other Adams and like the fuse in.
Speaker 1: where did you read this?
Speaker 1: I saw it where it was a tea Superman where I saw Superman on TV.
Speaker 0: Okay, black and white Superman black and white.
Speaker 0: Yeah card live-action.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay, Nick at night Okay, I never saw that one.
Speaker 0: I saw the old cartoon one which is in color, you know, doo-doo-doo.
Speaker 1: Superman Starts phasing through the wall and he gets halfway in and then the guy's like, oh crap Superman's coming I don't know how he knew and he's like, hey Superman What if you get stuck in that wall?
Speaker 1: Superman goes?
Speaker 1: Ah shit, you're right and leaves.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, how they get him?
Speaker 1: you want to know how they get him.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 1: You don't care.
Speaker 1: It's kind of funny All right.
Speaker 1: So he comes out after the statute of limitations up because he's got his atomic clock in there and he's like, all right Haha, I'm out.
Speaker 1: Ah, you can't arrest me.
Speaker 1: They arrest him.
Speaker 1: Anyway, Superman messed with his clock and he came out five minutes early.
Speaker 0: Okay, anyway.
Speaker 0: so yeah, basically, I think it's pretty interesting because That you Fifth Amendment.
Speaker 0: You don't have to you know, incriminate yourself.
Speaker 0: You can just shut up You can go to you don't have to sit.
Speaker 0: You don't have to testify in court.
Speaker 0: You can just be silent You don't have to say anything.
Speaker 0: Of course anything you do say will be held against you but no one can make you say anything in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Funny.
Speaker 1: oh that's such us I mean if you really think about it.
Speaker 1: That is such a strange right to give someone that you have to tell the truth unless something you say is Incriminating and then you don't have to say anything.
Speaker 0: Well, you if you do you basically you can choose to shut up or talk.
Speaker 0: you can basically choose between truth and shutting up.
Speaker 0: You can't lie.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm all I'm.
Speaker 1: don't get me wrong.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying we don't need the Fifth Amendment Yeah, I'm just saying it's funny how it works out.
Speaker 0: so well Yeah, but I think it's pretty interesting.
Speaker 0: What if I had a house like a physical house and the only way into the house?
Speaker 0: Was with information that only I knew and I I couldn't be forced to reveal that information to incriminate myself.
Speaker 0: I could be forced to reveal the information to incriminate someone else though.
Speaker 1: So yeah, so as long as you murdered the guy who designed the password scheme and you buried his body in the house Yes, so it's weird.
Speaker 0: I'm fully in favor of the Fifth Amendment because without it.
Speaker 0: It'll be horrible.
Speaker 0: It'll be like it's almost as bad as no habeas corpus.
Speaker 0: But on the other hand having the Fifth Amendment.
Speaker 0: in a world where you know We can use information to lock things and people you know are you know?
Speaker 0: Basically, we can use information not beat that was protected by law To seal up evidence and make it impossible to get at legally.
Speaker 0: It's it's easier to get away with things if you're smarter and think about this.
Speaker 1: this wasn't even that Deniable encryption where you could give someone a key that works and decrypts data But there's no way to prove beyond any doubt at all or even any reasonable doubt even any like unreasonable doubt That there's more or less data in there.
Speaker 1: It's perfectly deniable.
Speaker 1: Yep within you know and layers this guy.
Speaker 0: This was not the strongest most best encryption you could use for avoiding the law.
Speaker 0: There are better ways to do it and that the guy did it a sort of shoddy way And he still got away with it.
Speaker 1: see the moral here is pretty simple.
Speaker 0: on his Alienware laptop Which shows you how smart this guy is you should?
Speaker 1: Encrypt your important business?
Speaker 1: Yeah, probably and if you're using Gmail This won't hide it from Google.
Speaker 1: It'll hide it from other people.
Speaker 1: type HTTP s Doesn't?
Speaker 0: it does it on its own.
Speaker 1: No it doesn't.
Speaker 1: it goes back to HTTP after you log in.
Speaker 0: are you sure?
Speaker 1: I sniffed it unless it's changed.
Speaker 0: I'll have to check guys.
Speaker 1: I'm logged in at work today.
Speaker 0: You can also use fire GPG to add Pete fire PGP GPG fire GPG.
Speaker 0: I'm PGP adding G to add encryption to your Gmail.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't use PGP use GPG exactly.
Speaker 1: good
Speaker 0: God all right doing news,
Speaker 1: so I'm not gonna talk about this in depth partly because I think I want to do a whole show About it, but there's this article on slash dot by some guy Nicholas Carr who wrote a book about it Nicholas
Speaker 0: truck
Speaker 1: Nicholas autobus
Speaker 0: out the booth.
Speaker 1: that was pretty bad set up.
Speaker 1: so basically the headline is is the IT department dead?
Speaker 0: and As long as companies have computers probably not.
Speaker 1: the answer is no.
Speaker 1: Now the thing is this article is kind of weird.
Speaker 1: I have to read it again to really figure out because it's pretty much just PR fluff to sell this book and the book is Somewhat inflammatory just to sell better.
Speaker 0: But there seems to be a lot of people writing inflammatory books just to sell them.
Speaker 1: But it seems like the idea here is that?
Speaker 1: Computers are so good now and you can centralize things with things like Google so much that you don't need IT support anymore You can.
Speaker 1: just people can just do it all on their own.
Speaker 1: and the answer to that is ha ha ha.
Speaker 0: If they I guess you know he's right in a way in that it seems like people are so Ignorant that if they just sort of did things their own way and figured out on their own Except they wouldn't not yet right then at least it's like.
Speaker 0: right now We're in a situation where people the IT Departments are forcing the employees to do things the way that they know is best, but the employees are having hard time Doing things the best way.
Speaker 0: they can't live up to that.
Speaker 1: the thing is most employees can't even do things at all.
Speaker 0: I know I know, but if you just let them do it on their own know that nothing will get done Or they'll just do it the best way they know how which is the best that they would do it anyway.
Speaker 1: No It's actually far worse because then all your data gets compromised with spyware and Trojans.
Speaker 0: All those sorts of safeguards go away.
Speaker 1: pretty much that.
Speaker 1: to sum my position up on this article the the the things in it that are not bullshit are very few and far between and Basically the the only thing I can really agree with is that yes It's true that most companies really kind of do redundant IT work, or it's not really even IT work.
Speaker 1: It's computer work that they call IT.
Speaker 1: but a lot of companies invest a lot of money in technology infrastructure without necessarily understanding what that infrastructure actually does.
Speaker 1: and It's those poor and stupid uses of technology by people who don't know better that give the perception among a lot of employees and employers That technology and IT are a big money sink.
Speaker 1: companies that use IT correctly to manage their information and their business processes Save so much money.
Speaker 1: It's you.
Speaker 1: you couldn't even believe it.
Speaker 1: The problem is most people can't do that and aren't willing to pay people who know how to do it and are willing to learn How to do it because it's not easy.
Speaker 0: It requires lots of changing the way you think about business and the way you do business.
Speaker 0: you have to change and people fear change More than they fear anything else.
Speaker 1: Yep The sunk cost fallacy is probably the biggest thing holding back IT infrastructure in the entire world today.
Speaker 0: Probably the sunk cost fallacy holding a lot of things back.
Speaker 1: Yeah now, uh, you know the sunk cost fallacy I think keeps a lot of people playing World of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I already made it to level 60.
Speaker 0: It also keeps a lot of people from dropping out of school Yeah, and that's that's funny.
Speaker 1: But you know what?
Speaker 1: There are a lot of people at RIT who probably should have dropped out.
Speaker 1: Yep, we had some friends who were smart enough to drop out early on and go somewhere that was more suited to them.
Speaker 1: Things of the day.
Speaker 1: so, uh, we like Futurama.
Speaker 1: the new Futurama was okay wasn't super great.
Speaker 1: It was pretty good.
Speaker 0: It was okay.
Speaker 0: It got some chuckles.
Speaker 0: I think the Family Guy movie was better than the Futurama movie.
Speaker 0: as far as direct-to-video Fox cartoons go I think you're forgetting.
Speaker 1: everybody loves Hypno toad.
Speaker 0: That was the when the extras better than the movie.
Speaker 0: That's not a good thing.
Speaker 1: That was that was one of the defining moments in my life is watching an entire episode of.
Speaker 1: everybody loves Hypno toad.
Speaker 0: Are you serious?
Speaker 0: Not ironically.
Speaker 1: Are you serious?
Speaker 1: Not best moments defining moments.
Speaker 1: It defined a part of me.
Speaker 0: I think that part of me was defined on an April Fool's Day many years past and that this was just a reminder of that.
Speaker 1: I was not party to that because I while I caused that April Fool's Day that that that momentous occasion for many other people I Did not suffer through it.
Speaker 1: I in fact was standing outside the room waiting for people to figure it out and I didn't suffer through It.
Speaker 0: but I sat there sort of watching the other suffer through it, but I watch Hypno toad non-ironically.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I'll make this quick.
Speaker 1: Remember when bender brewed beer inside bender bender brow?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a good episode.
Speaker 1: someone made a bender that you can in which you can brew beer.
Speaker 0: Does it have a Poorly placed tap possibly.
Speaker 1: No, it doesn't.
Speaker 0: I thought it.
Speaker 0: I know it does.
Speaker 0: actually I saw it.
Speaker 1: I didn't actually look at it yet.
Speaker 0: The tap is in a quite a bad position.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow.
Speaker 1: Yes Okay This is however Extremely well done.
Speaker 1: like the level of quality is too much effort Wallet it reeks of effort while it reeks of effort at the same time kind of effort.
Speaker 0: bender would not expend.
Speaker 1: It is really really cool.
Speaker 1: Now the only thing the only thing that worries me is I really really hope that no one tries to have sex with it.
Speaker 0: Okay Anyway, this is a funny video that's gone around the Internet's.
Speaker 0: You've probably seen it already if you're paying attention the Internet's but maybe you haven't seen it and the videos called you suck at Photoshop Number one.
Speaker 0: Oh you're doing this and basically some guy made a little Photoshop tutorial and I thought you know I wasn't quite sure what it was when I watched it.
Speaker 0: I just saw links that said you suck at Photoshop.
Speaker 1: click here and suck is spelled wrong in that kind of Spelled wrong on the YouTube.
Speaker 1: So but all the posts I saw to it were sujk.
Speaker 0: Well, it's as you see K on YouTube.
Speaker 0: But anyway, there's a video and this guy it's just a screencast of his Mac where he's got Photoshop and says other Adobe photo program and he's Talking over this screen capture, right?
Speaker 0: And he's basically gonna demo how to do some stuff in Photoshop and he sort of does.
Speaker 0: He taught me how to do stuff in Photoshop.
Speaker 0: I didn't know how to do.
Speaker 0: I don't have Photoshop those It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: and I was pretty interesting.
Speaker 0: It's He's sort of in his Photoshop tutorial telling a story in the way a humorous Story and it's.
Speaker 0: I feel like this sort of joke has been done before but I can't remember exactly when and where and this is a good execution of this joke and Humor is there and if you want to be making the funnies, you should be watching this video.
Speaker 1: I found this just utterly hilarious.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it is.
Speaker 0: It's pretty funny.
Speaker 0: I didn't think was utterly.
Speaker 1: I think what made it hilarious for me is that I've always liked very kind of Straight man humor like Steven Wright always so that with a deadpan straight face You know your dictionary zebra did it never did.
Speaker 1: awesome dehydrated water.
Speaker 1: now I don't know what to add got some spot remover.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: I can't find my dog.
Speaker 1: I just I love that sort of deadpan humor and I think what makes makes something like doubly funny for me is if you could look at it and maybe if you weren't the brightest bulb or if you weren't paying attention or just it is Conceivable that you would watch it and not realize it was a joke.
Speaker 0: I think that's something that excellent humor does very well.
Speaker 0: is that it makes the person laughing at it feel smart that you know If you're if you tell a joke right that anyone in the world will get the joke.
Speaker 0: But anyone who gets the joke feels like other people won't get the joke whether they will or they won't.
Speaker 0: Penny arcade and I know that only video game people understand it.
Speaker 0: It adds to the joke.
Speaker 0: So the best joke in the world is the inside joke.
Speaker 0: But the best joke in the world can't be an inside joke because it's funny to so few people.
Speaker 0: you need a joke where everyone Feels like it's an inside joke or it makes them feel smarter or better than other people.
Speaker 0: But it makes everyone feel that way and that's just perfect joke.
Speaker 1: It wasn't overdone it wasn't overproduced.
Speaker 1: all the all the quips and all the humorous bits were Extremely subtle.
Speaker 1: like they they were.
Speaker 0: subtly starts out real subtle and he gets less subtle as it goes on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but even then it's in such a believable progression in terms of like.
Speaker 1: you could see someone doing this not as a joke But you know, this is a joke.
Speaker 1: But yet, you know, there are people out there who feel like this and have done this sort of thing and it wasn't a joke.
Speaker 1: Yep, I hope it was a joke.
Speaker 0: All right main bit.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So speaking of having sex with bender Oh good.
Speaker 1: God hungry Joe posts in the forums a while ago, and I'm surprised how little discussion is generated.
Speaker 0: Well, you wanted to talk about this.
Speaker 1: So well part the other reason I really wanted to talk about this because Scott couldn't come up with anything better and he agreed To it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I I'm still because you wanted to do this.
Speaker 0: you had.
Speaker 1: it's up to you to get the discussion rolling Alright, well basically this was what was posted in our forum.
Speaker 1: David Levy has a new book title love and sex with robots in which he predicts that robot technology will allow for such human-like creations in the near future that we can follow in love with them that the robots can at least mimic that they love us back and that they will be Viable sex partners.
Speaker 1: now I submit to you that this has already occurred and my evidence is the dildo.
Speaker 1: It is a viable sex partner.
Speaker 1: It may not love you back unless you have double D cells, but it is in fact a viable sex partner.
Speaker 1: You can have sex with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have a better evidence than that that this has already happened.
Speaker 0: real dolls?
Speaker 0: No, the the moe is there.
Speaker 0: I mean there are sick dudes out there that I do not condone but they honestly I think these sicko people They honestly fall in love with these animated fictional character.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: We're not talking 4chan fat thing.
Speaker 1: We're not talking someone masturbates to it.
Speaker 1: We're talking people actually have real strong emotions toward moe characters and bad shows.
Speaker 0: yeah, these people actually have fictional characters and while they may not physically have Sex with a fictional character because it's just a drawing on it.
Speaker 1: Oh, you can print it out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they might print it out or they might have.
Speaker 1: they might have a real.
Speaker 1: I wasn't being serious.
Speaker 1: I don't think many people have printed out a piece of paper on their inkjet and then had sex with it.
Speaker 0: No, but they had.
Speaker 0: these people have like real dolls and they have all sorts of sicko stuff that I you know I creased me out.
Speaker 0: I'm not comfortable with it But there are people out there who are effectively falling in love with and having sex with things that are not human beings.
Speaker 1: I Just I was thinking of disturbing things.
Speaker 0: All right, so yeah, it's all disturbing but it's it's happening and I really don't see having sex with say a Robot sort of Android that imitates a human being being much different.
Speaker 1: Well, I think there is definitely a Separation.
Speaker 1: I mean some people can make this distinction some people don't but a lot of people do very much separate Sex and love or sex and emotion people.
Speaker 0: I separate them.
Speaker 0: people will have sex They can go together but they are two separate things and they will enjoy their best together sort of like chips and salsa.
Speaker 0: But you can just eat salsa and you can just eat chips if you want to.
Speaker 1: it was actually a pretty apt analogy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right to continue this.
Speaker 1: of course, there is nothing new with this prediction.
Speaker 1: It's one of the oldest tropes in science fiction, you know.
Speaker 1: that trope guy makes a robot falls in love with the robot Robot kills him because it doesn't actually love him back and doesn't.
Speaker 1: it's just a machine.
Speaker 0: Yeah every ghost in the shell story Yeah, half of them.
Speaker 1: Well, the other half of ghost in the shell is it's not actually a machine.
Speaker 1: It's sentient.
Speaker 0: Yes, what do we do?
Speaker 0: 75% of Masamune shiro stories?
Speaker 1: They can say one thing though 100% of Masamune shiro stories have the big butt.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: It's there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that guy let's get the bus shiro tasm.
Speaker 1: If we'd done an episode on shiro just like as like the body of his work just go on with what you're talking about.
Speaker 0: So I'm trying to kill time.
Speaker 1: I'm not trying to kill time mustn't kill time boy Must spend time.
Speaker 1: Let's cherish it like five bucks to go get loaded loaded on Sexy robots, right?
Speaker 1: So can we become so attached to a machine that we can be said to love it?
Speaker 1: Would we feel gratified if a machine mimic?
Speaker 0: And if you're asking questions, why don't we answer them one at a time one by one?
Speaker 1: All right, so can't know let's do this in the royal we sense as humans.
Speaker 1: can human the royal?
Speaker 0: we saw only Kings Which includes me.
Speaker 1: can Humans become so attached to machines that they can be said to love them?
Speaker 1: now I think before I mean, I think the real tricky part here is that you know people always assume All right, it's either human or it isn't.
Speaker 1: it's either a machine or it's a human being.
Speaker 1: But what exactly is the line between sentience and not sentience?
Speaker 1: During tests during tests, uh, I'm just picking something I know cuz I submit that there are some.
Speaker 1: there have been several monkeys Well apes at least in history that could pass the Turing test.
Speaker 1: All right, so are they sentient?
Speaker 1: maybe so well Maybe you can't I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm just I'm just shooting out there.
Speaker 1: I know I'm not making a stance yet I mean, I think the Turing test is the closest we've got.
Speaker 1: but even then that really only takes into account human intelligence or intelligence recognizable as Exactly what we expect.
Speaker 0: I know some incredible alien could come with advanced alien technology and still not understand the Turing test to be able to take it.
Speaker 1: So I guess all right is sentience the line I mean.
Speaker 1: what is it?
Speaker 1: What makes having sex with the dildo different from having sex with say your Real doll, but or your pool cleaner.
Speaker 0: Well, if you're talking about sex alone, right just the salsa, right?
Speaker 0: I don't know why sex is the salsa, but
Speaker 1: You know, it seems to fit because I don't I wouldn't want to have sex with a chip But having sex with salsa wouldn't be that bad unless unless it was a habanero salsa
Speaker 0: You could just if you sealed the tip.
Speaker 0: it wouldn't be so again.
Speaker 1: Anyway, let's not go there.
Speaker 0: Let's not go there.
Speaker 0: All right, if you're talking about just the salsa, I just pictured everyone in the front row.
Speaker 1: crew was thinking to themselves I'm never fucking having salsa at rims house again.
Speaker 0: good more for us Untainted salsa Of course.
Speaker 0: if they see us eating it they'll know not to eat it.
Speaker 0: They'll know it's safe to eat.
Speaker 0: if we right we have to eat it in secret.
Speaker 0: so they don't know.
Speaker 0: They don't know which sauces are good and which ones are tainted anyway.
Speaker 1: So what were you saying?
Speaker 0: I was saying you're talking about just salsa.
Speaker 0: You got to get the good.
Speaker 0: now If you're talking about just salsa just sex, right Sex on its own is just.
Speaker 0: you're playing with parts of your body that happen have a lot of nerve you're stimulating nerve endings and then your brain is releasing chemicals that make you feel good and That's about it.
Speaker 0: So whatever way you make that happen if that's your only goal is to it's.
Speaker 0: basically.
Speaker 0: it's no different than like You know snorting cocaine.
Speaker 0: your brain releases chemicals that make you feel good because you stimulated nerve endings.
Speaker 0: I mean anyway, you stimulate those nerve endings.
Speaker 0: What's wrong with that?
Speaker 1: I mean doesn't matter how because it's kind of relevant ghost in the shell.
Speaker 1: there was that there's a lot of talk in the manga about the idea that if you're a cyborg or if we have such Technologies where we can understand the brain so well instead of having physical sex people can just stimulate each other's pleasure centers directly.
Speaker 1: Yep, and does that still count as salsa?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it might be more fun if say someone else who are stimulating your nerve endings in a Unpredictable or superior fashion.
Speaker 0: because you know, there are certain ways.
Speaker 0: It's not easy to stimulate the nerve endings.
Speaker 0: They're pretty complex, you know and on your own you can only do so many things and with more people You can do different things.
Speaker 1: Everybody was gaga deep in other people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and with a robot the right kind of robot, maybe there'd be more possibilities available to you.
Speaker 0: But if you're just talking about nerve ending stimulation Anything goes.
Speaker 1: I guess, you know, there's actually a comic I remember.
Speaker 1: I don't remember if this was a thin H line or if it was a Sunday morning coffee But it was a lab and they made a sex bot.
Speaker 1: It was up, you know, but classic anime kind of micro 2010 the perverted manga not the cute anime.
Speaker 1: It's a robot you have sex with.
Speaker 1: oh my god, and the scientists are of course men and the woman scientist is like What's wrong with you?
Speaker 1: This is disgusting.
Speaker 1: Why would you have sex with a machine and then blah blah blah blah and then that night she's using her dildo And then she stopped.
Speaker 1: she's like wait a minute.
Speaker 1: Ah Damn it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So now you're gonna talk about the chips.
Speaker 0: You wanna talk about the chips.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should talk about the chips All right.
Speaker 0: So the thing with the chips right is that you basically have a strong Emotional attachment to another person.
Speaker 0: that's considered normal.
Speaker 0: I guess.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Well, it's it's love.
Speaker 1: now We can start.
Speaker 1: I mean first, you know, we have to define our terms.
Speaker 1: what is love?
Speaker 0: it's love It's the words love.
Speaker 1: all you need is love.
Speaker 0: Okay, right, but it it's viewed by me and I guess other people that having a strong Emotional attachment right because the strongest emotional attachment people ever have is to like, you know people they fall in love with right?
Speaker 0: You really that's that's pretty much what comes down to and you know, you can have emotional attachments to other things.
Speaker 0: But if they're that strong, it's sort of disturbing, you know, I mean like some people might love their teddy bear.
Speaker 0: but if you love your teddy bear as much as you love Your wife that's sort of like.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's a little weird.
Speaker 1: See now it's easy to.
Speaker 1: I mean It's kind of like with a lot of arguments.
Speaker 1: It's very easy to say Well, that's and that's just because that's kinky and that's boobah Yeah, just because there's such a stark comparison.
Speaker 1: But what about say the love for a pet versus the love for a fellow human being?
Speaker 1: because now it's a lot closer in terms Of you know, it's a living thing.
Speaker 1: It's it's it's it's probably intelligent to some degree.
Speaker 1: it can respond Organically that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: What about again, it comes down to sentience.
Speaker 1: What's the line?
Speaker 1: is love with a sentient being shared love different from one way love with a non sentient item?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean do you really care if someone else has and I mean someone having an emotional attachment is something that's not real?
Speaker 0: All right, I guess the robot is definitely real, right?
Speaker 0: but I mean something that is not, you know, a human or is not the same species.
Speaker 0: whatever is Disturbing.
Speaker 0: I don't know exactly why is disturbing and have to think about it for a minute And I can't really think if I'm saying stuff like this, but it is disturbing.
Speaker 1: That's the thing.
Speaker 1: if you it's very this kind of argument or we're not really arguing It's just kind of a debate because I don't really have a position me there at all.
Speaker 1: but there's the you can.
Speaker 1: you can look at it from a purely like Subjective.
Speaker 1: Well, I like this and I don't like this and this is okay This isn't okay.
Speaker 1: And you can also kind of remove yourself from it and look at it from a purely clinical kind of.
Speaker 1: what exactly is the line?
Speaker 1: You know like like bestiality.
Speaker 1: there's a word I can throw out there since we're throwing out words.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the problem with bestiality
Speaker 1: is that Regardless of that just I know what you're gonna say, but for me purely like emotional or subjective stance most people are disgusted by the idea of bestiality or a lot of things like that and They wouldn't really think about exactly why it bothers them.
Speaker 1: There's kind of just this innate disgust for it.
Speaker 1: and yet at the same time clinically if you remove the emotion entirely you can look at it and say Alright well, obviously the non-sentient or the animal or whatever cannot give consent and blah blah blah danger.
Speaker 1: And there's kind of.
Speaker 1: there's two perspectives both of which condemn it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: What do you do when it's not so clear-cut?
Speaker 1: What uh, what about a computer or an Android or a robot?
Speaker 1: That is I wrote it in basic.
Speaker 1: I know I wrote it a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: I know exactly how it works because I wrote the software and someone else falls in love with it.
Speaker 1: Didn't they just fall in love with me by proxy or my programming skills?
Speaker 0: I don't know it.
Speaker 0: it's I mean people fall in love with other people's creations all the time.
Speaker 0: I mean people.
Speaker 0: have you know?
Speaker 0: Someone made that anime that moe show.
Speaker 0: there's some artist character designer and then someone else fell in love with it.
Speaker 0: They didn't fall in love with the character designer they don't even know the characters, but maybe they did.
Speaker 1: because think about it if you fall in love with an entity that was created wholly and Predictably by a person then you fall in love with something that was in created entirely by that person's mind And by proxy that person's creative output.
Speaker 0: So if I fall in love with someone I'm I fall in love with their mom Because the mom did not create unambiguously the person.
Speaker 0: now What if they Jeanette we get in the future and we're genetically engineering children.
Speaker 0: exactly That's that.
Speaker 1: if it was down to the point where you programmed the brain a hundred percent Exactly, because that's what I was saying.
Speaker 1: It's a cyborg that I programmed.
Speaker 1: I know the code.
Speaker 1: the code does not act randomly.
Speaker 1: The reactions it gives someone else could fall in love with it.
Speaker 1: But yet I know Well it reacted that way.
Speaker 1: it hugged them because it saw that their pupils were dilated by this degree and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: But how do you how do you explain when say there's a work of art that I may enjoy Yet the person who created that work of art.
Speaker 0: I do not like them and that happens often.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's very versa.
Speaker 0: where I like someone like I said, I don't like their art.
Speaker 1: They didn't fall in love with the person.
Speaker 1: you fell in love with the output of the person.
Speaker 1: what you fell in love with Was a construct that that person created.
Speaker 1: Yep, actually and even further think about what's the uh, what's the line?
Speaker 1: What is love versus?
Speaker 1: I mean, I've had emotional Attachment and attraction to a lot of characters in fiction.
Speaker 1: I've cried over people who never lived.
Speaker 1: Yep, is that different than falling in love with something that didn't exist or only existed in someone else's mind.
Speaker 1: What's the line?
Speaker 0: I guess there's some sort of you know line that we sort of invent Semantically that doesn't really have a provable real space.
Speaker 0: You know physical line that you know.
Speaker 0: when you are attached to something enough then it suddenly becomes like, you know Undying love and hope some holy time bound to you by change that only omnipotence can bright.
Speaker 0: and it's sort of like.
Speaker 0: You know, no one can say exactly where the line is or whatever and whatever.
Speaker 0: But I guess that's you know, that's what it's considered to be in in popular opinion.
Speaker 1: But alright, so someone falls in love with the lot the got the line.
Speaker 1: the machine I made that I wrote in basic.
Speaker 1: now Let's say I made a machine that was a neural network, whatever and it goes in the shell style.
Speaker 1: Effectively could pass the Turing test and as far as I could tell I could not predict its reactions a hundred percent anymore.
Speaker 1: and Effectively as far as anyone can tell is sentient.
Speaker 1: But it's a machine that I made.
Speaker 0: I will what if I make a person a real person out of Atoms because I have nanotechnology and when I'm done, they're biologically identical to a you know, human being.
Speaker 0: they're in the same species And everything.
Speaker 0: they can even make babies one way or the other depending on the gender I make it and you fall in love with that.
Speaker 0: It's no different I think.
Speaker 1: what it comes down to my personal belief is that love between any two set be any two Entities.
Speaker 1: I can't say being because what's the difference between an organic?
Speaker 1: what like what's that?
Speaker 1: What's a being?
Speaker 1: but a plant is dendrophilius between any two any n entities.
Speaker 1: I can't discriminate here any feelings of emotion between n entities of Similar levels of sentience.
Speaker 1: I cannot find fault with them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's really hard to figure out.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it's hard to say there's something wrong with anything unless someone's getting hurt.
Speaker 0: I mean sometimes this kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: There's someone getting hurt, you know, like One person loves someone else who isn't and they're not loved back.
Speaker 0: Someone is in love with something and it's you know, it can't give consent cuz like an animal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I love a cactus that relationship is not going to and it's not good.
Speaker 0: Not the crushinator or even whatever robot falls in love with a person and the person doesn't you know love robots.
Speaker 0: They love people only and they're not attracted to robot.
Speaker 1: I think there was a tessica about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mayhaps mayhaps Yes, and that the person could end up getting hurt by the crazed robot, you know Which is incredibly powerful and strong.
Speaker 1: or maybe the robot is hurt by the person.
Speaker 0: Maybe the robot is hurt by the person.
Speaker 1: I guess it just.
Speaker 1: I Cannot find fault with beings of similar sentience sharing emotional attachment.
Speaker 1: As a result if there are sentient machines or machines that are effectively sentient and someone has feelings for it I can't look at that any differently than I look at someone having feelings for another human being.
Speaker 0: right now.
Speaker 0: Here's another thing to look at right?
Speaker 0: There's a lot of basically, we you fall you biologically, you're attracted to other things in your species right, you know because you know evolution and things.
Speaker 0: You know things that were attracted.
Speaker 0: You know in any sort of non asexual organism right being biologically Programmed to be attracted to sexually and emotionally to things that you can procreate with is sort of an advantage.
Speaker 0: You know, that's that's sort of how you know, it worked out, you know, if you didn't have that you'd have.
Speaker 0: you know Like men and women not wanting each other and then they wouldn't make babies and humans wouldn't be around anymore Right now that gene or the genes that you know cause that you know are not present in everybody And you know you end up having some people who really can only you know Have these feelings toward things in their own species and some people can have it towards in their species and not.
Speaker 0: and some of this You know stuff is you know, even have you know gender stuff going on and some of this is biological and some of it is not.
Speaker 0: and The question might be is it good for the future of the species if we you know Take the selection pressure off of that?
Speaker 0: and now maybe one day in the future when robots are So much better and you know than people because you just program the robot to be everything You know the perfect thing for you to love and we stop, you know We totally lose our attraction for people in the same species of you know The opposite gender for procreating and whatnot.
Speaker 1: But what did even matter if we had full control over our genetic destiny and we just programmed ourselves or even became What if he had full control over robots but not yet full control over genetics?
Speaker 1: See, I think the fundamental question and ain't any time this sort of issue comes up just comes down to very simply What is the seat of human consciousness because that determines the answers to a lot of these questions?
Speaker 0: Like what about that episode of Futurama where he he's doing the robot and then everyone's doing robots?
Speaker 1: and if everyone's doing robots And there's no more people.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's tricky.
Speaker 0: It is tricky And it and see that that's a situation where there could be some harm if everyone's doing robots and then we run out of people.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow.
Speaker 1: I realized that looking at the rest of the questions here.
Speaker 1: We kind of answered most of them.
Speaker 0: Did we?
Speaker 1: Alright, alright Would we feel gratified if a machine mimicked loving us back or would we realize that it was just acting in accordance with its programming?
Speaker 0: Well, I think that some people would and some people wouldn't.
Speaker 1: I mean, I think Some people have a lot of difficulty Understanding how other people fanboys are a good example of this.
Speaker 1: Running the RIT anime club, you know as the president I I had to be like the public face for the club and a lot of people would Congregate around in like the social areas of club and I had to I kind of keep the peace and talk to everyone and be Like hey you how's it going?
Speaker 1: Hey blah blah, but Scott and all my friends could tell When I was totally blowing someone off and ignoring what they were saying But I was mimicking the right body posture in the right body language and I was doing the things that basically trick another person into Thinking that I'm engaged with them there.
Speaker 1: there are a lot of things you can do if you want to I guess in of Influence or effect the way someone perceives the way you speak just by using body language a certain way.
Speaker 1: It's not out of the realm that you could program a computer that did those same sorts of calculations.
Speaker 0: But aren't we gonna?
Speaker 0: we're gonna have to you know cross the uncanny valley of Emotion there and I think all that takes is more computing power and more time.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean the uncanny valley is an interesting phenomenon Which I've read multiple articles asserting that the reason it exists is because things that are alien or foreign We don't really have any sort of.
Speaker 1: we don't have to worry about because historically in the in the past of humanity Things that were very alien to us were different kinds of dangers But things that were very similar or almost normal But a little bit off often indicated disease or malformation or problems like that.
Speaker 1: I mean I saw a lot of studies where people were sickened and disgusted by certain kinds of images and yet we're not bothered at all by other very similar kinds of images and the Images that bother them were in the uncanny valley and similar to things that cause disease
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So yeah anyway What a robot necessarily be mimicking or could it possibly begin feeling?
Speaker 1: I I don't know what the seed of human consciousness is but I am Lee I'm about I'm 40% give or take leaning toward the idea that My intelligence is just the emergent behavior of a complex system.
Speaker 1: And if that is the case, then robots can most definitely feel as much as I can.
Speaker 1: Yeah, eventually There's no reason they couldn't.
Speaker 1: there's no reason any sufficiently complex system couldn't be Self-reflective in the same way that I am especially if I give it a fusiform gyrus.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I guess this is sort of idea that feelings are somehow Special in some like there's some holy, you know Sac, you know, what was the word sacred sacred kind of thing?
Speaker 0: Feelings are just chemical, you know results of the emergent, you know thing for the complex system.
Speaker 1: I mean if that's the case because we don't I mean all we know is that I mean I feel emotions humans feel emotions And they're very powerful and it's very difficult to separate yourself From the emotions you feel and it's very difficult to clinically observe.
Speaker 1: I mean, let's say that someday we map the brain perfectly and we're able to say without a doubt This is where every like each emotion This is how it forms and where it comes from.
Speaker 1: and here's how look I can make a device.
Speaker 1: you hit the button and it Makes you angry even it and you don't even know why you hit the button and it makes you happy.
Speaker 1: We could understand it a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: and if that sort of thing is possible I don't know how a lot of people would deal with that knowledge.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think a lot of people wouldn't believe it because it were.
Speaker 1: so it's very difficult to divorce yourself from your own perception of reality And kind of be self-reflective in that kind of clinical Objective way kind of like how it's very difficult for people to admit to their own inner failings to themselves.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: All right Blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: if mr Levy walked in on his spouse using a robot as a sex partner would he be right to feel jealous or angry?
Speaker 0: Well, I think there's sort of a you know, I guess another thing that's possibly biological instinctual that's been brought over over the years that you know You see, you know, we've grown into being some sort of this monogamous relationship At least humans have for the most part, you know sort of monogamous and whatnots
Speaker 1: and I'll give us
Speaker 0: what not.
Speaker 0: So, you know one man one partner of some kind, you know.
Speaker 0: And then you don't want the partner to be going with anyone else because then you feel like hey You know, they love them more than they love me, you know, you it, you know seeing something like that It's like oh you want, you know, everyone wants to have something all to themselves.
Speaker 1: but then at the same time we have friends and I've met a lot of people in my life who who are good or bad have transcended that and are in open or Multi-faceted relationships.
Speaker 1: and While many of them failed utterly at the same time many of them seem to be working very well.
Speaker 0: I guess it's just you know This is sort of a more general issue outside of the robots in that if you have a relationship with someone if it's a real Relationship then, you know the terms of that relationship, you know will be like agreed upon.
Speaker 0: And if you're not able to agree on the terms of your relationship with someone then what kind of relationship is that?
Speaker 0: That's not much going on there, you know, it's not really gonna work out if you can't even agree on something like that.
Speaker 0: So if one person's, you know wanting something different than the other person then you're gonna end up hurting someone.
Speaker 0: So don't make any promises that you're not gonna keep.
Speaker 1: Well, I think with this last question and we'll also probably end on that because we've gone on a while and I'm kind of hungry Okay, but I guess it also with this it comes down to are they using the robot as a dildo for the salsa?
Speaker 1: Or are they using the robot for the chips or both or both?
Speaker 1: because if someone's using being jealous of the robot if Using it purely for the salsa is like being jealous of a vibrator if you're jealous of a vibrator That's a little bit sad.
Speaker 0: I think well, I mean, you know, you'd like, you know The chips of the salsa goes so well together that you'd like to think that you know The salsa that you made goes to the chips the best.
Speaker 1: Well, I think there is an unrelated issue that a lot of people aren't very good at making salsa And a lot of people are very uncomfortable talking about it with possibly the people they also share chips with to the.
Speaker 1: I Love this analogy To the point that I think a lot of people could be having a lot better sex than they currently are and I'll leave it At that.
Speaker 1: this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.