Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, July 16th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 2: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, our amazing and awesome interview with Paul Otaking Johnson.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 2: So I hear you've been watching some of that there.
Speaker 2: eskaflone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's amazing.
Speaker 1: how little of the show I remember.
Speaker 2: But you've only seen it once.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think I've only seen it all the way through once in that marathon time.
Speaker 1: I never watched it again.
Speaker 1: And that was years and years ago.
Speaker 1: I remember some basic things about the show, like who the major characters are, what happens at the end.
Speaker 1: But I can really only tell you two or three sentences about what happens at the end.
Speaker 1: And a few other things, which are mostly spoiler things, like the big spoiler things.
Speaker 1: And I remember a couple scenes, but like I'm watching the first episode and they're like characters I don't remember.
Speaker 1: Huge parts of the plot I don't remember.
Speaker 1: It's like watching a brand new show.
Speaker 1: It's pretty crazy.
Speaker 2: Yeah, so with this new Scott renaissance of watching anime, we'll be reviewing a lot more shows much quicker.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you'd be surprised.
Speaker 1: It's like if you have a new piece of technology that's really fancy, it's like it sort of always makes you want to use it.
Speaker 1: You know, that's how you can sort of tell if you made a good technology purchase.
Speaker 1: Like if you buy something and then you're always going to really want to play with it right away.
Speaker 1: But sometimes you'll play with it right away and then it will just sort of sit there.
Speaker 1: And it's like, even though you might look at it and think, man, I bought that and I feel bad about not using it.
Speaker 1: If you don't sort of have this urge to want to use it, even if there's no reason to is probably a bad move.
Speaker 1: But the iPhone, man, it just makes you want to use it all the time.
Speaker 1: And if I want to use it all the time, I need to find something to do with it.
Speaker 1: So I'm glad about the 16 gig because I fit all of Evangelion and all of Escaflowne on there and the Evangelion director's cut episodes and there's room to spare.
Speaker 1: I can fit two entire anime series on there and I bought the cable that lets you plug it into a television or whatever.
Speaker 1: So now I can go to an anime convention, plug this thing into like a TV in the hotel room and boom, it's a marathon with this tiny little thing.
Speaker 1: It's crazy.
Speaker 2: You know what?
Speaker 2: You know what I really miss?
Speaker 2: When we actually would do anime marathons back at RIT when we had, I don't know, free time and no responsibility.
Speaker 1: It can do YouTube, too.
Speaker 1: So I can get YouTube on any TV screen where there's a cell phone signal.
Speaker 1: It's crazy.
Speaker 2: But yeah, my laptop came back from the shop, so I've been watching mad anime.
Speaker 2: I'm finally watching that time.
Speaker 1: Oh, but you have to like switch DVDs out and you got...
Speaker 2: Well, no, because half the shows I'm watching, I happen to already have in digital form for various reasons.
Speaker 1: You have to like load them up on the hard drive and you got to have this big thing on your lap.
Speaker 2: See, I don't mind the big thing.
Speaker 2: I got a big screen.
Speaker 2: What are you trying to do?
Speaker 2: Sell me an iPhone?
Speaker 2: I'm buying an iPhone.
Speaker 1: I'm not trying to sell you an iPhone.
Speaker 1: I'm just trying to make funny.
Speaker 2: You know, I got no complaints.
Speaker 2: Actually, because my laptop was in the shop for like a week when I finally got it back, I was watching anime and playing Civ 4 at the same time.
Speaker 2: It was like I had to use my laptop double to make up for the time I lost.
Speaker 1: What did you do when you didn't have the laptop when it was in the shop?
Speaker 2: You know what I did?
Speaker 2: I got on the train and I slept.
Speaker 1: Read books maybe?
Speaker 2: Actually, yeah, I got through about half of that Byzantine Emperor's history book.
Speaker 2: Half of one third of that history.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 2: Yeah, but I don't know.
Speaker 2: Is there any anime news?
Speaker 2: It's been kind of a dry week or two.
Speaker 1: No, there hasn't been much anime news other than the general anime in the US is going down the shitter.
Speaker 1: So I found a little comic news here.
Speaker 1: In shows past, you may have heard me discuss some of Boom Studios comics, the Tales series.
Speaker 1: You know, Zombie Tales, Cthulhu Tales, Pirate Tales.
Speaker 2: They seem to have been kind of hit or miss.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, they were anthology books.
Speaker 1: It's like, hey, anyone want to write like a five page ninja story with a twist ending?
Speaker 1: Send it in and we'll pick out the good ones and we'll put them all together in one book, right?
Speaker 1: So if you missed out on these things and didn't buy them like I did, which I now sort of feel bad about buying because they're free online.
Speaker 1: So for absolutely no money, you can go to this website that I'll link to.
Speaker 1: You can read Ninja Tales, Zombie Tales, Heroes Squared, Two Guns, ShmoBots or Cthulhu Tales or all of the above for no money.
Speaker 1: And that's it.
Speaker 1: You probably should because there's some good stuff in there.
Speaker 1: I haven't read all of it, so I can't speak for all of it.
Speaker 1: But there is definitely some stuff in there that is worth reading, especially for free.
Speaker 1: I mean, Cthulhu Tales for free.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: I mean, there's good stuff in there.
Speaker 2: So I'll keep this real brief.
Speaker 2: I'm actually going to skip on the news half because as you all, you're probably all here.
Speaker 2: You just want to hear the interview and we're going to try to get right to that.
Speaker 2: But I just want to point out, since the current sabbatical Geek Night schedule prevents us from talking every week about anime.
Speaker 2: So I figure I should mention this when I can.
Speaker 2: But don't forget that August 1st through 3rd at KineticCon in Hartford, Connecticut, we're doing a crazy ton of panels and events.
Speaker 1: I can't even name them all.
Speaker 1: There's so many.
Speaker 2: I'm not going to list them.
Speaker 2: We're pretty much going to be running programming at KineticCon all weekend.
Speaker 2: So if you want to see us, you should probably be there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: If we're not in some sort of panel, we'll be in the gaming room running mad gaming action.
Speaker 2: The weekend directly after that, Otacon in Baltimore, Maryland, we're going to be running two panels in addition to being at our front row crew area of the artist alley, which includes 11 tables.
Speaker 2: Oh man.
Speaker 2: We've got quite a posse.
Speaker 2: And the panels we're running, I can tell you now that the one of them anime you should see is actually scheduled for noon on Friday.
Speaker 1: So you got to, if you want to see us noon on Friday, you're going to have to rush into the con.
Speaker 2: Or, you know, get your badge on Thursday, like all civilized humans do.
Speaker 1: But you got to get into the con early Friday to get into that noon panel.
Speaker 2: All I have to say is I'm glad we're doing this noon panel because that means we can get into the con early and not have to deal with any of that business.
Speaker 1: We're going to get in early anyway.
Speaker 2: Also, I'm going to point out anything, you know, all you Otacon people, every year this happens.
Speaker 2: So in case any of you are thinking, go to Otacon, every year you realize that they open all the doors to the con when they open the con.
Speaker 2: And there's always a line to get in the front door.
Speaker 2: And that line will line up hours before Otacon opens on Friday.
Speaker 2: You don't need to stand in that line.
Speaker 1: They open all the other doors.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And sometimes at the other doors, like some of the security people give you guff, right?
Speaker 1: You just got to be like, look, I have a badge.
Speaker 1: The con is open.
Speaker 1: Let me in the door.
Speaker 1: I can come in here.
Speaker 2: Plus they only give guff for like five minutes.
Speaker 2: Then you'll get it.
Speaker 2: There is no reason to stand in the line on Friday.
Speaker 1: That's the thing.
Speaker 1: Even though if they give guff right away and you can't convince them not to, don't go wait in the line and try to get in the front door.
Speaker 1: Just stand on the side door where there's nobody, wait a few minutes and eventually, all right, they'll let you in.
Speaker 1: And you don't have to wait in a stupid line.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 2: So then there's going to be a brief sabbatical where we go on our annual writer's retreat.
Speaker 2: And then over Labor Day weekend, we're going to be at the Penny Arcade Expo where we're going to be doing yet another panel.
Speaker 2: And then in September, in fact, let me pull up the date here because it's a little ways off.
Speaker 2: But yeah, September 27th in the Javitch Center, New York City at the New York Anime Festival, we're going to be doing four panels.
Speaker 2: And let me tell you, one of these panels.
Speaker 2: 27th.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 2: These are some pretty epic panels we're going to be running.
Speaker 2: New York Anime Festival is always fun, at least for one day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that Pennsylvania thing we may or may not do is on September 6th and 7th, the week after.
Speaker 2: Good God.
Speaker 1: So we're basically going to be going to town.
Speaker 1: Do you want to do that?
Speaker 2: Yes.
Speaker 1: You do?
Speaker 2: But at the same time, I don't know if I can.
Speaker 1: We'll come back from PAX Monday, go to the convention Saturday and Sunday.
Speaker 1: That's crazy.
Speaker 1: In Pennsylvania.
Speaker 2: Plus there's that, I don't even know what we're going to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 2: At least the New York Comic-Con is a ways off.
Speaker 2: And Katsu-Con is a ways off.
Speaker 2: Though, for anyone who's excited about Katsu-Con, one, we've already got a large list of panels ready for Katsu-Con.
Speaker 2: But two, the staff is conducting their hotel walkthroughs because, as you know, Katsu-Con has moved to Crystal City.
Speaker 2: Well, back to Crystal City from where it was last year.
Speaker 1: Which is not in Washington,
Speaker 1: D.C.,
Speaker 1: like I said.
Speaker 2: But at the same time, it is not its own city, Scott.
Speaker 2: It is in Virginia, right next to Washington, D.C.
Speaker 1: It's a city.
Speaker 1: It's Crystal City.
Speaker 1: It's a place called Crystal City.
Speaker 2: Crystal City is a mall.
Speaker 2: Anyway, Katsu-Con is going to be pretty rockin'.
Speaker 2: And the staff's doing their walkthrough to figure out how to set everything up now that Katsu-Con's kind of gotten big.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a medium to large con.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not Otacon big, but it's not, you know, Kineticon small.
Speaker 2: Plus, you know, Kineticon is an awesome anime con.
Speaker 2: But at the same time, Kineticon's tabletop gaming content is better than most tabletop gaming cons by itself.
Speaker 1: I think that's just because of the high quality of the game room staff.
Speaker 2: Which this year will include, actually, a good portion of the gaming side of the front row crew.
Speaker 1: Maybe like two or three people.
Speaker 2: Actually, it might be up to four or five now.
Speaker 2: Oh, man.
Speaker 2: But they'll all be running demos of all the games all weekend.
Speaker 1: It'll be awesome.
Speaker 2: Burning Wheel, board games, awesomeness.
Speaker 2: But Katsu-Con is the same way with old school arcade games.
Speaker 2: The classic gaming room at Katsu-Con is so great.
Speaker 1: It is top notch.
Speaker 2: But anyway, we're going to move right along with this because I'm sure you're all excited to hear this interview.
Speaker 2: So anyway, before we get on to the interview, that music means it's time for Things of the Day.
Speaker 2: I explain only because I'm sure there's a lot of people who normally might not listen to Geek Nights who are here to hear this interview.
Speaker 1: I hope so.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't know how popular this particular interview is going to be.
Speaker 1: I mean, he's only, he had 15 minutes of internet fame.
Speaker 2: Even though he should have more because he's an awesome guy.
Speaker 1: The entire anime community needs to know about it.
Speaker 1: The thing is, he was all, like, when I emailed him asking for an interview, he was all shy.
Speaker 0: Like, oh, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: He was like one of the best interview people we've had on.
Speaker 2: He was just spot on.
Speaker 2: I hardly had to edit at all.
Speaker 2: Most of the editing was editing me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know, right?
Speaker 1: So let's hear what kind of Thing of the Day you got over there.
Speaker 2: Alright, well my Thing of the Day is actually Otacon related.
Speaker 2: So I used to love anime con dances when I went to a lot of cons early on.
Speaker 2: I'd dance everywhere and the best dance I ever went to was Katsu-Con.
Speaker 2: I think it was three years ago now because on Friday night, they basically played 80s music.
Speaker 2: Instead of the normal fair at anime cons.
Speaker 2: And as a result, there was only people... So there was nothing but people.
Speaker 2: my age, our age, dancing to the music we remember from our childhood.
Speaker 2: And it was totally awesome and non-smelly and just great.
Speaker 2: But the thing is, in general, Katsu-Con tends to have some of the best con dances because they... Instead of just playing, like, I mean there are a lot of different kinds of electronic music.
Speaker 2: And you can like or not like all the different kinds.
Speaker 2: But when every anime con degenerates into the most minimalist, boring techno in the world.
Speaker 2: Like, it's so just duh-duh-duh and there's nothing else there.
Speaker 1: I think part of it is, you know, the acoustics of the room, you can't hear the other parts.
Speaker 1: You know, the crowd of smelly people, the glow sticks.
Speaker 2: Well see, that's the other thing.
Speaker 1: The whole thing going on just doesn't work.
Speaker 2: But not every con has that culture.
Speaker 1: Not every con.
Speaker 2: The only thing I've ever had bad to say about Otakon is that their rave is terrible if you actually like dancing or music.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, it has nothing to do with the DJ selection.
Speaker 1: It has nothing to do with Otakon themselves.
Speaker 2: At the same time, I don't want to disparage the DJs.
Speaker 2: But a lot of people have been telling me that they mostly draw DJs from kind of the DJ scene in the Baltimore/DC area.
Speaker 2: And the kind of music at Otakon apparently is very representative of the club scene down there.
Speaker 1: But, you know, it's really, they have a dance, I guess sort of because they're semi obligated to in a way.
Speaker 1: Because I guess they're supposed to.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the deal is.
Speaker 1: But it's really not related to anime in any way.
Speaker 1: It's not an anime dance so much.
Speaker 1: But they get one or two, a handful of guys every year that actually do some anime musics and such.
Speaker 1: And that's where the action is really.
Speaker 2: But even then, it's really hard to find out when and there's usually not that much.
Speaker 1: And it's really crowded and smelly even if you get good dancing going on.
Speaker 2: Well the thing is, if you really want a good con dance, I'm going to tell you, you want to go to Katsucon.
Speaker 2: They have some of the best con dances out there.
Speaker 2: But if you want to risk the Otakon dance, because while it's smelly and loud, a lot of dancers are like that.
Speaker 2: A lot of clubs are like that.
Speaker 2: But a DJ posted in our forums, who listens to Geek Nights, to point out that he's going to be Friday night in the side room from 10.30 to midnight at Otakon.
Speaker 2: He is not going to be playing the standard kind of DC Baltimore Otakon Fair.
Speaker 2: He's going to be playing danceable anime music and just kind of awesome stuff.
Speaker 1: Alright, mad props to that guy.
Speaker 2: I will tell you this, I will be there.
Speaker 1: Oh, you will.
Speaker 1: I will.
Speaker 1: See, even if he was the most awesome anime DJ in the world, I would still send him all the props that I have available in my prop basket.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, there's nothing that's going to get me to go into the crowded, smelly room.
Speaker 2: See, the thing is, I really like dancing.
Speaker 2: And the only reason I don't go...
Speaker 1: Do I not really like dancing?
Speaker 2: I do dance at Katsucon.
Speaker 2: I didn't last year because we did like 10 panels.
Speaker 0: I was ill.
Speaker 2: You were ill and I was wrecked.
Speaker 2: But every other Katsucon, I always spend a lot of time at the rave because I like that sort of thing.
Speaker 2: But Otakon's been missing it for me for the last five years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's only really, it's just the crowd and the smell, which is not the fault of... I guess it's someone's fault, but I don't know who.
Speaker 2: Honestly, for me it's the music and the fact that most of the people there aren't actually dancing.
Speaker 2: They're kind of standing in a big circle.
Speaker 1: Well, that's part of the crowd.
Speaker 2: Well, the thing is, I feel like you can direct the crowd with the music.
Speaker 1: Partially, that's the idea.
Speaker 2: I think you can.
Speaker 2: Also, you have to have ringers, like we used to when we ran the club dances at RIT.
Speaker 2: Who, if people form a circle, you have ringers that are in the DJ's pocket who go in dancing and bust the circle up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's good too.
Speaker 2: Yeah, but Friday night, side room, 1030 to midnight.
Speaker 2: Check this guy out and I will be there dancing.
Speaker 2: Don't let us down, dude.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 2: So, do you have anything?
Speaker 1: Oh, oh, right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, thank you today.
Speaker 1: So, if you had to pick a top five newspaper strip cartoonist of all time.
Speaker 1: Calvin Hobbs.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: You're done.
Speaker 1: Bloom County.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: So, Bill Watterson, right?
Speaker 1: What is Bill Watterson known for besides Calvin and Hobbs?
Speaker 2: Being a recluse.
Speaker 1: But what else?
Speaker 1: Being a hermit.
Speaker 1: What are the comics?
Speaker 2: Calvin and Hobbs, the sequel.
Speaker 1: You think he just woke up one day and it was boom, Calvin and Hobbs.
Speaker 1: He never drew anything else in his life?
Speaker 2: You know what?
Speaker 2: I'll admit that I know almost nothing about him.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, guess what?
Speaker 1: I found a website.
Speaker 1: It is something, something, whatever.
Speaker 1: But at the top of the website, it says Rare Bill Watterson Art.
Speaker 1: You see, while a student at Ohio's Kenyon College, he drew cartoons to the school newspaper and the yearbook.
Speaker 1: And they're on his website.
Speaker 1: And in '81, he was a political cartoonist.
Speaker 2: So, when we weren't even born yet.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And some of these cartoons are here.
Speaker 1: His two political art cartoons, he drew at the Cincinnati Post in 1980.
Speaker 1: And his nicely painted sketch was drawn and painted in the early '86, which is Calvin and Hobbs related.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, there's a whole bunch of rare and sort of you're not going to see it anywhere else Calvin and Hobbs art on a website.
Speaker 1: So, you can easily see it.
Speaker 1: Which is exactly how it's supposed to be.
Speaker 2: That is pretty awesome because you know that feeling where there's like an amount of a certain kind of media.
Speaker 1: Like imagine if you saw like something that wasn't Calvin and Hobbs, right?
Speaker 1: Like on a table at a comic show and it said Bill Watterson on it.
Speaker 1: Like holy shit.
Speaker 1: What's that?
Speaker 1: But here it is on a website and there's a lot of it.
Speaker 1: So, holy shit times a bunch.
Speaker 2: Alright, so without further ado, the moment you've been waiting for.
Speaker 2: Here is the interview we conducted with the Ota King.
Speaker 1: Yes, Paul Ota King Johnson.
Speaker 2: So, this was recorded before the show.
Speaker 2: This isn't live like the rest of this.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, because it's so live with our recorded podcast.
Speaker 2: Well, live in that, you know, we record live.
Speaker 2: We don't really edit.
Speaker 2: We just kind of throw it up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we recorded it on Saturday, but right now I'm speaking on Wednesday.
Speaker 2: Yes, so enjoy this interview.
Speaker 2: Follow up in the forums.
Speaker 2: If you have any follow up questions, post them in the forum.
Speaker 2: I know that our forums are awesome by the way and you should probably join them.
Speaker 2: And we'll try to get some follow up answers because the guy's totally awesome.
Speaker 1: I'm also putting a link to a BitTorrent of his documentary.
Speaker 2: Yes, if you have not seen the Ota Kings fan sub documentary.
Speaker 2: I highly, highly recommend it.
Speaker 1: Alright, so tonight we have with us the famous, or perhaps infamous now, Paul Johnson, the Ota King, creator of the fan sub documentary.
Speaker 1: How you doing Paul?
Speaker 0: I'm not doing too bad.
Speaker 0: How are you doing?
Speaker 1: We're doing pretty great over here.
Speaker 1: Alright, so, I guess to start off, you made this documentary that has gotten a lot of attention in the anime community.
Speaker 1: What exactly, you know, was there some sort of spark that really sort of created your intention to do this?
Speaker 2: Like one fan sub that just went too far.
Speaker 2: What was the moment when you said "I must do this"?
Speaker 0: It's been simmering for a while, for about the past two years.
Speaker 0: But a couple of months ago I went downstairs and my housemate was watching Sayonara Zetsubo Sensei and the subs, the subs were so bad.
Speaker 0: Oh my shit, the subs were bad.
Speaker 0: They're actually the ones that I used on the video.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I saw them in there, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the ones that basically just fill the entire screen and you can't see a single thing.
Speaker 0: And I was like "Oh, that's it.
Speaker 0: I'm just going to have to, I'm either going to explode or I'm going to have to spend ages and make a
Speaker 0: documentary.".
Speaker 0: Well, it's not really a documentary, is it?
Speaker 0: It's a rant, it's just a rant.
Speaker 1: Well, but I mean it is, technically speaking, it is a film in documentary form.
Speaker 2: And it has a leg up on a lot of rants in that you actually cited sources and provided examples?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's kind of like a Michael Moore piece, but with a kind of little bit of research in there, maybe.
Speaker 0: I did cite some sources, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: that was one thing that really struck me about the video, and I guess what makes it so good is that you really only have like maybe five points to make, and they're all really good points and really solid, but you just show so many examples over and over again to hammer down every single point.
Speaker 0: And I scream the points louder and louder as I go along.
Speaker 0: It sounded more and more insane as I go, so yeah.
Speaker 0: I don't think a lot of people like that.
Speaker 0: I mean, it had the narrator select scene at the start, and I think most people would have picked Starscream if they could.
Speaker 1: I also would have said Starscream was a good choice, but Hagar is no slouch.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, the mayor, the mayor, he did a good job.
Speaker 1: No, so speaking of that select screen at the beginning and also the thing at the end, you made those, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, I'm an amateur animator.
Speaker 0: I don't get paid for it.
Speaker 0: I mean, I make all my work from freelance translation, but in my free time I do do some animation and some drawing and whatnot, and you can see a lot of my artwork online.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that animation isn't bad.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's pretty good stuff there for not getting paid for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, it took a long while, but I figured that if you're going to do something, you may as well put in a bit of effort, and hopefully it will get people's attention more if they think, "Well, he's actually put a bit of effort into
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was sort of surprising because I saw it.
Speaker 1: I'm like, "Obviously that's something that someone made just for this video,".
Speaker 1: but I was like, "If this guy is a professional translator, he's also that good an animator, that's pretty
Speaker 1: impressive.".
Speaker 0: Oh, thank you very much.
Speaker 1: Because I was like, "Oh, did he get someone else to do
Speaker 1: that?".
Speaker 1: Because you don't expect someone to have the great level of skill in multiple areas like that.
Speaker 0: I wanted to get some voice actor to voice act me and make me sound really cool, but then I thought in the end, "No, no.
Speaker 0: If I'm going to say all this stuff, then I may as well take the flack and use my own annoying
Speaker 0: voice.".
Speaker 0: And a lot of the comments I got were, "Fuck, this guy's voice is just so fucking annoying.
Speaker 0: I'm just going to have to turn it
Speaker 0: off.".
Speaker 0: And I mean, it's true.
Speaker 0: It's true.
Speaker 0: So I'll give him that.
Speaker 0: I'll concede that point, but that's the only one I will concede.
Speaker 2: So before we get right into the actual documentary or piece, it seems pretty obvious that you're an anime fan of some stripe, so tell us a little bit about that.
Speaker 0: Right, basically, I got into anime back in the early '90s with, I don't know how it was in the US, but in the UK, no one knew what anime was until a company called Manga Entertainment came out and they started bringing anime over, and they started with Akira, which was, well, a pretty good start, really, if you think about it.
Speaker 0: And yeah, we didn't know what anime was over here.
Speaker 0: We definitely didn't see any of it on TV or anything.
Speaker 0: And then BBC2 showed Akira really late at night one night, and I heard something about it from some friends.
Speaker 0: I heard it was an animation, but it wasn't like Disney at all, so I'd better have a look at it.
Speaker 0: And so I watched it, and I was writhing around on the ground frothing at the mouth there how good it was.
Speaker 0: And pretty much after that, I bought everything that Manga Video released.
Speaker 1: Even the Manga Video holy trinity of suck?
Speaker 0: Well, that's the thing.
Speaker 0: That's the thing, though.
Speaker 0: A lot of people slag them off, perhaps with validity about some of their really, really bad releases.
Speaker 0: But when they started off, if you look at the catalogue that Manga had when they started to release stuff right at the start, it was just gold.
Speaker 0: Like, every title was just gold.
Speaker 0: I mean, we had stuff like Fist of the North Star coming out and Vampire Hunter D and Cyber City, and just everything was good.
Speaker 0: It's just when they ran out of good titles to release, that's when things started getting a bit pear-shaped, I think.
Speaker 1: Yeah, weren't there actually-- I don't know, was this some other country, but there were laws about preventing anime from being imported to the UK?
Speaker 1: Or was that somewhere else?
Speaker 0: I'm not sure about that.
Speaker 0: I haven't heard anything about that.
Speaker 0: There were a lot of movements in the UK, in newspapers and whatnot, when Urotikidoji came out.
Speaker 2: I was about to bring that up.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: It's all just animated porn, and there's tentacles everywhere, and, you know, if you watch this, you're going to hell.
Speaker 0: But they ignored stuff like, you know, Ghibli stuff like My Neighbor Totoro and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: It's just journalism, I guess.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we also had Manga Video in the US, but we also, around the '90s, we had, you know, that stuff and some other stuff, like from Viz and such, was on the sci-fi channel.
Speaker 1: So that's how a lot of-- Right, of course.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it took us a lot longer to actually-- Well, I think, to my knowledge, it took us a lot longer to actually get some of the stuff on TV and get it out there a bit more.
Speaker 0: But, oh, yeah, I remember watching Fist of the North Star, the movie, and I just couldn't believe that I was actually seeing blood in what I thought was a cartoon, and the art was amazing.
Speaker 0: And, I mean, it's not every day you're going to get to see a guy walking through a skyscraper and breaking it in half with his head.
Speaker 0: This stuff was fucking cool, was what I thought at the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean, that's how they advertised anime at first.
Speaker 1: Like, when we would watch the sci-fi channel in those days, they'd be like, "Anime, it's totally violent and hardcore," and whatever, but, you know, that's-- You know, then we learned later that that's not really all that anime is about.
Speaker 0: That's not all it is, no.
Speaker 0: But they do it incredibly well, though.
Speaker 1: They sure do.
Speaker 1: So, what anime are like you watching lately that you're a big fan of?
Speaker 0: Right, the thing is, there's-- I've got a DeviantArt site as well.
Speaker 0: I know it's not especially-- You're going to have to use that cool filter here.
Speaker 0: I can't think of anything to say.
Speaker 0: I know DeviantArt isn't exactly held up as, like, the holy grail of amazing art sites where all the artists are, but I've got some pieces on there about how I hate modern anime artwork and how, compared to the '80s and '90s, anime art has just got so bad, and you just don't notice until you see examples side by side, and so, basically, a lot of modern anime hurts my eyes so bad, I just can't watch it.
Speaker 2: Well, there's got to be a couple of things that are worthwhile.
Speaker 1: I agree with you, you know, for the most part, is, like, you know, I download-- Like, I download episode one of, like, every fan sub, even if it's a bad moe show, you know, just to see what it is, and, you know, 90% of them are absolutely dreadful, but, you know, there's still some good ones out there.
Speaker 0: It's the gray that I don't get.
Speaker 0: I mean, anime used to have color, and now everything's just gray, and that just really pisses me off.
Speaker 0: The first thing you learn in art school is that if you've got a skin tone and you want to add some shading to it, you don't just add black to it because that makes it look gray.
Speaker 0: I mean, you have to add, like, some yellow ochre in and some, like, alizarin crimson and all these various other colors.
Speaker 0: You don't just add black, but that's what anime does now because it's all done on Photoshop or whatever.
Speaker 0: You just select an area, add a bit of black, and there's your shading, and it just looks totally different in style to how it used to when they used to actually use color and mix palettes together, and it's a real shame, I think.
Speaker 0: But, I mean, yeah, I do watch some modern anime.
Speaker 0: I mean, the Zetsubou Sensei subtitles that I showed were really bad, but some people did say to me, you know, that they're the worst ones we've ever seen, and if you watch some better ones, like these ones here, you might enjoy it, and so my housemate is forcing me to watch it at the moment, and it is pretty funny.
Speaker 0: With decent subs, it is pretty funny, I think.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, not every, you know, while I do think the vast majority of subtitles I see show at least some of the characteristics that you, you know, put down in your video, that there are still some subtitlers out there that are pretty good, like, you know, especially the ones that are subtitling older shows.
Speaker 0: Oh, Anime Classic, yeah.
Speaker 0: I've got respect for them, a lot of respect.
Speaker 0: They just seem, it's, you watch it, and it's just like you're watching an early '90s fansub.
Speaker 0: I mean, the font is just yellow and easy to read, and there's no karaoke bullshit at the top of the screen, and there's no names of the translators filling the screen, like, more important than the people who actually made the show or anything.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm watching, like, all the, whoever, I don't know who's doing it because I don't really pay attention to who the fansubbers are, but I'm watching, like, all the Galaxy Express 3.9 TV episodes, whoever's doing those, and they're, you know, they're doing a perfectly normal job.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I really want to see that, actually, but there's so much of it that I've put it off.
Speaker 0: There's Legend of the Galactic Heroes as well.
Speaker 0: My other housemate, who's just gone to work for Nintendo, he was downloading and watching that before he left, but there's hundreds of episodes, and I just don't know where I can start.
Speaker 2: Just Habsburgs killing each other in space.
Speaker 0: I know, yeah, it's meant to be incredible.
Speaker 0: Have you seen it, then?
Speaker 2: I've seen a little bit, and our friend Scott Johnson keeps trying to push on to us.
Speaker 2: He's got, like, this 26-gigabyte collection of all of it, and he's about halfway through, and I want to, but...
Speaker 0: But, yeah, yeah, that's meant to be great, so I really want to have a look at that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I am going to start watching more anime soon, now that I've got the iPhone, because I can just convert videos to the iPhone format and then watch them, you know, around.
Speaker 1: Right, right, okay.
Speaker 2: So, if you're not watching, you know, super new anime, for the reasons you brought up, what was the last good anime?
Speaker 2: Like, what were some of the shows that you did like, up until things started to change?
Speaker 0: Well, actually, I did watch Black Lagoon, and I did like it.
Speaker 0: And, I mean, that's new.
Speaker 0: I did quite like it.
Speaker 0: It's by Madhouse, and Madhouse are a sticky subject with me, and, I mean, a lot of my favorite shows in the '90s were by Madhouse -- Cyber City, Ninja Scroll, Monster City, all that kind of stuff, and they were known for their artwork.
Speaker 0: I mean, they were artwork gods.
Speaker 0: They were artwork gods, Madhouse were, but now it's just, hmm, you compare their artwork now to how they used to look, and it's just terrible.
Speaker 0: But I remember that Black Lagoon actually looked pretty good for modern anime.
Speaker 0: It looked pretty good, and the story was quite good, so I did enjoy that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think at Madhouse, it seems to me like they have multiple teams, and some of the teams are good, and some of the teams are bad, 'cause, you know, it's like the same company will, you know, do Paprika, but then they'll also do, you know, a lot of other stuff, like, you know, some crap moe show that's like, "This is also Madhouse?
Speaker 1: How can this
Speaker 1: be?".
Speaker 0: But, yeah, mainly it is the artwork that stops me -- well, obviously, it's the fan subs, but if the fan subs aren't an option, and, you know, I'm actually watching proper DVD subtitles, then I'm still having trouble with modern anime because the artwork is just not detailed enough, and yet it still costs as much to buy a DVD with a few episodes on as it would have done back in the day, except you used to get incredible artwork and animation and story, and now you might get good story and animation, but you're just not gonna get any detail.
Speaker 0: And so you're getting less for your money, I think, is the trouble.
Speaker 1: Well, in the
Speaker 1: U.S.,
Speaker 1: actually, the official, you know, legal anime industry is sort of on a downturn, you know.
Speaker 1: Companies are going out.
Speaker 1: You know, ADV, you know, the long, you know, like, king of anime in the U.S.
Speaker 1: is sort of having big trouble.
Speaker 1: But so lately, what's happening is a lot of more shows are being released in, like, these really budget slim packs, where you'll get, you know, a whole bunch of discs in, like, you know, just the box, and it's, like, 40 bucks for a whole show.
Speaker 1: Is that happening over there, too?
Speaker 0: Um, I don't think so.
Speaker 0: I'm not really seeing that much anime around on the shelves here these days.
Speaker 1: So maybe they just cut you out entirely.
Speaker 0: But everyone just uses eBay or whatever and just grabs it from the U.S.
Speaker 0: anyway, I guess.
Speaker 0: I mean, with your region free, you can just watch it however you like.
Speaker 0: And everything comes out in the U.S.
Speaker 0: first anyway, so why not, basically?
Speaker 1: So let's talk about the documentary you made here.
Speaker 1: It really feels to me like the argument that you're presenting, that, you know, the anime fan subs we have now are pretty bad.
Speaker 1: It feels like an extension of the old, you know, dub and sub debate.
Speaker 1: And, like, back in the day, we would argue, you know, oh, you have to stick with subtitles instead of dubs because subtitles are, you know, they're more like the original experience the Japanese people had.
Speaker 0: They're keeping it real, yeah.
Speaker 1: And now it seems like, you know, an attempt to keep it more real, the subtitles go off the hook.
Speaker 0: Well, they're keeping it real to the very definition of real by not translating anything at all and just leaving it in Japanese.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean, you know, to take the argument that you make to the extreme, then, you know, shouldn't we just do dubs because then we'll even be closer to the Japanese experience because, you know, of hearing, you know, instead of reading the dialogue?
Speaker 0: Right, that's an interesting one, actually.
Speaker 0: I was talking to my friend Ben, who's another translator.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm quite jealous of him.
Speaker 0: He's had some much better projects than I have in the gaming world.
Speaker 0: But what he was saying was that if they were done like really, really, really well, like incredibly well, then dubs would be preferable to subs because anime is an animated medium.
Speaker 0: and to read subs, even if you're a fast reader like I am, you have to take your eyes off the screen for maybe half a second.
Speaker 0: And so dubs theoretically are the best way to go if they were done right.
Speaker 0: But I mean, as I'm sure you've noticed living in America, dubs are just shit.
Speaker 0: It's the trouble.
Speaker 1: They're really, really bad.
Speaker 2: Some, there's like one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's like maybe five to ten good dubs I've seen.
Speaker 2: Well, I'm curious.
Speaker 2: I mean, are there any dubs that you've seen that actually were good that you would remember?
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, when I say dubs this year, I mean modern dubs, like stuff on TV like Beyblade.
Speaker 0: and oh, Beyblade's fucking good.
Speaker 1: My show's not even good, so it's not much of a loss.
Speaker 0: Beyblade makes me laugh so much.
Speaker 0: But no, some of the streamlined dubs I remember were very, very good indeed.
Speaker 0: And Fist of the North Star, I love the Japanese Fist of the North Star, but I remember manga released the streamlined dub of it and the voice acting was fantastic.
Speaker 0: Obviously, the problem is that they actually changed the story and they took out all of the science and all of the things behind it.
Speaker 0: So people's heads were exploding for no reason in the dub, whereas in the Japanese one, he was saying like, oh, I've hit you in these several pressure points and it means that your body's going to contort and explode in three seconds.
Speaker 0: But in the English one, people just blew up, which I thought was cool.
Speaker 0: So that was all right.
Speaker 0: But yeah, in terms of dub, it was actually really, really good.
Speaker 0: And a lot of manga's early dubs were fantastic as well.
Speaker 0: I mean, Cyber City is just filled with swearing, which is exactly-- you listen to the Japanese one, and I mean, these are hardened criminals.
Speaker 0: These are hardened criminals who have been in jail and they've been given a chance to get out by capturing criminals themselves.
Speaker 0: And so obviously in the dub, they just swear all the time because they've been in prison and they're just going to be swearing their heads off.
Speaker 0: But in Japanese, the trouble is you can't really do swearing that well.
Speaker 0: And that's another thing that I mean by keeping it to the Japanese.
Speaker 0: You're missing out on a lot of the things that English can offer, like in insults especially.
Speaker 0: English has such a richer range of insults than Japanese ever will have.
Speaker 0: And just by writing "chikusho" or "shimata," which is what everybody says when anything goes wrong in Japanese, you're just missing out.
Speaker 0: You're missing out.
Speaker 0: You really are, I think.
Speaker 1: Well, that is one criticism people often bring up about a lot of those older dubs, is that they just threw in lots of swearing to fit in with that marketing of, "These are hardcore.
Speaker 1: These are violent.
Speaker 1: These are bad.
Speaker 1: That's why you should watch
Speaker 1: them.".
Speaker 1: So being a translator yourself, you're saying that the kind of swearing that was going on was actually sort of appropriate to the original?
Speaker 0: When it wasn't, that was a problem, that everything had swearing in it.
Speaker 0: But with Cyber City, it really, really did fit the mood.
Speaker 0: And I mean, if you've got some hardcore show where you've got some yakas shooting each other, then you're going to want some fucking and whatnot in there, definitely, I would say.
Speaker 0: But it wasn't that bad, though.
Speaker 0: I mean, there wasn't any swearing at all in Fist of the North Star and Three by Three Eyes and that kind of thing, I don't think.
Speaker 0: Nothing really hardcore more than shit, though, I don't think.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I mean, there are a lot of dubs that I really like.
Speaker 0: A lot of my favorite actors are voice actors.
Speaker 0: I mean, people like Tony Barry in Dominion Tank Police.
Speaker 0: And I don't know, you might not have heard of Peter Marinca, but I think he's American.
Speaker 0: I can't tell because he does so many accents.
Speaker 0: But he's been in a lot of manga dubs at the start.
Speaker 0: Doom Megalopolis, did you see that?
Speaker 1: - Yes, yes.
Speaker 1: - We know of it.
Speaker 2: I've seen it.
Speaker 0: He was the bad guy in that, although it's been redubbed, so you might not have heard the actual dub.
Speaker 0: But what they did for that?
Speaker 0: to recreate the... because it's in 1920s Tokyo, to create the classic feel, they gave everyone English accents, like really kind of Victorian English accents, which sounded weird at first, but then it was kind of... Actually, that's really good.
Speaker 0: It kind of feels like the period does.
Speaker 2: Actually, I have a really kind of specific question suddenly that I hope you can answer.
Speaker 2: If you've seen the Helsing dub, the original Helsing, not the new whatever, because a lot of people have told me that the British accents were horrible, so I'm curious as to your opinion.
Speaker 0: I haven't.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen it, actually, but I'm interested now, and I would like to have a look at it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you'll have to get back to us on that one, because I do remember that was a dub that was sort of hailed for being good, but also some people put it down for having, you know, bad accents, so...
Speaker 2: And I'll admit I couldn't tell.
Speaker 1: -Yeah.
Speaker 0: -Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't know.
Speaker 0: A lot of people tell me that the Cowboy Bebop dub is really, really good, and I watched it, and it's good.
Speaker 0: It's good, definitely, but compared to some of the dubs that I remember from the '90s, it really wasn't amazing, I didn't think.
Speaker 0: I mean, I love Dominion Tank for the least.
Speaker 0: That had one of the greatest dubs I've ever heard.
Speaker 2: I'll admit I love that dub.
Speaker 2: We just watched that show again recently, too.
Speaker 1: I just read the manga a couple weeks ago, also, so...
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Shiro was a king before he turned into a 3D porn artist.
Speaker 1: Period.
Speaker 0: He was a guy.
Speaker 1: Usually we try to make that point a little more subtly, but I guess that works.
Speaker 1: It's insane.
Speaker 0: I don't know what happened to him.
Speaker 0: We're getting totally off topic here, aren't we?
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: Everything's on topic.
Speaker 0: He used to be the king of acrylic paint, and then suddenly he discovered a 3D program, and he was like, "Shit, I'm going to use this in every picture now,".
Speaker 0: and then suddenly all his girls are being screwed by tentacles or robots.
Speaker 2: I think he was one of those people where he was constrained by whatever, by his time constraints or by editors saying, "No, you can't do this," or whatever, but the inner Shiro was just always trying to get out, and that kind of let him bring out his full glory, kind of like Ikuhara in Utena the Show versus Utena the Movie.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: And the bastard guy.
Speaker 0: I forget his name.
Speaker 0: Oh, I forget his name, but... He's one of the greatest artists I've ever seen, but apparently I hear from my friends he had a nervous breakdown and just started drawing cocks in every single time.
Speaker 1: I guess that's better than the dragon half guy.
Speaker 0: Oh, right, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: Actually, he's one of my major influences.
Speaker 0: When I first started drawing, this was like years ago, people used to say to me like, "Your girls just aren't attractive.
Speaker 0: They're all spiky.
Speaker 0: If you tried to snog one of those girls, you'd just cut yourself on their face,".
Speaker 0: and I was like, "It's because of the dragon half
Speaker 0: guy.".
Speaker 0: It's because I'm following his example.
Speaker 0: Everyone has to be spiky.
Speaker 0: I've toned it down a bit now, but he's still there.
Speaker 1: What is the manga situation like in the UK?
Speaker 1: Because we have lots of manga going on over here.
Speaker 0: Well, that's another one that I'm with Dark Horse on.
Speaker 0: Basically, there's been an explosion, but it's unfortunately been an explosion of a lot of companies appearing and jumping on this manga bandwagon and going, "Right, let's get this stuff out on the shelves as soon as we can on the cheapest quality paper that we can.
Speaker 0: Let's just make as much money as we can whilst the fad's there,".
Speaker 0: and so you've got stuff, and it's not flipped.
Speaker 0: It's in Japanese format.
Speaker 0: None of the subtitles, none of the sound effects, rather, are translated.
Speaker 0: It seems to be minimum effort, and we've got that in the UK too.
Speaker 0: You go into your comic shops and whatnot, and all of the Tokyo pop stuff is there and everything.
Speaker 1: It's the same as it is here.
Speaker 0: And it's just really unfortunate, because if you look back in the '90s at the Ghost in the Shell translation and the Dominion translation and Appleseed, I mean, Dark Horse and Studio Approaches, they did a top-class job.
Speaker 0: I mean, they really did.
Speaker 0: If they didn't understand the term, Torrance Smith would ring Masamune Shirou up and say, "What did you mean
Speaker 0: here?".
Speaker 0: And Shirou would be like, "I'm asleep.
Speaker 0: Fuck
Speaker 0: off.".
Speaker 0: And then you tell him what it means, and that's the kind of quality that got me into reading manga in the first place.
Speaker 0: There's no honorifics, there's no notes, there's no footnotes explaining that onigiri means rice ball.
Speaker 0: It's all just perfectly localized into English, and it's just fantastic.
Speaker 0: And I'm sure a lot of the modern fansubbers and a lot of the modern fansub fans grew up reading that as well, thinking how great it was, and yet now that would seem really bad to them because they've localized everything into English and got rid of a lot of the Japanese.
Speaker 0: Because you don't need it to understand the story.
Speaker 0: You don't need to know what a nakamadoshi is or anything like that.
Speaker 0: You can just translate it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean, this wasn't even really an issue for me until I saw your video.
Speaker 1: For example, the karaoke thing, if you would have asked me about that, say, six months ago, I would have been like, "Yeah, I don't really pay attention to them, but
Speaker 1: whatever.".
Speaker 1: But now I'm like, "Oh, get that karaoke out of
Speaker 1: here.".
Speaker 0: Get that shit off my screen.
Speaker 1: But as for the manga, I sort of feel like, I see how the same argument applies.
Speaker 1: You should translate it to English, just like we used to.
Speaker 1: But manga, it seems like there's something different about it.
Speaker 1: For example, the sound effects in manga are part of the artwork.
Speaker 1: So if you were to erase them and replace them with English, isn't that sort of the same as in the anime, like when they write English on the gravestones and such?
Speaker 0: You've got me there.
Speaker 0: That's a very good point, actually.
Speaker 0: But I think that if it's done with the blessing of the artist...
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: If you remember, when Ghost in the Shell came out, the manga, that is, it was missing the dodgy lesbian scene.
Speaker 0: And so that's back in now in the latest release.
Speaker 0: But the three pages of dodgy lesbianism were missed out because otherwise it would have had to be adult-rated and put on the top shelves.
Speaker 0: And so what they did was they got Shiro to redraw the pages himself.
Speaker 0: And that's the kind of close-knit relationship with the creator of the original work that I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: I mean, I like it when they change the sound effects and put them into English, but it requires a massive level of artistic skill to actually change the panels like that.
Speaker 0: And you've got to do it with the artist's blessing or you're pissing all over their work.
Speaker 0: And obviously fansubs just do it, I don't know, just basically to show that they're better than other groups because they were able to put a bigger subtitle above "Police Station" that says "Police Station" or "Toilet" above a restroom or whatever.
Speaker 0: It's just, no, I don't know, it's just really annoying.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, of course it would be ideal to have the original artists work with the translators the way Shiro worked with Dark Horse.
Speaker 1: And I guess I think Otomo also worked with Dark Horse back in the day.
Speaker 1: But considering that some people, like say Tezuka, no longer live and other Japanese creators, they don't have a lot of free time or they don't know English at all.
Speaker 1: I mean, Satoshi Ka, we saw him a few weeks ago and he doesn't know English really at all.
Speaker 1: He knew how to say thank you and whatever.
Speaker 1: So wouldn't it be better to just do it the way they're doing it so that way we can at least read the manga as opposed to the alternative, which would be, you know, nothing?
Speaker 0: Rather than having nothing at all, it's probably better, yeah, I guess.
Speaker 0: But I can't help but feel that it's just done that way just because it's quicker and cheaper is the trouble.
Speaker 0: I mean, they've successfully advertised it as, "Oh, we're actually doing it right to left because that keeps the original
Speaker 0: feel.".
Speaker 0: But I think it's no, it's because you don't have to spend months flipping all the pages and adjusting the artwork.
Speaker 0: I think it's just cheap.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, it is cheaper, but shouldn't we, I mean, when you flip the artwork, you're sort of, I mean, there's a difference in the anime, right?
Speaker 1: When you subtitle it, you're not changing anything.
Speaker 1: You're just sort of providing the translation to be understood.
Speaker 1: But if you flip the manga, that's actually changing the artwork.
Speaker 1: So are you crossing a line there?
Speaker 1: Because I can't tell you, I've read a lot of flipped manga, and the original Akira from Dark Horse is still only available in a flipped version.
Speaker 2: Or like Sanctuary and Eagle and all that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the older Viz manga.
Speaker 1: And you do notice when you read them that there are certain panels that they just read out of order, or there are guys who are facing the wrong direction, and the camera sort of crosses.
Speaker 1: I guess it's a manga, so there's no camera.
Speaker 1: But you break all sorts of rules where you can't figure out.
Speaker 1: But then when you look at it, especially in action manga, when it's unflipped, everything looks right, and it works much better.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I can't say I've ever had that problem myself, but I don't know.
Speaker 0: I mean, obviously the main problem that people say is that in Kenshin or whatever, suddenly he becomes left-handed because it's flipped and things like that.
Speaker 0: But again, if it was a properly professional job, then you could get around all that kind of stuff, and all the logos on the t-shirts and whatnot could be redrawn so that they're the proper way around again.
Speaker 0: But I mean, I understand that it takes so long to do, and so a lot of companies, they're just going to want to keep it in the Japanese format.
Speaker 1: And also you mentioned just now that you complained that the manga was printed on really cheap paper.
Speaker 1: But isn't manga in Japan printed on the cheapest paper imaginable?
Speaker 1: that's not really used for anything in the U.S.
Speaker 1: because it's so cheap?
Speaker 0: Oh, indeed, yeah.
Speaker 1: So we should be getting even cheaper paper than we're getting.
Speaker 0: I'm a complete hypocrite there.
Speaker 2: But then we should also be getting the giant anthologies and all that sort of...
Speaker 0: That's the thing, yeah.
Speaker 1: I would love to get the anthology.
Speaker 0: That was the payoff that we had in that Viz would release Dominion, and it would only be 30 pages or whatever, but it would be on really nice paper with a really nice cover, whereas in Japan you'd get it as part of a massive anthology, and the payoff would be that you'd have to have it on toilet paper that you wouldn't even wipe your ass on.
Speaker 0: So I think it kind of swings and roundabouts, and we got a lot of stuff that they didn't because things come in the big anthology form over there, although I would like to see that.
Speaker 0: I mean, do we get that in the West?
Speaker 0: Not really.
Speaker 0: Probably not in English, but...
Speaker 2: Part of the problem is that it seems like the whole Tokyo Pop thing, you talk about how they were kind of get it out there as fast as possible, and they tried in America at least first with the violent, hardcore manga, and they brought out Sanctuary and all these kind of very adult, very heavy-hitting things, and they sold okay but not really well, and then when they brought out the Tokyo Pop shoujo-y stuff, it sold really well, so they brought out nothing but that.
Speaker 2: And as a result, we don't even get any of the kind of adult or serious but not pornographic manga in the US.
Speaker 1: Well, we do.
Speaker 1: We get some from Dark Horse and Vertical.
Speaker 2: Yes, but compared to how much there is in Japan, we get very little.
Speaker 0: Indeed, yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, that is a shame.
Speaker 0: That's a problem.
Speaker 0: I don't think that all of Bastard is out still.
Speaker 1: I'll have to look that up because I do know some of it at least is out.
Speaker 1: I'll have to go check.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I remember in the early '90s about two volumes had come out in the UK, and there was loads more in Japan, but obviously you've got the issue there that they basically had to say, "Look, just go on holiday or something because it's taken us so long to edit out your cocks that you draw on every frame.
Speaker 0: So just go and take a holiday until you get your head
Speaker 0: right.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, the guy from the manga cast actually on his website put a list of all the manga that were sort of cancelled in the US.
Speaker 1: Someone bought the license, but they failed to finish the series or didn't actually ever get a volume out or something like that.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I guess it's quite a big list.
Speaker 1: It's actually not that big, but there are some pretty sad things on there.
Speaker 0: Right, right.
Speaker 2: All right, so let's go back off on a different tack a little bit.
Speaker 2: The documentary.
Speaker 2: Did you get a lot of hate mail once it was released and once people started seeing it?
Speaker 2: What kind of response did you get directly?
Speaker 0: Well, most of the response was actually on YouTube to each one, but there were a few forums like Anime Ski and Kaizoku Fan Subs, who actually got quite a bad deal in the video, if you remember.
Speaker 0: Kaizoku Fan Subs, a lot of the things that they actually say really, really pissed me off.
Speaker 0: Their actual translation, what's the word?
Speaker 2: Oh, when you showed in your video their official statement about this is how we feel.
Speaker 0: Their official statement.
Speaker 0: Yeah, indeed.
Speaker 0: Their official statement on like, "Mikan doesn't just mean tangerine, it's got all these special connotations with money and wealth in Japanese, and so to translate it as tangerine, we can't do that because it's missing out all these special...".
Speaker 0: Bullshit.
Speaker 0: It just means tangerine.
Speaker 0: It's just that one character, like, put some kind of, I don't know, meaning of money onto it or something, and suddenly, oh, I don't know, and nakama as well, nakama is the worst one of all.
Speaker 0: You just translate it differently each time.
Speaker 0: It's not a special word in Japanese, it's only a special word in one piece because of the way that that particular author uses it, and dynamic equivalence, which is the form of translation school that I follow, says that basically you don't have to translate.
Speaker 0: Like, if someone says "chikusho," you don't have to translate it as shit every single time.
Speaker 0: You can translate it as something different depending on what the scene calls for, and so when someone says "nakama," you don't have to translate it as shitmate or comrade or friend or like whatever every single time.
Speaker 0: You translate it different each time.
Speaker 0: You can get around it, but they say that no, no, it has to be nakama every single time because it's such a special meaning that the pathetic English language can't hope to get the nuances across, and it's like, well, that's just ridiculous.
Speaker 0: That's just ridiculous.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah, maybe comrade sounds a bit Russian, but I mean, shitmate, come on.
Speaker 0: It's about pirates.
Speaker 0: Just say shitmate.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: That is one thing that bothered me even back in the days.
Speaker 1: You would watch, say, Ranma, and someone would say like, you know, "Baka, baka, baka, baka, baka," and the subtitle would just be "stupid, stupid, stupid,
Speaker 1: stupid.".
Speaker 1: And I'd be like, who says "stupid" that many times?
Speaker 1: It's not natural English.
Speaker 1: You would say like, "You stupid
Speaker 1: idiot."
Speaker 1: You'd have like this big, long insult sentence.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Again, that's what you can do in English that you can't do in Japanese.
Speaker 0: I mean, they'll just say "baka" like a bunch of times, but as you say, in the English, they could have done something really creative and created a massive string of incredible insults there, which would have looked cool and be incredibly funny as well.
Speaker 0: But I guess they just left "stupid, stupid, stupid" and it looked stupid like you said.
Speaker 2: You mentioned the, I guess, dynamic translations.
Speaker 2: What are the other schools of translation?
Speaker 2: I'm curious.
Speaker 2: This is not a topic I know a lot about.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I learned a lot about this on my master's course.
Speaker 0: I did a translation studies course, and this is actually where a lot of the documentary comes from.
Speaker 0: My, I guess, graduation thesis, you call it, dissertation.
Speaker 0: My end-of-year dissertation was on anime translation, anime and game translation, and the two different schools.
Speaker 0: And a lot of my quotes and things that I use in the video come directly from my dissertation.
Speaker 1: Is there a way for us to get the dissertation?
Speaker 0: I think it's on my DeviantArt account.
Speaker 0: I think it's on either that or the one from the year before from my actual Japanese course.
Speaker 0: But I'll dig it out and put it up somewhere.
Speaker 0: But yeah, basically, it's a translation debate that's raged since Bible translation times.
Speaker 0: And there's two schools, basically.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's more than two, but there's two main ones.
Speaker 0: One half thinks that the original language is so great that you need to leave it all in the original format.
Speaker 0: And the other side says that that defeats the point of translation, and they actually want to translate it into the target language.
Speaker 0: And so as an English translator who translates into English, I follow a school called Dynamic Equivalence that actually wants to translate anime, manga and games into English.
Speaker 0: And some good examples of dynamic equivalents are games like Phoenix Wright, which I'm sure you're aware of.
Speaker 0: You must have played Phoenix Wright.
Speaker 1: I own all four.
Speaker 1: I beat them all.
Speaker 0: All the jokes and all the puns have just been expertly localized.
Speaker 0: Or games like Snatcher on the Sega CD.
Speaker 0: Do you know about Snatcher?
Speaker 1: I know of it.
Speaker 0: Well, you know Jeremy Blaustein, the translating god who translated Metal Gear Solid?
Speaker 1: I do now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, Metal Gear Solid, the script on.
Speaker 0: that is probably one of the greatest translation scripts I've ever read in my entire life.
Speaker 0: But he started out doing Konami games like Snatcher, translating them.
Speaker 0: And basically that's just Dynamic Equivalence.
Speaker 0: Like, you won't find a single honorific or a single cultural note in Snatcher or in Metal Gear.
Speaker 0: Basically, if you didn't know that it was Japanese, you'd think that Metal Gear had been written by Tom Clancy or someone.
Speaker 0: And that's kind of the point of Dynamic Equivalence, that you are creating a translation which someone reads and it sounds completely natural to them.
Speaker 0: And so not once in their head are they taken out of the experience of watching the show by thinking, "Ooh, that sounds a bit
Speaker 0: weird.".
Speaker 0: It just sounds... And I'm not, for one second, saying that you should change names and change Yakumo in 3x3 eyes to Brad Spangler or something.
Speaker 0: You should never do that.
Speaker 0: But yeah, Dynamic Equivalence is just... Well, another example is Dark Horse's early manga translations that I was talking about.
Speaker 0: They convert all the honorifics in their Japanese terms to English and they just do an incredible top class job.
Speaker 0: And probably the translations of Appleseed and Dominion and Ghost in the Shell were just some of the greatest examples of a seamless read which doesn't lose any of the original plot story or character names.
Speaker 0: And again, no honorifics, nothing like that.
Speaker 1: So these fansubbers, what they're doing is following the other school.
Speaker 1: And you say in your video that all the professional companies are in your school.
Speaker 1: Are there any professionals who have the other idea about it?
Speaker 0: Well, the other school is called Formal Equivalence.
Speaker 0: And again, it all comes from Bible translation mainly.
Speaker 0: And it believes that if you change any of the source text, you lose the meaning and you ruin it.
Speaker 0: Which is why fansubbers leave in all the honorifics and put in the Japanese name order and produce incredible lines like the famous "Inawashishiro
Speaker 0: Kamehamehasi.".
Speaker 0: I can't even read it.
Speaker 0: The one that was on the video.
Speaker 0: "Inawashishiro Kamehamehasama has sent the meat of a renowned bushi from Izumono Kuni from View to
Speaker 0: enjoy.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, that one.
Speaker 1: I didn't understand that at all.
Speaker 0: I thought probably that I should repeat that about five times in the video.
Speaker 0: But yeah, unfortunately, that's the problem.
Speaker 0: A lot of DVD companies now are moving towards the Formal Equivalence because they've seen, I guess, that that's what fansubbers and people who watch anime mainly watch fansubs.
Speaker 0: I think it's fair to say.
Speaker 0: That's what they want.
Speaker 0: They want Formal Equivalence.
Speaker 0: They want everything in Japanese.
Speaker 1: I mean, outside of the anime translation world, say the people who translate French films to English.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of translating of Hollywood movies into all sorts of other languages.
Speaker 1: Japanese, French, German, Italian.
Speaker 1: Are those people also using Dynamic Equivalence?
Speaker 0: They're using Dynamic Equivalence from what I've seen.
Speaker 0: I put a couple of examples in the video.
Speaker 0: I mean, Bollywood especially, there's loads of honorifics in Hindi and various other Indian languages.
Speaker 0: And we were watching a few Bollywood films recently and they're all just localized.
Speaker 0: They're all just localized.
Speaker 0: It doesn't say Babuji.
Speaker 0: It says Dad.
Speaker 0: So it's Dynamic Equivalence pretty much all the way.
Speaker 0: There's a French film called Just Visiting with the really cool guy Jean Renaud.
Speaker 0: I think it's Jean Renaud.
Speaker 0: Either that or Gerard Depardieu.
Speaker 0: Anyway, some of the subtitles, the English subtitles for that, that was a masterpiece of Dynamic Equivalence.
Speaker 0: I was laughing my ass off at that.
Speaker 0: And if they just left all the French in, it just wouldn't have been funny at all.
Speaker 0: So mainly, yeah, professional companies, they use formal equivalents and that's what fansubs used to do.
Speaker 0: They used to try and be professional, is the point of my video.
Speaker 2: A lot of earlier anime releases would take the music and re-perform it in English to kind of translate the music along with it.
Speaker 2: What's your opinion on that?
Speaker 0: Pioneer used to do it, didn't they?
Speaker 0: A lot.
Speaker 2: I remember I watched Henshi and all those things.
Speaker 2: I have all the songs in English and Japanese.
Speaker 2: Regardless of how it works, in terms of listening to the two, they sound very similar.
Speaker 2: It was just amazing how close they get.
Speaker 0: I remember Moldiver was one of my favorite shows when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: I look at it now and it looks a bit ugly compared to the artwork of the stuff that I was watching at the time.
Speaker 0: But yeah, Pioneer would just do two versions, wouldn't they?
Speaker 0: They'd do the English version of the song and then the Japanese original.
Speaker 0: And you could just pick which one you liked, basically.
Speaker 0: And I think that's really cool, actually.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, we once did a whole sort of week and I was watching all the different openers to different anime from around the world.
Speaker 1: And we found the Italian One Piece opening song and the German Sailor Moon are fantastic.
Speaker 0: Oh, the German Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: Oh, don't remind me about that.
Speaker 0: We were so starved of anime in the UK that when satellite TV came out, because it wasn't digital, it was satellite.
Speaker 0: You used to be able to get signals bounced off from German satellites and stuff.
Speaker 0: And I found that if I finally tuned it in the morning, then about 7 a.m.
Speaker 0: every Saturday, I used to be able to get Sailor Moon in German.
Speaker 0: And that opening sequence, that German opening song, it's still in my head now.
Speaker 0: I can't get rid of it.
Speaker 0: And they used it for every series.
Speaker 0: They never changed the opening.
Speaker 0: They always just used that same one.
Speaker 1: It's pretty interesting that something that I found on YouTube and thought was pretty cool, you basically had drilled into your head for decades earlier.
Speaker 0: I learned a little bit of German.
Speaker 0: I can't speak any German at all.
Speaker 0: But I learned a little bit of German.
Speaker 0: From watching Sailor Moon so many times.
Speaker 0: And I've been Sailor Moon in the... What was it?
Speaker 0: In the name of the moon, I'm the best!
Speaker 0: Like that.
Speaker 0: And I've still not seen it in Japanese.
Speaker 2: Sadly, being also starved for anime, it was difficult to get a lot of it.
Speaker 2: I ended up watching all of Sailor Moon.
Speaker 2: I got Japanese fansubs by I think Vkill, who did, now that I think back, incredibly professional fansubs.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: Well, that was the old mail your VHS tape away days.
Speaker 2: Yes, I literally said, I bought these VHS tapes and the dude sent me the VHS tapes back from his SVHS masters.
Speaker 0: He genlocked his own translation.
Speaker 0: A lot of my stuff was like that.
Speaker 0: But yeah, the dual song thing, I always like it when they do that.
Speaker 0: I think it shows if the English version is any good.
Speaker 0: And they generally were with Pioneer.
Speaker 0: I mean, they certainly knew their music.
Speaker 0: But I've been watching my favorite Gundam series, Gundam 0083 Stardust Memory.
Speaker 0: And we watched that the other day.
Speaker 0: And when I had picked myself up off the floor, because the artwork is so fucking insane.
Speaker 0: You can notice that actually that's got a number of different versions of the songs on it as well.
Speaker 0: So the openings are in Japanese, but on the soundtrack CD you can get them in English as well.
Speaker 0: And sung by the same singer in pretty good English.
Speaker 0: But the lyrics are completely different and they're actually really, really good.
Speaker 2: How about, very specifically, Dominion Tank Police?
Speaker 2: Because they pretty much redid all the music for the English dub.
Speaker 2: And they didn't even redo it as in taking the Japanese song and just kind of doing it in English.
Speaker 2: They completely redid it and just made up all new music.
Speaker 2: At least with the original Tank Police opening song.
Speaker 2: Hot Dance and Cherry Moon was kind of this generic pop song that they threw in.
Speaker 2: I really like the American opener.
Speaker 2: I know what you mean.
Speaker 0: This is a weird one with me.
Speaker 0: Like the Street Fighter movie and the redub of all the music that they did with that.
Speaker 0: I've got a friend over the road, probably the biggest Macross fan in the whole of England, called Rick Newman.
Speaker 0: And he to this day refuses to watch the manga version of the Street Fighter 2 animated movie because the music isn't right.
Speaker 1: Well, Macross is another one.
Speaker 1: In Robotech they redid all the music, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: But at least that was in Robotech and you know that you're not watching Macross.
Speaker 0: So you can just watch Macross and hear all the proper music.
Speaker 0: Although it is very confusing.
Speaker 0: But yeah, he feels the same way about Dominion as well.
Speaker 0: And the trouble is, I grew up with the American version of Dominion and I just love the music.
Speaker 0: I think it fits it really, really well.
Speaker 0: It's all kind of ambient and kind of synthesiser-y and it just fits the scene so well.
Speaker 0: And when I heard the Japanese soundtrack I was like, "What the hell is this?
Speaker 0: This doesn't fit the atmosphere at
Speaker 0: all!".
Speaker 0: So maybe I think it's like, you know, when you get into a band, you ask Metallica fans what their favourite album is.
Speaker 0: And generally it's the one that they heard first.
Speaker 0: So I think whichever you hear first you probably like best.
Speaker 0: It's the same with Cyber City.
Speaker 0: If you've seen that manga video completely, we did the music with some hardcore metal and thrash.
Speaker 0: And it's just incredible.
Speaker 0: And then you watch the Japanese one and it's all just kind of really kind of tingly pop.
Speaker 0: And it doesn't fit the atmosphere for me at all.
Speaker 0: Even though that's the original music and that's probably what should be on there as well.
Speaker 1: Well doesn't that sometimes make it hard to judge which is better?
Speaker 1: Because you're really influenced by what you've gotten used to in some way.
Speaker 1: So what would be the proper way to say which one is more correct or more better if you're not influenced by just what you're used to?
Speaker 1: Or what you happen to have a personal attachment to?
Speaker 0: I reckon the best way is just to watch both of them loads.
Speaker 0: I mean the Street Fighter animated movie is so incredible that you can just watch it.
Speaker 0: I mean I must have watched it like 40 times.
Speaker 0: So I've watched the English dub with the American music about 20 times.
Speaker 0: And I've watched the Japanese one about 20 times.
Speaker 0: And it gets to a point where you just love them both.
Speaker 0: I mean the final fight song where they're fighting Vega in the Japanese one, the song to that is just incredible.
Speaker 0: But it's kind of incredible in the pop way.
Speaker 0: And you watch the American one and they're fighting him and his guitar is thrashing away.
Speaker 0: And it just sounds incredibly actiony.
Speaker 0: And I mean you've got the famous scene with Chun-Li and Balrog where he comes down to kick her ass.
Speaker 0: And obviously in the Japanese one that's just some really kind of subdued music in the background.
Speaker 0: So it kind of feels a bit like a ballet.
Speaker 0: You've got violence and really soft music which was obviously their intent.
Speaker 0: And then in the American music you've got again some hardcore metal playing which looks amazing again.
Speaker 0: So they both work.
Speaker 0: So I reckon the only way to do it is to just watch them both loads.
Speaker 0: And eventually you get to appreciate both I think.
Speaker 1: You obviously can translate Japanese and not German.
Speaker 1: But are there any other languages you translate?
Speaker 0: Various English dialects into other English dialects.
Speaker 0: We've got a lot of different regional accents.
Speaker 0: I remember in school the first time I met a Scottish guy and I couldn't understand the word he was saying.
Speaker 0: And after about five days I was like "I understand this
Speaker 0: now.".
Speaker 0: But no, Japanese to English, that's it.
Speaker 0: I can't do it the other way.
Speaker 0: The other way around is impossible.
Speaker 0: Because people think that if you can translate from Japanese to English, then you can meet a Japanese person on the street and just strike up a conversation in Japanese.
Speaker 0: But it's totally not true.
Speaker 0: About all I can say is my name is Paul Johnson and that's about it really.
Speaker 0: And then maybe quote Omae wa mou shindeiru or you're already dead from Fist of the North star anthem.
Speaker 0: And hope they see the funny side of it.
Speaker 2: So some people would point this out, and we've noticed this before, but at least in America, you're saying "oh, my voice,
Speaker 2: whatever.".
Speaker 2: But in America there's this kind of subconscious perception that whenever someone has an English or a British accent of any kind, it always sounds more literate.
Speaker 2: It's weird, but it affects us in this way.
Speaker 2: So could you do for me what you would think would be an American accent?
Speaker 2: Because I love nothing more than hearing what other people think we sound like.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I can.
Speaker 2: There's no way you could offend us because I'll point out that the only English accents we can do are Monty Python based.
Speaker 0: Well, I could say Metal Gear for you.
Speaker 0: That's about it really.
Speaker 0: I used to do a really good liquid snake impression, but I can only do that after playing the game and then it dies away.
Speaker 1: That's really good.
Speaker 1: Alright, so you seem to like Metal Gear.
Speaker 1: What video game consoles do you have?
Speaker 1: What are your favorite games?
Speaker 0: Well, my head's stuck in the 80s, and I'm an old man, so my favorite is the Mega Drive or the Genesis over there, I believe.
Speaker 0: My favorite is the Mega Drive and the Mega CD or the Sega CD.
Speaker 0: I mean, people slag off the Sega CD and say it was a pile of shit, but it really wasn't.
Speaker 0: And anyone who says that is just talking out of their arse, because essentially it was a masterpiece.
Speaker 0: It was like someone had poured liquid gold into a mold and out came the Mega CD as a beautiful machine.
Speaker 0: And yeah, admittedly I only had about three games for it, but so what?
Speaker 0: The music on those games was so good.
Speaker 0: It's got the best Sonic game that I've ever played, Sonic CD.
Speaker 0: The music on Sonic CD was fantastic.
Speaker 0: And when I heard that they changed it for the American release, I was like, what the hell?
Speaker 0: Because luckily in the UK we got the Japanese soundtrack.
Speaker 0: In Europe you got the Japanese music, but in America they just changed it all and it's totally bizarre.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was a re-release and I forget if they kept the original music or not.
Speaker 1: There was some talk about that.
Speaker 0: Right, right, okay.
Speaker 1: I have to go look that up again.
Speaker 0: I played, what were they called, Core Design before they decided to put all of their money into Lara Croft.
Speaker 0: They actually made some really, really good games.
Speaker 0: And I remember Battle Core and Thunderhawk on the Mega CD and the music on those were just... Because I mean, that was its main asset, the Mega CD.
Speaker 0: It could do CD quality music.
Speaker 0: And so they just used it to the full and every soundtrack to pretty much every game was just a masterpiece that you could listen to and just enjoy just for its music.
Speaker 0: I mean Final Fight on the Mega CD is still the best version of Final Fight you can get.
Speaker 1: Oh, I never played that one.
Speaker 1: I'll have to go after that.
Speaker 0: I'm including the arcade game with that because the music is so much better than the arcade version.
Speaker 0: It's all just been remixed with guitars and it just sounds amazing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now that I think about it, a lot of the old PC CD-ROM games they used to play on DOS, they would fill that CD up with actual CD audio.
Speaker 1: You could put it in your CD player and play it because it was just a CD.
Speaker 0: Totally, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: There was a lot of really good music on Descent 2 or Doom.
Speaker 1: that was on CD sounded really good, Quake, with all the music in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, someone's got to bring that back.
Speaker 0: I know, I kind of wish they would.
Speaker 0: Music in games, yeah, there's still some really good music in games.
Speaker 0: But when it was the main asset, like with the Mega CD, they just really, really went for it in a way that they just don't seem to do now.
Speaker 2: So you're obviously a Metal Gear fan.
Speaker 2: I assume you've played the original Metal Gear for the Nintendo Entertainment System.
Speaker 0: I had a go on the emulator the other day.
Speaker 0: But the trouble is, it's so different to the Metal Gear Solid that I'm used to.
Speaker 0: I was like, "What the hell?
Speaker 0: I can't get past this guy.
Speaker 0: He keeps seeing me.
Speaker 0: Where the fuck is my
Speaker 0: radar?".
Speaker 1: Yeah, we had the opposite.
Speaker 1: We played the old one and then the new one, so it's a bit different.
Speaker 1: I'm like, "Hey, where are the trucks for me to get
Speaker 1: into?".
Speaker 2: The trucks have started to move.
Speaker 2: There's a bad translation.
Speaker 0: Oh, missed translations are some of the best things.
Speaker 0: I mean, you must defeat Sheng Long to stand a chance as a classic.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, the thing is, a lot of those translations for, say, old video games were limited by memory.
Speaker 1: You needed more physical characters.
Speaker 1: You needed more space in the technology to put more words.
Speaker 2: It was literally like, "Alright, there are 18 Japanese characters.
Speaker 2: How can we say this in 18 English
Speaker 2: letters?".
Speaker 0: It's not quite that bad, but it is still quite bad now.
Speaker 0: A lot of the game translation, in fact, all of the game translation work I get is in Excel format.
Speaker 0: And you've got a character limit that you have to stick to.
Speaker 0: And often, on the left is the Japanese and on the right is the space for you to write your English translation.
Speaker 0: And on the left, you've got a five kanji compound, which means super spinning, multipart, deathblow, super special attack.
Speaker 0: And you've got to get that in 10 characters.
Speaker 0: And it's impossible.
Speaker 0: It's totally impossible.
Speaker 0: You just can't do it.
Speaker 0: So things have to go a lot of the time, unfortunately.
Speaker 0: Unless you're working designs, which was another translation company that got a bit of slack because they went too far and would just start putting American pop culture into the translation system.
Speaker 0: But what they would do was actually, they wouldn't just translate, they'd rewrite the code of the game and allow themselves more space and things like that, which was absolutely insane.
Speaker 0: I mean, they went beyond the call of duty, but they went under because of it, because it took so long to release each game, was the trouble.
Speaker 1: Do you think it would help if when they originally made the game, they just put all the different languages in there from the start, the same way they do with DVDs and such?
Speaker 0: It would definitely help, but it takes so long to get the games out, I guess.
Speaker 0: Because, I mean, I could be wrong, but the way it seems to work is that, obviously, the Japanese first, and then that gets sent to a translator who does the English one, and then the English one is taken as a basis and all the European languages are done from that.
Speaker 0: So you can, I mean, it may be different with different companies, but that's been my experience.
Speaker 0: And so if someone makes a mistake in the English, that mistake's passed down into all the European languages.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it would take ages to get all the languages in at once.
Speaker 0: But that said, though, with Silent Hill 3 and Silent Hill 4, you've got Japanese and English as standard on the Japanese game.
Speaker 0: So yeah, definitely a couple of languages you can do.
Speaker 1: Alright, so I don't know if you want to talk about this, but you do this professionally, do you want to talk about exactly which projects you've worked on, maybe some you're really proud of or anything like that?
Speaker 0: Right, the trouble we're working with games and novels like I do is that you've got your non-disclosure agreement which you have to sign, and so you can only really talk about it when the game or the novel is released on the shelves.
Speaker 0: But especially with novels, I mean, the first novels I translated for Del Rey, or was it someone else, I think, the first ones I did like two years ago, and they're still not on the shelves.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: And I mean, recently Tokyopop removed pretty much almost their entire novel range from what I could see, which screwed a lot of translators over quite badly, actually.
Speaker 0: I feel quite bad for a lot of agencies who were really, really screwed.
Speaker 0: They had the carpet pulled from under them, some people had translated several books which will now never see the light of day, which is a real pisser.
Speaker 0: But yeah, yeah, so a lot of the work I've done is still not out, is the trouble, so I can't really talk about it.
Speaker 1: Do you get, I don't want you to tell me how much you get paid, but do they pay you a flat fee, or do they pay you royalties, or how does that work?
Speaker 0: With novels, it's per book, I've noticed.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know, your average Japanese light novel is about, what, 3,000 pages?
Speaker 0: And so, I think, is it three?
Speaker 0: No, I'm talking about 300 pages.
Speaker 0: Terrible with maths.
Speaker 0: The other day, someone contacted me for a job and asked me, "What are your
Speaker 0: rates?".
Speaker 0: And I was like, "Oh, it's this much per
Speaker 0: word.".
Speaker 0: And they sent back and said, "That's 300 times more than what we pay our normal
Speaker 0: people.".
Speaker 0: And I was like, "Oh, sorry, I added an extra zero and the decimal point was in the wrong
Speaker 0: place.".
Speaker 0: So, I'm a complete moron, I'm surprised I get any jobs at all after some of the stuff that I've pulled.
Speaker 1: So, you work on your own, you don't have an agent or anything?
Speaker 0: I work for agencies, actually, because I've got my details on translation websites like Prose and Translators Cafe and things like that.
Speaker 0: So, people see that and they see that I specialize in games and novels and they contact me.
Speaker 0: And if you get a good working relationship with a company going, then, I mean, that's excellent, really.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's a company called Local Soft in Spain who are really, really good because they won't just send you the text to translate, they'll send you scans, all the scans you need, all of the glossaries and terminologies.
Speaker 0: If it's a game for the DS, you know, you'll get a glossary of every single DS part, the names of every component in the DS, so that you can make sure your translation's, like, spot-on perfect.
Speaker 1: So, you get to see some games, like, before they come out.
Speaker 1: That must be pretty cool.
Speaker 0: I don't, actually.
Speaker 0: That's the trouble.
Speaker 0: This is a lot of the problem with translation is that you'll get the manual, but generally, you're just seeing the text.
Speaker 0: But you're not seeing what's happening on the screen.
Speaker 0: And so, a lot of bad translations stem from that, from the fact that you can see someone saying something, but you don't know what's actually happening is the trouble.
Speaker 0: So, I mean, ideally, and people like Jeremy Blaustein and, like, you know, the real big names in translation industry, I'm guessing that they are playing the beta test versions of the games as they translate, and that's what you need to do, really.
Speaker 0: And I know that my friend Ben, for some companies, they actually send him the game as well, which he plays and translates as he goes along.
Speaker 0: But generally, I'm doing instruction manuals a lot of the time, and so I don't really need to.
Speaker 0: But Mario games, I've done a few Mario games, and mainly instruction manuals for them, but they're a bit of a bastard, because, obviously, every single character name, apart from Mario and Luigi and Peach, is different in America to Japan.
Speaker 2: So, what are you working on right now?
Speaker 0: I'm doing a Doctor Who animation at the moment, which I'm doing myself, so it's taking ages and ages.
Speaker 0: And that's about it, really.
Speaker 0: It's all on my DeviantArt page, which all the people at ConceptArt, all the real artists, will completely slag me off for saying that I've got a DeviantArt page.
Speaker 1: What's the URL of your DeviantArt page?
Speaker 0: Let me have a look.
Speaker 0: Actually, if you just go to Google and put in "Paul Otaking Johnson," it's the first thing that comes up.
Speaker 0: Actually, the documentary might be the first thing that comes up now.
Speaker 0: And various websites, like "Otaking is a gigantic faggot," and stuff like that.
Speaker 2: That's actually what I'm looking at right now, as I've searched on Google.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 2: That is, in fact, the fourth from the top.
Speaker 0: Indeed, yeah.
Speaker 1: Man, we've been doing this show for years, trying to get some hate, and you get it so instantly.
Speaker 1: It's not fair.
Speaker 0: I know, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: My five seconds of fame.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the thing, though.
Speaker 0: A lot of people are like, "Oh, he's just a gigantic troll.
Speaker 0: Oh, he's just doing it to get some attention," and whatnot.
Speaker 0: And it's not at all.
Speaker 0: I've had five seconds of fame from it.
Speaker 0: I've had 40,000 views on my video, and then it stopped.
Speaker 0: And that's all the fame I expect to get.
Speaker 0: I don't expect my name to be remembered or anything, and I don't expect to change anyone's mind, to be honest.
Speaker 0: Because no fan-subber is going to change the way they do things because of watching me ranting for half an hour.
Speaker 0: So I basically did it for myself, I think, really.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't think any fan-subber will change their mind, but someone like me who didn't really think of the issue at all... It wasn't... I mean, dubs and subs I thought about, but bad fan-subs versus good fan-subs was not... I didn't really think about it very much, but your video came along, and now suddenly I'm all on your side, like, "Oh,
Speaker 1: yeah.".
Speaker 1: So you've done something.
Speaker 2: Maybe there'll be some sort of movement eventually of awesome fan-subbers who decide to follow your way and make good fan-subs of new shows.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it is worth mentioning that a lot of the comments I got said you've deliberately picked bad examples.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 1: I do have to agree with that.
Speaker 1: But I think by showing the bad examples, like the worst of the worst, it's like I see aspects of those bad examples in, you know, the average fan-sub.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: And they sort of stick out.
Speaker 0: Well, I just grabbed what I could, was the thing.
Speaker 0: I didn't have the time to... I mean, it took long enough just to do the opening sequence.
Speaker 0: I didn't have the time to actually download a hundred episodes of One Piece and choose the worst ones.
Speaker 0: I just grabbed what I got, and that was what I ended up with.
Speaker 0: So I actually hope that what they're saying is true and that I ended up with bad examples and that there are actually much, much better fan-subs out there.
Speaker 0: I'd hate to think that the ones that I showed are what all the fan-subs are like.
Speaker 0: That'd just be terrible.
Speaker 1: No, I think in most fan-subs I watch, there'll be like one or two parts that are as bad as the examples.
Speaker 1: But for the most part, they're pretty much just, you know, normal-ish.
Speaker 1: You know, they're not great, but they're okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 2: All right.
Speaker 2: Well, thank you very much for being on the show with us.
Speaker 2: This was most enlightening.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: No problem.
Speaker 0: It's the first interview I've ever done, so I probably should have had some vodka before, but I had a Coke instead, and hopefully I haven't made myself look too much of an asshat.
Speaker 0: If "asshat" is even a real word.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's a word.
Speaker 2: Most definitely.
Speaker 0: It's a word.
Speaker 2: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 2: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com, where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 2: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week, covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 2: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 2: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Speaker 2: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com, or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Speaker 2: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 2: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial Share-A-Like 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it, as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.