Speaker 0: It's Wednesday April 2nd.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott yokai.
Speaker 1: It's no good Let's do this.
Speaker 0: I was so wrecked at work today.
Speaker 0: I almost fell asleep like three times.
Speaker 1: I was pretty wrecked him and I got into work and I went and I did a bunch of stuff and then I basically played Flash games rest of the day and I died.
Speaker 0: Well, actually I came into work and I asked one of the developers like hey Can I turn the log level down on this one thing?
Speaker 0: and he was like why?
Speaker 0: and I was like because it's generating like four Gigabytes of logs a day and I'm sick of dealing with it.
Speaker 0: And they're like, well, is there still a problem with that thing?
Speaker 0: And I'm like, yeah kind.
Speaker 0: He's like, yeah, we should leave it on.
Speaker 0: and then I was like, yeah Well, you know what?
Speaker 0: That's probably for the best cuz I'm sure it'll crash soon enough and crash and then I'll be able to Make use of those logs.
Speaker 0: and he was like don't be snarky.
Speaker 0: and I sit down at my desk and sure enough it was crashed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I sent him over a cord on fit and some logs.
Speaker 1: Cord, I'm fantastic yeah, but There was a little storm here last night, which is fine.
Speaker 1: I like me a storm little thunder lightning action.
Speaker 0: Oh, that was a great storm - it was okay.
Speaker 1: The thunder and lightning was not numerous or loud enough But the thing is the rain and the wind are pretty fierce.
Speaker 0: The thing is though it was super warm in the morning.
Speaker 0: So Emily and I are looking out the window like wow thunderstorm Let's totally run outside and we run outside and it had been 70 degrees when the storm rolled in as It was cold.
Speaker 1: as as storms do that makes the power go on and off a little bit, you know Not there's never like gonna be a big blackout, you know, especially at night when everyone's sleeping.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter so much Unless you have electric heat, but you know, it's just okay, whatever.
Speaker 1: But we were pissed off a long time ago because that would turn our computers off.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because our one our house is kind of crappy wiring because we're on the edge of beacon.
Speaker 0: So across the street from us a lot of those people start getting their power from other sources Like you can see the different sets of wires.
Speaker 1: Yeah Like when there's a blackout or when a power goes out you can look outside and you can see where there's light and where there's Darkness is different sets of power lines and you can tell where the breakage happened.
Speaker 0: But we're kind of on the end of our run.
Speaker 0: So we often have little blips.
Speaker 0: Also, our house is not the most well-wired house.
Speaker 1: Yeah, our house the power will be like on off on off and that's not good for computers and other electronic women.
Speaker 1: So we bought the cheapest UPS is imaginable and we brought.
Speaker 0: we got several of.
Speaker 1: we have four of them I think and the thing is they're fine.
Speaker 1: They help out a lot when the power goes blip all the computers are like what?
Speaker 1: what happened?
Speaker 1: Nothing, that's right.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: There's one problem.
Speaker 0: However with the cheap UPS So I'm asleep and scouts asleep and the power goes out.
Speaker 0: whatever.
Speaker 0: now, of course even without this I would have been woken up by the thunderous silence.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but You know when you're this.
Speaker 0: I've talked about this before we all you talk about this a lot But if you're tired and an unexpected noise happens your brain Like your body is flailing around trying to deal with it.
Speaker 0: But your brain's not awake enough yet to analyze the situation and be like that's not your alarm clock rim That's your cell phone.
Speaker 0: It's ringing.
Speaker 1: You can't stop it by turning off the alarm clock no matter how hard you try And now you're gonna go back to sleep and the cell phone stops ringing But you're not gonna wake up in the morning cuz you turned your cell phone off.
Speaker 0: So it's even worse when it's a really unexpected sound.
Speaker 1: so we're asleep and suddenly All the UPS's had run out of battery because they're cheap shit UPS's and they make loud noises.
Speaker 0: Well, they make noises saying hey the power's out.
Speaker 0: Just so you know, hey the power's out Just so you know.
Speaker 0: so and they actually last quite a while because we have one computer plugged into each and then the out.
Speaker 1: the last ones just like the night like crawl out of bed and stumble around turning off all these stupid UPS's and plugging things in and switching to my Cellphone alarm and all this bullshit.
Speaker 0: I was laying in bed.
Speaker 0: I'm like Emily.
Speaker 0: your cell phone's going off.
Speaker 0: Emily your cell phone's got.
Speaker 0: oh god.
Speaker 0: Damn it.
Speaker 0: No, I know what's going on.
Speaker 0: It's pretty bad, I really like crawl under my desk.
Speaker 0: I'm like trying to log into my computer to turn it off, but the monitor wasn't on but I was too tired to realize that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so in the end I just fucking turned off the UPS unplugged everything and then went back to sleep.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I did similar things in my room But then I lay back in bed.
Speaker 1: I'm like it's not cuz I looked at the clock before I turned it off.
Speaker 1: cuz you know as the clock is running on the Battery power and it's at 1158 and I'd gone to bed at like 10 something.
Speaker 1: It was like fuck.
Speaker 1: I felt like I was asleep for hours, but really I was not asleep very long at all.
Speaker 0: The worst thing is I get back in bed and then I hear faintly.
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah UPS on the networking equipment Yeah, and then when I woke up this morning gonna turn that back on because I couldn't get on the Internet's Yeah, well the thing is it whenever that UPS is going off.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much equidistant from me and Scott.
Speaker 0: So Well, I'll kind of lay in bed and thinking I hope Scott deals with it and he'll lay in a bed thing.
Speaker 0: I hope rim deals with it and then eventually one of us will stagger out there and like kick it to death.
Speaker 1: It did generally sucked.
Speaker 1: Hey, I use my cell phone alarm to wake up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my cell phone Strangely enough is having some problems.
Speaker 0: Suddenly.
Speaker 0: I think I'm gonna buy a new one already The the backlight just didn't turn off today really and it's still on and try messing with the power savings.
Speaker 0: I think The little thing that tells when you close the lid Is broken or something and it just it's.
Speaker 0: I think I gotta get a new cell phone.
Speaker 0: Just take it to the place Yeah, and they're gonna tell me get a new cell phone.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right, whatever Alright, so ready for news isn't what nuts?
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 1: so You can do you want to go first and I'll go first cuz I got news.
Speaker 0: I'm like some other lazy people.
Speaker 1: Hey, I'm not lazy.
Speaker 1: I'm Proactive.
Speaker 1: try to help the listeners.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know The only time I ever use the word Proactive is like it might work and there's something that needs to be done and there's something fun to do.
Speaker 0: Usually fun to do is like set up something new and awesome and not fun to do is like do the work.
Speaker 0: So it's like why aren't you working on the thing you're supposed to be working on?
Speaker 0: I'm being proactive Mmm, anyway, so there's a lot of Otakon news.
Speaker 0: I think the most important one.
Speaker 0: if you didn't realize it yet The artists alley is done.
Speaker 0: It's sold out.
Speaker 0: You're.
Speaker 0: if you don't if you didn't know you're screwed.
Speaker 0: Not necessarily, but Otakon historically has a problem.
Speaker 0: where the artist alley is so popular despite being so gigantic It's that artist alley is bigger than most anime cons.
Speaker 1: It's bad that pretty much the amount of room that the artists alley and the art show take up That room.
Speaker 1: you could have an entire comic convention in that room room to spare.
Speaker 0: Not only that it's more fun than a lot of anime cons.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would go to Otakon I think just for the artist alley but yet it's just one room of Otakon Otakon.
Speaker 0: but Historically when they announced the artist alley, it'll pretty much effectively be sold out within I don't know four seconds Maybe six seconds if you're lucky.
Speaker 0: But this year they did something a little different.
Speaker 0: now We got kind of a head start on this because our obsessive-compulsive friends Discovered the ASP that handles registration before it was announced and basically sat there all day hitting f5 until it worked and then told all of us some of them might have been pressing ctrl R. they might have been but Artist alley is open and this year It doesn't look like they're handling it the way they usually do because they didn't say Oh, it's already sold out and they haven't made any announcements to that effect.
Speaker 0: But the form just works and you fill it out all the artist alley stuff and then You get an email back saying we got your request.
Speaker 0: You will get some information soon.
Speaker 0: Now, I don't know how they're gonna handle it this year.
Speaker 0: I have no idea I have absolutely no insight into this and furthermore No one on the Otakon staff has given me any secret details about this in particular.
Speaker 0: So what you're about to hear is entirely speculation speculation.
Speaker 1: if
Speaker 0: I Were running the artist alley at Otakon and I would still say, you know, yeah, it's first come first serve Let it be however But secretly I would have in the previous Otakon gone around the artist alley or sent my lackeys around the artist alley Figured out who was good and made a list of like the people who are awesome and I also would have made a separate list of the people who were wasting their tables or In my opinion or in the opinion of say some sort of group of staffers working together What was not worth being there?
Speaker 1: because yeah, we weren't worth being there though.
Speaker 0: No, we totally weren't.
Speaker 0: Well this year will be worth being there But last year not so much.
Speaker 0: but part of that was that we didn't know we had a table until right before the con.
Speaker 0: but what I would do is I would kind of handpick who gets to be in because a Lot of people want to be in the artist alley at Otakon and Otakon has the best artist alley of any con.
Speaker 0: But three or four times the number of people who can fit in that artist alley Want to be in that artist alley every year and there's almost no fair way to do it.
Speaker 0: And when there's no fair way to do it You at least could do a way that I don't know makes the alley as good as possible for the people in it and for The people wanting to peruse it.
Speaker 0: So I think I would have done something like that.
Speaker 0: I don't know what Otakon is doing, but it was the smoothest registration they've ever had so kudos to them All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, nothing to say is that I got no god.
Speaker 0: No, so beyond that you got more than that Otakon as there there have been a lot of hints that this is gonna be the biggest and baddest Otakon ever.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's their 10th year at the BCC.
Speaker 0: It's also the 15th Otakon and There were a lot of rumors going around about.
Speaker 0: you know, they're gonna get some crazy musical act.
Speaker 0: Oh my god They're gonna get some crazy musical act some up.
Speaker 0: some staffers might have been banning these flames by periodically emailing us saying hey Something cool is gonna be at Otakon, but I can't tell you what.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, yeah not fooling anybody but it's finally been announced or at least part of it Otakon is going to have as their musical act one of their at least one of their musical act.
Speaker 1: now I don't know if there are any more musical acts I would suggest that there might be.
Speaker 1: there probably will be.
Speaker 0: I would be fine if this was the only musical act.
Speaker 0: They have announced that they have got jam Project.
Speaker 0: jam project is responsible for a lot of the music from anime that you know and love.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna do a whole show or a whole thing here about jam project But check out the Otakon press release and you'll see the names of a lot of things you might recognize.
Speaker 1: I think jam project was a great choice because you know in the past they've had like, you know huge You know much more much more popular bands at least, you know, it's sort of like hit, you know pop You know rock j-rock music like what
Speaker 0: they got laraku which was like amazing.
Speaker 1: Yeah But Basically, those are bands that were just musical acts that happen to have one of their songs be used as an opener closer to an Anime or something.
Speaker 0: Well, and they also happen to be really popular in Japan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but this case it's actually people who specifically make Anime music very specifically and like all their music is anime music.
Speaker 1: So it definitely has the wide appeal to both the music fans and the anime fans both.
Speaker 1: So you're not gonna get those people complaining like Those j-rockers come to my anime convention and right at those people can shove it.
Speaker 1: They those people can indeed shove it, but I think this is a much better choice overall.
Speaker 0: See, I don't know necessary.
Speaker 0: I think it's a good choice.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't necessarily say better but one thing that this group has over other possible musical acts is that everyone in the audience is gonna recognize a lot of the things they play and You know how anime cons.
Speaker 0: all you have to do if you're on stage is pretty much say something like hey guys Pikachu and the crowd just loses their shit.
Speaker 0: Well, if it's if it's these people playing songs that people recognize the crowd is gonna go crazy Like.
Speaker 0: I can't even imagine what the crowd is gonna be like.
Speaker 1: there will be.
Speaker 0: all shit will be lost is basically Now, I mean some of the people involved in this.
Speaker 0: the name that you'll probably know more than any is Masami okui.
Speaker 0: Look up what Masami okui has been responsible for Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Now that is not all of the awesome news for Otakon.
Speaker 1: for how much awesome Otakon news do you have?
Speaker 1: I'm sure you're not until August.
Speaker 1: Can't you save some of this news for when you don't have news next week?
Speaker 0: I think there's going to be a steady stream of Otakon news right up until Otakon.
Speaker 0: Oh good god, because I too
Speaker 1: many people we got like four
Speaker 0: months too many people on the inside have been hinting that Yeah, this is gonna be like the baddest Otakon ever and I Kind of expected alright, they're gonna get a crazy musical act or two and then they announce that it's like.
Speaker 0: alright They've got a crazy musical act.
Speaker 0: Okay, but I did not expect that Madhouse.
Speaker 0: Madhouse Studios, you know Madhouse It's going one of the best animation studios in the planet is going to be animating the opener as in like.
Speaker 0: if Otakon were an anime They're animating the opener to Otakon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah see that's a genius idea because any anime convention even super big ones like Otakon not enough people go to opening ceremonies.
Speaker 1: most of the people who go are like nubs or People who really have a thing for opening ceremonies or such.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean even we don't go to opening ceremonies.
Speaker 0: really the only kind I ever went to opening ceremonies That was.
Speaker 0: I went to anime central's twice, but that was because back then I went to opening ceremonies at penguin Otakon once and we tried to get the crowd to yell something and it failed.
Speaker 1: We tried to start a big chant and it didn't work because people weren't into it.
Speaker 1: now I was like, what's the point of coming opening ceremonies if everyone isn't gonna get all excited and rowdy?
Speaker 0: I think Otakon's opening ceremonies are gonna be all exciting and rowdy.
Speaker 1: This is the most genius idea ever to get people to come to opening ceremonies.
Speaker 1: show them an animation that can't be seen anywhere else.
Speaker 1: That was especially made just for those opening ceremonies.
Speaker 0: Yep, now they might.
Speaker 1: that's like if you had a video game convention and you made a video game that would only be played at Your convention made like by Square Enix to only be played at your convention at one event.
Speaker 1: He would be lined up around the doors.
Speaker 1: now I think that what says the most as in they'd be standing outside the door of their homes and the line to the convention would be forming for the.
Speaker 0: Here's a quote from the thing on anime news network because this is this is Otakon's Jim Vowels.
Speaker 0: You might remember Jim Vowels from such things as being at every Otakon ever and being awesome and liking Doctor Who More than any man should or than any man could know.
Speaker 0: No, but he's one of those like we talked about in the forum the.
Speaker 0: you know There's staffers at cons and then there's super staffers.
Speaker 0: He's one of those super staffers, but Quotes this was the most fun I've ever had.
Speaker 0: Now that quote is in reference to the meeting where they talked about what was gonna be in this opener And how it was gonna be put together.
Speaker 0: Oh good guy That was somewhat a selective quote.
Speaker 0: It's actually the most fun.
Speaker 0: I've ever had at an Otakon meeting No, all right, but I don't know the most fun.
Speaker 0: I've ever had.
Speaker 0: seems like a more news bite worthy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can imagine to be quite fun But yeah Otakon this year is gonna be.
Speaker 0: I can't even begin to think about awesome Otakon's watch.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be epic fail like anime Boston.
Speaker 1: It could happen.
Speaker 1: actually it could happen not likely but it could happen.
Speaker 0: speaking of that I want to touch on this very very briefly before Scott gets in.
Speaker 0: after we talked about the news anime Boston We got a few emails.
Speaker 0: What two of them were from?
Speaker 0: Otak anime Boston staffers who wish not to be named and we also got a lot of feedback from people are at the con and Like we kind of guessed it people said that other than registration the rest of anime Boston was in fact awesome As I
Speaker 1: as I suggested
Speaker 0: and furthermore it seems like they are fully aware internally as to exactly what the problem was and It'll be fixed next year or more bad things will happen.
Speaker 1: I am sure that an appropriate number of heads are rolling now.
Speaker 0: I can't really say more yet because it's way too soon, but there's too soon too soon.
Speaker 0: There's a good chance that we are going to be attending anime boss.
Speaker 1: Well a better chance than ever before.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't say good shit,
Speaker 0: I've already tentatively agreed
Speaker 1: All right, so I couldn't find a worthwhile news and I'm tired of anime news network and whatnot, right So I'm not doing a news but anime
Speaker 0: news Nina
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever and I've been doing a lot of geek bites on Wednesdays of you know, like comics I've read or whatnot.
Speaker 1: All right, but I actually am reading novel right now So I can't be reading any comics to do a geek bite of.
Speaker 1: So I try to think of something to fill this space with and I got an idea For a bit and I want to see if anyone out likes this bit.
Speaker 1: and if you like this bit I can make it a monthly bit and so it's sort of impossible for me to make this bit more or less than monthly.
Speaker 0: So what are you gonna call this bit?
Speaker 0: I mean, I have no idea that trouble naming bits.
Speaker 0: So we started out where like we called everything a geek.
Speaker 1: So why don't we tell what the bit is before we think?
Speaker 1: think of the name?
Speaker 0: Well first, you know our kind of Ad-hoc naming philosophy was that we kind of everything is geek something in camel case.
Speaker 0: But then we started falling away from that because nine times out of ten.
Speaker 0: That sounds really dumb.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but all right what you bit?
Speaker 1: All right, so you know, you listeners might know that I do not.
Speaker 1: I purchase comic books monthly mostly not actual comp books But you know big trade paperbacks and whatnot from a website or a service known as DCB service.com discount comic book service.
Speaker 1: calm and Basically what they allow me to do is I can order pretty much anything that diamond the evil comic distributors Of the direct market distribute two months in advance and then I get a tremendous discount.
Speaker 1: We're talking like 40% off.
Speaker 1: We're talking like four dollar comic books for 75 cents.
Speaker 1: It's way cheap, but I have to.
Speaker 1: the only disadvantage is that to buy things sight unseen?
Speaker 0: There's there's another disadvantage.
Speaker 0: I buy things through Scott because he'll say hey, do you want this?
Speaker 0: Hey, do you want this?
Speaker 0: and a lot of times I'll say yes without listening because it's so cheap.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 0: and then Scott gives me a pile of comic books that I remember.
Speaker 0: Oh, wait, I don't want this damn it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what am I gonna do with a serenity comic?
Speaker 0: It's awful.
Speaker 1: Yeah, was it awful.
Speaker 1: Did you read it?
Speaker 0: It was Expectedly bad.
Speaker 0: It wasn't awful, but it wasn't good.
Speaker 1: So there are.
Speaker 1: there are other websites that provide a similar service.
Speaker 1: heroes corner is one of them.
Speaker 1: I don't you know, I don't advocate any particular one.
Speaker 1: I just happen to use this one.
Speaker 1: and so basically what happens here is I get every month in the mail a giant box of comic books and I recommend Using a service like this to anyone who buys a significant amount of comics on a monthly basis.
Speaker 1: Who doesn't have a lot of money to spend and really really need that big discount?
Speaker 1: or if you don't live anywhere near a Comic book store conveniently, you know because then this way you don't it just shows up at your house You don't have to go driving to some comic book store an hour away or any bullshit like that, right?
Speaker 1: But I get this box of comics every month like at the beginning of the month.
Speaker 1: It's like clockwork and sometimes the little box sometimes a big box, you know, who knows.
Speaker 1: but I thought it might be an interesting bit To just sort of briefly go over Everything I got in the box this month and maybe you would call the bit like Scott's box.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: That's not the best name I think.
Speaker 0: I think you've named it.
Speaker 0: There's no going back from that.
Speaker 1: Oh this going back.
Speaker 0: There's there is no turning back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's that.
Speaker 0: you've already opened the coffin.
Speaker 0: It's open the vampires out.
Speaker 0: You can't put him back in the other coffin as a mummy.
Speaker 1: I'll just open that and they'll fight and then I can go back to choosing.
Speaker 1: maybe a slime will come.
Speaker 0: Everyone knows that vampires and mummies are natural allies.
Speaker 0: You need a werewolf to fight them.
Speaker 0: or good That's or a van peel.
Speaker 1: So I'm just gonna briefly go over every comic or you know book that was in the box this month and you know If this.
Speaker 1: I think this will help people sort of get an idea about what kind of comics I'm buying What sort of comics they might be interested in buying?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Tell me how.
Speaker 0: that totally reminds me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got a geek buy real quick.
Speaker 0: I read that Green Lantern Scott talked about last.
Speaker 1: I was terrible.
Speaker 0: What the fuck was that?
Speaker 0: That was awful.
Speaker 0: Why was Aquaman even there?
Speaker 0: He didn't even do anything.
Speaker 0: Neither did the flash seriously.
Speaker 0: Wow, okay, I'm done.
Speaker 1: All right Okay, so I'm gonna do this and then you're gonna go in the form and tell me if you think you want me to do This again.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So the first thing I'm just doing this in the order.
Speaker 1: It's listed on the website because on the website you can see what showed up in the box.
Speaker 1: It's pretty useful.
Speaker 0: Yes, yes in case you don't want to actually look in the box you can go.
Speaker 1: Well, it's easier for me to look at this webpage than to have a pile of comics in your room on the floor.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: So the first thing that was in the box back Mongolian chop squad manga volume 11.
Speaker 1: There are 19 volumes in total.
Speaker 1: This is you know back.
Speaker 1: It's the rock and roll kind of manga.
Speaker 0: I gotta actually watch that anime so we can talk about the anime I liked a lot.
Speaker 1: But the thing is with the anime is at the end of the anime.
Speaker 1: the anime sort of ends Not at the climax of the story and then they sort of tell the rest of the story During the closing credits of the last episode.
Speaker 1: So I wanted to get the manga to see first of all if there was any difference between that and the tv show.
Speaker 1: And also it is, you know sort of get the full fleshed out story that was in that epilogue and right now around volume 11 It's reaching the point where that of that climax.
Speaker 1: So now I think i'm gonna i'm finally gonna get to read new stuff as opposed to just sort of reading a Manga retelling of the anime even though the anime was retelling of the manga.
Speaker 1: next Uh andromeda stories volume three, I think this I think this is the last volume.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure of that but andromeda stories is by keiko.
Speaker 1: Takamiya the the two terra lady uh The there it's a little bit weird if you like to terra.
Speaker 1: I can't guarantee you'll like andromeda stories.
Speaker 1: I think rim will love andromeda stories.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: I will.
Speaker 1: um, it's a vertical manga.
Speaker 1: You can't go wrong.
Speaker 1: It's volume three.
Speaker 1: I bought it Uh invincible volume one family matters trade.
Speaker 1: It's an underwear perfect comic from image comics written by The guy who does walking dead and the most recent marvel team-up series robert kirkman.
Speaker 1: I bought it because people talk about it a lot and I figured yeah, the first trade is really really cheap.
Speaker 1: Whatever um Orion third edition trade paperback masamune shiro ghost in the shell apple seed Uh, etc.
Speaker 1: So orion is supposedly the most shirotastic Manga, so what?
Speaker 0: it's a hundred pages of a jiggling butt and then it's all one volume.
Speaker 1: This is the a new printing by dark horse.
Speaker 1: that's in the same Publishing format as all the other newer printings of masamune shiro's works.
Speaker 0: It's a hundred pages of a jiggling butt and overlaid over that is text ranting about some sort of societal Psychological future politics.
Speaker 1: i'm trying to make this quick rim.
Speaker 1: I got a lot of books here.
Speaker 1: Uh logan number one, this is actually a comic book, uh in the classic style, basically It's written by brian k vaughan the why the last man ex machina runaways guy.
Speaker 1: I pretty much buy any comic with his name on it No matter what like it could be poop on a stick by brian k vaughan.
Speaker 1: You got my money.
Speaker 1: So it's a wolverine comic.
Speaker 1: it's three issues.
Speaker 1: This is the first of three issues by him.
Speaker 1: I bought it.
Speaker 1: Uh terry moore's echo number one also a normal comic book.
Speaker 1: It terry moore is the guy who wrote strangers in paradise.
Speaker 1: I bought the first like pocketbook of strangers in paradise a while ago.
Speaker 1: I thought it was fantastic.
Speaker 1: I bought all the other five pocketbooks.
Speaker 1: So I have the whole series now, but I haven't read it yet because it's a lot.
Speaker 1: Um, and this is his new comic and it was issue one.
Speaker 1: So I said why the hell not plus?
Speaker 1: the cover is really nice.
Speaker 1: I got a study the omnibus volumes one and two.
Speaker 1: Yes, volume one is the beginning and volume two is the end.
Speaker 1: I don't think I need to own any more s3 right, so Uh, that's you know, because I sort of I like to you know comics that are like really Historically important and have a big significance.
Speaker 1: I like to own them.
Speaker 1: So i'm like, oh, I don't own any s3.
Speaker 1: Gotta get some of that Emma.
Speaker 1: volume seven for rim got anything to say about emma volume seven.
Speaker 0: I haven't read it yet because basically I bought like I. i'm missing volume four for various reasons.
Speaker 0: I bought an amazon.
Speaker 0: I just haven't yet because I always forget to buy it.
Speaker 1: You could have asked me the other day when I needed something to fill out an amazon order.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: You know, what did I just say?
Speaker 0: I always forget to buy it.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's every time I go to amazon and I order like a hundred things.
Speaker 0: then it's like is there anything else in the world?
Speaker 0: I need.
Speaker 0: I guess not.
Speaker 0: I click submit and it's like oh crap emma fuck it next time.
Speaker 1: All right, uh serenity better days.
Speaker 1: number one for rim.
Speaker 0: Anything to say about it, you know Firefly was good firefly comic not so worth reading.
Speaker 1: All right Marvel comics presents number seven.
Speaker 1: This is pretty much the only one of the only two Normal comic books that I don't buy and trade.
Speaker 1: I actually buy every issue because it's an anthology series.
Speaker 1: Like every month you get one comic book, but there's like three or four stories in there and it's just totally random Like marvel shit and it's totally off the wall by these small name guys and I always buy those series.
Speaker 1: I'm a sucker for them.
Speaker 1: Uh avengers the initiative volume one basic training.
Speaker 1: I bought this because it's written by dan slot because dan slot is.
Speaker 1: Every comic I have ever read that he has written has been amazing.
Speaker 1: And I realized somewhat recently that he wrote the red and stimpy comic that I was a fan of when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: ah And he wrote that somewhere.
Speaker 1: He wrote the awesome spider-man comic from free comic book day.
Speaker 1: He dan slot is awesome.
Speaker 1: So this is avengers written by dan slot.
Speaker 1: I said what the hell.
Speaker 1: Comic book comics number one.
Speaker 1: I bought this based on a recommendation.
Speaker 1: I don't know anything about it till I read it, but the cover's cool.
Speaker 1: Atomic robo number six the only other comic I buy not in trade paperback But actually in individual issues.
Speaker 1: it is brian clevenger writing about and a nuclear-powered robot who's sort of like indiana jones But snarky like spider-man and awesome.
Speaker 1: It's brian clevengers the 8-bit theater guy plus the art is amazing by the other guy.
Speaker 1: I forget his name.
Speaker 0: Sorry Yeah, what I was about to say was that uh, if you read this and you've read 8-bit theater All I have to say is that black mage comes out a lot.
Speaker 1: He sure does.
Speaker 0: It's like everything good about black mage just kind of oozes out of this robot almost done.
Speaker 1: npd psycho volume four dark horse publishing the.
Speaker 1: uh The ag.
Speaker 1: I think it's ag otsuka right the same guy who does the the corpse delivery service.
Speaker 1: I'm, pretty sure it's him.
Speaker 1: Uh, it's npd psycho.
Speaker 1: It's about you know, the scary detective with multiple personality disorder, but it's sort of.
Speaker 1: it's not real multiple personality disorder.
Speaker 1: it's movie fantasy multiple personality disorder and the serial killing and this horrible horrible hannibal style things going on.
Speaker 1: and It's it's quality.
Speaker 1: manga Death note profile.
Speaker 1: how to read 13 death note is a 12 volume manga.
Speaker 1: But in japan, they released a volume 13 that was sort of like the extras And viz just finally released This volume 13 in english and I skimmed through it a little bit and it is jam packed with shit.
Speaker 1: if you're a death note fan Uh, you should probably buy this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, um Showcase presents booster gold volume one.
Speaker 1: I bought this basically on a dare.
Speaker 1: It's one of those things where i'm reading it to.
Speaker 1: you know, pretty much I can't knock it if I haven't tried it.
Speaker 1: So I try it and then I knock it and we'll see.
Speaker 1: I don't I don't know if i'll knock it yet, but I got a prediction.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think I I I you may.
Speaker 0: you can call me a prognosticator.
Speaker 1: Okay, dmz volume four it's dmz.
Speaker 1: we talked.
Speaker 1: we did a whole show about it before.
Speaker 1: yeah, this is this is volume four.
Speaker 1: How could I not buy the next volume?
Speaker 0: Are you gonna keep reading it till the end?
Speaker 0: I don't think it's gonna end because I kind of lost interest already.
Speaker 0: Yeah Might be about the by two my second two favorite characters.
Speaker 1: I think it's about the story of him getting the eyeball.
Speaker 1: That's what I think.
Speaker 0: It's about but it's so easy to get those eyeballs.
Speaker 0: Just go buy them.
Speaker 1: I know right.
Speaker 1: Uh goon saga manga volume three.
Speaker 1: Remember that contest we're having where vertical sent us the three volumes.
Speaker 1: I've talked about this before.
Speaker 1: well, you know, they gave us the three volumes.
Speaker 1: But now the third volume that I paid for showed up Full metal alchemist manga volume 16, you know the full metal alchemist manga.
Speaker 1: I got it at the beginning because it was the full metal alchemist manga and that was so long ago.
Speaker 1: Right, like if the full metal alchemist manga volume one came out now I probably wouldn't buy it.
Speaker 1: and I started reading it and it was good and it diverged wildly from the show.
Speaker 1: But it wasn't bad.
Speaker 1: It wasn't great But it was.
Speaker 1: it was just kind of normal and at times I thought about stopping buying it.
Speaker 1: But the last volume that I read I think volume 15 Like came on full force and totally reminded me why i'm buying this.
Speaker 1: so volume 16.
Speaker 1: Here we go Phoenix volume 12.
Speaker 1: There are only 11 volumes of osama tezuka's phoenix.
Speaker 1: this volume 12.
Speaker 1: What viz has done is they have taken some earlier works of tezuka and some other things and sort of created a 12th volume of phoenix.
Speaker 1: Uh to sort of you know round out their publication, you know their series.
Speaker 1: So if you if you're buying the other 11 phoenixes, you gotta buy the 12th phoenix.
Speaker 1: and the last thing I bought was Transhuman number one, which is the guy who does nightly news brian hickman.
Speaker 1: Basically, if you haven't done any redney brian hickman's stuff, I think it's hey brian hickman It might be someone else hickman.
Speaker 1: I thought great.
Speaker 1: I forget.
Speaker 1: Sorry, but he's basically His comics.
Speaker 1: Yeah, his comics are amazing because they're basically like graphic storytelling via graphic design and they'll just blow you away if you Everyone should go buy nightly news.
Speaker 1: There's a trade paperback of nightly news.
Speaker 1: This is just the first issue of transhuman so I can sort of test it out to see if I want to buy the trade When it eventually comes out.
Speaker 1: And that's what I got in scott's box.
Speaker 0: Things of the day.
Speaker 0: so utenna is like one of the greatest anime ever made.
Speaker 0: we reviewed pretty great.
Speaker 0: We reviewed it before pretty terrific.
Speaker 0: someday We'll do some final thoughts bits, but that's complicated because utenna is one of the more complicated and literate shows out there.
Speaker 0: but uh if you need any more glowing recommendation as gomi dog in the forums because she finally saw the whole show and She will tell you Objectively how good it is.
Speaker 0: I might be a little biased.
Speaker 0: I'm kind of an utenna fanboy but uh kind of It's like the best show ever made with the exception of irresponsible captain tyler both of which made me cry.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so teen girl squad plus utenna equals uh Hilarity.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna leave it at that.
Speaker 0: The only other thing i'll say is that if you have not seen all of utana or at least if you've not seen any of utana This is still kind of funny.
Speaker 0: The more utana you've seen the funnier this is and the less spoilerific.
Speaker 0: It's not spoilerific.
Speaker 0: it's one of those like ava where like you see things in the opener or you see things and They might be a spoiler, but you have no context.
Speaker 0: So they're not a spoiler.
Speaker 0: That's sort of true Like if you see A scene of a giant white ray making people turn to goop.
Speaker 0: that doesn't really spoil ava because you have no idea What the hell that's all about.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: It's true.
Speaker 1: But yeah, uh If you are crazy with the spoilers you do want to avoid it though Yes and also if you really need to understand both teen girl squad and utenna to really Get the fullness of this mashup.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, you're not getting really out of it what you could get out of it.
Speaker 0: I think there are Three possible.
Speaker 0: I think there are three levels of Having seen utana in terms of getting all the jokes here And if you hit the third level you pretty much saw the rest of the show.
Speaker 1: It's a very deep uh mashup and that's why it's high quality and thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right.
Speaker 1: Check this out.
Speaker 1: There's a guy named evan shaner.
Speaker 1: He's got a you know, he's an artist dude makes comics and things.
Speaker 1: he's pretty good with the arts.
Speaker 1: He's got a website and a you know deviantart and all that stuff just like all the other arts peoples.
Speaker 1: And in his little blog here he made a little post on st Patrick's day that I didn't discover until recently.
Speaker 1: And in it, he has a little comic with him and his friends on st Patrick's day a little one panel comic kind of funny.
Speaker 1: And he also has a mashup.
Speaker 1: He did a little mashup with the watchman Little little mashup between the watchman and uh and peanuts.
Speaker 0: That is some hardcore action.
Speaker 1: It is a hardcore high quality mashup.
Speaker 1: You got you got your linus comedian your doc manhattan brown your uh.
Speaker 0: Your that sounds like a porn name your schroeder.
Speaker 1: Ozymandias doc to manhattan brown your uh, your rorschach snoopy your uh, what's the guy?
Speaker 1: who's the dirty guy?
Speaker 1: pig pen pig pen alley guy.
Speaker 0: He's not so much dirty as just frumpy and middle-aged.
Speaker 1: I know but he's big ben for the alley guy.
Speaker 1: I forget the alley guy's name.
Speaker 1: Ah, and what's the girl's name?
Speaker 0: I don't even remember which girl.
Speaker 0: there's more girls and peanuts than one the one who's going with.
Speaker 0: Dr Manhattan because there's peppermint patty.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: No, I know it's lucy.
Speaker 1: But who?
Speaker 0: the watchman name, you know, I already forgot her name.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah her lucy's the girl.
Speaker 0: Sorry Anyway, we're gonna talk about the show look at it tonight that we haven't seen in a long time but that's fine because In all and in fact, I actually only saw like the first seven episodes.
Speaker 0: I never watched the rest.
Speaker 1: That's fine because the show is really shallow and you don't need to really watch it recently to have a bunch to say about it.
Speaker 1: Plus a lot of the things you have to say about the show are meta.
Speaker 0: we're gonna talk a lot about the history of anime fandom in the us because gatekeepers was a forgettable Mediocre like, you know highly well produced but just other otherwise forgettable show.
Speaker 1: Gatekeepers was a show that was on tv when japanese school kids got home from school.
Speaker 1: you know is that kind of show like, you know, come home from school and Watch high school kids fight big alien robots pow Zap that that sort of show.
Speaker 1: and you know, we we watched it At the rit anime club in our freshman year.
Speaker 1: So in the year 2000 when it came out And you know, it was it was very shallow.
Speaker 1: It wasn't a deep show.
Speaker 1: It wasn't a high quality show but At the time You know gonzo It was.
Speaker 1: it was better animation than being seen in many other things at least in terms of the digital Technologies used by gonzo who had you know been making like video game, uh, you know cut scenes until then and It was one of the first digital fan subs and it was also a show that just the way it's structured If you have a room full of excited anime fans, they can yell and cheer and go.
Speaker 0: It's one of those shows that sets you up with things that are designed to make someone yell, yep
Speaker 1: Basically, here's how the show goes right high school kids Alien invaders the alien invaders are all cool and stylish like they all have black hats But one of them always has a red hat and he's the weak point.
Speaker 1: then they all form together Right into like a giant blob or something, right?
Speaker 1: And the cool part of each episode is seeing what the bad guys form into like in one.
Speaker 1: in one episode They form into like a piece of a super highway so it's like these two pieces of street are stomping around the town.
Speaker 1: Uh in another and I think the first episode they're just like a giant black ball.
Speaker 1: You know, they have all these different, you know formations and it's it's always sort of funny to see How the bad guys decide to attack this time.
Speaker 1: uh And the rest of it is just these high school kids.
Speaker 1: or you know They join or forced to join the secret organization aegis And jokai and jesu.
Speaker 1: and then there's these really cool kind of stylish scenes where they're like sent out into action and it sort of got like a Like a bit of a 50s styling to like drive an old motorcycle to the scene.
Speaker 0: The show was fly a retro rocket to the scene in like the late 60s in japan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's that's one thing you might not realize watching the show.
Speaker 1: I mean you have to kind of pay attention to that.
Speaker 1: it's set in an older time period.
Speaker 0: Not but it is the deal.
Speaker 0: we'll talk about gatekeepers itself first because I would have had a lot more to say about this show if we were doing geek nights.
Speaker 0: I don't know like April something in the year 2000 when I saw it because the show was Really crazily popular in america and it was like a big deal and everyone watched it Everyone knew about it and it was oh my god.
Speaker 0: If the same show or a similar show would come out today, it would have been completely ignored.
Speaker 0: Yep, and There's there's.
Speaker 0: the show is not deep at all.
Speaker 1: It is pretty much just fight the bad guys An incredibly shallow high school character development.
Speaker 0: I mean it there's.
Speaker 0: it follows shun the main character.
Speaker 0: who?
Speaker 0: Happens to have the most badass gate in the world gate by the way is just the powers they have.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, you know one girl is like gate open and she shoots an arrow with a magic gate and another girl like goes gate open and she Plays the piano and it makes things happen.
Speaker 1: I think her superpower was that she was incredibly stupid Yep, and the main guy of course goes gates open and he has a sword.
Speaker 1: Duh Sword.
Speaker 0: i'm not even gonna bother talking about the plot really because it's the show was just eye candy.
Speaker 0: And the things to remember about the show are one The way gatekeepers and like military people within this organization saluted each other.
Speaker 0: You could not walk around rit without someone doing that to you Every day for like a month after.
Speaker 1: it wasn't that bad but at anime club people would be going like I go ages All the time.
Speaker 0: it was and they make.
Speaker 1: I had a gatekeepers, uh, uh id card in my wallet that we got for free.
Speaker 0: somehow a lot of us had them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we did.
Speaker 0: Yeah this show was really popular at rit and the showing of it in the anime club was crazy yelling and screaming because What's his name?
Speaker 0: the guy who's like the head officer of the commander of aegis.
Speaker 1: every time he would send him out on mission He would do this phoenix right style pointing kind of thing like go You know what like aegis attack or something.
Speaker 1: I forget exactly what he said to call it phoenix right style.
Speaker 0: Does it a disservice if you think phoenix right has a powerful point?
Speaker 0: Phoenix right has got nothing.
Speaker 0: phoenix right is like a beginning pupil of the gatekeepers commander Like whenever he was about to do it you could tell that like the people animating it and everything were excited Because it would like zoom in and his hand would come up his whole body would rotate.
Speaker 1: His hand would like come out from behind his head.
Speaker 0: It would fly around in a circle with motion blur.
Speaker 0: It would come forward with action lines so hard.
Speaker 0: The screen would shake.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was that alone made the show worth watching pretty much and also like, you know The bus that turns into like a heavily armored vehicle.
Speaker 0: I think the best thing was that the secret base of aegis was just in the high school and It was secret.
Speaker 0: I don't think you can see me making quotation marks.
Speaker 1: It was a clark kent kind of secret.
Speaker 0: Not even that Everyone and I mean pretty much everyone on the planet except the bad guys knew that that was the aegis headquarters.
Speaker 0: They'd be like, oh the high school Yeah, you'd be sitting in high school in class.
Speaker 1: suddenly one year's one kid that always leaves.
Speaker 1: all the time.
Speaker 0: Lee walks out of the room like the fire alarm goes off and then and then a rocket flies out of the roof like basically like a smoke would appear if we're like, oh there's a Fire.
Speaker 0: and then like the bus full of guns flow not guns, but gatekeeper craft flies away.
Speaker 1: Basically, it's just a silly after school show with animation.
Speaker 1: That was impressive digital animation.
Speaker 1: That was impressive at the time.
Speaker 1: It's really shallow.
Speaker 1: It's good.
Speaker 1: If you want to have a fun time with a bunch of you know, anime club type people But it's really.
Speaker 1: it's not worth watching all the episodes unless you really don't have a lot better to do.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's okay But it's not great or anything.
Speaker 1: It's it's a. it's a solid low b high c kind of show.
Speaker 1: It's just fun and shallow.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean the other.
Speaker 0: oh, the only other thing I want to bring up before we stop talking about the anime itself was boncho.
Speaker 1: Yeah, imagine he was the comic relief kind of character.
Speaker 0: this is a show where everyone has a gate like a power They're all little superheroes, but boncho was not a superhero.
Speaker 0: He was just some guy who was really intense.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was his superpower.
Speaker 1: He's basically like let me join the team.
Speaker 1: I'm on the team whether you like it or not.
Speaker 1: He's like.
Speaker 1: he's like yes.
Speaker 1: I have a power.
Speaker 1: You just haven't seen it yet.
Speaker 1: Blah.
Speaker 0: Yeah guts and that's all he had.
Speaker 1: Yeah, his power was guts and he would just.
Speaker 1: he was just a tall bigger than the average high school student.
Speaker 1: It was really comic relief.
Speaker 0: So Why the hell are we talking about this show then?
Speaker 0: I mean there are better shows coming out now that we're not watching or reviewing.
Speaker 0: so why this?
Speaker 1: well because back in the day As I said before it was one of the first digital fan subs.
Speaker 1: and even if it wasn't the first digital fan sub, right?
Speaker 1: this show Basically, there was a website anime dash factory.
Speaker 1: I wonder if that website is still there.
Speaker 0: Well while you look it up, I mean the first digital fan sub that really got widely Circulated as far as I was aware was the escaflowne movie and people made a big deal about that and like, oh my god It's a fan sub.
Speaker 1: Yeah Because until then all fan subs were sort of vhs and a lot of people didn't even know what a fan sub.
Speaker 1: I didn't know what a fan sub was till I got to rit.
Speaker 1: so the idea of a digital fan sub really hadn't gotten around yet and It wasn't the first one because we did have the escaflowne one before we had the gatekeepers one, but The gatekeepers one was on a website that basically said come here and download gatekeepers episode one with subtitles And watch it on your computer and we'll have episode two soon.
Speaker 1: and then they started doing.
Speaker 1: boys b was the next show they tried to do and this sort of people saw that and it was sort of.
Speaker 1: they realized it clicked like Oh A digital fan sub.
Speaker 1: I get it Oh shit, and just because it happened to be the show that sort of started that Realization process it gained a lot of popularity.
Speaker 1: That was a lot very undeserved.
Speaker 0: But actually I think the escaflowne movie was released a little bit after.
Speaker 1: oh, was it really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so maybe it might have been the first digital fan sub.
Speaker 0: I'm just not committing to that because i'm not sure but This show kind of this marks a turning point in anime fandom in the united states like Anime fandom after this show was completely different in a lot of ways.
Speaker 1: I mean basically the anime club.
Speaker 1: when this started happening they had to debate at the anime club.
Speaker 1: Should we show this?
Speaker 1: You know and it was like a big.
Speaker 1: they had shown tape fan subs before but it's like can we show this?
Speaker 1: Should we show it?
Speaker 1: because in those days, you know the divics and stuff wasn't the same quality it is now.
Speaker 1: I mean, well vhs is terrible quality, but you know, there were all sorts of issues like should we show it?
Speaker 1: It was a big discussion and it was a major turning point, you know, it was pretty much like it was like, uh, You know They were on one course.
Speaker 1: then this happened and then that's when they started to turn towards the other course.
Speaker 0: I mean I I really gotta stress how much things change because before this for the majority of people who liked anime At rit just because that's an example If you wanted to see Anime that wasn't already released in the us on vhs or dvd and there wasn't that much that was easy to get especially for poor college kids You pretty much had to go to anime clubs And at the anime club the like the eboard would sit and debate and decide What are we going to show these people?
Speaker 0: They're a captive audience because this is the only place they can get this stuff easily And then they could check stuff out of the library too.
Speaker 0: Yes But at the same time the the club was like there was so much in the library because god We had so many tapes even before digital fan subs.
Speaker 0: It was crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah that there was like.
Speaker 0: people needed direction.
Speaker 0: So pretty much you'd have two hundred three hundred people come to watch anime Partly because they'd get to see stuff that they'd never heard of had really no easy way of finding out about.
Speaker 0: and the the like the goal of the club was to Show as many different kinds of anime as possible to get people into anime and then after gatekeepers People could go find out about anime on their own and then get it on their own.
Speaker 0: Yep, and there was a lot of talk about.
Speaker 0: well How are we going to get people to keep coming to the anime club?
Speaker 0: of course people kept coming and that's probably a topic for a separate show.
Speaker 0: as to how Some anime clubs survived this and many did not.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think we've talked about that plenty before but you know the the important point is that gatekeepers.
Speaker 1: It sort of got the ball rolling ironically enough because the bad guys turned into a giant ball in the first episode.
Speaker 0: It was also a lot of people called it the linux anime because the redhead guy was always the bad guy.
Speaker 1: Uh, it's so lame, but everyone I never heard anyone make that joke.
Speaker 0: people made that joke all the time.
Speaker 0: It's rit god.
Speaker 1: Oh, let me let me add in a note here gatekeepers has a manga, right?
Speaker 1: And it was a good call by tokyo pop to bring over the gatekeepers Manga because it would be able to sell to the people who had seen the gatekeepers anime Fan subbed based on the title alone and it.
Speaker 1: in fact, I bought volume one way back in the day At full price even though now this is super super super discount bin fodder And rightfully so because it is a terrible manga.
Speaker 1: if you think the anime is shallow and nothing The manga is 10 times more shallow and nothing.
Speaker 1: It's basically like you open it up and it's just really.
Speaker 1: it's like meant for like five-year-olds this manga.
Speaker 1: It's like attack the bad guy gate open boom The end.
Speaker 1: that's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: You don't need to read the manga.
Speaker 0: No, don't forget my fray for two words.
Speaker 1: They might enjoy it collateral damage.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's another thing about like this show.
Speaker 0: The other the revolution of anime fandom was also that up until this point and up until digital fan subs people kind of Took whatever they could get and pretty much any show that people got their hands on they would watch I mean god, we watch legend of lennemere And we watch a lot of bad anime.
Speaker 1: Yeah up until that point in my life, you know any anime that was on any You know, whatever sci-fi channel was showing I was there whatever anime club was showing.
Speaker 1: I think every anime that the anime club showed, you know was like, yes.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 0: Yes Awesome, and everyone would show up the people who only like giant robot stuff.
Speaker 1: They came to see the fancy lala-esque shows because it's anime It's anime, but this as you know within a few months just months because it was still freshman year Right after you know, this sort of this came out.
Speaker 1: You know, I was on you know hotline and there was plenty not actually ran a very popular hotline server At rit for a while quite uh.
Speaker 1: And you know We were all sharing all these digital fan subs that all of trygun and like real media files and it was all this stuff Going on and like.
Speaker 0: there was this sudden explosion and then all of a sudden A lot of people no longer had interest in one bad anime, but two anime that They on the surface didn't think they'd like.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: if we like fancy lala as an example ignore when fancy lala came out or whatever.
Speaker 0: But before the fan sub revolution and gatekeepers If we showed fancy lala everyone would come because all right anime the b-board picked it.
Speaker 0: It must be good enough to see and I want to see some anime.
Speaker 0: after that Fancy lala and people who like magical girls would come and everyone else would say screw it.
Speaker 0: I'll stay home and continue watching like fist battler baki And i'll wait for the next fist battler baki like show before I go back to the anime clubs.
Speaker 0: Yep
Speaker 1: You know the one more thing gatekeepers actually did is as far as i'm concerned is it was sort of you know It wasn't the first thing that gonzo ever did but it was one of the first uh, tv shows ever Animated by gonzo which is now a pretty big and important studio.
Speaker 1: they got their start doing you know video game cutscenes and then gatekeepers one of their first tv shows.
Speaker 1: and Gatekeepers really, you know the digital animation techniques used in that are pretty much used in everything today.
Speaker 1: And i'm not I don't think they invented those techniques But that was like one of the first places I ever saw animation.
Speaker 1: that was that shiny.
Speaker 1: Did you see animation that shiny before?
Speaker 0: then gatekeepers?
Speaker 1: I mean, I see I saw better animation like akira is much better animation than gatekeepers, but it wasn't as shiny.
Speaker 1: You see i'm the shiny does not go better.
Speaker 0: This is kind of like how tenchi muyo when american fans saw it There was a big hubbub because it looked so Shiny compared to other anime and it stood out as being like oh my god This was kind of similar that it looked really good and that drew a lot of people to it and gatekeepers Was like so shiny and so eye candy that a lot of people who had never seen this sort of thing before fell hand over foot for it because it just looked so Amazing
Speaker 1: Yep,
Speaker 0: and part of that too was that they just hadn't seen a lot of anime and this was kind of a new thing for Them.
Speaker 1: and I think that because it was one of the first if not the first show to be digitally fan subbed You know and the p I knew that was when I knew who ganzo was like Think about that someone who never really paid attention to who made anime.
Speaker 1: I didn't really pay attention to directors other than miyazaki until like a couple years ago Right, like when I started listening when podcasting started coming into being.
Speaker 1: you know An animal order told me.
Speaker 1: Oh, you should pay attention.
Speaker 1: I said, oh shit.
Speaker 1: You're right This is the year 2000, but I knew that this was made by studio ganzo because I don't know how that Knowledge like stuck with me, but it did and there was just something about that.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it was.
Speaker 1: So I I really I give gatekeepers a lot of credit for so.
Speaker 1: well Basically, I think that it had a significant role in bringing studio ganzo to to from being some nobody's made video game Cutscenes to the high profile studio they are today.
Speaker 0: Well, there was also a lot of some fun side stories that you know We talked about.
Speaker 0: oh This was a new issue much like when the un has to deal with like a new kind of weapon or a new kind of warfare.
Speaker 0: the anime clubs of the world had to deal with a new kind of anime distribution medium and the the most interesting debate that happened was actually after the fact because there was a sequel to gatekeepers called Gatekeepers 21 i've watched one episode and decided it was garbage.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I watched one episode and I didn't decide it was garbage.
Speaker 1: It seemed like it was a crime.
Speaker 1: It seemed like they were trying to ham-fist a show like noir Into the gatekeepers universe in the distant future and it wasn't working so well.
Speaker 1: But I don't think it was garbage, but I only watched one episode.
Speaker 0: It really didn't grab me at all.
Speaker 1: I was I didn't watch any more of it.
Speaker 1: That's for sure.
Speaker 0: but there was a crazy controversy about the gatekeepers 21 because we you know, anime clubs we had a lot of policies about what to show and Fan subs were usually deemed Okay because most fan subs weren't released like there are very few fan subs available that were ever released commercially.
Speaker 0: Are there any plans to release commercially?
Speaker 1: the issue of the vhs fan sub?
Speaker 1: You know was a solved problem long before we ever got to the anime club.
Speaker 0: Like we had all these policies to deal with it, but then with these digital fan subs, so gatekeepers 21 someone had laboriously fan subbed it and It this person.
Speaker 0: they wanted it to be shown at the rit anime club.
Speaker 0: like look what I did.
Speaker 0: Let's let everyone see this.
Speaker 0: but in between when the fan subbing was completed and when it was to be shown It was announced that it was going to be released commercially.
Speaker 1: Yep, because it's like wow because I didn't you know.
Speaker 1: up until then there weren't.
Speaker 1: The commercial releases of anime are few and far between.
Speaker 1: we're talking streamline vhs's and such But I mean we're talking like try gun came out on dvd kawa bebop was come was out on dvd.
Speaker 1: That was the beginning of professionally released anime in the us, you know being on dvd and being high quality and awesome.
Speaker 1: and There was an announced licensing of gatekeepers gatekeepers 21.
Speaker 0: I forget it was gatekeepers 21 is the specific one and We debated.
Speaker 0: we had like this crazy eboard meeting for hours where we debated whether or not we should show it.
Speaker 0: And then if we show it what's the rationale?
Speaker 0: if we don't show it what's the rationale what is our policy going forward?
Speaker 0: What like?
Speaker 0: we had to worry about this because it was a new thing and we didn't know what to do and we eventually came upon the kind of golden rule of anime clubs that still holds true to a large degree today, which was that We decided that as long as the show had not been given a street date as in there was.
Speaker 0: no We have the license.
Speaker 0: it is going to be released as of this day.
Speaker 0: We wouldn't wait until it was released because that was kind of crap because but We wait until they said it was going to be released and they said like it's going to be this day or this month Yeah,
Speaker 1: because someone could buy the license to something and then never release it.
Speaker 1: and we you know There was a sort of feeling that well if they're going to do that then You know There's a chance that they won't ever release it which is actually something that did happen way back in those days Not like now where they license something and it almost always gets released except, you know Even more recently the trend is reversed.
Speaker 1: So, you know if there was a if unless they said the dvd will be available volume one on this date Then that meant there was a chance that they were just going to hold on to the license and never release it.
Speaker 1: So he said in that case It's still okay for us to show a fan sub because this could be like, you know Lost art that no one will be able to see because someone's hoarding the license.
Speaker 0: Yep Now pursuant to that was the general policy that we'd never really showed whole shows and we kind of pointedly avoided.
Speaker 0: We never actually addressed the issue, but we never showed a marathon Of a fan sub.
Speaker 0: no We would show the first four episodes because if nothing else that did All that did is generate more interest in the actual commercial release.
Speaker 1: whenever we did a marathon of an entire show would always be the real dvds.
Speaker 0: now I to go over this very briefly.
Speaker 0: back then Industry relations in terms of fan clubs were kind of different from they were today and we'd always you know we got like legal permission to show things and all this sort of and we had the Implicit and tacit a kind of approval of our policies by the anime Quote-unquote industry.
Speaker 0: at the time there was kind of a yeah, they won't say that though But we we had a lot of working relationship with many industry people and the policy then was an unspoken.
Speaker 0: As long as you follow the rules, you said you're following we will never bother you about your the way you show fans.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is a long time ago though.
Speaker 1: So don't it won't.
Speaker 1: it's not the same today.
Speaker 0: It's totally different now.
Speaker 0: Now the other issue was all right.
Speaker 0: We had a gigantic anime library.
Speaker 0: Do we allow?
Speaker 0: Digital fan subs in the library and if so in what capacity?
Speaker 0: and that that argument lasted for months.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they would.
Speaker 1: they I think eventually like they took some digital fan subs and transferred them to vhs and put them in the library.
Speaker 0: But that died out and eventually actually became moot before we came up with a policy on how to deal with it.
Speaker 0: Everyone just downloaded their own fan subs and the only purpose of the library then was to get legitimate releases.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they eventually old old like vhs releases of.
Speaker 1: like rupan Yep, they eventually just started You know buying dvds and throw and replacing all the fans of vhs's that you know had dvd replacements.
Speaker 0: Of course right about then was when scott johnson was in the process of being the best goddamn librarian ever In terms of getting enough money from rit to buy the sick amount of dvds that we had.
Speaker 1: man He like the library was pretty big when I joined the anime club scott It was in these cabinets.
Speaker 1: They had these eight cabinets and the club library filled the cabinets, but that was it.
Speaker 1: Scott johnson got added so many tapes to the library that not only did he fill those cabinets all the way He completely covered like three or four long tables.
Speaker 0: Yes, like our office was basically just full of dvd and vhs tapes.
Speaker 1: It was it was quite a thing to see.
Speaker 0: and then scott Johnson was the like emperor justinian of the rit anime club library something along those lines.
Speaker 0: Yes, I remember.
Speaker 0: and then the worst thing is our method of dealing with like inventory was basically this little notebook.
Speaker 1: Yep,
Speaker 0: and we revolute we me and him sat there for like two days straight one weekend Recat catalogizing I'm gonna say catalogizing
Speaker 1: taking inventory of
Speaker 0: not just that but making the whole new system of taking inventory and relabeling Everything and the shit I got for the next three years because my g's look too much like o's and my handwriting was bad.
Speaker 1: Screw you you guys you guys didn't help me at all and gatekeepers was an instigator of the whole thing.
Speaker 0: I don't know what else we really have to say.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's a lot of Intimate little details about fan subs and gatekeepers and things that you probably don't care about.
Speaker 0: I don't think I want to get into the specifics of the arguments that we had in the club or Like just the reactions and all those crazy things.
Speaker 0: I think you get the overview of what was going on at that time.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Uh, all I gotta say now is that uh, I have received what appears to be Uh one more valid entry into the goon saga manga contest.
Speaker 1: Oh snap I am going to judge the valid entries this week and I will announce a winner Next wednesday on the show, but if you send in a valid entry between today and next wednesday I will enter it into the judging.
Speaker 1: So right now you got a one out of three.
Speaker 1: I think there's three entries and two of them are valid so far.
Speaker 0: so you'll win the goon saga manga.
Speaker 1: Your chances are good of winning if you send in a valid entry.
Speaker 1: listen to any geek nights.
Speaker 1: That was a recent wednesday show.
Speaker 1: for the rules.
Speaker 1: It's a real essay contest.
Speaker 1: and uh, tell me if you want to hear more of the scotts box bit.
Speaker 0: and also Uh, we were not originally intending on attending the new york comic con.
Speaker 0: We just had a lot of other things going on like gaming for hope which is the same.
Speaker 1: how much you're gonna give away now?
Speaker 0: All i'm gonna say is that we are now attending the new york comic con and we're going to be press for one.
Speaker 0: But much more importantly we're doing some events we're doing.
Speaker 0: we're going to be involved in something That may or may not involve guests of honor at the convention and may or may not be completely awesome.
Speaker 1: Off the hook if you will.
Speaker 0: this is this is one of those.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it's rare where I would say are we getting it over our heads now, but we might be.
Speaker 1: yeah It's there's gonna be.
Speaker 1: we went from not caring about the new york comic con which is really soon By the way, like this month to now.
Speaker 1: maybe something's gonna go down there.
Speaker 0: probably I think next week I will be able to divulge the details but suffice to say holy crap.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the rss feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and rpgs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tom foolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com Or you can send audio feedback via odeo.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an odeo on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in itunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 1: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night You.