Speaker 1: It's Wednesday January 2nd.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 1: We talk about the fifth strongest man on me pros island.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, uh one interesting thing did come out of the weekend of you know craziness here at the geek house other than the fact that I Barely made it into work this morning.
Speaker 0: I'll go to bed right after we finish this show.
Speaker 0: Well, I might do some stuff before then but not long after this show is done.
Speaker 0: recording.
Speaker 0: I am going through.
Speaker 1: the sleep today was rough.
Speaker 0: I'll put it that way I was sleeping on the train sleeping to work sleeping on the train.
Speaker 1: I should have stayed home But actually at the party our friend Nuri came, you know Everyone in the front row crew came.
Speaker 1: we had a big party and she presents to us this box.
Speaker 1: I don't know what's in this box.
Speaker 0: I don't want to talk about this.
Speaker 1: You don't want to talk about it.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 1: We have to talk about it.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: because she brought it it's hair.
Speaker 1: It's sitting in front of me.
Speaker 0: It's put in a closet or something.
Speaker 0: throw it out to sell it on eBay.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: If you really don't care I won't talk about it.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Okay, then talk about it then.
Speaker 0: So I was at the post office today and you know, I tried to go to the post office.
Speaker 1: I don't care about this.
Speaker 0: Okay, we won't talk about that either.
Speaker 1: You're gonna say that some fat lady got in front of you in line.
Speaker 1: You had to wait.
Speaker 0: No, I was also gonna talk about selling stuff on eBay.
Speaker 0: Ah, yeah, I sold something on eBay.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I figured out it's unless you are like super poor.
Speaker 0: It is not worth it to sell stuff on eBay.
Speaker 0: I mean I sold some RAM.
Speaker 0: I had lying around.
Speaker 0: that was still good But I had no use for it and I figured this will get some money.
Speaker 0: The amount of money I got versus the amount of trouble I had to go through to sell it Even if there had been no line at the post office Not worth it.
Speaker 1: So you're saying that it would have been more economical to throw the RAM away than to sell it on eBay.
Speaker 0: Maybe not economical because I have a salary job.
Speaker 1: You realize economical includes your opportunity cost of your time and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: then Yes, it would have been more economical for me to throw the RAM away.
Speaker 1: I have never bought anything on eBay and I've never sold anything.
Speaker 0: buying things on eBay isn't so bad if you can get a Deal.
Speaker 0: because I you know people always think oh eBay scams.
Speaker 0: and yeah, there's scams there But they're generally obvious and every time I've ever bought something on eBay.
Speaker 0: I've always successfully received it.
Speaker 0: I mean we got that dune game right?
Speaker 0: Perfect.
Speaker 0: So yeah, but selling stuff on eBay almost perfect.
Speaker 1: There's some creepy wax seals on a bunch of the spice.
Speaker 1: I don't know why that's there.
Speaker 1: Why are there wax seals on the spice?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: They keep prevent different flowing.
Speaker 1: I Can't wait to talk about the dune game.
Speaker 0: Well tell you how to do in game in a few weeks.
Speaker 0: We got some hot stuff next week.
Speaker 1: We should play some more two-player dune.
Speaker 1: I can be the Harkonnen about not All right.
Speaker 1: So what do you got in the anime manga comic news then?
Speaker 0: Oh God, I really I don't want to do this news because it's such a shit shit news.
Speaker 0: But there really isn't anything else to talk about.
Speaker 0: So I'd rather do the shit news than the nothing news.
Speaker 0: and you know, we've been laying on some underwear perfect Love lately.
Speaker 0: So now we got to lay back on five times the underwear.
Speaker 0: pervert hate.
Speaker 0: You're ready.
Speaker 1: All right, I'm ready.
Speaker 0: Okay, you know spider-man Yeah guy shoots webs.
Speaker 1: He had one possibly two good movies, and I don't like anything else spider-man, right?
Speaker 0: well, there was a recent story in spider-man right and The story goes like this remember recently spider-man like revealed himself to the world.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: Oh spider-man revealed himself to the world like a year ago months ago.
Speaker 0: Okay So the story now is this.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna try to sum it up in as few words as possible.
Speaker 0: if you actually care about Spider-man, first of all, how are you a geek nice fan?
Speaker 0: and second of all Tough shit.
Speaker 1: So did something happen to our friendly neighborhood?
Speaker 0: Listen to this, right?
Speaker 0: Look take what I'm about to describe to you as Sort of a a story Right and sort of examine this story from the perspective of someone who is like an author Someone who is judging good writing from bad writing right not from the respective of underwear perverts, right?
Speaker 0: Okay, so spider-man revealed himself to the world and his aunt May who by all means should have been dead a hundred years ago She must be like 300 years old by now get shot by like a sniper and is in the hospital But not dead this crazy old woman.
Speaker 0: so Spider-man really wants her to come back to life.
Speaker 0: So he goes to Iron Man.
Speaker 0: He says Iron Man give me some money and Iron Man's like black can't help you.
Speaker 1: But why not?
Speaker 0: Iron Man has money but then Iron Man gives some money anyway.
Speaker 1: so why did that do?
Speaker 1: that didn't even matter right.
Speaker 0: and then It still isn't helping right.
Speaker 0: your old lady's gonna die.
Speaker 0: So he goes and Mephisto shows up who's effectively Satan.
Speaker 0: spider-man makes a deal with Satan and It makes a deal with Satan that The old lady doesn't die.
Speaker 0: but Basically spider-man like for and his wife both forget their marriage like as as if it never happened.
Speaker 1: That is perhaps The dumbest thing I've ever heard.
Speaker 1: yeah Care about spider-man's marriage who's even married to Mary Jane, okay?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway, it's.
Speaker 0: it's so stupid.
Speaker 0: Even the underwear perverts don't like it like if there's a poll on you know that's the comic nerd news website.
Speaker 0: That's like do you think this was good, and it's like nine thousand.
Speaker 0: This is the worst thing ever like a hundred.
Speaker 0: This is great.
Speaker 0: so I Just want to point out that I really think this has revealed to me the fundamental problem with the underwear pervert comics Especially the ones that tend to be in the US Marvel DC that go on forever and ever and ever and ever
Speaker 1: Writing bad plot run out of stuff to do.
Speaker 0: no.
Speaker 0: It's that they have a status quo, right?
Speaker 0: you know this is what spider-man is.
Speaker 0: he's this and he's this and he's this right.
Speaker 0: and you really can't tell a story right with any drama or excitement or or Suspense or anything.
Speaker 0: you can't have any feeling in any sort of narrative without somehow threatening the status quo.
Speaker 0: and Years they change.
Speaker 0: the status quo is there was one girlfriend and then she actually died and then his friends died and then he got married.
Speaker 0: in the status quo change and change and change right.
Speaker 0: and But then you know once the status quo got to it's been in like one place for a long time now and all the stories All they all the stories ever do is change the status quo change it back change it change it back again change it change it back Again, so now because they've run out of things to do they went back to the original status quo of like 1960 whatever And pretty much every underwear pervert story you look at is change it go bring it back Superman.
Speaker 0: Remember they killed Superman in like the 90s.
Speaker 0: now Superman is just fine.
Speaker 0: Batman at one point like Batman broke his back.
Speaker 0: It was in a wheelchair.
Speaker 0: now Batman's just fine.
Speaker 0: You know Robin leaves they bring in a new Robin.
Speaker 0: Robin dies like a new Rob.
Speaker 1: I think what they Bank on here and I remember recognizing this as a kid This is one of the reasons I'd never wanted to read Underwear pervert comics was that I'd look and every time someone told me about a comic or they were excited about comic books And they like something happened.
Speaker 1: It would always be something like oh, man You won't believe what they did to Cyclops this time.
Speaker 0: And meanwhile now Cyclops just fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Jean Grey dead and alive.
Speaker 1: They're just fine later.
Speaker 1: It's that it seems like all that Matt like people were just like oh my god, so and so got Married to so-and-so and it wasn't the writing it wasn't really the story It was just the actual.
Speaker 1: something happened and the thing that happened is the only thing everyone cared about.
Speaker 1: They rabble and rabble and rabble about it, and then they'd get rid of that thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz basically all the fans of these things.
Speaker 0: They're just Somehow mentally attached to these you know iconic characters for whatever reason and they just they care so much about these Characters more than they care about real human beings you know and anything that happens.
Speaker 0: There's character is a big deal even though they know that the characters will always return to the status quo.
Speaker 1: It's not like anime is any different.
Speaker 1: I'm our manga I mean.
Speaker 1: look at one piece and bleach and Naruto.
Speaker 1: you hear someone talk about what.
Speaker 1: oh, man So and so fought so and so and and so inside the hair.
Speaker 0: they do like it for the same reasons.
Speaker 0: But if you look at the plot of even something like Naruto right the plot doesn't stay at some status quo.
Speaker 0: It's continually moving forward incredibly slowly You know in tiny tiny bits you know.
Speaker 0: and it's like even though you see what's coming a mile away.
Speaker 0: It comes eventually at some point.
Speaker 0: You know and they keep moving around even Pokemon.
Speaker 0: eventually He's the Pokemon master.
Speaker 0: eventually you know.
Speaker 0: it does happen at some point You know.
Speaker 0: and then they don't go on and make him the Pokemon masters.
Speaker 0: They can do it again.
Speaker 0: They just keep moving forward incredibly slowly.
Speaker 0: So it never changes too much to throw the status quo off so much that people will go Oh, what is this bullshit?
Speaker 0: But they do keep moving forward.
Speaker 0: so at least it's a little bit better even when it's crap like Naruto, so uh Spider-man is no wait a minute.
Speaker 1: They were married.
Speaker 1: right yep, so Ha the rest of the world knew they were married.
Speaker 1: so does spider-man just not remember, but everyone else does.
Speaker 0: it's well You know I don't know.
Speaker 0: I I didn't actually read this comic Paperwork.
Speaker 1: there's all that paperwork that he got married with.
Speaker 1: it's still there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just.
Speaker 0: you know they just go bleh.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever It's a comic book, but I only read the summary on Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 0: I'm not actually reading this shit comic.
Speaker 1: see I think the whole that that quip is actually very Very illuminating into the some of the fundamental problems.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's just a comic book.
Speaker 1: alright We don't have to worry anymore.
Speaker 1: that explains that.
Speaker 0: yeah, I mean they just they don't.
Speaker 0: you know they don't bother with details like that.
Speaker 0: They just they have a thing they want to do and then they just find a way to do it.
Speaker 0: They don't.
Speaker 0: actually the thing is the guy who actually wrote the story Posted a thing like yeah, I let everyone know that I thought this was a dumb idea.
Speaker 0: But you know that's what they pay me for.
Speaker 0: so I did it And they're all blamed on the editor and the editors like yeah, I did it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what I wanted to do.
Speaker 1: bleh Man, if you want to read a comic book just read bone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so finally reading bone good all of it, and it's great.
Speaker 0: It's great.
Speaker 1: I always knew it was great.
Speaker 1: It's one of those things.
Speaker 1: I'd always see it and go oh, that's that bone thing.
Speaker 0: the problem is it's gross and things like that.
Speaker 0: What do you do?
Speaker 1: read them all and the way?
Speaker 1: I do that is by not reading anything else.
Speaker 0: what happens if you don't finish before and you die first?
Speaker 1: I think I'm doing doing okay, so fine.
Speaker 0: You're doing all right.
Speaker 1: I think by not watching bleach Naruto one piece TV or Spider Man or Spider Man I Only even saw the first spider-man movie.
Speaker 1: I liked it, but I heard the second one's good.
Speaker 1: I had the third one stupid Yeah, who knows?
Speaker 1: so ever speaking of spider-man The Japanese released the top 10 manga of 2007 according to a bunch of retailers.
Speaker 0: All right, so these are what retailers in Japan selling.
Speaker 0: tonka bond not we're not counting like shonen jump sales or anything.
Speaker 1: You know it's the anime news network, and they don't say and their source is in Japanese, so that doesn't help me.
Speaker 0: I think that's in a safe assumption We can make though if it's retailers And they're getting the individual manga titles cuz I mean if you counted shonen jumps How do you do that?
Speaker 0: you get a count everything in shonen jump once for every shonen jump sold.
Speaker 0: that doesn't yep?
Speaker 1: And then the problem there is that all right add the tonka bond on top of that all right?
Speaker 1: But anyway, they went through.
Speaker 1: it's like the book of the year action committee.
Speaker 1: I don't need to read the bottom of this but bunch of stars and the list is one piece Nana Nodama cantabile Naruto full metal alchemist hunter x hunter bleach D gray man Etc.
Speaker 0: and make sense I Don't know.
Speaker 1: I can't really.
Speaker 1: I don't think many of these are good.
Speaker 0: No, many of them are not good.
Speaker 1: hunter x hunter was particularly dumb.
Speaker 0: have you read the manga?
Speaker 0: I haven't.
Speaker 0: I've only seen like one episode of the anime.
Speaker 1: I've heard it's really dumb from more than one person who I trust I watched the first episode of D gray man anime.
Speaker 0: That was pretty dumb.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Nana's great, but One piece is on top of it.
Speaker 1: one piece is only good in theory.
Speaker 0: one one piece some of its good and most of it's Just fights now.
Speaker 1: I've heard Nodama cantabile is actually really good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is I want to read it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's about the girl in the music school or whatever.
Speaker 0: yeah, yeah, it's supposed to be good.
Speaker 1: so how's that Naruto Popular?
Speaker 0: I mean think about this though.
Speaker 0: right Dragon Ball is like the most popular manga there ever was you know and it oh Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: one piece.
Speaker 1: number 46 is number one.
Speaker 1: Nana number 18 is not individual volume.
Speaker 0: daruto 37 fma 17, okay Now I see what's going on here, I see what you did.
Speaker 0: that all right What everybody owns there.
Speaker 1: so I guess I have a question cuz I didn't actually read any of it.
Speaker 1: the Fullmetal Alchemist manga.
Speaker 0: It's average manga.
Speaker 1: is it better or worse than the show.
Speaker 0: It's just different.
Speaker 1: is it worth it?
Speaker 1: If you got time is it actually worth it.
Speaker 1: Are you still reading it?
Speaker 1: Are you gonna finish it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I sort of like it's weird cuz every time I pick up a volume.
Speaker 0: I sort of just start reading it.
Speaker 0: It's just like tee hee hee hee and I barely even remember like what happened in the previous volume And it doesn't really matter either.
Speaker 1: huh, I'm just curious cuz I honestly I realized just now that I just never even read it.
Speaker 1: I just didn't.
Speaker 0: yeah, I have all of it.
Speaker 0: That's in English.
Speaker 0: I'm just sort of buying it somewhat out of habit But it's I mean it's not bad.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: it's not something like you know.
Speaker 0: It's not a good quality.
Speaker 1: I'd number nine is a kata keo hits man reborn.
Speaker 0: That's actually really funny.
Speaker 0: Yes, it is I think is I don't know.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of those comedy mangas and things other than gog manga.
Speaker 0: vre.
Speaker 0: You know there's sort of like one hit.
Speaker 0: wonders is where it's like.
Speaker 0: I could watch an episode of hit man reborn Maybe two episodes or read one volume of the manga and reading a second volume of the manga would just not be funny anymore.
Speaker 0: It's like okay.
Speaker 0: I've seen the joke.
Speaker 0: It's over funny little hit man.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: I get it yep But then there was the gonna guide chibi Kara world which didn't even have any jokes.
Speaker 0: yeah I think it had insider jokes for gonna guy fans And that was it.
Speaker 1: but it had a plot which kind of took the thunder out of all of that.
Speaker 0: it sure did.
Speaker 1: So uh last bit of news here just to pan this out because our news is we're both kind of lame and super.
Speaker 1: Our choice is anime news network or make something up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's not.
Speaker 1: So a gog manga.
Speaker 1: vre is for the eighth year running the number one media in the world.
Speaker 1: yes But oh this will be real quick but I just want to point out that it's a new year and with the new year comes the new con season and The first con of the season for us every year is katsu khan.
Speaker 0: well starting last year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well yeah, I went to katsu khan for two years.
Speaker 1: before that I just got to.
Speaker 1: khan was my third favorite Khan.
Speaker 1: it is now my second favorite khan and it might someday become my first favorite.
Speaker 0: I might be my thing.
Speaker 0: it might have been the best khan last year Maybe.
Speaker 1: well it really helps katsu khan is that it's not better than Otakon.
Speaker 1: It's just different.
Speaker 0: It's better for us.
Speaker 1: cuz you know the most of that video game room if you are between the ages of 17 and 30 The katsu khan is probably the best anime khan for you to go to especially if you're between 21 and 100.
Speaker 1: Yes, because it has the I think even though I I don't care about it.
Speaker 0: no,
Speaker 1: but the most important thing is that the bar at the khan is really classy and If you want if you're one of those people who's single and is going to anime cons you want to meet people You can go into the bar and basically be guaranteed to not break laws.
Speaker 1: Yep Anyway, katsu khan as you know is the khan where we do a lot of shit.
Speaker 1: to put it lightly I mean pretty much kinetic.
Speaker 1: how do we do a million panels and katsu khan?
Speaker 1: We kind of started high and are ramping it up every year.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So katsu khan is February 15 16 and 17. it's coming up pretty quick.
Speaker 0: If you already haven't if you haven't got a hotel already I don't think you're gonna the overflow hotel as Room still.
Speaker 1: however the overflow hotel you have to go over a bridge and the bridge sucks.
Speaker 1: But I'd be worried.
Speaker 0: but getting a badge is not difficult to this con.
Speaker 1: It might be worth it though I can tell you this.
Speaker 1: gig nights.
Speaker 1: We've announced in the forums.
Speaker 1: You can see the schedule there.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna read all of our events, but we are doing at least seven events at Katsu khan.
Speaker 0: we have rocked houses before.
Speaker 0: we have never rocked a house quite so hard as the katsu khan house will be rocked Pretty much Friday night from nine o'clock to one in the morning is all geek nights.
Speaker 0: Oh no and Saturday night Great.
Speaker 1: This is gonna be epic.
Speaker 0: Yes, it's in DC in the hotel.
Speaker 0: I forget the name of It's in a hotel in DC.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just katsu khan.
Speaker 1: Google it go to it.
Speaker 1: It's a great khan.
Speaker 1: Yep, pretty much if you live anywhere near DC, you have no excuse to not go for at least one day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's just go Saturday.
Speaker 0: if you live near, you know You know.
Speaker 1: and if you uh, well now go Friday because Friday night is when the biggest business will happen Okay, I thought Saturday night would be the biggest business.
Speaker 1: Well, Friday night is our biggest business.
Speaker 0: Okay, sure We're gonna get there Thursday and leave Monday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that like that.
Speaker 1: Anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: now some of you might be cool enough to already be listening to this band But if you're not here we go.
Speaker 1: So, um, you like Freddie Mercury.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a good artist you think yeah maybe was was a good artist maybe greatest live rock singer ever Possibly possibly.
Speaker 1: Well, uh, there is in fact a band and a singer that while they're not quite Freddie Mercury level they're very reminiscent of Freddie Mercury.
Speaker 0: I don't really think so.
Speaker 1: a lot of the songs are.
Speaker 1: one of the songs is a pretty much straight-up tribute to fat bottom girls.
Speaker 0: I don't know just cuz it has a similar subject.
Speaker 0: It's not really a similar song.
Speaker 0: nor does the guy Quite give me a Freddie Mercury vibe.
Speaker 1: Have you listen to all their music?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, there you go But it just so happens that the one I'm linking to is not quite the perfect example of that.
Speaker 0: However this uh This music video is pretty hot and I'm going to video is awesome regardless of how close it really it resembles Freddie Mercury or not.
Speaker 1: I am going to piss off Darryl Surratt and say that this music video is Definitely super flat.
Speaker 1: Oh, this is super flat.
Speaker 1: It is super flat.
Speaker 1: It's more yellow submarine Yeah, but it's too well animated and it's super flat.
Speaker 0: yellow submarine as well animated not as well as this.
Speaker 1: there were no computers back then.
Speaker 1: Okay This is pretty terrific and you should see it.
Speaker 1: if you can find a non YouTube version somewhere or I don't know any sort of Non-utubified thing because there's a lot going on in the animation that YouTube really can't show you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but regardless watching it in YouTube is still okay because this music video is probably in my top 10 now You can probably bit torn or something, right?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it's out there.
Speaker 0: I might think of the day.
Speaker 0: initial D The arcade game, you know it it exists.
Speaker 0: There have been four versions of this game version one kind of blab version.
Speaker 0: two kind of blab version.
Speaker 1: three amazing Version four even more amazing than version three if you thought that if you didn't think that was possible Yep, I think I talked about that a little bit when I was when I went back to Rochester for that weekend.
Speaker 1: I went to hammer girl and sure enough The initial D machine was a lot bigger and had LCDs and when I tried to do my classic Go down the mountain real fast.
Speaker 1: I crashed into every single wall because it was completely different.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I think it might be you know, if not already quickly approaching being I guess, you know I guess I assume there'll be a five and a six and whatever the greatest arcade racing game there is and I don't mean You know physically in the arcade even though that is also true I mean arcade style as in the style of driving is arcade style.
Speaker 0: driving which means a virtue erasing may be dethroned or maybe not but regardless in Japan the land of all the greatest things in the world that never go anywhere else They have made a special version a limited release of initial d4.
Speaker 0: it's the same game that you would play initial d4 in your local arcade, but it's the special edition.
Speaker 0: and Well, you will see in this video Exactly why this is a special edition of initial d4 not the regular edition.
Speaker 1: if I am ever Idly wealthy to the point where I just live a life of decadent powdered decadence I will purchase some sort of device similar to what Scott is going to show you in this video.
Speaker 0: I'll just let you watch the video on your own.
Speaker 1: This is a epic.
Speaker 0: even if you don't like initial D and you don't care about cars or racing video games.
Speaker 0: You should see this just as an example of that's how Japan does it and the u.s.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Doesn't do that.
Speaker 0: That's why they suck Oh Scott.
Speaker 1: I would just like to point out that the BBC Talks at length in two different articles about how Mika is in fact the reincarnation of Freddie Mercury whatever and apparently He recorded something recently on Freddie Mercury's piano Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Yes, Freddie Mercury had more than one piano.
Speaker 1: Well one of Freddie Mercury's pianos.
Speaker 0: I'll have to go look into this cuz I don't see.
Speaker 1: I think you should listen to more of his music before you say anything maybe.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, so, uh, we haven't talked about anime in a while.
Speaker 1: Have we not so much.
Speaker 0: No, we haven't watched any anime.
Speaker 0: This is what the hell are we gonna do?
Speaker 1: Well, I guess it works out that we've been reading a lot of comics.
Speaker 1: suddenly I guess it's comic season.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're making up for back in the day when used to hundred anime shows and no comic shows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the real problem is the only show I'm excited about now is bacchanal and I haven't watched enough of it.
Speaker 0: Maybe we should like Netflix one of those shows that you know from back like maybe the ergo proxy or something Did that finish coming out?
Speaker 1: I assume so I did genie on.
Speaker 0: is they're going out of business?
Speaker 0: prevent that?
Speaker 1: I really.
Speaker 1: I got to watch the rest of that show because I really like that show.
Speaker 1: and the thing is I Remember ergo proxy was coming out or watching it and I got to the point I'm like, wow, I'm suddenly bored with this.
Speaker 1: if the next episode doesn't Kick it into high gear.
Speaker 1: I'm done.
Speaker 1: And then the next episode kicked it up into high gear and I was hooked again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I checked the Netflix for that.
Speaker 0: Maybe we can watch it.
Speaker 1: See the thing is what are we gonna watch?
Speaker 1: the Netflix?
Speaker 1: We you know what the next anime in the queue is.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Kazu no yo Jimbo.
Speaker 0: That's a good one Which I saw.
Speaker 0: four episodes and they were good.
Speaker 1: and you know what's in the queue right now.
Speaker 1: You know what's sitting in front of the Mac right now?
Speaker 1: Yeah, gankotsu.
Speaker 1: Oh the last is that we still haven't watched.
Speaker 0: No Alright Well this weekend, you know, we're not doing anything.
Speaker 1: You know, maybe it's like the more of things we do at anime cons the less anime we watch.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling that if we start doing like main events at Otakon, we'll never watch anime again.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's kind of like an RIT the more we did with the anime club the less anime we watched.
Speaker 1: and pretty much if you grabbed like Level in the anime club hierarchy versus amount of anime watched the limit at infinity is zero and such.
Speaker 0: Yeah you think that like you go to anime con.
Speaker 0: right and there's the people at the top of the con like the con chairs and The guests in the the industry people right?
Speaker 0: These are the big people.
Speaker 0: right lots of access lots of everything.
Speaker 0: and then there's the lowly fan who's poor.
Speaker 0: They're a high school kid, right?
Speaker 0: That little high school kid.
Speaker 0: He might be all jealous of those people at the way top but little does he know.
Speaker 0: that little high school kid is watching a thousand Times more anime than the con chair has watched all year.
Speaker 1: I remember when I ran the RIT anime club.
Speaker 1: I didn't even like.
Speaker 1: we just put on anime.
Speaker 1: We'd show people anime and I would pretty much stand there in the back of the room after the anime started make sure nothing blew Up and then after the music videos played I'd leave because I had anime club work to do and it sucked.
Speaker 0: Yep, the people are making all this stuff happen are actually doing work and that's why you know everyone thinks Oh and I work on video games.
Speaker 0: I'll get to play video games.
Speaker 0: all they know.
Speaker 0: you will actually play almost no video games if you work in video games.
Speaker 1: In fact at best you'll play one video game that you're already sick of every day.
Speaker 0: If your job is writing comic books You will end up reading almost no comic books compared to just being a fan that this is the reality of geekdom get with it Understand it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, what anime let's?
Speaker 0: because we haven't watched anime recently But we have to do an anime show because it's mostly been comics lately.
Speaker 0: Let us talk about a show of anime from the olden days.
Speaker 0: All right, let's talk about Escaflowne but I haven't why I gotta watch that again cuz I forget it.
Speaker 1: All right, let's talk about dragon half.
Speaker 0: We could.
Speaker 0: I need a little bit reminder.
Speaker 1: I Think we talked about Ava.
Speaker 1: No, have we ever actually talked about cowboy bebop, you know, huh?
Speaker 0: It looks like we got a lot of enemies to talk about.
Speaker 1: I don't know I feel like a lot of those I want to hold off on but then again That was one of the reasons why anime world order avoided doing all those shows for so long.
Speaker 0: and I'll tell you what.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you what.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, never mind.
Speaker 0: See here's the thing.
Speaker 0: is I just?
Speaker 0: this is sort of off topic.
Speaker 0: I'm delaying the main bit here, but I Downloaded all those Lucasarts adventure games.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's what we need right now.
Speaker 1: You need to give me full throttle and grim fandango instead of anime, right?
Speaker 0: And I was just thinking well, you know what?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna do it.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna take those Ava discs and watch them on the train and we'll be done with it and we can do it.
Speaker 0: and Now I'm gonna be playing adventure game.
Speaker 1: sorry Okay, at least Ava went to one thing.
Speaker 1: it's still winter and I would like to point out that woman it's cold.
Speaker 1: it's cold but Maybe cuz I think Kate has never actually seen Ava.
Speaker 1: I think we got to have one of those old-school anime marathons like days of yore.
Speaker 0: But I was just thinking recently like yesterday if they're because you're looking at Lord of the Rings on the go I would much rather watch all three Lord of the Rings movies because I've only seen some of them like twice.
Speaker 1: I've only seen the third one once.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, but I've seen the third one three times.
Speaker 1: I've seen the first one three times.
Speaker 0: So the first one two times and the second one one and a half time.
Speaker 1: Why don't we just watch Star Wars?
Speaker 0: Because I've seen each of those 25 times each but I need to make it to 30 each.
Speaker 0: I'm just making I just make it up numbers But I'm probably not far off.
Speaker 1: Then we'll watch snatch followed by attack the gas station.
Speaker 0: I've seen attack the gas nation.
Speaker 0: I think seven times.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure that.
Speaker 0: okay, so We need an anime.
Speaker 0: What do we talk about?
Speaker 1: we talked about a while ago of slayers because this TV series because surprisingly copy rezo Scott had Never seen slayers.
Speaker 0: I saw like an episode or two.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it was one of my favorite shows.
Speaker 1: So we we got it.
Speaker 1: We watched it all back when we had no responsibilities and infinite money.
Speaker 1: You know those days are long gone.
Speaker 0: Copy rezo.
Speaker 1: God Slayer still wins the award for one one.
Speaker 1: It has a character who pretty much right away takes a sweat drop and beat someone over the head with it.
Speaker 1: Yep And to when the evil bad guy at the in like the climactic part is doing his ritual and the good guys come to stop Him he just runs away into another room locks the door and finishes the ritual immediately.
Speaker 0: I love that part.
Speaker 0: That's how it's got to go down.
Speaker 0: villains.
Speaker 0: learn none of the Sharks lasers shit.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: If you're gonna set off a bomb or send a drill to the middle of the earth or fire a laser at the moon Fucking push the goddamn button immediately as soon as you can because otherwise it ain't gonna happen.
Speaker 1: But we talked about the slayers TV show, I don't think we talked a lot about the OAVs.
Speaker 0: and okay Here's the thing with slayers right if you watch slayers slayers next or slayers try.
Speaker 0: these are TV series.
Speaker 0: They have a lot of episodes, right?
Speaker 0: They follow the story adventures of Lena inverse and her companions gallery and zellows and Amelia Amelia, Prince Phil, Prince Phil and such and such.
Speaker 0: it is a D&D adventuring party plus mostly comedy Going around fighting villains, you know having inns get destroyed, etc.
Speaker 0: Right, but there are also slayers OAVs and slayers movies and the slayers OAVs and slayers movies are also about Lena inverse but they are not about Zellows or Amelia or gallery or any of those other characters.
Speaker 0: They're basically not even there.
Speaker 1: This is from way before she met any of those people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she was paddling around with Naga the white serpent.
Speaker 0: Naga the serpent.
Speaker 0: Are you gonna make the laugh?
Speaker 1: I don't think I can.
Speaker 0: I think I've got something like this.
Speaker 0: I Can't do it.
Speaker 1: The thing is, you know these people it's the Fujiko laugh.
Speaker 1: It's there.
Speaker 1: There are so many evil women in anime with with like the finger next to the mouth and they make that laugh.
Speaker 0: She's one of those Laughter and she has giant boobs which aren't there for perverted reasons.
Speaker 1: They're there for fun unless you read the manga.
Speaker 0: if you read the manga that they're for perverted reasons.
Speaker 0: But then again the manga also uses Lena inverses non-existent breasts for you know perverted reasons.
Speaker 0: You know all the animations.
Speaker 0: they take the breasts and they keep them there and use them for comedic reasons.
Speaker 0: It's like in manga perverted jokes about tiny breasts.
Speaker 0: Anime hilarious jokes about tiny breasts.
Speaker 0: I mean actually the way how they did it.
Speaker 1: the way I would describe it is thusly if you watch the slayers TV shows They're really funny But there's a story and it's kind of like it kind of edges into serious territory And it never times that time.
Speaker 1: it never gets all the way serious But it gets real close and there's moments where you forget it's a comedy and you get really into it.
Speaker 1: You're like, oh man, and then suddenly something stupid happens.
Speaker 1: and oh crap slayers Adventure story.
Speaker 0: but in the parts of the adventure story where there isn't great tension and great immediate evil and stuff like that They as the plot progresses they toss in jokes and that's how it.
Speaker 1: that's why I know granted It has the syndrome where you know a lot of shows rollercoaster between really funny and really serious And they kind of skirt a lot like Fullmetal Alchemist did that a lot.
Speaker 1: Yep, like our mom's dead.
Speaker 1: Oh, he's really short.
Speaker 0: Yeah Slayers doesn't do that so bad.
Speaker 1: Well, it gets.
Speaker 1: it does that more and more as you fought like slayers next is more serious than slayers, but also funnier layers.
Speaker 1: try is Really really really goofy at times and yet at the same time it goes so far into serious territory that you really don't Know what you're watching, but then instead of gradually coming back into funny They pretty much will give you the plot of an epic anime and then Effectively ruin it suddenly with a really lame joke.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it still works though today.
Speaker 0: We're gonna talk about specifically.
Speaker 0: I think you want it.
Speaker 0: We're gonna talk about slayers the movie slayers the motion picture the slayers movie period.
Speaker 0: if there's more than one slayers movie We're talking about the first one.
Speaker 1: This is the one, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's called slayers the motion picture.
Speaker 0: That's what it's called.
Speaker 1: This was.
Speaker 1: I mean if anyone in America talks about the slayers movie they're talking about this now.
Speaker 1: the slayers OAVs and movies especially the OAVs are a lot like this.
Speaker 1: They have a different feel a different tone a different theme and it is not.
Speaker 1: it's Lena the same character you know and love but I don't know.
Speaker 1: everything's kind of Goofier a little more perverted a little funnier, but not it's not really funny or just a different kind of funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it there isn't so much serious action going on because you're only gonna you know, it's gonna be over so quickly.
Speaker 0: They just sort of tell as many jokes as they can and cuz naga the serpent there.
Speaker 0: She's pretty much only useful for comedy except for that.
Speaker 0: You know, it's basically.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like a buddy movie, you know You know, it's one of those instead of a party adventure.
Speaker 0: It's sort of a buddy tale where you know, I'm the good guy trying to save the day whatever and funny shit happens to me.
Speaker 0: Oh, but there's this bitch who comes along and fucks with me and makes fun of me and I fight with her.
Speaker 0: But in the end when the real villain comes along we team up and then we make fun of each other again.
Speaker 0: the end.
Speaker 1: Now the slayers motion picture that we're talking about kind of skirts the line between the OAVs and the show because the OAVs I mean, I think my favorite one is slayers gorgeous, which uh, let's say the giant golems.
Speaker 1: It is not the most plotacular Anime, it's also pretty short But the motion picture is goony and funny and in fact I'll get to this but it's actually super full of all these inside jokes.
Speaker 1: a lot of them I think are actually dub specific but there's a lot of kind of anime industry crossover inside jokes in the slayers like
Speaker 0: all the octopuses
Speaker 1: or the slime path or or Joyrock but At the same time the plot of the slayers movie comedy aside Is actually really kind of touching and sad and well done and it's it's kind of this Two-headed beast where it's a really fun movie.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you this the plot here that rim thinks is so touching.
Speaker 1: It has touching moments.
Speaker 0: I gotta say ready They're stuck on this island.
Speaker 0: and it's why?
Speaker 1: why are they at this island?
Speaker 0: I forget doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: Alright, so this movie actually this movie kind of opens the way.
Speaker 1: a lot of those like we have this show and it's super popular.
Speaker 1: We're gonna make the high-budget Movie.
Speaker 1: it has the set.
Speaker 1: actually actually watching the beginning of it I felt a lot like when I watch those Sailor Moon movies back in the day just in terms of Obviously, they're just having this high-budget thing.
Speaker 1: Check it out.
Speaker 1: Oh, look, it's Lena inverse.
Speaker 1: We're gonna have her come on screen in the epic way that you all expect and then we're gonna start the movie.
Speaker 1: Yep, and Long story short stuff happens and then her and Naga go on this kind of discount trip to a hot spring on an island.
Speaker 0: Alright the hot spring yes me pros island I think it's me pros Island it.
Speaker 1: well you realize that it's just promise.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know Oh, that was a spoiler.
Speaker 1: In the ancient language of the elves the word me pros means a promise to be kept.
Speaker 0: Yes Anyway on this island they are you know, there's inns exploding and there's a problem with octopuses and all sorts of other things going on.
Speaker 0: But primarily they get accosted by the fifth strongest man on the island.
Speaker 1: I believe I am the fourth strongest man on me pros Island.
Speaker 0: Yes, and well, you know you wonder huh?
Speaker 0: He's the fifth strongest man.
Speaker 0: Who's the first strongest man?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: and apparently all these different strongest men of the island are all working for you know The first strongest man or you assume so and you know They fight the fifth strongest man and the fourth and then third and a second and then eventually Surprise it's the first.
Speaker 0: and what who the first is is the way it's revealed I think is incredibly well done and It's foreshadowed in one of those in one of those clever ways where the foreshadowing was there all along.
Speaker 0: You saw it all along.
Speaker 0: There's no way you could have known but as soon as they reveal you think back and you give them the finger Who the first strongest man on me pros out is see the thing is this movie?
Speaker 1: The tone is just so different from every other slayers thing and that it's it's kind of got this cut like.
Speaker 1: there's this Undercurrent where the show is goonie and for the first half of this movie It is just they show up and these guys appear and this little whiny guy And then this big bustly guy goes I'm the fifth strongest man on me pros Island and then they fight and then there's sea cucumbers and it's explosion
Speaker 0: and it's
Speaker 1: just dumb and crazy.
Speaker 1: but yet There's all these like quiet Eerie moments and it's just undercurrent of.
Speaker 1: there's actually something bad going on here.
Speaker 1: There's something serious in this movie.
Speaker 1: There's something not quite right and I don't know.
Speaker 0: islands has an evil secret And it's not just oh.
Speaker 1: the evil secret is the plot in.
Speaker 0: the evil secret is actually, you know There's a lot of those cliche like one-shot adventure plots where oh, there's a mysterious dungeon There's a curse on a item or whatever and this is one of those plots.
Speaker 0: But it's actually not cheesy like it would be easy to make it cheesy But it's actually.
Speaker 0: it's not a bad little one-shot adventure plot It's it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: And also they the way they resolve it.
Speaker 1: in the end it actually it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: It's not like oh, well, this changes the can of slayers and all that but they definitely Introduce An element I don't want to really spoil because this movie is really worth watching.
Speaker 1: But it involves gallery's magic sword and maybe his family's lineage in some way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: it's one of those things where you know.
Speaker 0: It's like if you have seen other slayers, then you can sort of like take this hint and maybe you know Infer something about it.
Speaker 0: Like maybe they're trying to say something.
Speaker 0: maybe it's sort of like an inside joke And if you don't get the inside joke, it doesn't really take away from it at all.
Speaker 0: You don't even notice, you know, you just kind of like oh dude to do.
Speaker 1: But really this movie despite all the dumb humor is actually it really has this kind of.
Speaker 0: it Feels like a serious movie even though you know It's not is a above average classic anime movie that any anime fan should see.
Speaker 1: It's also really kind of.
Speaker 1: it's very slow paced and very just kind of Atmospheric and just.
Speaker 0: it is slow paced but then it's also not long.
Speaker 0: It's it's kind of weird.
Speaker 0: It's like you won't.
Speaker 0: if you watch this movie You won't feel like you were sitting there for a very long time But you'll feel like you saw a lot in a very short amount of time, but nothing feels hurried.
Speaker 0: It's a I can't really imagine it doing it much better than that.
Speaker 1: Now one thing a lot of people really seem to remember from this movie and I just I see it all the time maybe not so much now, but Being an anime fan and you know the late 90s and all that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: when this movie was you know Slayers was big for a long time.
Speaker 1: and now I realize a lot of people Haven't seen slayers don't even know what it is or they vaguely like they see it they go.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's that slayers thing, but no one really watches it.
Speaker 1: and a lot of people really don't remember this movie, but The song they play at the end of this movie for some reason I remember it being kind of a big deal.
Speaker 1: like every anime fan loved this song and listen to it all the time and It was just midnight blue, you know, Megumi Hashibara.
Speaker 1: She's all a million.
Speaker 1: She did all the slayers music pretty much Except that one god-awful in English song from Valgaav in slayers tribe My baby.
Speaker 1: you don't know how much I love you me.
Speaker 1: I love you.
Speaker 0: Okay, and I don't remember that song.
Speaker 1: No, I played that song for you.
Speaker 0: Don't play it for me again.
Speaker 0: Sounds bad Sounds very bad But the movie.
Speaker 1: actually if you don't want to watch the movie, you don't get what I haven't seen it You don't get like oh what.
Speaker 1: how could it be this?
Speaker 1: Slow-paced serious movie and yet it's full of explosions and I'm the fourth strongest man on me.
Speaker 1: pros Island secret cucumber smash.
Speaker 1: Listen to that song and that song kind of really sums up the mood of this movie.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Well, I just looked it up.
Speaker 0: You can get the digitally remastered in 5.1 version of the slayers motion picture for $18 in Amazon.
Speaker 0: All right, that is totally worth it, but it's four dollars and eighty cents for a used coffee.
Speaker 1: That is Also totally worth it.
Speaker 0: Yes, very much.
Speaker 0: So I mean no reason not to get this one and you can Netflix it for sure.
Speaker 1: It's not the greatest movie ever made it's no Akira It's no.
Speaker 0: me is.
Speaker 1: a lot of my enjoyment of this movie is definitely nostalgia And also just my love of slayers and wanting to see more slayers because I've seen.
Speaker 1: yeah I think here's I can see.
Speaker 0: I think you're really.
Speaker 0: I don't know if this should be the first slayers you ever watch.
Speaker 0: I think you should watch some other slayers before you add to the Slayer.
Speaker 1: But then again this was for a lot of people in our generation the first layers that they saw because it was marketed.
Speaker 1: It was marketed heavily and a lot of people Oh the slayers movie and they'd see a slayers movie and then they'd see a pile of VHS tapes and they we were poor and it was like 30 bucks for four episodes of a subtitled anime.
Speaker 1: Yep, so they just buy the movie and watch that.
Speaker 1: and there were.
Speaker 0: there were slayers you could watch first.
Speaker 0: You can watch that slayers gorgeous first.
Speaker 0: That's not a good first slayers.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, it's not.
Speaker 0: but there's also better first layers.
Speaker 0: I think you should at least start watching the TV show a little bit like maybe four episodes.
Speaker 0: at least then you can watch this Movie because you'd understand the character is.
Speaker 0: now it's going.
Speaker 1: this is one of those movies were really I mean I think everyone should see eskaflowne and cowboy bebop and slayers and all these you know, just important shows.
Speaker 1: and the OAVs of slayers are really only for people who really like the humor of slayers and That sort of thing and really like these OAVs because they're goonie and they're silly.
Speaker 1: But I think the
Speaker 0: only reason that it really shouldn't be the first slayers you watch is because a lot of the jokes like Exploding ins and stuff, you know They only happen once or twice in the movie and you'd only laugh at them as hard as you should If you knew that.
Speaker 0: yeah, that's a slayers in Joe.
Speaker 0: It's a trope.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It's a trope of slayers.
Speaker 0: So you have to watch the TV show to get the tropes that you see.
Speaker 0: you can laugh at them in the movie Plus the movie really?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I Don't know what I was even gonna say there.
Speaker 0: Awesome Slayers movie me pros Island High quality if nothing else.
Speaker 1: It's one of those kind of not.
Speaker 1: it's not like a revolutionary anime movie.
Speaker 1: Important because it was a very popular and very well-known movie when it came out.
Speaker 1: and I feel like if you are Someone who wants to have seen that, you know the full breadth of everything that there is anime out there.
Speaker 1: There aren't a lot of anime movies that are like this.
Speaker 1: This movie kind of stands out among the many anime movies out there.
Speaker 0: It's kind of strange.
Speaker 0: Like if I if I just sort of Think in my brain what other anime movie was like this I don't come up with any but if I feel in my gut.
Speaker 0: it feels like every anime movie is like this and yet They're not and it's.
Speaker 1: I don't know why that is.
Speaker 0: I don't know But maybe that's why it's so great.
Speaker 0: It's like this is the core of the awesomeness.
Speaker 0: That was the anime Feeling that we had when we got into anime like 98 99.
Speaker 0: Yes, this movie definitely you will feel the Night the late 90s anime fan nostalgia Yep, and if you weren't an anime fan in the late 90s watch this and you'll see what it was like to be an anime fan In the late 90s.
Speaker 0: and the dub ain't so bad.
Speaker 1: Well, no, I mean the dub.
Speaker 1: this was Lisa Ortiz.
Speaker 1: She was you know Yeah, yeah, she was on our magic game.
Speaker 1: She's really awesome.
Speaker 0: But Titles are probably a little bit better.
Speaker 0: But you know, the dub isn't a bad dub.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is this and I think we've said this before a lot but dubs from this era We're not technically as good as dubs today.
Speaker 1: But at the same time even though they weren't as accurate and they weren't as technically well done and there were problems with them I feel like in the end they were a lot better than the dubs of today on average and not It's definitely not the nostalgia talking I think there was I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think that partly just because a lot of the people who were doing the dubs back then were kind of into the Anime that certain groups of dub actors just they got into the spirit of it And it felt like they had a lot more fun making these dubs than some people now have making dubs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe you should just watch both.
Speaker 0: I mean it's a fun enough movie.
Speaker 0: I've seen it multiple times.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've seen it dubbed.
Speaker 1: I've seen it sobbed.
Speaker 1: I the the sob is technically better But the dub has a lot of heart and I think a lot of new anime Has a lot of different jokes - yes, it does.
Speaker 1: There's a. the dub has some Late 90s anime inside jokes that you may or may not pick up on.
Speaker 0: It's it's worth it though.
Speaker 0: Alright, we got anything else to say?
Speaker 1: I'm going to bed.
Speaker 1: There's the last picture.
Speaker 1: the last of the Visigoths left our house as This morning as I was going to work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it's time to get some sleep.
Speaker 1: All right This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio.
Speaker 0: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.