Speaker 0: It's Tuesday June 10th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: Tuesday tonight We talk about Super Dodgeball and Super Dodgeball brawlers.
Speaker 1: Let's do this So as soon as we start doing the show Twice a week because you know we're sort of running out of things to talk about losing steam.
Speaker 1: No, I think the steam bucket fills up crazy.
Speaker 0: that just proves what I'd suspect it all along.
Speaker 0: It's not that we're running out of things to talk about far be it.
Speaker 0: That's not even like.
Speaker 0: that's not even on the table.
Speaker 0: as one of the reasons why we had to slow down the show temporarily.
Speaker 0: I think it's just that we don't have enough time to be awake enough to do the show the way we'd want if we continue to do it four nights a week, but Because we're doing it at this reduced schedule now.
Speaker 0: I still have all the stuff I want to say, but I don't have enough shows to say it in.
Speaker 1: It's definitely kind of just.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's ironic or not, but we haven't done a show in six days Which I think is the longest.
Speaker 1: it's like rain on your wedding day yeah, as long as stretch of no shows and quite a very long time and Suddenly we've got mocha to talk about we've got iphones to talk about we've got shit all over the place.
Speaker 1: That's happening everywhere in all of geekdom.
Speaker 1: I think we've only got two shows and none of them.
Speaker 1: we really needed a Monday show, but we didn't have one.
Speaker 0: I think what it really proves Is that the only thing preventing geek nights from being four nights a week is the fact that we have day jobs.
Speaker 1: Yes, that could be true.
Speaker 0: geek nights was somehow my job.
Speaker 0: You can bet that there would be like ten shows a week.
Speaker 1: I don't know ten shows, but there will be four geek night shows and maybe other shows in addition Shows.
Speaker 1: one of them would be right.
Speaker 1: there are ten nights.
Speaker 1: We can't do ten geek nights.
Speaker 1: Okay, I mean unless suddenly we add you know the three extra days to the week.
Speaker 1: You know Scott day Scott or day and Caturday.
Speaker 0: Caturday's already a day.
Speaker 0: it comes after Friday and before Friday.
Speaker 0: Okay Anyway, so I have another quick announcement.
Speaker 0: We'll have a lot more about this in the upcoming weeks, and I don't know months.
Speaker 0: It's not like it's exactly on the near horizon But we've said before and we're saying again geek nights is going to the penny arcade expo in Seattle this summer.
Speaker 1: We're going no matter what we will be there Maybe just cuz.
Speaker 0: I've been dealing with emails and stuff a lot lately But I almost said penny arcade is coming to geek nights, then I realized that that is not in any way true.
Speaker 0: I wish that was true But no we're good.
Speaker 0: not only we're going to be at PAX And I'm going to talk a lot more about this once we confirm a few of the special details that are not quite public yet.
Speaker 0: But we're not just going to PAX as rim and Scott We're going to fax as rim and Scott VIPs because we're totally running a panel.
Speaker 1: awesome.
Speaker 1: one panel gets you VIP status.
Speaker 1: That's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: You know I got to say penny arcade the most professional professional conventions in terms of dealing with us as like guests or as Staff or as talent or panelists or anything like that?
Speaker 0: Otakons way up there like they're really good at that and katsu khan is does a pretty good job.
Speaker 0: But the penny arcade expo has farmed away with the possible exception of the for-profit New York comic-con New York anime festival been the most professional in terms of their dealings with us.
Speaker 0: From what I'm feeling is that I think they're twice as professional as the New York and in festival comic-con now because there was It's a different kind date the New York comic-con anime fest and all that are like.
Speaker 0: we are Professional in the.
Speaker 0: we are making money off of this way and everything has to be perfect.
Speaker 1: But I mean you said they replied to the email like ten minutes.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: That's not.
Speaker 0: that's not necessarily a sign of professional.
Speaker 0: Yes, no because I can tell you this and like at IBM if you responded to an email right away And you did this all the time It was pretty much assumed that you weren't doing your real work, and we're just kind of dicking around in your office.
Speaker 1: This was usually true, but what if your job is email?
Speaker 0: No one's job is email.
Speaker 0: I get is if you're like you know Mention I'll tell you a little bit about IVM's corporate culture And it's I can't.
Speaker 0: this is not a an indictment of IBM because most large tech companies are like this.
Speaker 0: I Gained an average of 10 to 40 unread emails a day.
Speaker 0: now that doesn't mean I got 40 emails a day.
Speaker 0: That means all of the emails I got every day.
Speaker 0: 10 to 40 of them I did not read and that meant that they never got read.
Speaker 1: Wow, yeah, but I'm saying is that if you're say the panels person for a convention that only happens You know like one weekend out of the year.
Speaker 1: your primary work is mostly reading and writing emails And then you know other than that.
Speaker 1: It's like figuring things out on paper.
Speaker 0: I can say this this is the second time that a panel person has Responded to me with the phrase we would be honored.
Speaker 0: I am very happy about this, but now the panel We are running will involve Dungeons and Dragons in some way and other tabletop role-playing systems.
Speaker 0: but I'm going to be sparse on the details until we Finalize more of them.
Speaker 0: I'll leave it at that.
Speaker 0: We're going to be at penny arcade Expo in a big way, and I highly recommend you all be there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and since you won't have any tables or anything like that We're pretty much gonna run this panel and the rest of the time The packs is pretty much the only con in a live for a long time.
Speaker 0: We're not only will be able to see us do something But you'll have a chance of hanging out with us or talking to us for more than 30 seconds.
Speaker 1: Oh, and it's Labor Day weekend.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Oh, and it will probably gonna fly out like Wednesday night.
Speaker 1: So if anyone like Thursday wants to chill in Seattle, that's that's what we're gonna be doing.
Speaker 0: Yes, and to all the people who try to see us at all these anime cons like katsu khan and kinetic on It won't be like that where you're like see us running by and you yell.
Speaker 0: Hey, we'll actually have time to chill.
Speaker 1: Yep I don't know what else to say about it right now, except I'm excited.
Speaker 0: I've what I.
Speaker 1: except for now all the West Coast people can shut up cuz like hey we come to the West Coast.
Speaker 1: You can't say all the East Coast is too far.
Speaker 0: I can't come over Meanwhile to certain people who do a webcomic copped out of coming to Otacon and then don't really come to the East Coast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we're bringing it to.
Speaker 1: you went to the Baltimore comic-con a couple times.
Speaker 0: Whatever Baltimore comic-con would just be depressing.
Speaker 0: as much as I like comics just one room out of the whole.
Speaker 0: Being at the Baltimore Convention Center and not having the entire convention center would be frightening.
Speaker 1: It would quite be quite eerie I believe.
Speaker 0: not just that.
Speaker 0: the fact that you at Otacon and it's not just like it'd be sort of like.
Speaker 1: I imagine it's be Sort of like, you know Thursday reg at Otacon where it's sort of like activity in one area but the rest of the thing is like.
Speaker 0: But even Thursday reg at Otacon has like 10,000 people standing outside making a ruckus.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, they're outside but you know, it's like they're feeling in the convention center would be similar.
Speaker 0: see to me.
Speaker 0: I think being it at any convention at the BCC like that That's so small would be like when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: first of all, it's not worth the trip to Baltimore.
Speaker 0: Baltimore is not that far.
Speaker 1: It's still too far for a tiny convention.
Speaker 0: It's not really not much further.
Speaker 0: that actually is about the same distance all told is getting a Rochester.
Speaker 1: Hey Rochester is not worth it for a tiny convention either.
Speaker 0: No Toricon but that's that's.
Speaker 0: that's a very near and dear to our heart convention.
Speaker 0: Once I've been to almost all of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah I Founded the thing that eventually was gotten rid of and replaced by the thing that became Toricon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can say that much.
Speaker 0: but I think being it like the BCC on one of those small comms would be like when I Was a kid and I was at Cedar Point and I'd be in the fantasy land of.
Speaker 0: I am in roller coaster heaven but then I'd be at the top of the roller coaster and there's that kind of Moment of pause between when the click click click click click stops before you go over the edge When I'd look to my left and I'd see over Lake Erie all the normal people in the normal buildings working And the real world would like intrude into my happiness for that brief second.
Speaker 0: It's like it's like seeing the janitor when you're at an amusement park But the janitor is usually like in a costume or something depends on the amusement park.
Speaker 0: I guess Wildwood's janitors are usually well anyway We'll leave it at.
Speaker 0: that is we're in Canada suits, so I'm gonna get right into this.
Speaker 0: This is not my news, but I have to say something about this.
Speaker 0: We can now look at the cover for Soul Caliber 4 And I think Kotaku said it better than I ever could have said.
Speaker 0: rest in peace.
Speaker 0: Soul Caliber 1998 to 2008 wrong They actually the reason.
Speaker 1: now you I'm saying wrong which means you think I might disagree that Soul Caliber is dead.
Speaker 0: No, you're saying that it died long before.
Speaker 0: You are wise.
Speaker 0: I guess he got shy vote, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Soul Caliber 3 I mean some people say it's okay But I highly doubt that Soul Caliber 3 is anything like Soul Caliber 2.
Speaker 0: so as far as I'm concerned Soul Caliber 3 was not a bad game.
Speaker 0: It was just not better than 2.
Speaker 0: Yes, so I know people out there right now.
Speaker 1: We're going over image Scott.
Speaker 1: You don't know anything.
Speaker 0: You know what the majority people out there are going huh?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you need any proof of that go to any convention right?
Speaker 0: Katsucon was a good example.
Speaker 0: You'll see a lot more people playing Soul Caliber 2 than Soul Caliber 3.
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus Soul Caliber 3 didn't wasn't on.
Speaker 1: you know every system like 2 was which really actually hurt it in a ways.
Speaker 1: Yeah But Soul Caliber Soul edge the business Soul Caliber the business Soul Caliber on the Dreamcast the business Soul Caliber 2 Double business.
Speaker 0: one of them.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to say is the best the best 3d fighting game ever.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I'd say that because it's what's better.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: 3d fighting games See actually a three.
Speaker 1: it can't be one of those 3d fighting games like virtual fighter one that wasn't actually 3d.
Speaker 1: It just looked 3d.
Speaker 0: What about Bushido blade 3?
Speaker 1: Bushido blades not good And it's definitely not as good as Soul Caliber 2.
Speaker 0: Well one fuck you and two.
Speaker 0: but now the cover of Soul Caliber 4. alright It's got Darth Vader on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like it's.
Speaker 0: it is actually Darth Vader.
Speaker 1: Usually this is the kind of it's.
Speaker 1: it's weird, right?
Speaker 1: It's like when someone throws a character like that in there.
Speaker 0: if I was 14, no No, if I was 13, this would be the best like alright.
Speaker 0: So think about it.
Speaker 1: when they put link in there.
Speaker 1: Everyone was like hell's yeah And that sort of encouraged them to do that again, and they they basically went for they went straight for the throat.
Speaker 0: Know what they did in the in the immortal words of Rama Sharma.
Speaker 0: They they tried to do too much with it.
Speaker 1: they shared it.
Speaker 1: they basically we said well putting link in there worked.
Speaker 1: Let's just go for the biggest what guns we can now Darth Vader.
Speaker 1: You can't get much bigger guns than that.
Speaker 0: It's been a while.
Speaker 0: So I should probably explain the Rama Sharma.
Speaker 0: You tried to do too much with it.
Speaker 0: very briefly So at IBM, there's this awesome dude named Rama Sharma and I worked with him.
Speaker 0: He was awesome.
Speaker 0: He was Indian and he played tennis and he was all cool and I usually went to lunch with him in the eunuch Santa.
Speaker 0: but Whenever we play tennis or actually whatever anything was happening anytime someone obviously put did something that reeked of effort or Tried to do more than they probably should have tried to do.
Speaker 0: like, you know We're in a tennis match and I could have just hit it.
Speaker 0: I could have just hit it over the net but no I tried to slam it over the net and instead I slammed it into The net and lost the game.
Speaker 0: He would look at me and he put his finger out and he'd waggle it in my face and he'd say you know Your problem is.
Speaker 0: you see you you tried.
Speaker 0: you tried to do too much with it.
Speaker 0: If you had you done less you might have made it.
Speaker 0: but no you tried to do too much and I got the point And you lose.
Speaker 1: yep If you try to do a fancy move But it that causes you to fail in a situation where you could have pulled off the simple move that would have guaranteed non-failure.
Speaker 1: That is when you tried to do too much with it.
Speaker 0: So Darth Vader too much.
Speaker 1: That's too much basically I see.
Speaker 1: the thing is why didn't they realize right that in this whole caliber too when they threw in the extra characters That only people only like the link people hated the spawn and the whatever his face was right?
Speaker 0: And I was.
Speaker 0: why didn't they?
Speaker 0: was that more a product of the fact that link is so independently popular Coupled with the fact that it was like the first fighting game on the Gamecube?
Speaker 1: I think that might have had.
Speaker 1: there were there many factors the reasons why link was accepted and people were overjoyed at that inclusion.
Speaker 1: However, why didn't they just like, you know put out like a little focus group about this Darth Vader Yoda thing before they did it?
Speaker 0: It's it's one of those things where link is like.
Speaker 0: All right I kind of understand and it did work But it just even.
Speaker 0: when I heard that Darth Vader and Yoda were gonna be in Soul Calibur I didn't think it was a joke.
Speaker 0: I assumed it was a joke.
Speaker 0: I was absolutely sure that it was fake and then when it was until it was actually officially announced I did not even consider it.
Speaker 1: Well, that was that we talked about that for quite a while.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not your news.
Speaker 0: So anyway, the cover to Soul Calibur 4 is epically fail.
Speaker 1: It is quite the epic fail All right.
Speaker 0: Also the lightsaber should be cutting through that sword.
Speaker 0: Good God.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so anyway If we did a Monday show yesterday, you probably would have talked about iPhones and such for a long time.
Speaker 0: I'm probably gonna buy one.
Speaker 1: I'm probably going to also but more on that on a Monday My blackberry and I'm gonna get rid of it.
Speaker 0: I've had it for one like six months.
Speaker 1: That's all right.
Speaker 1: You didn't pay for it.
Speaker 1: now regardless I can talk about iPhones today because they announced many games for the new iPhones.
Speaker 1: you see and Let's see.
Speaker 1: They got the monkey ball.
Speaker 1: They got this other game called Pangeas some other.
Speaker 1: the company is Pangea software.
Speaker 1: They have a game called enigma and there's a game called chromag rally, right?
Speaker 1: And basically what's going on here?
Speaker 0: It chromags like the thing that ruined sliders.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Is that a sliders game?
Speaker 1: I think it's a racing game of like cavemen.
Speaker 1: You're like chromagnon.
Speaker 1: Ah, no, I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: I didn't look at it.
Speaker 1: All I see is the name here, right?
Speaker 1: but basically the iPhone is looking to be sort of a gaming platform right and How I think this is gonna go right is first of all, this is not competing with DS's and PSP's Even though the graphics look better than DS but a little less than PSP, right?
Speaker 1: This is not going competing in those marketplaces.
Speaker 1: What this is competing with right is not so much Games on other cell phones because people buy games for whatever cell phone they have right?
Speaker 1: It's competing for the developers of cell phone games.
Speaker 1: you see The people whose job it is to make cell phone games Right are going to choose to.
Speaker 1: instead of making a Java cell phone game They are going to choose instead to make an iPhone cell phone game or both.
Speaker 0: I choose you.
Speaker 1: All right, but the iPhone has features such as touchscreen and accelerometers where people are going to make iPhone cell phone games that are not going to work in any other phone and Thus all these developers of cell phone games spend their time making iPhone games.
Speaker 1: other cell phones won't have so many games.
Speaker 0: The iPhone will look pretty hot compared to those other cell phones Never mind the fact that I was sold that I could have the Cisco VPN and an SSH client.
Speaker 1: Yeah now here is here's one thing about the the iPhone games that sort of make me a little iffy here and I'm probably not gonna buy Any iPhone games even if some of them are pretty good, huh?
Speaker 1: Basically a lot of these games are using the accelerometers and the iPhones that you can sort of tilt it Right, and you might think that makes sense, especially for monkey ball the first game They showed.
Speaker 0: my one concern is much like trying to play certain games on the DS in public places.
Speaker 0: You either feel stupid or end up waggling around like an idiot.
Speaker 1: No, that's that's not my concern.
Speaker 1: No, my concern is that notice how the DS uses the touchscreen only whereas the Wii has the waggling All right.
Speaker 1: If you put the waggling in the DS this problem happens and that while you waggle You're actually waggling the screen at the same time.
Speaker 1: That's going to make for a very bad game If I have to tilt the screen forward to move the monkey ball forward and now I can't see the screen Problem.
Speaker 0: Hello.
Speaker 0: Yeah, same time you could you could.
Speaker 0: I feel like that sort of control could be used subtly to great effect But if overused well Too much require a great deal of calibration to make sure that you don't have to move the screen very far.
Speaker 1: But then you have these very tight controls that might be too tight, you know, it's it's gonna be really tricky there.
Speaker 1: But I guess touchscreen games could be fun.
Speaker 1: little touchscreen Tetris could be okay if you're bored or whatever.
Speaker 1: But really if I'm looking for gaming, I'll just whip up my DS.
Speaker 1: You know the iPhone won't have the sort of local wireless multiplayer The DS has.
Speaker 1: it won't have the two screens the DS has.
Speaker 0: yes Remember that the touchscreen is not.
Speaker 1: what made the DS the amazing at least not to people have the tactile You know arrows and buttons the DS has which are essential for many many games.
Speaker 0: Yes But the thing is you don't.
Speaker 0: could be really really good on The iPhone would be adventure games like a little Phoenix right would be okay and real-time or turn-based strategy games That'd be okay.
Speaker 0: because this that sort of interface games where it's not there's there's different game control and the idioms like Mario games and platformers that sort of thing won't work at all because you really do need those buttons.
Speaker 0: But idioms like I have menus and I'm clicking on things work real Well, which is yeah all good.
Speaker 0: for rim who thought Gemfire was one of the best games ever a Phoenix Right would work and say an Advance Wars might work.
Speaker 1: The thing is right.
Speaker 1: even with an Advance Wars the single-player be okay Multiplayer no go.
Speaker 1: unless they set up some sort of Bluetooth gaming which is I don't think it's gonna be fast enough Some sort of ad-hoc Wi-Fi I don't know, but the DS Completely a win for at least for me personally was the local wireless.
Speaker 0: Everything else is just a okay, whatever.
Speaker 1: But the local wireless revolutionized gaming for me and it could theoretically do a local wireless because does have Wi-Fi in it.
Speaker 1: Yes, and you know, what is that?
Speaker 1: gonna disconnect you from the Internet's, you know?
Speaker 1: And then maybe they could do internet Wi-Fi, which actually be pretty cool.
Speaker 1: I doubt they're gonna let you play games live over the 3g even if it's possible You know because they don't want you using up all that crazy bandwidth or whatever because they're assholes.
Speaker 1: But yeah, iPhone gaming might be something I really do.
Speaker 1: I think I think the iPhone should really would be a hit in terms of gaming.
Speaker 1: is If someone who made like MMOs, right?
Speaker 1: Let's say Blizzard made like not a full-on World of Warcraft client for the iPhone But sort of like a mini World of Warcraft client.
Speaker 1: We're like you could do a few World of Warcraft things on your iPhone.
Speaker 1: So like the crazy addicts that would make mad moneys.
Speaker 1: not that I want that but you know that make bad moneys Right.
Speaker 0: So I actually have some news.
Speaker 0: Luckily, we don't need to talk about it for a long time.
Speaker 0: I think you all know my opinions on this and also coming around to this Scott side of things there, huh?
Speaker 1: Don't just keep going.
Speaker 0: no No, cuz the thing is I don't think that this hurts the thing that is being applied to in any way.
Speaker 1: Well, it hurts it in one sense and it helps it in another side.
Speaker 0: now the thing that the reason I don't want to talk about it a lot is because while This is totally a rumor and I have not is it.
Speaker 1: I thought it was real.
Speaker 0: Where did you see that?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I just sort of saw words on the Internet's.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: I've seen words about this all over the place.
Speaker 0: However, I did not look too deeply into finding out if it is true or not because the original thing I read way back was based mostly on a couple of screenshots and some other speculation.
Speaker 1: Okay, all right.
Speaker 1: So so this is now real.
Speaker 0: and well this mayor this may have been verified since I looked but Going two nights a week does not mean I'm gonna put any more due diligence into my news than I have before.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: However spirit I'm gonna talk about don't try to do too much of it.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I think you're trying to use the try to do too much with it too much and thus are trying to do too much with Perhaps perhaps Indeed so quite quiet.
Speaker 1: You're trying to do too much with these.
Speaker 0: sure Supposing World of Warcraft were to get achievements.
Speaker 1: This is the whole game just achievements already.
Speaker 0: So this enters this delicious world of meta that I. it's so wonderful.
Speaker 0: It's so meta that there would be achievements in an achievement based game.
Speaker 1: I mean pretty much the game is achievements.
Speaker 1: It's like kill the guy.
Speaker 1: get this item kill that guy get this.
Speaker 0: no, no, no, that's not a while works at all Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: You obviously have never played.
Speaker 0: Wow Get a bunch of people together kill all these guys.
Speaker 0: What if you will get an item?
Speaker 0: do the exact same thing until everyone gets the item?
Speaker 1: That's even worse.
Speaker 0: But supposing that were you to get to level 15 without dying you would get 50 something points.
Speaker 0: or were you to?
Speaker 0: Complete 10 quests in the howling fjord you would get 50 something points.
Speaker 1: But isn't the game already give you something if you complete a quest?
Speaker 0: Yes, it gives you something but it doesn't give you something points.
Speaker 1: See, that's the thing with all these games.
Speaker 1: Really on the fundamental levels that they're not games of winning and losing.
Speaker 1: they are games of do stuff and gets and get Meaningless rewards no matter what you do.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: It's it's no different than SimCity in that regard.
Speaker 0: Now it's don't.
Speaker 1: you can lose it SimCity.
Speaker 0: no you can't.
Speaker 1: yeah You can be no matter how bad.
Speaker 1: you could run out of money.
Speaker 0: No because no matter how badly you're going No, you can just bulldoze everything down to like a couple of little zones.
Speaker 0: You're one little power plant and then leave the game on for like a week or two And then you'll get enough money back to start playing again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the year will advance so far into the cares.
Speaker 0: That doesn't do anything.
Speaker 0: You're doesn't mean Jack.
Speaker 1: The thing is if SimCity wasn't a broken game It's it's theoretically at least a game of design and you have to come up with a better design That works.
Speaker 0: the problem is it's a game of.
Speaker 0: there is a perfect design simply implemented.
Speaker 1: That is a problem.
Speaker 1: Yes, if it was much more complicated and difficult to come up with a good wasn't?
Speaker 0: then it would just be a sandbox with multiple paths.
Speaker 1: at least the sandbox is better than a you know a Manual labor for meaningless.
Speaker 0: I don't share your vitriol when it comes to World of Warcraft because I don't see you playing it.
Speaker 1: Well, there's
Speaker 0: the thing if you remove the grind from it and you just look at playing the game Like let's say I could just if I if I was subscribed to Wow I could anytime arbitrarily pick a level pick a class pick a race Pick all my equipment and then do whatever raids I want to do with all my friends who have picked similar levels.
Speaker 0: Then the game would probably be pretty damn fun and I could see playing it with my friends.
Speaker 1: I don't think so because then what would be?
Speaker 1: you're doing this thing, right?
Speaker 1: You just picked the best equipment.
Speaker 1: there is you.
Speaker 1: it's basically no different than the World of Warcraft card game Which is you?
Speaker 1: you know, if you have enough money, you can pick whatever cards you want and it's just a matter.
Speaker 1: It's basically rock-paper-scissors, but you see the scissors.
Speaker 1: I just decide to throw rock.
Speaker 0: Not really How?
Speaker 0: not really because in this case, it's kind of like playing Team Fortress where alright, we're all gonna do this thing.
Speaker 0: I mean basically once I'd done every raid a couple of times I would have no reason to play again.
Speaker 0: But at least I wouldn't have to level up to get to that point.
Speaker 0: because then it's alright, let's go on this mission.
Speaker 0: It's a lot like Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles get all your friends together and you go on this kind of mission together.
Speaker 0: When you're done, you're done and hey, we beat it now.
Speaker 0: Let's do the next one.
Speaker 0: let's all meet on Saturday and do some other one.
Speaker 0: if you remove all the doing something more than once in order to get items or Doing something more than once in order to get levels or basically any sort of non arbitrary advancement I would be all about Wow until I'd done every raid a couple time.
Speaker 1: Now the thing about the diff the thing that found all these Crystal Chronicles is a good example because it's basically Wow Except there is one key difference that separates it from Wow Which is why the newer Crystal Chronicles is the suck.
Speaker 1: is that it actually the whole?
Speaker 1: mechanic of having the secret information based on which player you are and one person has the map and someone else is The only thing that made that.
Speaker 1: that was the only thing that made that game worthwhile.
Speaker 0: I don't think so at all.
Speaker 1: No, that is the only reason that that game was not terrible.
Speaker 1: I the fact that it forced you to have the set up this sort of interaction between the people and in this Cooperation whereas and Wow, it's pretty much you just learn the exact job You're supposed to do and then you just do the job repeatedly.
Speaker 0: But you can do the exact same thing in Crystal Chronicles because those maps and all that in secret information Was in the end useless and all it did was make the game faster.
Speaker 0: It didn't actually help you ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it did cuz it didn't it did.
Speaker 0: all you had to do was always turn left and you would always solve every puzzle and Get to the end.
Speaker 0: all the maps did was give you guys people an excuse to talk to each other.
Speaker 0: What made that game?
Speaker 0: Great was the fact that you get four friends together and you would be in this shit together.
Speaker 0: and also it ended.
Speaker 0: No, well ending is important too, but it had a good theme and had good style.
Speaker 0: And it was you take four people and you play together.
Speaker 0: I also feel that Crystal Chronicles was only worth playing if you played through it in like one or two goes like a group of people one group of people all the way through and also if you ignored pretty much all the Advancements of the game other than the advancement that occurs naturally in the course of playing.
Speaker 0: I feel as though World of Warcraft would be as fun as Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles.
Speaker 0: If I did not have to ever Level and no one else ever had to level and you could never get anything that affected the game in the game.
Speaker 1: That would make it a little bit better, but it still would not make it good.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 1: because there's still you're not doing it.
Speaker 1: All you're doing is manual labor.
Speaker 0: You realize the only manual labor is the grind.
Speaker 1: So be what so but do it's no different.
Speaker 1: So the only difference is I'm doing the same exact labor only now.
Speaker 1: numbers don't go up because I control the numb.
Speaker 0: doing any one Raid or any one part of the game once would be fun No less fun than doing any one level in Crystal Chronicles.
Speaker 1: doing the same with the levels in Crystal Chronicles is annoying.
Speaker 1: The fun part was trying to figure out where to go and then, you know, try to figure out.
Speaker 1: Okay, you take this, you know competing for all those the items at the end like oh Are you gonna take that one and you know sort of bickering with each other?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: actual game itself didn't offer anything.
Speaker 0: I kind of disagree again.
Speaker 0: It was okay.
Speaker 0: I don't understand why you hate like why you get so freaked out about World of Warcraft every time it comes up and you get So angry about it and just vitriol left and right because I don't I don't like I had this.
Speaker 1: It's just World of Warcraft happens to be the most popular big phenomena.
Speaker 1: So that's why it gets most of the vitriol.
Speaker 1: I feel the same way about all.
Speaker 0: every game that has the same Characteristics and yet you want to play other get like some board games we have that are just worse in many regards gameplay wise.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I feel as though wow wouldn't be that bad.
Speaker 0: and my question to wild players I'll end it on this at least to all of you out there.
Speaker 0: Look, I honestly answer this question for me.
Speaker 0: I'm really really curious.
Speaker 0: I'll put up a poll or something on the forum about this.
Speaker 0: if World of Warcraft were changed.
Speaker 0: It was the exact same game Except that every single player could arbitrarily choose their level and equipment at any time.
Speaker 0: Well at any time outside of a raid once you start a raid you stuck with what you got.
Speaker 0: But you could just arbitrarily choose level and arbitrarily choose equipment.
Speaker 0: Would you continue to play World of Warcraft and do you think you would make it a better or worse game?
Speaker 0: I imagine that question will tell me a lot about who what kind of person you are.
Speaker 1: I imagine that most people would do that go around and sort of see everything there was in the game and then stop playing.
Speaker 0: But yes, you know what because then the game would be almost exactly like Crystal Chronicles.
Speaker 1: Yes Well, the other thing right is that I've noticed there are some people in the world right like look at counter-strike, right?
Speaker 1: There are some people who play counter-strike and they don't cheat and they actually want like a good game right and like like if I cheated a counter-strike like I mean Oh, I had.
Speaker 1: I was I had a computer once that you know It was at like a LAN party or whatever and it was all full of counter-strike cheats.
Speaker 1: and you know You played a few times with all the cheats and you just shoot everyone in the head and you win and you win and you Win and whatever and it got boring really quick.
Speaker 1: But there are other people where with the cheats like they're having fun forever with those cheats like it's never unfun for them, right and I imagine the kind of person who Enjoys, you know the cheating game continuously You know is the one kind of person and the person who can't deal with the cheating game is the other kind of person.
Speaker 0: See, I don't know how relevant it is.
Speaker 0: I mean sure there would be some people but I guess the other extension you could have is every raid would have a level cap.
Speaker 0: so it's not so.
Speaker 0: then the Pre-game meta grind crap no longer exists because no longer do you have to do repetitive tasks?
Speaker 1: But how is that any different from the World of Warcraft card game, which we were bashing because that's not a multiplayer game?
Speaker 0: That's not.
Speaker 1: it is when you do those raid thingies.
Speaker 1: It's a bunch of people together versus the one guy who has the raid deck.
Speaker 0: Well, if you do that specific aspect of the game, which we didn't play and can't talk a lot about Yeah, but we pretty much confirm that the way the game works is a matter of you.
Speaker 1: once you know What's in the raid deck?
Speaker 1: It's just a matter of Constructing your deck to beat it as in a rock-paper-scissors where you know The other guy has rock and you win.
Speaker 0: that could probably be really fun.
Speaker 1: So if I know the raid is full of fire, I choose all the water.
Speaker 0: It would be just as fun as playing the hero quest like games or beat the game games for alright Here's the game you play request is terrible.
Speaker 0: Well, actually it's kind of funny.
Speaker 0: You just got to add a lot of style to it and just get into it.
Speaker 1: No, it's terrible.
Speaker 1: What's they are?
Speaker 1: you want to play hero quest now?
Speaker 0: The only problem was when we decided to iterate through it perfectly.
Speaker 0: and I'm not.
Speaker 0: I mean Wow is a lot better than hero quest in that regard even the card games a lot better than hero.
Speaker 1: Well, because only because it's more complex so it but it fundamentally is no different.
Speaker 0: but you're I just don't get your.
Speaker 0: oh well fundamentally because all games fundamentally are either completely arbitrary or completely stalemate or Completely solved.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why?
Speaker 0: if you argue with that level then there's no point in even talking about games anymore?
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are because there are games that are not solved.
Speaker 0: So then play those games.
Speaker 0: I do not really you don't play go You don't really play chess because goes not fun.
Speaker 0: No, it isn't.
Speaker 1: it's mostly.
Speaker 1: so no it isn't solved enough.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: There are only so many possible.
Speaker 1: board configuration.
Speaker 0: Yes, and we have not explored it fully.
Speaker 0: chess is nowhere near solved.
Speaker 1: No, they're computers that beat everyone.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 0: No, hey, whatever things of the day.
Speaker 0: So you go in a nother out along with Conrad and we went to the mocha and all that stuff this weekend.
Speaker 0: But one thing that you go showed us in the litany of because it's kind of a I don't know front row crew Instead of like shaking hands when we all get together.
Speaker 0: We all show each other all the internet things we've seen recently.
Speaker 1: Yeah and some people have all seen the same sort of stuff because they don't go to good sites and other people have seen all sorts of Things because they're internet addicts with nothing to do at work,
Speaker 0: but at the same time Some of us like just we're in different circles on the internet, but this is a game.
Speaker 0: it's on pixel jam called Dino run and the premise is pretty simple exchange studios and all that.
Speaker 0: Basically, you take a little yellow dinosaur and you run away from the apocalypse.
Speaker 0: Now I'm not gonna go into any depth about this game.
Speaker 0: You should probably just play it and you'll figure out what's going on pretty quick.
Speaker 0: All I really want to say is that doom surfing is really fun.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah The the way the game handles it's a lot.
Speaker 0: It's very pixely really good control and it reminds me a lot of passage just in the.
Speaker 0: it's very artistic and wallets pixely.
Speaker 0: It's very stylistically awesome.
Speaker 1: The gameplay reminds me of this one level from kid chameleon.
Speaker 1: if you haven't played kid chameleon It's one of the great old Genesis platform games that has been forgotten and if you should really go get it Maybe that should be on the virtual console.
Speaker 1: I wonder if it is or isn't.
Speaker 0: I Don't know but the effect of the apocalypse when it's coming up behind you is actually really scary and as you get into the higher Levels this game is so unnerving and like all your muscles just tense up and was like
Speaker 1: Yeah, even though it's primarily a game of holding right but those stegosaur
Speaker 0: I oh man and it gets a lot harder as time goes On.
Speaker 0: don't worry.
Speaker 1: The other thing is the game has some interesting stuff you can do that you might not realize like there'll be a Pterodactyl and like if you you know, I think they come at you.
Speaker 1: That's this bad like if I can joust but at the same time sometimes they'll pick you up and carry you farther ahead to help You out.
Speaker 1: It's it's pretty, you know, if you do the right thing.
Speaker 0: Also your little avatar the dinosaur is super cute.
Speaker 1: He's alright.
Speaker 0: He is super cute.
Speaker 0: You don't understand.
Speaker 1: He's not that cute.
Speaker 0: Yes, he is.
Speaker 0: Anyway, he waves at you and he wears a crown once you've won.
Speaker 1: really I gotta get the crown Alright, so when we were at the mocha, right there was some other stuff going down in the city.
Speaker 1: I don't know if you remember this but way back in the day I don't know how way back in the day But these people played this game of pack Manhattan where they combine sort of GPS computer portable technology But also the real world and the street and human beings to sort of make a game, right?
Speaker 1: So people would actually walk around the street to control the Pac-mans and the ghosts you see and that resulted in a pretty fun game.
Speaker 1: So they had this event this weekend.
Speaker 1: This is the problem of doing shows unfrequently.
Speaker 1: is that I talked about things after they happened.
Speaker 1: Isn't that said?
Speaker 1: Called come out and play festival 2008.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: it was this past weekend June 6th through 8th, and they had a whole bunch of games sort of like this And they are all sort of pretty cool and you can read about them and see pictures on their flicker group and all that good stuff of all the cool sort of outdoors Synergistic cool games these people were playing and I like this kind of action.
Speaker 1: if it wasn't mocha this weekend I probably would have been doing this.
Speaker 1: In fact, it was sort of a crazy weekend.
Speaker 1: It was like all these events in the city happening simultaneously.
Speaker 1: There was like a. there was also a Kaiju Big Patel on Saturday I believe.
Speaker 1: Alright, so way back in the day on the NES if you were a cool kid you had River City Ransom And if you had River City Ransom you probably also had Super Dodgeball and possibly World Cup possibly World Cup.
Speaker 1: But you noticed even if you were a dumb kid that these games looked familiar and similar For some reason maybe perhaps because they're both made by the same company or part of the same series of games.
Speaker 0: Now we're not going to get into the whole history of the Kunio Kun franchise.
Speaker 1: No, we are not.
Speaker 1: we're going to talk just about mostly Dodgeball because there is a brand new game that just came out for the DS Super dodgeball brawlers and we both got it.
Speaker 0: Now this game is based pretty much straight up on Super Dodgeball for the NES Which well, that's how you all would have known it and when I was a kid This is probably one of my favorite games ever I got to the point where I could beat the entire game on hard without ever once being hit by any ball at any point.
Speaker 1: I didn't get that good, but I could definitely beat the game on hard.
Speaker 0: The best part was when you beat the game on hard on any of the settings especially hard without losing anybody.
Speaker 0: Then after you beat the Soviet Russians, then you find the evil team the shadow team Which is your team only evil and black and white with lightning in the background and pretty much some of the best music in any NES game ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was good.
Speaker 1: I wonder if you can do a similar thing in the DS one.
Speaker 1: I haven't made it happen yet.
Speaker 0: I haven't really tried because the single-player is kind of crap.
Speaker 1: But anyway, yeah single-player is pretty crap.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so Super dodgeball check this the way this thing works.
Speaker 1: It doesn't work.
Speaker 1: like the dodgeball you play in gym class, right?
Speaker 1: Which actually I like the gym.
Speaker 1: gym dodgeball you play in gym class better as a game But it doesn't work as a video game.
Speaker 1: This works as a video game.
Speaker 1: The way it is is there's a field with two squares that are even in size and each square has four guys.
Speaker 0: I'm curious if anyone out there is so far removed from gaming that you've never played Super Dodgeball.
Speaker 1: I'm just describing it real quick.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah I'm just curious.
Speaker 1: and the four guys?
Speaker 1: if they all get hit with the ball and so Enough that their life is completely lost?
Speaker 0: Hey guys All right There was only four and I call the new game has four and the the.
Speaker 0: I guess the original arcade game had four But the original arcade game is weird.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna talk about.
Speaker 1: the original NES only had three, huh?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't remember that.
Speaker 1: I see.
Speaker 1: No anyway, the new DS one is four.
Speaker 1: There's three or four guys in the box and if you you try to hit the other teams three or four guys in the box with the ball and Then they die.
Speaker 1: eventually if you hit them enough with powerful enough moves And then if you eliminate all their guys in the box you win.
Speaker 1: You also have three guys on the other sides of the box.
Speaker 1: So Basically, the two boxes are connected.
Speaker 1: So it's your three or four guys versus their three or four guys.
Speaker 1: but then you also have one guy above the other team one guy below the other team one guy behind the other team to sort of help you out and they have one guy behind you one guy above you one guy below you and You just throw the ball back and forth try and hit the other guy and this super moves.
Speaker 1: and you can do jumping super moves And you can do regular throws.
Speaker 1: you can do tricky stuff like by passing the ball like jump up like you're gonna do super move But then pass the ball back to your team and then they throw a super move or throw the ball over their heads Then throw it back over their heads and then throw it at them.
Speaker 0: But regardless of all that what made?
Speaker 0: at least we'll talk about the original first.
Speaker 0: What made the original game great?
Speaker 0: Was that it was a?
Speaker 0: I mean had a single-player and it added like actually had a couple of different like single-player multiplayer modes But nothing really.
Speaker 0: the only thing that was really good about the game was playing versus with another person Absolutely direct straight up.
Speaker 0: I am playing against my little brother and one of us is going to win and the game was so.
Speaker 1: it was all about Skills of button pressing timing.
Speaker 1: I mean you would throw the super move and everyone can see the super move coming from a mile away.
Speaker 0: But it's could you push the button with the correct timing to catch the ball and the one great thing is unlike the situation We're in now like Scott is with dr.
Speaker 0: Mario or I'm with advanced wars or the way I am with gemfire and all those stupid games that no one in the world likes but me Everyone I knew was just as into super dodgeball as I was so like all of my little friends We'd all get together and play dodgeball all the time yeah, and always be like the because you pick teams at the same time.
Speaker 0: the teams are not even at all and It always be the same.
Speaker 0: like I would very purposefully pick very quickly and pick the weakest ass team which by the way was England Yeah, and then the other players.
Speaker 0: than a conundrum.
Speaker 0: Do they similarly defect and take another crappy team like India or Do they decide to just be a loser and pick Russia and try to beat me?
Speaker 1: Yeah, because if they pick Russia and they win whatever it's a lot like playing Mario Kart with the wee wheel instead of using the Nunchuck wiimote combination because if you lose with the wee wheel Well, of course you lost you using the wee wheel.
Speaker 1: if you lose with England against Russia, of course you lost.
Speaker 1: you were England They were Russia, but if you win with England against Russia, whoa That's like using the wiimote to beat someone with the better controls.
Speaker 1: I mean the the we wheel.
Speaker 0: anyway The game was super awesome.
Speaker 0: I remember like and everyone had different super moves, but the game was kind of Undocumented back then and like no one seemed to really remember that you had your air move and your ground move.
Speaker 0: But at the Steve on everyone's team because all the teams were kind of the same had three moves.
Speaker 0: He had two ground moves and one air move.
Speaker 1: Yep The other thing about the game is that no matter how good anyone got no one ever got to be perfect.
Speaker 1: Like when we were in the duck hunt tournament, we were perfect, but it's super duh.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: in multiplayer You'll always Eventually, even if two people are great throw the super move catch it.
Speaker 1: throw the super move catch Well, they would try to fool them.
Speaker 1: super move catch Well, no if you're someone will eventually not catch it.
Speaker 0: really good like actually truly perfect or really good.
Speaker 0: players were playing.
Speaker 0: it came down to who Became fatigued the quickest and games would last an hour or more until eventually someone was so tired.
Speaker 0: But that's what dodgeball is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just like a real dodgeball when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you this though.
Speaker 0: I Thought that Dodge like I always because I had this game one what we would play dodgeball in the yard with all our friends.
Speaker 0: We would play it like super dodgeball.
Speaker 0: We like I'd run up to the center and jump and throw and that was not a good idea.
Speaker 0: Totally awesome.
Speaker 0: but beyond that I Always thoughts for the longest time when I was a little kid because of this game That when you were in gym class in school in elementary school playing dodgeball That wasn't a real dodgeball.
Speaker 0: that was wuss dodgeball for little kids and somehow I thought that there was an Olympic sport And I used to.
Speaker 0: as far as I was concerned the rules were When someone can't get up anymore and the entire team is knocked unconscious Then your side won and I thought that this was based on that and I thought that they played with a volleyball or maybe a medicine Ball,
Speaker 1: maybe that's the ticket to get all the nerds to play.
Speaker 1: We should play some dodge balls.
Speaker 0: Well, I ordered a regulation kickball.
Speaker 1: see what that's not see.
Speaker 1: that's enough for one ball.
Speaker 1: see the kind of dodgeball.
Speaker 1: Oh, maybe we should just talk about the dodgeballs.
Speaker 1: We played as kids.
Speaker 1: That's a separate show I know but I got it.
Speaker 1: I got like a lot of dodgeball things to talk about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we always like we'd play in the gym where if you could make a basket then you let's make a dodgeball week.
Speaker 1: We're doing a Thursday this week.
Speaker 0: Thursday We'll talk about Dodge ball in gym class not Barack Obama and the fact that American politics is finally going in the right direction for the first time In a long time.
Speaker 0: No, I'm so excited.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I'm so.
Speaker 1: people want to hear about the video games.
Speaker 0: Just can't hide it.
Speaker 1: So The dodgeball for the DS is largely the same as the original dodgeball.
Speaker 1: However, there are many improvements and changes.
Speaker 0: one the super moves.
Speaker 0: are there a lot more of them?
Speaker 0: And if you're good, you can't just catch all of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean the one that have rim hates the most is the one where you run up you throw it and it looks like I Faked it and I passed the ball just to the other teammate on the other side.
Speaker 1: But it makes the super move noise and that's the hint you need to know to turn around.
Speaker 1: Cuz it looks like a normal pass that's going slow But then it turns around it goes whoosh and hits you in the ass and does a lot of damage.
Speaker 1: I love that one the best.
Speaker 1: you got a favorite super move in there.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: my favorite super move was still and they have it in this game But it's not quite the same cuz I used to.
Speaker 0: I played this game so much the original that I had like Personalities for all the people on all the teams.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, definitely and all the moves meant stuff to me And to me.
Speaker 0: the nuts shot, you know Like that downward angle disc that the good guy has like the main character good guy.
Speaker 0: That was like the good guy move.
Speaker 0: Like that was the noble awesome move of good guy.
Speaker 1: That is the noble move indeed.
Speaker 1: However, it is also the easily caught move.
Speaker 0: That's another thing is that the move felt like that game did more damage against the evil team at the end even though I know It totally did.
Speaker 1: it is another thing right is that the super moves in the game sort of have this nice balance to them.
Speaker 1: For example, there's one move where all it is.
Speaker 1: It's a straight throw and but it's really fast.
Speaker 1: It's easy to catch actually, but if it hits guys it goes straight through them.
Speaker 1: So if the other team is all in a clump, you can hit like everyone on the other team with one throw.
Speaker 1: However, that one's really really easy to catch but it also doesn't do a lot of damage.
Speaker 0: However, if you use that with the neck ketsu ultimate shot Yeah, I wiped out an entire team in one shower exactly.
Speaker 1: That is the one thing that has been added to this new DS version.
Speaker 0: bunch can be turned off which I love.
Speaker 1: Yeah, everything can be turned off in this which is cool.
Speaker 1: Is this ultimate shot business?
Speaker 1: We have this meter and it builds up and catching balls and pass and doing certain certain things builds up your meter.
Speaker 0: also Dicking around and not refusing to throw and like just not throwing the ball makes it go down eventually.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is great.
Speaker 1: It is great.
Speaker 0: Hurry up and throw one time to try to win a game against my brother.
Speaker 0: They've been going on for a while.
Speaker 0: I refuse to play anymore and I just stood there with the ball and I basically told him either you're going to give up or I'm going to sit here until we starve to death.
Speaker 1: Yeah anyway, so You get this meter that fills up and when it fills up you get this super super super move and you can choose actually Prior to the match which super move you would like.
Speaker 1: one of the moves is like super defense and catching for like a minute or so Stupid except the ultimate shot.
Speaker 1: The ultimate shot is pretty much you get one shot to throw the ball and if it actually hits someone they die no matter what.
Speaker 1: And that is the move that everyone picks.
Speaker 1: because how could you God?
Speaker 1: How could you not pick?
Speaker 1: Guaranteed kill if you hit someone with the next throw?
Speaker 0: I mean, come on My favorite thing to do and in the original game at least was to run backwards with the accelerator ball.
Speaker 0: that I never really saw Until the Russians used it against me in the end of the game.
Speaker 0: But you run backwards and throw from the other side and it would get away fast.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz it's an accelerator.
Speaker 1: It starts out slow.
Speaker 0: It didn't actually do any more damage I don't think but it felt real good.
Speaker 1: and it also is a lot harder to catch when it was going fast.
Speaker 1: So they would start like way in the back goes slow slow slow speed.
Speaker 1: Oh, see don't see it up.
Speaker 1: Oh my god is too fast to catch it and it's a lot harder to catch that than the balls of the constant speed You know or the wobbly balls or anything like that.
Speaker 1: All right, so what else they add in this?
Speaker 0: Diaz for hunching kicking and sticks and shit you can throw at each other?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that stuff is kind of good right.
Speaker 1: the punching and kicking though is a little.
Speaker 1: it's.
Speaker 1: it's a little bit Okay, and a little bit not okay.
Speaker 0: I think it.
Speaker 0: the thing is you can turn it off so I can't complain about it at all, but it adds this extra element to the game.
Speaker 0: because Thing is the single-player game is Just don't buy.
Speaker 0: it's not worth it except to be good at the game and when there's no one to play with The only reason to ever play this game is multiplayer against other people.
Speaker 0: Yep The only reason to play the single-player is to get good at multiplayer with other people.
Speaker 0: Yep, don't even bother with the leveling up getting items.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing that I liked.
Speaker 1: if you play the one player game does leveling up an item is another bullet straight up like River City Ransom.
Speaker 0: off is awesome.
Speaker 0: buy nice items and such.
Speaker 1: right but it's unnecessary because when it comes time to do multiplayer, right?
Speaker 1: Let's say I play through the single-player with not ketsu high school, right?
Speaker 1: Okay, I level them up big time.
Speaker 1: now I want to play multiplayer on the team select screen Niketsu high school actually appear twice.
Speaker 1: there'll be white and red versions.
Speaker 1: The red version is the leveled up version and the white version is the flat even version.
Speaker 1: So you can play with your leveled up stuff if you want to do that sort of game or you can play straight up a fair Game, which is what of course real men do.
Speaker 0: it's kind of like initial D. You turn off the boost exactly exactly.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: the one thing we neglected to mention about both up by dodgeball game so far is the brawl Schoolyard mode.
Speaker 1: you see me.
Speaker 1: Yes in the original dodgeball There was a schoolyard mode where basically instead of having this sort of structured team game It was an every man for himself game and you the body would just be an open schoolyard.
Speaker 1: Everyone can run wherever they want and throw the ball at whoever they want and the last man alive is the winner.
Speaker 1: and this mode comes back in the new dodgeball with a fierce fierce intensity because For the first time it's eight player wireless multiplayer eight people running around the schoolyard Independently of each other trying to kill each other.
Speaker 0: I don't think you understand how awesome that is.
Speaker 1: The hardest part is getting eight people.
Speaker 0: planet gaga God you should see this shit deep and other people ain't talking about disease.
Speaker 0: We don't need.
Speaker 1: we do need it cuz it's so awesome to run around eight separate people throwing shit at each other Kicking and plus the kicking and punching in that.
Speaker 1: Oh, come on.
Speaker 1: It's good stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah plus just playing multiplayer against other people.
Speaker 0: Cuz one thing that's really good is you can customize your team in this perfectly fair Baseball simulator 1000 style of.
Speaker 0: pick the special moves pick the names pick the way they look and let me tell you you think you're gonna Pick the way they look.
Speaker 1: There are so many faces and hairstyles like you choose the hair the eyes the head the skin color All kinds of stuff.
Speaker 1: There's so many options.
Speaker 0: It's so fantastic.
Speaker 0: I got a minute.
Speaker 1: I'm very.
Speaker 1: let's tell people What teams we made?
Speaker 0: Well, I'm very.
Speaker 0: I'm.
Speaker 0: first I made the Romans.
Speaker 0: I dressed him up in togas.
Speaker 0: They had cool names.
Speaker 0: I got sick of that real quick.
Speaker 0: So then I made Da mecha dodgeball.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, so you've got who's the heart?
Speaker 0: got usa Hara who can jump really high and he's real fast And I don't know who.
Speaker 0: I made the stats all one But I don't know.
Speaker 1: so you made the stats actually match the the the character to a point.
Speaker 0: No, okay, but I also made rim who is just really good.
Speaker 1: See on my team.
Speaker 1: I made dodge dango And you see all of my characters, all right, check out the four guys I have in the box are all Zelda bosses.
Speaker 1: I've got gliok Not da-dango, but I have mon hondler.
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: My hondler was a Goma and Dig dagger.
Speaker 1: right and I made them look like they're supposed to look.
Speaker 0: no no Paul's voice.
Speaker 1: No, no No chick.
Speaker 1: All right and dodge dot like dig dagger is like miss has like an X for an eyeball And he's sort of yellow with spikiness on him and Goma has like this this weird Chupa what's it called?
Speaker 1: You He's got a Lucha Libre mask that makes it look like you were gonna say Chupacabra.
Speaker 1: No, I knew it was it's Lucha.
Speaker 0: Not anyway, why'd you said Chupa?
Speaker 1: I was close.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you know I made them all look like the bosses right.
Speaker 1: then the three guys I have on the defense side are Keys like like and And Stop flows and the one guy looks like a skeleton.
Speaker 1: The other guy has like bat blue bat hair that looks like a bat and the like-like is just sort of blobby And it totally made them look like the Zelda guys thing is.
Speaker 0: I think I'm gonna make my final team I'm gonna go with and I think it's gonna be chromare high school.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's a good one, but Because there are plenty of pompadours in this game for your selection so many different styles of pompadour.
Speaker 1: I mean if you're a pompadour Enthusiast buy this game for no other reason than the hairstyles.
Speaker 0: pretty much.
Speaker 0: if I'm gonna we're gonna You know endorse this game or whatever.
Speaker 0: the single-player is Really fun if you're still in the stage of your life where River City Ransom is fun for a non-nostalgic way in that You are willing to level up and bullshit buy stuff and you like that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: You don't even need to do the leveling up.
Speaker 0: you can ignore it because you like the single-player without that I'm saying is if you like that stuff the game will cater to you.
Speaker 0: But where I think the only reason to truly buy this game as opposed to borrowing it from someone is if you plan To play seriously against other people all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we bought.
Speaker 1: I bought this game for full price on Amazon.
Speaker 1: You know when it was announced and I pre-ordered it and everything and that you know That was okay for us because we have to review it and we're big dodgeball fans or whatever and we have plenty of money If you even if you want to play this game.
Speaker 1: The game is good for the DS the super dodgeball brawlers.
Speaker 1: But I really suggest you wait until it's a little discounted before you.
Speaker 0: $20 for it not 30 if you want to be the very best.
Speaker 1: Yes I don't think you need to really be the very best of this.
Speaker 1: It's sort of.
Speaker 0: I've been playing on hard now with the team that has all one stats just to practice.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's pretty good.
Speaker 1: I put all my guys at like even stats just to you know Cuz I'm not sure which stats mean.
Speaker 0: that's matter a lot.
Speaker 0: just on a lark.
Speaker 0: I made one guy I put like ball speed up to 32 and the ball was like wickedly fast.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: See that's what I'm trying to figure out.
Speaker 1: It's like okay if I put the ball speed up to 32, I'm gonna have to have like no dodging ability.
Speaker 1: It's like alright.
Speaker 1: Well that me, you know, is it worth it?
Speaker 1: You know, will I?
Speaker 1: will I win more often if I have an incredibly fast ball?
Speaker 1: That's hard to dodge You know, I got to figure that stuff out anyway.
Speaker 1: Super dodgeball brawlers original super dodgeball.
Speaker 1: Yeah people go out and get the ROM of the original super isn't it?
Speaker 1: Maybe it's on the we.
Speaker 0: we were Console if I if it is and I didn't buy it I consider that a failing in my life.
Speaker 0: This game is so like to me and my little brother.
Speaker 0: if nothing else this game was like the best fucking.
Speaker 0: it was this an Arrow biz.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah super dodgeball either.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's on virtual console, but on ROMs at least or super dodgeball brawlers.
Speaker 1: you should at least play some of these and figure out what the deal is with this because this is sort of a Semi big deal for cool video game peoples.
Speaker 0: and on that note We're probably gonna stop because this crazy thunderstorm is rolling through and I got and I'm not.
Speaker 0: I haven't hooked the moran's back up since mocha So it's if the power went out I would pretty much have like 30 seconds to get the show saved before the UPS died.
Speaker 1: Good God save.
Speaker 1: oh my god.
Speaker 0: Yes the end This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.