Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, October 21st.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm sky, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: Multi-winia and its demise.
Speaker 0: oh you put in its demise in the title.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: I Woke up this morning.
Speaker 1: I thought maybe I got in your hand.
Speaker 0: no And I thought maybe I just won't go.
Speaker 0: Just stay home today.
Speaker 1: You know when I worked at IVM anytime.
Speaker 1: I thought that I didn't go in When I worked at the hospital any time, I thought that I didn't go.
Speaker 0: well I've only got four and a half days.
Speaker 0: well two vacation days and two and a half sick days left.
Speaker 0: So not going is like a right.
Speaker 0: so I go.
Speaker 0: you know I ate this egg ate a cereal real quick.
Speaker 0: I've been eating cereal again.
Speaker 1: You know I noticed you ate a cereal real quick because I came home and there was a bowl full of Encrusted dried cereal that obviously had once been milked.
Speaker 0: yeah And I had a spoon stuck in it had to eat it real quick.
Speaker 0: cuz I was gonna miss that train I got down to the train station.
Speaker 0: He started walking towards a train after I parked the car and some people were walking the other way.
Speaker 0: And I'm thinking oh you know there's a train that goes the other way a little bit.
Speaker 0: You know before my train, and you know there might be these must be people go.
Speaker 0: who were you know coming to beacon from the city?
Speaker 0: People must work the night shift right I keep walking.
Speaker 0: Eventually one of these there were more people walking the other way than usual and they didn't look like night shift people.
Speaker 0: And they were just like yeah Eight seventeens canceled.
Speaker 1: so wait wait why walk the other way?
Speaker 1: What are you gonna?
Speaker 1: Do you don't have time to go home?
Speaker 1: another train is coming the next train.
Speaker 0: is it 90?
Speaker 0: something you a lot of time?
Speaker 0: Especially if you live close like me.
Speaker 1: yeah most of those people don't.
Speaker 1: I mean plus.
Speaker 1: it takes like you know Seven minutes to drive to the train station plus walking back to the car.
Speaker 0: Well, I was already only halfway from the car, so I drove home, and I actually when I got home I said I have to do something in this time.
Speaker 1: What did you do?
Speaker 0: well cuz well first I said you know what I would.
Speaker 0: maybe I won't go.
Speaker 1: I would have gone back to my car either.
Speaker 1: I would have gone back to my car and Set my cell phone alarm and taken a nap yeah, or I can't sleep in the car.
Speaker 1: I have often slept in my car.
Speaker 1: many a road trip.
Speaker 1: It's the worst road trip of my life.
Speaker 1: Well the worst solo road trip in my life the worst road trip in my life.
Speaker 1: you were driving But the word the worst solo road trip of my life.
Speaker 1: I was so tired, and I had so many more miles to go That I pulled over on the side of the road and just went to sleep.
Speaker 0: That's an attic.
Speaker 0: It's not a bad idea if you're tired.
Speaker 1: And no it's a terrible idea because I woke up in the car And I'd been so used to fighting to stay awake the whole time I was on the road that I woke up realized I was behind the wheel Screamed and tried to stop the stop.
Speaker 0: you're supposed to sleep in the passenger seat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't think of that.
Speaker 1: plus then I would have I would have done the same thing But simultaneously would have yelled where the fuck's the steering wheel?
Speaker 0: now Jesus am I in London?
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: so I drove home.
Speaker 0: I said Maybe I just won't go.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't have gone if I got.
Speaker 1: no if I'd gotten home I wouldn't go back to that train station, so I'm sitting there, and I'm thinking is should I go?
Speaker 0: should I not go?
Speaker 1: Will he stay or will he go now?
Speaker 0: I remember that the at work We just merged our domain with the other domain so the email was funky all right, so don't go you're not missing anything.
Speaker 0: I didn't do anything at work today, so why'd you go?
Speaker 1: Well, you know
Speaker 0: I went, but when I got home I knew I said I had to do something so I actually cleaned up all the shit off my floor in my room and put on my dirty clothes clean clothes away and also the dirty clothes away and Then I said all right fuck it.
Speaker 0: I went you know See speaking of which.
Speaker 1: actually I was thinking you know what how many vacation days I got left I want to take like a day or two off around New Year's.
Speaker 1: to you know all the people are gonna be around get ready for the giant annual FRC New Year's bash.
Speaker 1: so I go to the HR person.
Speaker 1: I'm like hey, how many vacation days do I have left?
Speaker 1: She's like give me a minute.
Speaker 1: I'll let you know.
Speaker 1: come back after lunch.
Speaker 1: I come after lunch, and she's like Yeah, you've got 16 All right, like what she's like.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you didn't really use that many this year And I can only roll five of them over to the next year, so I got to take 11 days off.
Speaker 0: Oh, they let you roll over.
Speaker 1: I realize the hospital that you roll over infinitely.
Speaker 0: I can't roll over anything not even a single day.
Speaker 1: There were people who wouldn't take a vacation day for like five years running and then disappear for a long time.
Speaker 0: If I could roll over I would use sick days.
Speaker 0: I would use all my sick days to go to conventions.
Speaker 0: I take all these Fridays off and the next year.
Speaker 0: I would just go away for a month.
Speaker 1: That's not what sick days are for.
Speaker 1: plus luckily Every company I've ever worked for.
Speaker 1: sick days did not count.
Speaker 1: they were just infinite.
Speaker 1: if you were sick don't come in.
Speaker 0: They were infinite where I work and so we got bought.
Speaker 0: we got bought.
Speaker 0: yeah, everything changed.
Speaker 1: well actually the hospital It was complicated because they gave us flex time that counted for any time you took.
Speaker 0: flex time is supposed to mean Work 40 hours.
Speaker 0: We don't know which hour.
Speaker 1: I also had that and I had as long as I worked well build 37.5 hours per week I was in the clear.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh even if it was Monday Tuesday, and that was it theoretically.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, see I love that.
Speaker 1: well the thing is at the hospital because of the independent nature of my work There are very few people who would have noticed if I was not there like I could have.
Speaker 1: just I once near the end like after I Resigned myself to quitting I didn't show up one day.
Speaker 1: You know I was actually like kind of sick, so I just didn't go in and I emailed the HR person whatever.
Speaker 1: I didn't realize that the HR person.
Speaker 1: I emailed had quit like a month before.
Speaker 0: So basically no one knew I didn't set up the email to forward to the new HR person.
Speaker 1: There's a reason.
Speaker 1: I'm working for this other company now right, but like no one noticed I was gone well at.
Speaker 0: I took so far this year ten vacation days, and I have two left.
Speaker 0: I also have two and a half sick days because now we don't have infinite sick days anymore.
Speaker 0: They gave everyone two and a half because they bought us in June the middle of the year And they usually give five.
Speaker 1: so I thought I used a lot more than I did But then I realized that I had five rolled over from the previous year Right and then I was trying to figure out what the actual holiday days off were.
Speaker 0: Apparently this company gives you know Christmas Day, New Year's Day, but they also have four Christmas holiday days pretty much that the days between Christmas and New Year's.
Speaker 0: So I think I can use my four and a half days and get you know basically the end of the year off and then Cuz after New Year's it's a new year, and there's that one Friday in there.
Speaker 0: I can I can use the next year's day to get that off.
Speaker 1: - see I think I actually have to work the Friday after New Year's because everyone else in my company is taking that day off, but I got all these vacation days to burn.
Speaker 1: So I'm probably gonna take like the week before it off And I'm gonna spend the rest of the day's skiing like I'm just gonna like take every Wednesday off in December also in the middle Of November you know when a whole company goes to Puerto Rico.
Speaker 0: I have two days, so it's gonna be good, too.
Speaker 1: So you don't have to go to Puerto Rico.
Speaker 0: no, I just you know I said ours.
Speaker 0: I RSVP'd.
Speaker 0: no and that was it.
Speaker 1: oh all this drama and everyone's like hey Scott going is Scott going?
Speaker 1: I guess that's the answer.
Speaker 0: It's not it's not.
Speaker 0: what was the drama?
Speaker 0: It was just.
Speaker 1: you know the dresser was drama for everyone, but you apparently anyway.
Speaker 1: There's actual video game news that kind of.
Speaker 1: I'm excited about this.
Speaker 1: It's the.
Speaker 1: I haven't been excited about many video game things in recent memory.
Speaker 0: I mean well the main reason like there are a lot of video I used to you know really anticipate games and buy them and then beat him right away.
Speaker 0: the problem I'm having right is not that there's no Games to anticipate.
Speaker 1: There's no time to play in blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: I have a whole bunch of games that are unplayed.
Speaker 0: I haven't even touched Mega Man 9.
Speaker 0: I played like Gemman.
Speaker 1: you haven't touched Mega Man 9.
Speaker 1: I've beaten two of the robot masters only two.
Speaker 0: It's nothing.
Speaker 0: I.
Speaker 1: I've only played a couple hours video on But I was.
Speaker 1: let's see I'm excited about Left 4 Dead.
Speaker 1: I'm excited about Fallout.
Speaker 0: I already pre-ordered Left 4 Dead.
Speaker 1: I should.
Speaker 1: I was excited about bionic commando.
Speaker 1: I was not disappointed.
Speaker 1: that game was like the best game.
Speaker 1: I played since portal hands down.
Speaker 1: Oh my God, and I'm excited almost surprisingly About punch-out for the Wii.
Speaker 0: now you might want you to be excited for punch-out.
Speaker 1: I wasn't.
Speaker 1: I didn't really like the Super Nintendo.
Speaker 1: I usually liked no iteration of punch-out other than Mike Tyson's punch-out.
Speaker 0: What's wrong with Super Nintendo punch-out?
Speaker 1: It just wasn't as good.
Speaker 1: It didn't have as much character.
Speaker 1: I mean it had Gaby J. Gaby J. Yeah But there was something about Mike Tyson's punch-out.
Speaker 1: none of this, Mr.. Dream.
Speaker 1: I'm talking Mike Tyson's punch-out, but Basically Nintendo has been screwing me left and right with new games like
Speaker 0: WarioWare
Speaker 1: for the Gamecube was one of the best games that has ever been on a Nintendo platform and of course Nintendo had no idea why it was a good game and thus The same game released on the Wii was one of the worst games Nintendo has ever released.
Speaker 1: But you know I expected them to do the same thing with punch-out.
Speaker 1: I expected it to be some like waggle Bs.
Speaker 0: I expected to have like probably is going to be waggle Bs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see if it is that I'm probably not going to be excited anymore But of course it's going to be happy.
Speaker 1: Nintendo has this history of getting the right things wrong and the wrong things right in like every remake of a game they make with rare exception and I was really worried that punch-out was going to be generic.
Speaker 1: It was going to be all like me's fighting each other and none of the original charm.
Speaker 1: The trailer for punch-out on the Wii came out and if any of you have not seen it I recommend that you stop listening go click on that link and watch it because let me tell you all The racism is there and it's surprising, but that excites me more.
Speaker 1: well not racism Nationalistic stereotypes.
Speaker 0: you see that's the one part of the game that they could have removed And I wouldn't have been upset you know as long as they had the quality gameplay of the original.
Speaker 0: You know the the simple yet complex nature of a boxing game where you only have you know five?
Speaker 0: Attacks and like you know three or four dodges, and that's it.
Speaker 0: and that that's what I was looking for.
Speaker 0: See it's kind of like that.
Speaker 0: They brought back these hilarious nationalist stereotypes.
Speaker 1: There's conflation like in jeans where like the jeans for something like red hair might be conflated with the jeans for something else.
Speaker 1: People with one genetic trait will often exhibit another seemingly unrelated genetic trait.
Speaker 1: Games are the same way, and I feel as though by getting that right by having the croissants flying through the air out of glass Joe after you knock him out and Such and by having the Kaiser and King Hippo in the game And it the game looks like it's just basically a straight up remake of the original punch-out.
Speaker 1: by getting that right I'm confident that they have gotten all the right things right and the wrong things also right because they're not there.
Speaker 0: See thing is I've been deceived by you know the images too many times.
Speaker 0: I no longer fall for that.
Speaker 1: like what I mean.
Speaker 1: why are you aware for the Wii?
Speaker 1: We weren't.
Speaker 1: we were deceived by the name.
Speaker 1: there was no image There was no like thing where I said oh look they know what they doing except the dancing cats.
Speaker 1: See the thing is I already knew the game was bad by the time I got to the dancing cats.
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 0: There's been plenty of games out there that you know.
Speaker 0: they.
Speaker 0: they get the visuals of the audios right you know But
Speaker 1: the
Speaker 0: gameplay isn't very
Speaker 1: specifically that they kept the nationalistic stereotypes They kept but like the thing that you expected them to drop first They kept the hardest and that that gives me more hope than anything anyone ever could have said.
Speaker 0: no Hope because you know it's gonna be some waggly controlled thing.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna be you know it actually well controlled thing.
Speaker 1: It's I don't think so I'll bet.
Speaker 1: what's what it's gonna Be is there's probably gonna be some sort of waggle option and maybe you waggle to do like the super punch or something.
Speaker 1: But I'll bet that there is an option just hold that controller sideways in fact.
Speaker 1: I'll bet ten bucks.
Speaker 0: I'm not betting against it, but I'm not too confident about.
Speaker 0: I'm ten dollars confident, and you know what I can wait on it.
Speaker 0: I got plenty of games going on right now like for example You know the WarioWare Whatnot?
Speaker 0: what's it called?
Speaker 0: not WarioWare?
Speaker 1: There's only one good WarioWare game.
Speaker 1: What are you talking about?
Speaker 0: Wario what they call it the shake Wario shake, which is the business?
Speaker 1: It's a I don't even know the name of the of your favorite current game the game.
Speaker 1: You're currently playing.
Speaker 0: I'm not actually currently playing it.
Speaker 0: I'm semi currently playing it concurrently playing it with many other games.
Speaker 0: I'm playing natural selection Zelda 3 playing that.
Speaker 1: yeah I've resolved not to because I've tried to replay that game like six times since I originally played it as a kid And I'll get about halfway through the dark world, and I'll just like Something will rise in my gut and suddenly I'll go god damn it never mind and just put the controller down and give up
Speaker 0: and playing some.
Speaker 0: you know that Tetris game I guess Tetris party.
Speaker 1: yeah, that's really not a single-player game though.
Speaker 0: It has single-player mode?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm done with playing Tetris by myself Tetris.
Speaker 0: That's why you suck at it cuz I don't practice.
Speaker 1: I know I know could I beat you in like almost all of those modes.
Speaker 1: We played Handily.
Speaker 0: no no you ruined us.
Speaker 0: in the co-op mode I noticed.
Speaker 0: and the modes you beat me and we're not Tetris II modes They were.
Speaker 0: you know racing required much higher level cortical input.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh the racing mode was so much better than the Father's me.
Speaker 1: about the racing mode Scott is that it was Trivial to be like it took.
Speaker 1: I could have beaten it with my eyes closed one hand.
Speaker 0: Yeah the only the only reason you won is because at the start I was trying to figure out how it worked and you just held Down right away, and that's that tiny head start.
Speaker 0: I could not catch up because that's the one at the same speed realize That's the reason why I tend to.
Speaker 1: I have a record of when we get a new board game.
Speaker 1: I'll win like oh In the first instance of that game like 90% of the time But then I'll lose like the next four because I've in every game.
Speaker 1: I just hold down immediately.
Speaker 1: I don't care what the rule.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna hold down because you'll probably win the first round that way.
Speaker 0: yeah, you're depth first that I'm breath first.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if I only play every game ever once I'll be the undisputed champion of every game, and I'll retire.
Speaker 0: Well as long as you're playing as people have never played before.
Speaker 1: yeah, so you guys are doing breath first.
Speaker 1: Like you I have to play brand new games and only play them once.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: all I have to say is I am excited about this that the video Gives me confidence more confidence than I would expect.
Speaker 1: and also I point out that One of the most played games on our we even today is Mike Tyson's punch-out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know what it is about that punch-out the old NES one But it's good.
Speaker 0: the fact that it has a good control.
Speaker 0: with the you know as opposed to the uneven on the NES They game controlled very you know difficultly.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: it's a perfect Game like.
Speaker 1: it's the perfect implementation of that specific game like you.
Speaker 0: just pick it up I mean and put it down.
Speaker 1: you could have made a better game, but that game itself I don't think there's anything anyone could say is wrong with it.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have more guys.
Speaker 1: That's that's like saying that citizen the Australian guy because it should have been longer.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, what do you have for me?
Speaker 0: Oh, it's not for you.
Speaker 0: Who says it's for you.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: I want some news here.
Speaker 0: I mean, I got news.
Speaker 1: It's not seem so interested in my news.
Speaker 1: What do you got?
Speaker 0: You know?
Speaker 0: What's 30 years old?
Speaker 1: Your mom?
Speaker 0: no my mom's a lot older than 30. all right My mom was 30. that means she had me when she was 3 or 4.
Speaker 0: How about that?
Speaker 1: there could be a time to?
Speaker 0: Anyway, don't be talking about that.
Speaker 0: 30 years ago today in The MMO was bored.
Speaker 0: now a lot of people think oh, no they first time.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know ask some kid What was the first MMO?
Speaker 0: who'd be like EverQuest?
Speaker 0: Or maybe he'll say Asher ons call or maybe you'll be smart and say something like meridian 59.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if they say the realm.
Speaker 1: They're smart because that is the answer.
Speaker 1: that is the first Graphical massively multiplayer online role-playing game.
Speaker 0: you know there were ones with graphics before the realm.
Speaker 0: I just weren't ready.
Speaker 0: The realm wasn't really 3D It was yeah, it was.
Speaker 0: it was you know a first-person perspective.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: No it wasn't.
Speaker 0: no no meridian 59.
Speaker 1: Uh the realm was not a first-person was an ultimate online older than now.
Speaker 1: the realm was the first one.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna have to go look that up anyway.
Speaker 1: the point is out of my shirt.
Speaker 1: Oh, don't debate me on this.
Speaker 0: debate you easily here.
Speaker 0: We go.
Speaker 1: You're wrong.
Speaker 0: I'm going to look right now mister.
Speaker 1: All right, so we got to kill air time.
Speaker 0: while you go to Wikipedia I see the realm came out five months before meridian 59. yes Which was in?
Speaker 0: Yes, hold on come on December 31st 1996. yes, Ultima online released Okay, 97.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what was that?
Speaker 1: What was that?
Speaker 1: Did I just win?
Speaker 1: the point is competitive tonight?
Speaker 0: Is that none of those?
Speaker 0: Those games are not the first mo MMOs.
Speaker 0: the first MMO was mud one at Essex as in Essex the college in Britain and that game came out in 1978 and all it was for.
Speaker 0: you know I don't think a lot of people out there know what muds are.
Speaker 0: you know they might have heard of muds and mud is a Multi-user dungeon basically the first mud.
Speaker 0: they took the dungeon mode in zork right which is a basically text adventure game right and They just made it so that multiple people could move around in The dungeon at the same time.
Speaker 0: and the way it worked is.
Speaker 0: they'd be a server.
Speaker 0: you would tell that to the server and You know in your terminal right.
Speaker 0: so this one computer a pdp-11 or pdp-10.
Speaker 0: You know old ass you know digital machine.
Speaker 0: everyone on their terminal connects to the machine and You go around the dungeon.
Speaker 0: You know north east south kill rat kill rat Kill other guy and everyone else is also in the same place.
Speaker 0: So if you go into the same room that someone else happens to be in it says rim is here all right all right.
Speaker 1: So what's the difference between?
Speaker 1: massively multiplayer and multiplayer?
Speaker 1: there's a massively multiplayer and multiplayer because you can't just say you stateful stateless because you could have a Little a game like I don't.
Speaker 1: you can have any kind of game this multiplayer That's stateful, and you can meet each other in a. you could have a mod that only two people play.
Speaker 0: the difference is The number of players.
Speaker 0: you see in a multiplayer game something like counter-strike, right?
Speaker 0: You have many many many servers and each server has this limit of you know say 30 players.
Speaker 0: so even where tribes 2 Has a limit of 60 players or there's some other games out there I've seen some FPS is where the servers have a limit of a hundred something players.
Speaker 0: all right.
Speaker 0: It's not massive.
Speaker 0: What's massive is when the server takes?
Speaker 1: Infinity play, but modern MMOs don't do that.
Speaker 1: they break people up into separate servers Which is BS.
Speaker 0: back in the olden days you join a mud and just people could keep joining the mud and keep joining it Until the server crashed.
Speaker 1: well yeah And the realm was like that too early.
Speaker 1: MMOs were and they changed that because no hardware could scale to deal with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that the real I could.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna talk about the technical solution to that which is obvious and has not yet been executed uh-huh, but Needless to say that the mud is 30 years old today.
Speaker 0: Everyone out there who's thinking about you know or who is now if you've only ever played say wow Or if you've never played any of these games There's still muds.
Speaker 0: you can go to the mud connector and mud still exists.
Speaker 0: you can tell them that to them very easily.
Speaker 0: Don't become involved in muds.
Speaker 0: That's gonna waste a lot of your time like I wasted in high school.
Speaker 0: But go find a mud and explore it and see what it's like and learn and you will see how scarily similar the muds are to the WOWs out there and the Tabula Rasa's and all those other grindy games out there.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much the same exact game.
Speaker 1: Well, there's one difference.
Speaker 1: most muds that I hung around in the maximum level wasn't 60 or 70 or 100.
Speaker 1: It was like five thousand.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it would take you like a year to get while level at some of the higher level.
Speaker 0: the worst part Right was that a lot of these muds.
Speaker 0: You would go around the mud and you would go and you would eventually be fighting the strongest bad guys in the game.
Speaker 0: It'd be no way to level up So strong.
Speaker 0: you would kill like the guards in town in one hit and then be like what the hell am I supposed to do?
Speaker 1: And they're okay.
Speaker 0: get any better equipments.
Speaker 1: I got to level 70.
Speaker 1: I could kill the king killer on the baddest ass in the game trivially.
Speaker 1: He gave me two experience.
Speaker 1: I needed a thousand to get up a level.
Speaker 0: All you could do right was make another character level up just as far and then have you two characters kill each other to get Experienced but when they died they lost experience.
Speaker 0: It was good times.
Speaker 1: now a quick quiz because you know muds weren't the only thing.
Speaker 1: there was this whole, you know back when Avatars and shared spaces were kind of the thing on the internet.
Speaker 1: There were just muds.
Speaker 1: There were mucks mushes moves.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well those came later the mucks mushes and the moves quick.
Speaker 1: What's a move?
Speaker 0: It's a Multi user.
Speaker 0: object oriented is just object oriented.
Speaker 0: That's what I mean.
Speaker 1: Usually people call them moo, duh Because dungeon or whatever at the end But basically that would.
Speaker 1: those were like people.
Speaker 1: programmers would hang out and code Like rooms or code things like.
Speaker 1: everything was object oriented.
Speaker 1: That's that's the best way I'd explain it.
Speaker 1: and mushes were like a role-playing and I was no no moves.
Speaker 0: It didn't stand for a multi-user.
Speaker 0: It stood for mud object oriented.
Speaker 1: that made sense.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz you remember the original, you know Muds were written, you know is written for like this old crappy mainframe computer.
Speaker 0: Well, not crappy You know, the pdp-10 is not a piece of crap.
Speaker 0: Well, at least it wasn't in the day, but you know when object oriented programming came around with object oriented programming You know the having a text adventure built on that type of probe made a lot easier to make a dungeon.
Speaker 0: You know, it's sort of it sort of fits, you know with all these objects in it.
Speaker 0: If you ever played a game like, you know gemstone 3 on AOL or whatever you could really tell.
Speaker 0: you know with all the different crazy stuff going that you can make custom items and stuff like That.
Speaker 0: and that was you know, those sorts of features were easy for the people to program into the game because they were using an object oriented programming language.
Speaker 1: and I forget the exact Difference between a mush and a muck, but I think they were the ones where there were no rules and role players would go Role-playing.
Speaker 1: usually they were scared.
Speaker 0: Well mushes are more like social kind of things Right where there's supposed to be role-playing going on, I guess theoretically.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think I mean, I'm not gonna look it up It's like multi-user shared something.
Speaker 0: Yeah and most I think it was social something.
Speaker 0: and I think muck was chat Kingdom and I don't I don't remember the point of what Those are supposed to be.
Speaker 0: I just remember his check.
Speaker 1: It was for people who was.
Speaker 0: I thought the chat Kingdom was cool.
Speaker 1: Maybe they were just too cool for IRC or IRC was too cool for them.
Speaker 1: I it's hard to tell which yeah.
Speaker 0: But anyway, if you don't know about muds and I think a lot of people out there don't you really should to understand You know gaming history and internet history properly.
Speaker 0: You should really investigate them and you know poke at a few to see what the deal is.
Speaker 0: I still would say now on the 30th anniversary.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't call them MMOs because that word has really come to mean something pretty specific nowadays.
Speaker 1: Well, MMO RPG means something very specific nowadays, and I really would say that well I do.
Speaker 1: writing.
Speaker 1: I would say that from the realm to today is the same era of massively multiplayer games and everything before that Was this entirely different era?
Speaker 0: I do agree that it's sort of.
Speaker 0: it's a different thing now because it's you know, graphical but really not.
Speaker 0: the underlying game Is the exact same thing.
Speaker 0: this it's so it's only it's.
Speaker 0: it's so the exact same thing But it's the same.
Speaker 1: look at all like people say You know first gen platformer second gen platformers or like the NES days the SNES days The fundamental concepts of the games are the same.
Speaker 1: all that's changed is the technology the presentation, you know all those sorts of things.
Speaker 1: No, I do things were made possible by technology.
Speaker 1: It's just the NES era the SNES era.
Speaker 0: The thing is when you look at something like say compare Super Mario Brothers to Mario 64, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's still a platformer.
Speaker 0: It's still jump on the bad guy, etc.
Speaker 0: But the 3d me the 3d ness of it like was game-changing.
Speaker 0: The graphics, you know added to the to the mud to make the end, you know, the modern MMORPG Didn't really change.
Speaker 0: the game is the same game.
Speaker 0: We just look at it I think instead of typing see there's something.
Speaker 1: the complexity has gone to the point where I would call it a different game.
Speaker 1: just because The interface allows so much more The interface allows less.
Speaker 1: a text-based interface is the most flexible of all Interfaces except for the fact that the the vast majority of mods you could type up down left right kill Equip unequip like it was still very rigid.
Speaker 1: And in fact the fact that it was text-based Prevented most people from playing it like in terms of who played why they played how they played.
Speaker 1: Everything is completely different now.
Speaker 1: different kinds of people play for completely different reasons.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that's for sure.
Speaker 1: I just I feel like it's really worth it to use the terms to differentiate between these two eras.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I don't know if those terms are right.
Speaker 0: Well that definitely should be.
Speaker 0: you know a way to differentiate between the two.
Speaker 1: say this Those terms are.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna say this the terms are right and I say they're right because that's how everyone in the world uses them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people there's a you know, there are so many.
Speaker 1: Are you advocating prescriptive language?
Speaker 1: No, that's what's happening here.
Speaker 0: No, where you go with it?
Speaker 0: I'm saying is that there are so many instances in the in the world and especially in the English world and especially on the internet of All sorts of terms being used in literal and non literal and wrong and right and backwards and sideways meanings that I'm really just getting tired of the whole thing and we should just pretty much whatever people using terms weirdly or wrongly Just go out whatever fuck it.
Speaker 1: Why so so then I'm right and that's how those terms are.
Speaker 0: No, I'm saying is that there is no right.
Speaker 0: just let it be whatever.
Speaker 1: Yes, there is no right.
Speaker 1: the meaning of language is determined by the users and the users determine collectively that MMO basically means something different from mud.
Speaker 1: Well, so says you RPG.
Speaker 1: I think most people will agree.
Speaker 1: I call them two separate arrows.
Speaker 1: We'll leave it at that.
Speaker 1: Anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: so Emily showed this to us a long time ago and it's so well executed that I've kind of been just saving it for the day when I would use it as a thing of the Day, and I kind of forgot about it And then I remembered it added it back to my delicious and then I thought hey Didn't I already use this?
Speaker 1: I couldn't find it.
Speaker 1: So Boot to the head Phoenix, right?
Speaker 1: I find this hilarious.
Speaker 1: It's utterly well executed.
Speaker 1: I'll leave it at that.
Speaker 0: Oh I also have a a Phoenix, right if you will really perhaps.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Wait, the site has other things All right.
Speaker 1: Well, you can save those for another day.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I can.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll have to.
Speaker 1: so what's this thing of the day?
Speaker 0: Um So, you know, I guess people on Wednesday shows would be more familiar.
Speaker 0: Of course I think most people listen to all our shows or whatever.
Speaker 0: You know in Japan, they have the garage kits and basically the idea of a garage kit Is that some super nerd like the nerdiest of all nerdy otaku in the universe?
Speaker 0: Makes their own toy or their own figurine or whatever it is.
Speaker 1: Well their own partially nude semi erotic figurine, right?
Speaker 1: Most of the time partially needs Half the time the other times the robots the other half the time.
Speaker 1: It's a robot or a mecha most likely.
Speaker 0: Yes But As a result in Japan, they also just make really high quality toys You know mostly because you got to be able to compete with the garage.
Speaker 0: kids here are four amazing-looking at least as far as I'm concerned Phoenix Wright figures and There's an Emma sky.
Speaker 0: I think I gotta be gotta be sending some monies It's.
Speaker 0: But actually if you look around on the side of this site, I didn't notice.
Speaker 0: There's a whole bunch of other figures.
Speaker 0: I did not notice previously to just two seconds ago including a Lupin and G again in spacesuits.
Speaker 1: Oh snap.
Speaker 0: All right I'll just check this space helmets and show and and possibly the best has any Miku figure I've ever seen I might have to send even more money across the ocean.
Speaker 0: Anyway Phoenix Wright toys that if you're a Phoenix Wright fan, you'll want the end.
Speaker 1: So up, there's a company a video game company called introversion software And if you're not familiar with funny how we're we're not really introverted Huh, huh.
Speaker 1: So, how would that be funny?
Speaker 0: We're talking about introversion, but we're all extroverted.
Speaker 1: That's that's like saying huh funny You're talking about apples.
Speaker 1: You're not an apple.
Speaker 0: No, it's more like funny.
Speaker 0: you're talking about apples.
Speaker 0: you're an orange.
Speaker 1: that's not any.
Speaker 1: Doesn't work anyway If you don't know who they are.
Speaker 1: and I'll admit that I didn't for the longest time.
Speaker 1: But Darwinia Defcon uplink multi winnia all made by the same company.
Speaker 0: right way back in the day I don't know not too far back in the day There was a game called uplink and uplink is a pretty cool game.
Speaker 0: because if you ever watch a movie right movie like hackers Or something right or what was that the net remember that movie?
Speaker 1: Ah, man the net.
Speaker 1: that movie Was very rare.
Speaker 0: It was like some hacks and Wolfenstein 3d in the beginning or something like that.
Speaker 1: That game was very.
Speaker 1: that movie was very reminiscent of the time period from which it was wrong indeed.
Speaker 0: But you ever watch a movie like that and the hacking in the movie doesn't look anything like real hacking.
Speaker 0: You know at least in that one matrix movie like the hacking was.
Speaker 0: she did like this You know sort of frequently, you know, well-known SSH crack and it was just a terminal and someone you know Executing a program and that at least was semi real even though it didn't match what they said they were doing.
Speaker 0: But you know movie hacking it looks like you're like, you know fucking War games or whatever, you know, it's oh it's a map of the world.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch of lines going across it and you know, someone's tracing you.
Speaker 1: Oh, man war games was actually very realistic in attacking though somewhat somewhat More so than hackers in the net.
Speaker 1: at least hackers was what we wish.
Speaker 1: hacking was like hackers.
Speaker 1: Hackers is to hacking and computer science.
Speaker 1: What's the craft was to Wicca, right?
Speaker 0: so uplink was a game that sort of simulated that.
Speaker 0: You know movie hacking like you play it and you're a hacker But you feel like you're a movie hacker because it looks like movie hacking and it's like all vans.
Speaker 0: The game was pretty cool and that game sort of made this company, you know some money and it made them You know popular and well-known.
Speaker 0: it took this indie game company and there was still indie.
Speaker 0: They never didn't make it big, but they made it a little better than the bottom rungs.
Speaker 0: They were able to keep going and keep rocking and they made I think the next game was I've never actually played Darwinia.
Speaker 0: Darwinia is like a single-player RTS kind of game, you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: well, basically I do know this much.
Speaker 1: Here's the history.
Speaker 1: Darwinia came out.
Speaker 1: Everyone said wow, that would have been a great game if it had multiplayer.
Speaker 1: Well,
Speaker 0: it was originally intended to be a multiplayer game, but I guess the technology or whatever at the time prevented them from making it multiplayer it had to be you know, and they ended up just Taking what they did and making the single-player game because that's all they could pull off and around that time.
Speaker 0: They also, you know managed to partner up with valve and steam and they got the distribution You know more prominent and whatnot as opposed to just sort of try to sell it out on their website.
Speaker 0: You know uplink was real slow to catch on and sort of bubbled up from underneath, you know.
Speaker 0: But as soon as they you know valve steam came around it was like aha.
Speaker 0: Here's those guys.
Speaker 1: There they are But we're not gonna talk about all their other games.
Speaker 1: I don't really want to talk a lot about the company though some of that will be unavoidable at the end of this because There's kind of a sad tale to multi-winia.
Speaker 1: but multi-winia basically Scott played the demo and then he bought it and I basically Based on what I had heard from everyone else bought the game sight unseen.
Speaker 1: I just assumed All right, this game is gonna be great and I just bought it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, Darwinia was this, you know when I played Darwinia, it was basically I was a little air with the controls.
Speaker 0: I mean I played.
Speaker 0: actually a really early versions are winning had like these mouse gestures and weird crap going on and whatnot.
Speaker 0: But it was a game that it was like an RTS.
Speaker 0: but it wasn't an RTS, you know.
Speaker 0: instead of you know It's like controlling individual guys.
Speaker 0: You sort of had these Darwinians everywhere and you controlled sort of their flow, you know You had.
Speaker 0: you would upgrade Darwinians to be like, okay You're now a commander and he would you know say everyone go over there.
Speaker 0: so any Darwinians that were near him would do what he said to do.
Speaker 0: and You know, you could do certain things like drop bombs here or send an engineer over there and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: But but you know, it solved all the problems I had with.
Speaker 0: RTS is of the past which was you know really fiddly controls of manipulating lots and lots of tiny things and making it difficult to actually execute a strategy of any sort.
Speaker 1: because I've been really I Mean, I love the idea of RTS and I love strategic combat and yeah, it's like it.
Speaker 0: It's like a turn-based, you know strategy game a war game, but it's in real time.
Speaker 0: So it's not slow You don't sit there forever and ever and ever.
Speaker 1: I beat both sides of command and conquer.
Speaker 1: and yet I really in retrospect Like I kept trying to tell myself.
Speaker 1: This is great.
Speaker 1: But honestly, I hated every minute of it.
Speaker 1: It was just a it was absolutely unfun and I hated it.
Speaker 1: I absolutely hated it and I hate most RTS.
Speaker 1: is to be perfectly honest.
Speaker 0: I don't hate RTS.
Speaker 0: This is weird.
Speaker 0: It's like I actually like them.
Speaker 0: The problem is is that whenever I play multiplayer say multiplayer Starcraft, right or even just skirmish spacecraft I pick a map and it's one-on-one, you know me against the computer on the easiest or normal mode, right?
Speaker 0: And it's not the campaign to the campaign.
Speaker 0: I can actually get pretty far.
Speaker 0: It's in the you know, just regular battle mode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you both start with you know, the one unit and you go for it.
Speaker 0: I Just they.
Speaker 0: they kill me every single time.
Speaker 0: I can't even get anywhere I just get crushed.
Speaker 0: Well see and I can't.
Speaker 0: it's like you have to memorize the exact right order to build the things in and click quickly enough to Build them without wasting any time.
Speaker 0: and then you know And the end goal is pretty much build the biggest bestest units as many as you can.
Speaker 0: not necessarily.
Speaker 1: sometimes it's build a lot of small weak units and send them at your opponent's
Speaker 0: if you're the Zerg or you know, but You build whatever it is You're supposed to build and then send it at the enemy and then you win or you might have to do it again.
Speaker 0: You know, it's not it's not a lot of complexity going on there.
Speaker 1: The reason I guess I said I hate RTS is that every time I play one I envision strategy I envision, you know I'll send this unit to the north on a scouting expedition to Skirmish and see if there are any bad guys in those woods so I can get those resources.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, I want an actual skirmish line here and I want like I have all these supply lines and strategies and I think all this out.
Speaker 1: but then the game either by interface or by design or by just anything about it Will not actually let me play that kind of game and not playing a very different kind of game Where the strategies usually boil down very quickly to either as Scott said clicking quickly or Memorizing a pattern or there's usually a very small number of specific ways to win.
Speaker 0: Yeah that like for example in Warcraft 3 right for any.
Speaker 0: My brother played that a lot and he was actually pretty good at it.
Speaker 0: And the thing is basically the idea that game was number one.
Speaker 0: you manage this heroes.
Speaker 0: He had to play this little hero game while you played the.
Speaker 0: you know The regular RTS and basically the goal is to level up the hero because he only had one and not let him die.
Speaker 0: All right, the other part of the game was you know build up and you pretty much picked one units.
Speaker 0: Like if you were the orcs say right you could go.
Speaker 0: I don't remember the specifics of I'm wrong shoot me.
Speaker 0: You could go for like the Torrens or say the dragons, right?
Speaker 0: So the orcs had like, you know, three or four big units to choose from.
Speaker 0: she would go for one of those.
Speaker 0: So they're actually like four different patterns to choose from but it was more of a rock-paper-scissors kind of thing.
Speaker 0: You know if the other guy picked this thing then it was better for you to pick dragons.
Speaker 0: But you have to go and find out and if you spent the time to go and find out you would fall behind in the Race to get you know, your guys built fast enough and whatnot.
Speaker 0: and it wasn't really a game of military strategy or anything like that.
Speaker 0: it was a game of remember one of the patterns.
Speaker 0: Execute the pattern that you remembered.
Speaker 0: do it as quickly as possible.
Speaker 0: Don't let the hero die.
Speaker 0: level up the hero.
Speaker 0: the end.
Speaker 0: but
Speaker 1: thus why I always ended up hating RTS is I'd play them Much like when I played WarioWare for the Wii and the whole time I would think This could be so much better than it is and could be so much more than it is and I'd always think about the game I want to be playing.
Speaker 1: Realize that the game I was playing was not that game.
Speaker 1: turn it off and go play weapons factory Yeah, or counter-strike.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the one problem in the of wanting the RTS that you want.
Speaker 0: I also want the RTS that you want, right?
Speaker 1: I actually wrote something in high school.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's probably on that stupid hard drive I have that's crashed.
Speaker 1: that also has the eight people monologue.
Speaker 1: uh-huh, but I wrote this long thing.
Speaker 1: that was basically.
Speaker 1: I Set forth all the precursors that would need to exist technologically and programmatically To allow the kind of RTS I want to.
Speaker 0: yeah, I think the bait.
Speaker 0: think about right what it takes to do.
Speaker 0: You know the real military, you know in real time you have these, you know hierarchy of command, you know One person gives a very generic command but another person breaks it down another person breaks it down.
Speaker 0: eventually you have like this squad commander who breaks it down into.
Speaker 0: you walk That way you walk that way, you know, I need that whole structure and so an art.
Speaker 0: It's very difficult to make a game where you are at the top But yet are you know doing the work of this entire chain of command in real time a turn-based games?
Speaker 0: You can pull it off because you have all the time in the world in a real time game.
Speaker 0: It's sort of impossible without incredibly advanced AI or well a whole bunch of physical human players all on the same team all taking money.
Speaker 1: you say that because I had a ten-point list of these are the ten things that must Exist and I remember that I wrote better AI Nine times and most of the paper was talking about all the reasons you need AI to have a true RTS.
Speaker 1: exactly I think that multi-winnier I was about to say we should stop talking about RTS is the thing that multi-winnier gets, right?
Speaker 0: Is much like Darwinia.
Speaker 0: You don't control the individual units.
Speaker 0: You control very few units who are sort of like you're at the top of the hierarchy of military command.
Speaker 0: You command these big Darwinian guys, you know And you have a few other commands you can do and the actual the troops just sort of do what the few big guys You know are commanding them to do and thus you can actually you know control a bigger Your mass of forces in a complex and more strategic way and it's not perfect we're gonna get to that.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like you can set up all your like flows of guys and units and stuff and then you zoom out Watch the situation watch what the other guys doing and then react accordingly like ah I should direct more guys to that Eastern Front because he's really laying it on there or There's a crate over there and I see him going toward it.
Speaker 1: I better send a formation that way to stop him exactly.
Speaker 1: and I really wanted to like multi-winnier.
Speaker 1: Like I when I start played through the demo.
Speaker 1: and if Here's where this sad tale really begins.
Speaker 1: I bought multi-winnier installed it.
Speaker 1: I heard great things.
Speaker 0: Well, the sad tale begins with the fact that they were selling multi-winnier right in a pack 20 bucks.
Speaker 0: You get multi-winnier and Darwinian.
Speaker 0: I already owned Darwinia now when Valve sold us the orange box and I bought it, right?
Speaker 0: I already owned most of the games in it except for portal and tf2 and Half-life episode 2. so they gave me a free copy of half-life 2 and a free copy of half-life episode 1 to give to someone Else.
Speaker 0: now rim did not own Darwinian and I did so.
Speaker 0: I thought that by buying the pack with Darwinian and multi-winnier for 20 Bucks, I'd get a free copy of Darwinian and be able to give it to somebody, right?
Speaker 0: No such luck.
Speaker 0: I basically have paid for Dart Darwinia twice and only gotten it once.
Speaker 0: That was the beginning of the badness.
Speaker 1: now for me the beginning was I install it I Go to the menu.
Speaker 1: I look around.
Speaker 1: I spent 10 minutes Trying to find the menu to change my controls and I kept thinking it's got to be here.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'm stupid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I gotta find.
Speaker 0: and normally, you know changing controls and an RTS isn't a big deal because it's you know Just move the mouse around and click on things and sort of a two-dimensional plane and then you know They're you know hotkeys for some shortcuts that not too many people change.
Speaker 0: I guess some people change them but not that I.
Speaker 1: you know, I don't know this game.
Speaker 1: You basically have your three.
Speaker 1: that your two-dimensional movement, you know strafing and moving forward and back and they're hard-coded to WASD.
Speaker 0: yeah, cuz it's it's a 3d game and You're most of the controls are camera control, you know turn rotate I will say one zoom in zooming out.
Speaker 1: There is no reason for this game to actually be 3d.
Speaker 0: The 3d really isn't.
Speaker 0: for the game to be 3d is because of the terrain going.
Speaker 0: You know having highs and lows and the guy, you know moving up a hill and moving down a hill.
Speaker 1: That's the reason for the game to be yeah But at the same time you could have had the same effect with the game that was More two-dimensional and thus easier to control and easier to see.
Speaker 1: but I digress that's true.
Speaker 1: So Alright, I have to use WASD now.
Speaker 1: I've never used WASD like in my entire life.
Speaker 1: I use completely different sets of control.
Speaker 0: I never used WASD either until I get the happy I can keyboard that I just forced myself to use it.
Speaker 0: cuz I said You know what?
Speaker 0: You know, I won't have Big arrows like I did in my previous keyboards.
Speaker 0: every game uses WASD by default.
Speaker 0: I'll just get used to it even though I hate it and then it'll be real easy to play every game And it's paid off.
Speaker 0: I'm kind of I can understand.
Speaker 0: if I'd never bought the happy hacking keyboard I'll be right there with rim rim bitching and moaning that it's forces you to use WASD.
Speaker 1: I kind of could be okay with WASD except for the fact that W is way off to the left.
Speaker 0: That's that was my problem too.
Speaker 0: That's why I never liked it.
Speaker 0: I just forced myself to get used to that.
Speaker 1: I just made sure nothing was bound to ease.
Speaker 1: So when I hit E and W at the same time, it didn't cause a problem.
Speaker 1: But alright, I can deal with that.
Speaker 1: I'll live with that.
Speaker 1: Mouse isn't inverted and that that is much more crippling than I would have expected.
Speaker 0: Yeah there I mean I don't use the inverted Mouse unless I'm in a vehicle of some sort usually a flying vehicle and then I must have an inverted Mouse.
Speaker 0: but I can understand if someone wants an inverted Mouse in their 3d games and they don't got it.
Speaker 1: It seems like I mean a lot of people most new FPSers definitely use the non inverted Mouse and a lot of old FPSers use the inverted Mouse.
Speaker 1: But it looks like it's 50/50 or at least 60/40 in favor of non inverted.
Speaker 1: But a lot of people use an inverted Mouse and I remember at PAX we were playing a demo of some you know tribes like game and Of the like 20 people standing around playing there were like 10.
Speaker 1: Well there were more like 8 people gaga who couldn't play because it was not inverted and they couldn't figure out how to make it inverted.
Speaker 1: But this game I can't invert it.
Speaker 1: so between the WASD and the fact that I can't invert I really can't play the game because all my muscle memory causes me to always zoom.
Speaker 1: I'm okay when I'm like you know standing up the game in the beginning But as soon as I need to be reacting quickly I just cannot control the game at all.
Speaker 0: like I can't play multi-winia Yeah, I am able to play it.
Speaker 0: You know I sort of got used even though there are other problems in the controls that I have issue with.
Speaker 0: you know Like it sometimes you can't select the guys you want exactly.
Speaker 0: and you know sometimes like it's you'll you'll tell a guy to go in One direction, and he sort of takes a different path.
Speaker 0: And you know sometimes you'll tell it's hard to get the guys to make Formations sometimes because the way to make a formation is to click on a guy then click right next to him But if there's something else right next to him you might click on that and you can't always get the formation exactly the way you want it Yeah, and you can't tell the guys to strafe.
Speaker 0: It's like if you want a formation in a particular place facing a certain direction You might actually have to tell him to walk one way then rotate now Then walk another way.
Speaker 1: that I agree with because that is though That is the element of the formations that causes them to be so strategic.
Speaker 1: Those are the kinds of concerns that formation fighting has had since the dawn.
Speaker 0: I mean phalanx but a form but a formation of dudes.
Speaker 0: you could order them in practice and have them all walk, right?
Speaker 1: Depending on the formation maybe not.
Speaker 1: there were a lot of formations that couldn't.
Speaker 1: also without that restriction Formations become an order of magnitude more powerful because of the way they're implemented And it really removes one of the few really strategic things in that book one of the few really Tactical things in that game.
Speaker 1: the formations being the way they are I think is perfect.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, it's just sometimes, you know what you want to execute you can't do and the only other you know complaint in that of that variety that I have is that sometimes like I'll tell a Formation to move and like I'll say formation move like, you know just forward a little bit right and the guy like starts spinning around in his circle and then all the guys a bunch up and It doesn't you know, it's like come on.
Speaker 0: This is simple guys.
Speaker 0: All right, it just messes up.
Speaker 0: Sometimes sometimes they'll walk into a wall, you know, come on all RTS is walking in the walls.
Speaker 0: I thought we figured that one out at least.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know how many men I lost to my own harvesters.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so This is not the problem.
Speaker 1: I mean, these are minor things.
Speaker 1: I could even overlook the control thing because the game is what is otherwise good.
Speaker 1: But if you go online right now, you know, you just you have multi.
Speaker 1: when you buy it and you say hey I want to play a game with someone and you click on you know servers and you look There is currently one Game of multi when you're going on and it is full.
Speaker 0: Wow one.
Speaker 1: There are two other games, but they say beta test and it doesn't look like I can join them.
Speaker 1: They're also.
Speaker 1: they only have one person in each of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's kind of sad.
Speaker 1: No, I can't join them.
Speaker 0: I mean when the game first came out right there were looked like there were a whole bunch of games going on online but really there was a bug that made single-player games show up online and So it looked like there was a lot of games being played.
Speaker 0: after they fixed that bug It was sort of barren and not only that but the multiplayer.
Speaker 0: a lot of it just didn't work.
Speaker 1: now reports vary but The agreement seems to be that for the first couple days after multi when he was released a lot of people just couldn't play online.
Speaker 0: Well, I remember when Def Con came out Right that also had a lot of problems where it just the multiplayer didn't work.
Speaker 0: a lot of times He said connecting one two three and the mistake they made is that you know If you play so look if you want to play something like half-life 2 right someone else set up a server somewhere and everyone connects To it and plays.
Speaker 0: hooray If you want to play, you know, if you try to set up your own half-life server It's a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: You set up your port forwarding on your router and you got to get a static IP and all the other, you know It's a pain.
Speaker 0: It's not it's not easy.
Speaker 0: It didn't know about networking at least somewhat Darwinian multi when it being PC games.
Speaker 0: in the modern era where pretty much everyone has a NAT router Alright, and all the NAT routers are different You when you want to play multiplayer you either join which means directly connect to someone else's computer or someone directly connects to you.
Speaker 0: The solution to this is do it.
Speaker 0: Skype does right.
Speaker 0: Skype also has this problem.
Speaker 0: The way Skype solved it is they have an intermediary server that does some net busting.
Speaker 0: They did not provide this.
Speaker 0: thus you're trying to connect directly connect your computer or Directly host on your computer a server for other people to connect you on the internet.
Speaker 0: It's a mess of the port forwarding and the routing and all this network stuff and it they work.
Speaker 1: The thing is it worked for a lot of people but it didn't work for everyone and it didn't work for enough people.
Speaker 1: early on to where there was a lot of Bad taste in the mouth of the internet and we only we tried to play a LAN game and it didn't work.
Speaker 0: And we know what we're doing now.
Speaker 1: luckily it didn't work and it didn't work.
Speaker 1: and then the next day it worked We finally got it to work.
Speaker 0: It was, you know, huge pain, but even then just I don't know.
Speaker 1: I feel like the game had such potential.
Speaker 1: and I talked more about the game.
Speaker 1: You know, I play all the different modes and the game's really fun and I'd like to play it but I think I'm only gonna be playing it with front row crew people or Scott or Alex or people like that because No one's playing it online and the game is basically dead.
Speaker 0: Well, that's that's a problem we could talk about a little bit and then I'll talk about the game modes and whatnot And that'll be.
Speaker 0: it is that multi, you know online games sort of have this momentum problem, right?
Speaker 0: Where if no one is playing the game online No one else will start playing the game because no one's online and you can see this.
Speaker 0: For example, if you look at you know natural selection, right?
Speaker 0: If you go look at the list of natural selection servers at any given moment in time Every server will either be empty right
Speaker 1: or
Speaker 0: it will have a bunch of bots All right, and maybe someone's playing with the bots but not you really or it'll be crazy full and crowded.
Speaker 0: And the thing is no one wants to join the server.
Speaker 0: That's zero.
Speaker 0: everyone wants to join in where there's other people already playing and Thus if no one's playing you have this catch-22 of no one's going to play.
Speaker 0: No one's going to start a server if there aren't any out there.
Speaker 0: So you might have a million people looking at this list of servers where it says zero and they could be playing with each other.
Speaker 0: But nobody clicks.
Speaker 0: play No one because they don't want to join the zero.
Speaker 0: You know if I join a natural selection server with zero and get one of you know An FRC person to also join it to get the number to two Suddenly the server fills up every time.
Speaker 0: guaranteed BAM.
Speaker 0: the server fills up every time.
Speaker 0: so I think that You know multi Winnie is having this problem right now where there's.
Speaker 0: you know, the community isn't big by any means.
Speaker 0: But there might be 20 people out there looking at this list of zero not playing.
Speaker 1: No, because I every time I make a server no one ever joins ever Ever ever ever.
Speaker 0: but it could be the network problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's hard to say.
Speaker 1: but they what they really needed was an outside server with like a ready room someplace people could chat set of Ladders have state they should have like staged events where they say yeah at five o'clock Everyone join the the big official server.
Speaker 0: and well, this is also right.
Speaker 0: This is what Nintendo got wrong to is that they didn't do online Multiplayer the way it had been done for ages and the way that it always worked properly the way that you know The way the counter-strike does it the way that tribes even tribes do did it, right?
Speaker 0: You know it just they died for other reasons.
Speaker 1: But there are more problems than this.
Speaker 1: Even even if you get someone to join your game like someone you buy the game.
Speaker 1: you're new you want to play online with someone.
Speaker 1: The only people left playing multi-winning who will join your game are people who are a million times better than you and will crush you Immediately.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So the game is now almost a hundred percent new bun friendly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no one.
Speaker 0: that's why a lot of games let you know It's even other RTS is like Warcraft 3 and whatnot.
Speaker 0: sort of have this, you know ranking system where it's like aha It'll match you up with someone who's a similar rank and if you keep crushing people it raises your rank up.
Speaker 1: You know the Nintendo matchup system for like Mario Kart would have worked better than what multi-winning has now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually that would have worked better because all you would do is say I want to play multi-winning And then boom you're in a game with someone, huh?
Speaker 0: You know and it tries to match you up with someone or the relative skill level.
Speaker 1: I just feel like the game Was a really good concept and great ideas.
Speaker 1: But it's like they forgot all the basics of making a multiplayer game.
Speaker 0: exactly what I'm trying to say Can't change the controls.
Speaker 1: That's like the immortal sin of a PC game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a flash game out right now.
Speaker 0: That's that's making the rounds right and it's basically just a platformer.
Speaker 0: But it's a little bit parkour esque in many ways and you're basically trying to navigate a you know A platform place and whatnot, but and avoid dangerous robots, but the controls on it are messed up.
Speaker 0: It's it's difficult to make tiny and subtle jumps because of the way the controls are set up.
Speaker 0: and so many games these days Are great in many aspects.
Speaker 0: They've got the ideas great.
Speaker 0: Even the execution of the idea is great.
Speaker 0: But all the fundamental things that are just sort of basic things to come into all games are messed up.
Speaker 0: The controls are not smooth.
Speaker 0: You know the multiplayer doesn't work, you know There's basic things like that.
Speaker 0: These people are failing on.
Speaker 0: you can't customize the controls and if they didn't fail on those, you know Fundamental things that need to be true and set in a certain way for all games.
Speaker 1: There'd be a lot more awesome games out there but making a PC game where you can't just in a menu change your controls in this modern era is Like making a car that doesn't have doors.
Speaker 0: Yeah, seriously bad.
Speaker 1: when someone complained saying well, what would you want doors for?
Speaker 1: No one else has doors.
Speaker 1: Everyone else is fine with outdoors.
Speaker 0: It's like NASCAR climbing the window, right?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Okay Yeah, so before just let's talk about the cool game modes and multi winning because multi winning does have cool game modes.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's like domination.
Speaker 0: just you'll be Is basically there are spawn points where that are you know army generators and you basically try to capture more than the other guys.
Speaker 1: So it's fun.
Speaker 0: Usually the maps are symmetrical.
Speaker 0: It's fair, you know, you fight whatever this king of the hill Which is where there's these scoring zones and you try to get more of your guys in the scoring zones per unit time.
Speaker 0: So it's not who has them at the end It's you know, every guy you have in there and every second that they're in there you're getting points.
Speaker 0: So you try to just funnel all your guys into these scoring zones to get more points than the other guy.
Speaker 1: I'd say that's the second most fun mode.
Speaker 0: It's pretty fun.
Speaker 1: My favorite mode is statue.
Speaker 0: That is pretty good.
Speaker 1: Go grab this statue and your little dudes have to carry it back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you you have these statues right.
Speaker 0: you send guys over to the statue They pick it up and try to carry the statues to the scoring zones.
Speaker 0: And if you want the maps are symmetrical yet again, so you could you know, just play along with the other guy.
Speaker 0: No one fights each other and you just each capture an equal number of statues and the game's over.
Speaker 0: But when guys are cat, you know, the more guys you have at a statue the more they lift it.
Speaker 0: but guys carrying a statue can't fight.
Speaker 0: so you need to send guys over to defend the statue.
Speaker 0: and You know, if you don't have enough guys at a statue, they'll drag it slower or they might even drop it.
Speaker 0: So it's really easy to go and attack the other guy carrying the statue and fuck him up and then it gets pretty rough.
Speaker 0: one of the modes I like best is sort of like the assault mode where there's big bases that are set up at the beginning and One side is the defender of the base and one side is the attacker and the attacker gets floods and floods of guys.
Speaker 0: but the defender has this really good entrenched position with turrets and everything and You're starting to keep them it to basically protect your base until the end.
Speaker 0: And the only other mode that I can remember right now is the the nuke mode Which is actually pretty creative and how it works.
Speaker 0: There's these Sort of solar panels and you send your guys out to capture your solar panels and the solar panels fuel your rocket Right, and so you're fighting over all these solar panels in different areas of the map.
Speaker 0: But you've also got the rocket.
Speaker 0: now you want your rocket to get a hundred percent fuel and liftoff before the other guy Does just that.
Speaker 0: now?
Speaker 0: Even when it gets two hundred percent fuel or even before it gets two hundred percent fuel You can actually attack the other guys rocket directly.
Speaker 0: Thus, you know you could the other guy could get to a hundred percent fuel.
Speaker 0: then you go blow up his rocket.
Speaker 0: now You've got you know, even if you had less solar panels than he did you've got you know, seventy percent fuel He's got zero.
Speaker 0: what's gonna view now?
Speaker 0: Defend that rocket and then you win.
Speaker 0: It's so it's actually sort of like this crazy, you know Strategies that can emerge of.
Speaker 0: you know, should I go for more solar panels thus having less guys to defend my rocket?
Speaker 0: Should I you know just try to defend my rocket get a few solar panels that he won't bother taking from me and then attack His rocket with a crazy powerful force when it gets close to full but then taking the risk that it takes off and it Gets pretty hairy.
Speaker 0: So it is clever game modes.
Speaker 0: You have an RTS where you sort of can you don't control things at the minute level so you can actually deal with it And it's fun.
Speaker 0: and and you know, not complex strategies.
Speaker 0: Well, not uber complex, but decent enough strategies emerge.
Speaker 0: It's not just about clicking fast or remembering a pattern, you know, it's about you know, controlling the flow of units Almost more like Tron than like most RTS is You know watching how the other guys flow changes and changing your own flow accordingly.
Speaker 0: But the fundamentals of the game the things that are common to all games the network You know the networking changing your control and before basic user and before anyone writes to us with some angry hate mail.
Speaker 1: Yes, I am aware of the hack way to change your controls.
Speaker 1: it is hackish to the extreme.
Speaker 1: It still doesn't fix half the things I want to do with the controls.
Speaker 1: it's and that's so newbie unfriendly that Basically if introversion expects that to be the answer to basically have to hack your own game to change the controls You're not gonna make any more sales with hacking.
Speaker 0: It doesn't count.
Speaker 0: It's like oh our game doesn't have that problem because you can hack it in.
Speaker 0: if you want to make that Excuse right then I can make the same argument that you know GTA had prod in it because you could hack it.
Speaker 0: right now if something is hacked into a game It's not part of the game and cannot be judged as part of the game.
Speaker 0: It is separate and it does not.
Speaker 0: you know, excuse the fact that you know.
Speaker 0: Oh the network works.
Speaker 0: if you just employ this patch that you get from some untrustworthy source.
Speaker 0: No, the network doesn't work, you know, you can change the controls.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you employ this, you know incredibly difficult thing over here and you don't bind anything to equals.
Speaker 1: God help you If you if you bind anything to equals.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right, that doesn't work either.
Speaker 1: I guess it's just Introversion kind of dropped the ball on this one and unless they fix all these problems and kind of re-release the game I would already call multi-winning effectively dead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is a problem.
Speaker 0: right as you put out a game you have problems.
Speaker 0: Even if you fix it, it's really hard to bring a game back from the dead.
Speaker 0: You know, you got to From the dead.
Speaker 0: You have to find some source of players that will surge into the game and just fill it up as if it were a new Game.
Speaker 0: and with an indie title like this that's not uber popular.
Speaker 0: and you know It only appeals to a sort of a hardcore niche off to the side Demographic, you know because it who does it appeal to?
Speaker 0: it doesn't appeal really to RTS people.
Speaker 0: They're going for Starcraft 2 and whatnot.
Speaker 0: It doesn't appeal to you know, you know I guess it appeals to some indie, you know people who are Into the indie game.
Speaker 1: it appeals to introversion fans and it appeals to me But I can't play the game because the controls are on a whack.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh, that's the thing.
Speaker 0: You're appealing to the heart, you know, if this game was trying to aim for a less heart You know was.
Speaker 0: it was more of a you know a general game for the masses.
Speaker 0: you can get away without Inverted mouse because only you know gamers care about inverted mouse, you know to be honest people Self-identified gamers would care about inverted mouse.
Speaker 0: No one else would care.
Speaker 0: But you know, they know that the only this is only available on like Steam and their website.
Speaker 0: It's not like a game you buy at Walmart.
Speaker 0: So you can't leave that shit out.
Speaker 0: You're just asking for it Isn't it on the Xbox?
Speaker 0: Is it?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: How could you play it on the Xbox?
Speaker 0: That must be a nightmare.
Speaker 1: It would probably be better than what I got going now.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't know if it's Anything else.
Speaker 1: if I were them they probably would have done much better to release it on the Xbox if they're gonna make it.
Speaker 0: Also, you know Def Con had network problems and so did multi-winning.
Speaker 0: if introversion if you don't yeah, if you don't die because of you know, the the lack of success for multi-winning if you're still around to make another game, I Suggest that you you know, write new netcode or come up with some sort of new network thing.
Speaker 0: Maybe even you know spend some of your you know short, you know low funds to get some sort of server setup.
Speaker 0: You know to.
Speaker 0: you know resolve these network issues so that it's very easy for evil.
Speaker 0: this, you know I'll start the game and play done.
Speaker 0: It works.
Speaker 1: You have a server online Populated with servers that are look like real games, but are actually bots from your end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or just trick have people that work at introversion, you know when the game is new Just play the game turn all day.
Speaker 0: Yeah Get some interns to play the game to give people someone to play against.
Speaker 0: and you know have them Play on easy mode and help people out and be nice and new friendly, you know I talked about muds at the start of the show and one thing about muds is that when you joined a mud for the first time Even though not everyone in the mud was awesome, right?
Speaker 0: They would always be if the mud wasn't dead someone in the mud playing who would stop playing because you know who needs to grind That much and come and talk to you and teach you how to play the mud Even if you'd never played a mud before in your life.
Speaker 0: They would show you around tell you what to do give you some items all that good stuff And I think a lot of you know More difficult multiplayer games nowadays could really use something like that and it you know, it just doesn't happen.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know doesn't happen on Nintendo cuz there's no chat and it doesn't happen You know here because they don't run any servers.
Speaker 1: Oh luckily, I Can still play NS and I've been playing more NS than I have been pretty much any game for the last couple weeks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've been.
Speaker 0: I've been mostly reading but I'm almost done with this book and then video games will be.
Speaker 1: fourth This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 0: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.