Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, November 25th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight left for dead.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Oh Feels a long time since we made a show, huh?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, it's been that long.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, but the first thing I got I got a few items to take care of here.
Speaker 1: Oh, do you?
Speaker 0: yeah, the first one is that this Thursday, which would have been the next episode Right was scheduled to be the book episode.
Speaker 1: because you know You could have just not said anything and no one would have remembered No, but could have just said without any preface just hey and don't forget the next Thursday show is the book one But this Thursday is Thanksgiving.
Speaker 0: So this is not gonna be a show.
Speaker 1: Oh, there might be a show.
Speaker 1: No, ah, well, there's probably gonna be a show.
Speaker 1: No, I'll make a show.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, you can make a show on Thursday, but the Thursday after that.
Speaker 0: so two weeks Which would be that gets the second week in December will be the book episode.
Speaker 0: and the book is you know The first book of you know You know, you acted like you didn't know.
Speaker 0: it's the first, you know tales of earth.
Speaker 0: see the first book.
Speaker 0: and I met.
Speaker 0: speaking of that book I met water is poison in the city today because his his Georgia Tech marching band is in the Macy's Parade sees And he was telling me he read the book pretty much on the way here on the bus.
Speaker 0: It didn't take very long at all.
Speaker 0: That's why I chose the book cuz a lot of you people don't read.
Speaker 0: This is like it's an easy book like a middle like it's like a middle school kid book.
Speaker 0: All right, you can read it.
Speaker 0: It's cheap.
Speaker 0: It's tiny.
Speaker 0: Get the book and read it.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna put the link in today's episode to remind you and two weeks from now We will actually talk about this book.
Speaker 1: Well, if you need a more more, I don't know prerogative more incentive I'll warn you if you don't read this book and you're thinking you'll hold out until the next book I'm picking the next book.
Speaker 1: Yeah Take that as you may.
Speaker 0: Second item right because it is Thanksgiving on Thursday a holiday only United States people celebrate.
Speaker 0: But uh, I think the United States constitutes the majority of our audience.
Speaker 0: I am Reinstituting my Thanksgiving thing from last Thanksgiving.
Speaker 0: Send me our cornucopias.
Speaker 0: last time I got one Cornucopia, it was pretty good.
Speaker 0: It was an awesome cornucopia.
Speaker 0: It was like the best cornucopia I've seen in my life But it was only one.
Speaker 0: so Make yigi cornucopias for me.
Speaker 0: I want them and also don't want your copias.
Speaker 1: don't worry that these will go into some internet void because Part of the new website will eventually have galleries and places to show off stuff.
Speaker 0: people have sent us Yes, including a special cornucopia page.
Speaker 1: You still have that old cornucopia.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: I have all cornucopias.
Speaker 0: I am a collector.
Speaker 1: you have one.
Speaker 1: Yes And also even if you collect you can't have all of them.
Speaker 0: I have every geeky cornucopia worth having.
Speaker 1: oh Do you I do but I thought you only had one.
Speaker 0: That's everyone worth having right right right this right now?
Speaker 0: video games.
Speaker 0: you have video games I don't know.
Speaker 1: I thought you had some.
Speaker 1: you made like you had this news.
Speaker 1: You won't tell me.
Speaker 0: Oh, you want to go to news?
Speaker 0: I thought you had something to say about video games before news.
Speaker 1: No I'm playing video games.
Speaker 0: Ah, me too.
Speaker 0: Mostly NS and left for dead.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: and pie crust.
Speaker 0: Hi cross fucking pie crust, you know, I still haven't even opened.
Speaker 1: order ecclesia.
Speaker 0: No, you know chrono trigger comes out.
Speaker 0: I think on.
Speaker 1: I know I pre-ordered it.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right I don't know.
Speaker 0: you could have waited.
Speaker 0: it would have been cheaper later.
Speaker 1: I've beaten that game like a hundred times.
Speaker 0: I've beaten it at least two times once on regular once on plus mode.
Speaker 1: I've got it have memorized.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got a half memorized too.
Speaker 0: Well, I start my memory only gets fuzzy once he gets like caveman land.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah So check this out Richard Bartle, do you know Richard Bartle is?
Speaker 1: I've no idea.
Speaker 0: He's the guy who made the mud the original mud right apparently Despite making and inventing the mud for all intents and purposes, you know Just as much as I guess Alexander Graham Bell invented the telephone.
Speaker 0: He likes playing Wow and that that alone is shocking.
Speaker 0: but He's talking about the wrath of the Lich King, right and he put this post up on I guess his blog and he's complaining about this quest early on in the game.
Speaker 0: and Basically, it's a quite want.
Speaker 1: you kill six snow moose.
Speaker 0: Yes kill six.
Speaker 0: No moose.
Speaker 0: No This quest basically is a. it's a pretty simple quest.
Speaker 0: You know, you take this needling rod of some sort and You go find this prisoner and you torture them for information.
Speaker 0: Basically, you needle them until they tell you what you need to know and then you complete the quest.
Speaker 1: Congratulations, but in Warcraft wouldn't this be basically you have the needler you find the guy you stand in front of him I'd like hold down whatever but that's that's pretty much all you have to do.
Speaker 0: the what his problem Richard Bartle's problem?
Speaker 1: they're gay.
Speaker 1: one kids could guess that his problem is that you're Torturing someone in game.
Speaker 0: perhaps but that's not just.
Speaker 1: that's not his only problem You see see cuz the other way to go would be.
Speaker 1: maybe his problem is that the torture is lame and not realistic.
Speaker 0: No, no He's the crux of his problem.
Speaker 0: Is that you can't decide not to You can't say you can't you know, the guy comes up to you and says hey torture this prisoner.
Speaker 0: You can't say no, it's it's you either do it or you're stuck and you can't continue.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much the way all quests and all MMOs have always been.
Speaker 0: You know, that's true to some extent.
Speaker 0: but the thing is I think about the old muds.
Speaker 0: Right the old muds.
Speaker 0: and even though the old muds, you know, they were no, you know burning wheel They they were you know They they didn't have.
Speaker 1: usually the choices.
Speaker 1: if you were on a quest in the old muds was The king is giving you a quest do you accept?
Speaker 1: and if you say no he kills you.
Speaker 0: well Yeah, that was quite often.
Speaker 0: but there were you know attempts to give because those things were based on D&D.
Speaker 0: There were some attempts to give you choices and things and you know make things matter.
Speaker 0: and you had like You're all you had actually had an alignment that would you know change from you know?
Speaker 0: Lawful to neutral and good depending on what you did, you know, even the realm had that.
Speaker 1: I mean, I remember you you started out good neutral evil, whatever.
Speaker 0: I pick neutral because if you start, you know, if you go to the one place and kill angels you become evil.
Speaker 0: But if you go to the other place and kill the devil's you become good.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, you steal from people you become evil.
Speaker 1: And I remember I became evil in order to get the multi blade aka the multi pass Which was not nearly as powerful or cool as I thought it would be once I got it.
Speaker 0: But it does make me realize something in that That even that simple Effectively useless.
Speaker 0: right, you know alignment decision mechanism that was in the older muds is apparently completely non-existent in Wow and even that all you know tiny bit of nothing is better than nothing.
Speaker 0: and it is kind of sad.
Speaker 0: and Not only that but he says You know, what is this gonna mean for you know on a regular server people just questing to you know advance No, a lot of people won't even notice or anything, you know, but he's like on the roleplay servers.
Speaker 0: What are they supposed to make of this?
Speaker 0: Everyone is a torturer?
Speaker 1: Well from what I've gathered most of the people are role-playing.
Speaker 1: games like Wow Will basically roleplay.
Speaker 1: we're among themselves with their own stories just happening to use the kind of world around them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they'll ignore the quest and stuff because it doesn't make sense.
Speaker 1: Everyone did the quest.
Speaker 1: everyone's the hero.
Speaker 0: So yeah, the other thing is that he says.
Speaker 0: the other thing He that bothers him is that this torture was not.
Speaker 0: it's not that there's a quest with torture, right?
Speaker 0: You can make a quest with torture.
Speaker 0: That would be good.
Speaker 0: You know what if you had a decision or if you portrayed it in such a way as to make people realize Something?
Speaker 0: or maybe if you tortured and then you know, someone came and it was like what the hell bucks wrong with you Why couldn't it just be?
Speaker 1: the moral of the game is that torture is awesome and always gets you what you want.
Speaker 0: I mean, okay But he says the thing that bothers him.
Speaker 0: the most is that this torture was sort of placed in the game Casually as a run-of-the-mill quest with no regard for the fact that that was something that was sort of weird.
Speaker 1: You know Something that wait, but I point out bionic commando back in the day one point you find this Enemy's this Nazi soldier and he basically says I ain't talking to you And if you rough him up a bit, then he talks to you.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, and they added that I mean They're Atari the fact that they took that and made sure that it was still in the new bionic commando.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're like, hey torture that guy.
Speaker 1: So you walk in and you just kind of poke him a bit then he goes out he talks and then you kill him.
Speaker 0: but I just think it's you know, It's sort of interesting.
Speaker 1: There's two ways to go.
Speaker 1: I mean, of course my ideal MMO, you know massively multiplayer online role-playing game, which is not what mmorpgs are anymore.
Speaker 1: well, if they ever were that.
Speaker 1: but imagine a world where You have junctures like that all the time and you always have all these choices and not everyone follows the same path.
Speaker 1: You could take the the oblivion or the fallout idea of there's a million different things out there.
Speaker 1: But and everyone can take different paths, you know kind of like a multiplayer fallout but with a lot more stuff and they're not all just fetch quests and Make it so that every decision you make affects your character permanently in some way.
Speaker 1: that's rolled into your narrative.
Speaker 1: That's one way to do it.
Speaker 1: The other way is to have it where you go one step further.
Speaker 1: every single quest every single thing is unique and isn't just Creating the character the narrative for your character.
Speaker 1: You're creating the world's narrative.
Speaker 1: you went and did this thing.
Speaker 1: now the flavor text there or the characters there reflect that.
Speaker 1: the problem is the former is too difficult for a lot of players and it also and but yet it's not far enough for The people are really into role-playing.
Speaker 1: The latter is in no way economically viable.
Speaker 0: See, I think really what the thing what could happen here right is.
Speaker 0: I was thinking about NS which is a game We're playing a lot lately.
Speaker 0: and the thing about NS that's different from every other game that I've ever that I can think of right is That the quests or objectives and NS if they're not like a built into the game kind of thing It's not like, you know, you play some games and it's like go here and pull this lever like look at left for dead.
Speaker 0: It's like everyone get in the crane and push the button.
Speaker 0: That's the quest.
Speaker 0: It's built into the game.
Speaker 0: It's a set thing and NS as a team or as an individual.
Speaker 0: you are constantly Making quests making up objectives, but they make sense.
Speaker 0: You know, it's your create your sculpting the game on your own as a player.
Speaker 1: So what if you had a game like if Wow had a thing where you know the Horde and ever they're fighting and you Like when you can play?
Speaker 1: every time you complete these unique quests?
Speaker 1: They change things in the world on the other side and accomplish but not even not in the court?
Speaker 0: There wouldn't be quests programmed into the game at all.
Speaker 0: You would come up with the quest.
Speaker 0: you would just do things You came up with.
Speaker 0: yeah, I did that other players decided, you know, what game did that planet side Did area?
Speaker 1: planet side was basically a giant NS in that regard.
Speaker 1: It was you know, I'm on this team.
Speaker 1: Hey, let's all attack such-and-such.
Speaker 1: Just go there and attack it and take it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, of course, I'm at other problems.
Speaker 1: Well, I wasn't.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about the concept.
Speaker 1: I mean if you wanted to.
Speaker 1: if I bring up any game We could of course talk about what's wrong with it because as everyone knows we hate all games.
Speaker 0: all games suck Except for an asset for Tigris in your phrase except for TD NS tribes - that's it.
Speaker 0: Every other game sucks.
Speaker 1: Zelda one Zelda 2 was better.
Speaker 0: No, you what do you know?
Speaker 1: I know Zelda 2 was better.
Speaker 0: So you just said the translation, you know, nothing Anyway, but actually this it's still.
Speaker 1: this really plays into what I've always my whole life.
Speaker 1: what I've wanted is even a single-player game where Decisions matter and you're allowed to lose and the game continues, you know a branching story where our fortress But that's not really.
Speaker 1: it's not the same kind of game.
Speaker 0: Well to our fortress is similar and that you have a narrative emerging from your own decision-making.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about something as simple as all right.
Speaker 1: It's a Final Fantasy ish game.
Speaker 1: go and save the princess.
Speaker 1: if you make it you save the princess.
Speaker 1: great You know the plot continues.
Speaker 1: if you fail princess dies.
Speaker 1: game continues to the end.
Speaker 0: Well, our game continues in some way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well it ends.
Speaker 1: all games end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, except Wow.
Speaker 1: But well, I guess you've hit level 80.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's only so many times you can kill the exact same monster over and over again and everyone else also kills them over and over again.
Speaker 1: But just the idea that Losing.
Speaker 0: and think about how many times this prisoner has been tortured, but how many games could just do this?
Speaker 1: I mean burning wheel.
Speaker 1: remember we talked in beyond Dungeons & Dragons about how in D&D what?
Speaker 1: generally when you play Dungeons & Dragons it is make a test.
Speaker 1: try You know fighting.
Speaker 1: do a fight.
Speaker 1: if you make the test or win the fight the plot continues.
Speaker 1: if you fail at the test or lose the fight the plot basically stops until you Make the test or win the fight.
Speaker 1: in Burning wheel the idea is that no if you make the test you continue to the next test.
Speaker 1: if you fail Instead of stopping you go in a different direction with a complication being added.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm yeah, everything you're everything you do in a game just takes the game in a different direction.
Speaker 0: as opposed to they're being a line and You try to get to the end of it.
Speaker 0: It is you take a step and then every time you take a step you either go straight left or right and you know If you fail, you're gonna say basically take all left turns until there's no until you die or there's nowhere else to go You know, but if you succeed you're gonna go straight ahead.
Speaker 0: if you succeed every time, you know.
Speaker 0: But if you succeed and fail in different ways You go straight left right straight and end up at different places every time you play.
Speaker 0: and I think if you had a game Like fallout, right?
Speaker 0: But if you took out the sort of you know, do this quest here and the game ends kind of stuff, you know It was just here's the world go instead of you know, go get me that water controller chip at the below.
Speaker 1: it is Here's the world go.
Speaker 1: but there's also a way to end the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's fine.
Speaker 0: It's okay.
Speaker 1: I mean the real problem with those games is that but it's better than torture this prisoner.
Speaker 0: You have no choice.
Speaker 1: Well, no The only problem with those games really is I've found is that there just isn't enough to do.
Speaker 1: that's novel and most quests are Effectively the same thing.
Speaker 1: I mean oblivion.
Speaker 1: go get this book from this cave.
Speaker 1: Thank you.
Speaker 1: Here's some money.
Speaker 1: I heard there's another book in another cave.
Speaker 1: I could give you money in exchange for getting it.
Speaker 0: great.
Speaker 0: I Like.
Speaker 0: I like books.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, this is all all these.
Speaker 1: all this is bit by bit getting rolled into what is eventually going to Be the panel we hope to present at the next packs, which we're still tentatively calling losing should be fun.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: But anyway, there's this article on slashdot.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to talk about it because these sorts of articles come up a lot now.
Speaker 1: it was how politics interact with games and Constantly in every gaming plan s people go blah blah blah Ron Paul Ron Paul Obama Obama Obama, but that that's not games.
Speaker 1: That's the internet.
Speaker 1: you go anywhere.
Speaker 0: You realize Ron Paul supporters are like random encounters on the internet except You know how many times I've gone to the ready room in an NS game and there's someone yelling like spouting conspiracy nonsense Like oh, man's your evil politicians.
Speaker 0: They ruined your economies All your money.
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 1: OBS totally causes cancer.
Speaker 0: Don't build them Man so true.
Speaker 1: But it's true.
Speaker 1: some gorge told me right.
Speaker 1: hey really yeah, I was you know, I was running away, you know They were totally raping our IP and I get I find this gorge.
Speaker 1: He's like man.
Speaker 1: the OBS cause cancer.
Speaker 1: Why do you think I look like this?
Speaker 1: I'd rather be a gorge.
Speaker 1: Anyway, did I derail you?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I gotta steal.
Speaker 0: that joke is so good.
Speaker 1: I think it's that I mean it's right out there with me.
Speaker 1: Don't worry.
Speaker 1: I got you.
Speaker 1: I built an OC All right, yeah, man, I got this I got this I got it I got this All right, actually before we go any further as a public service announcement.
Speaker 1: I'm proud of all of you.
Speaker 1: Geek nice listeners seem to account for about 80% of the NS noobs right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all back is.
Speaker 1: I love you guys.
Speaker 1: you guys for like a week almost ruined NS for me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you don't know how to play NS Don't play.
Speaker 0: well do play but don't play with people who know how to play because you'll ruin the game.
Speaker 0: I mean think about a game you're really good at right a minute.
Speaker 1: What but how hypocritical is this?
Speaker 1: We like this really obscure game that no one else likes and we're really good at it.
Speaker 1: So we tell people how great it is.
Speaker 1: Yep, and we tell them to play it.
Speaker 1: Yep, they come and play it and pee in the pool as a result.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and now we tell them to get out of the pool.
Speaker 0: We don't get a pee in the kiddie pool first And then you can come in the big kids pool and then you can come on the high dive.
Speaker 0: Kitties who pee can't go on the high dive.
Speaker 1: All right The problem is the kiddie pool and NS.
Speaker 1: is that one like marine training bot server?
Speaker 0: Well, you guys got it.
Speaker 0: You know, there's people are and if you go to the forum You know, we're trying to set up a server.
Speaker 0: I think G David set up a server.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they are working on some tutorials.
Speaker 0: But yeah, well all you kiddies can go try to like play with each other on some empty servers or something.
Speaker 0: Don't come to our servers.
Speaker 0: Don't join our games Unless you're good until you figured it out.
Speaker 0: not because I don't want to play with you I do.
Speaker 0: and if you actually if you guys you know do find a kiddie pool to play and maybe I'll come in the kiddie Pool and you know show you how things are done.
Speaker 1: But I believe you mean come in the kiddie pool and shove everyone down laughing hysterically the whole time.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, that's probably what'll happen because that's how the game works.
Speaker 1: But you know, it's Imagining jump into the calm drop one shotgun and then like man rush the hive.
Speaker 0: think of it.
Speaker 0: think of it this way right?
Speaker 0: pretend you're really good at.
Speaker 0: oh You know monopoly right.
Speaker 0: monopoly is a game that even if people don't like it because we don't people understand it, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say you're playing monopoly and you know how to play you're really good and everyone else sucks.
Speaker 0: That's kind of fun for a little while.
Speaker 0: cuz it's like I got boardwalk and the other guys like Oh, New York I don't need to buy that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll just pass on that one.
Speaker 0: Who cares, you know, oh shit.
Speaker 0: I'm in jail.
Speaker 0: What's this?
Speaker 0: get out of jail free card, dude?
Speaker 0: Should I use that?
Speaker 0: No, okay I won't you know, but imagine if someone who doesn't know how to play is on your team.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah I don't want to buy that boardwalk.
Speaker 0: What's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: Oh my god by the stupid boardwalk.
Speaker 0: No, I don't want to.
Speaker 0: ah You know, you're gonna be mad frustrated.
Speaker 0: So when you join an NS game It's a team game.
Speaker 0: So if you're not good, you can especially if you're an alien Scott Scott, you can ruin your team.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna translate what you just said.
Speaker 1: get the hell off my lawn.
Speaker 1: God damn it.
Speaker 0: Join the other team at least not my team.
Speaker 0: mean if you're At least if you're a marine you can build.
Speaker 0: most damage you can do as a marine is just keep getting killed Constantly and all that will do is give the other team some RFK.
Speaker 0: if you're an alien You're getting these resource points.
Speaker 0: if you don't know how to spend them or if you like turn into an onos and die You just cost your team like 75 res.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, you just hey for everybody compared to Scott Johnson and left for dead.
Speaker 0: Well, we'll get to that.
Speaker 0: We'll get to that Anyway, but the regardless of all that did the same thing in NS - he joined a game of NS and he was sitting there Not spending his res.
Speaker 0: and then he sort of he turned into a gorge built some things and then left when he realized he forgot how to play.
Speaker 1: I've whenever I'm gonna leave a game and I ever as I always turn into a gorge build a bunch of stuff and then leave.
Speaker 1: I figure leave a nice parting shot for my friends.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got to do something like that.
Speaker 1: or just onos rush and die and then leave At least be a lurk and spray a bunch, but no, that's a long-term strategy.
Speaker 1: Not a short-term.
Speaker 1: Anyway, no this article reeks of trying to tie Barack Obama's name into a video game article for a good press and linkage, but Basically the gist of this article is that yes with Barack Obama in power Maybe we can save the video game industry and
Speaker 0: I don't know about that.
Speaker 1: No, here are two of the points.
Speaker 1: This guy makes one.
Speaker 1: We have to save the middleware developers Okay from being bought out by the game developers the middleware developers of the unsung heroes But no one knows who they are and they should get tax cuts in order to remain independent.
Speaker 1: What and This one?
Speaker 1: this should have not?
Speaker 0: Barack Obama doesn't give a shit about this.
Speaker 1: No, they're saying that the Politicians and the government should intercede in the video game industry to foster a better environment for it And maybe it'll be.
Speaker 0: maybe in no France or Canada.
Speaker 1: the weak sauce tie to Barack Obama Is that he's a new president?
Speaker 1: Maybe he'll do this stuff, but the one that bothers me Giving recognition the shitty article we now have to link to because I want to talk about an issue that they bring up.
Speaker 1: This has come up a lot and I talked about it I think last time but he basically says we need to crack down on the secondary market.
Speaker 1: people who make games should get mandatory legal compensation Every time the game changes hands in the secondary market fail And the government should regulate this with the equivalent of a blue book and at the same time price controls To make sure that the secondary market that is regulated doesn't gouge anyone
Speaker 0: Fail.
Speaker 1: well, I mean aside from the obvious argument of anytime someone creates IP I mean, I think everyone agrees that if you create intellectual property, you need to be compensated in a reasonable way.
Speaker 1: Otherwise the incentive to create intellectual property or the ability to raise money to create high-budget intellectual property Basically goes down the toilet and nothing else gets made.
Speaker 0: Well, unless we go back to the old-school Patron system which you know has infinity problems.
Speaker 0: Well, yes Because then probably the real thing is we have two systems the patron system and the copyright system and both of them have infinity Problems each.
Speaker 0: So what do you do?
Speaker 1: But the thing is the.
Speaker 1: I think the free market Compensation system works a lot better.
Speaker 1: The only problem with IP is that the compensation system is set to where you can make one thing and expect a profit off of It for 90 years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway Why do people treat the video game secondary market so differently from everything else?
Speaker 0: They're used bookstores are off, you know authors are still not complaining about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah used CD stores have always been a big hit.
Speaker 1: There's.
Speaker 1: I can buy a used car.
Speaker 1: There's no regulation.
Speaker 0: are used used cars are the reason that you know, they should just ban the sale of used cars.
Speaker 0: Then Detroit will be saved.
Speaker 1: I saw someone argue that not ironic.
Speaker 0: What the fuck what the fuck?
Speaker 1: Yes But that seems like the video game industry.
Speaker 1: it has this weird relationship with politics in that politicians especially in America and Australia and Britain Seem to really really really like metal in the video game industry a lot.
Speaker 1: yet They don't metal it nearly the same level in all the other kinds of IP.
Speaker 1: They don't come down on violent movies nearly as hard as they do in violent video games.
Speaker 1: They don't come down on.
Speaker 1: I mean a boob in a movie.
Speaker 1: All right, that's okay nowadays You know it.
Speaker 0: back in the day They came down hard and the rock music and then now the people in charge are the rock music.
Speaker 0: So as soon as the people in charge are the video games, they won't come down on anymore.
Speaker 0: It's the history of the world.
Speaker 0: It can't be changed.
Speaker 0: I know things are.
Speaker 1: the problem here is that technology is moving a lot faster than it used to and Video games have gone from nothing to niche to mature wide market audience Long long before that change.
Speaker 1: I mean the rock and roll revolution and the movie industry revolution.
Speaker 1: The technology and the advancement of movies just went more slowly.
Speaker 1: Look how far video games have come in the last I don't know ten years And yet the politics have gotten more restrictive and even worse.
Speaker 1: well, I don't know what to do about it.
Speaker 1: But at the same time we've got people like this guy and he's not the only one Like they don't want the politicians stepping on their freedom of speech and regulating their industry Except when the regulation makes them more money and then they really really.
Speaker 0: that's how everyone you know.
Speaker 0: That's the difference between someone who has a you know political science Principle and someone who just is looking out for their own, you know self-interest right.
Speaker 0: someone like me.
Speaker 0: If you ask me a question, right - I'll give you an answer such as you know.
Speaker 0: I don't care what regulation you want, right?
Speaker 0: There shouldn't.
Speaker 0: there should be less regulation on video games period right, but someone else will come in and they'll be like.
Speaker 0: You know, I don't care about your political principles your ideologies the Constitution, you know, if it's good for me You know, it's good.
Speaker 0: if it's bad for me It's bad like there was a. I was reading a threat in a for a superhero forum.
Speaker 0: and they were like What if there really were vigilantes?
Speaker 0: and a lot of people are like yeah as long as they only go after the criminals Yeah, beat the shit out of them criminals.
Speaker 0: and I'm like How about the principle of you know innocent until proven guilty?
Speaker 1: No, but to play the the devil's advocate there are two ways to look at American democracy.
Speaker 1: on one hand there's the political science view of you strive for the Political ideology and political framework where in the reasonable debate and the decision-making can happen.
Speaker 1: The other way to look at it is that it is an adversarial system and you should use every instrument provided to you by law within the system to get these specific issue things that you want for your best interest accomplished in the hopes that the varied and competing Self-interest balance out.
Speaker 1: and our government system is based very heavily on that principle.
Speaker 1: I mean look at our balance of powers.
Speaker 1: We have three different branches that each have the power to screw the other two.
Speaker 0: It's like a giant Democratic paper rock scissors Yes, but the two things can work together, you know, if you have a strong do that's called American democracy.
Speaker 0: But yeah, if you have a strong, you know political principle underlying everything.
Speaker 0: There is still plenty of room for debate on specific issues, you know I mean the.
Speaker 0: you know, you say Congress has this power.
Speaker 0: Yes, they do.
Speaker 0: Okay, that question is answered.
Speaker 0: They could still choose to do this or that and you have your you know, your specific issue.
Speaker 0: debate going on.
Speaker 0: - quote.
Speaker 1: Perhaps it's my own personal audacity of hope that work here that president-elect Obama will care enough about our industry's plights to create introduce or sign into law legislation that will benefit us as a business.
Speaker 1: or maybe it's audacious enough to suggest that he'll even have the time to address these issues as America tries to pull itself together in the midst of everything that's going wrong.
Speaker 0: How about video games like the last thing on the list?
Speaker 0: and - you're better off writing like your congressman.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Obama doesn't give a shit and there's not much he can do unless Congress does something first.
Speaker 0: Even if this was a good idea, which it is not it's not this who wrote this article.
Speaker 1: Give me a second.
Speaker 1: who actually wrote this?
Speaker 0: a retard Nick machete Not smart.
Speaker 1: I don't know who Nick machete is and he is the Something something combo.
Speaker 1: I give up because it's time for things of the day.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: Do I have a thing of the day?
Speaker 0: Oh, yes, I do.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got two because they're both kind of lame.
Speaker 1: on one hand the concepts behind them.
Speaker 1: Both are awesome.
Speaker 1: On the other hand the actual reality of what has been done Not so great because I learned one thing almost every Left 4 Dead video on YouTube has stupid music Just like added to it.
Speaker 0: You can remove a word for that sentence and it would still be true every Left 4 Dead on YouTube every video.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but two things stood out.
Speaker 1: one someone remade CS office in Left 4 Dead.
Speaker 0: I think that's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: I like that action.
Speaker 0: I want to see more that I want to see as a state on Left 4 Dead.
Speaker 1: Yes Cuz remember that mod for CS the zombie mod.
Speaker 1: that was actually very similar to Left 4 Dead and very very a little bit The concept of you got some humans fighting co-op and just hordes and hordes and hordes of aliens Zombies coming at you and you got a hole up and then win.
Speaker 0: Yep, but number two Left 4 Dead and Counter Strike.
Speaker 0: You can also tell that you know Counter Strike.
Speaker 0: people don't realize.
Speaker 0: Counter Strike originally was a free mod for Half-Life 1 Made by some dudes and then those dudes got bought by valve and that's why Counter Strike isn't free anymore.
Speaker 0: It is clear if you have ever played Counter Strike.
Speaker 0: when you play Left 4 Dead It is clear that the Counter Strike team made Left 4 Dead.
Speaker 0: You can tell.
Speaker 0: by the way the weapons work.
Speaker 0: There is there is no question about it.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I saw this and I thought oh that's clever.
Speaker 1: and then I you know I mourn the loss of CS thunder and all these sorts of things.
Speaker 1: but then I thought hey Yeah, this one.
Speaker 0: There's that one map in Left 4 Dead that really reminds me of de vertigo.
Speaker 1: Oh Man, that was the one where I was the tank.
Speaker 1: But anyway, and you punch someone off the building punched three people off the building.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, it was great.
Speaker 1: But item two I thought hey we should make a Leroy Jenkins video in Left 4 Dead.
Speaker 0: and then I thought You got that whole thing with the witch and everything and the boomer.
Speaker 0: if someone just said Leroy Jenkins and ran in and got boomed And then woke the witch up that would totally be funny.
Speaker 1: So what I linked to is the best one that is out there.
Speaker 1: someone made up the best Left 4 Dead Leroy Jenkins video.
Speaker 1: That has been.
Speaker 0: it's still not a good video, but it's the best one Yes, so I implore all of you at least smelly poop.
Speaker 1: if you someone out there I don't have time make a Leroy Jenkins Left 4 Dead video But if you do it use the audio from the original one, don't put any music over it.
Speaker 0: Yes Just have some people talking.
Speaker 0: This is how the video goes ready.
Speaker 0: Some people are talking right in the game.
Speaker 0: then one guy isn't moving as They're talking.
Speaker 0: the guy goes Alright, let's do this Leroy Jenkins.
Speaker 0: And he runs out and he wakes up.
Speaker 0: the witch gets boomed and uses a molotov and sets himself on fire all at the same Time.
Speaker 1: now you need the key to their two key elements.
Speaker 1: Well, actually there are three key elements.
Speaker 0: Someone then has to say god damn it Leroy.
Speaker 1: There are exactly three key elements.
Speaker 1: one After he runs in there's a moment of silence of about three seconds Followed by some the guy who was talking saying did he just run in there?
Speaker 1: Two you need as everyone else runs in the shot of Leroy on fire Running back toward the pot getting hit by a witch covered in vomit.
Speaker 1: And three you need the long scene of everyone dying.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Y'all see it's not my fault.
Speaker 1: Yes This I got chicken.
Speaker 1: I got chicken or I'm not chicken.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Ah, remember when Leroy Jenkins.
Speaker 1: It was fresh.
Speaker 1: Yeah, remember that Otakon where you could walk around Otakon yell Leroy and like a thousand people would yell Jenkins back at you.
Speaker 0: Oh, that was a good Otakon that one.
Speaker 0: Yeah We need some more.
Speaker 0: someone needs to make more memes that have those sort of call-outs in them.
Speaker 0: You know the wherever you can yell something and then someone will say the other part.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, so check out this thing of the day.
Speaker 0: and keeping with my Thanksgiving yummies What do you do on Thanksgiving?
Speaker 1: I eat my weight in Turkey.
Speaker 0: well here you can eat far less than your weight in Turkey.
Speaker 0: It's a papercraft turkey.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: That's it That's.
Speaker 0: it's a papercraft turkey.
Speaker 0: and you know, the best part is has those little chef's hats on the on the drumsticks.
Speaker 0: I love those.
Speaker 0: You know, I've never actually seen those in real life, but I keep seeing them like whenever someone draws like a Thanksgiving turkey.
Speaker 0: They always have them but in real life.
Speaker 0: I've never seen one, you know what those are for?
Speaker 0: See easier to hold the drumstick without getting your hand dirty.
Speaker 0: Yes, even though I just I just use a napkin you do know.
Speaker 1: Do you realize there are paper towel in Detroit with the Lions on Thanksgiving?
Speaker 1: involving a turkey?
Speaker 0: They don't.
Speaker 0: they have one at the game or something.
Speaker 1: and well what they do is one.
Speaker 1: there are the traditions.
Speaker 1: it's a gaming day.
Speaker 1: We don't just talk about video games.
Speaker 1: real.
Speaker 1: briefly the Detroit tradition for Thanksgiving is such one They will have a home game where they wear their old away uniforms the old old old ones.
Speaker 1: Two at halftime, they'll bring out a turkey with end drumsticks attached to it and people bet on how many drumsticks There will be Three.
Speaker 1: they'll be up by at least 14 By the and then lose it in the last eight minutes.
Speaker 0: Well, well rim I have I have some sad news for you.
Speaker 0: You're ready for this sad news number one The Lions so far this year are winless.
Speaker 0: I don't think any NFL team has ever gone the entire season without winning.
Speaker 1: Hey, hey, hey, if anyone can do it we can right.
Speaker 0: well.
Speaker 0: secondly You just said, you know, the Lions are gonna be up and then lose it at the end.
Speaker 1: Oh, they're gonna be up on Thanksgiving.
Speaker 0: They are.
Speaker 0: The Lions are playing this on this Thursday.
Speaker 0: the Tennessee Titans the best team in the AFC.
Speaker 0: They're going to get killed from the start to the end.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be a slaughter.
Speaker 1: I don't think you understand the magic you see.
Speaker 1: the Lions can only do well When they're about to be crushed and the more they're about to be crushed the better they will do in the beginning.
Speaker 0: and the third News is that there is talk going on of ending You know because Detroit sucks so bad and no one wants to watch them.
Speaker 0: You're right.
Speaker 0: I mean a guy on the internet.
Speaker 0: a guy on the internet was talking about how he got.
Speaker 0: you know You know 50-yard line tickets real close real easily.
Speaker 1: Hey, if I lived in Detroit, I would totally go to Lions games all the time.
Speaker 0: Yes, you get the season tickets real deep.
Speaker 1: if you've got a really good sports team.
Speaker 1: It's awesome.
Speaker 1: And if you've got a really bad sports team, it's awesome because you got something to talk about.
Speaker 1: Well, you
Speaker 0: have you know, this is like I went way back a few years ago many years ago Actually to a New England Patriots game right when they were kind of good Maybe you know not read not super recently And it was like the first home game that they had lost in a very long time like at that point in time they hadn't lost a home game in like a year or so and I think they might have won the Super Bowl the previous year.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: and Like walking out of there because if you ever been to that stadium It's this long road to back to your car and they basically turn the road into a one-way road and then during the game They switch it to one way in the other direction so people get in and out.
Speaker 0: It was just like this quiet like it was like a funeral march out of there, you know, I didn't care I'm a Giants fan what I give a shit, but it was very, you know in Detroit They don't know winnings like.
Speaker 0: so if they won they just wouldn't know what to do.
Speaker 0: But when they lose they're just like yeah another loss Thing is they relish in losing.
Speaker 1: the philosophy of Detroit.
Speaker 1: Is that you have to balance good teams with bad teams?
Speaker 1: Mmm, that's why the Red Wings and the Pistons are so great because we have the Tigers and the Lions.
Speaker 0: Tigers are middling.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're better now than they were when I was middling.
Speaker 0: They're not great, but they're middling.
Speaker 1: my god when I was a kid All right left for dead.
Speaker 0: Oh, but there's talk of ending the tradition of letting the Lions Have always the Thanksgiving game and giving it to someone people actually want to see.
Speaker 1: Detroit would riot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: Anyway left for dead Before we go any further.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna say right now if you're looking for the quick review one is great To buy it as soon as possible because it doesn't have staying power.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much what it comes down to.
Speaker 0: left for dead is a great zombie game, you know.
Speaker 0: But there is a question as to how long the game will hold our interest, you know, or anyone's interest And I think it's.
Speaker 0: I go from penny arcade agreed.
Speaker 1: I give the game for me personally.
Speaker 1: It's got no more than two months to go before I'm done with it.
Speaker 0: I mean the game only has like four campaigns, right?
Speaker 0: So after you do those four campaigns Maybe you can replay them on a harder difficulty level, right.
Speaker 0: and maybe there's two campaigns You can play in versus mode.
Speaker 0: You can't play all four campaigns in versus mode But you can play two of them in versus mode.
Speaker 0: So it might be worth it to replay the campaigns both of the ones in versus mode.
Speaker 0: Once you've done that and you've done it all in co-op and such.
Speaker 0: What is there really, you know more to the game?
Speaker 0: Maybe if you decide that you want to play the versus mode competitively and like make a team and Like compete and tournaments or something and some sort of clan thing Maybe they'll have a little bit more replay value.
Speaker 1: maybe because it has the one added benefit.
Speaker 1: I mean the fact that because you play as a team of four I found that pretty much you'll find a group of four who's really good that you work together with and you'll just play with them All the time.
Speaker 1: so the game really lends itself to team-based, you know pod ladder play.
Speaker 1: However, even if I get into that and there's a tiny chance I will.
Speaker 1: but even if I decide to go all the way I play left for dead like as much as you can play.
Speaker 1: I join the ladders.
Speaker 1: I join one of those clans or whatever.
Speaker 1: That's gonna be propping up.
Speaker 1: Well, even then I can't see myself playing the game more than six months.
Speaker 0: Yeah there's also you know if user Generated maps start coming out and being easier to play and load up and whatnot like the first I don't know five are gonna be Terrible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean people are making the mall from dawn to the dead Which is an obvious idea right, you know that you just saw one.
Speaker 0: That was what DE office, right?
Speaker 0: I'll see us office de office.
Speaker 0: We should make de office be hilarious.
Speaker 0: CS office, you know if enough maps come out maybe can hold your in just a little longer.
Speaker 0: Maybe a valve releases some more campaigns, you know, like hey, here's the new campaign.
Speaker 0: Even if the new campaign was like five bucks see I would pay five bucks for a full left for dead campaign.
Speaker 1: Here's my worry.
Speaker 1: I Mean I didn't play the game until recently.
Speaker 1: I actually didn't play it at all until a few night.
Speaker 1: You know a couple nights ago a few nights ago where Scott nine to four nights got together And we just went right into the advanced campaign and just kind of trivially went through beating it.
Speaker 1: Well, no difficulty at all.
Speaker 1: Like it didn't.
Speaker 1: even there was no question.
Speaker 0: Nobody died ever because we work together.
Speaker 0: We were all smart.
Speaker 0: None of us had lag.
Speaker 0: We all had skill.
Speaker 0: we beat it.
Speaker 1: So obviously we have to just play an expert.
Speaker 1: but the thing is there's a limited number of game mechanics and left for dead.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's basically every map the way it is now because you can't interact with the environment The game really doesn't have enough.
Speaker 1: half-life 2 that's.
Speaker 0: that's really one thing that's bothered me about every source engine game.
Speaker 0: That's Team Fortress 2 counter-strike source and left for dead.
Speaker 0: These are all on the source engine right the same source engine that is used in half-life 2 with all the crazy physics of picking Barrels and throwing soda cans and gravity guns right now.
Speaker 0: I understand portal doesn't even have any of the physics engine stuff.
Speaker 1: I understand why Team Fortress 2 doesn't because it's this really stateless non narrative kind of.
Speaker 1: well, it's not stateless anymore.
Speaker 1: Thank you achievements.
Speaker 1: But anyway, it's a game that's supposed to be a direct competition and adding all that stuff would make it a lot fuzzier.
Speaker 1: And the maps, you know, they wouldn't be as clean.
Speaker 1: but for a game like this where it's kind of a single-player co-op You know narrative beat the game meet this objective thing.
Speaker 1: It really could be just like a co-op.
Speaker 1: half-life and the read.
Speaker 1: the moment I realized this was it.
Speaker 1: we were playing the dead air campaign we were playing and you have there's this crane.
Speaker 0: remember in half-life 2 there was a crane.
Speaker 0: and what you had to do with this crane is you to pick up a shipping crate and Basically put it down?
Speaker 0: No You had to pick up your car and put it down up top where you could.
Speaker 0: you know that way you could drive.
Speaker 1: You know you did.
Speaker 1: first you picked up a cargo container swung it as fast as you could and threw it at some people.
Speaker 1: then you went knocking troops off of bridges and then you swung Stuff around.
Speaker 1: you played there for like a half hour and left for dead the crane.
Speaker 0: you basically get in the crane Pull the lever then you defend the crane from zombies and survive for like a minute or so And then the crane just automatically does its thing and creates a bridge so that you can go to the next area.
Speaker 0: Why can't I use the crane to swing around and knock the zombies off the building?
Speaker 1: just think about that.
Speaker 1: That would have been the best thing ever.
Speaker 1: if in that scene the person who was in the crane Could just start swinging that container around just like knocking zombies off left and right That would have.
Speaker 1: that would have made this game immortal.
Speaker 1: Yeah That would having the half-life if you could.
Speaker 0: you know I mean in this game a good strategy is whenever you especially if you're playing Versus is to close doors behind you because it's zombies can go through doors, but they have to break them first.
Speaker 0: So it slows them down You know.
Speaker 0: and if someone on the other team decides to spawn behind you and you close the door behind you you can get away from them and force them to.
Speaker 0: you know spawn again or whatever.
Speaker 0: and Imagine if like in half-life 2 you could pick up items and put them down or pick up items and throw them right.
Speaker 0: You could pick up items to sort of put them in front of the doors to make little barricades and things.
Speaker 0: Instead you know barricades like just sort of appear on their own like whenever you start a new section of a campaign Like a barricade just appears in the safe room on its own like the people had built it when the screen was.
Speaker 1: That's what really bothers me.
Speaker 1: I mean it's better from a kind of straight-up gameplay Perspective in that the game is really clean and really simple and really predictable.
Speaker 1: I mean and this adds a lot of atmosphere I mean you have the different musical cues when different things are about to happen and You kind of you go into every game expecting certain things.
Speaker 1: but Because of that and because it's basically just a pop-up book with zombie fights I mean you go to a place you hit the button to make the pop-up book thing happen And then you do the fight and then you move on hit the next pop-up book thing And you know every map is go in there's gonna be smokers and boomers and things.
Speaker 1: Oh now here's the part where we fight the tank and then we continue.
Speaker 1: you're waiting for it.
Speaker 1: You can only make so many campaigns Where until you've exhausted every possible novel game mechanic that the game presents and then the only thing a campaign can add is Narrative and color and at that point the game's not gonna have anything else to offer.
Speaker 0: to most people I mean the one thing the game does have is the so-called director.
Speaker 0: You know the AI director where you know the game plays it up like each campaign is a movie and you're acting in the movie.
Speaker 0: You know the zombie movie, and you know the directors sort of.
Speaker 0: you know change every time you play a campaign.
Speaker 0: It's not exactly the same like if you play half-life 2 The.
Speaker 0: there's the same number of bad guys in every spot every time.
Speaker 1: you know this idea.
Speaker 0: room Always has one of those poison headcrabs in it.
Speaker 1: this idea was brilliant because it Lets the game even if you play through a campaign a second time Keep that kind of aura of suspense that you can't mean.
Speaker 1: if it was exactly the same every time like most FPS Has been up to this point it would it would be the game of.
Speaker 1: I memorized it and I can speedrun it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But no the director sort of changes the flow of the game as you go on.
Speaker 0: so like you sit in one place and don't move like Zombies will sort of keep coming at you.
Speaker 0: if you don't start moving you know they'll be like another flood of zombies.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: You one of them saw you right, or you know maybe sometime.
Speaker 0: You'll go through.
Speaker 0: There'll be a witch in this spot, but maybe the witch will be in a different spot Or maybe there won't be a witch.
Speaker 0: There'll be a tank.
Speaker 0: Maybe there'll be two tanks.
Speaker 0: Maybe yeah, and It's sort of the game throws.
Speaker 0: You know the bad guys at you as if there was a director.
Speaker 0: You know a real director sort of deciding and controlling the flow of the action.
Speaker 0: But it's just an AI controlling the flow of the action.
Speaker 1: the game does a really good job of keeping the atmosphere Right and balancing hectic times with quiet scary times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think if you play an expert those a lot less quiet times Yeah, but an advanced.
Speaker 0: you know that at least the balance for cinematic purposes is just right But it's not hard enough, and we just beat it every time.
Speaker 1: yeah But I just I feel like there's so little long-term play the game has to offer that even if they have DLC I'm using it downloadable content, and I can buy campaigns.
Speaker 1: I feel like every the campaigns that came with the game have already exhausted every possible game mechanic unless they add Game mechanics, and they would need to make campaigns that were sort of different or longer or better.
Speaker 0: Or I mean the other thing that gets me out the campaigns is that they're a little bit like too linear.
Speaker 0: I mean sometimes you have a choice of like go the back way or go the front way But you don't really have a choice.
Speaker 0: like I want like have a campaign where maybe if I go I can like You know get to a boat or maybe if I go this way we can get to a train or me.
Speaker 0: Or maybe there's like a vehicle we can ride in or we can sort of take the rooftops Maybe like a big decision.
Speaker 0: that way even a single campaign has a lot of replay value, and that's another thing.
Speaker 0: Where is the vehicle?
Speaker 0: I mean usually people go our vehicle mission?
Speaker 0: Zombie needs a vehicle mission.
Speaker 0: Oh, no game needs a vehicle mission.
Speaker 0: one guy drives the van everyone else shoots out the sides.
Speaker 0: Where is it?
Speaker 1: I can't find that would be great.
Speaker 1: because think about here's the cinematic scene you set up.
Speaker 1: you get in the van you start driving a Tank runs up from the side and knocks the van the fuck over.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's hot you're in it.
Speaker 0: everything is chaos and spinning and the only thing is this one scene where you come out into the back of this garage and Francis goes I hate vans Every time I go into that room.
Speaker 0: I go I hate vans Just to demonstrate that I've memorized the line.
Speaker 1: That's the other thing I like.
Speaker 1: the characters are great like the.
Speaker 1: they're pretty good.
Speaker 1: the cinematics of the game like the opening movie Is brilliant because on one hand it's a pretty good zombie movie in and of itself and it on the other hand it introduces the characters the plot and every single game mechanic.
Speaker 1: Like right then you watch that opening movie.
Speaker 1: You know what all the zombie types are.
Speaker 1: you know what to do about them?
Speaker 1: You know all the game mechanics.
Speaker 1: You know what pipe bombs do.
Speaker 1: it's basically a tutorial that doesn't act like a tutorial.
Speaker 1: more games need that.
Speaker 0: Another thing that is sort of weird though.
Speaker 0: while the game has these four characters right Zoey Francis Bill and Lewis, right?
Speaker 0: And they sort of fit the stereo.
Speaker 0: Lewis in a zombie movie, you know the grizzled vet the biker dude the token black guy and the girl You know typical zombie movie.
Speaker 0: That's that's how it goes.
Speaker 0: You let you choose which character you want to be but it doesn't really make a difference.
Speaker 0: They're all exactly the same.
Speaker 0: They all move at the same speed.
Speaker 0: They have the same HP.
Speaker 0: They have the same, you know, you pick whatever weapon you want.
Speaker 0: They're all the same accuracy And I think that was a missed opportunity to increase the replay value even more.
Speaker 0: if the characters were different in some way.
Speaker 0: you know, maybe the grizzled vet is better aim and Maybe Francis has better melee attacks And it's harder for like smokers to grab him or something.
Speaker 0: or you know Lewis can carry a lot more stuff and Maybe the girl is faster and she can duck and maybe roll or jump farther and stuff like that, you know What?
Speaker 1: Black zombie killer needs med pack badly.
Speaker 0: No, okay You know that would have increased the replay value fourfold because I'd want to play through is each character Each time.
Speaker 1: but now that little thing even if they were really really really subtle differences would have just added that feeling.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like one person can carry two med packs one person carry a little bit more ammo, you know Just a little.
Speaker 0: even it was a little tiny difference between the characters.
Speaker 0: It would make a big difference in the game.
Speaker 1: Hey, if only someone could make a mod where it's just you play Left 4 Dead, but you pick everyone picks a Team Fortress 2 class Yeah, and you just go I don't know.
Speaker 0: I just pick the scout and run to the safe room and close the door.
Speaker 1: I Don't know.
Speaker 1: engineer could be fun everyone could be fun except the spy.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the heavy would get owned.
Speaker 0: he wouldn't have a chance.
Speaker 0: I mean, he'd mow him down, but then he would get overrun.
Speaker 1: But I don't know the game.
Speaker 1: the single-player game is not gonna have staying power.
Speaker 1: So that's why I said if you want to play this game Play it now because everyone who's into it now the player base is gonna drop off like a rock within a year.
Speaker 1: This is gonna be one of those situations where if you weren't in at the ground floor.
Speaker 1: You're really gonna miss out because by the time you decide to play a year from now No one's gonna be playing and no one's gonna be if you get say the 360 version, right?
Speaker 0: You can play it with people in your house.
Speaker 0: So if you have friends who also haven't played it and you can get them together All you need is four people and if you've got four people that haven't played you can play anytime.
Speaker 0: But if you want to play it with the people who are playing it now, right the people who got into ground floor The we're gonna be bored of this game in like a month or so, and then we're not gonna play it anymore.
Speaker 0: So if you want to play, you know you with co-op with and you don't have three friends who also have not played You.
Speaker 0: now is the time you got to pay the 50 bucks and get on that.
Speaker 0: Also, you know that there is a 360 and ps3.
Speaker 0: I think this is a ps3.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: there's definitely a 360 version and Really though you should play the PC version.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you definitely should.
Speaker 0: yeah, you know the 360 version people There's other problems with it.
Speaker 0: And also, you know valve just tends to give a lot more respect to.
Speaker 0: I mean think about this Right the demo for left 4 dead got three patches in one day.
Speaker 0: 360 version Didn't get shit, right?
Speaker 0: So the PC is where the love is gonna be from valve.
Speaker 0: This is where you're gonna get your extra maps.
Speaker 0: This is where you're gonna get your mods.
Speaker 0: This is where you're gonna get all the good stuff.
Speaker 0: So Really any valve game you should play on the PC, you know get steam just go Play on the 360. unless you don't have a good PC and you do have a 360 There's really no reason to get that version plus.
Speaker 0: the 360 version is more money.
Speaker 0: I mean, I pre-ordered the PC version for $45.
Speaker 0: the 360 version is $60 and you're getting less.
Speaker 0: What the hell?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So before we really talk about the multiplayer We need to tell the tale of the because the first time I ever played multiplayer Was right after the first time I'd ever played the game which was the game that I'm talking about right now?
Speaker 1: it was me and Scott.
Speaker 1: and who was it who was with us?
Speaker 0: classic and Someone else.
Speaker 0: All right, remind me someone else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you guys were.
Speaker 0: maybe it was Tay Dan pilot or bronze dragon?
Speaker 1: Oh, I don't remember.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's some people playing with us.
Speaker 0: They're all cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and there are people on the opposite team.
Speaker 1: But we know we decide to play the versus because we've played out the single-player right then and we're feeling it.
Speaker 1: We got a good group going.
Speaker 1: Well the color Well, I call it the single-player because it's basically while it's a co-op game.
Speaker 1: It's really plays like a single-player game.
Speaker 1: Yep, I mean your friends are basically just advanced AI.
Speaker 0: Well, they talk to you, which is nice occasionally.
Speaker 1: But so we decide to play the verses and the verses works.
Speaker 1: Okay, I mean, it's it's really The verse is pretty clever it is but it's not super fun to play at the zombies.
Speaker 0: well, the thing is is the way that the verses works just for people who don't know.
Speaker 0: is It's not like some other zombie games where it's like, oh you're a survivor, but you get bit and you turn into a zombie?
Speaker 0: No, no You have a team of four people who are the survivors and they're trying to beat the mission as you know as they would In a normal game and then the other four people are the zombies.
Speaker 0: They're basically instead of the AI director controlling the smokers and other specialized zombies you have humans controlling the specialized zombies just not the witch though, but the other ones.
Speaker 0: and you know basically You're trying to get to the end as quickly as possible and with the most health as possible and the zombies are Trying to make as hard as possible for the other team.
Speaker 0: and then after one team does you know does their thing?
Speaker 0: Succeeds or fails you switch.
Speaker 0: so it's basically who can you know?
Speaker 0: play the game better as survivors and who can make the game harder for the survivors as zombies.
Speaker 0: and So it's sort of team versus team at playing the normal game.
Speaker 1: It's really I can't come up with a better way to handle it and it works really really well It was.
Speaker 0: it was a clever idea that I would not have come up with.
Speaker 0: the only problem.
Speaker 1: Is that basically if You're good at the game You will not have fun because the majority of people are bad at the game.
Speaker 0: And yeah, every time I played a game well, I tried to play versus just by joining online games with people strangers.
Speaker 0: and Every time I was either on a team that was so good We just won on a team that was most of the time I was at a team that was so shitty I couldn't win no matter how good I was.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's all.
Speaker 1: in general This is really a game where playing with strangers is not reward.
Speaker 1: I mean you can play with strangers and you can make friends and all that.
Speaker 1: but if you really want to enjoy this game You really should play it with friends of yours or like of the set group of people or have like a circle of maybe 12 Friends who all take turns playing with each other.
Speaker 1: because if you're not playing with friends You're gonna miss most of the magic of this game Mm-hmm, but in terms of the multiplayer the four of us went into the multiplayer against four other people and I think we were the zombies first and They didn't make it 20 feet out that safe room door.
Speaker 0: They didn't make it at all.
Speaker 1: I think the saddest part was when their score broke double digits because they had us their score.
Speaker 0: basically You get a score based on how much health and how far you got through the level and how difficult the level was and all These factors and their score was like ding ding ding ding eight Eleven.
Speaker 1: I was like no they broke into double digits those fuckers This is our turn and we literally just kind of run at full speed through the map killing all the zombies straight for the exit Taking no damage.
Speaker 1: We got 4,000 points.
Speaker 0: Yep So so Another problem right is that this happens.
Speaker 0: right one team is good one team is bad.
Speaker 0: So what happens here?
Speaker 0: people on the team that is losing?
Speaker 0: Leave because it's not fun to lose.
Speaker 1: everyone on the losing team quit Immediately.
Speaker 1: except for bronze dragon you get mad props for sticking to the end.
Speaker 0: He had wicked lag - yeah, right Here's another.
Speaker 0: here's some of his.
Speaker 0: the problems that fold out of this problem Number one, if you join a game online randomly, where are there going to be empty slots on losing teams?
Speaker 0: Alright teams that have just and which means you're against a good team Which means you're gonna lose.
Speaker 0: you can't carry the team on your own.
Speaker 0: You need three other good players.
Speaker 0: Problem number two if you're a winning team a winning team spends a lot of time playing as survivors Because they probably make it to the end of the level and when they're zombies they end it real quick.
Speaker 0: So a winning team plays a lot of survivor and very little zombie.
Speaker 0: a losing team plays very little survivor and a lot of zombie.
Speaker 0: Zombies can be fun, you know smoking people and you know barfing on people and all that good stuff We get.
Speaker 0: being the tank is super fun but when you're the zombies right you're spending a lot of time dying because you die very quickly and Trying to find a spot to spawn Waiting to enter spawn mode.
Speaker 0: It's it's more boring overall.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of waiting and a lot of doing nothing.
Speaker 0: Where's in your survivor?
Speaker 0: You're playing constantly.
Speaker 1: Let's imagine how on the phone it'll be.
Speaker 1: you're playing against a good team.
Speaker 1: So basically they see you you die you grab someone you have to wait 30 seconds before you can play again.
Speaker 0: Then you see then you join you spawn you attack Maybe you get some damage on you die you wait 30 seconds to do it again.
Speaker 1: So really the only way to play the multiplayer Where it's fun is either to form a team of four and play against another formed team of four.
Speaker 1: that will not rage.
Speaker 1: quit.
Speaker 0: that is also good.
Speaker 1: or at least similar in skill level or Join the professional ladder play.
Speaker 0: Yeah or something.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But yeah, that's that's a serious flaw in the versus.
Speaker 1: I gotta say that the versus mode is pretty fun when it when it works Be in the tank and that vertigo map was like the best thing ever.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's another flaw in the verses.
Speaker 1: I just run up to a survivor and I'm like punk.
Speaker 0: and just so let's say you're playing versus mode.
Speaker 0: Right, and it's four on four.
Speaker 0: All right You have to in order to win as the zombies.
Speaker 0: You need to kill all four of the other players.
Speaker 0: Let's say it's four on one in versus mode.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Well, it's one real player and three AI players.
Speaker 0: You only have to kill the real player and then you win.
Speaker 0: so it's actually completely unfair Because you know if you have less players you are an extreme disadvantage to where three of your players don't even count.
Speaker 0: Just one of them dies and it's game over.
Speaker 1: Well, I think the idea is that you're only gonna have AI there temporarily until someone else joins your losing team and then rage Quits.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah rage quitting is a big problem.
Speaker 1: So it is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean, what can I say?
Speaker 1: the game is really fun, but it has enough flaws to where I'm not gonna be playing this come February.
Speaker 0: No, but I'm glad I bought it.
Speaker 0: I am actually playing it.
Speaker 0: Yes, you know more so than other games.
Speaker 0: I am and I'm not playing Bioshock or Fallout 3 or any other games I bought recently, but I am I'm playing Left 4 Dead and I'm playing NS sort of in equal doses.
Speaker 0: The only thing is I think a couple months from now.
Speaker 0: I'll still be playing NS, but I won't still be playing Left 4 Dead.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is think about how much staying power NS has had.
Speaker 1: we've been playing NS continuously for six years.
Speaker 1: Yep Six years now.
Speaker 0: That's a long time.
Speaker 0: Left 4 Dead is not a six year game.
Speaker 1: Left 4 Dead is not a six month game I want to make a.
Speaker 0: I want to make a parody of Left 4 Dead called Right to Live.
Speaker 1: What kind of game is that gonna be?
Speaker 0: It's gonna be a zombie trying to turn back into human.
Speaker 1: So what you run up to humans going please help and then they shoot you.
Speaker 1: Though I have to give a very important public service announcement and I mean this with all the love I can Because this is a dear friend of mine One of the chorus and most stalwart members of the front row crew the spine that was forged in steel and iron the man who gave us cowboy bebop, but Scott Johnson is Possibly the most dangerous person to ever have on your team in Left 4 Dead.
Speaker 0: He's terrible now for someone who likes zombies and zombie movies.
Speaker 0: so much for someone who will talk.
Speaker 0: You know who loves doing the old zombie survival discussions.
Speaker 0: He's really bad at Left 4 Dead.
Speaker 1: I love you Scott Johnson.
Speaker 0: You're terrible.
Speaker 1: No, I love you, but Well, I hadn't even played Left 4 Dead yet.
Speaker 1: I didn't even know how it worked.
Speaker 1: I hadn't read anything done.
Speaker 1: anything.
Speaker 1: Scott's playing in his room.
Speaker 1: I walk in me and Emily are standing there watching.
Speaker 1: we see Scott.
Speaker 1: he sees a witch and yeah, I see the witch on Scott's screen.
Speaker 1: and Scott says hey everyone.
Speaker 1: There's a witch right here.
Speaker 1: I'm looking at it.
Speaker 1: Just walk past it.
Speaker 1: It won't notice us.
Speaker 1: Scott backs away.
Speaker 1: He turns around.
Speaker 1: we see Scott Johnson.
Speaker 1: go Run straight for the witch stand on top of it and start shooting it.
Speaker 1: Luckily Scott shot him dead.
Speaker 0: Yep, I kept my word and I shot Scott Johnson dead because I was role-playing.
Speaker 0: You know, that is one thing that Left 4 Dead actually has is role-playing ability, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, there are a lot of people who will role-play in the game.
Speaker 1: It's kind of cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's some videos of it of like good people doing it.
Speaker 0: Well also there and I basically said holy shit This guy is dangerous.
Speaker 0: He may be not a zombie, but he's going up and waking up witches.
Speaker 0: This is not someone that I can be with and I shot him dead because this friendly fire in the game Which is totally cool.
Speaker 0: Then right playing with Scott we're playing a game.
Speaker 1: Well, he's not easy.
Speaker 1: He appeared out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: He's kind of like the tank you're playing a game and suddenly there's Scott Johnson.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we were playing and someone in our you know party dropped out and Scott Johnson just sort of joined in on his own.
Speaker 1: Immediately, we didn't know the way.
Speaker 0: steam has pretty good handling of the friends steam system and integration with Left 4 Dead.
Speaker 0: So if you have friends on Steam, it's very easy to get into games of Left 4 Dead with them and that's great.
Speaker 0: So Scott Johnson used that ability to join our Ability to kill us all.
Speaker 1: basically if I was role-playing our game of life words would have been Scott Right, you've killed us all.
Speaker 0: so he joins.
Speaker 0: he joins this game of Left 4 Dead that we're playing and this me rim and classic.
Speaker 0: We're doing great.
Speaker 1: I think the game Scott Johnson was playing was not Left 4 Dead.
Speaker 1: He was playing.
Speaker 1: how much damage to the party?
Speaker 1: Can I do in 20 sec?
Speaker 0: So the first.
Speaker 0: so he comes in.
Speaker 0: he's playing normally.
Speaker 0: the first thing he does he comes up and he starts to Heal me now.
Speaker 1: I had yellow health.
Speaker 0: Everyone else had green, but I still had like 30-something health.
Speaker 0: I did not need healing yet.
Speaker 0: He starts healing me.
Speaker 0: I'm like get the fuck off of me.
Speaker 0: I don't want your stupid healing get off.
Speaker 0: There's no way to get him off of you.
Speaker 0: I tried to shoot.
Speaker 0: there was no way to make him stop.
Speaker 0: He wasted one of our health packs too early by healing.
Speaker 1: now That's fine.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's not too bad Whatever cuz?
Speaker 1: I mean I've wasted molotovs.
Speaker 1: I waste things all the time, but well I waste mother sometimes.
Speaker 0: but the fact that Scott health packs a little more precious.
Speaker 1: Scott Johnson Immediately after doing this like literally you you join the game.
Speaker 1: you waste the health pack and then you turn Toward a boomer and basically jump it as fast as possible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was a. there was a ladder and there's a boomer coming up the ladder.
Speaker 0: I saw it there So I hit it with the melee attack and I back and it fell down the ladder and I started to back off and I Pulled out my pistol and I was like boomer boomer on the ladder.
Speaker 0: get away get away.
Speaker 0: Scott Johnson runs right at it.
Speaker 0: The boomer comes up the ladder and explodes on him because he shot it when he was standing right next to it.
Speaker 0: It was it was beautiful He might be able to.
Speaker 1: it was literally.
Speaker 1: it was like he joins Medpack.
Speaker 1: boomer vote to kick.
Speaker 1: vote passes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's one thing.
Speaker 0: It does have a good, you know, there's a good voting system.
Speaker 0: You can vote to kick players off your team and all that.
Speaker 0: So if you have an afk you can just sort of stick around in the safe room vote them out you know and get the AI to come in which is better than an afk at least and stuff like that, but He might be able to make an excuse that you know, he was doing it on purpose or something like that, which is possible.
Speaker 0: But if that is the case, that means he should be able.
Speaker 0: if he was doing that on purpose then He needs to prove that he doesn't suck by playing well.
Speaker 0: So if his in if in his attempt to play well he fails then he was obviously not doing poorly on purpose and That that's it.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: He.
Speaker 0: so he has a chance.
Speaker 1: Oh, so public service announcement.
Speaker 1: Scott Johnson is the MD of left for dead.
Speaker 0: do not play left for dead with Scott Johnson.
Speaker 0: He will ruin you.
Speaker 0: I mean think about this, right?
Speaker 0: I played left for dead.
Speaker 0: It was like me Sad Johnson and two other people, you know, and I don't know, you know, I forget who the other people were.
Speaker 0: But we're doing basically the very first campaign on advanced.
Speaker 0: We're just dying all over the place.
Speaker 0: dead dead dead dead dead, right?
Speaker 0: The night or a night or two before that I was playing the same campaign with water is poison and Alex and someone else.
Speaker 0: We got all the way to the end.
Speaker 0: We couldn't beat the end, but we got all the way to the end, right?
Speaker 0: Then me rim classic and someone else played the campaign.
Speaker 0: We just got to the end of beat it.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute I got an idea without dying Scott Johnson.
Speaker 0: same campaign same difficulty Scott Johnson.
Speaker 1: I have an idea.
Speaker 1: All right An ultimatum perhaps an offer.
Speaker 1: We will never make fun of you on the show.
Speaker 1: in regards to left for dead again if you will assemble a team of four people of your choosing who are willing to play with you and Take Scott and I on with a team of our choosing.
Speaker 0: Yeah Beat us at versus.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: They got no chance.
Speaker 0: Come on.
Speaker 1: You can train you Give you do it sometime in like January or February.
Speaker 1: Let's do it.
Speaker 0: I'll take classic.
Speaker 0: I'll take water is poison.
Speaker 1: We got a film a demo with this.
Speaker 1: This has got to be the drudge match of the century.
Speaker 0: We can't lose.
Speaker 1: There's no way and I know I am pre hoc trash talking as Scott will attend.
Speaker 0: You ready?
Speaker 0: I got the fucking dumpster of trash, right?
Speaker 1: Scott Scott get a test.
Speaker 1: that pre hoc trash talk is something I don't do frequently.
Speaker 1: It is not a thing I did.
Speaker 1: I will do the post-hoc.
Speaker 1: once I know I'm going to win or once I have won the trash talk will come out about how so how bad you are and How much better your mom was the night before?
Speaker 1: But if I'm not sure I'm gonna win I often won't trash talk because then if I lose the trash talk is returned to me Threefold much like Wicca.
Speaker 0: Yep, any trash talk you dispense that was not validated by victory is You know multiplied and you know, rich reverse direction.
Speaker 0: It's just like is why you should not dish it here.
Speaker 1: I until you are sure that the victory will come to back it up Of course, if you might if you think you're gonna lose and you trash talk anyway, and you pull it off.
Speaker 1: That's like the 10x multiplier in a pinball machine.
Speaker 0: That is because if you pre talk and then if you're pretty tall and you win Multiplied and sends forward you could have had some interesting rhyming.
Speaker 1: if you're pre talk and walk the walk They can't lame.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I think we're done.
Speaker 1: left for dead is fun, but it's not that fun.
Speaker 0: Play while you can and Scott Johnson sucks in.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.