Speaker 0: It's Tuesday March 18th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk about Professor Layton and the Curious Village.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: You know you never really notice sometimes how?
Speaker 1: Bad something is until you get it replaced with a new one of that thing and then you go oh man How was I using that old thing for so long it didn't even work?
Speaker 0: Yeah?
Speaker 0: It's like you'll have.
Speaker 0: I don't know like.
Speaker 0: I can't even think of something.
Speaker 1: cars a good example.
Speaker 1: I mean you get really used to driving an old busted car.
Speaker 1: Then you get a brand new car.
Speaker 1: you drive a brand new car.
Speaker 1: You're like.
Speaker 1: Oh wow new cars.
Speaker 0: Go yeah It's like you that the quality of something is sort of relative.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: so like if you have a television, and you don't look at other televisions and your television works You just you know that you go.
Speaker 0: What's wrong with it?
Speaker 0: It's fun, then if someone brings in a new television and puts it next to your old one You're like wow my old TV is shitty.
Speaker 0: But I didn't realize it because I didn't have a good one for comparison.
Speaker 1: But yet at the same time like if you only if you like when at RIT we had a god-awful television oh it was god-awful good goddamn.
Speaker 1: this TV was from 1974 and I think we've talked about the TV, but I didn't say suffice to say I almost did but.
Speaker 1: But it was so awful, but we never noticed except every now.
Speaker 1: And then we'd look at another TV and like ah ah but then as long as we didn't see another TV after about a week We'd forget and then the old TV was just fine As long as we didn't look at a color test cuz we realized that red wasn't red and there was no green.
Speaker 1: yeah But so the part of my car that was broken right the only part other than the fact that I still can't Imagine how I was missing a lug nut Like I was missing a lug nut.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well if you're not missing more than a few then you won't really notice.
Speaker 1: Where did it go?
Speaker 1: who took it?
Speaker 0: I have not.
Speaker 0: maybe the last time a tire came on or off it just you know.
Speaker 1: But the last time I took a tire off I took it off and I put the tire back on.
Speaker 0: maybe you forgot it.
Speaker 1: Can't forget a lug nut.
Speaker 1: cuz you look at it.
Speaker 1: You go wow.
Speaker 1: There's a lug nut miss.
Speaker 1: There's only five of them.
Speaker 1: They're big anyway.
Speaker 0: Well if they get loose also You know as you drive they could you know spin off.
Speaker 0: you got there.
Speaker 0: if they're not on there super tight And you keep driving and driving and driving it's gonna come off of there.
Speaker 1: the other thing is Where'd it go?
Speaker 1: because it was behind my hubcap?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: maybe when they took the hubcap off it sort of fell to the ground.
Speaker 0: They didn't notice.
Speaker 1: Maybe someone stole.
Speaker 1: They they took my hubcap off.
Speaker 1: They stole a lug nut to make a crack pipe.
Speaker 0: Not does not make a crack pipe make.
Speaker 1: I still can't figure out how you'd make a serviceable crack pipe out of them.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the spark plug spark plug.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I kid what.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there's a website.
Speaker 0: Let's see how to make crack pie.
Speaker 0: I'm actually typing this in from.
Speaker 1: That's like what badgers eat Crack pipes.
Speaker 0: the idea is to cover my motorcycle with crack pipes.
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: Okay, I don't know.
Speaker 0: What's up with that?
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the only thing that was actually wrong with my car was that the thing that controls the headlights.
Speaker 1: now actually It's only one thing that controls the headlights the hazard lights the turning lights the brights Everything.
Speaker 0: it's a stick with a bunch of switches on it and inside is all that like it's modular.
Speaker 1: I didn't really realize how it all worked, but they had to replace it and you couldn't get one from salvage.
Speaker 1: so I got a new one and It's so nice.
Speaker 1: Like I was turning my lights on and off all the way home It's silent - it doesn't make any noise.
Speaker 1: when I like move it doesn't click it's solid.
Speaker 1: It was so nice and they gave me the old one.
Speaker 1: So I learned that because this new one cost a hundred and sixty dollars I'm gonna open up the old one and fix it then sell it on eBay or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe I could probably sell it for at least 80 bucks.
Speaker 0: How would you know if it was working?
Speaker 1: It's actually pretty obvious.
Speaker 1: if you'll I can show it to you.
Speaker 1: It's in my car right now.
Speaker 1: You'll be like, oh duh All right, whatever.
Speaker 1: But yeah, that's that's the most exciting thing that happened to me today.
Speaker 0: No, it's funny that your your thing that happened to you today involves cars because last weekend, you know the weekend of March 14 15 16 etc.
Speaker 0: was was a special weekend for cars in 2008.
Speaker 0: It is the weekend of the Australian Grand Prix the first Grand Prix of the year.
Speaker 0: So today I have two news is involving cars and a thing of the day involving cars.
Speaker 0: All right All right See how many go for these newses.
Speaker 1: go for it.
Speaker 1: my interest in f1 and racing in general Waxton Wayne and wax and Wayne and it's real Wayne right now.
Speaker 0: anyway Gran Turismo 5 is coming or great.
Speaker 1: All right I got to say one thing before you continue because I don't know what you're gonna say.
Speaker 1: But regardless of how the game plays I'm not one to say all graphics make a game but that game looks freaking amazing.
Speaker 0: I was about to say I'm not.
Speaker 0: you know, I do not buy games based on graphics.
Speaker 0: I don't judge games based on graphics.
Speaker 1: Well beyond the obvious limit of I can't tell if that's Mario or a smudge on the TV, right?
Speaker 0: but you look at the screenshots and videos of Gran Turismo 5 and I Thought it was just race footage or like the open.
Speaker 0: know that it's actually.
Speaker 0: that's what the game looks like.
Speaker 0: good God,
Speaker 1: you know I've wanted a realistic racing game pretty much for as long as I've known that there were cars Like seriously and the thing that always stops me is that even the realistic ones Like Gran Turismo most people play them with like an Xbox controller and that's not gonna do it for me.
Speaker 1: That's the point of realism if I get an analog stick.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I really have a hard time playing these games In general, like I like the idea of like Gran Turismo, but actually trying to play it I always just spin out and crash because there's you know But in the arcade and when I got the wheel and the pedals I rock and roll.
Speaker 0: So anyway, I'm not exactly sure what the deal is because act there's a game called Gran Turismo 5 prologue coming out And it's not just like a demo.
Speaker 0: It's actually a game you pay for and it's got over a million pre-orders in Europe already, it's crazy.
Speaker 0: But I don't know.
Speaker 0: is Gran Turismo 5 gonna come later, I don't know some game journalists we are yeah But I can't really figure it out.
Speaker 0: I tried to figure it out I can't.
Speaker 0: what I do was able to figure out is that Gran Turismo 5 is Going to have.
Speaker 0: one of the cars available is going to be the 2007, you know f1 Ferrari Huh?
Speaker 0: This is being called God mode.
Speaker 0: I stole that from Kotaku, but whatever it's funny.
Speaker 0: Yes, yes, that's all I got to say about that.
Speaker 0: now my other racing news which is something we can actually talk about Mario Kart for the Wii is gonna be out in like a month or so, which is too soon too soon.
Speaker 0: You just put out Smash Brothers.
Speaker 1: I mean, I haven't even gotten to the second tier of goodness at Brawl.
Speaker 0: I know people complain that Nintendo will release a game that have a big drought of no games and then release a game again.
Speaker 1: Never complain about that.
Speaker 0: but asshole if you release a game too soon after another game I won't be done with Smash Brothers, but I'll have Mario Kart and that'll be frustrating.
Speaker 0: on two games at once.
Speaker 0: It's no good.
Speaker 1: Some of you might make the argument which is true in some cases that oh Well you old men with your podcast and your jobs don't have the free time that us college kids do.
Speaker 1: so.
Speaker 1: as a result You need more time.
Speaker 1: We're already done with brawl But I point out that when we were in college brawl lasted us like three years.
Speaker 1: well melee Yeah And there was pretty much one continuous game going on being handed off controller to controller at some point in our apartments Pretty much for as long as we were at our IT.
Speaker 0: Yeah But anyway, this is Mario Kart Wii that is coming out is gonna have little plastic steering wheels and whatnot.
Speaker 0: And you know, whatever.
Speaker 1: am I gonna have to take my DS?
Speaker 1: Well, not my DS is not a DS game.
Speaker 1: Am I gonna have to waggle the stick back and forth forth so hard that my hand hurts Continuously in order to get good score.
Speaker 0: In fact, my news is that you will definitely not have to do so.
Speaker 0: The Mario Kart Wii will have no snaking whatsoever.
Speaker 0: It'll actually be a game of racing skill where the longer you hold Your power slide the bigger a boost you will have when you let go.
Speaker 1: that is so hardcore because that's the most fun.
Speaker 0: I think that is what the intention was.
Speaker 0: I think in the DS one It just the way they programmed it like by holding a boost longer.
Speaker 0: You would get blue but holding a slide longer.
Speaker 0: You got blue sparks, right?
Speaker 0: But you but you could.
Speaker 0: actually the way it was programmed You could actually do multiple boosts and go faster.
Speaker 0: You could actually do boost on straightaways.
Speaker 0: I don't think that's going to be possible at least from what Nintendo says in the Wii version Which I think is actually gonna be great because you know, you're gonna be steering by, you know Twisting the Wiimote back and forth.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna be wanna have to do multiple boots per turn.
Speaker 0: That's gonna hurt a lot.
Speaker 0: And I think this is great because you know It's.
Speaker 0: it's finally the first time since the GBA Mario Kart my favorite Mario Kart where there's no snaking there's.
Speaker 0: no, you know, it's a decent game and They're not gonna have.
Speaker 0: it's not gonna be cheating like, you know Sick Mario 64 kart 64 and it's not gonna have some gimmick like the to the tag team stuff of Double Dash.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be a real Mario Kart and I'm all about it.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Everyone get Mario Kart Wii.
Speaker 1: All right, Scott, just so you know I'm not gonna get into this but all the information about Gran Turismo 5 prologue is on the Wikipedia about the game.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, but what is that Gran Turismo 5?
Speaker 0: No, so what's Gran Turismo 5?
Speaker 1: Gran Turismo 5?
Speaker 0: So what?
Speaker 0: what's the difference?
Speaker 1: Gran Turismo 5 prologue is the precursor to the planned Gran Turismo 5?
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, it's basically Gran Turismo 5 and Gran Turismo 5 is Gran Turismo 6.
Speaker 0: Say that's.
Speaker 0: it was not easy because with the naming and the is it a demo?
Speaker 0: is it just a preview?
Speaker 0: is like Gran Turismo 5 just gonna be this game with more stuff.
Speaker 1: Whoa, this short version title is a precursor to polyphony.
Speaker 1: polyphony digital's bland Gran Turismo 5.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, Gran Turismo 5 prologue features 16 player online races over 60 cars 14 tuned cars five tracks 7.1 HD sound.
Speaker 0: that sounds like a whole game to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it sounds like a prologue.
Speaker 1: Anyway, well, apparently there was a Gran Turismo 4 prologue that was released everywhere But the United States one year before Gran Turismo 4 came out.
Speaker 0: If I would have known that it would have made a lot more sense.
Speaker 0: But the five prologue is coming out in the US.
Speaker 1: It looks like Top Gear is gonna be involved in this with their track is in the game episodic contents.
Speaker 0: See actually this really isn't a bad idea this prologue thing because what you can do is You know some video games take a long time to make right and every time and you want to take your time to make it Just right, especially when it's such a big project like this, right?
Speaker 0: But if you take too long You're not gonna make any money Because you're gonna spend all this money Developing and developing and you're not gonna make any money for years and years and years and the fuck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: And also, you know people will be like all delays Delays with this sort of prologue thing.
Speaker 0: where you can do is you can make a game You can sort of put out more than a demo but less than the full version for amount of money.
Speaker 0: Sell it to finance the further development and it's it's not really, you know, I can kind of go for that.
Speaker 1: Hey, actually they're gonna support a really really good racing wheel.
Speaker 0: it looks like By a ps3 and an HDTV two wheels.
Speaker 1: and this game, you know what it almost would be.
Speaker 1: where I have to try the game first It's only like five thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: my whole life, right?
Speaker 1: I've always wanted a ultra realistic car simulator because I'd love to be a Crazy good driver and imagine a video game that is so accurate that practicing on it is tantamount to practicing real car.
Speaker 1: Also, then I can try out cars that I will never own my entire life.
Speaker 1: Yeah The only thing it really would lack is the whole Feeling the car around you.
Speaker 1: Of course, I could get that initial D thing from Japan.
Speaker 0: Why don't you try that live for speed thing?
Speaker 1: How much money is that?
Speaker 0: I don't I'm not sure but it's like probably more than a PlayStation Really fancy PC racing simulator like, you know those fancy PC flight simulators.
Speaker 0: This is sort of like the same thing but for racing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 1: I don't know this game.
Speaker 1: I don't think I'll get a ps3 for it just yet.
Speaker 1: But if you have a ps3 and you like racing games One you should get this game.
Speaker 1: more importantly if you get this game and you do not have a good racing wheel What the hell is wrong with you?
Speaker 1: I mean seriously who plays a racing game with an analog stick, especially a realistic one I live for?
Speaker 0: speed is forty seven dollars and sixty two cents.
Speaker 1: All right, is it good?
Speaker 1: Is it perfect?
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it's a really fancy racing simulator much like the flight simulator.
Speaker 0: That's all I know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll have to look into this business.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not that I play PC games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're gonna buy a wheel for the PC, right?
Speaker 1: I would if it was good enough.
Speaker 1: I'll look into this.
Speaker 1: All right, I can boot into Windows about half the time.
Speaker 1: Okay, the other half the time windows won't boot.
Speaker 0: All right, we got news over there.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I got doing news.
Speaker 1: Well, there was no gaming news I cared about and Scott did two newses.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna do something crazy.
Speaker 1: I got a geek bite here.
Speaker 1: Oh, no Now there's been this mod for counter-strike this zombie mod and what's one of those?
Speaker 1: really good idea?
Speaker 1: Really poor execution really hacked together Only fun once or twice and then gets real old.
Speaker 1: Well, uh, we wondered why didn't anyone make a zombie mod for like half-life a half-life 2 or something?
Speaker 0: Well, actually I was just you know, I wanted to play an FPS really badly.
Speaker 0: So I started looking for you know mods to plus zombie panic exclamation point source.
Speaker 1: Mmm, it's actually not at all fun yet and barely playable.
Speaker 1: But they're working on it and a lot of the concepts in this thing are real good.
Speaker 0: And as long as they it's better than the average mod, but it's not great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, as long as they continue to work on it, it'll be good.
Speaker 1: But then again, I'm not too.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't have a lot of confidence because this has been around for years And if it's all been around for years, but the source one is much newer than the non source one.
Speaker 1: in 2006 zombie panic source was picked as one of mod DB's top 100 unreleased mods of the year.
Speaker 1: Yep Wow in 2007 it was marked again.
Speaker 1: They went.
Speaker 0: that released my a hundred over a hundred unreleased mods.
Speaker 1: That says something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they began development in 2005 And the game is fun, but it really doesn't work at all.
Speaker 0: it works It just doesn't work super well.
Speaker 1: Yeah play it more than once and it turns it ends up being not fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it depends.
Speaker 1: every map is broken.
Speaker 1: If you don't play objective mode the game is just completely broke.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah you need to play objective mode.
Speaker 1: half the objectives just don't work or no one knows what to do.
Speaker 1: all the controls for Managing ammo or controls are managing.
Speaker 0: that's really annoying.
Speaker 0: I gotta say it's the number one thing that's wrong with it.
Speaker 1: Here's the cool idea.
Speaker 1: the game starts out much like the game vampire tag in that one player is a zombie who can infect or kill and Everyone else is just some human with a gun and very little ammo and maybe some melee weapons.
Speaker 1: now I'll point out so I have to say it again.
Speaker 1: The melee weapons are designed as All FPS melee weapons are.
Speaker 1: they're awful.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean they some of them can do some pretty big damage, but try hitting with them.
Speaker 0: Good luck with that, especially you don't want to hit with them because the zombies only have melee attacks.
Speaker 0: So trying to go after a zombie with a melee weapon, that's not pretty much on the brink of death It's just.
Speaker 0: it's a guaranteed death for you.
Speaker 0: It's totally not fun because the melee weapons are used for breaking things.
Speaker 1: The melee weapons are no better than the melee weapons in the goddamn Ninja mod for quake 2 and if anyone else played that my hat is off to you.
Speaker 1: But that aside the hammer was the best weapon.
Speaker 1: But anyway so other than that you you know You find guns or shotguns and AKs and all these different guns and every gun takes a different kind of ammo and you can drop Individual specific amounts of different ammo from different guns to give to other people, right?
Speaker 0: So like if I have like if I have a rifle and have lots of rifle ammo, but I pick up some shotgun ammo I don't you know carrying that around makes me walk slower.
Speaker 0: It burdens me so I want to get rid of it.
Speaker 0: So you have to move this little arrow up and down and then push a button to drop your shotgun ammo.
Speaker 1: It's really annoying and while the sort of resource management survival mode thing is really cool It's almost totally mitigated by the fact that the way it's implemented is fiddly and completely non-fun.
Speaker 0: I think the real problem with this sort of zombie survival game right is that it plays in rounds that are like counter-strike.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like play around play around play around.
Speaker 0: as you know Many FPS's are want to do and as the engine is sort of designed to do but a Survival game really has to be sort of long.
Speaker 0: Oh my What I would do Have objective.
Speaker 1: Well, this game has all that.
Speaker 1: It's just it's not that fun.
Speaker 1: yet what I would do is I'd make a game like this where Human that the goal is simply survive for the humans and kill for the zombies and there's million ways to do that.
Speaker 1: But it's basically how long can the humans hold out?
Speaker 1: and then you switch it up.
Speaker 1: How long can the other humans hold out?
Speaker 0: and it's not bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you want to get it to the point where Eventually, you will run out of all your bullets.
Speaker 1: Eventually, the zombies will get you.
Speaker 1: there is no way to win as the humans.
Speaker 1: It is only how long do you hold out?
Speaker 1: It's not bad like defending a house infinite horde.
Speaker 1: I can think of a million ways to do it, but I don't want to get bogged down.
Speaker 0: What I was really looking for was some sort of co-op mod Like I wanted it to be like me and rim versus a bunch of AI zombies.
Speaker 1: That's the problem.
Speaker 1: is Scott yells at me.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I found this co-op zombie mod.
Speaker 1: Let's play it.
Speaker 1: So we put all this effort.
Speaker 1: It said co-op zombie mod.
Speaker 0: It was lying.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 0: It's a team zombie mod.
Speaker 0: Not a co-op zombie mod.
Speaker 1: It's just counter zombie as opposed to yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's worth playing once or twice.
Speaker 1: They really need Half-life 2.
Speaker 0: it's free, right?
Speaker 0: So why why not?
Speaker 1: well, it takes you know, like 20 minutes to download it and get it set up and then you'll have to learn the controls.
Speaker 1: and the only one cool mechanic I like is that humans are real slow.
Speaker 0: and Well humans are actually if you're not carrying anything are the fastest, but if you're uninjured They're pretty much real slow because you're gonna be carrying stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, there is Zombie panic mode.
Speaker 1: hence the title of the mod.
Speaker 1: you hit a button and your guy panics.
Speaker 1: He drops half the stuff he's carrying and starts going But at the same time he goes stupidly fast and you can run away.
Speaker 0: Yep, and mostly you get much faster because he dropped a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 1: But also you just get faster and the whole the the speeds of everything are really finely tuned in this game.
Speaker 1: I feel like they put more effort into that then into the rest of them.
Speaker 0: I think that's that's a very important thing that they it's good They paid attention to because the zombies having only melee weapons, right which is their hands, you know The speed of the of the players and the their ability to move is everything.
Speaker 0: because if the human can move faster than the zombie The zombie can never catch it and then that's a stalemate and it's stupid, you know.
Speaker 0: But if the zombie moves faster than the human, you know The way the zombies work with their regenerating health and and there are lots and lots of damage with their melee weapon Then the humans have no chance.
Speaker 0: So you really you have to you know Really finely tuned how speeds are affected by different things and such to to make the game work out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only other thing I can say is that Natural selection probably as a mod has the best new new friendly environment in the history of mods.
Speaker 1: If you join a natural selection server and you have no idea how to play pretty much everyone on both teams will help you.
Speaker 1: Zombie panic.
Speaker 1: And this game is not noob friendly.
Speaker 1: Everyone is going to be a cock to you.
Speaker 1: There's going to be yelling at you because you don't know what button to hit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know where the objective is the game doesn't tell you.
Speaker 1: Learning the maps is really hard and annoying and it's like yeah, don't expect anyone to help you when you play this game But luckily you're not gonna want to play this game very much.
Speaker 1: It's not Great.
Speaker 0: speaking of natural selection.
Speaker 0: I just went to the website cuz you mentioned them.
Speaker 0: Yes, they put out the 20th episode of their podcast.
Speaker 1: Did they say in that episode that the new natural selection is going to come?
Speaker 0: No, they say Investment received.
Speaker 0: they secured investment from partners.
Speaker 1: Ah, ah Ah There's only one Possible.
Speaker 1: well now there are three items of news in the gaming world that could come out.
Speaker 1: that would be better than that.
Speaker 1: The first one would be natural selection.
Speaker 1: source is out and playable right now.
Speaker 0: Natural it's not gonna be.
Speaker 0: natural selection - I believe is what it's gonna be called whatever.
Speaker 1: whatever ain't I knew natural selection comes out I guess - would be tribes - put back together Re-released and now available for playing online.
Speaker 0: Whoever natural selection - I predict will come out by 2010. if it doesn't come out in the year 2010, then I'll be wrong and It'll be the new and when it comes out, it will become the new greatest online FPS.
Speaker 1: Oh when it maintain that title for years if that game ever comes out is going to be.
Speaker 0: that is my prediction.
Speaker 1: Natural selection is so good.
Speaker 1: If you have never played it go play it.
Speaker 1: people still do an episode on it.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure we did.
Speaker 0: Let's do things of the day now.
Speaker 1: Okay, so things of the day.
Speaker 0: that was quick.
Speaker 0: You got a thing today or you want me to do mine?
Speaker 1: I guess you can do yours.
Speaker 0: All right, you know my my two news is we're racing related.
Speaker 0: So here we have a Ad.
Speaker 0: yeah, I know it's an ad.
Speaker 0: it's annoying for a car specifically the Pontiac something or other.
Speaker 0: I don't even know.
Speaker 0: This ad is the coolest ad for a car I've ever seen in my entire life.
Speaker 1: It is very rare to run afoul of someone out there in the business world in the marketing world Who was tasked with making a bit of marketing.
Speaker 1: who knew?
Speaker 1: Who got it?
Speaker 1: That's the only way I can put it.
Speaker 1: who gets it.
Speaker 0: This is the only ad for a car I've ever seen that actually Somehow I don't know how but some psychology something Unconscious in my brain.
Speaker 1: It kind of makes me wanna like learn Maybe I want this car the fact that it includes Actual footage from the original game and then it goes back to that at the end with a little explosion.
Speaker 1: This I think this is the best ad ever made.
Speaker 0: Maybe you should see this ad if you're a geek of any kind of video games.
Speaker 1: now If you're watching this ad and you don't know what the game is you suck.
Speaker 1: No, it's more that you're a lot younger than us And you suck.
Speaker 1: So, uh, what what game was this ad?
Speaker 0: This how?
Speaker 0: I think people should know when they see the ad.
Speaker 0: we telling them would be sort of like Let me tell you I'll say this then if that's like being like this is a square class.
Speaker 1: if they made a movie About this game.
Speaker 1: It would look exactly Like this advertisement.
Speaker 0: Oh and there would be no Actors except for cars.
Speaker 1: I would go see that movie in the theater.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just cars.
Speaker 0: No, no people.
Speaker 1: Hell if that ad were the trailer for the movie, I would go see it in the theater.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I go see an opening night pre-ordered wait in line.
Speaker 1: Okay, all right.
Speaker 1: So, um speaking of old games What if you took an old Nintendo cartridge and made something out of it?
Speaker 1: people do that all the time like a crack pipe or?
Speaker 1: Something I don't know.
Speaker 0: whatever do that all the time.
Speaker 1: Well, I we found something.
Speaker 1: Scott found this we kind of swapped things of the day around here because we really wanted to talk about And we thought it would be very interesting if I had all racing things.
Speaker 1: yeah, yeah, and I also spoiled it spy hunter.
Speaker 1: I think I've ever seen anyone turn Into a harmonica.
Speaker 0: Doo doo dee dee dee dee dee dee dee dee.
Speaker 1: it's such an obvious and good idea And I'm just maybe someone has done it before.
Speaker 1: but we found this and here it is.
Speaker 0: It's so ironic because you would blow into your NES cartridge, but now blowing into the any ice car.
Speaker 0: She produces music.
Speaker 1: Putting that any ice cartridge in does not make a game come out.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't.
Speaker 0: It's okay.
Speaker 0: I think you use tech mobile.
Speaker 0: He probably still has super tech mobile.
Speaker 1: So he's okay Right, so what are we gonna review tonight?
Speaker 1: I mean, we've been doing video games lately and board games and such and role-playing games.
Speaker 0: Well, we didn't play enough Smash Brothers yet.
Speaker 0: So maybe we'll talk about the next week.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well also we really have to get the fullness of that game and you all cut.
Speaker 1: I don't think anyone wants to hear.
Speaker 1: oh my god.
Speaker 1: I'm playing it metanide something blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: You wanna hear a real kind of in-depth review, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess I mean plus.
Speaker 0: seriously Anyone who's gonna buy the game has already bought it.
Speaker 0: He really see the point in doing a review except I guess there'll be people in the future when wheeze are cheap.
Speaker 0: The list they'll be like, huh?
Speaker 0: What Wii games do I get?
Speaker 0: and it's like.
Speaker 0: It amazes me how many people like ask us like what DS game should I get?
Speaker 0: It's sort of obvious like I Don't know.
Speaker 0: It's obvious to me.
Speaker 0: Anyway, like what the big hit games.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's obvious to you the person who played those games.
Speaker 0: Yes, cuz I buy them anyway All right, so today I guess we'll talk about the.
Speaker 0: the professor Layton right how much have you played?
Speaker 1: I've got 998 picker ads.
Speaker 0: how many puzzles did you complete?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I beat the whole game, but I didn't.
Speaker 0: I maybe left a handful of puzzles.
Speaker 1: I haven't really gotten to the point of getting any information about the actual mystery of the game.
Speaker 0: well, see that's the thing about.
Speaker 0: the first thing I tell you about this game right is the game is sort of a plot combined with puzzles and that's pretty much it right.
Speaker 0: and The plot is these mysteries and at the beginning of the game There's a mystery and then you kind of solve that mystery.
Speaker 1: Well that we can spoil that.
Speaker 1: Oh my god the cat.
Speaker 1: right off We got the cat.
Speaker 0: Yes, then it was right.
Speaker 0: there as the game goes on They add more and more mysteries and they never solve any of the mystery.
Speaker 0: They even have this little screen.
Speaker 1: They're like you've unlocked the mystery of the dead body or the mystery of the scary thing and you'll pretty much unlock all the mysteries And then all get solved.
Speaker 0: only at the end of the game You just sort of solve like a whole bunch of it.
Speaker 0: You solve all the mysteries at once pretty much.
Speaker 0: The thing is even though I didn't solve the mysteries in-game Until the very end which is how it's supposed to be I solved them in my brain like when I had around 40 puzzles complete.
Speaker 0: I figured out everything.
Speaker 0: Basically the story is.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna summarize the basics of the story.
Speaker 1: before you summarize the story We should summarize what the game is.
Speaker 1: The game is half an anime that you watch and you unlock pieces of the anime by solving math problems.
Speaker 0: Some of them are math problems or logic puzzles.
Speaker 0: Yeah Some of them are visual puzzles.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but usually they're visual puzzles that are solved by logic.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yes, usually and Yeah, you know you've played puzzle.
Speaker 0: You've probably done puzzles like these before in your life, especially if you were in like the math Olympiad in middle school.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you ever done the puzzle where it's like there's three sheep and three.
Speaker 0: There's three sheep and three wolves, right?
Speaker 0: And you got to get them from one side of the river to the other.
Speaker 0: if there's ever more Wolves than sheep on one side of the river then the sheep the wolves will eat the sheep and you'll be screwed.
Speaker 0: And you have to put at least one wolf or one sheep onto the boat at a time in order to you know Not have in order to get it to go across When it's empty.
Speaker 1: my dad's twice as old as my mom and my mom is four times as old as my brother and my brother's Tears older than me.
Speaker 1: How old is the dog?
Speaker 1: kind of problems?
Speaker 0: Yep, though, or I have 12 match.
Speaker 0: I have 12 matchsticks.
Speaker 0: Fuck you Or like, you know, it'll be.
Speaker 0: the matchstick ones are like, you know.
Speaker 0: Look at the.
Speaker 0: these matchsticks are arranged in a way that you know draws That you know.
Speaker 0: four squares move only two matchsticks so that there are only three squares instead of four square.
Speaker 1: one thing I got to say about this game is that you expect a certain kind of level of sensibility from Nintendo games and the game looks a little bit like cutesy like this is gonna be a very wide audience kid friendly little game.
Speaker 1: But it's it skirts the edge a little more than you'd expect.
Speaker 1: I mean, I remember one of the puzzles.
Speaker 1: This is it's a really hilarious puzzle is Doggy and it shows there's the doggy made out of matchsticks gets run the fuck over by a car.
Speaker 1: What's he look like now?
Speaker 1: move to matches?
Speaker 0: I love that puzzle.
Speaker 0: That was like I got that puzzle right away.
Speaker 0: But meanwhile to rim and someone else I know both had wicked trouble on that puzzle.
Speaker 1: No The only trouble I had was the first time.
Speaker 1: I was like I know what the dog looks like.
Speaker 1: so I drew the dog Squashed but I angled one of the matches wrong.
Speaker 1: It was like no you're wrong I'm like, ah, and then I drew it again.
Speaker 1: my angled right and there was like, yeah, you got.
Speaker 0: yes one thing.
Speaker 0: I was very careful to make sure all the things are like.
Speaker 1: I got that one puzzle wrong.
Speaker 1: I was like double careful and everything else It was one puzzle.
Speaker 0: right where it's like.
Speaker 0: here are five playing cards and it then it was a logic puzzle.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: this card comes before this card.
Speaker 0: this card comes after that card.
Speaker 0: This card is you know, not third and what you know that sort of puzzle.
Speaker 0: So I arranged I moved.
Speaker 0: all the cards are sitting there in slot.
Speaker 0: So I moved them all around and then I pushed submit and it said you're wrong and I'm like I'm like.
Speaker 0: no I'm right.
Speaker 0: I had to put them in different slots.
Speaker 0: There were another set of slots that I didn't see.
Speaker 0: If there was another set of slots Why did it?
Speaker 0: let me rearrange the cards within the slots that they were already in as opposed, you know, it's the anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's fun.
Speaker 0: If you like solving clever little puzzles Like if you like doing you know, you buy those puzzle books in the store that you know.
Speaker 0: I don't know how popular they are now, but I remember before you know, the big portable video games are awesome.
Speaker 0: You would go to the store.
Speaker 0: you buy a book of word search or a book of crossword puzzle But they had the other ones that were like book of logic puzzle or book of you know, acrostics.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this game is for you.
Speaker 0: Good God if you like those things.
Speaker 1: But then again at the same time if you're really into those things You've seen every one of these puzzles before prop
Speaker 0: or some cut some, you know similar puzzle Yeah,
Speaker 1: but then again, there's the nice benefit that you might have seen similar puzzles before but the puzzles are actually really really really varied.
Speaker 1: And on top of that a lot of the puzzles are set up such that That the game uses the fact that you are on a video game console.
Speaker 1: so well in that like, you know The classic puzzle of.
Speaker 1: I've got three pictures the whole different amounts and I have to get the liquid I love.
Speaker 0: those are my favorite ones.
Speaker 0: I did and the problem was I did all those picture puzzles like right away and then there were none left.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, but doing those on paper and like the math Olympiad when yeah, it's like sucked.
Speaker 0: I've got one pitcher of water and has ten liters.
Speaker 0: I've got a three liter pitcher and a five liter pitcher.
Speaker 1: How can I get to four liter pitch?
Speaker 0: How can I get to four to four liter pitchers, you know?
Speaker 0: It's like ah, but this it lets you actually pour the water from one to the other and it's mad fun mad fun.
Speaker 0: I love doing that.
Speaker 0: Yeah I could just do water pitcher puzzles from like now till the end of time also like weight puzzles where it's like Here's a here's a scale and here's a bunch of weights.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know Oh, that one was really.
Speaker 1: it's one of the really early ones too.
Speaker 1: It's like here's eight weights.
Speaker 1: One of them is lighter than all the rest.
Speaker 1: You can use the scale twice.
Speaker 1: Which one is it?
Speaker 1: And the cool thing is I actually I was curious how the game works.
Speaker 0: So it randomize them.
Speaker 1: Yes time I tested that to be sure I was like one two, three four five six seven eight.
Speaker 1: Yep, they're uneven and I kept doing it and the sides kept switching like yep.
Speaker 1: They don't let people cheat.
Speaker 1: How awesome is that?
Speaker 0: It's pretty awesome right there.
Speaker 0: You actually have to solve the puzzle.
Speaker 0: You can't just sort of go by luck.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's some puzzles where you can go by luck Like there'll be a multiple choice like ABCD, which is the odd one out and if you choose wrong It'll say you're wrong and it'll take away picker ads from you.
Speaker 0: So it's like it really encourages you.
Speaker 0: I mean you could just be like a B C D and you'll get it right.
Speaker 1: but then Puzzles you're not going to because it's just like what's the answer and you just write a number?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's really good at recognizing what number you write.
Speaker 1: Yeah, God The handwriting recognition in this game is absolutely fantastic.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz it only has to recognize, you know, like letters and numbers and it puts that little grid there and it's it's really smart.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course The one thing that was really really smart about that This is when they want you to type in like your name in the beginning It always asks you uppercase or lowercase which may just from a programming perspective Makes it a thousand times easier to recognize characters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like how's it gonna recognize uppercase or lowercase C?
Speaker 1: That's really hard really hard for you to do and it does Recognize the way I write to and for as opposed to the way some other heathens write.
Speaker 0: I think also the way that it presents the input interface.
Speaker 0: for you know Writing the numbers and letters in it really sort of encourages you to sort of write them carefully and neatly.
Speaker 0: It is like a little school is like a cross and it's like, okay So I put the top right of my letter in the top right box and out, you know Actually, I think carefully though I've written just in like one corner and it works just as well.
Speaker 0: Oh it does.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it does but it encourages you to write neatly.
Speaker 1: I think what also encourages you to write neatly is the fact that Layton is so gentlemanly and neat and precise that you feel bad About being all scribbly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you definitely feel bad.
Speaker 1: Layton is so cool and he's such a badass.
Speaker 0: So here's the story of the game, right?
Speaker 0: You've got the.
Speaker 0: I have 12 match.
Speaker 0: I have 12 match six But you have a guy named professor Layton and he's all British.
Speaker 1: Take like Sherlock Holmes Remove the pretension and add like lady killer and civility and and just consummate badass.
Speaker 0: Right, and he's got a little assistant.
Speaker 0: What's the assistant's name?
Speaker 1: I Already forgot and I play.
Speaker 1: I play the game.
Speaker 1: I was playing it like an hour ago little kid who's dressed in blue.
Speaker 0: he's really funny cuz he's kind of funny and The game has actual like animated video Cutscenes that are like fully voice acted.
Speaker 1: fully
Speaker 0: voice acted in the voice acting is pretty good except personally, like the voice acting is high quality it really goes well, but When ever you beat a puzzle the character either Layton or the kid is like, you know They say something like catchphrase like you got it or like yeah I solved the puzzle or every puzzle has an answer.
Speaker 1: I think my favorite one is like logic and reason win the day or something like that.
Speaker 0: I like, you know, I like that.
Speaker 0: But hearing them over and over and over they got a little bit, you know Cuz there weren't enough variations of the success voice acting that it sort of got a little annoying hearing the same ones over and over.
Speaker 0: I don't know just me.
Speaker 1: maybe see it didn't bother me at all.
Speaker 0: It bothered me.
Speaker 0: Anyway, of course then again that the voice acting in the videos is just fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's great.
Speaker 1: and I'll just say the soundscape the way like the sound design of this game is absolutely amazing.
Speaker 1: the background music is Interesting enough to where you'll probably find yourself playing this game with headphones or with the sound all the way up Even after you've been playing the game for hours and hours and hours.
Speaker 1: You've already heard all the music, right?
Speaker 0: So professor Layton and his kid are driving their car to this town in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 0: He got a. professor Layton received a letter in the mail about someone had inherited some monies.
Speaker 1: It's a very LePon the third kind of plot.
Speaker 1: It is a very LePon the third plot without the stealing though Yeah, but it's kind of like a Cagliostro-ian plot Kinda, yeah, it's like oh there's the treasure but is the treasure what you think it is?
Speaker 1: Ah, the treasure is my only daughter.
Speaker 1: The treasure is the historical record of the city that was buried.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is a very LePon a plot.
Speaker 0: You're right, but he goes to this town and he's like, oh, it's an interesting plot.
Speaker 0: We must uncover it and basically he goes to this town and everyone in the town just asked him to solve puzzles all the time Which provides the game?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and also people are disappearing and also people are disappearing or getting murdered and all sorts of things happen and you sort of Go around solving puzzles and the more puzzles you solve the more the plot is revealed to you.
Speaker 0: And that's that's pretty much the game.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna reveal more of the plot than that because that would just.
Speaker 0: what's the point of playing then?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's it's a halfway decent plot.
Speaker 0: The only thing I found wrong with the plot was that I figured out the rest of the plot about like A third of the way through the game.
Speaker 0: I said basically the town is fucked up in some way But you can't.
Speaker 0: it's like the town is weird and something is wrong But you don't know what and they don't tell you what until the end of the game.
Speaker 0: I figured out what and I was right way early on.
Speaker 0: it's not hard.
Speaker 1: I'm curious if I'll figure it out at about the same point Scott did or not.
Speaker 0: Well, I figured I looked up in the corner when I figured it out and I had about 50 puzzles solved.
Speaker 1: So I'm nowhere near that.
Speaker 0: Okay, okay But yeah, I haven't.
Speaker 1: I haven't done anything yet.
Speaker 1: pretty much I got to town save the cat.
Speaker 1: some dude got axed.
Speaker 1: Okay, yeah No, and I have been ignoring the plot and pretty much searching the game for every possible puzzle.
Speaker 1: I can find it just completely ignoring the plot.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but yeah, it wasn't hard to figure out the plot But yeah that I guess that's the whole game right?
Speaker 0: It's like it's the kind of game where you'll buy it You'll play it through once.
Speaker 0: Maybe you if you're you really like it You'll go through and try to find all the puzzles you missed because you can miss puzzles Like you sort of have to click on the screen to find the puzzles so some of them you might not click on and you don't have to.
Speaker 0: you only have to beat like 70 or so puzzles to actually beat the game, you know, so
Speaker 1: but the game definitely does have a little bit of that adventure game point-and-click walk around look at stuff and Maybe this game will be a very slight step toward games like that coming back in a big way on the DS.
Speaker 0: Maybe there's gonna be a sequel to Layton already.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna get it no matter what.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Now if you have a bunch of friends I'd highly recommend just because you know This is what you do one of you buy the game beat it and then just pass it around.
Speaker 1: There's no reason to own it after you've beaten it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well there is one reason to own it after you've beaten it and that is there's a download option.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, the weekly puzzles.
Speaker 0: basically you connect to the Wi-Fi and it'll download one new puzzle every week.
Speaker 0: I think they've already made all the puzzles.
Speaker 0: It's just they sort of.
Speaker 0: I guess their server like, you know delivers new ones weekly.
Speaker 0: So you connect.
Speaker 0: if you connect now don't worry about missing puzzles because it'll download every weekly puzzle that's been released so far.
Speaker 0: So you'll be alright and the weekly puzzle is just as good as the in-game puzzles.
Speaker 0: It's just more of them.
Speaker 1: Now if you're one of those people who won your parents have a DS or you want to get your parents a DS You pretty much want to get them a Sudoku or something because a lot of people like that and like brain training and cooking mama And this game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is this is the game to get people who are not mad gamers.
Speaker 0: The only thing wrong with this game is that it's a playthrough once and you're done game and maybe play a little bit more.
Speaker 0: You know redoing the puzzles is at least you know, if there was another Pitcher puzzle I could do it.
Speaker 0: But if it's the same pitcher puzzle again, it's like, okay.
Speaker 0: I already know the answer.
Speaker 1: It's it's a waste of my yeah, but I mean at least even if like just some of the puzzles I mean that they're so varied that some require logic and some require just algebra.
Speaker 1: And if you're not good at algebra, you will have a hard time solving them.
Speaker 0: One more thing is that some of the puzzles I disagreed with the wording of them like It's one that says something about you know Don't make a mirror image.
Speaker 0: and I came up with the answer and I'm like, I'm pretty sure this is the answer They're looking for and I was right but I claim that that answer was indeed a mirror image But they specifically said not to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I haven't run into anything really big like that yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's also some of those like trick word puzzles The one that's like how many candles are left after blah blah blah Fuck that.
Speaker 1: I got that one right on the first try like two seconds.
Speaker 0: Oh, that was actually of all the puzzles in the game.
Speaker 0: I had the hardest time with that one.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, literally I look at it.
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh duh beep You know what this is.
Speaker 1: this is the best part of this game you realize.
Speaker 0: see the Reason that one got me is cuz okay.
Speaker 0: I know the answer is not the obvious answer, right?
Speaker 0: It's some clever answer and I came up with a clever answer.
Speaker 0: But my answer was more clever than their clever answer.
Speaker 0: So there's no way I was gonna get their clever answer cuz I had a cleverer answer.
Speaker 0: What was your clever?
Speaker 1: I Forget I'm curious cuz I don't think there was a cleverer answer.
Speaker 1: I forget there are Answers depending on how much you thought about it.
Speaker 1: I know that much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it makes sense.
Speaker 0: It does make sense They're right.
Speaker 0: I was wrong, but damn fuck them on that puzzle.
Speaker 1: but this is see.
Speaker 1: this is why this game is really fun cuz you're gonna play through it and you're gonna get some puzzles like That and some puzzles are gonna totally just wreck you and your friends gonna play it and they are Invariably going to wreck every puzzle you had trouble with but they are going to have had trouble with all the puzzles you read
Speaker 0: So far.
Speaker 1: that's the case with us and it's that that will bring so much fun You can get.
Speaker 1: you can all call each other stupid for weeks and weeks and weeks after you all play this game.
Speaker 0: here.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you one of the putt.
Speaker 0: Here's an example of a tricky word puzzle, right?
Speaker 0: It was actually the most recent download.
Speaker 0: play puzzle.
Speaker 0: So rim hasn't heard this one, probably so.
Speaker 0: an astronaut lands on a planet, right and there's there's all sorts of creatures living on the planet hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of them, right.
Speaker 0: and So he starts he decides he's gonna count them, right?
Speaker 0: And there's like.
Speaker 0: there's so many green ones and there's so many red ones and there's so many purple and they give you all these Numbers like there's two red ones and they multiply at this rate.
Speaker 0: and there's so many green ones and they multiply at this rate.
Speaker 0: You know, it's gonna take it, you know, he's gonna stand there and count for this long.
Speaker 0: How many will there be you know, like how many aliens are on the planet?
Speaker 0: And the answer is one because he's the alien he's on their planet.
Speaker 0: And I got that immediately and it was sort of boring.
Speaker 1: but that's actually one really good one that I liked was the one about Bacteria in a jar.
Speaker 1: and what if you start with two instead of one?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that was a good one.
Speaker 0: There's a bunny one like that.
Speaker 0: Oh good.
Speaker 1: All you need anything can be accomplished with the power of love.
Speaker 1: Yeah Seriously though this game is fantastic.
Speaker 1: I have very little bad to say about it at all.
Speaker 0: The only thing is the game only has three save slots.
Speaker 0: So if you actually want your game to be saved you can only share it with two other friends.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but what do you care?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's also some unlucky stuff in the game like character sketches and what it seems corner.
Speaker 1: Eh, yeah now on that note I mean, there's not much more to say about Leighton.
Speaker 1: I mean reviewing a game.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 1: It's always great The graphics are fine and the sound is great and the game is good and you should buy it.
Speaker 1: Thanks.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I mean we could do a final thoughts, but that would just be.
Speaker 1: ah, the plot was blah wasn't that great?
Speaker 0: Well plot was it was.
Speaker 0: it's a decent average plot better than a lot of other plots But not like some epic plot you'll remember for your entire life.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I think we'll end it there.
Speaker 1: But I've there's something we've been meaning to do for a long time and I'm gonna start doing this every Tuesday for a while.
Speaker 1: All
Speaker 0: right
Speaker 1: I'm sure all of you are gamers in some stripe and you're familiar with Dungeons and Dragons and I'm sure many of you who've listened to geek nights long enough are familiar with the burning wheel
Speaker 0: Burn away,
Speaker 1: uh Basically, we're going to run for the next several weeks now.
Speaker 1: I know that this is not advertising.
Speaker 1: We've not been paid in any way.
Speaker 1: In fact at best we stalk the people who pull the person who makes burning wheel.
Speaker 1: Well, it's friend you do.
Speaker 0: Yes, I do I'm just chillin.
Speaker 1: but uh Luke crane the man who made burning wheel and continues to work on burning wheel and he if ever there has been a person who would be described as a rock star of role-playing games.
Speaker 1: it is this man and I could contend that burning wheel is the best role-playing collaborative storytelling system in the world and We play it now in the front row crew.
Speaker 1: and pretty much what I want to do is remind everyone every week for a while that if you have any Role-playing bones in your body if you even think you like Dungeons & Dragons or if you hate Dungeons & Dragons Because the demographic applies regardless You should buy the core books to burning wheel because it will revolutionize your world.
Speaker 0: I didn't even realize there's a third printing and we have actually an older printing.
Speaker 0: I feel like buying the new printing even though it's like if this isn't even change.
Speaker 0: This is like like, you know Like D&D is like three.
Speaker 0: three and a half is sort of a significant change.
Speaker 0: Change right.
Speaker 1: Scott and I are people who when D&D 3.5 came out.
Speaker 0: We kept our old books Forever and then I bought the three and a half and then barely used it and regret buying three and a half.
Speaker 1: Yeah But we kept the old books to the point that we had a lot of rules wrong and we just refused to upgrade and didn't Care.
Speaker 0: and there was a big difference this.
Speaker 0: the difference between the new printing of Is like some a handful of errata.
Speaker 1: it's like word and the Advancement table is slightly skewed.
Speaker 0: I feel like I should buy the new books even though it's just some.
Speaker 0: errata is fixed.
Speaker 1: But seriously I just I have to point this out because I know a lot of you out there here is talk about burning wheel every now And again, if you haven't if you're a new listener go find the episodes on burning wheel.
Speaker 1: We've done several of them and I cannot recommend to you enough.
Speaker 1: by burning wheel You will never play Dungeons & Dragons again Unless you suck.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.