Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, August 5th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, DS, Homebrews, and ROMS.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well, hello, Kineticon, or at least all the people who came to the Geek Nights fold after seeing us at Kineticon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, Kineticon wasn't that big.
Speaker 0: I guess it had more people than last year, at least it felt like it did.
Speaker 1: It's hard to say because Friday was real weak, but then Saturday busted out more so than I would have imagined.
Speaker 0: But this Kineticon, more so than any con before, really felt like we had a big connection with our existing listeners, as well as people who became fans of us at the con, or at least as far as I could tell.
Speaker 1: Well, I think what happened was, I mean, a lot of you probably came to that 8 a.m.
Speaker 1: match game and discovered- Yeah, but because we didn't actually run the match game, well, we did, kind of, but we basically just kind of hung out at the front of the room for two hours.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they're not going to give us celebrity guests.
Speaker 0: A match game can only be an hour, really.
Speaker 1: Granted, had we known we weren't going to have guests, we might have had something more ready to go than we did.
Speaker 0: Well, I would have rescheduled.
Speaker 0: I would have changed it.
Speaker 0: I would have had it not be a match game.
Speaker 0: I would have done something else, and I would have only done it for an hour.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I can say one thing, it must have worked well, because pretty much every panel throughout the day had a bunch of people who went to the previous panel, and then some new people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, at every panel I announced what our remaining panels were, and people seemed to actually pay attention, and I guess they wrote it down or circled it on their schedules or something, because I saw the same faces many times throughout the day.
Speaker 1: Now, before we go any further, I do want to point out, because I'm sure many of you, you know, you went home, you went, "Oh yeah, that Geek Nights thing,".
Speaker 1: and now you're listening to this, the most recent episode.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is four nights a week, and this is Geek Nights Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: So, you know, Mondays, Science Tech, Tuesday, gaming, which a lot of you are probably here for the gaming after the Burning Wheel events.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was great.
Speaker 1: But many of you are probably here for Geek Nights Wednesdays, Anime Manga Comics, so stay tuned tomorrow night when we'll have our actual coverage of Kineticon.
Speaker 1: And Geek Nights Thursdays, we talk about whatever.
Speaker 1: That's kind of the fun time.
Speaker 0: It's kind of weird, though, to do the Kineticon coverage tomorrow, because most of the con was gaming action.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the other thing is that Geek Nights is four nights a week, but this summer we're currently on our sabbatical schedule, so we're actually doing, like, one week Monday-Wednesday, the other week Tuesday-Thursday.
Speaker 1: So basically, it's four separate shows, and they update.
Speaker 1: You can look at the feeds on the website, figure them all out.
Speaker 1: If you got this far, you probably know how podcasts work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but this week we're going to do a Tuesday-Wednesday, just a little bit weird, because the way the conventions are.
Speaker 0: Yes, also- After, in September, things should return to normal.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Now, these might be slightly atypical episodes, too, just tonight and tomorrow, because one, we were at Kineticon last weekend.
Speaker 1: Two, tomorrow night we were packing up, and then Thursday morning we're driving to Baltimore for Oticon, where we were doing another five panels.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you want to listen to some more typical, run-of-the-mill Geek Nights episodes, go back a few weeks, a few months, maybe go on the site and search for a topic that interests you, or check the categories on the left.
Speaker 0: Maybe you'll find something you like.
Speaker 0: Listen to a show about something that you already enjoy, and then you'll know if this is a show you want to listen to.
Speaker 1: But to not continually tick off all the existing listeners with every time we go to Oticon, we talk about- Yeah, and granted, at least from what I saw at Kineticon, it was surprising that- It's like making a guy who's beaten the game sit through the tutorial.
Speaker 1: But I got to say, an anime you should see, that's usually an event where we don't expect our existing listeners to go to it, because they know what we're going to say.
Speaker 1: But there were a lot of you in that audience.
Speaker 1: I guess we've done big con things, but we haven't done big con things as Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: We've kind of been doing these panels.
Speaker 1: that's just, "Yeah, we do this panel,".
Speaker 1: but this time, the first time, we were like, "Hey, we are Geek Nights," and there's a lot of you out there.
Speaker 1: It's kind of scary to see that many fans in one place.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like some people are forum listeners, but there are people who just listen, and they went to the con.
Speaker 0: In fact, almost everyone- They never went in the forum or emailed us or anything.
Speaker 1: Almost every person who came up to us was like, "Oh my god, I listen.
Speaker 1: I've been listening for
Speaker 1: years.".
Speaker 1: I'm like, "Yeah, so who are you in the
Speaker 1: forum?".
Speaker 1: They're like, "Uh, I don't post in the
Speaker 1: forum.".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the one thing I got to say is it was something else to be- it's our last panel of the night, the Beyond Dungeons and Dragons, which, by the way, for all you new listeners, we are doing that exact same panel, only for real, at the Penny Arcade Expo.
Speaker 0: I don't see how the one we didn't do wasn't real.
Speaker 0: Well, it'll be- And the one we did already wasn't real.
Speaker 1: It'll be for a much larger audience, I guess.
Speaker 0: Yeah, other than that, it'll be mostly the same.
Speaker 1: Mostly the same.
Speaker 1: I'm going to have a better example than a hammer and a nail versus a hammer and a bust.
Speaker 1: that's Seinfeld.
Speaker 1: I don't know where I was going with that.
Speaker 1: But, yeah, we're doing that at the Penny Arcade Expo.
Speaker 1: I highly recommend, if you happen to be going to the Penny Arcade Expo at the end of the month, or I guess the beginning of next month, the end of the month.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's Labor Day weekend.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: And Saturday, August 30th, from 6 to 7 in Satellite Theater Room 307.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but it was something to, you know, the panel before us is running out of the lake.
Speaker 0: I hope that, if it's Saturday night, I hope it doesn't conflict.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm going to this con and I'm doing one panel, so really, most of the other time there, I'm going to be trying to enjoy the con, and I got some things I want to do.
Speaker 0: I want to go to the opening keynote.
Speaker 0: I want to go to the concert.
Speaker 0: I want to go to, you know, Gabe Draws, Hot Dog Fairy.
Speaker 0: Maybe I want to see the Omega-thon final.
Speaker 0: You know, there are certain things that happen at PAX that I want to do.
Speaker 0: I hope Saturday night that our panel doesn't conflict with, say, a concert or something.
Speaker 0: That would suck the ass.
Speaker 1: I haven't looked at all, but anyway, it was, you know, we go in the room and the person before us is going a little long, and we're, you know, in the room like, "All right, what are we doing?
Speaker 1: Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 1: Laptop out, getting
Speaker 1: ready.".
Speaker 1: And then we walk outside the room to see the situation and to see all of you people lined up all the way down the hallway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like we had a line and the panel that was in there had five people, and they were giving us guff.
Speaker 0: I'm like, "Look, we got like a hundred people.
Speaker 0: You got like five people.
Speaker 0: You can just stop your panel.
Speaker 0: No
Speaker 0: one.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the other shout out I want to give is that, you know, Alex was doing Birding Wheel demos for pretty much the entire time.
Speaker 0: And he got mad bored.
Speaker 0: Well, he didn't get mad bored, but he was a little, "Eh," because he only brought the sword.
Speaker 0: He didn't bring any other scenarios.
Speaker 0: He was doing the same thing over and over again.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, every sword went completely different.
Speaker 0: I ran a sword.
Speaker 0: Everyone was amicable.
Speaker 0: I was like, "What the fuck?
Speaker 0: Why are we
Speaker 0: amicable?".
Speaker 1: He ran one at the same time, and like everyone drew swords within about 30 seconds.
Speaker 0: I got some plans the next time I played the sword.
Speaker 1: I got to say, though, the elf was doing surprisingly well overall.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I thought I heard that like all the elves got chumped except for one.
Speaker 1: Well, one elf went out in a blaze of glory.
Speaker 0: I think that counts.
Speaker 0: Well, there was a rat that got set on fire, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was also a blaze of glory.
Speaker 1: But to all of you who played Birding Wheel games at Kineticon because you saw our panel or you heard us talking about it, I hope you're listening because we talk about Burning Wheel kind of often now.
Speaker 0: Go to burningwheel.com.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and also, Luke Crane, just in case, he's going to be at the Penny Arcade Expo.
Speaker 0: Is he really?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: In fact, we're probably going to take the crowd, if we can, from the Beyond Dungeons & Dragons panel directly to Mr.
Speaker 1: Luke Crane, who will probably run a demo.
Speaker 0: So he did confirm he was going to be there?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: I told him, "Yeah, Kineticon, blah, blah, blah, panel," and he basically said, "Hot
Speaker 1: shit.".
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, Kineticon coverage will be tomorrow night.
Speaker 0: Dun, dun, dun.
Speaker 1: Dun, dun, dun, dun.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, we got any video game news here?
Speaker 0: You want to go News Time?
Speaker 0: All right, here we go.
Speaker 0: Check this out.
Speaker 0: So people have been talking, you know, the Virtual Console has been a little weak lately.
Speaker 0: I mean, a lot of companies said, "Oh, yeah, our games are coming out of the Virtual
Speaker 0: Console.".
Speaker 0: You know what came out of the Virtual Console?
Speaker 1: What came out of the Virtual Console?
Speaker 0: I think it was like Splatterhouse 2.
Speaker 0: Not too bad.
Speaker 1: Hey, Splatterhouse 3 is where it's at.
Speaker 0: It might have been 3.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: One of the Splatterhouses and the Sega Master System Sonic the Hedgehog.
Speaker 1: Whoa.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty bad.
Speaker 0: So, you know, it's been pretty weak over there.
Speaker 0: And then, like, the WiiWare.
Speaker 0: I mean, some of the WiiWares were good, like, you know, the Dr.
Speaker 0: Mario and the Lost Winds, you know.
Speaker 0: But they put out a lot of their heavy hitters right away, and now they're bringing out the weak sauce.
Speaker 0: But next week, the word on the street is that the WiiWare game is going to be Strong Bad.
Speaker 1: Ah.
Speaker 1: Now, I imagine that this is going to be much like the Penny Arcade game, where the game will probably be alright, but it'll be carried primarily by theme.
Speaker 0: Pretty much.
Speaker 0: But, I mean, the thing is, even when, you know, the Homestar guys were doing their vid-electrics, making, like, the Trogdor game and such.
Speaker 0: Those games that they made were actually not bad.
Speaker 1: You know, they were better than the average Flash game you play online for five minutes.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: So, if they make a whole, if they put their resources into making an entire game worth, this could be something worth paying.
Speaker 0: I mean, I haven't paid attention to Homestar in years, you know.
Speaker 0: It sort of became the same joke over and over and lost its funny.
Speaker 1: Kind of like, or at least to us, kind of like the, uh, the Ask A Ninja.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like that's- I almost said the Ninja Consultant.
Speaker 1: I'm like, "No, that's not it.
Speaker 1: That's completely
Speaker 1: different.".
Speaker 0: No, but Ask A Ninja, you know, it's like, "I look forward to killing you
Speaker 0: soon.".
Speaker 0: And it's like, okay, it was funny a whole bunch of times, but then, eventually, it's sort of the same thing over and over again, and I no longer laughed at it.
Speaker 0: And Homestar was the same way, but maybe I'll check this out.
Speaker 0: I think it's going to be on PC also, so maybe I'll check the PC action.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'll think about it.
Speaker 0: But yeah, you should, if you got WiiWare, you might be wanting to consider getting this, even if you're not a Homestar fan.
Speaker 1: I remember the time I got WiiWare.
Speaker 1: It all started when I drank 48 glasses of marinade.
Speaker 0: Because if you don't, your Wii might lie dormant for quite a while.
Speaker 1: You know, I love the Wii, and the thing is, though, the DS has been my primary console pretty much since it came out, and nothing- The only thing that distracted me from the DS for any length of time was when I got Civ 4, and for the two days after Team Fortress 2 came out before I solved it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I said it before on the show, I'll say it again.
Speaker 0: It's like, I read comics, I read books, I watch anime, now my iPhone, right?
Speaker 0: I play Wii, I do all sorts of geeky things.
Speaker 0: I have a queue of geeky things.
Speaker 0: I program stuff, right, on my laptop.
Speaker 0: If there's a DS game that's good, everything else takes a back burner.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it is about the DS, but it's just- My brain will always have me go for an unplayed, good DS game before anything else, and you're gonna see why that tendency is incredibly dangerous when we get to the real part of the show.
Speaker 1: Well, you see, I think what that is, I think that is misplaced game desire from the fa- I mean, back before we were in the real world, you know, when we were in college.
Speaker 1: As in, infinite free time, zero responsibility, no money, so we couldn't go anywhere anyway.
Speaker 1: It's not like I commuted.
Speaker 1: So, I'd wanna play games.
Speaker 1: I would just sit down in front of a console in our house and play games.
Speaker 1: I would sit down and play a game, like, all the way through.
Speaker 1: But now I don't have time for that.
Speaker 1: I mean, I get home and I gotta do the podcast, I gotta, you know, eat.
Speaker 0: See, it's weird, 'cause if a really good Wii game comes out, like a Twilight Princess or a Metroid or something like that, I do sit down and play the whole thing.
Speaker 0: It happens, you know, I come home every day and play it.
Speaker 0: But there hasn't been a game like that, really.
Speaker 1: Well, see, the other thing is, you get home, your schedule's a little different from mine, and getting up at like 4.30 in the morning really puts a damper on playing games at home when I could be outside.
Speaker 1: Of course, you know, it is also summer.
Speaker 0: It is summer, but you know what, we always say, "Oh, in winter we're gonna play so many
Speaker 0: games.".
Speaker 0: Then in winter we don't play any games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there were reasons for that.
Speaker 1: I mean, we were, the show, we were really kinda doing a lot of Geek Night's work last winter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, alright, we'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: It's alright.
Speaker 1: I feel as though it is not the DS that is causing the desire to play games, the exclusion of all else.
Speaker 1: It is the fact that because we, in particular, have a long commute and aren't home that often, the DS is always there and there's nothing else to distract.
Speaker 1: I mean, think, when you're on the train, I got my laptop.
Speaker 0: But I mean, even if I get a new DS game, like when I got Professor Layton, right?
Speaker 0: I would wake up, get on the train, not even listen to my typical morning podcast and play Professor Layton.
Speaker 0: I would get to work.
Speaker 0: As soon as I walked out the office door, I'd turn it on and play it on my way to the subway, on the subway, on the train.
Speaker 1: But see, it's the same thing for me.
Speaker 0: I got home, I would get home, we would do the show, I would get in bed and play Professor Layton until it was beaten.
Speaker 0: As soon as it was beaten, I put it down.
Speaker 1: But wait, wait, wait.
Speaker 1: For me, it's the same thing with anything I get into.
Speaker 1: that's good that I can do portably.
Speaker 1: So when I was watching Bocorato, you know, right?
Speaker 1: I would pretty much get off of work, run to the train, sit down, start watching, skipping openers and closers, watch as much as I could.
Speaker 0: But I only really do it for DS games.
Speaker 0: I guess I did it for The Prince of Nothing also, but I only really do it for DS games.
Speaker 0: Like, even if I have an amazing anime, I won't do it.
Speaker 1: You said not a few days ago you were doing it a little bit for Evangelion when you were relaunching it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I wasn't watching Evangelion at home.
Speaker 0: It was only on the train only.
Speaker 0: Not home.
Speaker 0: It wasn't as strong as a DS game is.
Speaker 1: Plus, you don't have the ultra immersion of Civ 4 destroying your life like I do right now.
Speaker 0: I was playing the Civ Revelation Revolutions.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Civ Revolutions is a different game.
Speaker 0: It is a different game.
Speaker 1: I'd say it's a completely different game.
Speaker 1: Now, they're very similar, and I'm not saying that one is more fun than the other one, but Civ 4 is definitely not the same game.
Speaker 0: No, I didn't say they were the same game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I actually have been feeling the Civ 4 drive madly.
Speaker 1: But I gotta talk a little bit about it.
Speaker 1: Now, we talked not too long ago about this.
Speaker 1: Diablo 3 is coming out, and all the fans of Diablo, basically...
Speaker 0: You're not doing the news we have to do?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna have to do another news.
Speaker 1: Oh no, we'll get to that.
Speaker 1: I gotta talk about this, because there's some screenshots, and this epitomizes everything I hate about the internet.
Speaker 1: So people saw what Diablo 3 is gonna look like, and people who have never played Diablo before, because they're either younger than us, or smarter than everyone who played Diablo back when it came out...
Speaker 0: Well, they're not smart.
Speaker 0: I mean, never having played Diablo doesn't make you smart.
Speaker 1: I think it does.
Speaker 0: Never going to play Diablo makes you smart.
Speaker 1: But they saw, "Oh, Diablo.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's based on some old game.
Speaker 1: Oh, it looks like, wow, the
Speaker 1: end.".
Speaker 1: But people who had played the old Diablos looked at it and said, "Wow, those graphics are way too good.
Speaker 1: Fuck
Speaker 1: them.".
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And that bothers me a lot, but here's the deal.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm usually the kind of person who says graphics don't matter, that gameplay is more important as long as the graphics uphold the game.
Speaker 1: But I tend to disagree a little bit in that very good atmosphere and very good graphic and immersion design can cover for a lot of gameplay design.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's mostly the design, not the image quality.
Speaker 0: There's the two very different things.
Speaker 1: But there's a line.
Speaker 1: Eternal Darkness was an okay game that was made much, much better just because of the style and everything.
Speaker 1: But if the graphics had been too much worse than it was, they couldn't have pulled off the style in the first place.
Speaker 0: It would have looked like those old walk around with tank controls games and polygons.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: When you played those games way back in the day...
Speaker 1: They weren't immersive at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they were.
Speaker 1: I guess if you were stupid.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Like Half-Life 1, just as immersive as Half-Life 2.
Speaker 1: Half-Life 1, I don't think you understand the level of bad graphics I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about third person view of an 8 polygon man in a 16 polygon world.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's a little different.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so a bunch of fans decided to put together screenshots of what the game should look like.
Speaker 0: Uh huh.
Speaker 1: And on the left, one, this is shit grammar.
Speaker 1: How it looks like, how it should look like.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 1: That is bad.
Speaker 1: But on the left, I see a game that looks incredibly polished and it looks kind of like "wow" and it looks really, really good.
Speaker 1: On the right, I see it looks like they just turned the saturation of the colors down, turned the contrast down, made it dark.
Speaker 0: Well, because that's the thing.
Speaker 0: They're not complaining about the image quality of the graphics.
Speaker 1: They were a little.
Speaker 1: One of the complaints was there's colors.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the thing.
Speaker 0: is that Diablo, if you play Diablo 2, Diablo 2 is the only one I've played.
Speaker 0: I've never played one.
Speaker 1: By the way, it's a terrible game.
Speaker 1: It was a terrible game when it came out.
Speaker 0: Click, click, click, click, click.
Speaker 0: We're done with that.
Speaker 0: The first level.
Speaker 1: Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait a minute.
Speaker 1: No, it was a great game.
Speaker 1: It was the perfect implementation of Ground Pound Down, I guess.
Speaker 0: So, the first level is a city, is a little village at night with the surrounding woodsy grassland, you know, towns and caves that are all dark and evil.
Speaker 0: And there's evil people all about.
Speaker 0: Level 2, I think, was a dark, evil-like rainforest where it rained.
Speaker 0: I don't remember exactly.
Speaker 0: Then, you know, the final level was hell where it was dark and fiery.
Speaker 0: And every level was, you know, nighttime, dark, raining, hell, fire, brimstone, everything evil and dark.
Speaker 0: And the game had that kind of mood.
Speaker 0: And if you add colors to it, they're not complaining it looks too good.
Speaker 1: They're complaining.
Speaker 0: it doesn't look, it doesn't have the same dark and evil all the time feeling that the old Diablo had.
Speaker 1: See, at the same time, that feeling came mostly for the fact, you know, just design limitations that they had.
Speaker 1: Not so much as...
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but they, you know, that's...
Speaker 1: And two, I mean, a lot of the complaints, like, people were, like, the things people were complaining about basically did boil down to.
Speaker 1: it looks too good.
Speaker 1: A lot of people were complaining that it was anti-aliased and that it looked smooth and that the animations were, like, smooth and didn't chop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, that's, well, that is, you know, someone saying it's too good.
Speaker 0: But it seems like the majority of the people are saying, "Why are there bright colors?
Speaker 0: Diablo should be dark and evil and look like hell and bad things all the
Speaker 0: time.".
Speaker 1: Now, the game designer and a lot of smarter people came back and said, "One, these are mostly still screenshots.
Speaker 1: And if you played the game the way it looks in these fan-made screenshots, it would basically be unplayable.
Speaker 1: And the game, the way they designed it is that way because that way you can actually play it.
Speaker 1: And it's a fun game and it might be slightly
Speaker 1: more.".
Speaker 0: Wait, wait, how is it a fun game?
Speaker 0: It's still going to be... Well, that's what they're claiming.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: It's not going to be a fun game.
Speaker 0: A lot of people will think it's a fun game.
Speaker 0: They like, wow, they like Diablo.
Speaker 0: It's the same thing.
Speaker 0: It's like they made Diablo 3.
Speaker 0: I'm going to guarantee you this right now.
Speaker 0: It's basically going to be, right, a set of, you know, wow instances that you could play single player or multiplayer without a wow account.
Speaker 0: And it's going to be the most incredibly polished wow instances to ever exist.
Speaker 0: And that's all it's going to be.
Speaker 0: So if you like doing a wow raid or whatever, Diablo 3 is going to be the most polished wow raids in the universe.
Speaker 0: That's all it's going to be.
Speaker 0: It's going to be click, click, click on the bad guys and eventually you win.
Speaker 1: You know, I can't think if there's any other video game or board game or role playing game news.
Speaker 1: I mean, nothing else really happened except for the fact that PAX is coming to the East Coast in 2010.
Speaker 1: Oh my fuck.
Speaker 0: I mean, this is a news we kind of knew already, sort of, because they said it at MIT and they said it at some other places.
Speaker 0: But I got to talk about this.
Speaker 0: Oh my fuck.
Speaker 0: They're dropping.
Speaker 0: But now they're like, OK, official announcement.
Speaker 0: Fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They haven't said where yet.
Speaker 1: However, I have an educated one.
Speaker 1: It's been they're having it run by Reed Exhibitions, the people who did, you know, the New York Comic Con, the New York Anime Festival.
Speaker 0: And oh, comics, anime, gaming.
Speaker 0: They got a trifecta.
Speaker 1: The reason behind that is pretty much they don't have the time, the resources, the energy or any of that to deal with doing another PAX on the East Coast.
Speaker 0: Kevin, could you run two cons of that size a year on your own news?
Speaker 0: People have a hard enough time running Otacon once a year.
Speaker 0: Maybe a little hard enough time running KatsuCon once a year.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: If I didn't have a day job, I think I could.
Speaker 0: If I didn't have a day job, which is exactly why Reed Exhibitions is a good help, because their day job is run the conventions.
Speaker 0: Gabe and Tyco still have to make a comic every day, make merch, do the child's play, do the PAX one, do everything else they do.
Speaker 0: So they don't really have time to do two conventions.
Speaker 1: Because we found out about this for real at Kineticon, so of course at every panel we did, we're like, "By the way, PAX East
Speaker 1: Coast.".
Speaker 0: Thanks to my iPhone, I found out about it.
Speaker 1: And everyone kept asking us, "So where's it going to
Speaker 1: be?".
Speaker 1: So in case anyone hasn't figured this out or is smart enough to look around and do some research, or if you're just not familiar with the East Coast, there are really only three, at most four places it could conceivably be.
Speaker 0: Well that's assuming Northeast.
Speaker 0: If you went...
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: I'm assuming all.
Speaker 1: Because Northeast, or at least Middle North, like the middle of the East Coast, are the only viable places.
Speaker 1: If it's further south, most people aren't going to bother.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, you can go to North Carolina area.
Speaker 0: That's about as south as you can go.
Speaker 0: If you go more south than that, you pretty much have to go down to Atlanta or Orlando to get a convention center.
Speaker 1: Because most of these people coming to those counties, even in the south, are coming from the north anyway.
Speaker 1: But here's the deal.
Speaker 1: In my professional opinion, it can only be in either D.C.
Speaker 1: and their convention center, Baltimore at the BCC...
Speaker 0: Which is the place where Otakont is.
Speaker 1: It could conceivably be in Hartford, Connecticut, which wouldn't be the worst place.
Speaker 0: That's not big enough.
Speaker 1: No, it isn't.
Speaker 0: Not even close.
Speaker 1: That's why that's like the fourth string.
Speaker 0: It could be in Boston before it was in Hartford.
Speaker 1: No, they'd probably go for Hartford before Boston.
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about based on how far people are willing to travel.
Speaker 1: Because remember...
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm talking about the space.
Speaker 1: No, I'm talking about all the factors.
Speaker 1: Because there are other factors.
Speaker 1: I mean, how many people do they actually expect to attend?
Speaker 0: I think there's going to be 30,000 plus people.
Speaker 1: Scott, you're not letting me finish.
Speaker 1: I do too.
Speaker 1: I don't think they're going to expect that many people.
Speaker 0: I think they know how many people are going to come.
Speaker 1: No, I do not think that they expect that the East Coast Packs would, in its inaugural year, have more people than the West Coast Packs.
Speaker 0: I think that they must expect that the East Coast Packs will have more than the West Coast Packs.
Speaker 1: Now, why would they?
Speaker 1: I don't think that they know anything about East Coast inventions.
Speaker 0: Because they have Reed Exhibitions doing, helping them out.
Speaker 1: But they just announced... They probably said, "Reed, do our
Speaker 1: convention.".
Speaker 1: Reed said,
Speaker 1: "Okay.".
Speaker 1: And Reed's doing the... They don't care.
Speaker 1: They don't know.
Speaker 0: No, they seem to say that they had a lot of say in what's going on and Reed is just doing the logistics for them.
Speaker 1: Yes, but at the same time, they wouldn't know.
Speaker 1: And Reed doesn't even really know.
Speaker 1: Because Reed, they're probably going to want it to be in the Javits, which is probably the worst possible place it could be.
Speaker 0: That's a really bad idea to put in the Javits.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess it has enough floor space for the exhibition hall.
Speaker 1: No, there's no hotels for people to stay in.
Speaker 1: There's no easy way to get to the Javits.
Speaker 1: It would be a shitty con.
Speaker 0: It would be a very shitty con.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, that's probably one of the few places it could be.
Speaker 1: And there's a decent chance that's where it might end up.
Speaker 0: Just because Reed Exhibitions is in love with that building.
Speaker 1: But seriously, it can only really be in
Speaker 1: D.C.,
Speaker 1: Baltimore, or New York City.
Speaker 1: And honestly, if I were them, I would put it in the Baltimore Convention Center.
Speaker 0: I also would.
Speaker 0: Because Otacon takes up that whole building and they have almost 30,000 people.
Speaker 1: Plus, by 2010, the giant expansion to the BCC will be done, which is going to allow Otacon to expand to 30,000+ easily.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think PAX could definitely use that entire building.
Speaker 0: If you look, instead of the dealer's room, they would have the exhibition room that could fit in there.
Speaker 0: Plus, plenty of room for everything else.
Speaker 1: Forget all the logistics and everything.
Speaker 1: The D.C.
Speaker 1: Convention Center is big enough.
Speaker 1: But it's also, for the kinds of cons that these are, a really bad layout.
Speaker 1: The Javits is almost as bad, but the D.C.
Speaker 1: Convention Center just wouldn't cut it.
Speaker 0: Because the Javits is really only designed for the one big room kind of con.
Speaker 0: If you have the auto show, it's a big room with big displays.
Speaker 1: Well, there's more to it than that.
Speaker 1: I mean, anime and gaming cons have a lot of hotel to convention back and forth traffic.
Speaker 1: They have a lot more internal foot traffic.
Speaker 1: They have a lot of bursts of traffic.
Speaker 1: They have a lot of people hanging out in hallways.
Speaker 1: It's a totally different thing from every other kind of convention in the world.
Speaker 1: And the BCC is one of the few convention centers that really, really deals with it well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just because it has so many, you know, it's wide, it's got hallways, it's got lots of separate rooms.
Speaker 1: It's got multiple paths to get to most places.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's got, you know, hotels are across the street directly.
Speaker 1: Also, the BCC's escalators hold out better than any con center I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can walk to a place to eat.
Speaker 1: Well, that's starting to change.
Speaker 0: It is, but actually I was reading that some new places opened up.
Speaker 0: There's apparently a Chipotle next to the Hard Rock.
Speaker 1: Ah, but there's no Fuddruckers anymore.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: May it rest, may it burn in hell.
Speaker 0: I'm going to eat at that Chipotle at least once.
Speaker 1: But yeah, PEX, 2010, East Coast.
Speaker 1: We work with Reed Exhibitions a bit because, you know, New York Comic Con, New York Anime Festival.
Speaker 1: So, we'll see if we can get some sort of scoop.
Speaker 0: Oh, we're going to be scooping it up, there's no doubt.
Speaker 1: I'm also going to try to talk to everyone involved and at least make my opinion known because, seriously, I think Baltimore is the best choice.
Speaker 1: And I think that the Javits would really fundamentally hurt PAX East Coast.
Speaker 0: I think if they had it in the Javits, it would bomb and then they might not do it again.
Speaker 1: But here's my prediction.
Speaker 1: If it were in the Baltimore Convention Center in, say, May, that's probably the best time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely you want to do it April/May because that way it won't conflict with pretty much anything.
Speaker 0: Don't put it in August with the other cons.
Speaker 0: That's just making a mess of everything conflicting.
Speaker 0: Go May when there's no other conventions going down.
Speaker 0: Sure, the kids are still in school a little bit, but it's on the East Coast so they don't have to go very far.
Speaker 1: I would wager it would get 28,000 people.
Speaker 1: That is like the number I would put out as my number.
Speaker 0: I'd say it could be as high as 35.
Speaker 1: It could be, but I'm guessing 28,000.
Speaker 1: That is my absolute guess.
Speaker 1: It could be higher.
Speaker 0: I'm guessing actually 30+ definitely.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't think you understand how many people on the East Coast are like, they hunger for the petty arcade action and they haven't gotten any.
Speaker 1: I know, I know, but I also know there are people who will wait a year.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 1: Plus remember, the East Coast was burned by the first New York Comic Con in a big way.
Speaker 0: But that was a Comic Con.
Speaker 0: This is gaming, video gaming on the East Coast.
Speaker 0: There hasn't been a gaming convention over here ever and there are lots and lots of video gamers and they hunger, seriously.
Speaker 0: So this is like a brand new thing.
Speaker 0: They're going to be like, "Holy
Speaker 0: shit!"
Speaker 0: and poop their pants and go.
Speaker 1: Run, coward, run, run, run.
Speaker 1: The other thing is that there is someone out here that they could tap in a big way if they're down in DC or Baltimore.
Speaker 1: Me?
Speaker 1: Other than us.
Speaker 1: It's the dude who supplies the classic arcade cabinets.
Speaker 1: To Katsucon.
Speaker 1: Every year, we hang out in the video game room in Katsucon, we're staffed there, we do shows, it's a big deal.
Speaker 1: They have an arcade and the arcade has like, root beer tapper and zookeeper.
Speaker 0: That video-topia guy, Pax, could actually afford to probably get him to bring every game he has to Pax.
Speaker 0: The thing is, he would need to hire guys to temporarily repair all the machines.
Speaker 1: Pax could cover that.
Speaker 0: They could.
Speaker 1: That guy's not that expensive.
Speaker 0: He's not, but it would be crazy awesome.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we have to talk.
Speaker 0: If he could set up all his machines at once.
Speaker 1: Yeah, listen.
Speaker 1: So, all of you out there, if you happen to know Monsieurs Gabe and Tycho, not to say, "Listen to us, listen to us,".
Speaker 1: but we kind of know all the business about running an East Coast convention.
Speaker 1: We could probably help in a big way.
Speaker 1: Anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: Again, all you new listeners.
Speaker 1: Things of the day is a little bit we do.
Speaker 1: You know it's a late show.
Speaker 1: Late shows have to have bits.
Speaker 1: We basically just talk about the funniest, coolest, weirdest, or whatever thing we've seen in the last day or so.
Speaker 1: that might be at least somewhat related to the topic of the night.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, should I go first?
Speaker 1: I think you should.
Speaker 0: This isn't really gaming related, but that doesn't ... Well, unless you're talking about the game of life or the game of don't go to jail or I guess get out of jail free.
Speaker 1: I'm real good at that first game.
Speaker 0: So, this is a video of this.
Speaker 0: Pretty much he's like a defense lawyer, professor.
Speaker 0: I'm not really sure, but he's definitely a defense lawyer type person.
Speaker 0: And he basically gives this ... He talks really fast and I really ... I don't think I like his personality.
Speaker 0: At least the personality, the idea I get of his personality.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 1: Do you get the impression that he's a little sleazy?
Speaker 0: I get the impression that he's sort of a fast talking sort of kind of guy.
Speaker 1: He's a lawyer.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No offense to all our lawyer friends.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: He definitely seems like he has ... I agree with everything he's saying.
Speaker 0: It's just his personality is a little bit grating.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the points he's making are great, which is he pretty much says, "Don't talk to the police under any circumstances, whether you're innocent, whether you're guilty, no matter what
Speaker 0: happens.".
Speaker 1: Well, there's one exception though that I do want to bring up, just in case.
Speaker 1: If you're witnessing a crime, you probably want to tell the police what you saw, as long as you're not a suspect.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but he's pretty much saying, "Use the Fifth Amendment whenever
Speaker 0: possible.".
Speaker 0: If you have Fifth Amendment rights, exercise them to the fullest extent, no matter the circumstances.
Speaker 0: Don't say anything unless you have to say something.
Speaker 0: Get a lawyer before you open your mouth about anything, and then talk only to the lawyer.
Speaker 0: And then he goes through a whole bunch of points of exactly why.
Speaker 0: The most interesting point he brought up, actually, that really freaked me out, was we know that a lot of the people on death row, right, were pretty much they didn't do it.
Speaker 0: And then they were later proven to be not guilty by DNA evidence, right?
Speaker 0: 25% of those people who were found out later, not just death row, but 25% of the people who were exonerated after the fact because of DNA evidence, were people who confessed because they talked.
Speaker 0: They basically didn't use the Fifth Amendment.
Speaker 0: If they had used the Fifth Amendment, they wouldn't have been in jail, and they wouldn't have had to be exonerated by DNA evidence later.
Speaker 0: And they could have avoided jail, and their lives could have been great, but they didn't use the Fifth Amendment, so they got fucked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically it's just that you kind of have to protect your own rights, and because you can't be sure of a police officer in a situation, and because of the way the system is, you really, you've got to hold on to your right.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, the case in point, the good example of if a police officer wants to search your car, and you say no, you don't consent, and he doesn't have probable cause, but he decides to search it anyway, or demands that you open the trunk, or he's going to shoot it open, or whatever.
Speaker 1: You've got to just keep saying, "I'm not going to resist because blah, blah, blah, but I still do not consent to this
Speaker 1: search.".
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the best part of the video, right, is actually, you know, he talks really, I think maybe he's talking really fast, not just because he's a fast talker, but because he doesn't have a lot of time, and he's trying to give this other guy enough time to talk.
Speaker 0: And the other guy is actually a policeman, basically, but he's also, he said they don't like the word interrogation, they use the word interview, but he's interrogated.
Speaker 0: He says thousands of people, at least hundreds, lots of people, right, or interviewed hundreds or thousands of people over his years, you know, 20 plus years as a police officer.
Speaker 0: And he pretty much comes up, and you expect him to be like, you know, disagreeing with the guy who just talked, saying, "Don't talk to the police.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the police to argue with
Speaker 0: me.".
Speaker 0: And the guy, the cop comes up, and he says, "Everything that the defense lawyer said is absolutely correct.
Speaker 0: Don't say a thing.
Speaker 0: Here is how we turn what you say against
Speaker 0: you.".
Speaker 0: Because remember, anything you say may be used against you in a court of law.
Speaker 0: There is no way anything you say can help you.
Speaker 0: It can only hurt you.
Speaker 0: So don't say anything.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: You want a good example?
Speaker 1: Remember that movie, My Cousin Vinny?
Speaker 1: Good movie?
Speaker 1: Remember how?
Speaker 1: one of the reasons they convict him is they sit him down, the police officers, and he doesn't know that they're trying to get him for murder.
Speaker 1: He thinks that they sped or something.
Speaker 1: He has no idea why he's in the police office.
Speaker 1: And then the cop's like, "You killed the
Speaker 1: clerk.".
Speaker 1: And he's like, "I killed the
Speaker 1: clerk?".
Speaker 1: And then in the courtroom, they read his confession.
Speaker 1: It's like, "I said again, you killed the
Speaker 1: clerk."
Speaker 1: To which he responded, "I killed the
Speaker 1: clerk.".
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: So you should watch these two videos, and I don't know if anyone who's smart enough to be a Geek Nights listener will have too many run-ins with the police, other than maybe some traffic tickets.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, traffic tickets.
Speaker 1: We should do a show on how to get out of a traffic ticket, because I've gotten out of about 60% of the ones I've been pulled over for.
Speaker 0: The first thing this cop says when he gets up, he says, "People ask me, 'How do I get out of a speeding
Speaker 0: ticket?'".
Speaker 0: He says, "Don't
Speaker 0: speed.".
Speaker 0: So yeah, watch these two videos, and in your life, if it ever becomes necessary, hopefully it won't, but if it does, keep your mouth shut and get a lawyer.
Speaker 1: Here's the difference.
Speaker 1: Unless you did it.
Speaker 0: Well, no.
Speaker 0: He says, "Whether you did it or didn't do it, keep your mouth
Speaker 0: shut.".
Speaker 0: Because look, if you talk to the police, right?
Speaker 0: This is why this video is so great.
Speaker 0: He says, "Look, let's say you did it, right?
Speaker 0: Of course you want to plead guilty to get a lesser sentence, because you're not going to get out of it without Johnnie Cochran, right?
Speaker 0: If there's a mountain of
Speaker 0: evidence.".
Speaker 1: But they won't give you the real plea bargain unless you actually talk to a lawyer who does all the business.
Speaker 0: Right, right.
Speaker 0: If you just talk before your lawyer gets there, they're just going to run you through.
Speaker 0: If you just keep your mouth shut until your lawyer gets there, then you're going to get to bargain and get your better deal.
Speaker 1: That is game theory for the South.
Speaker 1: But for society, if you did it, confess, asshole.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just not right away.
Speaker 0: Wait until the lawyer gets there.
Speaker 1: Do I know how to avoid having run-ins with the police?
Speaker 0: Don't commit any crimes?
Speaker 0: Of course, the thing is...
Speaker 1: Or don't film police officers doing their duty.
Speaker 1: They hate that.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is, right, Rim, you know how we always talk about how basically there are so many laws that pretty much everything is illegal, and if a cop looks at you long enough or drives behind you long enough, they can always find a reason to pull you over no matter what.
Speaker 1: I mean, if I, I don't know, murdered a bunch of... Well, I guess if I murdered a bunch of people, I'm crazy, so I'm not going to confess anyway.
Speaker 1: I don't really have a good example.
Speaker 0: These guys actually talk about how there are so many laws that we can't count them.
Speaker 0: We don't know how many laws there are.
Speaker 0: And if you talk, they will go over everything you said, and they will find something illegal every time.
Speaker 0: Like, he was talking about people who they got because they had, where they were in possession of lobsters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay, because pretty much everything is, they can always find something illegal no matter what.
Speaker 0: So don't say anything, and you won't incriminate yourself for anything because they don't decide, you know, it's not like you go in and they're like, "We're only looking for robbery if you say you did
Speaker 0: something.".
Speaker 0: No, they're looking for anything.
Speaker 0: If you broke any law, they got you.
Speaker 1: So, I have a vidya game-related thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Tribes 2 is like the best...
Speaker 0: Is it the bees?
Speaker 1: No, not the bees.
Speaker 0: It's not the bees.
Speaker 1: Not the bees.
Speaker 0: So it's not the bees.
Speaker 1: It's not the bees.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, what is it?
Speaker 1: What is that?
Speaker 1: What is it?
Speaker 0: It's not the bees.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So Tribes 2 is pretty much the best for Team... Stateless... never mind, I'm not going to go into that again.
Speaker 1: Tribes 2 is like the best Team FPS ever made.
Speaker 0: It is the best to ever exist.
Speaker 1: It is the best team-based multiplayer stateless capture the flag FPS.
Speaker 0: Well, it is all those things, but what non-stateless, non-team-based multiplayer FPS is better?
Speaker 0: Nothing.
Speaker 1: Well, I also said capture the flag.
Speaker 0: What capture the flag is... What capture the flag FPS is better than...
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'm saying not because it's a non-capture the flag game.
Speaker 1: I don't want to...
Speaker 0: It is all those things, but...
Speaker 1: I don't want to compare apples to oranges.
Speaker 1: That's like saying, "The Godfather is the best movie or video game ever
Speaker 1: made.".
Speaker 0: Well, there is a Godfather video game, I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Not the best video game ever made.
Speaker 0: No, but Tribes 2 is the best multiplayer FPS compared to all other varieties of multiplayer FPS.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: NS is up there, but anyway...
Speaker 0: NS is the second best multiplayer FPS.
Speaker 1: Anyway, Tribes 2 was great, and this video basically shows... You know, the game had vehicles and everything.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to talk.
Speaker 1: Just watch it.
Speaker 1: if you thought Tribes 2 was awesome, and this shows you a dude who is one of the better Shrike pilots I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: Now, the thing to remember, if you're not too familiar with Tribes 2...
Speaker 0: Go try to pilot the Shrike.
Speaker 0: It sucks.
Speaker 0: The thing just crashes all over the place.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Tribes 2 could have been made better.
Speaker 1: Halo and a lot of games have learned how to do vehicles a lot better, but Tribes 2 did it first.
Speaker 0: Well, it wasn't the first game to ever have vehicles.
Speaker 0: I mean, Half-Life 1 had vehicles.
Speaker 1: Those were not vehicles.
Speaker 1: Those were basically suicide machines.
Speaker 0: They were vehicles.
Speaker 1: However, I contend that the vehicles in Counter-Strike in particular were more fun than the vehicles in any FPS today.
Speaker 0: Jeep-a-thon 2K!
Speaker 1: That was like the best map ever.
Speaker 0: She gets some of that going on, but anyway...
Speaker 1: Nothing was more fun than being in a Jeep with six other guys, Paris...
Speaker 0: Three other guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, saw a number of guys driving past another Jeep with an equal number of guys all with Paris, shooting at each other, having a ride as time, and then suddenly one of the Jeeps flips over and kills everyone in it randomly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the point is that Tribes 2, as great as it was, it's an old game from 2000-2001, and the vehicles were busted because that was the best they could do in those days, and they were very hard to pilot.
Speaker 0: And here's a video of a guy piloting them like his car.
Speaker 1: Now, the other cool thing is that if you're not familiar with Tribes, keep in mind that while these guys are piloting these vehicles all up, they're just dudes around the map fighting on foot at the same time.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I thought that was pretty cool.
Speaker 1: So, we're going to go kind of short because it's late, it's Tuesday, tomorrow night we got a pack for Otacon.
Speaker 0: Yep, so check this out.
Speaker 0: I've been looking in the, you know, the DS Homebrew scene for a while, right?
Speaker 0: There's all this huge hullabaloo, especially on the other side of the Pacific Ocean about the R4 and these things, but basically... Yeah.
Speaker 1: You said hullabaloo, I don't know what the hell you were thinking.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: So, but basically the deal is, is that people know how the DS works.
Speaker 0: The DS is not a complicated piece of hardware, right?
Speaker 0: The Nintendo DS.
Speaker 0: And it didn't take hackers a very long time.
Speaker 0: I mean, this technology has been around for years.
Speaker 0: Basically what they do is they have this card that goes in, it looks like a DS cartridge, but you put a normal microSD memory card in it.
Speaker 0: And you put that in your DS and it boots on your DS.
Speaker 0: And then your DS can, you can run any software you want in your DS, not just games you buy at the store.
Speaker 0: So this includes, you know, technically people write their own software and run it on the DS.
Speaker 0: You can make your own DS games.
Speaker 0: People were doing this in GBA days too.
Speaker 0: They're making their own GBA games and putting them on, you know, flashcards.
Speaker 0: They, you can go and download, you know, NES and SNES ROMs and ROMs for other systems too.
Speaker 0: Like I guess, you know, Sega Genesis and Master System and I guess maybe Commodore 64, who knows?
Speaker 0: And you have emulators that they wrote for the DS.
Speaker 0: And then you run these ROMs in the emulator on the DS and it lets you take your NES and SNES games portable.
Speaker 0: And also what you can do is you can just put Nintendo DS or Game Boy ROMs on this, on the memory card.
Speaker 0: And then just play them on your DS without actually buying them.
Speaker 0: And so I've been curious about these things for a while, but the thing was, is that there were always trouble.
Speaker 0: You had to buy like a bunch of separate pieces.
Speaker 0: You had to flash your firmware on your DS.
Speaker 0: It was a whole bunch of trouble.
Speaker 0: I didn't want to brick my DS.
Speaker 0: You know, it was a little risky.
Speaker 0: I was waiting for sort of the perfect solution, you know, something that didn't stick out the top of the DS.
Speaker 0: Something that didn't cost a fortune.
Speaker 1: Something that didn't completely eat the battery in like 10 minutes.
Speaker 0: Well, I'll get to that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess the answer to the begged question is that now you didn't find a perfect one, not even close.
Speaker 0: Well, it's all going to tell you.
Speaker 0: So at Kineticon, I finally broke down and I bought the M3DS Reel.
Speaker 0: I bought sort of like the ultimate one.
Speaker 0: It came with a little micro SD USB reader.
Speaker 0: It came with a rumble pack.
Speaker 0: It came with a GBA expansion slot and it came with the M3DS, the actual card itself.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And the guy was talking it up.
Speaker 0: He's like, yeah, it's all just drag and drop all the stuff onto the memory card.
Speaker 0: And it works is mostly true.
Speaker 0: So I get home.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Here's what you got to know about these M3DS Reels or I guess the R4 or any of the other things.
Speaker 0: You get it.
Speaker 0: You got to have an SD memory card.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I suggest getting a big one.
Speaker 0: I ordered a four gig micro SD because DS games are like 256 megs.
Speaker 0: So if you want to have more than one on there, you're going to need a lot of space.
Speaker 1: Luckily, that sort of memory is getting cheaper and cheaper.
Speaker 1: So these.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I ordered a four gig micro SDHC from Newegg for, I think, like fourteen dollars, maybe seventeen dollars.
Speaker 0: So it's basically nothing.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So you get you put the memory card in there.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And you put it in the DS and it says, you know, well, first, if you don't put a memory card in, it says no memory card.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So you put the memory card and it says no system files found.
Speaker 0: You have to go online and get the system files and put them on the memory card.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 0: That's how it works still.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So you get these system files and you drag this folder onto your SD memory card.
Speaker 0: Now the system starts up and the system has a bunch of built in software.
Speaker 0: It has a built in NES emulator, SNES emulator and has media playing stuff or playing music and movies that are converted to the right format.
Speaker 0: It can play and and Nintendo DS and GBA games.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But it plays those natively.
Speaker 0: It doesn't emulate them or anything.
Speaker 0: It just sort of loads them into the memory of your DS and runs them as if you actually had the cartridge and PDA stuff in there, whatever.
Speaker 0: And I tried out all these things.
Speaker 0: You know, I even installed like alternative SNES emulators because really I wanted to sort of get some SNES on the go.
Speaker 0: And while they work, they don't work well.
Speaker 0: It really reminds me of sort of the DOS days, not super DOS days because there's a GUI going on and it's a little bit easier than that.
Speaker 0: But everything is sort of hackish or not very polished.
Speaker 1: The original GUI interface to Nesticle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know it's it's it is.
Speaker 0: it's a lot like the old Nesticle, like the emulators don't work perfectly.
Speaker 0: Like in Super Metroid, I had to keep adjusting like the layers of sprites and backgrounds and which ones were on top of which other ones.
Speaker 0: Because like Sam, everything would look fine, but then I'd go in a door and Sam was to be on top of the door.
Speaker 0: I'd be like, no, Sam is supposed to be in the door.
Speaker 0: So something's wrong.
Speaker 1: So that's even worse than the DOS days.
Speaker 1: I didn't really have problems like that often.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 1: So except for like like a really crazy Rob.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: StarTropics.
Speaker 1: There's no way that's working now.
Speaker 0: But basically, the limitations of the DS hardware make a lot of these homebrew apps less than polished.
Speaker 0: They're not perfect.
Speaker 0: You know, like the PDA stuff and the media playing stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean, because I have an iPod and iPhone, actually, that stuff is pretty much useless.
Speaker 0: But I could imagine if I was a high school kid and I didn't have an iPhone or an iPod or anything, that wouldn't be too bad.
Speaker 0: It would.
Speaker 0: you know, it would be worth my trouble and time to get that working, you know, especially especially if I had a big old SD card.
Speaker 0: But as it is, it's basically subpar.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like the Internet on the Wii with the Opera browser.
Speaker 0: It's like if you have a computer plugged into your TV, why would you ever use the Wii Opera browser?
Speaker 0: But if the Wii is the only thing plugged into your TV and you don't have a computer plugged into your TV, which I imagine is actually the case for most people, even though, you know, you're geeks, you should have a computer plugged into your TV at this point.
Speaker 0: The Wii Opera browser becomes sort of useful if you want to watch, look at a web thing, you know, or I guess you can watch YouTube on it, right?
Speaker 0: Does that work now or does it not?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I haven't even checked.
Speaker 0: I haven't used it in forever.
Speaker 0: But, you know, that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: It does, you know, if you want to do that, then that's a good way to go.
Speaker 0: So it has this PDA and media playing functionality.
Speaker 0: It's really only good if that's the only poor PDA media playing functionality that you have.
Speaker 0: that's portable.
Speaker 0: If you have an iPod, it's useless.
Speaker 0: So the emulating is sort of hackish.
Speaker 0: I already said that.
Speaker 0: Another problem with it is that the battery life, it sort of sucks.
Speaker 0: I mean, DS, if you're playing off a real DS cartridge, the battery lasts for like fucking ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like I'll go days and days and days.
Speaker 1: Then suddenly, oh, my battery.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I had a fully charged DS this morning.
Speaker 0: I played a game for about half the train ride.
Speaker 0: I played it for a little while at work because no one's at work now.
Speaker 0: They all went to North Carolina.
Speaker 0: They saw the other tech guys and then I played it on the way home.
Speaker 0: And while the battery didn't die, the light was red all the way home.
Speaker 0: It was not.
Speaker 0: it was not good.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm used to having the light green throughout the entire day.
Speaker 0: So that that didn't please me very much.
Speaker 0: But it did play the game, you know, for as long as I wanted to play it.
Speaker 0: So I guess that that wasn't a problem.
Speaker 0: So really, you know, they justify this.
Speaker 0: These, you know, DS homebrew cards saying, oh, we're making homebrew apps, which I can fully support.
Speaker 0: And they say, you know, oh, we're taking games that aren't portable, making them portable.
Speaker 0: that, you know, we own them.
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh, that's not.
Speaker 0: that's justifiable in some way.
Speaker 1: Back in the day, I wanted nothing more than to be able to carry an SNES game around with me.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And this is a lot better than getting one of those guys who took an SNES and put it in a different box that's smaller.
Speaker 0: You know, that's that's unpractical.
Speaker 0: So I can sort of support that even though the software that does it is pretty shitty.
Speaker 0: The thing is, the only thing this card does well is play DS and GBA ROMs.
Speaker 0: And it does it.
Speaker 0: it does it perfectly because it's just taking the software and running it natively.
Speaker 0: Like you put a GBA ROM in there and it's as if you had the cartridge.
Speaker 0: You put a Nintendo DS ROM in there.
Speaker 0: It's as if you had the cartridge.
Speaker 0: It is absolutely perfect, except for the battery life.
Speaker 0: And it just works.
Speaker 0: And yeah.
Speaker 0: So on the one hand, I sort of because I've bought a lot of DS games in my day, a lot.
Speaker 0: So now that I don't have to buy any DS games because they're basically all free.
Speaker 1: Oh, so you're just going to start pirating everything?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm sort of torn on this situation because on the one hand, it's like, well, I've always been able to afford DS games.
Speaker 0: You know why?
Speaker 0: There's no reason for me to stop buying them now.
Speaker 0: And plus, if you buy them, you get the better battery life and the club Nintendo and the club Nintendo and many other things.
Speaker 1: And the box, which you keep an eye long ago, sort of thrown away.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There's many reasons to buy this, you know.
Speaker 0: But on the other hand, there's a lot of DS games that I sort of glanced at and never bought.
Speaker 0: Like I sort of maybe wanted them, but I didn't really want them.
Speaker 0: And DS rental.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess, you know, game fly sort of does that and some other places do it, but not really so much.
Speaker 0: I guess you can rent it from Blockbuster, but not really.
Speaker 0: So there's some DS games where I kind of thought about buying them and but didn't.
Speaker 0: And there's some DS games where I did buy them and I sort of regret it a little bit.
Speaker 0: You know, like dodgeball.
Speaker 0: I mean, we talked about dodgeball.
Speaker 0: We did a whole show about it, but we haven't really played it since.
Speaker 0: It hasn't been getting much play.
Speaker 0: I sort of feel like maybe.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is, the single player game, like any dodgeball, there's no single player.
Speaker 1: And while I want to play a multiplayer, there aren't that many people to play with.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: So it's sort of like I probably shouldn't have bought that.
Speaker 0: It was, you know, I didn't have to, you know, and there's some other games I want to try out before I buy.
Speaker 0: And this sort of fills that purpose.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like there's the good and the other thing.
Speaker 0: Here's the real thing about this.
Speaker 0: I'm going to get to in a minute.
Speaker 0: Like first I went is a game that's out now called Etrian Odyssey two.
Speaker 0: There was an Etrian Odyssey one for DS that I sort of missed.
Speaker 0: I sort of didn't find out about it until the sequel came out.
Speaker 0: And this is sort of a, this game is a double edged sword.
Speaker 0: On the one hand, it's this awesome game where you have this giant labyrinth, but you have to draw the map on the touch screen.
Speaker 0: That's fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: So awesome, right?
Speaker 0: Problem.
Speaker 0: It's a typical JRPG level up kind of game at the same time.
Speaker 0: Not awesome.
Speaker 1: Now we're not going to do a full review of that.
Speaker 1: I got to play it first.
Speaker 0: But Alex actually bought the game and he was playing it and he sort of said basically what I thought.
Speaker 0: Which is the maze thing is pretty cool, but there is this dungeon crawling bit.
Speaker 0: But the dungeon, the monsters are actually really hard.
Speaker 0: So when I got this little homebrew card for the DS, I went and I got this game.
Speaker 0: And actually I'm kind of digging it even though it's got this level up bit because the maze bit sort of outshines it.
Speaker 1: I really, I mean the thing I love is the idea that the bosses are not, the bosses aren't like normal bosses.
Speaker 1: I don't want to get into it, but I think it's really cool.
Speaker 0: The bosses are just really annoying.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: But yeah.
Speaker 1: The way Alex described them, I thought they were awesome.
Speaker 0: Well, you'll see.
Speaker 0: But basically, you know, I sort of was able to learn that I kind of like this game.
Speaker 0: And the reason that I can tolerate this game is because the dungeon crawly bit is less of, there are random encounters.
Speaker 0: But it's more a resource management thing and less a grind thing.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like you don't have so much gold.
Speaker 0: You never have enough gold ever.
Speaker 0: You never have enough health ever.
Speaker 0: You never have enough anything.
Speaker 0: So you're basically, you're not trying to beat the monsters to level up.
Speaker 0: You're just trying to survive and see as much of the maze as you can.
Speaker 0: And the monsters are draining your resources.
Speaker 0: And the fights are actually ways to sort of manage.
Speaker 0: You know, you're not trying to beat the monsters effectively, even though it's not a bad way to go.
Speaker 0: You're trying to get through and get through the maze and accomplish the quests and things and discover as much labyrinth as you can without running out of resources.
Speaker 0: And I was able to learn all this, that I kind of like this game from pirating it, basically.
Speaker 0: The other thing about this that I think is far more justifiable than, you know, straight up piracy of DS games, right?
Speaker 0: Is if you live in the US, you can just go online and download Japanese DS roms and vice versa.
Speaker 1: So have you touched any witches?
Speaker 0: So of course, I go online.
Speaker 1: How do you get the witch touching game?
Speaker 0: I'm like, I got to get me a Japanese DS game.
Speaker 0: A witch to touch.
Speaker 0: And of course, the first one that I sort of come across, I don't know why, but of course, obviously, if I'm going to get a Japanese DS game.
Speaker 1: It's going to be a witch touching game.
Speaker 0: It's going to be Doki Doki Maho Shinpan 2 Witch Touching.
Speaker 1: So did you touch any witches?
Speaker 0: You know, Doki Doki Maho Shinpan, playing it was a lot like playing sort of a Tokimeki without the school sim.
Speaker 0: I walk around, characters talk to me.
Speaker 0: There's a whole lot of Japanese text I can't read.
Speaker 1: You did not answer my question.
Speaker 0: I'm not done.
Speaker 1: Did you touch any witches?
Speaker 0: I'll let you know.
Speaker 0: This is the only thing you all want to know.
Speaker 0: Well, you're not going to find out unless you let me tell the whole story.
Speaker 0: So I'm playing and you talk to people and there's a whole lot of Japanese text and you watch characters reactions on the screen.
Speaker 0: And, you know, it's all right.
Speaker 0: You're going through.
Speaker 0: You don't know what's going on because I don't speak Japanese.
Speaker 0: And there's a lot of kanji in there anyway.
Speaker 0: I can't even not that I can read the hiragana.
Speaker 0: And occasionally they'll give you a choice of three things to say.
Speaker 0: And I'll just pick one randomly.
Speaker 0: that looks cool.
Speaker 0: And the characters will react.
Speaker 0: And I keep going around and it's like I go to school.
Speaker 0: I touch things, you know, like I look behind things.
Speaker 0: Well, I look behind the blackboard.
Speaker 0: I find a clue.
Speaker 0: It's an investigation game actually.
Speaker 0: You're going around trying to get clues similar to Phoenix, right?
Speaker 0: But not so similar.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, I never, I played the game for like a good 30 minutes.
Speaker 0: Didn't touch a single witch.
Speaker 0: There was not a single opportunity for witch touching.
Speaker 0: So even though this is the witch touching game, you got to play a lot.
Speaker 0: I guess maybe knowing Japanese, I might have been able to touch witches sooner.
Speaker 0: But I did not arrive at a single witch touching situation.
Speaker 0: It was all investigation.
Speaker 1: That's a little sad, but at the same time it's oddly comforting.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it's sort of like a porno.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, you get this plot the whole time and there's a sex scene at the end.
Speaker 1: But all you want to do is touch a witch.
Speaker 0: I didn't want to actually play this game.
Speaker 0: I can't understand it or anything.
Speaker 0: I'm getting nothing out of playing it.
Speaker 0: The only reason I got the game was to basically see what the witch touching was all about.
Speaker 0: So I could comment on it.
Speaker 0: But I have no idea what it's like to touch a witch.
Speaker 1: I can tell you exactly what it's like.
Speaker 1: You touch a witch.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It is witch touching.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So, yeah.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know what the final verdict is.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm sort of torn about the justifiability of just pirating DS and GBA games.
Speaker 0: I mean, for some of the games I feel it's okay because it's hard to get the games.
Speaker 0: Maybe they're out of print.
Speaker 0: Maybe they're old GBA games that aren't around anymore.
Speaker 0: You know, it's a little bit more justifiable.
Speaker 0: Just getting Etrian Odyssey 2, beating it and not playing it.
Speaker 0: Feel a little bad.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll go buy it.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking because I really like it.
Speaker 0: And I sort of, I'm thinking about starting over in the beginning anyway because I sort of fucked up.
Speaker 0: And I didn't know what I was doing early on and I died a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no manual.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no manual.
Speaker 0: It kind of sucks.
Speaker 0: So, you know, if you have a DS and you're like a high school kid, you should probably totally get one of these things, whichever one you can get your hands on.
Speaker 0: If you have money, man, you have an iPod, you don't really need one of these things, but you could get it to sort of test the waters of DS and GBA games you're thinking about getting, maybe.
Speaker 0: You know, just sort of test them out.
Speaker 0: If you want to save a lot of money because you're poor, you should probably get one of these and you could have mad fun on your DS.
Speaker 0: I mean, sure, sort of hard to justify the piracy, but whatever, you're poor.
Speaker 1: The real point is there's very little use for these things other than piracy, so don't kid yourself.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: It's a pirating machine.
Speaker 0: The only things it does well are play DS and GBA games sort of natively, ROMs of DS and GBA games natively.
Speaker 0: It does a lot of other things.
Speaker 0: It doesn't do them well.
Speaker 0: It does them half acid and hackily, which a high schooler could tolerate.
Speaker 0: Maybe someone without a lot of money could tolerate, someone with an iPod could tolerate.
Speaker 0: I can't tolerate it.
Speaker 0: I pretty much, you know, I played with it, used every feature on it.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty much only ever going to use it for DS and GBA games.
Speaker 0: And actually what I did is I went and I downloaded a bunch of old GBA games that are not easily available and I've been trying to play those, you know, games that I would never pay money for and just want to see, like play them for 30 seconds.
Speaker 0: Like I played Mario Pinball for 30 seconds.
Speaker 1: That's about all that was worth.
Speaker 0: I played Pokémon Pinball for 30 seconds.
Speaker 1: I'll bet that was worth the same 30 seconds.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I played Yu-Gi-Oh, one of the Yu-Gi-Oh games.
Speaker 0: Bad.
Speaker 0: You know, that sort of thing, just to see what the deal is.
Speaker 0: And I think it's, you know, it was worth buying the price I paid for it.
Speaker 0: I think I paid 80 bucks.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Maybe I got ripped off.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really matter.
Speaker 0: I could afford it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I'm glad I didn't buy it at the con.
Speaker 1: I'll hold out.
Speaker 1: I'm going to hold out until the technology gets better, until I can actually use it.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the thing is that this has been the same technology for a couple of years now.
Speaker 0: It's not really going anywhere.
Speaker 0: It's sort of leveled out.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll just install Nesticle or, well, I guess modern emulators.
Speaker 0: Well, what you can do is you can go get...
Speaker 1: On my laptop.
Speaker 1: And I'll just play ROMs on my laptop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can just totally get a GBA or DS emulator for your computer and plug in a controller and go at it if you don't want to.
Speaker 0: The only reason to do this is for the...
Speaker 1: Is to touch witches.
Speaker 0: Is for the DS-ness and the touch screen-iness.
Speaker 1: And the touching of witches.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I think we're done.
Speaker 1: Tomorrow night, coverage of Kinetic Con.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I'm going to try the Wii homebrew soon and I'll give you a report on that after I play with it.
Speaker 1: You mean a witch.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's any witch touching on the Wii.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rem and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Crapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights.
Speaker 1: And Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com.
Speaker 0: Or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution, non-commercial, share-alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it, as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.