Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, July 2nd.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, after talking a little bit about Otakon and Satoshi-Kon, we talk about Princess Tutu.
Speaker 1: Let's do this!
Speaker 0: The beauty of doing Geek Nights Wednesdays every other week instead of every week crammed in with everything else is that I will generate, no matter what, something to talk about before the next show.
Speaker 0: every time we do a show that is related to anime.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean when we're doing it every week it's hard to watch anime every week or read it kind of.
Speaker 0: The problem was twofold.
Speaker 0: One, we were busy with other stuff, so we didn't watch a lot of anime, so it wasn't like every week.
Speaker 0: we'd say, "Oh, I'm watching this show," and blah.
Speaker 0: We really didn't watch anything and we had to talk about something else.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, we just talked about something else last week.
Speaker 0: And while most of the time my life is amusing on a daily basis, it is not always that I will, in the course of every single week, have an anime, manga, or comic-related anecdote.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and video game-related anecdotes happen pretty often, or you know, at least gaming in general, because you know, geeks are playing games all the time and we're using technology 90% of every waking moment of our lives.
Speaker 0: Even though, even though it's a technology thing to say, I've realized that a good half of my gaming happenings are not actually happenings.
Speaker 0: They're just sudden nostalgia for past gaming happenings.
Speaker 1: That's the same thing.
Speaker 0: More often, I will have more conversations about how great Tribes 2 was than I will play any current FPS.
Speaker 1: Oh, we're bringing back Tribes 2, but it's Wednesday, so.
Speaker 0: Yes, good God, didn't I talk about Tribes 2 for a while yesterday?
Speaker 0: Alright, so.
Speaker 1: Alright, so the other thing is that I'm really tired because I got home way later than Rim last night.
Speaker 0: Again, why?
Speaker 0: Because we went to a gaming night that was awesome last night.
Speaker 1: It's pretty awesome, even though I didn't finish a single game.
Speaker 1: I played two half games.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah, the other reason that it's good to do the anime nights every other week is because, like, in a span of a week, I would read a bunch of comics and Rim would watch a bunch of anime, but not too often would we both watch or read the same thing.
Speaker 0: So we get to here before the show, and I'll be like, "Alright, I watch Kazen no Yojimbo.
Speaker 0: Let's review
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: And Scott's like, "I didn't watch
Speaker 0: shit.".
Speaker 0: I'm like,
Speaker 0: "Bye.".
Speaker 0: He's like, "Well, I read these five comics.
Speaker 0: Did you read any of
Speaker 0: them?".
Speaker 0: I'm like, "I have
Speaker 0: them.".
Speaker 0: "One of them is in my
Speaker 0: bag.".
Speaker 1: With two weeks between the shows, now there's actually a good chance that there'll be one thing that we have both watched or read.
Speaker 0: However, I will warn you all, here's what happened.
Speaker 0: Instead of, "I didn't watch any of that," "Well, I didn't read any of that," I watched all of Princess Tutu, Scott watched one DVD.
Speaker 0: Scott read all of Jonah Hex.
Speaker 1: Well, I read all of Jonah Hex a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Yes, I read one volume.
Speaker 1: Are we gonna do both?
Speaker 1: Is that what you're saying?
Speaker 0: No, I'm just pointing out that basically the slider moved a little bit toward the middle.
Speaker 1: That's alright.
Speaker 1: It moved close enough towards the middle to get a show out.
Speaker 1: That's all we need.
Speaker 0: But anyway, because we're doing, you know, we didn't get to talk about this right after it happened, but we got to meet my, I think, my favorite director ever.
Speaker 0: Nah.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Miyazaki's right up there.
Speaker 0: They might be equal in my mind.
Speaker 0: I think Miyazaki is probably more important and possibly better, but... Tezuka directed.
Speaker 0: Yes, yes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, fine.
Speaker 0: So there's a holy triad of Miyazaki, Tezuka, and Satoshi Kama.
Speaker 1: What about Oshii?
Speaker 0: Oshii is really important, but he's the prince.
Speaker 1: What about, um...
Speaker 0: Stop naming people.
Speaker 0: We got to meet Satoshi Kan, and the one thing I can say about Satoshi Kan as opposed to many other directors is that the man has never made a mistake, as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: Mistake?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: He said his mangas are pretty bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, but I haven't read them.
Speaker 1: I haven't read them either, but he said that they were unsuccessful, and people always ask him, you know, about his manga, like, "Oh, you want to know about your
Speaker 1: manga?".
Speaker 1: and he's like, "Why?
Speaker 1: They sucked and no one bought them, and now you want to know about them because my anime is
Speaker 1: good?".
Speaker 1: And they're like, "Are you going to go back to
Speaker 1: manga?".
Speaker 1: He's like, "No, my anime is rocking the house, and my manga sucked.
Speaker 1: Why would I go back to what I sucked
Speaker 1: at?".
Speaker 0: But basically, we went to see at Lincoln Center.
Speaker 0: Satoshi Kan got a retrospective at Lincoln Center in New York City, so basically...
Speaker 1: It was in Lincoln Center, which is actually many buildings, but it wasn't in, you know, like, the opera house, the ballet house.
Speaker 0: Why would it be in the opera house or the ballet house?
Speaker 1: Because if you're mad awesome, then you can watch a movie in there.
Speaker 1: It's just, you know, really, uh, big.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway... It was in the school next door.
Speaker 0: Satoshi Kan, at the Walter Reed Theater at Lincoln Center, was given a retrospective, and basically over the course of several days, they showed pretty much all of his animated works, including a large chunk of Paranoid Agent.
Speaker 0: And the one night we went, they were showing Paprika, which, while I was super tired, and I was really only going to see Satoshi Kan, watching Paprika on the big screen again was suddenly worth it.
Speaker 0: the moment it started, because I freaking loved that movie.
Speaker 1: Like, up until, like, we actually got there, I was sort of like, "Uh..." because I committed to this way in advance, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, because Emily was like, "Hey, Satoshi Kan," and we were both like, "We're gonna be there, hot
Speaker 0: shit.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then, like, as soon, like, during the whole day, I was like, "Oh, I have to go to this thing.
Speaker 1: I'd rather not go to this thing.
Speaker 1: I'm not feeling it today.
Speaker 1: I want to go home and go to
Speaker 1: bed.".
Speaker 0: See, for me, it was just, I'd stayed up late the previous two nights, so I was freaking exhausted, but I really, really wanted to meet Satoshi Kan.
Speaker 1: I did, but I felt like, you know, even that, I would have other chances, and, you know, in the future, he's not that old.
Speaker 1: I'd see him again.
Speaker 1: He's in the U.S.
Speaker 1: relatively often.
Speaker 1: Other people have seen him, you know, in other places in the
Speaker 1: U.S.,
Speaker 1: so...
Speaker 0: I wasn't quite as cynical as Scott.
Speaker 0: I was super excited about the event.
Speaker 0: I was just, I was tired, and I wasn't super excited about seeing Paprika again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wasn't.
Speaker 1: I danced mostly.
Speaker 1: I didn't want to watch the movie again, but anyway, when I actually got in there and watched the movie again, well, I could always watch the opener again.
Speaker 1: It was the opener to that movie.
Speaker 1: Good God.
Speaker 0: The credits, the opening credits to Paprika are some of the...
Speaker 1: I can't express to you... Best opening credits ever.
Speaker 0: Might be.
Speaker 1: I can't express to you how... Full-length motion picture, animated, whatnot.
Speaker 0: They're one of those few rare things where you get that slight chill of, like, you're watching it, and you're experiencing it, but this meta part of your brain can't enjoy it because it's saying, "This is so good.
Speaker 0: Look at how good this is.
Speaker 0: I can't get over how good it
Speaker 0: is.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much, and really, the one thing that you need to make that opener really work is a powerful sound system, because I saw that opener way before I ever saw Paprika, but I watched it...
Speaker 0: On loop for, like, a week.
Speaker 1: I watched it on the Sony Motion Pictures Classics website in a little tiny box with, like, little headphones on, and it didn't really do anything for me, but I saw the exact same thing in the theater, and it just blows you away.
Speaker 1: Anyway...
Speaker 0: Also, Paprika is an awesome movie, and seeing it again, it made so much sense, and it was so good.
Speaker 1: Seeing it the first time, I was like, "Well, that wasn't bad.
Speaker 1: It was
Speaker 1: alright.".
Speaker 1: But I didn't really get a lot of it, but watching it the second time, I don't know if there were different subtitles on it this time, or just because I had seen it before, even though I barely remembered most of it from, you know, the first time I saw it, but it made a whole lot of sense the second time.
Speaker 1: In fact, I sort of felt stupid for not getting it the first time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I noticed all these little clues, and all these things, like, "Whoa, duh.
Speaker 0: Oh, duh
Speaker 0: again.".
Speaker 1: It's really, really straightforward, and I just didn't get it the first time I watched it, but the second time I watched it, it was just obvious, like, "Oh,
Speaker 1: alright.".
Speaker 0: But also, again, that movie is just... If you have not seen Paprika, one, make sure you've seen everything else.
Speaker 0: Satoshi Kon did first, and then go see Paprika.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: You can watch him any order, really.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I would watch him in the order they were put out.
Speaker 1: That's a good way, you know, but it's not any worse than doing it in any other order.
Speaker 0: Ah, I get this feeling.
Speaker 1: Tokyo Godfather is a good one to watch first, actually.
Speaker 1: It's the most accessible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Perfect Blue is the most disturbing.
Speaker 0: Also, I think it's my favorite in the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Uh... Yeah, maybe.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I really like Tokyo Godfathers.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I'm really tired.
Speaker 0: The deal was, we see Paprika, and then Satoshi Kon comes out, and he looks kind of... I mean, you've seen pictures of him before, but seeing him in person, he looks, and he carries himself pretty much exactly the way you'd expect that kind of person to carry themselves.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 1: You know, the thing is, whenever people see artists, right, is they always expect the artist to reflect the art.
Speaker 1: Like, you ever see those pictures of, like, a person and their dog, and they're, like, the same, even though they're not?
Speaker 0: Sometimes it's very much like, "Oh, yeah," and sometimes it's completely the opposite, because there's really no true correlation.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Satoshi Kon, you know, it's like his movies.
Speaker 1: You'd think he's, like, a weird or scary guy, but he's not.
Speaker 1: He's just a normal dude.
Speaker 1: What's up?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: He's not quite a level of Mr.
Speaker 0: Watchman.
Speaker 1: No, no.
Speaker 1: You mean Alan Moore?
Speaker 0: He's just really cool, and he carries himself, and he's really funny, and he's really... The things he said were really interesting and really insightful.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: He's smart and level-headed and not weird and not crazy.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't know.
Speaker 1: He's generally all right, a lot better than a lot of other anime people who are, you know, kind of weird.
Speaker 0: Now, what they do at Lincoln Center when they have this sort of thing is, you know, they showed his work, and then they ask him a few questions, and then they show a clip from, like, Perfect Blue or something, and then they talk about that, and then they show another clip and talk about that, and it was kind of this live, semi-impromptu, semi-planned interview, and then at the end, of course, they take questions from the audience.
Speaker 0: Now, I'm sure you all know when we talked about Paranoia Agent that I had a pet theory as to what I thought Paranoia Agent was about, and I had all these reasons for it, and I had so much, and I'd always thought, "Man, if only I could ask Satoshi Kon to find out if I'm full of shit or not,".
Speaker 0: because as you all know, it's really easy to read into things like Lord of the Rings and, "Oh, it's a World War II blob,".
Speaker 0: but then J.R.R.
Speaker 0: Tolkien says, "Nah, just a bunch of elves and
Speaker 0: hobbits.".
Speaker 1: I mean, you could read anything into anything, and there's only so many stories out there.
Speaker 1: You can match up.
Speaker 1: You know, we were just talking about matching.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, there's definitely sometimes an artist will make a metaphor, and if you ask them, "Yes, I based it on that.
Speaker 0: Congratulations, you figured me out,".
Speaker 0: or, "Well, I guess you didn't read the autobiography where I said I based it on
Speaker 0: that.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like discovering the intent.
Speaker 1: Somehow, if the author intended it, then somehow it's better than if you just match it up on your own.
Speaker 0: No, it's more interesting, I think.
Speaker 0: It's cool when you read a work, then there's a non-explicit kind of parallel, and you see it, and then you find out that that is exactly what the artist was intending.
Speaker 0: It's kind of a, "Oh, wow, that's
Speaker 0: cool.".
Speaker 1: They did good arts because their message actually got through.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's kind of this indirect meeting of minds.
Speaker 0: I was going to quote something from The Prince of Nothing, but we've talked about that enough, but there's a very relevant scene related to this sort of thing.
Speaker 1: About seeing something or not?
Speaker 0: No, more about what it is to read something or experience an art someone else created.
Speaker 0: But anyway, my pet theory, to sum it up in a very kind of oversimplified way, was that Paranoid Agent was about Japan's atrocities in World War II.
Speaker 0: My idea was much more complex than that, but that's kind of what you boil it down to.
Speaker 0: I tried to ask my question.
Speaker 0: There's a million people there, and everyone had a million things to ask them, so I didn't get called on.
Speaker 0: Then, at the end, we go out, and he totally stayed and talked to anyone who wanted to talk to him, and signed autographs and pictures.
Speaker 0: There was a gallery of other art of his outside.
Speaker 0: He was totally cool, but I wanted to ask.
Speaker 0: Emily was like, "You want me to just ask
Speaker 0: him?".
Speaker 0: I was like, "Yes!
Speaker 0: Good God,
Speaker 0: yes!".
Speaker 0: So we walk over, and Emily asks him my crazy theory in Japanese.
Speaker 0: He considers it, and he looks at us, and he says, "No, I hadn't really intended that, but that's a really interesting idea, and it kind of
Speaker 0: fits.".
Speaker 0: So I was totally wrong, but he didn't blow me, he didn't completely shoot me down.
Speaker 0: But he basically said, "No, I didn't intend that at
Speaker 0: all.".
Speaker 1: I mean, if you would have said, "Is Paranoid Agent about how farts you
Speaker 1: smell?".
Speaker 1: He'd be like, "Well, you know, I didn't intend that, but that's a good way of looking at
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 0: I think he would have said, "What are you, crazy?
Speaker 0: No!
Speaker 0: No one farts in farts!
Speaker 1: Where do you get that?
Speaker 1: Well, the bat is a metaphor for the smell, and how it knocks you out, because it's so
Speaker 1: disgusting.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I feel relieved, because that's one of those things where you say like, "Oh, if only I could ask the person.
Speaker 0: I got to ask the person.
Speaker 0: I got an
Speaker 0: answer.".
Speaker 1: It's not like, you know, a lot of other things where, "Well, let's ask
Speaker 1: Shakespeare.".
Speaker 0: Or, "Fucking
Speaker 0: Ikuhara.".
Speaker 0: Well, I can't tell you why Toga did what he did in Utena, because, you see, I don't know what Toga was thinking.
Speaker 0: You'd have to ask him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, fuck you, Ikuhara.
Speaker 1: He's a crazy, crazy man.
Speaker 1: Not a smart man like Satoshi Kon.
Speaker 1: That's why Satoshi Kon is making the mad money as an Ikuhara, I assume, must be in a poorhouse somewhere.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure Ikuhara is doing very well.
Speaker 1: He's not doing anything, as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: He did at least one thing after Utena.
Speaker 0: I think he was smart.
Speaker 0: There's a fine on one end.
Speaker 0: There's the smart scale, right?
Speaker 0: But directly parallel to that is the crazy scale.
Speaker 0: And if you have smart, 100% smart, and 0% crazy, you get Satoshi Kon.
Speaker 0: 100% smart, 100% crazy, you get Shiro.
Speaker 0: Maybe Kojima.
Speaker 0: And there's those fine lines.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to say where I think Ikuhara is, but he's not 0% smart.
Speaker 0: He's not 100% smart.
Speaker 0: He's negative 100% smart.
Speaker 0: I like what Ikuhara did, and I'll leave it at... Well, one thing he did, and I'll leave it at that.
Speaker 1: He likes that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: God, God.
Speaker 0: All right, last thing, and I'm going to move on from this.
Speaker 0: If you ever want to find out what Kunihiko Ikuhara is really like, the guy who made Utena with Chiyo Saito, and the guy who made the Utena movie, and nominally with Chiyo Saito, watch the Utena movie with the commentary from Ikuhara.
Speaker 0: Because you will learn the depths of the creepy dude that is Ikuhara.
Speaker 0: When he gets distracted by the creepy shit going on in the movie he made, it's kind of epically hilarious.
Speaker 1: Naked cars, naked cars.
Speaker 0: It was totally awesome to meet Satoshi Kon, and the only thing I have to say, I'm not really calling anyone out, but I want to mention this.
Speaker 0: People ask questions, there's always... When you go to this sort of thing all the time, there's always the kinds of people who ask certain questions.
Speaker 0: There's always...
Speaker 1: You could categorize the questions in many different ways, but I categorize questions asked to panels into pretty much three categories.
Speaker 1: There's the, well, maybe four.
Speaker 1: There's the smart question, it is very rare.
Speaker 1: There is the pretty much question everyone asks, like, "What's your inspiration?
Speaker 1: How do I become just like you?
Speaker 1: Why are you so
Speaker 1: awesome?".
Speaker 1: Those are the stupid questions.
Speaker 0: There's the, I'm not actually asking a question, I'm showing off.
Speaker 1: Well, it's sort of like the pretentious question, where it's not really a question, or it's not a question that anyone can actually answer.
Speaker 0: Now, these questions are usually spotted because they begin with a long expository statement that is not a question, and end with a barely relevant question, like, "Well, having read your insert super obscure work done by a guy you're asking the question to, blah, blah,
Speaker 0: blah.".
Speaker 1: I noticed you had a lot of imagery involving elephants, and as it related to this, and how it means this, and this, and this.
Speaker 1: Is that imagery relating to you in this kind of way, or in this kind of way?
Speaker 1: And it's just like, uh...
Speaker 0: Now, these are often also noted, especially at an anime convention, by the person in the audience who clearly speaks English, who asks the question in Japanese, thus fucking everything up in terms of filming and translating.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Bonus points if they don't actually speak Japanese, and are reading off of something that is not written in Japanese.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: So those are the... And then the final kind of question is sort of like the tasteless question, which is sort of like, "Oh, why are you asking that?
Speaker 1: You know, you shouldn't be asking that
Speaker 1: shit.".
Speaker 1: Like, it's something... Maybe you're asking something that's taboo, or out of place.
Speaker 1: Like, for example...
Speaker 0: I think the word is crass.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, for example, there was that guy from Gainax who had that whole issue that went on, like, you know, 2chan or something like that, and he got to resign or something.
Speaker 1: You don't really ask about that, you know?
Speaker 1: It's like it doesn't...
Speaker 0: Unless you're, like, in a hard-heading journalist situation.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: If you're at a panel at a convention, that's not what you go for, you know?
Speaker 1: Or, like, if a voice actor was, like, having a feud with someone else.
Speaker 1: You don't go asking about that kind of thing, you know?
Speaker 1: You only ask about what's really relevant.
Speaker 1: I mean, you can ask hard questions about what's relevant.
Speaker 1: Like, at a Bandai visual panel, you can say, "Why are your DVDs so
Speaker 1: expensive?".
Speaker 1: But at a Bandai entertainment panel, I wouldn't go and ask, "Did you fire that Bandai visual guy's
Speaker 1: ass?"?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't ask that.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Now, in the interest of friendship and being nice, which is a change for Geeknives, I'm not gonna say who asked this question.
Speaker 0: But I would like to point out... Well, they know.
Speaker 0: Yes, they do.
Speaker 0: But I just want to say that this was one of the most tasteless questions I have ever seen someone ask someone at a panel.
Speaker 0: It was basically, "So, you know what happened in Akihabara, right?
Speaker 0: What do you think of
Speaker 0: that?".
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Now, this was at a panel about Satoshi Kon and a retrospective of his works.
Speaker 0: And they basically asked, "So, yeah, you know that random murder that happened in the country you happened to be from?
Speaker 0: Yeah, what do you think of that?
Speaker 0: Never mind your works or
Speaker 0: anything.".
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, it's slightly related because it's an Akihabara, and the murder was committed by, basically, the worst kind of otaku in the world.
Speaker 1: And he creates works which appeal to that demographic somewhat.
Speaker 0: But it was just the question...
Speaker 1: But that's like if you asked Will Wright, who makes video games, about Columbine right after it happened.
Speaker 1: Be like, "Hey, Will Wright, what do you think about
Speaker 1: Columbine?".
Speaker 1: He's like, "Why are you asking me about...".
Speaker 1: I don't think that's really... It's really not relevant to the person.
Speaker 0: Now, to his credit, though, to Satoshi Kon's credit...
Speaker 1: Yeah, he answered perfectly.
Speaker 0: Not only did he take the question in stride, but despite the translator, was a little flustered.
Speaker 0: Satoshi Kon actually had a really interesting answer about how, in particular, the person who committed this crime, it was almost as though it was a crime committed against victims.
Speaker 0: The person didn't care who the victims were.
Speaker 0: And in the end, maybe the perpetrator was kind of created by the media or created by society such that it didn't matter who the person doing the crime was either.
Speaker 0: It was this really interesting answer that I think lost a little bit in the translation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it did a lot of things.
Speaker 1: I mean, the translator, she was really, really good, but she was also paraphrasing a bit too much.
Speaker 0: Basically, a question we could ask, and Satoshi Kon would talk for five minutes straight without breathing.
Speaker 1: That's the thing, though.
Speaker 1: Well, he wouldn't breathe, but he would go... Yeah, you know, and I realize, you know, and it's like in the
Speaker 1: U.S.,
Speaker 1: in English, right?
Speaker 1: If I sit here on geek nights and I go "sun, sun, sun, uh, sun, sun, eh," right, then obviously I'm having a bad night like tonight.
Speaker 1: But in Japan, or at least in the Japanese language, it seems like that everyone does that all the time.
Speaker 1: And it doesn't make you sound dumb or slow or like you can't think quickly.
Speaker 0: Well, different languages do different things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know, but I just think it's an interesting thing.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 0: But also, Satoshi Kon would talk for a long time without giving the translator a chance to translate any of it.
Speaker 1: Well, she had a little notepad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it worked pretty well.
Speaker 0: But, I mean, Emily was there, and she, it was obvious from her responses that the translation was being brevined somewhat.
Speaker 0: That's totally a cromulent word, so shut up.
Speaker 0: Anyone out there is about to complain about that.
Speaker 1: It was being paraphrased, like I said.
Speaker 0: Made more brief.
Speaker 1: Paraphrased.
Speaker 1: I gave you the word.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm well away.
Speaker 1: The cromulent word.
Speaker 0: No, no, that's not a cr-, that is not a cromulent word.
Speaker 0: No, it's truly cromulent.
Speaker 0: It was more than, I was thinking leavened, and I like the word leavened, so I wanted to take brief.
Speaker 1: Like, like, you gave Satoshi Kon the yeast?
Speaker 1: Is that what you're saying?
Speaker 1: Rim like's giving him the yeast?
Speaker 1: Anyway, so, uh, you might want to get some of that, uh, cream from the store if you got the yeast.
Speaker 0: So, Scott, well, do you get Monostat 7-3 or 1?
Speaker 1: Is that what that does?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I just know that there's a cream.
Speaker 1: I don't know which one.
Speaker 0: Okay, so, is in the non-Rim and Scott got to geek out over Satoshi Kon in person.
Speaker 0: What's in the news?
Speaker 1: So, I was just talking a few minutes ago about the Bandai visuals.
Speaker 1: Oh, huh, huh.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, they went out of business.
Speaker 1: Big surprise.
Speaker 0: Big surprise.
Speaker 0: It always amazes me how often a company will do something or start, and it's like, I know along with the majority of the world who knows what they're doing.
Speaker 0: that is a bad idea.
Speaker 0: It's like everyone knows.
Speaker 0: it's a bad idea but them.
Speaker 0: Don't they know?
Speaker 1: So, anyway, they got folded back into Bandai Entertainment, which is the Bandai that existed was putting out Gundam DVDs and Cowboy Bebop DVDs and Escaflowne DVDs and such and such and such, right?
Speaker 1: So, now they're both, it's just Bandai Entertainment is the only company now, and they have all of Bandai Visuals stuff, and they put out an announcement, basically, because the anime expo is really soon-ish, like this weekend, and they're basically like,
Speaker 0: all right,
Speaker 1: here's what we're going to do with the Bandai Visuals stuff.
Speaker 1: They're going to put it under the, you know, the Oniyamis label, which is where it was under already, which is, if you have never seen Wings of Oniyamis, you probably should, because I haven't, because I suck, and Bandai Visuals DVD is too expensive, or I'd buy it.
Speaker 0: Hey, don't worry, I've only seen it once, and I saw like an eighth generation fan sub.
Speaker 0: It cuts out for about 10 minutes in the middle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's like, you know, that's like their highlight movie, so that's like, that label basically means, you know, awesome, QWERTY anime, and that's, you know, QWERTY?
Speaker 1: QWERTY.
Speaker 0: Was it Ferrier?
Speaker 1: Yes, it was.
Speaker 0: Opposite of Inferior?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Bonus points to anyone who isn't Scout Johnson who knows what that is a reference to.
Speaker 1: Anyone who's in the front row crew knows that's a reference to.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: All right, so, um, all right, so basically, good game.
Speaker 0: GGG.
Speaker 1: All right, so basically the things that they had already announced that were going to be delayed indefinitely, like Engage Planet Kizdom, I just love that name, Kizdom, Shigofumi, Sola, True Tears, whatever.
Speaker 1: Those are still indefinitely gone, right?
Speaker 1: Basically, most of the DVDs and whatnot that they were already coming out with are going to keep coming out.
Speaker 1: And they're basically, there's only a few things have gone missing, like, you know, the original Gunbuster video and whatnot.
Speaker 1: The thing is, they haven't really changed the prices on any of these things.
Speaker 1: Oh, well.
Speaker 1: So what?
Speaker 1: what did they really accomplish by closing Bandai Visual besides getting a bunch of people off the payroll?
Speaker 1: Nothing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, like, let's see.
Speaker 1: Here we go.
Speaker 1: Gunbuster two version volume one DVD.
Speaker 1: Forty dollars.
Speaker 1: Freedom volume one HD DVD and also regular DVD on the same disc.
Speaker 1: Forty dollars for what?
Speaker 1: One episode?
Speaker 0: That's cheaper than your mom.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because I'm so great.
Speaker 1: But so still too expensive.
Speaker 1: You haven't fixed it.
Speaker 1: I mean, here's the thing that really bothers me.
Speaker 1: Look at some of these things.
Speaker 1: I didn't even know that they were putting out.
Speaker 1: Jin Ro.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: We saw Jin Ro back in the day on DVD.
Speaker 1: It cost us less than 20 bucks for those DVDs.
Speaker 1: They got a Blu-ray version of Jin Ro now.
Speaker 1: Eighty dollars.
Speaker 0: Yes, that is totally worth every single one of those dollars.
Speaker 1: Sarcasm detector exploding.
Speaker 0: A sarcasm detector.
Speaker 0: How useful is that?
Speaker 0: That's useful.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So useful as an 80 dollar Jin Ro Blu-ray.
Speaker 0: So Otacon.
Speaker 0: Otacon this year is just shaping up like every time.
Speaker 1: there's how many weeks and how many?
Speaker 1: Let's do a little countdown here.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So exactly.
Speaker 0: Oh, crap.
Speaker 0: There's no counter on the Otacon website.
Speaker 0: Five, six.
Speaker 1: I think it's this weekend, the weekend after that, the weekend after that.
Speaker 1: So that's this weekend, which is July 4th weekend.
Speaker 1: One, two, three, four weekends.
Speaker 1: And that fourth weekend is Connecticut.
Speaker 1: And then the fifth weekend is Otacon, if I am correct.
Speaker 0: No one.
Speaker 0: If you're around, go to Connecticut.
Speaker 0: We're running a million panels and a ton of stuff.
Speaker 1: I am correct.
Speaker 0: But anyway, there's a bunch of Otacon news.
Speaker 0: I'm get through it all because one, it was announced just recently that Peter S. Beagle, the person responsible for the last unicorn, is going to be at Otacon.
Speaker 0: He was at Otacon last year.
Speaker 1: I totally miss like I didn't totally miss him.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like he was there, but like he's in the dealer's room at this table almost the whole time.
Speaker 0: Well, this year he's doing a screening of the last unicorn by Q&A.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: That's how it's done because last year he was in the dealer's room and I walked by and I was like, ha ha.
Speaker 1: And I was like, oh, last unicorn guy.
Speaker 1: I thought I heard that he was going to be here, but that was all I got out of it.
Speaker 1: So now I don't think I got to go to that screening.
Speaker 0: Also announced that our friend Peter Fernandez, the original voice of Speed Racer, who was totally awesome, is going to be at Otacon.
Speaker 0: I hope, I mean, no, I don't think we're going to do our anime match game.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 0: Otacon is the only con we don't run this game show at, but almost every, like half the voice actors at Otacon have been on our match game.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Let's look at the list.
Speaker 1: We could figure it out.
Speaker 0: I'll figure it out later.
Speaker 0: I'll post some sort of who's been on it, who hasn't.
Speaker 0: But anyway, Peter Fernandez is totally awesome.
Speaker 0: And if whatever panel he does, you should totally go to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Cause I mean, you're going to see this little old man hobbling, looking all fragile, booming radio voice of the gods.
Speaker 0: Pretty much the man has presence.
Speaker 1: I want me some radio voice training, radio voice training.
Speaker 0: I'm going to get some, actually, it's kind of expensive.
Speaker 0: I was looking into it, but Peter Fernandez has some gray shade oratory.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you what for real.
Speaker 0: But, uh, one more announcement Otacon, you know, one thing that has again, be said about Otacon is that it has grown almost entirely through word of mouth.
Speaker 0: They don't really advertise.
Speaker 0: people just know, or they don't.
Speaker 0: And despite the fact that 20 to 25,000 people show up at Otacon every year, I'll go to Kineticon or Katsucon, which is right there.
Speaker 0: And people have never heard of Otacon.
Speaker 0: Lots of people, anime fans who live near Baltimore have never heard of Otacon.
Speaker 0: Lots of them.
Speaker 0: So, uh, you know, there's going to be this BCC expansion next year and Otacon's cap can go up and up and up as they get more streamlined and everything and Otacon gets better and better and better.
Speaker 0: But what can Otacon do to get more people?
Speaker 0: Advertise.
Speaker 0: What costs a shit ton of money?
Speaker 0: Advertising.
Speaker 0: What's the best way to get a bunch of free press?
Speaker 0: Have a contest.
Speaker 1: Well, contests are a good way.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, there's plenty of other ways to get some free press out there, but yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: So Otacon is doing a lot of that.
Speaker 1: But the big problem with Otacon advertising is they don't want to spend any resources on it because that's resources that won't make the convention better, you know, and except for getting more people to show up.
Speaker 1: And if you advertise, you know, in a good way, too many people might show up and they're not, I don't think they're ready for too many more people to show up.
Speaker 0: I mean, not yet.
Speaker 1: I think with a real ad campaign, like with the ads, like posters or on television, they would get thousands of extra.
Speaker 1: And I think they can only handle a few thousand extra.
Speaker 0: A little bird tells me that there may be some Baltimore targeted advertisements.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to say it's okay.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to say exactly the way, cause I didn't, I wasn't, I didn't get the, you can talk about this on the show.
Speaker 0: It was just in a conversation.
Speaker 0: But, um, I feel like that.
Speaker 0: the strategy here is tap Baltimore this year.
Speaker 0: And then next year when there is this expansion on the BCC go all out further.
Speaker 0: Cause I think the cab can go way up, but you know, that's all speculation on my part, but this caught the Oticon 2008 web comics challenge.
Speaker 0: You can read the rules and the deadline is pretty quick.
Speaker 0: Basically any web comic published between now and July 11th, featuring a storyline specifically about Oticon is eligible to win some shit.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: What do you win?
Speaker 0: I'm not even going to go into that.
Speaker 0: Cause I want to get past this.
Speaker 0: I'm real hungry.
Speaker 0: I'm real tired.
Speaker 0: And you can read all the details.
Speaker 1: What if I just draw like stick figures real quick and slap them up on the website?
Speaker 1: Can that count possibly?
Speaker 0: Well, you'll be eligible.
Speaker 1: Oh, all right.
Speaker 0: I mean, we've had contests and you might be eligible.
Speaker 0: Does mean you're going to win.
Speaker 1: Oh, is it random or is it best one?
Speaker 0: Uh, well the big rule, all decisions of Oticon staff regarding eligibility as well as prize awards are final.
Speaker 0: And it looks like they can just decide.
Speaker 0: There's a whole bunch of rules here.
Speaker 0: You get all the rights.
Speaker 1: They're just going to pick whichever one they like pretty much.
Speaker 1: So it's better to be good.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the other news that I really want to talk about, and this is another thing a little bird told me it hasn't been announced yet.
Speaker 0: this week, Oticon is going to announce the other musical acts.
Speaker 0: Oh no.
Speaker 0: Now they've already got freaking jam projects.
Speaker 0: So who the hell are they going to announce?
Speaker 1: Well, it could be a lesser act because in the past, you know, they've had a big one and then a few, you know, side ones.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, all indications are that this Oticon is going a couple of steps above and beyond every other Oticon in terms of programming.
Speaker 1: That could be true, but I have, you know, sort of, I'm done.
Speaker 0: I've let, I've exhaled as far as, you know, waiting for some sort of like a Yumi or it's going to be a Yumi Hamasaki and Megumi Haji Barra and two mix and mine, Yoko Kano.
Speaker 1: And I don't know, the year before we got there.
Speaker 0: Yes, I could cry.
Speaker 0: I listened to that MP3 kind of often.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But regardless, this Oticon, just in terms of already what has been announced so far, the raw programming panels, musical acts that have been announced thus far guests.
Speaker 0: I think this is going to be the best Oticon programming wise of any Oticon ever.
Speaker 1: I hope that I just hope they keep the dealer's room with the same layout where they can use that extra space under the stairs.
Speaker 1: And that one lobby for the exit of the dealer's room.
Speaker 0: Plus I'm looking forward because the only badge we don't have at Oticon now is staff.
Speaker 1: We're going to be, the badge you don't want because then someone could tell you what to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Unless you're a Kotsukon at Kineticon.
Speaker 1: So we're going to have press, regular, artists alley, panelists.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: And we don't have guests either.
Speaker 0: We don't have guests or staff.
Speaker 1: That's all right.
Speaker 0: But we've got guests and staff at Kotsukon and Kineticon.
Speaker 0: So I think all around we've got everything.
Speaker 0: We don't have con chair.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I'm willing to ever deal with that.
Speaker 1: How about no.
Speaker 1: I don't have time for this.
Speaker 1: How much does that time for that shit?
Speaker 0: Things of the day.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day is going to be basically Satoshi Kon.
Speaker 0: The really cool thing is that he kind of he brought this camera with him on stage.
Speaker 1: But it was a Nikon DSLR.
Speaker 0: We know because he told us.
Speaker 1: Well, I could tell just looking at it was a Nikon digital SLR.
Speaker 1: I didn't know if it was like the D. I guess they have like the 80 and the D. I don't forget there's a bunch of different numbers.
Speaker 1: Bigger numbers means fancier.
Speaker 1: And he was like, as the Nikon, the pride of Japan.
Speaker 1: And I was like, oh, I was not aware that the Nikon was the pride of Japan.
Speaker 0: But one thing he did a bunch of times while he was talking is he would just take a picture of the crowd.
Speaker 1: Usually that's the kind of thing that'd be sort of annoying and weird.
Speaker 1: But he sort of did it in a way that wasn't weird.
Speaker 1: He did it.
Speaker 0: And then he made a really interesting point with it.
Speaker 0: And then he kind of used it to kind of pull the thread together.
Speaker 0: Then at the end, he's like, now, before you all go.
Speaker 0: And then he took like one final picture.
Speaker 0: My thing of the day is that picture.
Speaker 0: Now, we were there with a bunch like Emily's there and a bunch of people.
Speaker 0: But the important thing is Scott has the most demure, like debutante, like he's like he's so enamored with Satoshi Khan and he wants to ask him out.
Speaker 0: He's like, oh, no, because Satoshi Senpai.
Speaker 1: I don't know you.
Speaker 0: You did the picture.
Speaker 0: The way you look in this picture is so demure and hilarious.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I remember at the time I was just sort of like sitting there resting my head on my hands, just sort of tired.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Well, in this picture, you can come look at it when we're done recording.
Speaker 1: I don't seem to look good in any picture, really.
Speaker 0: It's hard.
Speaker 0: The thing is pictures of me from straight on front.
Speaker 0: I always look kind of weird because I have these gigantic smile all the time.
Speaker 0: But from the side, I look a lot more normal.
Speaker 1: See, the thing is, you know, like you just look at me, you know, walking around.
Speaker 1: I'm all right.
Speaker 1: But if you take a picture of me, you'll see that like one half of my chin is bigger than the other half.
Speaker 1: And my like a giant, you know, my mouth is sort of uneven if I open it and whatever.
Speaker 0: You're so worried.
Speaker 0: But you're very demure in this picture.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So check this out.
Speaker 1: This actually I didn't realize till just now, reading the text under the video here, the what do they call it?
Speaker 1: The subtext or caption the caption that this is actually a really old thing.
Speaker 1: It's just it didn't get posted until the Internet until a few weeks ago.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, since we're doing less episodes, it didn't make it till thing of the day until today.
Speaker 1: Actually, I might have done this thing today and screwed up if I did tell me about.
Speaker 1: I think I did anyway.
Speaker 1: So there's this performance artist in Japan.
Speaker 1: It's a lady named Sako Kojima.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I guess a long time ago, at least a year ago, she did this performance art in the window of a store where she became a hamster.
Speaker 0: And you might be thinking, wait, wait, what?
Speaker 0: Like metaphorically, does she dress up as a hamster?
Speaker 1: No, literally her her installation slash performance.
Speaker 1: Why I became a hamster included treats, housing, chew toys and food all scaled to her size.
Speaker 1: She basically spent multiple days living as a hamster, acting as a hamster in, you know, in a store window.
Speaker 1: And she's at once one half.
Speaker 1: It's like, wow, that's really cute.
Speaker 1: And the other half is like, wow, she's really crazy.
Speaker 1: Remember how I talked about the is the smartest and insane scale is the perfect metaphor for Japan.
Speaker 0: I don't know what to say other than that.
Speaker 0: It's really, really cute.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, it is really, really crazy.
Speaker 1: But I guess there is some kind of art to it in a way.
Speaker 1: You know, it's up to you whether you like it.
Speaker 0: It's surprisingly well done.
Speaker 0: Like, it's very well put together, this thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: She definitely put a lot of thought into this.
Speaker 0: So I hate we weren't going to do like a cop out or like a special now that we've got the schedule short.
Speaker 0: But Scott and I are both kind of going out of town.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott's going to see his grandma in Florida.
Speaker 0: And Emily and I are going to the beach in Wildwood with Scott Johnson and Laura.
Speaker 1: So as a result, I always say Laura, it's Laura.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not Laura or Lara or Lira or Lara, Laura, as in Laura, as in battle, Laura.
Speaker 1: The thing is, Laura is no you in it.
Speaker 1: It's a different name.
Speaker 0: I'm totally indifferent.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying anyway.
Speaker 0: So it's not like I'm trying to kill some time between that other Laura that we knew.
Speaker 1: Are you not able to say this?
Speaker 1: Is it you have a problem?
Speaker 0: Michigan accent.
Speaker 0: What do you want from Laura?
Speaker 0: Here's the thing in the Midwest.
Speaker 0: The way we pronounce a is pretty much at all times.
Speaker 0: The only people who pronounce it worse than that are the people in Scranton, Pennsylvania.
Speaker 0: Scranton.
Speaker 0: No offense to anyone in Scranton, but I've never had a good time when I've been there.
Speaker 1: I avoid that place quite much.
Speaker 0: The thing is, as far as I can tell, it's just an interchange between 81 and 84.
Speaker 0: My dad is to go there for work sometimes.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So as a result, instead of totally copping out, luckily we kind of went long unintentionally in the first half.
Speaker 0: So we're not going to review Princess Tutu.
Speaker 0: We're not.
Speaker 1: I've only seen one disc.
Speaker 0: A full review of it, though in the future at some point, we will fully review this show because it's a show that's worth reviewing.
Speaker 0: But what we're going to do is preview it.
Speaker 0: Now remember, the kind of the way we do this is that a preview is either.
Speaker 0: we haven't seen all the show, though in this case I have seen the entire show, but we're really not going to try to spoil anything.
Speaker 0: We're mostly going to.
Speaker 0: a preview is kind of like if it is worth it for you to watch a show is what we do.
Speaker 0: You know, this is what the show is about.
Speaker 0: This is our impressions of it.
Speaker 0: Yada, yada, yada.
Speaker 0: If you're this kind of person, you'll probably like it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So Princess Tutu is a show that the way most people who like it would explain it is, yeah, I totally would have never thought to watch a show called Princess Tutu.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, you look at it like, OK, it's called Princess Tutu.
Speaker 1: And it's like, even though I should have learned my lesson from liking Fancy Lala.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Let's see shows that by the name, you don't think you'll like Fancy Lala, Princess Tutu.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But I like Fancy Lala, at least what I saw.
Speaker 1: So but yet Fancy Lala Princess Tutu comes along and I'm like, there's no way I can like Princess Tutu.
Speaker 1: But Princess Tutu is all right.
Speaker 1: Now, now here's I got to say, all right, if you don't want any spoilers whatsoever, because it's really hard to talk about the show, because there's pretty much something that happens in pretty much every episode, that because of my experience watching the first episode and being stupid, it would have been a spoiler for me if you would have said the most basic, obvious thing about the show.
Speaker 1: So I feel like if you have already decided you're going to give it a go, you know, shouldn't listen to this episode anymore, because then you won't have any chance of having this really weird experience I had in the first episode.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: So if you have already decided that you are going to watch Princess Tutu based solely on the fact that we have said it's worth watching, stop right now and go watch the first episode of Princess Tutu or buy it or rent
Speaker 1: as soon as you watch the first episode, then you can come back and listen to the rest of this without any worries.
Speaker 0: We're not we're not really going to spoil anything, but you'll get a better experience if you don't know anything going into it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'd say don't even look at anything online.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Avoid even looking at the box.
Speaker 1: Just put the DVD in and go.
Speaker 1: And now let me explain to you why this is, you see, Princess Tutu, right?
Speaker 1: If you didn't realize it, because I apparently I sort of.
Speaker 1: it's one of those things where it's like, you know it or you feel like you should know it or it's obvious, but you don't know it.
Speaker 1: It's a magical girl show and a magical girl show has magical girls transforming.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Which is sort of obvious.
Speaker 1: Now, the thing is I was watching the first episode and you have this girl transforming from a duck to a girl.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So there was the transformation.
Speaker 1: I didn't.
Speaker 1: another transformation, you know, from average girl to Princess Tutu was not expected.
Speaker 1: So in the first episode, when it happened, to be honest, it blew me away.
Speaker 1: I was like, OMG.
Speaker 1: So I feel like if you know what I told you, if someone had told me, Scott, remember, it's a magical girl show, then that wouldn't have blown me away.
Speaker 1: So I feel like you can sort of spoil that cool experience of being blown away in the first episode by not fully grokking the magical girlness.
Speaker 0: But there's a few not really misconceptions, but a lot of people I found and I was included until I actually sat down and watched this show don't know anything about it.
Speaker 0: Other than that, a lot of older or more hardcore anime fans will mention it.
Speaker 0: And it's usually mentioned in conversations that also involve like Utena and Rose of Versailles and those sorts of shows.
Speaker 0: So a lot of people who just hear the name think like they expect a certain aesthetic and a certain kind of show.
Speaker 0: And I think a lot of people who actually sit down and watch the show are very, very surprised to see a recent, modern, crisply animated, not at all stylistically like those shows show.
Speaker 1: No, not really.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much a standardly, moderately animated.
Speaker 0: What I'm saying is a lot of the people I talked to who clearly just have heard that, oh, Princess Tutu, I've heard that's good.
Speaker 0: They think if you ask him, what do you think that is?
Speaker 0: They think it's this old, old, old show.
Speaker 0: I've run into a lot of people who think this because it's not a show that's out there.
Speaker 0: A lot of people don't know about it.
Speaker 0: So not many people have actually seen what the show looks like, which is kind of surprising, except for the fact that there's so much anime out there.
Speaker 0: It's real easy to see.
Speaker 1: I mean, because it is easy to get confused because there are a lot of older anime that are, you know, could be confused like Princess Knight.
Speaker 0: So plus, I mean, people do talk about it and they tend to bring up shows like Utena in the same breath.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: But Princess Tutu is the story of a young duck.
Speaker 1: Quack.
Speaker 0: Named Ahiru.
Speaker 1: Which Ahiru is the Japanese word for duck.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: So it's a duck named Duck.
Speaker 0: Now, this is not a metaphor.
Speaker 0: She's literally a duck.
Speaker 1: Literally.
Speaker 1: We're talking like it's in the water and it goes quack, quack, quack.
Speaker 0: I really like how the beginning of the show opens because it's pretty much, it shows a prince dancing ballet, you know, Swan Lake sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They, they, I mean, Tchaikovsky, he's my man.
Speaker 1: I love his action.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And he's got the mad ballets going on, but really like they put him on a little too much.
Speaker 1: It feels like there is enough balance.
Speaker 0: The show called Princess Tutu about ballet.
Speaker 0: every episode is a metaphor for a different ballet.
Speaker 1: I meant the Tchaikovsky is in there a little too much.
Speaker 1: You got to put in some other ballets in there a little bit more.
Speaker 1: Balance it out.
Speaker 0: I think part of it is that Swan Lake, considering that the main character is a duck girl is not a Swan.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: But consider where the show might be going.
Speaker 1: It's actually become a Swan.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to say anything at all.
Speaker 0: This show, I'm not going to spoil, but basically it's like it starts out and it's really cool.
Speaker 0: And there's this prince and he's dancing here, this voiceover of a girl, like I've always loved the prince, that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: And then, but I'm a duck and it's a duck watching this dancing and the duck loves the prince, but the duck's a duck.
Speaker 1: Literally like quack.
Speaker 1: I'm in the water.
Speaker 1: I have webbed feet and little wing-a-lings.
Speaker 0: But then the duck wakes up as a girl and there's some flashbacks.
Speaker 0: And it basically for the first several minutes of this show, the girl wakes up and you're kind of, she's not sure and neither are you if she was always a girl or always a duck.
Speaker 0: Is it a duck who dreamed it was a girl, a girl who dreamed it was a duck?
Speaker 0: Is it a girl who and it's pretty explicitly, you figure it out after a while and they kind of explicitly say, no, it's a duck turns into a girl, but it's really left open and that kind of matters later.
Speaker 0: But Laura, who lent us the two sets of this show?
Speaker 0: because she really likes it and I really like it too.
Speaker 0: The way she described it, and this is probably the best way to describe the show to someone is that it is a show that as long as you are comfortable and expect, comfortable with and expecting the fact that the characters will fight with each other and express their feelings almost entirely through ballet and independent of that, the show is about a bunch of people at a ballet school.
Speaker 1: That is one thing that it has in common with a lot of other anime like Gutena is that it sort of has the inexplicable school, right?
Speaker 1: It's like there are a bunch of people in a school somewhere.
Speaker 1: There's no other world.
Speaker 1: They don't have parents.
Speaker 1: They don't have siblings.
Speaker 1: It's just a bunch of kids in a school inexplicably.
Speaker 1: And this may be a teacher or something, but that's it.
Speaker 1: And it's like, huh?
Speaker 0: But at the same time, this show, unlike other shows, addresses that.
Speaker 1: And there's a point at which someone's really addressed it in the first disc.
Speaker 0: No, but as the show goes on, it gets to the point where what's outside the gates, fuck if I know.
Speaker 1: I mean, they walk around town.
Speaker 1: sometimes they interact with the town a little bit, but not much.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much just a place.
Speaker 0: It's like, well, if they leave the school, they're in the town and antennas like that, where you see a few, like a few times someone's outside of the school.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like they go out, they like say, oh, and she gets an apartment in town at one point, right?
Speaker 1: Or walk about has an apartment in town and she, some people go, there's a couple scenes where someone goes to town shopping to buy something.
Speaker 0: Or there's a scene where some people go to a, an amusement park together.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: To go get some Curry.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: We just totally obliquely referenced like everything that's good about that show or bad about that show or all anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But the town, you know, it's not really there.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like the show kind of like, all right, we're in this walled garden, let's just go.
Speaker 0: But then, you know, people from the outside, like a ballet troop will come at one point and the people who come, things kind of happened to them as a result of them being there.
Speaker 0: And it's from that point forward, the fact that the school is inexplicable suddenly becomes very relevant.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I've always wanted to show like, you know, sort of take that idea because so many other shows take that inexplicable school mechanic for granted.
Speaker 1: They just have the inexplicable school there the whole time so that their story can take place within it.
Speaker 1: Yet, if a show actually took the inexplicable school and then said, why is this school so here and such and weird, then that would be totally cool.
Speaker 1: So if this show does that, that sounds good to me.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: The other thing that's pretty cool is that the show takes nothing for granted.
Speaker 0: And as you go on, everything is explained or relevant and there's nothing's really taken for granted.
Speaker 0: And a lot of it's pretty interesting.
Speaker 1: The first episode is a little bit, you know, weird, but the second episode pretty much smooths things right over and puts you into the monster, the weak groove.
Speaker 1: And then each episode sort of reveals a little bit more, but the first episode is weird, but the second episode, everything is straightened out and you're like, oh, I get it.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: It's not like a tenor where it's all weird.
Speaker 0: It's pretty obvious that the show will be like plot monster of the day ish for a while.
Speaker 0: And then back to like straight out plot until the end.
Speaker 0: And it's in two, like it's two separate shows.
Speaker 0: Basically the first half of the show, the first 12 or 13 or whatever episodes goes, stops the show ends.
Speaker 0: Plot is resolved.
Speaker 0: Next episode, we continue.
Speaker 0: And the show happens again.
Speaker 1: The thing is in like episode two or three, they tell you like, what's going to happen.
Speaker 1: They're like, this is a trade.
Speaker 1: They pretty much say in plain Japanese, this is a tragedy.
Speaker 1: Hello.
Speaker 1: Like they, and she says, oh, it's a tragedy.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Like that's what the character says.
Speaker 1: So it's like, huh?
Speaker 1: Is it actually going to be, I don't know, but they just said it was going to be.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But one other thing I want to say, it's not really a spoiler, but this show breaks another trope of magical girl shows where pretty much right away, people are like, well, you're princess too, too.
Speaker 0: Duh.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's not like sailor moon or Superman.
Speaker 0: It's like, oh, you fucking disappear.
Speaker 0: Francis Tucci, who looks a lot like you appears immediately.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like an episode, uh, four or five, right?
Speaker 1: There's a scene where, you know, the duck in human form.
Speaker 1: And that's one thing I like about the show.
Speaker 1: is that most magical girls, like sailor moon, right?
Speaker 1: She's either sailor moon or what's her name?
Speaker 1: What's her name?
Speaker 1: Which is not sailor moon.
Speaker 0: Well, depending on if you watch the dub, it's Serena or Sagi.
Speaker 0: Her full name is skin.
Speaker 1: Oh, Sagi, whatever the girl, when she's not sailor moon, that's it here.
Speaker 1: We've got duck.
Speaker 1: The animal quack quack turns into girl named duck.
Speaker 0: Who's just a girl whose friends are complete jerks to her.
Speaker 1: I love that.
Speaker 1: And then she transfers into princess too, too.
Speaker 1: It's fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: So it's kind of weird.
Speaker 1: Like, you know, there's a girl who's the cool girl, Roo.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: And Roo is my favorite character.
Speaker 1: I think so.
Speaker 1: Cause all the other characters are annoying or evil or stupid in some way.
Speaker 0: She's cool, except for her cool and smart.
Speaker 1: She's cool and smart and not stupid or annoying.
Speaker 1: Uh, but so Roo's hanging with duck, right?
Speaker 1: In monster of the week, basically.
Speaker 1: And when the monster of the week shows up, duck disappears and princess who shows up.
Speaker 1: And then after they deal with the monster of the week, Roo is like, uh, you disappeared and ducks like, and duck is very annoying.
Speaker 0: That was actually a pretty apt, uh, expression of how she laughs.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Duck.
Speaker 1: That's the thing.
Speaker 1: Even the main character duck is annoying, except actually it's weird when she's in the form of the animal, the duck, when she's in princess tutu form kicks all ass.
Speaker 1: But when she's in, you know, most of the time she's in normal girl, when she's by herself, it's kind of like with Nana.
Speaker 0: when she's by herself, thinking in her head, she's cool, collected and smart about everything, or at least smart enough.
Speaker 0: And it's like kind of insightful and good.
Speaker 0: And she's okay.
Speaker 0: She's a character when she's talking to other people.
Speaker 0: It's like, just shut up.
Speaker 0: You're annoying.
Speaker 0: I just picture, shut up, shut up, shut up.
Speaker 1: It's like every character shutting up.
Speaker 1: The only character is that I don't want to just shut up.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Are, uh, the weird Dusseldorf guy, Drosselmeyer, Drosselmeyer.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I got to say something there.
Speaker 0: The, the, I catch in the second season that you have is different.
Speaker 0: Not only is it different, but it goes too far.
Speaker 0: It's awesome.
Speaker 0: You know, you don't, you just, I catch you'll like, it'll have like, it'll move.
Speaker 1: because the, I catch in the first season is him spinning around and then taking like a little bow.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: But notice how it's like, there's the first action and then like the second action that ends it.
Speaker 0: It's like action action that ends it.
Speaker 0: And a lot of eye catches are like that.
Speaker 0: The second season I catch it's like, it has too many actions.
Speaker 0: And then when you think, all right, that was too many actions, but now it's done.
Speaker 0: There's one more action.
Speaker 1: Does he just moon you close?
Speaker 0: Basically it's like this cabinet spins around and then the door opens and you see him in there and you're like, okay, that was the action.
Speaker 0: But then he like bow, like steps out and you're like, oh, okay.
Speaker 0: And then he, he raises his glass and smiles, this fucked up smile.
Speaker 0: And it's totally out of pace and rhythm with the rest of it.
Speaker 0: So it's like, I catch, I can't, whoa.
Speaker 0: And it's, and that's the eye catch for the rest of the show.
Speaker 1: Ah, that's pretty scary.
Speaker 1: But yeah.
Speaker 1: And then there's the, uh, the music box lady.
Speaker 1: She's all right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: She's basically, it really feels to me like, um, in antenna, you have the shadow girls and she's like the shadow girl.
Speaker 1: She shows up right before the monster of the week shows up, says something cryptic.
Speaker 1: You listen.
Speaker 1: And basically that's a metaphor for what the episode is about.
Speaker 1: And then you fight the monster of the week.
Speaker 1: Well, you dance with the monster of the week.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Once again, people fight through ballet and you might think, nah, no, that is they, they literally you, it is literal.
Speaker 0: They are fighting through ballet.
Speaker 1: Now this is actually one thing that bothers me with the show, right?
Speaker 1: The show is about ballet.
Speaker 1: Ballet is a huge part of the show, right?
Speaker 1: I want to see more fully animated dancing.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of the dancing is still frame of people in a pose, pan across still frame of them in another pose.
Speaker 0: You actually get a lot more of that as the show goes on.
Speaker 1: I want to see, you know, I really feel like when I'm watching them dance, when the princess two, two shows up, I want to see, you know, fully animated entire dances and not just like animate one move, cut, animate a different move, cut, animate a different move on to see like the whole ballet going on.
Speaker 1: But I didn't get to see much of that in the first disc, or at least not as much as I wanted to.
Speaker 1: And it's a little frustrating watching the dancing scenes that didn't have enough animation going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But you get a lot more of the animation later.
Speaker 1: And one day later on, it really was like an antenna fight as opposed to say a gun.
Speaker 1: I mean, at least in a Gundam fight, they might use stock animation, but at least it's moving all the time.
Speaker 0: But later on, one really cool thing is there's a point at which there are ballet fights and the Raven, basically the Ravens kind of henchmen or the things that fight on the Ravens behalf.
Speaker 1: I know the Ravens coming in.
Speaker 0: Yes, but the Ravens things are basically just people wearing Raven costumes, carrying swords, doing ballet.
Speaker 1: Do they fully animate the dancing to a point?
Speaker 0: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it could be cool.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying it's not cool, but I wanted to see like the whole dance animated.
Speaker 1: Like there was some parts where in the show where they're like, you knew the dances are wicked awesome.
Speaker 1: And they seem to really do a good job of getting across the how well the people are dancing.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I really like you really start to respect Fakir and Rue just by seeing them dance in the real world of the show.
Speaker 1: But I want to see more full animation.
Speaker 1: I guess it would have been too expensive and take it too much.
Speaker 1: I mean, animating people doing ballet like an entire dance, not easy.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, you know, it's sort of like, well, you sort of needed it kind of anyway.
Speaker 0: But I guess we'll kind of wrap this up because I want to get ready to go to the beach and I'm tired.
Speaker 0: But what I mean, we've said all good.
Speaker 0: The only bad thing really about the show is not really bad.
Speaker 0: It's just that the show is great.
Speaker 0: A great show bar.
Speaker 0: none for younger kids.
Speaker 0: This show is so perfect for a younger kid.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, totally.
Speaker 0: But for it and I and to qualify that I also really like the show.
Speaker 0: But if you're looking for, I guess, the Utena depth, it's not there.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this isn't like the highest brow.
Speaker 1: This is like if you're a little kid watching this and maybe like a middle school kid and you watch this, then it's like it's like high brow for middle school kids.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, super awesome for them.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Because it's, you know, it's above their above their level a little bit.
Speaker 1: They can feel smart, but also watch a cool show.
Speaker 1: But for, you know, people in college or older, you know, normal people, adults watching this, it's sort of like, well, it's a little bit straightforward and obvious.
Speaker 0: And yeah, a lot of things you'll think are straightforward.
Speaker 0: But then as you watch the show, you realize you were totally off base.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, a lot of the metaphors and a lot of the kind of messages and a lot of the morals and a lot of that sort of thing are very transparent.
Speaker 0: And if they're not, they're usually explained fairly explicitly at some point, just in case you didn't get it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Pretty much everything is explained explicitly.
Speaker 1: And unless you're, you know, spoiler in, you know, at least I don't think you're going to find out any twists and turns.
Speaker 1: And if you when they do happen, they're going to be explained explicitly.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: But don't let that discourage you.
Speaker 0: The show is worth watching.
Speaker 0: I did enjoy watching the entire show.
Speaker 1: I enjoyed watching the first disc, especially that first episode, because I didn't realize that, you know, she was going to transform into Princess Tutu because I was stupid.
Speaker 1: And that's sort of an obvious thing.
Speaker 1: So when she transformed into Princess Tutu the first time, it was totally awesome.
Speaker 1: And it's the first time like, you know, a transformation in anime, I think, had that full effect going on.
Speaker 0: And I'll say this.
Speaker 0: If you're worried that the show doesn't go anywhere, the show goes real dark.
Speaker 0: Don't worry.
Speaker 0: The show does not go to good places.
Speaker 0: Bad things happen.
Speaker 0: But the other thing is, I generally I would recommend this show to anyone who wants to see something different because this show is very different in a lot of ways from a lot of the other shows you're going to be seeing nowadays.
Speaker 0: It kind of stands out.
Speaker 0: And also, if you're looking for a magical girl show that isn't Sailor Moon, this and Fancy Lala are pretty much where you want to be.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Fancy Lala.
Speaker 1: It's another magical girl show, which it had a similar feel of as a show for kids.
Speaker 1: It's not really deep, but there's enough going on here and it's intelligent enough to be worth watching.
Speaker 1: And it was basically this magical girls that transform.
Speaker 1: But there's this dinosaur plot that is really cool.
Speaker 1: And it's like I didn't.
Speaker 1: I never watched enough Fancy Lala to see what the deal was, but I've always wanted to know what the deal was.
Speaker 0: I'd pretty much say that I think Princess Tutu is a better show than Fancy Lala.
Speaker 0: So if you're going to choose between the two, I don't know how much Fancy Lala you've seen.
Speaker 0: I saw the first like eight episodes of that and I saw all of Princess Tutu.
Speaker 1: See, I've only seen like four episodes of Fancy Lala.
Speaker 0: I want to see more Fancy Lala.
Speaker 0: I'll watch it at some point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I think we're done.
Speaker 0: Don't try to get a hold of us.
Speaker 0: Scott's going to be out of town and I'll be at the beach.
Speaker 0: We'll see you on Tuesday where we're going to talk about tribes two.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: I want to.
Speaker 0: I could talk for like two hours about tribes two right now.
Speaker 0: I think I'll end on this.
Speaker 0: Tyco, God, ending on a non-anime Tyco from Fenny Arcade said it best.
Speaker 1: And he's in the most recent book.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: The case of the Mummy's gold.
Speaker 0: He pretty much said the tribes two accounts for a full 15 percent of his gaming memories.
Speaker 1: I agree.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: For the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share-alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.