Speaker 0: Hey, it's Monday June 30th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm sky, and this is geek night tonight We talk a bit about the purchasing of laptops.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So last week something happened that sucked.
Speaker 0: it sucked a great deal, but I'm like it didn't suck.
Speaker 0: that bad for me.
Speaker 1: It's like lesser me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mainly because I'm on the side of the house that faced this thing more so I had to deal with it.
Speaker 0: But basically we did the show last Thursday, and we're all said I'm real tired, but it's okay I'm gonna go straight to bed, and then the next day We're gonna stay in the city late go see Satoshi khan and all that business which we'll talk about on a Wednesday night.
Speaker 0: And then just as I'm editing the show I hear a crash outside amidst a bunch of fireworks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was in the bathroom, and I heard fireworks go off And I'm like.
Speaker 1: some people think the fourth of July is a little early.
Speaker 1: They couldn't keep it in their closet.
Speaker 1: You know granted when I was a kid, but I was blowing stuff up pretty much from the June In the middle of these fireworks I heard one that was much louder, and I thought it was much closer than the others and I was like huh That's strange.
Speaker 1: Did it like fail - you know the key went up in the air came down and then exploded.
Speaker 0: What was up now meanwhile, but I didn't think anything more of it because I was in my room with the window open.
Speaker 0: I heard a very dear.
Speaker 0: I heard an explosion Followed by holy shit.
Speaker 0: what happened to that pole?
Speaker 0: ah And these guys cuz you know we have a car dealership across the street And there's these punk kids who work there overnight like they wash the cars and they work on them.
Speaker 0: And we figured out in the course of all this How they deal with their overnight job.
Speaker 0: because as we were walking over to inspect what befell We saw there's seven cases of corona that they were loading in obviously to replace their previous seven cases of corona.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so I'm sitting there and Scott walks in my room is like what was that noise?
Speaker 1: I didn't ask what that was that noise.
Speaker 1: I was in my room because I thought nothing of it.
Speaker 1: you came and told me what was going on anyway.
Speaker 0: So I hear holy shit look at that pole.
Speaker 0: It's gonna fall over.
Speaker 0: Oh, no what happened?
Speaker 0: I don't know when these guys are like what happened.
Speaker 0: I'm looking out the window and sure enough the pole the utility pole down the street is basically Held up by the other two poles adjacent to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, other people might you know live in places the world where they don't have telephone poles like see when I grew up basically, we live in New England, which is the oldest part of the United States and You know telephones are sort of invented.
Speaker 1: well at least they may.
Speaker 1: you know someone else might have invented them.
Speaker 1: besides What a telephone pole is I don't know some people they might only have underground telephone where they live.
Speaker 0: granted where I grew up There were no the only telephone poles that weren't underground where the high-tension power lines yep.
Speaker 1: But now we have pieces of wood that are all along the side of the street with wires going from one to the other.
Speaker 0: and actually I feel like I could do a short show about because a lot of you it's actually very regimented how Utility poles put together and the best way to explain it electricity at the top.
Speaker 0: the more dangerous something is the higher up It is.
Speaker 1: yes because that way the telephone guy doesn't have to get anywhere near the electricity because he'll die.
Speaker 1: But the electricity guy cuz he's so badass.
Speaker 1: You know he can go past the telephone.
Speaker 0: He doesn't give a shit, but actually the details of how all that works is pretty fascinating.
Speaker 0: and also There's an unrelated issue.
Speaker 0: that it's kind of related because it's the reason the pole basically shattered.
Speaker 1: as opposed to Taking the car they use a certain kind of wood.
Speaker 0: well now It's more that the put.
Speaker 0: the average age of a utility pole in the United States is ludicrous.
Speaker 0: most of them were put up in The 70s and haven't been touched since.
Speaker 1: well cuz even works don't touch it.
Speaker 0: But the thing is they don't work anymore because they were designed to do power and Telephone.
Speaker 1: and now you look at a telephone pole And it left power on the one at the end of ours at the one at the end of our street Which is adjacent to the one that broke.
Speaker 1: God is ludicrous.
Speaker 0: We should take a picture of that thing and upload it.
Speaker 0: just you guys like it look at some sort of monster.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 0: but basically you look and there's the three phase like power and then the little phone.
Speaker 0: And then there's a million gigantic data cables like dragging all these things down And amount these things.
Speaker 0: they use bolts and screws and they grow into the wood and as a result They've weakened the wood the telephone pole infrastructure in the United States is on the verge of collapse.
Speaker 1: How is that any different from any of the other infrastructure in the United States?
Speaker 0: Because a lot of the other infrastructures are still being maintained much more readily than these poles are I
Speaker 1: guess but not much
Speaker 0: Actually, no these I think that the telephone pole infrastructure in the US and as an extension the power distribution grid in the US Are the most critical infrastructural problems we have today.
Speaker 1: It's one of.
Speaker 0: but what's worse than that?
Speaker 0: What's the worst set of infrastructure?
Speaker 0: a lesser maintained more poorly put together?
Speaker 0: More prone to failure more likely to fuck us?
Speaker 1: bridges.
Speaker 0: bridges are doing fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only bridges that are all the bridges are old because they never knock them down and rebuild them So they're all busted.
Speaker 0: Oh, they're not.
Speaker 0: actually the only bridges that are having trouble are the white stone and the frogs neck because they're the same damn Bridge, it was a shitty design when they made it in the first place.
Speaker 1: They're like three or four bridges that are messed up.
Speaker 0: Which what bridges they're doing fine.
Speaker 1: It's like the shitty bridge up in Poughkeepsie.
Speaker 1: Which one you know?
Speaker 1: the one that goes across the the Hudson up in Poughkeepsie.
Speaker 1: So I got like two lanes.
Speaker 0: you mean the mid Hudson bridge has four lanes.
Speaker 1: No, I'm pretty sure this is it.
Speaker 1: There's a really tiny scary one.
Speaker 1: No, there is doesn't have a dividing in the middle.
Speaker 0: Are you talking about the bridge way further north that you've never driven on?
Speaker 1: No, I've driven on this bridge.
Speaker 0: Okay, I don't know what you're talking about them.
Speaker 0: anyway, it's fine.
Speaker 0: It's also in perfect working order and it's not that old.
Speaker 1: There's that bridge that collapsed out west a bit a while ago, which bridges?
Speaker 1: this you don't remember.
Speaker 1: There's a huge.
Speaker 1: You're saying the name of the bridge.
Speaker 1: yeah, this is it over.
Speaker 1: there was also a galloping gurney Decades ago.
Speaker 1: how many times millenniums got?
Speaker 0: how many colors that are not gray are in the video of the of that bridge - Dark brownish and sort of whitish.
Speaker 0: regardless as a as an IT Professional it is my opinion that the power distribution infrastructure in the United States and by extension the data Distribution infrastructure is the most prone to failure and most dangerous thing.
Speaker 0: We've got going right now.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so Basically, this thing's being held up and the poles and other side of it are kind of drooped in a little bit and you look And then right as we see oh, there's a car there.
Speaker 0: I hear the guys outside go.
Speaker 0: Holy shit.
Speaker 0: There's a car.
Speaker 0: it stuck to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some guy crashed his car in a telephone pole this punk kid and he wasn't drunk.
Speaker 0: I saw him do the sobriety test.
Speaker 0: He was just stupid.
Speaker 0: He ran into this thing.
Speaker 0: I didn't just run into this pole at the speed limits like 25 there.
Speaker 0: He ran into this pole fast enough to shatter it and to deploy his airbags and completely ruin his car.
Speaker 0: Yep, he was fine, though He was fine But the front of an end of his car was completely smashed.
Speaker 0: fluid was dripping out all over the place.
Speaker 0: car wouldn't start.
Speaker 0: it was.
Speaker 1: Luckily, he crashed right on top of the drain in the streets.
Speaker 1: All the fluid went down the drain instead of covering the street making it slippery for the next guy.
Speaker 0: So of course Scott and I walk out and we're standing there kind of sniggering.
Speaker 1: There's sort of rubber necking.
Speaker 1: only we don't have a car to rubberneck out because they're walking.
Speaker 0: Our conversation is along the lines of what a dumbass.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, here come his parents.
Speaker 0: They don't look happy.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, here come police.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, here come the fireman The fireman.
Speaker 0: but then part of the discussion was wait a minute.
Speaker 0: If then if that pole gives way the power line is gonna fall right on us.
Speaker 0: Let's stand somewhere else.
Speaker 1: We stood somewhere else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we're like, ah, we kind of back away walk around and we're watching and one cop car shows up Yells at the kid another cop car shows up now.
Speaker 0: The the real problem here is that This is the only non freeway East-west road basically in Dutchess County.
Speaker 1: Yeah There's this.
Speaker 1: basically there's a lot of places people want to go that the only way they can get there is by driving on this Road past our house.
Speaker 0: There are only two roads that go east-west interstate 84 and Route 52 that goes past our house.
Speaker 1: It's also 90.
Speaker 0: Not really.
Speaker 0: that goes north-south Scott.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you can you can sort of you know, take 90, you know if you want to Parallel to 52 for quite a bit.
Speaker 1: Not really.
Speaker 1: Yeah You can say if you go on the prison road, you can take nine.
Speaker 0: Yes, you can go north not east or west on 90 but it's parallel to 52. actually No, it isn't.
Speaker 0: then you get on that other road 60 Whatever that goes at a looping angle around and then meets up with 52 it dead.
Speaker 1: But you you can take it as a detour.
Speaker 0: Anyway, my statement.
Speaker 0: it's the only east-west roads in the area Sands.
Speaker 0: because you said no if you go way out of your way, you can take that north-south road.
Speaker 1: No, it's a detour.
Speaker 0: So it's not a east-west road.
Speaker 1: You can use it to get farther westward.
Speaker 0: Yes, you can all right anyway, well no you have to use the other road.
Speaker 0: It doesn't go east at all or west.
Speaker 0: you have to get on that other road.
Speaker 0: Anyway, regardless there is no way like whenever there's an accident on i-84 Basically, it is impossible to go east or west in this area for like four hours.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's not really a good situation.
Speaker 1: they're very few major roads.
Speaker 1: There's lots of side roads But the major roads are few in number and the reason there's extremely limited number of ways to get from any location to any other Given location is actually only one reason for this and the reason is nimby's and bananas.
Speaker 1: pretty much.
Speaker 0: We need to build more roads around here.
Speaker 0: We definitely do Someone's down houses down at which yes, we have to buy their houses knock them down.
Speaker 0: build another road.
Speaker 0: It will be.
Speaker 1: it's the only way we can do it.
Speaker 0: Alright basically the end result of this and this this is a topic that has often angered me.
Speaker 0: It angers me less now that I don't drive to the Bronx every day But basically because one dumb kid drove stupidly and crashed on a road.
Speaker 0: The number of people that were inconvenienced and the thousands upon thousands was probably well over $10,000 in damages to the city of beacon and all these delays and all this craziness.
Speaker 0: and It's very difficult to get any of that money out of the kid who made a stupid mistake.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean he has to pay for you know a new car.
Speaker 1: Maybe his car insurance premiums.
Speaker 0: He's definitely gonna get a ticket.
Speaker 1: He's gonna get some sort of ticket and whatever but you can't sue him for the actual damage caused.
Speaker 1: I mean like let's say I crash my car.
Speaker 1: I mean the George Washington Bridge, right?
Speaker 1: Okay, so, you know, there's the damage to my car.
Speaker 1: There's the damage to the guy I hit which they can make me pay for.
Speaker 1: Right, there's.
Speaker 1: maybe I'll damage the bridge a little bit Maybe I'll scrape it up Right, but think about the traffic that causes of all the time of all the people that is now lost because I screwed up.
Speaker 1: No one pays for that time.
Speaker 1: Those people are just fucked.
Speaker 1: There should be a way to force that person to pay for that time.
Speaker 1: but no one could afford that time except Bill Gates.
Speaker 1: because think about that you're wasting an hour of the time of Thousands of people.
Speaker 1: an hour times thousands of people.
Speaker 1: that's millions of dollars I mean.
Speaker 0: and the worst thing is if it was the middle of the night It's like 1130. and yet the amount of traffic that got backed up by this thing right away.
Speaker 0: Well, when I'm ready, the only reason it was okay is because you could take it.
Speaker 0: The accident was in the perfect place.
Speaker 0: You could take the little detour around past our house to get around it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is when I woke up in the morning, right?
Speaker 1: They were stay had a new pole in the ground But they were still moving the wires from the old pole to the new pole.
Speaker 1: it was actually I was kind of envious of those guys because they got to wake up in the middle of the night which Sucks and then work on this pole pretty much non-stop until it was done, but it was a Friday.
Speaker 1: So as soon as they finished it They got to go home and probably didn't have to work at all and they got paid mad overtime.
Speaker 0: So I was like, oh you asshole the part that sucks and the reason I say all this sucks is alright.
Speaker 0: So I'm we find I upload the show and I know the power is gonna have to go out while they fix this at some Point and it's balls hot out real hot.
Speaker 0: So I decide alright, I'm not gonna bother with the AC I'm gonna turn everything off.
Speaker 0: Leave my windows open leave the fan out as long as I can and go to sleep.
Speaker 0: So I lay in bed.
Speaker 0: Bang crash guy yelling bang crash guy yelling bang crash guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't have that problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well because my windows basically are facing directly at all the business.
Speaker 1: I had my windows closed to my AC on.
Speaker 0: yes I didn't do that.
Speaker 1: Why didn't you?
Speaker 0: because the power is gonna go out.
Speaker 1: Then you can get build up some AC.
Speaker 0: see but that wasn't gonna work.
Speaker 1: it worked for me.
Speaker 0: now, it's alright.
Speaker 0: anyway Some are damaged.
Speaker 0: I closed my windows and turn on the AC and I said as cold as I can.
Speaker 0: So the room gets through about 65 degrees.
Speaker 0: That's a little too cold because I figured that'll hold me over all night And that's fine.
Speaker 0: I was actually very comfortable all night Because even after the power went out The room stayed cool and it warmed up gradually and then I woke up and went to work and the power was still out.
Speaker 0: Problem is the power went out.
Speaker 0: my AC turns off which wakes me up.
Speaker 0: I'm ready to go back to sleep But then I hear the baby of Scott's UPS cuz he didn't turn it.
Speaker 0: also the one in the hallway and the one in the Hallway, cuz again Scott didn't turn it off.
Speaker 1: Why am I?
Speaker 1: the one has to throw the one in the hall next year bedroom?
Speaker 1: That doesn't mean anything.
Speaker 0: I just ignored it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I took care of it.
Speaker 0: Say I woke it up all these times.
Speaker 0: then I had to go to work then I stayed out all night.
Speaker 0: I was so exhausted Friday night All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see I woke up.
Speaker 1: the only trouble it caused me because the power was on when I woke up but I think it killed the DNS server, which is sad because we had all these computer parts enough to technically build three or four computers and We only managed to build one computer and now it doesn't even work.
Speaker 1: We have all these computer parts and zero working computers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what sucked was when I woke up the power was still out So I had to shave and shower in the morning without any lights.
Speaker 1: See I woke up.
Speaker 1: the power was on but I had to get all these computers back in business as much as I could.
Speaker 0: Right bother.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I did, you know check my emails.
Speaker 0: Don't just go to work and check it.
Speaker 0: use your phone or something.
Speaker 0: Good guy.
Speaker 1: My phone doesn't do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah And then when I tried to get out of the driveway, there was a lineup of cars taking the detour But I managed to squeeze out and go to the train.
Speaker 1: luckily very luckily But yeah, it was.
Speaker 1: the detour is pretty backed up because it was getting towards, you know Daytime rush hour about then and they were still working on the pole and the road was still completely closed.
Speaker 1: It was fixed when I got home though, and now all is well.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that's all we got.
Speaker 0: So, uh What do you have in tech news?
Speaker 1: so check this out, right There's a lot of places on the Internet's to legally purchase the digital music.
Speaker 1: Right, you got your iTunes with its drm's that were used.
Speaker 1: they sell you individual songs.
Speaker 1: You got your your Napster.
Speaker 1: You know what bought the name Napster, but isn't really Napster is you know, Amazon mp3 store Which is actually not so bad, but the price is still too high for me.
Speaker 1: And now the Rhapsody.
Speaker 1: now the Rhapsody.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: a lot of people know about the Rhapsody.
Speaker 1: I don't know how popular it is.
Speaker 1: It basically works it has DRM and it works with like a lot of these, you know Microsoft Kind of crappy mp3 players like the cheap ones you see in the store.
Speaker 1: But the way it works is you actually you pay a flat fee Monthly and you can download as much music as you want and this mad DRM on it.
Speaker 1: So you can only play it on, you know DRM players.
Speaker 1: But there's a hell of a lot of music in there.
Speaker 1: like holy shit, and these Rhapsody people they decided All right Here's what we're gonna do and do what everyone else is doing and take out our DRM.
Speaker 1: and when I read that headline Rhapsody Removes DRM.
Speaker 1: I'm like, I'm signing up I'm gonna sign up and download as much music as I want without DRM for a monthly fee.
Speaker 1: Holy shit Holy shit, and I read onwards.
Speaker 0: Because think about it for one the only.
Speaker 0: I mean we use the Roku for Netflix a whole bunch and it is super DRM.
Speaker 0: But I don't care because I want to watch a movie.
Speaker 0: I It's not like.
Speaker 0: they pretend that they're selling me a movie and then they charge me a bunch of money.
Speaker 0: They charge me almost nothing and I'm clearly renting the movie.
Speaker 0: So it works out.
Speaker 0: but music was tougher because with the DRM.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it's with music.
Speaker 1: with a movie.
Speaker 1: I'm fine having the movie, you know, not so portable with music.
Speaker 1: I need to be able to copy it all over the place I gotta be able to bring it on my laptop and my iPod and I need to be able to mix it into a movie.
Speaker 0: If I want to make a movie, I gotta be able to make excerpts of it for the show whenever it comes up.
Speaker 1: Yep anyway, so I go and I'm like, I'm totally gonna do this and I look and Disappointment, but of course, I guess it was expected They're keeping their subscription service.
Speaker 1: if with the DRM if you don't do the DRM They're selling the music individually by the song or by the album Just like everyone else is basically no different than the Amazon mp3 store.
Speaker 1: And if I'm gonna do one of these where you buy the music individually, I'm gonna do the Amazon mp3 store.
Speaker 1: Why should I bother with this Rhapsody?
Speaker 1: Bullshit thing when the Amazon mp3 store is the same and has you know more music that I want and also doesn't have DRM And works with Amazon which I use a lot anyway And I can actually get like 10% off if I sneak around at the Amazon affiliates program and shit.
Speaker 0: Ah the Amazon affiliates program Amazon associates, but so Really?
Speaker 1: What are they thinking?
Speaker 1: and how come?
Speaker 1: it's obvious?
Speaker 1: I mean if you made a subscription music service just like the Netflix of music where Oh Download as many know that everyone everyone in the universe would sign up everyone who makes Knows this.
Speaker 0: it's it's common knowledge.
Speaker 0: They know exactly what would work very well.
Speaker 0: It would make a ton of money.
Speaker 0: What would be perfect?
Speaker 0: the people that won't let it happen are the record labels and the artists?
Speaker 1: I think there's some artists who wouldn't mind.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but by and large it's the And the record labels who the artists sign their rights away to.
Speaker 1: I think about this you sign into iTunes, right?
Speaker 1: And there's that front page that's like hot new music.
Speaker 1: check these people out, right?
Speaker 1: But it all costs money.
Speaker 1: so you don't really click on any of that shit, right?
Speaker 1: Imagine it was a subscription service.
Speaker 1: download all you want.
Speaker 1: I'll just try everything on the front page and then artists would be paying a hell of a lot of money to get them on The front page because pretty much everyone would download and listen to them and then their concerts to be sold out if they were any Good,
Speaker 0: but who doesn't make money off of this game?
Speaker 0: the record label and record label just needs to die.
Speaker 1: Yes, I think that's made clear.
Speaker 1: And actually I read this really great article today.
Speaker 1: I just remembered.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna link to it.
Speaker 1: basically the.
Speaker 1: What he says in this article right is that there's sort of this common perception right that you that Technology is moving so fast.
Speaker 1: The business can't keep up with it, right?
Speaker 1: He's like that's complete bullshit.
Speaker 1: That's like saying all these snails.
Speaker 1: They're going too fast for us.
Speaker 1: Napster came around before the year 2000 not and music record companies still haven't changed now.
Speaker 0: 2000 doesn't seem that long ago.
Speaker 0: That was eight years ago.
Speaker 1: These people have had between five and fifteen years and actually deal with the Internet and all of the other Technological consequences was when Napster died.
Speaker 0: now when it started they have had eight years.
Speaker 1: the music companies TV Everyone who is getting all the businesses that are getting destroyed because technology has made them obsolete.
Speaker 1: These companies have had forever to do something about it to change in some way And not one has managed to do anything about it.
Speaker 1: Not one.
Speaker 1: the technology sure It's moving pretty fast compared, you know in a historical perspective, but it is not moving so fast.
Speaker 1: You can't adapt to it.
Speaker 1: That is a ludicrous ludicrous idea.
Speaker 1: Well, it has taken years for these things to happen.
Speaker 1: You know, even if it only took months months is plenty of time But years.
Speaker 1: you had eight years since the death of Napster to do something to fix music and they haven't done shit.
Speaker 1: They can't be blaming.
Speaker 1: the technology moves too fast.
Speaker 1: Their business is slower than a snail.
Speaker 1: Well is all their fault?
Speaker 0: speaking of come the one company that does get it.
Speaker 0: I Remember a while ago Netflix announced famously that they're just.
Speaker 0: they didn't really announce.
Speaker 0: They just kind of emailed all their subscribers and said hey less than 1% of you use profiles.
Speaker 0: So we're just gonna get rid of them and That's the end of that.
Speaker 0: and we're done.
Speaker 0: That's all we're saying about it.
Speaker 0: And of course the internet lost its shit about this.
Speaker 1: Well, let me for people who don't use Netflix.
Speaker 1: Let me explain right?
Speaker 1: so Netflix is basically automatic DVD rental.
Speaker 1: They if you buy if you let's say you choose you want a two DVD plan, right?
Speaker 1: So you go on the website you pick DVDs out and you put them in a queue.
Speaker 1: It's the order you want to get that.
Speaker 1: you want to watch the movies in.
Speaker 1: They mail you the movies you mail them back when you're done and every time you mail one back They send you another one.
Speaker 1: So a two DVD plan means you will have two DVDs in your possession at once and when you mail one back you get one Back, you know the one thing when I first got onto Netflix and I noticed right away.
Speaker 0: Alright, I have three DVDs.
Speaker 0: I want to have a DVD dedicated to anime a DVD dedicated TV shows like Seinfeld and a DVD dedicated to movies.
Speaker 0: and Netflix said Oh, you can't do that.
Speaker 0: And I said hey, but then my friend Scott Johnson said, oh well You have to make a separate profile for each person and make up some people.
Speaker 0: So yes See the idea I made up anime McAnime and TV show McTV.
Speaker 1: Yes, see the idea behind the profiles feature right?
Speaker 1: is that?
Speaker 1: let's say you're a family.
Speaker 1: you have mommy daddy and two kids.
Speaker 1: You're a perfect American family.
Speaker 1: How nice.
Speaker 1: you would buy a four disc plan and each person would have their own Netflix account But you only pay for one plan and that way each person Manages their own cue for their one DVD separately.
Speaker 1: The thing is they didn't anticipate, you know.
Speaker 1: And they still apparently don't understand that if one person has more than one disc Even they want one account one login, but they want separate cues for each disc.
Speaker 1: It just makes sense.
Speaker 1: I don't want to have one.
Speaker 1: I mean if I have one cue right just one list and I put I want Seinfeld season four.
Speaker 1: That's like, you know, how many discs right?
Speaker 1: I don't want three discs of that at once.
Speaker 1: I had to watch one then watch the other then watch the.
Speaker 1: it doesn't help me.
Speaker 1: I need I might as well just get one disc at that point.
Speaker 1: I want three separate discs.
Speaker 1: that way I can have you know a movie a disc of Seinfeld and An anime, you know show at the same time.
Speaker 1: So that way I can watch some anime when I feel like it.
Speaker 1: when I send an anime back I get an anime bag.
Speaker 1: That's what I want.
Speaker 1: but the only way that's possible in Netflix is to make up fake people and pretend you're a Family with an anime watching kid a Seinfeld watching person and a movie watching person, but Netflix.
Speaker 0: What I thought was beautiful about this debacle was that they said and they kept saying less than 1% of our users use it.
Speaker 0: I think it was noted on Fark and slash dot and dig that well I guess that entire 1% is everyone on Fark slash dot and dig.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much Either either.
Speaker 1: Netflix has an extraordinary Number of customers.
Speaker 1: to end the vocal Netflix customers on the internet are only 1% of their total customer base Which is I guess could be possible.
Speaker 0: Well, we got lying.
Speaker 0: See the thing is we got the answer to this quite clearly because I got an email from Netflix today and it says and I quote We are keeping Netflix profiles.
Speaker 0: dear Brandon you've spoken we listened.
Speaker 0: we are keeping profiles.
Speaker 0: Thank you for all the calls and emails telling us how important profiles are.
Speaker 0: We are sorry for any inconvenience We have caused.
Speaker 0: we hope the next time you hear from us.
Speaker 0: We will delight and not disappoint you Your friends at Netflix.
Speaker 0: now one.
Speaker 0: this tells me that they were lying about the 1% because they wouldn't do this unless they had taken a hit and two.
Speaker 0: it proves that when Geeks can they vote with their wallets because I remember when they announced this I didn't notice until Scott Johnson said Oh my god, and then I looked and sure enough.
Speaker 0: They'd cut our way profiles.
Speaker 0: I called Netflix immediately and I when I picked up they didn't say, you know, huh Netflix, how can I help you?
Speaker 0: They said are you calling about profiles?
Speaker 0: And I said is there anything I can do to keep my profiles?
Speaker 0: and they said no.
Speaker 0: and I said the only reason I'm not Roku.
Speaker 0: what's the cheapest plan I can get and still use my Roku?
Speaker 0: I want that plan.
Speaker 0: and they said fine It's $8.99 one DVD unlimited.
Speaker 0: It'll be effective.
Speaker 1: even to fight with you retention didn't even come play into it.
Speaker 1: They just said let's get this over with.
Speaker 1: I got like a hundred calls about the profiles after you kids.
Speaker 0: Yep now and For what I gather pretty much everyone called and either canceled their Netflix or dropped to the cheapest plan They could be which was one.
Speaker 1: because if you only have one disc and one profile, then it's okay You don't have a problem.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess if I have two discs, I need two cues.
Speaker 0: I guess if you're unemployed or something Then you could deal with having like four DVDs in one cue because you don't care you're gonna watch them all immediately.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah Netflix.
Speaker 1: really though I mean the profiles are good because there are plenty of people who have a Household of multiple human beings and what they want one Netflix account one Netflix bill and multiple people to have one cue each.
Speaker 1: That makes sense.
Speaker 1: However, there are also people out there who are a single human being yet They want multiple DVDs at a time and they need to add the feature where you can have multiple cues in one profile.
Speaker 0: the thing is I get the impression that what a lot of people do and I saw a lot of people saying this on The internet when other people complained and I'm going to paraphrase all of their responses into one made-up post that I'm going to quote now Thus constructing the perfect straw man to that argue against
Speaker 1: alrighty.
Speaker 0: I don't know why you people are so mad about this.
Speaker 0: I mean, seriously, I have four DVDs and you know what.
Speaker 0: every time I send a DVD back I just go to the queue and rearrange everything.
Speaker 0: so it works and you know what.
Speaker 0: the only reason I use I'm not quoting my Straw man anymore The only reason I use Netflix because I don't have to do that.
Speaker 0: if I had to do that I wouldn't be using Netflix.
Speaker 1: time is yeah.
Speaker 1: If I was doing that I just go to blockbuster and pick out a movie every time.
Speaker 0: in fact I would probably get the blockbuster plan because then I can just go to the blockbuster and get video games And get whatever thing I want.
Speaker 0: I only use Netflix because it requires zero effort.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just want to set up these cues and then if I ever think of a movie or if I notice a movie I just add it to the queue not even think about it and just DVDs come in the mail without having to think and that Is why Netflix is great?
Speaker 1: So having one cue and having to constantly finagle the cue to get it in the right order because that's a really good word Multiple discs.
Speaker 1: That's one of my favorite words Defeats the purpose of having Netflix and there's no reason to pay for something like that because it'd be actually take less time.
Speaker 1: Just go to blockbuster Like on the way home from work or something.
Speaker 0: But anyway Netflix Realize this.
Speaker 1: I still think if we're strong enough to get Netflix to bring back the feature We can force them to add the next fee.
Speaker 0: Well, well, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: Here's the rub Netflix fucked up.
Speaker 0: We had four DVDs come into this house and because we're busy all the time partly We used to use all those DVDs, but then you know, we started doing geek nights and we stopped watching movies.
Speaker 0: We kept all the DVDs.
Speaker 0: tonight Anime cue that I was using because I watch stuff on the train and the movie cue pretty much didn't get used anymore.
Speaker 0: but one of the cues Emily used one of the cues was like the Simpsons and whatever cue.
Speaker 0: but When Netflix fucked us and I dropped to one cue I noticed that wait a minute.
Speaker 0: every TV show I can watch free online now, except Seinfeld.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got the Hulu.com action going on Is not bad as distasteful and corporate as it is.
Speaker 1: the ads are short and tasteful and the content is plentiful.
Speaker 0: So I use that for all the you know, old TV shows and new TV shows.
Speaker 0: I want to watch like The Daily Show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I use South Park their website to watch South Park.
Speaker 1: I use College Humor YouTube Angry video game.
Speaker 1: nerd, you know, I'll see.
Speaker 1: ya get the the zero punctuation.
Speaker 1: There's plenty of videos on the Internet's to entertain now that we have a computer.
Speaker 0: basically the TV Netflix did is make me realize that I only need one or at most two cues.
Speaker 0: So they're not gonna get my business back.
Speaker 0: they basically just screwed themselves out of my money.
Speaker 0: and I think I'm not the only one because Like I was isn't a fast karate.
Speaker 0: and he was talking about how awesome his Roku is.
Speaker 0: and I think the Roku is the future.
Speaker 0: and I think Netflix kind of made a bad move here because a lot of people are Probably not going to get their cues back because they're gonna realize how little they use them.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing.
Speaker 1: check this out.
Speaker 1: You're ready in a way.
Speaker 1: It's not a bad move for Netflix.
Speaker 0: And here's why Oh, yeah, they're all I agree with.
Speaker 0: I think I know what you're gonna say here.
Speaker 0: Let's see if I was gonna say the same thing.
Speaker 0: you were gonna say It's a lot cheaper to stream shitty movies to people than to mail good physical movies to people.
Speaker 1: and they're paying the same Subscription price And they're paying $100 for a box They're probably profiting.
Speaker 1: that box is maybe maybe like 25 bucks of electronics.
Speaker 1: Maybe at the most.
Speaker 0: Yeah Look at the movies in there.
Speaker 0: I mean, what did they just add in the last couple?
Speaker 1: all the troma films which suck.
Speaker 0: We actually watched Teenage Cat.
Speaker 1: No, I don't call that watching.
Speaker 1: we skimmed.
Speaker 1: we we all right.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you land stat it to see what the deal was.
Speaker 0: teenage cat girls in heat was one of those movies.
Speaker 0: That was awesome in the kind of I remember the title like that.
Speaker 1: How can it not be infamous?
Speaker 0: We did I remember we were told it existed and did not believe that it was real.
Speaker 0: until we saw the DVD at video bar We laughed hysterically and decided that we weren't going to get it for obvious reasons.
Speaker 0: Yep, but now Netflix on demand.
Speaker 0: it cost us nothing but our time.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute.
Speaker 0: I said a little while ago that my time is my most valuable commodity and what do I do?
Speaker 0: Piss it away on teenage cat girls in heat immediately.
Speaker 1: Well, we fast-forwarded through it So it.
Speaker 1: we didn't really waste that more time than it was worth that movie.
Speaker 0: not enough cat girls not enough.
Speaker 1: Well, there were no cat girls.
Speaker 1: They were cast.
Speaker 1: that turned into non cat girls Yes, which was disappointing.
Speaker 1: at least put some ears on them.
Speaker 1: or like a you know, leopard print You know loincloth, but to not enough heat.
Speaker 0: three mostly about these two really stupid guys.
Speaker 1: It was one of those typical late-night not Cinemax cable movies where it's pretty much You know teenage boys watching go.
Speaker 1: Oh man.
Speaker 1: Oh man, there's gonna be action and there's never any action.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: You're better off watching our MD guys He's better off watching skin of X because there'll be some action.
Speaker 0: MD guys is the most dangerous, but he is not a doctor.
Speaker 1: No All right.
Speaker 0: All right, you know, I feel like I should talk about this.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna I'm not gonna actually talk about it.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna bring it up.
Speaker 0: all this business with Unlimited, you know flat top-level domains anyone can pay for a top-level domain.
Speaker 0: That is possibly the dumbest thing that I cannot express to you from a techno Technological standpoint as an IT professional Someone who has paid a lot of money to sit there and tell other people what I think about technology.
Speaker 0: It is such a bad idea.
Speaker 0: I'm not even gonna say why.
Speaker 0: I just want to get my opinion out there and be done with it.
Speaker 0: And don't even get me started on internationalizing the domain names with like Russian and Cyrillic and Japanese characters.
Speaker 0: Ah Anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: the the fact that this is on gizmodo is Pretty much entirely made up for by what it is.
Speaker 0: I really wouldn't link to gizmodo if it weren't totally awesome Because they're kind of just classless and I really don't enjoy them.
Speaker 0: But anyway Lego has a vault of almost every Lego product they've ever made Unopened and this video shows you all of it and the reason.
Speaker 0: you know the reasons they keep the vault, you know copyright and trademarks and patents and you know Also for museum purposes and archives and whatever.
Speaker 0: The coolest thing is that you'll watch this video and you're gonna see all these things things that you had played with in your youth or saw other kids play with.
Speaker 0: the nostalgia factor is Painful, it's super painful.
Speaker 1: Especially of course the guy goes right for the best possible sets.
Speaker 0: He's like the original yellow castle the better castle that came later the pirates the spacemen the monorail.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because you know you all wanted the monorail and none of your parents would buy it for you.
Speaker 0: Maybe there was that rich kid down the street who had the monorail, but he never let you play with it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know the yellow castle as nostalgic and cool as it is.
Speaker 1: I much prefer the castle that comes after it the the black knight the castle that came before.
Speaker 1: that he shows.
Speaker 1: He shows it for like a second.
Speaker 1: I never had that castle, but I wanted it badly, but it was a hundred dollars which in those days was crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the model Lego sets now are like more than a hundred hours.
Speaker 0: The monorail was a hundred and twenty dollars.
Speaker 0: I wanted it desperately.
Speaker 0: It was on every Christmas list when I was a kid and my parents, you know Santa Claus never brought no the biggest Lego sets like I were like these $60 ones I never ever ever got.
Speaker 0: the biggest one ever got was at the end.
Speaker 0: But the last Lego I ever got with my own money my own money meaning my allowance I bought the space shuttle.
Speaker 1: yet in aggregate if you added my Legos together I could have had three of those giant castles.
Speaker 1: I would have traded all my Legos for three giant castles.
Speaker 0: You realize you guys are so lucky that our Legos are not here because gig knives would end and I would be playing with my Legos every other night.
Speaker 1: I guess you can make Lego videos.
Speaker 0: We just turned into the Lego show.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Is there a Lego podcast?
Speaker 0: it needs to be I really want to play with like someone.
Speaker 1: get on that.
Speaker 1: All right, so There have been audio files before.
Speaker 1: I'm worried about what you're gonna bring up, you know people who say oh, yes, if you use this wooden volume knob It will cancel the evil vibrations your music will sound better.
Speaker 0: I remember reading a journal about some audio files and they were completely.
Speaker 0: they had this.
Speaker 0: it was like a blog and they were talking About ah this room.
Speaker 0: like we had this problem one day.
Speaker 0: the craziest thing and you know We we were doing audio tests and this one stereo sounded great.
Speaker 0: Then we went to get lunch and we came back and it sounded like shit.
Speaker 0: We couldn't figure out why and blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: and then we figured out that Joe had spilled a little bit of coffee on the Coffee table and that was ruining the sound and we got the coffee table out and replaced it with a different table.
Speaker 0: It sounded great again.
Speaker 0: So watch where you spill stuff.
Speaker 0: And I remember my brain wanted to jump out of my eyeballs and kill itself.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: So this is perhaps the worst audiophile offending product ever.
Speaker 0: Right, even what you're bringing up here.
Speaker 1: There is the $1,200 power cable.
Speaker 1: That was pretty offensive.
Speaker 1: Actually, I say this is equally offensive.
Speaker 1: Here we have the for all the five hundred and one dollar Ethernet cable.
Speaker 0: now, I'm probably.
Speaker 0: this is ripped off almost shamelessly from Lewis black, but it's digital.
Speaker 0: It's digital.
Speaker 0: It can't change.
Speaker 1: I can't have any effect.
Speaker 1: a $2.00 network cable That was like Lewis black but then Gilbert Godfrey stuck his way On Amazon, it's only four hundred and seventy-five dollars.
Speaker 0: Oh the Amazon discount.
Speaker 0: Yeah, how it's worth it.
Speaker 1: Yeah suddenly, right?
Speaker 1: It's just a network cable with some fancy stuff around it.
Speaker 0: It's cat four thousand e.
Speaker 1: yeah The reason this is a thing of the day, right?
Speaker 1: It's not because I want to you to buy this thing or not just to warn you not to buy because if you're a geek That's listener.
Speaker 1: I hope you're smart enough not to buy this.
Speaker 0: if you're not well email me because we have to talk.
Speaker 0: I got some other products that might be up your alley.
Speaker 1: Yeah lobotomy home kit.
Speaker 0: It's called.
Speaker 0: it's called an ice pick and a poor understanding of science.
Speaker 1: I've got also a What's the word for making sterilization kits?
Speaker 0: It's called an ice pick and a very good understanding of science.
Speaker 1: All right So this is actually a Dean on a KDL one dedicated link cable.
Speaker 1: Do not buy any product by Dean on.
Speaker 1: I do not.
Speaker 1: if it says Dean on on it don't buy it now.
Speaker 1: The reason I'm linking to this as I was about to tell you I'm gonna tell you right now is because an Amazon.
Speaker 1: Amazon not only sells products at a good price They allow customers to review products And of course, you know, you might expect there to be stupid customer reviews of audio files saying Oh, I use this network cable on my audio equipment.
Speaker 1: Oh, it sounds so great.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: This is totally worth the $500.
Speaker 1: You're wrong.
Speaker 1: You might be expecting to see Customer reviews from people like myself saying wow anyone who buys this is a complete idiot.
Speaker 1: Why are you spending four hundred eighty dollars in something?
Speaker 1: That's no better than something for them like a piece of copper wire from home from Radio Shack.
Speaker 0: What Scott do we see?
Speaker 1: Let me let me read you once.
Speaker 0: What do you see?
Speaker 1: Let me read you the first sentence from the first customer review and This is from Michael McKinley on amazon.com rating one star disappointing quality.
Speaker 1: a caution to people buying these if you do not follow the Directional markings on the cables your music will play backwards.
Speaker 1: Please check that before mentioning it in your views.
Speaker 1: I Disappointed.
Speaker 1: I consider myself an audiophile.
Speaker 1: I regularly spend over a thousand dollars in cables to get the ultimate sound.
Speaker 1: I keep my music listening room and a Faraday cage to prevent any interference that could alter my music listening experience.
Speaker 1: Sending any signal down ordinary copper can degrade the signal considerably Well.
Speaker 1: ordinary listeners might not notice to somebody with even a rudimentary knowledge of sound.
Speaker 1: the artifacts are glaring.
Speaker 1: Denon should have used silver wiring hermetically sealed inside the rubber sheath to prevent any tarnishing of course Which has significantly higher conductivity than copper.
Speaker 1: Furthermore Denon needs to treat the wires they use in the cable with polarity inductor to ensure minimal phase variance.
Speaker 1: Leanless to say I return the cable and wrote an angry letter with the so-called engineers at Dena.
Speaker 1: Let me let me read one more Four stars.
Speaker 1: it gets me closer to the Lord.
Speaker 1: If I could use a Ross rusty box cutter to carve a new orifice in my body that's compatible with this link cable I would already be doing it.
Speaker 1: I can just imagine the pre-musical goodness that would flow through this cable into the wound and fill me completely like white Holy light.
Speaker 1: holding this cable in my hands actually makes me feel that much closer to the Lord Jesus Christ.
Speaker 1: I only make 625 an hour at the jack-in-the-box, but I saved up for three months so I could have this cable.
Speaker 1: It sits in a shrine.
Speaker 1: I construct it next to my futon and mother's basement.
Speaker 1: I only give it four stars in my review because I can't find music that is worthy enough to flow through this utterly perfect Interconnect.
Speaker 0: the fact that he refers to mother as opposed to my mom They there are many many many more reviews in this hilarious style, thank you.
Speaker 0: Thank you internet.
Speaker 1: It's incredibly evil and scam artist product to use a Riley ism.
Speaker 0: You've you.
Speaker 0: my faith in the internet is back.
Speaker 0: You people make me proud to be an internet person.
Speaker 1: so go forth.
Speaker 1: Hey of course you know it's really sad if you look at the reviews.
Speaker 1: of course You can't really trust the reviews cuz a lot of them are just you know random like that four star one.
Speaker 1: But actually there are a hundred and four or five stars and sixty seven one star.
Speaker 1: oh well.
Speaker 0: so I Bought a laptop recently and Scott owns a laptop that I bought about a year earlier And Alex just bought a new laptop and way too much money, but it's worth it.
Speaker 0: I don't think it was way too much money.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 1: It was it was the price that was demanded for the quality.
Speaker 1: Yes You get what you pay for.
Speaker 0: but we realize we should talk I'm not gonna talk really in the abstract a lot about the concept of a laptop.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: well You see what's been going on is actually we've reached a point where laptops are more popular than desktops.
Speaker 1: Laptop sales exceed desktop sales.
Speaker 1: that is the world we live in there.
Speaker 1: a lot of this is the world we live in and They seem to have a really hard time picking out a laptop.
Speaker 1: which ones are good which ones are bad?
Speaker 1: Which one should I buy?
Speaker 1: and a lot of people make you know not so good decisions and some people make good decisions But some people don't.
Speaker 1: and we often are asked which laptop should I buy?
Speaker 1: or here's a few laptops?
Speaker 1: Which one should I get?
Speaker 1: or I need a laptop for this other person?
Speaker 1: Which one should they get?
Speaker 0: and if you don't want the belabored answer we have a short easy set of questions.
Speaker 0: You can ask yourself, but then we'll talk in depth.
Speaker 1: Yes, so the first question you ask yourself.
Speaker 0: This is very simple this you need a computer.
Speaker 0: Yes now that might sound like a dumb question, but Seriously think about it.
Speaker 0: I've seen people who own laptops who do not use their computer let alone their laptop.
Speaker 0: Yep, so all right you've answered that question.
Speaker 0: then question number two is very very simple.
Speaker 1: Do you have money?
Speaker 1: Don't have money.
Speaker 1: a laptop is probably something you shouldn't buy.
Speaker 0: well We'll get to that.
Speaker 0: you could buy the the cheapo.
Speaker 0: yeah That's.
Speaker 1: if you don't have maybe have no money But if it basically how much money do you have is?
Speaker 1: that is the real question you have to answer.
Speaker 0: well It's do you have money?
Speaker 0: are you willing to spend it?
Speaker 0: because if you have the money to spend just go buy a?
Speaker 0: Really good two to three thousand dollar laptop.
Speaker 0: It'll do everything you want.
Speaker 0: It'll be perfect in every way you're done.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if you don't care about spending more I mean even if you only need a thousand dollar laptop if you're stupid rich why not buy the $3,000 laptops,
Speaker 0: I'll tell you what like the difference between a thousand dollar laptop and a two thousand dollar laptop Is that it'll be smaller lighter faster the battery will last a freaking lot longer It'll be supported better, and it'll just work.
Speaker 0: the difference between a $2,000 laptop and a $3,000 laptop Is that the battery will last about 45 minutes longer.
Speaker 0: It'll be a little bit lighter and a tiny bit smaller.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but really it's.
Speaker 1: it's the three thousand dollar laptops.
Speaker 1: even though the actual numerical increase is only marginal The actual life experience increase is like chocolate and shit.
Speaker 0: it is that Pretty much.
Speaker 0: if you're if you want a good laptop Spend the money and if you don't spend the money then you're not going to get what you could have gotten.
Speaker 0: You're not going to be satisfied, right?
Speaker 1: So the thing you have to ask yourself now is what are you gonna?
Speaker 1: Do with this laptop?
Speaker 1: if you're just looking to you know browse the web on the go do a little word Processing a little email little forums right maybe a little flash games You know.
Speaker 1: then maybe you know you can look at.
Speaker 1: start looking at maybe the MacBook Air.
Speaker 1: Maybe look at you know with some of the cheap $1,000 guys even the EPC but again the MacBook Air.
Speaker 0: do you have money?
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: Now let's say maybe you actually want to do.
Speaker 1: you know real computing, but you don't want to really do like 3d games But you want to do real everyday computing a whole lot of it.
Speaker 1: You know it'll sit on your desk a lot.
Speaker 1: You know you this will be your primary computer.
Speaker 1: Well now you're starting to look at like you know Lenovo t-series You know.
Speaker 0: this is the other question you ask yourself Are you going to use this computer at the places you end up at or on the way to those places?
Speaker 0: Now if you answer yes to the first and yes to the second you still need a tiny expensive laptop.
Speaker 0: if you answer Yes to the first and no to the second meaning like you're a business traveler You have a computer used at home you travel to a destination You stay there for a week doing your business traveling whatever and you use the laptop in your hotel room.
Speaker 1: in other words when you're?
Speaker 1: Like say if you're a bit we're talking about here is the difference between this one person has a laptop right they get to a Hotel they open it they close it.
Speaker 1: they get to an office they open it they close it they get home They open it they close it.
Speaker 1: They're not like going into Starbucks and opening it all the time or they're not Opening it on a train and opening it on a plane and opening it all over the place.
Speaker 1: See if you only open it when you're sitting down at a desk or a table you can probably get a nice 1415 even 17 inches if you need that say your graphic design.
Speaker 0: So you get one of those big honking fast machines or the battery only lasts about an hour.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because you'll be plugging it in all the time.
Speaker 1: if you're at an office or at your home You can plug the thing in.
Speaker 1: you don't need the battery life to be you know many many hours long.
Speaker 1: You just want something that's a powerful computer that you can set up on a desk in different places.
Speaker 1: you can carry it with you in your luggage and It'll work, and it can be your primary computer, and you don't need another computer.
Speaker 1: But if you're opening this bitch in Starbucks if you're opening this bitch on the train you need a tiny bitch Cuz.
Speaker 1: you got to be out of that lap now, and you gotta have that.
Speaker 1: batteries gotta last like 10 hours.
Speaker 0: Now the thing is 10 hour battery right.
Speaker 0: if you want any amount of battery life you have to spend at least $2,000.
Speaker 1: pretty much all the laptops that have good battery life right have one of two things or both.
Speaker 1: They have one an extended battery.
Speaker 1: for example on the Lenovo machines They have regular batteries, then they have the extended batteries, which are?
Speaker 1: they go in the regular battery slot But they're twice as large.
Speaker 1: you have to buy that.
Speaker 1: when you buy the laptop you to get the extended battery.
Speaker 1: Two are the bay batteries is what my laptop has where yeah, but these are getting not as easy to use anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a little tricky with the bay batteries But some laptops offer the bay battery option.
Speaker 1: for the people who absolutely need that extra hour or two.
Speaker 1: You can take the CD-ROM out and in the same slot where the CD-ROM usually goes You can slide a battery in there, and now you've got two batteries and when the bay battery runs out It'll start using the regular battery.
Speaker 1: so like my bay battery lasts like a couple hours It's actually starting to get a little hairy now.
Speaker 1: I've been sitting here doing the show And only when that runs out does the main battery ever get used.
Speaker 1: so most of the time I end up just using the bay Batteries filling it up using the bay battery filling it up and the main battery is like a rock.
Speaker 1: It's like hardly ever discharges.
Speaker 1: now the other thing you got to do when considering the size It's not just the battery life and the weight and how easy it is to carry on But the screen size and particularly the screen resolution are really important.
Speaker 0: You still have to watch out because some cheaper laptops that seem small and nice will have a decent size screen But they'll have a low resolution screen, which is almost useless.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: I mean you can get a 15 inch laptop, right?
Speaker 1: But if the screen resolution is 1280 by 1024 You're not really any better off than say a 12 inch laptop.
Speaker 1: But the screen resolution of 1280 by 1024 because even though things are bigger and maybe easier to see if you have a you know You're a problem seeing.
Speaker 1: you're basically getting a bigger heavier laptop that uses more electricity But you don't have any more screen real estate.
Speaker 1: You can't fit more information on the screen at one time.
Speaker 1: So and it's it's not like a desktop computer.
Speaker 1: We can change the monitor out right.
Speaker 1: This is this is locked in.
Speaker 1: you can't change shit.
Speaker 1: So you better have it right the first time or else you're stuck with it until it breaks or you return it.
Speaker 0: now You know we say you got to think about what you're gonna use this laptop for.
Speaker 0: I mean the reason laptops are getting so popular Is that more and more we're getting detached from our storage?
Speaker 0: I mean as long as I have an internet connection I can do almost everything that I need to do with my computer.
Speaker 0: I don't need my data store except for like my media and that's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: Everything else is either online on a USB stick synced up whatever Google gears.
Speaker 0: there's a million ways to do it and that's why laptops are popular.
Speaker 0: so think about what you do.
Speaker 0: and Also, there's actually this kind of sucks, but if you were the kind of person who needs the internet to do your stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean I watch a lot of Media and I write things for my blog that never gets updated and I work on stuff I don't need my internet connection.
Speaker 0: if you need an internet connection all the time that costs a lot of money And there's no easy cheap way to do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean they make.
Speaker 1: you can buy these PCM say or USB things from Sprint or Verizon or whoever anyone and you pay this monthly fee I think $60 is the most expensive sprints actually pretty little cheaper and you plug it into your laptop And you can get internet of varying quality You know ranging from really damn good to kind
Speaker 0: of end.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you one thing though it mostly sucks.
Speaker 1: I mean it only really works if you're in a you know high coverage area like cities and such Work.
Speaker 0: if you think you're gonna if you ever think all right I'm gonna get a Verizon wireless card, and I'll use it when I'm traveling or commuting.
Speaker 0: those things generally don't work.
Speaker 0: Well when you're moving yeah, not at all.
Speaker 1: don't work on the train too.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like they cut in and out, but if you're sitting in it and say you know a park in the city And there's no Wi-Fi.
Speaker 1: That's looking good.
Speaker 1: It'll totally rock the house, and it's wicked fast.
Speaker 1: It's like evdo pretty good, but it costs a lot.
Speaker 1: They actually make some laptops where you don't need the card.
Speaker 1: the card is built into the laptop And you just need to find some way to activate the service and those are actually pretty good.
Speaker 1: But you have to know that that's what you want going in.
Speaker 1: you can't like decide on that later.
Speaker 0: So if you look at high-end pretty much the only decision you really have to make is do you want large?
Speaker 0: Powerful with a low battery life or small slightly less powerful and lasts forever?
Speaker 1: now There's one thing that's really popular on the high end these days, and that is the solid-state drive I was just about to bring up.
Speaker 0: if you're in the high-end market one of the biggest decisions you have to make is whether or Not you want to go solid-state.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see the advantage of the solid-state drives is number one you're gonna have longer battery life because they don't use as much electricity - you're gonna pay a lot of fucking money because they're really expensive.
Speaker 0: and three you're gonna have Relatively little storage on your laptop.
Speaker 0: these things aren't big.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean you know the biggest fanciest ones are 64 gigs which is pretty big But you're not putting your mp3 collection on there.
Speaker 1: basically if you get the solid-state drive You're looking for speed and battery life, but you're not gonna store stuff on there.
Speaker 1: You're mostly gonna put the operating system on there.
Speaker 0: It's like quietude and the fact that you can shake the thing around as much as you want while you're using it And it'll have no ill effects.
Speaker 1: yes with with a regular Mechanical magnetic hard drive if your laptop shakes or bumps you know it has to unseat the heads And you know that can cause trouble over time and the drive is probably gonna go bad.
Speaker 1: a solid-state drive Really doesn't go bad for a very long time.
Speaker 0: It will eventually but because it's basically flash so it will go bad.
Speaker 1: it is flash But it will go bad eventually.
Speaker 1: so but you're not gonna be storing mp3s on there so much.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna happen.
Speaker 1: so you need some sort of external drive or some sort of internet drive or something.
Speaker 0: But that's the thing I mean.
Speaker 0: if you're someone who's using laptops on the go And you use it frequently then the little tiny hard drive solid-state is great But if you're one of those people who brings Everything you need with you like a business traveler.
Speaker 0: Then you probably want the laptop that has the 400 gigabyte hard drive And then you bring your one terabyte external hard drive and your carry-on and yep now There is the the Mac or PC decision to make which can be a little tricky.
Speaker 0: Here's my answer.
Speaker 0: Do you have money?
Speaker 0: And also are you going to be using the creative stuff?
Speaker 0: because if you're not using the tools that work well on a Mac There is no reason to get a Mac laptop.
Speaker 0: They're more expensive than equivalent PC laptops.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if you're gonna be doing the basic stuff You know the web browsing the iTunes which is on PC all you know Windows also that sort of stuff, right?
Speaker 1: Why pay you know for the same amount of money?
Speaker 1: say a $1,500 MacBook costs a?
Speaker 1: $1,500 Lenovo something or Toshiba something will be faster and better.
Speaker 1: So if you're doing the same stuff on either one you should get the PC laptop.
Speaker 1: You should not get the Mac unless the Mac does something you need that the PC doesn't do.
Speaker 1: so a graphic designer with an Apple laptop Makes total sense right because you're gonna be like turning that really nice screen around and showing people stuff at Presentations and all that kind of business right up.
Speaker 0: maybe developer not so much.
Speaker 1: No Linux, and here's the thing a lot of people talk about Linux on laptops.
Speaker 1: all right There are plenty of laptops out there that work fine with Linux.
Speaker 1: the problem is that people buy laptops And then they try Linux later.
Speaker 1: all right if you actually bother to look and figure out if your laptop works with Linux Before you buy it You'll find out there's actually a lot of them out there that work really great with Linux.
Speaker 1: You can just install Ubuntu on them.
Speaker 1: in fact Dell sells laptops with Ubuntu on them that work perfectly.
Speaker 1: There's plenty of other people that do it as well.
Speaker 1: Lenovo's pretty much work.
Speaker 1: Fujitsu's most of them work.
Speaker 1: There's you know I mean even ones that don't work that well as long as they.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: Maybe they might have a weird wireless card, but it'll mostly work on just about any modern laptop.
Speaker 1: So you know if someone's gonna start making the the Linux complaint?
Speaker 1: really it takes like 10 minutes of researching.
Speaker 1: You know if Linux is gonna work on there or not in which parts of the laptop are gonna work or not cuz they're like On my laptop.
Speaker 1: you know the fingerprint sensor doesn't work in Linux.
Speaker 0: That's about it now that I would go and set further and say this much like with the Mac if you don't have a need Or a good reason to run Linux on your laptop.
Speaker 0: Don't bother.
Speaker 0: Windows works just fine on the laptop and in fact in a lot of ways.
Speaker 0: It'll work better.
Speaker 0: You'll generally get better battery performance.
Speaker 0: No It depends on most laptops.
Speaker 0: you will.
Speaker 1: the windows power management is better than the Linux really depends in the drivers and the exact power Management hardware in the computer, and you know how well Linux.
Speaker 1: You know no deals with that particular hardware.
Speaker 0: Yes, I'm just saying that on average if you just buy a laptop You're probably better off just running windows.
Speaker 0: and I mean unless you can articulate to me What you need Linux for on the laptop don't bother because you will.
Speaker 0: I mean the webcam and sometimes the Bluetooth.
Speaker 0: a lot of little Things left some trouble with.
Speaker 1: yeah like I have you know there's two buttons on my laptop next to the power button.
Speaker 1: those buttons don't Do anything in Linux at all.
Speaker 0: and also like I have the same fingerprint reader Scott does But because I just use Vista I can use it.
Speaker 0: It's really great.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good.
Speaker 0: I love it.
Speaker 1: Yeah But yeah, is there any other laptop buying advice?
Speaker 0: Oh, I guess laptop accessories if let's for example all right one Bye, I don't care how little you spent on your laptop buy another charger.
Speaker 0: Yes, own two chargers for your laptop.
Speaker 0: Good.
Speaker 0: God is this the best purchase you will make?
Speaker 1: because check this out, right?
Speaker 1: I have a charger at home and a charger at work.
Speaker 1: I don't have to carry this AC adapter from home to work back and forth.
Speaker 1: I just spent the money on another one.
Speaker 1: It was a little expensive because they rip you off on these things was like 40 bucks.
Speaker 1: But not having to carry that thing back and forth is so nice.
Speaker 1: I only that means I only have to carry a charger if I go on a trip or something.
Speaker 0: If I leave directly from home, I bring my home charger.
Speaker 0: if I take a plane that isn't from Stewart Airport I just leave from work to the airport.
Speaker 0: I take my work charger.
Speaker 1: yeah, you'll always have you don't have to you know, remember to pack the charger cuz every you're leaving from you have one and It's generally a good idea to have one charger per place.
Speaker 1: you you you live.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess if you're a student you're pretty well.
Speaker 1: You're pretty much gonna have your dorm or your school or whatever You know or your home.
Speaker 1: if you're living at home in high schools, then you only do one.
Speaker 1: But if you have two places that you are like most people home and work you want two chargers now, too And this is actually very very important.
Speaker 0: Get you need to get a bag or something to hold your laptop in and you have to actually get one that is for a Laptop or your laptop will break.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean people get ones that are like not the exact right size for their laptop And then what happens is their laptop like shimmies around in there.
Speaker 1: That's no good.
Speaker 1: other people get once They're too small for their laptop and then they just return it cuz their laptop doesn't fit or they jam it in there.
Speaker 0: Then the screen cracks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I don't even seen too many people doing that pretty much I mean, I'm not gonna get it.
Speaker 0: There's a little to a separate show on good laptop bags But you need one that will at least absorb Shocks enough to where you won't break the laptop in the average carrying it around scenario.
Speaker 1: Yep Now the thing is you.
Speaker 1: there's two options actually.
Speaker 1: you can either get a bag like a backpack or a messenger bag that has a laptop Compartment, which is what I got which is what rim has?
Speaker 1: I purchased a sleeve that is the correct size for my laptop.
Speaker 1: So the laptop has its own protective case and then I just put you know I it's a. put it around the laptop and zip it shut and then I just toss that in a bit.
Speaker 1: whatever bag I'm feeling like and those are two perfectly good options depending on your particular situation.
Speaker 1: You know if you got multiple bags going on you might want to go with the sleeve But if you have a weird size laptop The sleeve is.
Speaker 0: I stress this again never put your laptop in just a normal backpack.
Speaker 0: that actually puts.
Speaker 0: I mean depending on how you wear it, obviously, there's a lot of variables, but that puts a ton of wear and tear on your laptop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also by the same token don't carry your laptop around on and not in sleep mode unless you have a solid-state drive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it'll overheat and shit.
Speaker 1: Also a lot of people they don't think about this.
Speaker 1: but unlike your normal computer, you know Your laptop is something hope.
Speaker 1: if you're carrying it around it's gonna get beat up.
Speaker 1: You know the screen will get must up and it will get dinged and you might drop it once, you know.
Speaker 1: So you really want to take a look at how durable the laptop is there.
Speaker 1: surprisingly There are a lot of very non durable laptops out there.
Speaker 1: They crack they break very easily They're very flimsy.
Speaker 1: the screen hinge very important piece is often really shitty.
Speaker 1: You know, I noticed this mostly on a lot of laptops you can buy like Best Buy or whatever.
Speaker 1: They're very very flimsy and shitty.
Speaker 1: Make sure that if you're gonna be moving the laptop around a lot you want to pay extra to get something really Sturdy like Panasonic's Toughbooks, which are freaking tough.
Speaker 0: There is something along those lines Yep, but I mean generally most very high-end laptops, especially these small ones tend to be pretty derp.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it does.
Speaker 1: It really does seem.
Speaker 1: like you know, the more expensive laptops are more durable like the more expensive laptops are clearly superior.
Speaker 1: I basically I mean look at Lenovo.
Speaker 1: right Lenovo has the the idea pads Which are like the consumer line and they have the think pads, which is the business line.
Speaker 1: Think pads can take like a baseball bat idea pads.
Speaker 1: I could break them with like my pinky finger.
Speaker 1: They're just like flimsy cheap plastic pieces of shit where the think pads are made with like Nintendo plastic Which you can't break if you like, you know hit it with a sledgehammer.
Speaker 0: Now if you're gonna be traveling long distances a lot, I recommend buying another battery just to keep up with you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the reason you want another battery is let's say I have 10 hours of battery life.
Speaker 1: well, if I think I'm gonna be on like, you know a Camping trip right where there's no electricity Well, I can charge up some extra batteries before I go.
Speaker 1: then when they batteries run out I just swap them and I'm all you know, I get another few hours in there.
Speaker 1: That's a good idea.
Speaker 0: Of course if you're really gonna travel a lot I know Lenovo makes them and I'm sure other people do too you'd actually buy these big pads that you sit onto your laptop and just plug in to the power and They're basically just a gigantic external battery that lasts for fucking ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a docking station is also something to consider.
Speaker 1: if your laptop or you know a port replicator some people call it if your laptop I used one of these actually when I worked at the company that I quit before.
Speaker 1: I worked at my current company.
Speaker 0: if it's if Your laptop is your primary PC like you use it at home But then you take it with you use it on the train then use it at work.
Speaker 0: You want to have a docking station at home and at work with a monitor and a real keyboard?
Speaker 0: You just kind of slide the laptop into it.
Speaker 1: Yeah So what I would do back in those days right is I had this laptop.
Speaker 1: I use it on the train Get to work at work.
Speaker 1: I would put it in his docking station and there was a monitor at work and there was a real mouse and a real keyboard At work, so at work.
Speaker 1: I had the happy hacking keyboard my awesome keyboard instead of the cramped laptop keyboard.
Speaker 1: I had a real mouse on its own not the touchpad and the laptop monitor and a regular monitor.
Speaker 1: So it was two monitors at once and it was like, you know The laptop was really powerful and it was plugged into the walls.
Speaker 1: There's worry about the battery and it was like goddamn.
Speaker 1: and then when I went home I would just take the laptop out of the docking station.
Speaker 1: and What do you know?
Speaker 1: It's just a laptop on its own, but it's the exact same computer.
Speaker 1: It's all the stuff I had at work and it was really great.
Speaker 1: And if you're in that kind of situation where your laptop is your primary computer.
Speaker 1: The port replicator is a good idea, especially if like a printer you can plug the printer into that thing.
Speaker 1: You could plug scanners into it all kinds of good stuff.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know there's not much else to talk about.
Speaker 0: I mean everything else is just.
Speaker 0: they all support Wi-Fi.
Speaker 0: it works just fine They.
Speaker 0: you at least want to look at what connectors that has.
Speaker 0: I mean the laptops.
Speaker 0: I I mean my laptop has firewire and like to you actually I think has three USBs and a modem and an Ethernet.
Speaker 1: Then I want to look if you want to plug it in for like presentations.
Speaker 1: Most of them have VGA out but you might want to see if it has this video out or a DVI or something like that.
Speaker 1: You want to check if it has you know, microphone hole audio out that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: granted every laptop I've seen has a terrible audio and it just if you're gonna be like podcasting or something.
Speaker 0: You want to use your laptop for audio.
Speaker 0: buy an external USB?
Speaker 0: Non wall powered sound card and just use that for recording.
Speaker 1: It's kind of scary.
Speaker 1: but a lot of laptops have actual dial-up modems in them.
Speaker 1: Like mine has dial-up.
Speaker 0: So does mine.
Speaker 0: I don't know why like who uses that stuff, you know what if we had a regular phone line I would totally have a dial-in.
Speaker 1: I guess the reason for that though, at least it makes a little bit of sense.
Speaker 0: shitty hotels, too.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, you could be traveling anywhere so you might be trapped traveling to someplace.
Speaker 1: You mean I never use a dial-up modem, but it's a laptop.
Speaker 1: I might travel somewhere where dial-up is the option.
Speaker 1: So rather than forcing me to carry a modem a dial-up in there.
Speaker 1: It doesn't take up much room on the laptop It's just a tiny telephone hole.
Speaker 1: Why not have it?
Speaker 0: plus seriously if I if we had a phone line I would totally just set up a computer that if a computer called would answer and I could dial into my house.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would do something like that.
Speaker 0: That'd be really useful.
Speaker 1: It'd be okay.
Speaker 1: But yeah Buying laptops is not really that hard.
Speaker 1: You just need to think about.
Speaker 1: you know It's much like it's no different than buying anything else.
Speaker 1: It's just we keep explaining this buying procedure because people don't seem to get it.
Speaker 0: Think about what you need.
Speaker 0: think about what you need how much you're willing to spend what?
Speaker 0: Opportunity cost you're willing to put forth?
Speaker 1: then do research to figure out which products will meet your needs within your price range.
Speaker 0: Nothing meets your needs.
Speaker 0: compromise or don't buy something and then make a purchase.
Speaker 0: Now If you're looking for some specific advice, I know that Scott and I basically have two generations of the same laptop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, take that as you will.
Speaker 1: the lifebook p-series is very nice.
Speaker 0: Yes Seven and I have the eight.
Speaker 1: if I were to buy a laptop today I would go with what Alex just got me Lenovo x300.
Speaker 1: Yes is the hotness of all hotness.
Speaker 0: Honestly, if I were buying a laptop right now, it's also $2,500, but I'm glad I bought the laptop.
Speaker 0: I did because for what I use it for and for when I bought it, it was a good job.
Speaker 0: I had to sneeze right then awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pray, you know the x300 wasn't around when you bought your laptop But now it is plus.
Speaker 0: I actually really like my laptop and it was about five hundred dollars less.
Speaker 1: Well, you know you're manufacturing that happiness.
Speaker 0: No, actually, I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'm really I'm happy with it.
Speaker 0: No, okay Because the thing is you have your bay battery and your battery last for fucking ever.
Speaker 0: my battery still lasts about nine hours.
Speaker 1: Very last a long day.
Speaker 0: It drops down to about six if I place it.
Speaker 1: Oh my battery ran out.
Speaker 0: Oh did it?
Speaker 0: Yeah So said yeah, plus the thing is my laptop is better than Scott's because the newer one but at the same time It's a lot more powerful.
Speaker 0: But it's also stupidly light.
Speaker 0: like it's lighter than the MacBook Air which is actually surprisingly I think the batteries out of mine.
Speaker 1: It weighs nothing.
Speaker 1: Oh The weight is in the batteries.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I take the battery out of mine, it basically does weigh nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Oh, there's two other things to consider.
Speaker 1: Let me just throw these in.
Speaker 1: it will be done.
Speaker 1: Right, some of the small laptops don't have CD-ROM drives.
Speaker 1: For example the x300 which I just mentioned.
Speaker 1: Well, if you tell drives right right DVD CD whatever if you get the DVD CD drive in there You cannot get the bay battery.
Speaker 1: It's not an option on there.
Speaker 1: So but on my laptop I can swap out the optical drive and the bay battery all I want.
Speaker 0: now It looks like in a lot of like in new things.
Speaker 0: It seems like the way they're going is that when you buy the laptop you choose if you want the removable bay battery or the?
Speaker 0: optical drive.
Speaker 1: X300 does.
Speaker 0: yeah I've heard many rumors that the that the life books are gonna be updated in the future to have that capability.
Speaker 0: But no swapping anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like the swapping.
Speaker 0: I do too.
Speaker 1: but if you plan on you know watching DVDs on your laptop your options are either like handbrake them on another computer or You know just get the optical drive.
Speaker 1: Yeah the other thing is that you know you got an LCD.
Speaker 1: when you're buying a laptop you're buying a computer and a And a keyboard and a mouse.
Speaker 1: so make sure you like the keyboard Make sure you like the monitor and make sure you like the mousing device.
Speaker 1: like there's gonna be a Lenovo x200 soon.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna have a touchpad.
Speaker 1: It's only gonna have the red nub.
Speaker 0: You know what if you don't like bullshit the red nub is the worst possible thing.
Speaker 1: right nub is okay And I used to be a on the touchpad and yeah on the red nub But you get used to the touchpad eventually you don't need the nub anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the nub is just.
Speaker 0: it's not as powerful.
Speaker 0: The thing is I know why a lot of people are turned off by touchpads because by default on every freaking laptop in the world If you touch it it thing is what it says.
Speaker 0: Oh, he must have wanted to click on that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got to turn that shit off.
Speaker 0: Yes, and some shittier laptops the drivers wouldn't let you do that easily.
Speaker 0: Yeah, modern ones you can just turn that off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I used to like the nub and hate the touchpad But just use the touchpad.
Speaker 1: enough that doesn't bother me anymore.
Speaker 1: And then you know the nub bothers me only a little bit.
Speaker 1: now You know make sure.
Speaker 1: and also the screens.
Speaker 1: some laptops have the matte screens and somehow the glossies know what that means.
Speaker 0: They're they're equally good for different purposes.
Speaker 0: Yes, like.
Speaker 1: if you want like really bright image quality that sort of thing you probably want the glossy screen.
Speaker 1: It looks really good.
Speaker 1: It's a lot more impressive in the store But the glare is really crazy.
Speaker 1: if you try to use it when like the Sun is shining you can't see shit.
Speaker 1: the matte Screen which is sort of just like a normal LCD It's not as shiny It's not as impressive But it does the job and there's a lot less glare if the Sun
Speaker 0: If the glare is coming from certain angles the gloss is better and from other angles the matte is better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, really fine.
Speaker 0: I mean it's easy to find examples of both.
Speaker 0: Just go to the store and fiddle with them and decide which one you like.
Speaker 0: They're equally good.
Speaker 0: It's just a matter of your preference and they're really the resolution and the size matter more than the glassy matte the glossy matte Yeah, I mean I'd recommend to if you have the choice.
Speaker 0: a lot of people want XP for some stupid reason.
Speaker 0: if you're buying a New laptop just get Vista.
Speaker 0: It works fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a lot of people like oh no Vista is the evils.
Speaker 1: Well, this is not so great because it's not.
Speaker 1: you know It didn't really make any improvements over XP and I guess that's a valid criticism, but really it works.
Speaker 1: I have it on my desktop computer.
Speaker 1: There's only one problem I've had with it so far.
Speaker 1: There's no reason to bother with XP.
Speaker 1: it's just more trouble than it's worth.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm.
Speaker 1: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: You can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives Visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution Non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.