Speaker 0: It's Monday January 28th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek knives tonight.
Speaker 0: software should always get better.
Speaker 0: Let's do this Today when I got home from work.
Speaker 0: I was greeted by possibly the most wonderful thing I've seen in about five months.
Speaker 0: give or take I get off the train and there's this orb this Gigantic fiery ball and it wasn't like on the ground.
Speaker 0: It was up in the sky Like floating there and there was light coming off of it.
Speaker 0: There was light everywhere.
Speaker 0: There was light.
Speaker 0: I there was light outside.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen such a thing in many moons.
Speaker 1: It's been pitch black for what?
Speaker 1: how long.
Speaker 0: well considering up in the winter I get up at the crack as of before dawn and I go to work and I come home from work pretty early But not before that big fiery day star goes down.
Speaker 1: Well, that's cuz it's the winter and you know the daylight savings whatever time.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's daylight savings time or not, but it's one of the it's.
Speaker 1: either is or it isn't.
Speaker 0: See, that's the one thing.
Speaker 0: the one regret I have from moving away from the Midwest was that when I lived in Detroit or Serling Heights, I was on the other end of effectively the same time zone.
Speaker 0: Well, not effectively.
Speaker 0: I was on the other end of this time zone So I basically got an extra hour of daylight every day that I don't get now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, try living in Boston or Somewhere like that.
Speaker 1: It's way East.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: I'd probably cry.
Speaker 0: I had enough trouble living in Rochester.
Speaker 0: It was cold all the time.
Speaker 1: Maybe someone should do like a little chart I bet like people who live on like Western halves of time zones a little a little happier.
Speaker 1: Maybe you
Speaker 0: know they might be because that I don't understand why we don't just have daylight savings time all the time because all it does is give the Vast majority of people an extra hour of sunlight because
Speaker 1: crazy parents don't want their kids to Have it be dark in the morning, even though it's dark in the morning.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I know God even I remember getting up in high School.
Speaker 0: I'd get up at like 530 to go to high school.
Speaker 0: Let me pitch black out.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep Yeah, walk up the hill and two miles in the snow barefoot.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that was your grandpa.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, anyway, it's I've been getting static shocks, you know from static electricity quite a bit lately.
Speaker 1: My some contributing factors might be you know, the wearing of sweaters.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know when I did my laundry this weekend I took me, you know the t-shirt out of the inside of the sweater because You know, but actually at work I've been having a real problem in the.
Speaker 1: you know, the bathroom has a door handle right and like for a good wait a minute Static electricity in the bathroom is always dangerous.
Speaker 1: No No for like a week or so Right or even more than a week like every time I would go to the bathroom Right when I would reach for that handle to open up the door to the bathroom.
Speaker 1: I would get a shock.
Speaker 0: Wow, it's kind of like a reverse Pavlovian dog.
Speaker 0: We're now and think about it.
Speaker 0: Did you ever have this thought where you're walking up to that door and you're about to grab it and then you think oh I'm about to get shocked.
Speaker 1: I Was about to say that basically without even realizing it.
Speaker 1: I'm sort of every time now I go to that handle I hesitate and then just grab it anyway because I have to.
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: Brown always hesitated when he touched Door handles.
Speaker 0: now I was in high school, but that was because we tended to put Tesla coils on the other sides of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but now I'm going to intend now what I'm gonna do to counteract this.
Speaker 0: You should carry around a little like de-static.
Speaker 1: er What do you?
Speaker 1: what?
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: a wire?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: What do I do with this wire?
Speaker 0: Well, I have one end of it just to hold two ends of it Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah and touch one end to like the doorframe or like Dangle it on the ground or something or a light switch and when I guess get shot to that way Well an insulated wire God It's I would get shot you wouldn't it would.
Speaker 0: it would go through the wire not shocking you It's not going to go into the wire.
Speaker 0: and then look it's like imagine this.
Speaker 0: Here's what the electricity is gonna do.
Speaker 0: Imagine you're in you're stuck in a traffic jam.
Speaker 0: You're an electron you're in this horrible traffic jam and and it really sucks and suddenly a 12-lane freeway appears directly in front of you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and no one else has access to it.
Speaker 0: But you yeah, so you charge down that thing as fast as you can.
Speaker 0: cuz goddamn and Along the way you see an exit an Exit that goes up and down a mountain and completely out of the way you want to go.
Speaker 0: but eventually we'll get where you're going and that's also full of traffic and it's one lane and there's a bus on fire or You can see at the end of the freeway where the hell's is going exactly where you want to go.
Speaker 0: The electricity is not gonna go through you.
Speaker 1: It's gonna go through the wire But it is how is the wire any different from the handle to the bathroom?
Speaker 0: Because you touch the other end of the wire to something.
Speaker 0: where do you think the electricity goes when you touch it?
Speaker 1: Where does it go when I touch the handle of the bathroom?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Do you know where it goes out of me into the bathroom?
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah Well, it depends.
Speaker 1: It was if it goes out of me and shocks me through a wire out of me and shocks me through a hand.
Speaker 0: Well, if you take the wires you see and you have it dangling on the ground all the time Okay, that would do it.
Speaker 1: yes, cuz then it would.
Speaker 1: yes, but you know touching the wire to like something and prior to touching Anyway, you can always just carry a taser and get it back.
Speaker 1: Yeah Point is I gonna to unlearn this hesitation of touching the door handle?
Speaker 1: I'm just for now on I'm gonna just go for it like every time.
Speaker 0: Will you now?
Speaker 0: yes, I am if I worked at your office and I listen to this show There would so be a Tesla coil on the other side of that door handle tomorrow You might get the people who work in the other Offices on the floor.
Speaker 0: even the more people you get with a Tesla coil when you deploy it the better off you are as a human being All right.
Speaker 0: So what do you got in the news?
Speaker 1: It's actually got a bunch of news as I'm gonna combine here because they're more interesting when combined, right?
Speaker 1: So first of all, I got I got to put up some information, you know Cuz some people probably didn't listen to one of our early shows the window manager episode, right?
Speaker 1: So in Linux your your GUI is usually provided by the X window system, right?
Speaker 1: And the X window system just handles the windowing and stuff and it's actually on its own.
Speaker 1: It's just a server and you need to connect to it and run a window manager and you could choose from many window managers.
Speaker 1: There are many choices, but there are mostly only two really popular choices and then one sort of third choice, right?
Speaker 0: FVWM and ice.
Speaker 1: No, except CE is the third choice.
Speaker 1: The two big choices the most popular choices are gnome and kte right and the main difference between the two is that gnome all of its gooey stuff is based on these GTK libraries and Katie all its gooey stuff is based on these QT libraries.
Speaker 0: now The difference as far as you can tell is that gnome has a lot of intelligent defaults and seems to just work and Katie Has a million check boxes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know tea some people like one some people like the other like, you know Linus Torvalds like Katie and I like gnome.
Speaker 1: so, you know do use whatever you like best.
Speaker 1: Ubuntu uses gnome kubuntu uses Katie e zoo boondoo with an ex uses XFCE whatever.
Speaker 0: I've actually been.
Speaker 1: there's a whole show on it.
Speaker 0: I've actually been using FVWM a lot at work.
Speaker 1: now I guess it's good, you know, if you have a really specialized, you know, it's ugly.
Speaker 0: It's ugly as hell because you can see easy to make FVWM do exactly what you want.
Speaker 0: It's just not easy to make it look good while it does it.
Speaker 1: Yeah anyway, so The Katie recently has gone to Katie version 4 and if you want to try it out Kubuntu has a special live CD you can get now.
Speaker 1: in addition to that they Katie e. Oh, okay I forgot one more piece of backup information right.
Speaker 1: the QT library that you know Katie uses to do all its gooey stuff, right?
Speaker 1: He's made by this company called troll tech.
Speaker 1: now on Linux the QT library is sort of free open source But on Windows and Mac not as free and open source like they actually sell, you know QT libraries that you can make applications with them on Windows and Linux and whatnot.
Speaker 1: now The GTK libraries for gnome are fully open source.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the Katie e4 came out recently.
Speaker 1: you can try it out.
Speaker 1: and What happened recently?
Speaker 1: is the troll tech company said?
Speaker 1: All right We're just gonna make it all sort of open source for Windows and for Mac also.
Speaker 1: So now you can make QT library applications work on all the OS's and the Katie People are actively porting k-office Amarok K-right, you know all the Katie e applications which are generally awesome to Windows and Mac.
Speaker 1: So I think that's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Now it gets one step trickier.
Speaker 1: You can see all these things the Katie has been doing recently.
Speaker 1: Katie e4 came out.
Speaker 1: they updated, you know the QT's.
Speaker 1: they made them open source on the other OS's.
Speaker 1: They're porting the Katie applications to the other OS's.
Speaker 1: This is all leading up to something Unbeknownst to us, but now it was revealed Nokia is basically effectively going to buy troll tech right now.
Speaker 1: Nokia who makes phones, you know for nor right.
Speaker 1: so they're buying the company that makes the QT libraries that they use to do Katie e and all this other stuff and basically, they're going to become a. What do you call it a?
Speaker 1: Sponsor.
Speaker 1: You know when someone pays someone to make art for them you're a patron.
Speaker 0: Yes patron of the arts or in this case a patron of the.
Speaker 0: Well, I was trying to make a joke with arts, but doesn't really fit.
Speaker 1: So yep go on But they're.
Speaker 1: Nokia is basically going to become a patron of Katie e and they're gonna own troll tech.
Speaker 1: So Nokia phones which run the Symbian OS I guess Traditionally are now going to be loaded with all sorts of Katie apps and you know things that are similar to Katie.
Speaker 1: So if you're someone who likes Katie Then a Nokia phone might be in your future and I think this is getting.
Speaker 1: this is getting pretty interesting here Especially for people who are you know Katie users.
Speaker 1: that could be some serious integration between like, you know Symbian phones and Katie on Linux and you know different Katie apps on all.
Speaker 1: you know You have these applications that work on all OSes because the QT will be on all OSes and your phone will you know?
Speaker 1: Integrate with those apps.
Speaker 1: So now people could choose their OS get a Nokia phone and work with the apps, you know It'd be good stuff's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: I think yeah, I'm so glad I have a new Blackberry now instead of blackberries not bad.
Speaker 0: Okay, the only problem I've done with having with the blackberry is that?
Speaker 0: Google apps are great Google domains are great.
Speaker 1: Google domains and Google apps don't play together so well, but it's Google apps for domains But the Google mobile apps do not work with Google apps for domains and that is that is my trouble.
Speaker 1: Yes, I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna bitch about that at some point in the future.
Speaker 1: I got a whole thing to say.
Speaker 0: So I have two stories that are related in a way and I find it interesting that they both came out at a similar time.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: first there is this idea that what if we had Cellphones all be radiation detectors or anthrax detectors or whatever just built in so they just kind of passively detect and now you basically have without having to do much other than put these in cell phones a Giant nationwide network of detectors that could be used to watch for terrorism or all sorts of dangerous things.
Speaker 1: Actually, you know in one in one sense it's not such a bad idea because it does allow for added security without any sort of invasion of privacy or reduction of civil liberties, but The problem I see is you know, if you have like people have Geiger counters in their pockets, right?
Speaker 1: You know normal people don't know shit about Geiger counters and radiation.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I mean if they have any way to see it detecting radiation, you know There's background radiation everywhere.
Speaker 1: Geiger counters tick all the time and it's gonna freak people out and they're gonna get crazy scared and stupid.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: This is being developed by Purdue And the idea is that and I can imagine that it wouldn't be Like just always on or accessible to the people who own the phone.
Speaker 0: unless you do something to activate it or look at the data You know the nerds are gonna.
Speaker 0: you know, they're gonna yeah, but the nerd who figures out how to unlock his cell phone Yeah knows how many milli rads are dangerous and how many aren't exactly.
Speaker 0: but I think it's interesting idea.
Speaker 0: But the thing I really want to talk about is that kind of pursuant to or related to this is this Article on slashdot about how there's a push in New York City to require permits to own any sort of biological or radiological Detecting device that is Geiger counters or anthrax detectors.
Speaker 1: Well, I could see banning You know nuclear weapons Rods of plutonium or anthrax but banning the things to detect them.
Speaker 1: what?
Speaker 1: what's the fucking point of that?
Speaker 1: as basically you're saying Hey everyone, bring your anthrax here no one will know.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell the idea is that or the rationales that people are stupid like you said earlier and people are more and more as they get afraid of terrorism and all this sort of thing or realizing that they can buy just Geiger counters and all sorts of environmental detecting things and that People stupid in quantity with these things might detect radiation.
Speaker 0: that's perfectly natural and cause a panic.
Speaker 0: and in New York City where there's a lot of people living a Panic of stupid people is possibly the most dangerous thing that could ever happen in New York City.
Speaker 1: It's not a bad thinking but the correct solution to that to that problem.
Speaker 0: I have education.
Speaker 0: I have two solutions.
Speaker 0: education one.
Speaker 0: You could just set up and I'm sure a lot of universities and things in New York City or even most of downstate New York Would love to do this free Geiger counter calibration places.
Speaker 0: you can just go and Calibrate your Geiger counter and a professional will make sure it's calibrated and give you a little pamphlet that explains how it works and then Deputize you as an honorary.
Speaker 0: watch out for the terrorist, dude I got another idea right.
Speaker 0: normal people aren't gonna be buying like the kind of Geiger counters you're gonna use in a real lab Right, actually most people seem to buy like surplus Soviet ones that they get from like sharper image kind of magazine.
Speaker 1: That's bad too.
Speaker 1: what someone should do is come up with a product that's sort of like the handy-dandy wuss Geiger counter Right where instead of going tick tick tick tick tick, you know.
Speaker 1: And then you'd like like.
Speaker 1: so like a normal Geiger counter does it'll just have green yellow and red and it would almost.
Speaker 1: it would basically Never turn red unless you've stuck it near some uranium or something.
Speaker 0: Even then it probably wouldn't.
Speaker 0: uranium is pretty inert.
Speaker 1: all things can say no But you know considering that almost nothing is gonna bring you to that level of radiation I mean maybe you know some weak uranium would make it yellow or something.
Speaker 1: So that way you won't have idiots being scared But they'll still feel safe and they'll still spend money on your handy-dandy friendly user-friendly Geiger counter.
Speaker 1: I just I really Like.
Speaker 0: I see why they said they're pushing this law and I understand all the words that were written about it.
Speaker 0: not all that all the words that were said but they really just don't make sense to me because it's just all I Can't imagine.
Speaker 0: the government basically saying all right There may or may not be a fear out there this legitimate a thing that could be dangerous that could happen.
Speaker 0: So to protect you all we're going to ban the possession of anything that could detect that dangerous thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah Education can almost of course.
Speaker 0: then again we say oh just educate people.
Speaker 0: but at the same time How many people would even bother to go get educated or bother to even read the pamphlet that came with their Geiger counter or anything?
Speaker 1: The solution is to Socially engineer the people into not being dumbass isn't?
Speaker 1: because you can't educate them into not being dumb ass.
Speaker 0: So, how do you socially engineer people to not be stupid?
Speaker 1: They'll be afraid they buy your Geiger counter.
Speaker 1: But your Geiger counter is smarter than they are and it they will never scare them because it'll always be fucking green.
Speaker 0: but what if Joey Jojo Shabbat whose discount Geiger counters are five bucks on eBay and They go off after you give your cat some chemo.
Speaker 0: then What do we do about that?
Speaker 1: then the guy will show up and you'd be like it's cuz.
Speaker 1: he gave her cat chemo.
Speaker 1: As long as you see you explain why.
Speaker 1: if he doesn't know where it came from then I'll be afraid.
Speaker 0: I guess The summary I have is simply that this is a really stupid idea.
Speaker 1: Better yet right.
Speaker 1: to alleviate people's fear you give them a Geiger counter that doesn't tell them when there's danger.
Speaker 1: It just we assure them that if it detects danger it will radio, you know the authorities, okay,
Speaker 0: okay okay, now that makes sense because that's the kind of idea that's kind of the you know needs of the many over needs of the Few like the person who happens to be nearby if something goes off or something happens.
Speaker 1: I mean that'd be pretty good.
Speaker 1: Go Google Maps and get like a sort of.
Speaker 1: if there were these things all over the city You could see like radiation levels around the baby kind of like with the cell phone detectors.
Speaker 1: Yes, kinda only not in your cell phone against your will but intentionally purchasing on purpose.
Speaker 0: see I'm almost okay with the whole cell phone detectors even against your will kind of thing Just because the information you could gather not just nuclear danger.
Speaker 0: Oh my god anthrax, but you could detect a lot of Environmental information and you know the conditions of the air in places where people actually live and work constantly in my pocket The Condition of the air in my pocket the uranium in my pocket.
Speaker 0: Well, I know you carry a lot of like, you know, I got I got a big radioactive rod in my pants.
Speaker 0: But oh do you?
Speaker 0: oh, yes, I heard it was uh inert.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No quite the opposite I don't know.
Speaker 0: I find the phone out there.
Speaker 0: I find my first news interesting and my second news not so much frightening or stupid, which is baffling things of the day.
Speaker 0: I like puppies, I like robots and Nothing is funnier than watching a puppy Interacting with an autonomous robot whose aggression level is set too high Really?
Speaker 1: I'm beginning to think YouTube is encouraging animal cruelty.
Speaker 1: I mean there's a look at all these people torturing their animals with lights and robots and and all sorts of manner of inanimate on at the same time.
Speaker 0: watch this video and The puppy's tail does not stop wagging at any point in this video.
Speaker 1: I think it's wagging in anger though and not in happy hugs.
Speaker 0: Oh, hey, they're tails in anger.
Speaker 1: Are you sure?
Speaker 1: Yes How do you know you read your dog brain reader?
Speaker 0: I know a lot about Deggs.
Speaker 1: Deggs.
Speaker 0: a lot of our caravans too Like Deggs, but like the thing is their videos like this.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of videos like this.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of videos involving puppies and this exact same robot.
Speaker 0: of all those videos This one is the best because not only did they just have the video but they edited it properly Imposed man, they edited it to show all the cute funny bits and they added music sound effects and a scoreboard and they just.
Speaker 0: this is the perfect puppy versus robot video.
Speaker 0: and I think the best part at the end is where the puppies kind of figured out what's going on because at one point he looks Up at the dude who's obviously standing there with the camera with this look of seriously, dude.
Speaker 0: What the fuck?
Speaker 1: I think I can make a better puppy verse robot video.
Speaker 0: Well first you'd have to get yourself a puppy.
Speaker 1: No, I would just Photoshop some puppy into like a Gundam show or something.
Speaker 0: I would love to see you do that.
Speaker 0: I do not think that is in your realm of skill.
Speaker 1: No, I just pay someone else to do and say I did it.
Speaker 0: Scott patron of the arts.
Speaker 1: Yes, indeed.
Speaker 1: Alright, so so when you're in your blogging, right?
Speaker 0: Blogging we have blogs.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah when you're blogging Right you uh after you're done writing your blog post, you know, you write it you save it you edit it Eventually push that publish button and and then I almost immediately go ah shit and then I go edit.
Speaker 1: but I mean you know the the in theory right as far as you know the publish button what it does is it You know makes the post actually appear on your site instead of just in your administrators interface, right?
Speaker 1: But in fact when you click that publish button a whole shit ton of crazy things happen that you don't see going on.
Speaker 1: And unless you really understand how the web works You might not realize just how much happens when you push that publish button.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends on what kind of you know content management system using it does.
Speaker 1: it depends on a great many factors But it also depends on other people and how popular blog is.
Speaker 1: and you know exactly how much I mean.
Speaker 1: If you just start a new blog and push the publish button in your first post not much will happen if you're say Huge popular blog with a state-of-the-art content management system and you push the button a lot more stuff is gonna happen But you know really the many factors.
Speaker 1: the point is my thing of the day is this little thing on wired here.
Speaker 1: That's a nice diagram.
Speaker 1: It's sort of interactive in a shitty way But the content is good enough to warrant the shitty interface of this diagram.
Speaker 1: and the diagram shows you If you're a layman and you don't really understand fully, you know the the details.
Speaker 1: but this will explain to you pretty simply all the crazy shit that goes on when you publish a blog post and If you're interested in blogs in the web and whatnot.
Speaker 1: This might be informative to you.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, and it's the 50th anniversary of Lego.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna say anything.
Speaker 0: be a show about Lego.
Speaker 1: I know we knew that it was coming up.
Speaker 1: We would have waited.
Speaker 0: Lego bricks are to bomb diggity And the only reason geek night still happens is because my mom still has all my Legos and the day she mails them to me Is the day geek night's ends as I build gigantic forts and then fight with Scott's gigantic farts
Speaker 1: But all my things are castle.
Speaker 0: I have a lot of castle.
Speaker 0: equally dispersed among the castle is a lot of ice planet Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I got any.
Speaker 0: we're not gonna talk.
Speaker 0: We just talked about that on like Thursday.
Speaker 0: No, so Software always gets better right?
Speaker 0: I mean every time software is updated.
Speaker 0: It always gets better.
Speaker 0: They always fix something They always make it faster stronger Lighter Bigger.
Speaker 1: I mean version 3 is always better than version 2 and version 4 is always better than version 3 Right.
Speaker 1: I mean they wouldn't make something worse.
Speaker 1: I mean you have something right?
Speaker 1: It's in a state.
Speaker 1: You do a bunch of work on it.
Speaker 1: Why would you do work on something?
Speaker 1: It takes you so much time and effort to have the result be worse than where you started.
Speaker 1: You're always moving forward.
Speaker 0: So You know a while ago I will a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I had a copy of a piece of software called cool edit.
Speaker 0: I had cool edit 2000 and that was eight years ago, and I had cool edit Pro Mmm, now cool edit was a suite of audio editing software single track but it also had a multitrack component that was written originally in like 1990 freaking one.
Speaker 0: All right, my some guy who is basically just an audio nerd.
Speaker 0: He was really into like audio and his cool guy.
Speaker 0: I might have been two guys I forget but anyway, so the software Rapidly became the premier audio editing software in much of the civilized world.
Speaker 0: Most radio stations used it for almost everything they did this.
Speaker 0: This was just like the best audio editing software ever and it got better and better and better and better and better up until cool edit Pro version 2.1 and then in May of 2003 a company you may have heard of you might know him called Adobe
Speaker 1: adobe adobe
Speaker 0: bots Centrillion which made cool edit.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: They then discontinued cool edit and Nominally included everything it did in a Audition.
Speaker 1: yeah, they basically they made a new product called audition which is bait with a cool edit Pro and they adobe fight it and they called it audition and They made it worse.
Speaker 0: Yeah audition.
Speaker 0: Well when audition first came out, it was basically just cool edit and that was it.
Speaker 0: and then over time I mean I've used new versions of audition and I Contend that cool edit was like the best audio editing program ever.
Speaker 1: I mean audition does have some cool features like if you buy the right equipment, right like a digital mixing thing You can actually have say three microphones and it will record in audition in three separate tracks and that is pretty cool.
Speaker 0: But I can do that in cool edit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: How do you do in a cool edit?
Speaker 0: How do I do one cool that is specifically Scott?
Speaker 1: Well, you know, you could do a left and a right.
Speaker 0: You can record more than two tracks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you how can you separate it with a bunch of microphones in the same mixer split them up into separate tracks.
Speaker 1: with one Soundcard you can record from multiple sources But you only have one sound one USB hole.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: I only have one USB hole in my computer that has 12 USB holes.
Speaker 1: No, I'm saying is that?
Speaker 1: well, that's what audition can do.
Speaker 1: is with what through?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know but it yeah, you can do more than two track recording.
Speaker 0: You can even do that with like audacity.
Speaker 1: Yes, but you need multiple input sources.
Speaker 1: audition can do it through one digital input.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so can Pro Tools.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of things.
Speaker 1: Yes, but cool that it couldn't do that It's only one cool thing Audition does the cool that it doesn't do.
Speaker 1: and there are many cool things cool that it did that audition doesn't do.
Speaker 0: Well, the real deal was simply that I mean if you're doing like professional music like many many track music then Pro Tools and all Those professional programs and audition are actually pretty good.
Speaker 0: They're good for that.
Speaker 0: And that's what you probably should be using.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the problem was what a lot of people use cool edit for.
Speaker 0: was radio Kind of like podcasting?
Speaker 0: now about some people talking You're probably gonna bring it down to like a stereo or a mono.
Speaker 0: am FM radio kind of thing?
Speaker 1: I can have too many tracks.
Speaker 0: You're gonna do a lot of single track editing.
Speaker 0: You're more concerned with like quickly editing and quickly processing.
Speaker 1: You're not really concerned.
Speaker 1: You're mostly concerned with the volume and not so much, you know other things that you are concerned with music.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you compress and all that stuff and you'll do a lot of filtering and stuff.
Speaker 0: But other than that, you don't need a lot.
Speaker 0: you just need a very specialized piece of software that does all those things very very efficiently and very very well.
Speaker 0: and Now this wouldn't have been a problem because an audition while the interface I don't think is the greatest thing in the world can do Most of what cool that it could do.
Speaker 0: Audition costs off fuck of a lot more than cool edited.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean cool that it was originally like cripple wear where they you could get it But all a bunch of features were damaged and it costs.
Speaker 0: Did you say cripple?
Speaker 0: worry because you just looked it up on a Wikipedia and they say that it was cripple where they're.
Speaker 1: maybe Maybe But it was only a few hundred bucks and back in the day.
Speaker 1: We're like a few hundred bucks.
Speaker 1: What the fuck?
Speaker 1: We're not paying that now.
Speaker 1: What does audition cost?
Speaker 1: like a zillion dollars.
Speaker 0: now audition is like $400.
Speaker 1: it's like twice as much.
Speaker 0: and the thing is cool edit.
Speaker 0: what I was used by radio stations and I'd always been under the impression and I'd had people tell me this before that a Lot of radio stations still use cool edit to this day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean they had cool edit.
Speaker 1: cool edit was fine.
Speaker 1: It was perfect.
Speaker 1: It did everything they needed it to do.
Speaker 1: so why would anyone ever you know upgrade or switch to something else unless it was better?
Speaker 1: and What?
Speaker 1: the new product that came out was worse, so no one's changed or very few people have changed.
Speaker 0: Yeah now don't don't get me wrong It's not like a cool edit.
Speaker 0: was the second chroming of jeebus and audition Like can't edit audio at all or anything.
Speaker 0: auditions a pretty solid piece of software.
Speaker 0: The real issue is that cool edit was perfectly fine and had a lot of really good stuff in it and furthermore It served a very specific purpose.
Speaker 0: It filled a niche that there is no longer a solution that fills that niche.
Speaker 0: there is no longer a Low cost specialized piece of software for podcasting or radio.
Speaker 0: I mean, what are you gonna use?
Speaker 0: ReSound is the spiritual successor to cool edit.
Speaker 0: ReSound is great Except that it's really crappily written crashes all the time and isn't even half as functional.
Speaker 1: Yeah an audit and Audacity is free But audacity doesn't even do like 10% of the stuff cool that it does and the interface is not even close.
Speaker 0: Audacity olive.
Speaker 0: if any of you are using audacity to run like a compressor or anything, especially the built-in stuff Those things don't work.
Speaker 0: Those things are awful.
Speaker 0: That's why your podcast sounds bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and things like garage band are designed for music and the stuff that you know.
Speaker 1: Podcasting stuff is hacked in there and not good.
Speaker 1: That's why we couldn't stand it and I'm it's.
Speaker 0: it bothers me that there's really no kind of low-cost Entry-level single track.
Speaker 0: I want to do a podcast audio editing software that works.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I feel like someone could write something but no one does and I'm sure I don't have any time to do that.
Speaker 0: I've thought about it several times.
Speaker 0: I started learning lisp just so I could write Nyquist plugins, but Yeah, that's in the hopper with a lot of other things.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So another thing, right There was a program back in the day when you know mp3s are brand new.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh something that involves llamas and whoopings.
Speaker 1: Yeah The only way to really play mp3 is or at least the only practical way was use a pro called win amp win amp win have win amp.
Speaker 1: it really whips the llamas ass and I don't know why.
Speaker 1: there was a bad because Llama sheep with the sheep come from.
Speaker 0: what sound do you think llamas make?
Speaker 0: Nah No, and it was llamas.
Speaker 0: make the noise that you heard in cool it hurt not cool at it.
Speaker 0: and win amp.
Speaker 0: Anyway win amp by null soft was like the bomb people used to joke about how win And was more stable than windows.
Speaker 0: and like man if your window starts crashing just turn on win amp.
Speaker 0: It'll hold it together It'll take up all the RAM and didn't save it.
Speaker 1: Yeah When it was really was just a terrific program and pretty much everything null soft made was terrific programs.
Speaker 1: I wonder what happened to?
Speaker 1: because they went on.
Speaker 1: remember they made that.
Speaker 1: what was the thing called?
Speaker 0: Well, they were bought by AOL.
Speaker 1: No, they were bought by AOL, right?
Speaker 1: But the guy just didn't frankly he went on and he made that other program That was like to make the encrypted peer-to-peer whatever.
Speaker 1: remember that.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, and whatever happened with that I did that obviously didn't pan out but that I don't know what he went on to do.
Speaker 1: after that I got to look him up.
Speaker 0: cuz you continue to tell the story.
Speaker 0: I'll look up that business.
Speaker 1: Yeah, every program he ever made was awesome.
Speaker 1: The guy the Justin Frankel I think of null soft, right?
Speaker 1: Anyway, so when amp came out when it was like the perfect mp3 playing program in every way and it pretty much set the standard For mp3 plug playing programs from there on out, right?
Speaker 1: It was like the best thing ever Yeah, and it just kept getting better and better and better and better and better and better.
Speaker 1: right then one day They you know, they got win f1 they went up to and they just kept improving.
Speaker 1: when amp 2 without making any big changes You know, they would just fix bugs and add features and fix bugs and add features to win amp 2, right?
Speaker 0: Nutella.
Speaker 0: but the one you were thinking of I think was waste.
Speaker 1: Yeah waste that was the one waste was some actually hot shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, win it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Think about that.
Speaker 1: Nutella the most popular Peer-to-peer thing there is was the same was also written by the guy who wrote win amp is an important software developing guy.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Yep way Oh, we should do an episode on waste.
Speaker 0: just the concepts of waste.
Speaker 0: cuz if you wanted to do shady business on the internet If you wanted to pull off illegal shenanigans waste was basically written to facilitate that.
Speaker 1: We tried to set it up in college and we did but we could.
Speaker 1: it was so diff.
Speaker 1: It was too difficult with the key sharing.
Speaker 1: No one actually got to you.
Speaker 0: It was basically one of those.
Speaker 0: it was so secure that none of us It was not worth the effort to be that secure in our lives.
Speaker 0: I didn't have much to hide.
Speaker 1: So no plus, you know waste wasn't all that complicated.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 1: I could write waste if I wanted to.
Speaker 1: so, you know, whatever anyway.
Speaker 1: So when it was great and eventually I said, all right when amp 2 is great We're gonna come out with when amp 3 and when amp 3. the big advantage of it was that you could do these crazy skins Because you know when it one of the big when I'm as big as thing was the skins, you know It was skinnable before any other.
Speaker 1: anything else is skinnable, right?
Speaker 0: So I used to have a collection of like 200 anime themed skins.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah It was all about the way to win am skin.
Speaker 0: I'll win it.
Speaker 1: I remember picking the win am skin was so important to match your desktop wallpaper.
Speaker 0: I had a plug-in that would Rotate the skins depending on like.
Speaker 0: it was awesome.
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: Those were good days.
Speaker 1: It was a good days.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have nostalgia for those days.
Speaker 1: I wish computing was so simple now.
Speaker 0: I remember specifically I think was version 1.91 or 1.9.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, oh Those are good days.
Speaker 1: Okay So when I'm three came out and the thing with when I'm three you think when I'm three be better than when I'm two now?
Speaker 1: It was just shit.
Speaker 1: It was slow.
Speaker 1: It was unstable.
Speaker 1: It crashed used too many resources and offered no advantages over win empty whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Besides that you could go crazy with the skins and going crazy with the skins made it slower and shittier and it sucked.
Speaker 0: It was less stable.
Speaker 1: and wasn't that right after AOL bottom and they included a lot of it was either right after right before And it was not good times not good times at all And people just kept using win amp 2 and didn't use win amp 3 and eventually they sorta win.
Speaker 1: M3 was sort of like was like beta and then they sort of pulled it back.
Speaker 1: Eventually like over time they tried they tried to push it forward and then they pulled it back.
Speaker 1: They cuz it sucks so much that no one used it.
Speaker 1: Everyone used win amp 2 anyway, and he was like, haha we win we win.
Speaker 0: And eventually now they think they're winning five or six or that what they basically they realize that Everyone had turned on them.
Speaker 0: So what they did is they came out with win at five and the rationale was we took the good stuff from two You know the fact that it worked and the good stuff from three Not much.
Speaker 0: and they made five which was actually really really good and that was pretty much the mp3 player Until very recently.
Speaker 1: Well 5.52 is the current version according to win amp calm and it is the mp3.
Speaker 1: It's it's pretty badass.
Speaker 1: I mean if I if you're not using iTunes and an iPod when amp is the way to go It's still to this day, but we know unless
Speaker 0: you're in Linux then I use audacious and xmm s depending on what I'm
Speaker 1: doing Amarok or whatever, but the audacious also, but yet when a version 3 was worse than 2 quite significantly
Speaker 0: Yeah, we don't need to get into all the details But it had like serious problems and also I think a lot of people just didn't trust it because they didn't trust what was going On with the development.
Speaker 0: and there there was.
Speaker 0: there was shading is going on.
Speaker 1: There was indeed shading is going on But why does software get worse?
Speaker 0: How can this happen?
Speaker 1: well Sometimes it just happens where you know, so software, you know gets worse for the same reasons that Software is bad in the first place.
Speaker 1: right like you see a new project and the project will result in a bad piece of software.
Speaker 1: Well when someone you know tries to make a big change to a piece of software It's really no different than when you try to make a brand new piece of software and what they try could suck.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, what if they tried to make an mp3 player from scratch?
Speaker 1: Well, it might suck.
Speaker 1: Well, when m3 was just a new mp3 player from scratch just they just called it when m3 and it sucked.
Speaker 1: if you poorly designed software if you aim too high if you if you have Ideas, but those ideas aren't actually good ideas.
Speaker 1: They're good on paper, but in reality, they're no good.
Speaker 1: You know all those things can cause a piece of software to get worse.
Speaker 0: I think also there's a there's a factor that and this happens A lot with operating systems.
Speaker 0: I mean how many times is Microsoft release an update and it fixes something But it breaks something else?
Speaker 0: or there's a kernel update in Linux and now there's support for the food bass motherboard Whatever but suddenly support for the bar bass bad bad motherboard doesn't work so well and you start getting kernel panics.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this this can happen a lot.
Speaker 1: I mean if you're especially with low-level software like, you know kernels and thing and drivers and whatnot is you know?
Speaker 1: You're you're writing this piece of software.
Speaker 1: Let's say it's a sound card driver, right and that sound card driver supports.
Speaker 1: You know, there are five different sound cards that will all use that same driver.
Speaker 1: Well, let's say a new sound card comes out and that sound card also wants to use that driver.
Speaker 1: Okay so you modify the sound card driver to work with that new sixth sound card.
Speaker 1: in doing that you might make it so that some of the old sound cards don't work anymore and you really have to test it with all the different sound cards to make sure.
Speaker 1: And you know if you you know that you're you have win m2.
Speaker 1: it works on all these different Windows computers.
Speaker 1: Okay, so now you make some changes to it.
Speaker 1: suddenly, you know, you might you know It might work on your computer and all the computers you have available But you might have done something that makes it not work for people who have a certain video card.
Speaker 1: You don't know.
Speaker 1: it could happen and you know, so whenever you're changing a piece of software and for any reason There's always a chance that you could make it work or not work depending on you know, the peculiarities of any individual users.
Speaker 1: You know configuration hardware and software.
Speaker 0: Now, I guess a lot of people might have expected us to say the the obvious of well The reason software gets bad and can't get fixed is because obviously it's closed source.
Speaker 0: I mean look if cool edit had been open source, then people would have just forked the good version and Continued with it forever and resin would have basically just been cool at it awesome, or when when m3 came out people would have just kept making when I'm too better, but Open source software suffers from this problem just as much because While open source means yes, if things go bad You don't like the direction development is going you can always just cut and run take the good version and then fix it.
Speaker 0: But how many people at the time or the expertise or the knowledge?
Speaker 0: not just programming but in terms of what the software does?
Speaker 0: I mean if you want to write a cool edit or you want to write a resound You don't just have to know how to code You have to know about audio a lot about audio or you have to know someone who does and it's not.
Speaker 0: It's often a fallacy that just because something's open source means you're always safe from problems in the development chain.
Speaker 1: Well, you're safe in the fact that if the new version is worse.
Speaker 1: The old version is always still available.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know what if we're nap, you know, you they don't have the old versions available on their website They only have the new version there.
Speaker 0: as far as I know They actually did for a long time keep available version 2 and version 3.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they might still I don't know.
Speaker 0: But plus don't forget old versions calm.
Speaker 1: There was.
Speaker 1: is that website still around?
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna check right now.
Speaker 0: But I mean, yeah, that is true.
Speaker 0: I mean at the same time, I guess we're just lucky in that cool edit specifically Centrillion doesn't exist anymore at all and Copy protection was not quite as robust as it is now.
Speaker 0: back then there was no like phoning home or anything.
Speaker 0: If you want a copy of cool edit, you can probably get it.
Speaker 0: However, I will say that every version of cool edit I've ever seen on the the torrent networks out there every single one without exception has been absolutely full of Malware.
Speaker 0: like you wouldn't believe you do not want to install cool edit that you just find somewhere on the internet.
Speaker 0: Get it from someone you trust.
Speaker 0: try to make a friend at a radio station.
Speaker 0: They'll give it to you.
Speaker 1: Hey By the way, I'm at old version calm here.
Speaker 1: An old version calm doesn't need seeds still exist anymore.
Speaker 0: It's a porn site now.
Speaker 1: No, it's.
Speaker 1: he's got all these.
Speaker 1: He's got old versions.
Speaker 1: You can get old versions of all these different programs.
Speaker 1: In fact, you can get old versions of cool edit bro.
Speaker 1: You can get cool edit one three two one three three really for a 2.0.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they're unlocked or anything, but he's got old versions here, huh?
Speaker 0: I would look into this cuz I forgot.
Speaker 0: I didn't really think I'd to be honest.
Speaker 0: I did not believe that that website was still around and I did not do my due diligence.
Speaker 1: They got cool edit Pro 2.0 cool edit Pro 2000.
Speaker 0: Do they have 2.1?
Speaker 0: Cuz that's that's the that's the business.
Speaker 1: No, they don't have 2.1.
Speaker 1: Ah, oh, well, but they got you know, let's see.
Speaker 1: They got let's see iTunes.
Speaker 1: They have every version of iTunes from 4.1 to 7.0 to It.
Speaker 0: didn't old version calm because newer is not always better is I think the best example of that ever was Windows me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was newer Arguably, it was not better.
Speaker 1: Well, Vista's the same way.
Speaker 1: It's it's newer, but it's arguably not better.
Speaker 1: a lot of people don't like it and it's really not granted too.
Speaker 0: Well, I will say this.
Speaker 0: I think that a lot of the people who say they don't like Vista Don't know why they don't like Vista and don't actually understand what is good or bad about Vista.
Speaker 0: I think I've heard a lot of Unreasonable unverified claims that Vista has bad things in it.
Speaker 0: That's just totally and patently not true.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think Vista's only real problem is that it's not significantly better.
Speaker 1: It's just more of the same.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not it's not really.
Speaker 1: I used it.
Speaker 1: It wasn't terrible or anything.
Speaker 1: I don't know and see what people are crying about.
Speaker 0: I use Windows 95 like B right or a right up until Windows 2000 came out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's just because I didn't have USB.
Speaker 0: So I had no reason to upgrade.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Oh ICQ there's another program you hated when it changed.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, I see Q. They made new versions of ICQ.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you a lot.
Speaker 0: The only complaint people had against ICQ was that it was kind of bloated and it was.
Speaker 0: but part of the reason I think you like it was like the first one.
Speaker 0: it was like god damn people don't realize how old ICQ was but made by that there's Israeli company Mirabilis.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: It was hot shit and there was Spira Mirabilis Spira Mirabilis soup But like oh did we did a show on the history of I am didn't we?
Speaker 1: Think we did?
Speaker 0: if we didn't we will.
Speaker 0: but yeah ICQ was like it wasn't.
Speaker 0: I mean I am.
Speaker 0: was this new concept?
Speaker 0: so AOL had its.
Speaker 0: I am but it was basically just check and nothing else.
Speaker 0: It was like chat with someone.
Speaker 1: It was it was chat room with two people.
Speaker 0: It wasn't I am and ICQ was kind of like directly in between email and instant messaging like it was a full-on messaging solution as in it had the Statefulness and the offline delivery and the multi-chatness of email coupled with the immediacy of AOL.
Speaker 0: you know instant messenger kind of thing and I think that it was the best fusion.
Speaker 0: the problem was it was written by a bunch of cool dudes.
Speaker 0: who?
Speaker 0: Were all cool and techie and as a result the interface looked like something that only a hardcore techie could love.
Speaker 1: It had way too many buttons and they kept adding way too many features.
Speaker 0: But and then they started adding bullshit to it and then AOL just bought it.
Speaker 1: and then yeah, that was the end of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, ICQ died the day AOL bought it.
Speaker 1: pretty much.
Speaker 0: You know though I think you died long time before that and I think the it was taken off life support when AOL bought it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, of course now.
Speaker 0: I have Google talk and I couldn't care less.
Speaker 1: Nope could not care jabbers, but anyway Yeah, we got anything else to say on this topic.
Speaker 0: I don't think we do.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: It's Monday.
Speaker 0: I'm looking forward to some chicken.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 1: As long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.