Speaker 1: It's Tuesday April 1st.
Speaker 1: I'm Red.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek knives tonight collectible gaming.
Speaker 0: Let's do this All right, it's it's the April Fool's Day.
Speaker 1: Scott is really down on April Fool's Day.
Speaker 0: I don't understand why suddenly suddenly I'm down in April Fool's Day.
Speaker 0: I'm down with April Fool's now because it Thanks to you know when I was a kid right April Fool's Day was awesome because no one hardly ever did anything.
Speaker 0: cuz you know Kids are afraid to do something and they didn't have the resources to really do anything.
Speaker 1: So I mean, well, you must have my school was like, I don't even it was like a war zone on April Fool's Day.
Speaker 1: But sometimes we just get the day off because they didn't want to deal with it.
Speaker 0: So but I mean like, you know, if you put chalk in the eraser that was like, oh man.
Speaker 0: So, you know having actual pranks in April Fool's Day other than the ones we saw on TV and such was like, you know It would have been an amazing thing.
Speaker 0: So, you know as I got older like anticipating they're actually being pranks was like so awesome.
Speaker 0: But now with the Internet's right, it's like people have forgotten that they're not even pranking anymore.
Speaker 0: You know, I think I actually I think it goes back to the newspaper strip comics or an April Fool's Day.
Speaker 0: They would all sort of trade comics and like, you know The the peanuts guy would draw Garfield and the Garfield guy would draw Dilbert and you know They'd all mix it up.
Speaker 1: the web comics all did that people trying to read XKCD.
Speaker 0: Well, they didn't know they didn't.
Speaker 0: what they did is they said if you go to the one they just basically changed all their DNS.
Speaker 0: So one website goes to the other goes the other which is a really clever idea.
Speaker 0: I think it's okay idea, but it's not the same as drawing the other guys comic Which actually I think the Wondermark guy.
Speaker 0: he drew his comic instead of you know, photoshopping it as usual, but I mean those aren't Pranks, that's just doing something silly.
Speaker 0: I mean and that's oh that's well and good and sometimes it can be amusing But it's not a prank it's not.
Speaker 0: you're not making a fool of anyone You actually have to make a fool of someone or it doesn't count in the book of Scott.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, and the book is Scott where nothing's a prank and yet you never pull any pranks.
Speaker 1: I've never seen you pull a prank in your life.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because I'm not gonna pull one if it's half-assed.
Speaker 0: I if I pulled prank it's gonna be so extravagant and so devastating.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I will see.
Speaker 1: see the thing is to me the best pranks aren't the ones that just publicly humiliate one person.
Speaker 1: They're the ones where you catch someone and even if it's not apparent they have that moment.
Speaker 1: It might even just be a second where they like go to the forum and see a thread That has a title of something.
Speaker 1: they go to a web page and the news is like RIAA Disbanded and it's April 1st.
Speaker 1: It's obvious It's a trick.
Speaker 1: but for that second before the rational brain kicks in and says no, you're just a dumbass they go.
Speaker 1: Oh and that second is what I live for.
Speaker 0: that second doesn't do anything for me.
Speaker 0: Second is just like a groan.
Speaker 0: It's like ah, you're so lame I don't think anything does it for you anymore.
Speaker 1: everything everything's laying your man about everything.
Speaker 0: I see if there's a real April Fool's prank, right?
Speaker 0: You got to be running someone like all day and at the end of the day They're crushed like yeah, and they like they want to kill themselves because I'm so thoroughly put up or shut up.
Speaker 0: All right, it's just you know, you got to give me some years.
Speaker 0: It takes years to prepare something.
Speaker 1: I mean actually though the French guy.
Speaker 1: my work was pretty good with all this.
Speaker 1: All he did was pulled the classic French thing of hey, there's a fish on your back and he got everyone.
Speaker 1: He pulled it on except me because I knew what it was.
Speaker 0: Yeah, randomly, you know, here's here's the thing.
Speaker 1: It's like there's a fish on your back and I'm like, yep last last April Fool's Day.
Speaker 0: I was fooled by a Somewhat good prank of the board game geek people.
Speaker 1: I know that bark did almost the exact same prank.
Speaker 0: That's actually approaching a good prank right approaching.
Speaker 1: That was brilliant.
Speaker 0: It was okay.
Speaker 1: Wait, wait, if that was okay, then what's great?
Speaker 1: I mean a tire iron.
Speaker 0: No, that's not a prank.
Speaker 0: That's just outright.
Speaker 0: See now what would be a great prank right like his tire iron.
Speaker 0: Well, no, like if someone is a kids one I just thought up right?
Speaker 0: This is a pro.
Speaker 0: This is not a great prank, but it's getting closer to one.
Speaker 1: Is it the Our friend who was afraid of class?
Speaker 0: for example someone gets to work and there's a message on their answering machine.
Speaker 0: That's actually from a police station talking about how their car has been broken into and then they go home early on the train and they go back to the parking lot and That's not a good prank.
Speaker 1: That's just being an asshole I know.
Speaker 0: and then right their car is there and they go.
Speaker 0: what the fuck.
Speaker 0: so they get in their car and then You know like something in the car like totally gets them like I don't know an inflating something or you know Something like that.
Speaker 1: That was like the worst prank ever.
Speaker 0: That's a great brain.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: that's just being a jerk.
Speaker 0: exactly.
Speaker 0: What do you think a prank is?
Speaker 0: you make someone feel like a dumbass and you make their life miserable?
Speaker 0: And then you laugh at them.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, it's so much more subtle and clever than that.
Speaker 1: No, you got it.
Speaker 1: This is why you don't pull pranks.
Speaker 1: This is why I'm the prank man.
Speaker 0: No Lame prank man.
Speaker 1: I prefer the more psychological pranks.
Speaker 0: No, it's a prank is all about laughing at other people suffering.
Speaker 1: No, a prank is about knowing that you got someone out there that someone went.
Speaker 1: Oh For that one sec, that doesn't do anything for me nothing does anything for you.
Speaker 0: Yeah laughing at people suffering great, all right, so Basically though despite me not being fooled by any actual April Fool's Day pranks today.
Speaker 0: I Fooled myself.
Speaker 0: Oh Yes, I woke up.
Speaker 0: I turned on my computer and such and I was like, it's April Fool's Day.
Speaker 0: Everything is bullshit.
Speaker 0: So I just I wasn't gonna read any web pages.
Speaker 0: I was gonna fill my iPod and go right.
Speaker 0: So I go to fill my iPod and in the feed for the Roadhouse the best blues podcast in the universe Right.
Speaker 0: It says Roadhouse announcement and I'm like Come on man, and he what you know, he doesn't you know Tony the Roadhouse guy doesn't seem like the guy kind of guy who would do pranks and whatnot, right and You know before I even listen I didn't even listen to it, right?
Speaker 0: I just you know sync my iPod, you know from upstairs, you know, and then I just sent him an email like You're not fooling me with your announcement stuff.
Speaker 0: It probably says something like the Roadhouse is gonna switch to being an 80s podcast instead of a blues podcast or something like that.
Speaker 0: Blah, all right.
Speaker 0: so I get on the train and I listen to it and It's actually a totally serious announcement that was actually posted late on March 31st.
Speaker 0: Good job.
Speaker 0: So I got to work and I was like, uh, I'm a dumbass [laughter].
Speaker 0: So so in fact, I think There's a fish on your back.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think now because April Fool's Day is just so obvious and so overbearing and so lame That the way to really do April Fool's Day is to actually say something true that people are likely to disbelieve and thus they fool themselves.
Speaker 0: and in fact a one website followed the same Philosophy.
Speaker 0: new scientist calm I think it is.
Speaker 0: Yes new scientist calm posted all stories that seem fake but aren't and It's really really good idea.
Speaker 0: I like that action because people read these headlines like dinosaur killer found in volcanic bubbles China's boom sparks mass species invasion Wings with elbows, you know, they're pretty crazy If you actually read these stories right universe's tiniest black hole discovered right, but they're all true stories.
Speaker 0: They just seem weird.
Speaker 1: Well, I remember actually last year We got a lot of people surprisingly with a prank that we came up with at the last minute.
Speaker 1: We were allowed all day.
Speaker 1: We're like, what are we gonna do?
Speaker 1: Everyone does something on the internet?
Speaker 1: We got to do something but we don't want to do what everyone else does because it's usually not that good other than Like what board game geek and park did and we can't do that.
Speaker 1: It's already been done Yep, and you can't just Rick roll.
Speaker 1: someone cuz whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much I noticed I saw it coming a mile away to Everyone on the internet who wanted to do an April Fool's Day joke, right but was lazy about it.
Speaker 0: They all just did a Rick roll.
Speaker 0: YouTube did a Rick roll.
Speaker 0: Mahalo did a Rick roll.
Speaker 1: You know if I were YouTube what I would've done hollow or whatever.
Speaker 0: It's called for.
Speaker 1: just today I would have redirected every possible link to my site to a Rick roll all day.
Speaker 0: Just It's just so grown worthy.
Speaker 0: It's like it's great.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: see to me the Rick roll like Rick rolling someone itself is lame.
Speaker 1: It's obvious It's bloods like all.
Speaker 1: right, you're linked to something but it was actually a redirect to a Rick roll.
Speaker 1: Good job But to me the Rick roll doesn't symbolize that anymore.
Speaker 1: The proper use of a Rick roll is kind of like the modern equivalent of going.
Speaker 1: haha It's like you see that Rick roll.
Speaker 1: It doesn't mean I Rick rolled you.
Speaker 1: I'm just pointing out that I got you with something and the Rick roll is merely the means.
Speaker 1: you were tricked by Something else not just a link something beyond that.
Speaker 0: and the Rick roll is like hey Yeah, but a lot of people today have been.
Speaker 0: the Rick roll itself has been the trick and it's not a much better trick.
Speaker 0: It is not amusing.
Speaker 0: It just makes me groan.
Speaker 0: Ah
Speaker 1: Rick
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that I actually what someone should have done is coming up with something, you know They should have done the same trick as the Rick roll But coming up with something better than that video something else like, you know, perhaps some horrible two girls one cup Rick roll.
Speaker 0: Yeah force people to watch that mother.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's good but that's still the same joke.
Speaker 1: It's just oh.
Speaker 1: you thought you were clicking on a yeah one thing, but it was actually a link.
Speaker 0: right that's thing.
Speaker 0: That's the first part of the joke.
Speaker 0: The second part of the joke is them vomiting because they're watching the vomiting and me laughing at god You're like the worst prankster ever.
Speaker 1: I can just see this now.
Speaker 1: like what if we what if we like play the leak spin song in the background for like four hours until Scott Johnson freaks out trying to figure out what that song is before anyone else knew about the leak spin and Then we all laugh at him for like an hour after that and then you're like, yeah And then we fucking kill him and bury
Speaker 0: him out.
Speaker 0: bad You see cuz like the original pranks.
Speaker 1: right we're all like Original pranks like when look all raw was running around.
Speaker 0: No, like you give someone the hotfoot, you know, it's like that's not a prank.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's criminal.
Speaker 0: I know it's criminal But that's that's where pranks came from the hotfoot the bucket of water on top of the door that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: That's funny action right there.
Speaker 1: I don't agree with your philosophy on pranks one bit.
Speaker 0: I like that kind of prank.
Speaker 1: I prefer the.
Speaker 0: I'll just point out that the Scott Johnson with the hose in the middle of the winter Wow, you know surround their car with big frozen blocks of ice so they can't drive it out.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: much more clever is to replace someone's car with a very similar car.
Speaker 0: That's a good one, too.
Speaker 0: But anyway and put their car on the other side of the schools They have to walk through a mile in the cold snow to get to it.
Speaker 1: Oh No, yes, actually to me the best pranks are the psychological ones that last for months and you build up to some climax.
Speaker 1: but the climax is sometimes so anti climactic like got like Penn's thing where they had the friend who had the Gas efficient car and he was like it was a hybrid.
Speaker 1: He's like, oh man, I got my hybrid I'm saving the earth.
Speaker 1: So every couple of nights they put like an extra gallon again.
Speaker 0: That was a good one because eventually he ran out of gas on the highway.
Speaker 0: No Cuz when they stopped filling his car with gas he ran out and then you laugh at his suffering of not having any gas.
Speaker 1: That's not that bad.
Speaker 1: But your idea would be and then the car blows up because of the pipe.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't need to blow up.
Speaker 0: You just need.
Speaker 0: you just needs to run out of gas on the highway.
Speaker 1: Ah, I gotta say though.
Speaker 1: I'll say this on Tuesday because I don't want to say it on Wednesday.
Speaker 0: How come?
Speaker 1: no one is acted like they're gonna do a cosplay skit and then just Rick rolled the audience.
Speaker 0: Because that that's about to happen at every convention this year Played out.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: I guarantee that at every anime convention There'll be at least one cosplay that involves a Rick roll.
Speaker 0: somehow.
Speaker 1: See the thing is just involving Rick roll is Nick's.
Speaker 1: remember they make you do the like Performance ahead of time and you don't get to do your audio to real anime cons.
Speaker 1: You give it to the con ahead of time and they play it over the speakers with no control from you during your skit.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: There's no way for you Easily to make the Rick roll sound
Speaker 0: happen because the the convention will hear it Which is means you pretty much have to do a Rick roll skit and then the convention Runners and the other cosplayers will know you're doing it But no one else will know
Speaker 1: that.
Speaker 1: the best way is to either one have one man on the inside who does it Like the guy who does the audio is the only one who knows if you pay him off.
Speaker 0: That's a that's a good trick.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or secret speaker Secret speaker is also a good trick.
Speaker 0: Of course, it's hard to overpower the sound system It's.
Speaker 1: um, although the sound system itself you say my ours is a silent skit.
Speaker 1: That's how you do that good one See.
Speaker 1: and then of course your version of that is and then I bring out a tire iron and I kill the M's.
Speaker 0: well, no, what I would do is I would you know and have some sort of right cosplay.
Speaker 0: right and You know, I'd have a bunch of people but one person who is in the cosplay actually with us.
Speaker 0: You know The rest of us would know everything that was gonna happen and they would only know most of what was gonna happen and then maybe Like cover them with paint or something paint.
Speaker 0: I don't know something.
Speaker 1: God You know remind me to never let you pull a prank ever God.
Speaker 1: Anyway, what are you on the news?
Speaker 0: Ah, so being here a fool's day.
Speaker 0: It was not easy to find real news.
Speaker 0: I mean, I could have just looked at yesterday's news.
Speaker 0: That's what I did, but I was lazy.
Speaker 0: Actually, I've been wanting to talk about this all week Yeah, but anyway, there was one news that came out today that seems to be corroborated on multiple websites So I'll trust this as a true news.
Speaker 0: The news says that Ubisoft or Ubisoft or whatever you want to call it is gonna put a lot of their games Such as the Assassin's Creed's and the Far Cry's on Steam and that's you know, I guess it's a big news if you're a fan of those games.
Speaker 0: But really what this says to me is something that I semi predicted long ago Is that Steam is now becoming pretty much synonymous with high-end PC gaming.
Speaker 0: High-end PC gaming and Steam are like one in the same now Microsoft games for Windows and you know there I guess there was some sort of attempt to sort of mix the Xbox Live and Windows Vista in some way but that doesn't seem to be doing it.
Speaker 0: Steam seems to be where it's at and I really think you know since PC games are just not on the shelves at stores anymore.
Speaker 0: Really I think Valve Steam is pretty much gonna be the PC gaming source for the foreseeable future.
Speaker 1: I could see eventually.
Speaker 1: this is still.
Speaker 1: I think that what Steam what they should do is sell Steam as an operating system.
Speaker 0: they should they should but the only problem with Steam is that it only runs on Windows PCs and Not so much on Macs and Linux.
Speaker 0: and I there's so a vert.
Speaker 0: I guess it's so.
Speaker 0: a lot of the software is so heavily based in DirectX You know which is very.
Speaker 0: there's no blaming them for that because it is really easy to make high-end 3d games and direct.
Speaker 1: Like a lot of people I've said in the past Why don't you make like a virtual machine like I'll run on anything and I've actually been dealing with VMware because that no really hurt video card type performance action.
Speaker 1: if you do that beyond all that I've been actually working with some higher up engineers at VMware and with other Virtualization solutions, and I can tell you this Clock timekeeping.
Speaker 1: and when I say timekeeping, I don't just mean your clock is accurate.
Speaker 1: I mean like the ticks you cannot have accurate time.
Speaker 1: No accurate time means no video games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much so but really that's the only thing wrong with steam is it's limited to just Windows.
Speaker 0: And of course Windows is still number one in terms of numbers.
Speaker 0: So it's not a big problem.
Speaker 1: But for now, there's a really on the horizon.
Speaker 0: the Macs are getting crazy popular.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: Linux is you know more popular than it's ever been.
Speaker 0: it's it's significant even you know If it's not big.
Speaker 1: they could sell the steam hardware.
Speaker 1: It's a steam computer with steam OS and you can subscribe to periodic hardware updates.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the problem is that would be a lot of money.
Speaker 0: You see that's that's the problem really with gaming.
Speaker 0: Is that a gaming PC is a lot of money like that at least $1,500, right?
Speaker 0: So if you're spending that kind of money and all it does is play games you feel like a moron because For a lot less money, you could have gotten a ps3 or an Xbox 360 Which is still a lot of money which just plays games and maybe does a few more things.
Speaker 0: So if you're paying out for a PC You want it to still be able to do everything a PC can do because you're paying so much for in steam.
Speaker 1: you could run VMware to run Windows stuff.
Speaker 0: I guess they had to sell you a Windows license with your steam or just they could get bra.
Speaker 1: I mean, what do you need nowadays?
Speaker 1: You need web browser?
Speaker 0: Yeah word processor Can't even need word processor because you have Google Docs.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm talking about normal people not cool people.
Speaker 1: Google Docs Anyway, plus until Google Docs is fully integrated with Google Gears.
Speaker 1: I still need a word process.
Speaker 0: They really got to integrate that Google Gears more.
Speaker 0: That's like.
Speaker 0: but yeah, that's the only thing that's wrong with steam.
Speaker 0: And other than that steam in terms of PC gaming I think that's it's where it's gonna be at for a long time and they've pretty much Conquered the PC gaming world.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is I ever it really what let him do it, too Was that portal action?
Speaker 0: because before then steam was really just a thing for all the counter-strike peoples, you know in the half-life peoples.
Speaker 1: I remember when steam first came out.
Speaker 1: it sucked and was hated.
Speaker 1: It was awful.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why is it good?
Speaker 0: Well, yeah had problems.
Speaker 0: I never had problems with it But a lot of other people did and I won't deny that they.
Speaker 1: early on when it came out for a lot of people It was basically on here.
Speaker 1: I'm like the only person who never had problems with steam Yeah, but you also didn't play as many games as a lot of people.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: I mostly just played valves games and and mods like natural selection, but Yeah, oh, well.
Speaker 1: Well speaking of steam I know you all know I've bitched about this a bunch of times but that they're updating Team Fortress 2 now.
Speaker 1: Part of this.
Speaker 1: if you notice not many people are playing Team Fortress 2 anymore.
Speaker 1: That game did not win by any stretch.
Speaker 1: But the thing that they've been saying they're gonna go forward with is that they're gonna have Unlockable content as in if you get 20 achievements on the medic you unlock Extra medic guns and this is coming closer to reality.
Speaker 1: and it looks like in a couple of weeks We're gonna see the first bits of this.
Speaker 1: and I'm starting to worry but not worry too much because I tried to play Team Fortress 2 the other day and I remembered Oh, yeah, it's not the greatest game in the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'm playing Smash Brothers now and in a and then I'm gonna be playing Mario Kart and somewhere in there I'm getting the rondo of swords.
Speaker 1: So not so interested in Team Fortress 2 really but I'll say this my main complaint My main worry was alright, so you're gonna let people with crap metagame stuff unlock permanent things They can use in-game that have an effect.
Speaker 1: So in this interview, I found someone asked a question quote.
Speaker 1: It was IGN.
Speaker 1: actually if some players are running around with unlocked items and some aren't How are you taking steps to assure that gameplay remains balanced between classes?
Speaker 1: They basically said well all the new weapons are mostly balanced with each other.
Speaker 1: As in it's all about options.
Speaker 1: you have more options But they're balanced options like instead of getting invulnerability you get a hundred percent crit rate.
Speaker 1: great and Yeah, I don't want to get into this.
Speaker 1: I've talked about this a bunch but I think this is a crap move.
Speaker 1: and the worst thing is they kind of ask him like So why are you doing this?
Speaker 1: They basically talk about up?
Speaker 1: Well, this is the future gaming and this seems to be what people want.
Speaker 0: well, you know you look at it right and you look at numbers and sales and games that do have this sort of Persistence.
Speaker 0: or you know collecting Pokemon World of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: It's great for me.
Speaker 0: That's what the money's at.
Speaker 0: So that's where everyone's going.
Speaker 0: and I think you know, they made Team Fortress 2.
Speaker 0: They didn't have that stuff.
Speaker 0: their game sorta, you know, I mean, I guess it did well, but it mostly rode on portal.
Speaker 0: You know, no one not really as many people are playing it as you know.
Speaker 0: Ten years of waiting and the awesome style and all the hype and effort they put into it, you know should mean I mean, I don't have numbers but looking at just what.
Speaker 1: so how many people are on what servers?
Speaker 1: ah More people were playing counter-strike.
Speaker 1: My people are still playing counter-strike.
Speaker 1: then we're playing Team Fortress even in some of its peak days.
Speaker 1: Yep But I don't want to talk about that.
Speaker 1: I don't want to talk about all these problems.
Speaker 1: But I point out that I've seen a couple of references to the fact that they're now going to start releasing more of those.
Speaker 1: meet the whatever videos.
Speaker 1: I've seen multiple sources state that meet the scout is coming And I realized what those were and why they made a few and then they stopped making them.
Speaker 1: So I got a six shooter and I'm gonna shoot Scott, you know, it's a prank.
Speaker 1: It's April 1st.
Speaker 1: It's a prank.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna prank him.
Speaker 1: Yep, so I shot him twice in the head.
Speaker 1: Oh Now I could have kept shooting and emptied my gun But I got these bullets and he might die of those two gunshot wounds.
Speaker 1: So I'm just gonna keep those bullets and if the game does well, I don't need to even bother firing.
Speaker 1: I can keep him for another day.
Speaker 1: But if the game starts to falter zombies God's back from the grave.
Speaker 0: That's a good prank.
Speaker 0: Just ram sleeping at night thinks I'm dead zombies.
Speaker 0: God comes and eats his brain Doesn't see it coming.
Speaker 1: I can start firing off more of those bullets.
Speaker 1: Now the problem here is that what I see that it's kind of like my thing about Hillary Clinton.
Speaker 1: now the news I talked about last week wasn't a big deal in and of itself But the kind of reading between the lines was that Hillary's campaign is stalled and this is like the last chance grasping at straws.
Speaker 1: But I see valve is going down the same route here with Team Fortress 2.
Speaker 0: I also see the same route.
Speaker 0: They're basically saying shit.
Speaker 0: We spent a lot on.
Speaker 0: this game portal was a success.
Speaker 0: Half-life 2 kind of a success.
Speaker 0: Team Fortress 2 not a successor hoping for.
Speaker 0: let's do whatever we can to try to.
Speaker 0: You know make it into something but yet they're not doing what they need to do.
Speaker 1: I think the core problem with Team Fortress 2 was that it didn't actually target a demographic that exists.
Speaker 1: They unwanted I mean they tried to split two demographics.
Speaker 1: They wanted to be the.
Speaker 1: you don't need a lot of FPS skills.
Speaker 1: the console gamers can play it.
Speaker 1: It's pick up and run.
Speaker 1: It's simple.
Speaker 1: It's on the 360 and the ps3 and that demographic would rather play Halo Yep, and the other demographic is Hardcore.
Speaker 1: capture the flag.
Speaker 1: people who've been waiting for this game forever.
Speaker 1: There's no capture the flag in Team Fortress 2 worth a shit and they've released a couple more maps But by then all the hardcore people left.
Speaker 1: so no one plays those CTF maps.
Speaker 1: and what did they think to do?
Speaker 1: And what are they doing now?
Speaker 1: Gold rush a totally new mode.
Speaker 1: We have to walk a minecart past the enemies.
Speaker 0: That was always a good idea.
Speaker 0: I thought was to have some sort of map where you drive a car and then is it's not like that I know.
Speaker 0: and then yet you had to sorta remember they made what was that one in half-life one?
Speaker 0: With that with the vans and that everyone got in the trucks.
Speaker 0: Well, there was just Yeah Jeep a thon that's it.
Speaker 1: 2k man, you know what?
Speaker 1: I realized something Hardcore like you can tell the hardcore FPS gamer kind of like the hardcore anime fan Playing Jeep a thon was like watching Excel saga.
Speaker 1: Like if you're not already a fan of FPS is or already a fan of anime That means nothing to you and is not fun He put on is like the best hat Counter-Strike map ever.
Speaker 1: Jeep a thon was like this broken ass man.
Speaker 0: I remember driving up that ramp and half the time that you would just kill yourself.
Speaker 1: It looked like shit.
Speaker 1: It wasn't.
Speaker 1: but at the same time it embodied that hardcore.
Speaker 1: It's like it was.
Speaker 1: it was art.
Speaker 1: It was art and it was the same as the ready room and natural selection.
Speaker 0: I mean in a way right that the vehicles in more modern FPS is such as halo and unreal tournament and such are much better implemented than the vehicles in half-life 1.
Speaker 0: Yes, but there was something about the way Jeep a thon worked where that is the absolute best.
Speaker 0: one guy drives the Humvee and Three guys sit in the Humvee shooting out the windows at the other people in the other Humvee shooting out the windows Game that has ever existed and I mean also like remember the APC On on assault or it wasn't assault was it?
Speaker 1: it was one of those rare.
Speaker 0: I mean the one where you have to break into the base over the bridge but yet half the time you get in the APC and you start driving.
Speaker 0: and What the hell was that map call?
Speaker 0: that map doesn't exist.
Speaker 1: No It doesn't.
Speaker 1: but half the time You'd get in the APC and the driver would just back it up against the wall.
Speaker 1: So no, you could get out and then jump up and down on top of it until the enemies came and grenaded you to test.
Speaker 1: It's a thing of beauty, but it was more than like the community around the game would support that kind of meta barely gaming more like collaborative Experienced.
Speaker 1: it's hard to explain what was good about that And I'm not claiming that that was great in terms of gameplay by any stretch.
Speaker 1: But Team Fortress 2 didn't really capitalize on that and they didn't capitalize on the hardcore FPS capture the flag Which was like the basis of why I was looking forward to that game and the lack of it was the reason I stopped playing Though I can say this I played over the weekend for like 20 minutes.
Speaker 1: I joined a random server.
Speaker 1: It was 15 on 15 like one of those big old in an awesome mat and It the game been going for like 20 minutes.
Speaker 1: No time limit.
Speaker 1: No sudden death and it was zero to zero.
Speaker 1: I just turned into a scout and captured the flag three times.
Speaker 0: Immediately sounds about right?
Speaker 1: Yeah That was bragging.
Speaker 0: but I feel proud about that because the problem is a lot of people play that game.
Speaker 0: the way they play is They say I want to do this role.
Speaker 0: So they pick the role they want to do say sniper and then you just sit there and snipe and then they don't do anything.
Speaker 0: They don't think about the flag They don't think and then someone else's.
Speaker 0: I want to be the engineers.
Speaker 0: they sit there and they set up their thing and they maintain It and that's all they do now.
Speaker 0: and that because that's sort of that World of Warcraft style play.
Speaker 0: I want to be the healer.
Speaker 0: you just sit there and you pay attention to your little healing and you just heal as best You can.
Speaker 0: you don't think about the big picture winning the game or anything like that.
Speaker 0: You know sitting there doing busy work That's fine for games that kind of.
Speaker 1: I mean for World of Warcraft Like you want it.
Speaker 1: letting everyone do exactly what they want to do works But for a game like Team Fortress, it works for the casual gamer.
Speaker 1: doesn't work for the hardcore gamer.
Speaker 1: it's all the hardcore FPS people to even bother with the game and all the casual people left and The the thing I really want to point out at the end of this interview because this is a question.
Speaker 1: This says everything.
Speaker 1: Question will the console versions ever see these updates?
Speaker 1: No Answer we're still trying to figure that out.
Speaker 1: Yep right now We're working on a map pack that we hope will contain gold rush and the rest of the math We've shipped to the PC customers so far.
Speaker 0: Yeah map pack they can do.
Speaker 0: they've done map packs on the 360 before So there should be no reason why they can't do one now, but anything else.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they can be able to do that.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'm sort of on a disc.
Speaker 1: I think we need to set up some sort of all the old school FPSers versus the rest of the forum on Team Fortress 2 on a private server.
Speaker 0: Are we gonna tell who's the old school who's not?
Speaker 1: I think we will do the Turing test one by one.
Speaker 1: Well, well, you're like.
Speaker 1: we'll chat with each of you individually and I'll be.
Speaker 0: that's all you.
Speaker 0: I don't have time for that pretty much.
Speaker 1: It's have you ever played any of the following games?
Speaker 1: action quick to counter-strike 1.6.
Speaker 0: Yeah weapons factory I tried to play some counters like 1.6 last week and just as the getting was good everyone quit Like I sucked.
Speaker 0: cuz I parent I haven't played the game in years But I was getting it back and then everyone quit but there's one guy obviously cheating.
Speaker 0: So the vat the the the vac thing is not up to snuff really.
Speaker 0: it's still possible to cheat apparently.
Speaker 1: Anyway things of the day, so, you know They were coming and I love the fact that now we have the YouTube generation.
Speaker 1: We can see him right away.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: the thing is though.
Speaker 1: How come the YouTube generation doesn't know how to use the frickin video out of their?
Speaker 1: we Don't know why was every video capture cards but Anyway, there's so many ways to do this.
Speaker 1: if you have a camera Oh, this is not an April Fool's Day, by the way, if you have a camera kid Alright cameras always almost always video cameras also have a video.
Speaker 1: in autumn a lot of them do So you could have just pla anyway, so this video this is the best one out there.
Speaker 1: There's a glitch that has already been found in brawl.
Speaker 0: Well, you remember Smash Brothers Melee had a glitch with the black hole.
Speaker 1: It had a couple of glitches.
Speaker 1: the black hole was my favorite one by far.
Speaker 1: But this glitch is basically.
Speaker 1: So if you take jigglypuff, there's a couple of things I don't think people have figured out all of the things that will do this yet that will cause him to double in size suddenly and permanently.
Speaker 0: Well, you mean using his final smash makes him like no well it's complicated.
Speaker 1: this final smash makes him grow but there must be some sort of kind of like.
Speaker 1: how if you add a bold tag and forget to unbold it or You add an unbold tag, but there's no bold tag in front of it Like.
Speaker 1: or you have a paren that opened something but you forget to have the clothes paren.
Speaker 1: So now you've got like all these friends that are out of sync if a certain thing happens.
Speaker 1: Something like that must have happened with jigglypuff because if you interrupt his final smash in any way or If you cancel it and then certain things happen, you'll double in size.
Speaker 0: Well, if you use if you do with the final smash, it looks like he'll remain at final smash size.
Speaker 0: But there's another trick with Yoshi that will double his size.
Speaker 1: So this video outlines both of those and then they do what.
Speaker 1: all you're all thinking What if I combine them?
Speaker 1: and the answer is it doubles the size whatever the size may be.
Speaker 0: So when he's if you make a jigglypuff really small and then do the trick He'll be the same size small but times two.
Speaker 1: So if he already takes up half the screen and then you do the trick whoa?
Speaker 1: now yes, now the the interesting thing to note is that it appears that double size jigglypuff is Absolutely useless and furthermore is no more powerful than any normal jigglypuff.
Speaker 1: But this is really cool and really awesome And I love the fact that kids find these things and post videos of them.
Speaker 0: If anyone can pull this off in like a tournament like for reals You're the win man.
Speaker 1: I would I would collaborate with other people like at a team tournament get Yoshi jigglypuff combo and then you know Just collaborate with a bunch of people and be like if we face each other.
Speaker 1: Let's do it kind of like those two guys.
Speaker 1: then ping-pong tournament with that one round of just crazy hilarity.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, just like that.
Speaker 1: But anyway, what do you got for me?
Speaker 0: Okay, so You know back in the day There's a kind of game to play on the web right where you know I mean lately the big thing has been flash games tower defense kind of stuff, right?
Speaker 0: That's well and good But there's a style of web game.
Speaker 0: It's actually a style of game that's been around since the BBS days where it's a game that you sort of check in on Once in a while like the game is literally always going but it goes very slowly.
Speaker 0: So imagine like an RTS where your guys walk real slow.
Speaker 0: Well, you can walk away from it for like a few hours and come back and walk away and come back.
Speaker 0: and since it's so slow you just sort of when you come back you sort of do all your stuff and then you walk away and you can you know You can even forget about it for a day or two and then come back and it's still okay, you know you can't get killed.
Speaker 0: so instantly cuz everyone else is going really slowly.
Speaker 0: also and Basically, there's a website.
Speaker 0: I found e carry him.
Speaker 0: I think it or I carry him.
Speaker 0: I don't know how to correct pronunciation.
Speaker 0: That's I K AR.
Speaker 0: I am dot org and it's basically a simplified version of civilization.
Speaker 0: But you know play it on the web and you only have to check in like once or twice a day Maybe and you'll be just fine.
Speaker 1: I played a game like this and so did Scott and everyone else in the crew And our IT was sort of wizards and you build.
Speaker 0: that one was pretty much just like.
Speaker 0: you have ten nights You know and he just had the word nights and the number ten gaga.
Speaker 0: This one actually looks like civilization.
Speaker 0: there's graphics and the user interface and the whole thing and it's really slick and it's free.
Speaker 0: There's that.
Speaker 0: there's a mode.
Speaker 0: you can pay for like.
Speaker 0: I carry them plus but I'm not paying for that And we're I'm on the Zeta server.
Speaker 0: So everyone who I told already followed me to the Zeta server.
Speaker 0: I chose the Zeta server at completely arbitrarily.
Speaker 0: So if there's actually a difference between the servers we can you know, maybe fix that or something.
Speaker 0: But our plan is to make a giant alliance on the Zeta server and conquer the whole server at least as much as possible.
Speaker 0: Hmm, we'll see that'll probably take a while.
Speaker 0: My current short-term strategy is basically I'm upgrading my Academy and nothing else and trying to get All the science.
Speaker 0: So once I get all the science then I'll be able to like just upgrade my place crazily to full-on and then Build a giant army and slowly conquer everything near me.
Speaker 0: That's my.
Speaker 0: that's my strategy for the.
Speaker 1: I have yet to even look at this game.
Speaker 1: I didn't have time.
Speaker 1: I was actually working at work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you may you may or may not enjoy it.
Speaker 0: You know, this is the kind of thing where I'll probably log into it in the morning I'll admit log into it maybe at lunch and log into it You know, maybe don't when I get home don't misplace my.
Speaker 1: I haven't tried it yet with cynicism.
Speaker 1: I love games like this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it just most of the games like this aren't always that good.
Speaker 1: But the thing is it's not Is so little.
Speaker 0: yeah, there are already some problems with it that I'm that I'm starting to detect and that you know They're pretty much.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna get into it now, but this is you know, it's it's at least gonna occupy You know the the the attention of some people's for at least a few weeks I'm assuming.
Speaker 0: so get in it while strike while the iron's hot.
Speaker 1: Well, actually I played that mage.
Speaker 1: It was like the ascension or something.
Speaker 1: I forget what it was exactly.
Speaker 0: I think I might have played something called anarchy but I don't remember.
Speaker 1: all I remember is that I decided to be like white magic and I was.
Speaker 1: I was very defensive and my people were prosperous and my goal was not to expand or engage in like the crazy PvP, but to Expand slowly and moderately and then just have this gigantic perfectly stable utterly defensible Kingdom.
Speaker 1: And then I found out that they periodically just reset the game and make everyone start over and then I just quit.
Speaker 0: No, screw that shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I'm gonna have a persistent world, I want a persistent goddamn world.
Speaker 0: Yes, that is.
Speaker 0: one thing is that this is sort of like it's civilization But every you know, every city in town is owned by someone.
Speaker 0: if you attack someone's gonna You know come home at night log in for five minutes and they're gonna see Scott is attacking you and they're gonna be like that Fucker.
Speaker 1: also the the way of doling out resources and time and that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: in general I'd like to do a show on game mechanics or like different collaborative or multiplayer game mechanics because this is one very Underutilized mechanic that has great promise like good God.
Speaker 1: Could you do awesome things with this idea?
Speaker 1: But mostly people have made very simple games so far.
Speaker 0: Yep Alright, you want to get on with the show?
Speaker 1: I think we can All right, so you have a little more venom in you than me about this.
Speaker 0: You can introduce the time some venoms a bit.
Speaker 1: Basically, I have a little more venom because I think I invested a lot more time and money into these things than you Maybe but I invested quite a bit of time and money.
Speaker 0: I got the box of cards to prove it under my bed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: my box of cards is in Arizona far enough away to where I'll never be tempted to play it Again, yeah, I'm never gonna be tempted.
Speaker 0: Anyway, basically we're talking about collectible games.
Speaker 0: Collectible card games are the most popular subset.
Speaker 0: We're gonna talk about collectible games in general here.
Speaker 0: We'll probably do another show on mad just magic itself in the future But we'll both be using magic as an example quite often but also other things now.
Speaker 0: But a collectible game is is it's a game just like any other game, you know Just like Puerto Rico or anything except the pieces of that game.
Speaker 0: You have to collect them.
Speaker 0: So imagine if you are gonna play say collectible chess, right?
Speaker 0: But everyone wasn't just always playing with the same chess pieces every time, you know one guy He was wicked rich went out on eBay and bought a full set of Queens and he just all Queens.
Speaker 0: Everyone else is playing with like mostly pawns and like.
Speaker 0: maybe they were lucky and they had like one Queen and a few bishops You know and me and such.
Speaker 0: that's what a collectible game is.
Speaker 1: now I just want to point out that we because we have to make this clear right away because there are Games that are like this that are not actually collectible games.
Speaker 1: They're a completely different kind of game.
Speaker 0: Yes, for example Take magic gathering right?
Speaker 0: It is a collectible game.
Speaker 0: when you buy cards at least the official way you're buying them.
Speaker 0: You know sort of randomly, you know And you know, there is a I guess collecting market and a collector's value to the cards and such.
Speaker 1: You know what if you and all your friends each bought one revised set one dark set and one legend set Everyone had the exact same list of cards and then you created decks and fought with each other?
Speaker 0: Well, that's just a customizable game.
Speaker 0: You see because everyone is playing with the same set I mean, let's say we're playing the customizable Collectible chess, right, but we agree that all right You know, we look at everyone.
Speaker 0: everyone has managed, you know, what chess pieces everyone has managed to collect.
Speaker 0: and we say all right everyone.
Speaker 0: You know you.
Speaker 0: you can have these sets of pieces and then make you know pick whichever ones you want from these.
Speaker 0: So no one can make a full set of Queens even if they own them because we're gonna you know Arbitrarily limit you in this case.
Speaker 0: So in that case you can actually preserve and have a good Customizable game where people can customize what they're using to play the game.
Speaker 0: But it's still not the.
Speaker 0: the influence of it being collectible doesn't ruin the game.
Speaker 1: part now the smart kids who play magic.
Speaker 1: I don't know how it is now because there's so many cards that I've got the fact that magic is still going and that they have actually plotted out every expansion that's gonna be released through like 2012 when I guess they didn't go beyond that because that's when gets the Guadal is gonna kick everyone's ass, right?
Speaker 1: But The The fucking magic.
Speaker 1: Yeah But the smart kids did.
Speaker 1: I lost my train of thought.
Speaker 1: I was trying to cover that up But was that what I did?
Speaker 1: what a lot of us did is we would take land and we write Mox emerald or black Lotus on them and we'd still follow the rules for creation.
Speaker 1: But if we didn't own a card We would do that so that we could play with these cards because otherwise the rich kid who bought Great wall of magic, which literally was just every wall ever released in magic up to that point I also ended up acquiring that at some point because guy was stupid and That was also before the internet where you couldn't just look up all the awesome old car
Speaker 0: as he gets cry magazine to get.
Speaker 1: That's the whole show in and of itself.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Remember magic the conquering?
Speaker 1: no Oh, it was a basically was a way to play magic on a board where you move the creatures around.
Speaker 0: But there are other sorts of collectible games like that.
Speaker 0: don't have this problem.
Speaker 0: for example take a war hammer.
Speaker 0: right war hammer is collectible, you know, but the thing is is You know exactly what you're buying.
Speaker 0: you go to the store and you say I want five of those and ten of those.
Speaker 0: now The thing is there's still a matter of having enough money to play the game, but more money doesn't mean more winning.
Speaker 1: It does If you can't afford the pieces you want.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, that's true more that there's no limit of supply.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not like magic where well, you can't get a black Lotus.
Speaker 1: There aren't any in your town.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or in the thing is a game like war hammer is actually a good game all around.
Speaker 0: It's just because it's somewhat collectible not randomly collectible, but like magic but collectible in a way.
Speaker 0: It's very expensive game.
Speaker 0: So basically if you have a lot of money It's a good game and you can play it.
Speaker 0: But if you don't have a lot of money You probably shouldn't play it because you can't just cost too much pieces of cardboard with you know things written on them.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I'll say this trying to play a war game like that.
Speaker 1: You might say hey the pieces are just fluff.
Speaker 1: They just like add color to the game.
Speaker 1: That's like saying yeah graphics are just fluff.
Speaker 1: You don't need graphics in a game and then Imagine if half-life 2 looked like doom.
Speaker 1: It wouldn't have been as immersive or good a game.
Speaker 1: war war hammer and all that.
Speaker 1: I've tried to play those games with just pieces of cardboard and it's just not nearly as engaging.
Speaker 0: and if you're gonna battle the battle Tech you can play but you.
Speaker 0: even then you can't get too big a game going on or else it becomes unmanageable without real pieces.
Speaker 1: yeah, but I don't know how much we have to say about what's wrong with collectible games because it comes down to Basically if you spend money you can just pretty much make a better thing Or have a better chance of winning.
Speaker 1: it adds this whole meta element your Factors affect the game that have nothing to do with the game itself.
Speaker 1: There's kind of this real-world game of collecting now Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: See there is an additional thing though.
Speaker 0: Is that it is true?
Speaker 0: A lot of people say that like oh, it's not just whoever has the most money wins.
Speaker 0: Well in magic it was what.
Speaker 1: in magic it was magic.
Speaker 0: in the early days It was but now it's.
Speaker 0: it's really not.
Speaker 0: I mean Bill Gates could just buy every magic card ever But he probably still won't beat like world champions because he doesn't you know know how the game works and doesn't know how to play.
Speaker 1: What have you heard?
Speaker 1: someone else to make a deck for him?
Speaker 1: The strategies are very simple.
Speaker 0: They used to sell on, you know sets to be like this is the deck the champion used last year You know.
Speaker 0: and like you could buy this you could buy two of those give one to your friend and play against each other You know and it still would come down to be who is better.
Speaker 1: So well, it depends because.
Speaker 0: and randomness because it is a game of drawing cards out of a deck There is a lot of randomness.
Speaker 1: There's also other troubles in that.
Speaker 1: The reason they were able to keep magic going like that was that they kind of had different kinds of tournaments.
Speaker 1: I mean when I stopped playing magic Seriously a type 2 tournament meant you could use revised fallen empires and the dark.
Speaker 0: Yeah, when I played I plan to one magic tournament and then I stopped playing magic forever.
Speaker 0: The type 1 tournament was like you can use anything almost except for banned cards and whatnot.
Speaker 1: For me already that was type like.
Speaker 1: that was type 0. and then type 1 was you can use everything except these restrictions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, type 2 is like you can use fourth edition and you know any.
Speaker 0: you know new cards But basically you could use still in print and available cards that normal people could get.
Speaker 1: I'm sure they've changed.
Speaker 0: But the rules I'm sure a lot of things have changed.
Speaker 1: But the actual type 2 rules used to be you can use the most recent Normal base set and the previous two released Expansion sets and that's it.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't know.
Speaker 0: The thing is is that collectible gaming it sort of has, you know I've done a collecting rant on the show before.
Speaker 0: I don't know what episode it was.
Speaker 0: I could do it again in the future perhaps revise it in some ways.
Speaker 0: But basically, you know when I was a kid my dad would you know occasionally bring home like, you know Some baseball cards or something, you know, and it was fun.
Speaker 0: I liked it when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: and then Like I sometimes I get like a sticker book.
Speaker 0: You get like a book and you get a pack of stickers and the stickers are on cards and like each card had two stickers It was like a pack of cards.
Speaker 0: but really it was like a whole bunch of stickers and you put them in the book and you would try to fill the whole Book.
Speaker 0: and you know, it was.
Speaker 0: it was sort of fun and like I had like a little collect.
Speaker 0: I wasn't like a super collector when I was a kid, you know.
Speaker 0: But you know, I like to put like the baseball cards in order had a little bit of OCD action going on.
Speaker 1: You know, I had a green binder a blue binder a black binder a white binder.
Speaker 0: Well, you went all out.
Speaker 0: I just have a box.
Speaker 0: I still have the same box I use.
Speaker 1: the cards were organized by type and then within type alphabetically.
Speaker 0: You went way more than I did.
Speaker 0: I just sort of you know Organized them by color green white red blue black in order of how much I like the fact that I needed the gold binder Cuz.
Speaker 1: I had enough gold cards from like legends and all that.
Speaker 0: I didn't have that many cards and then I would sort of do it like by.
Speaker 0: I do like by type and then sort of by how good I felt they were.
Speaker 0: like if I like my Force of nature would sort of be in the front of the green creatures, you know.
Speaker 0: And like the like the shitty one one green creatures would be in the back You know.
Speaker 0: and then the forests and then the white cards and such.
Speaker 0: but yeah, you know I had a little OCD kind of action.
Speaker 0: I was a kid, you know, I collect the comic books You know, I sort of had to get all the issues and I keep him in order and such and everything.
Speaker 1: You know, I used to collect x-men cards, but I got.
Speaker 0: I have a lot of x-men cards Under my bed.
Speaker 0: I really like those superhero cards.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what those are actually really good.
Speaker 1: as much as I hate superhero comics I actually did like those cards a lot.
Speaker 1: I still have mine.
Speaker 0: Yeah superhero cards, you know while collecting them was kind of you know That was a problem.
Speaker 1: Hey, does anyone want to buy a full set of the foil?
Speaker 1: Special reprints from the Wolverine seasons or series - yeah, I don't need him anymore.
Speaker 0: You could probably be that shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe I could maybe.
Speaker 0: But actually that you know Some of those cards, you know, they didn't do anything right but they had sort of like an entertainment value.
Speaker 0: Like you would read the text on the back and you would look at the art I remember trying to like, you know trace the superheroes off of the cards.
Speaker 0: They try to learn how to draw them and stuff You know, there was.
Speaker 0: there was some merit to them at least a little bit, you know, not much.
Speaker 0: But then as I grew older I sort of realized, you know around the time when I was actually began spending my money on these Things and not someone else's money That you know collecting was really dumb and a waste of money and and a waste of time and it was pretty much just getting enjoyment from owning something pretty much the height of materialism and consumerism and such.
Speaker 0: and Really?
Speaker 0: What I wanted to do was play.
Speaker 0: and I realized you know I look back at what I had done with Magic the Gathering.
Speaker 0: I had done a lot more Collecting Magic the Gathering than playing like.
Speaker 0: I spent a lot of time like sitting around my room play it looking at the cards reading them.
Speaker 1: I spent a lot.
Speaker 1: I spent a lot more time like Designing decks and designing designing decks, but I never could play with those decks because the decks always needed cards.
Speaker 1: I didn't have yeah.
Speaker 0: and reading magazines reading.
Speaker 0: I have a little book.
Speaker 0: I still have the book like how to win at magic.
Speaker 1: I go to conventions and try to like trade man.
Speaker 0: There was a time when you can I had a few friends I would play with but we didn't play well And I never had you know the cards.
Speaker 0: I really wanted to play well, and I went to that.
Speaker 0: one time I went to that tournament right.
Speaker 0: I had a deck like planned like.
Speaker 0: I had this clever idea.
Speaker 0: I thought I was so clever when I was a punk stupid kid right and I made this little deck And I got it pretty close You know with the money I had.
Speaker 0: you know because that was pretty much the only time I was able to buy cards Individually is that that little tournament place, and then I went I played and I just got hosed by someone.
Speaker 0: I actually knew what they were doing man.
Speaker 1: I designed this awesome deck.
Speaker 1: It was basically I called it the Annihilator.
Speaker 1: We'll save that for the magic show, but that deck was like the best fucking deck ever.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 0: So you know I started that died out and then in college You know we were playing the battle tech and they came out with this mech warrior mage night.
Speaker 0: You know the clicks thingies.
Speaker 1: well god I all I remember is that everyone else in the front row crew and all of our like tertiary friends not everyone Almost everyone was like hot shit.
Speaker 1: check it out.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, and I took one look at it and said that game is shit.
Speaker 1: It's mostly random.
Speaker 1: It's not a game.
Speaker 1: look at it doesn't?
Speaker 1: it's not even battle tech this half and half next on him It's just numbers that you click.
Speaker 1: It's nothing.
Speaker 1: yeah Well like the only one who didn't I had played.
Speaker 1: I believe Scott himself called me stupid and not into this thing.
Speaker 0: I admit it.
Speaker 0: I was wrong in the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there were like I remember multiple times.
Speaker 1: You'd be like man You're missing out.
Speaker 1: I was playing with Luke and Greg and that and then like a week later.
Speaker 1: He's like yeah I'm done with that game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically that the thing is with the clicks games.
Speaker 0: the clicks games are actually it's not a bad functional idea.
Speaker 0: Right you play a tabletop.
Speaker 0: You know miniatures war game right except the pieces click and Sort of as they take damage.
Speaker 0: you can actually click the pieces.
Speaker 0: You don't have to like keep track on a piece of paper, and it's it's much less finicky.
Speaker 0: And it's it's.
Speaker 0: it's a pretty good idea.
Speaker 0: The thing is the way they sell those games Right like the hero clicks and the mage knight and the.
Speaker 0: whatnot is you're trying to collect the pieces and some are better than others.
Speaker 0: it is better.
Speaker 0: and You know we actually played the mech warrior game quite a few times because we had a lot of people going in on it And it was sort of you know that collecting bug like came and bit me again And I was like you know if I had ten more bucks as larger.
Speaker 0: is this not buying a few more?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that would be an awesome mech in the in the next little box I bought.
Speaker 1: but then you realize that there was actually no strategy in the game other than have your tanks next to your max.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean then I actually kept playing the game enough, and I fully realized you know after a few plays Wow There's real this isn't really.
Speaker 0: um.
Speaker 0: You know it doesn't matter what my strategy is It's pretty much just that it just kind of happens, and it's not a good game.
Speaker 0: and even if it was a good game It was still.
Speaker 0: you know the collectible aspect of it You know also hit me like wow if I just had better mechs I would win even if my strategy was a lot dumber and even if strategy mattered.
Speaker 0: and That was like the final nail in the coffin for the collectible games for me.
Speaker 0: And I sort of went back and now I only play non collectible games.
Speaker 0: thing is Customizable games are awesome are still good, and it's the thing is a customizable game And it's very nature.
Speaker 0: think stratego is a customizable game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we both have a set and there's a set of rules for putting your things onto the board.
Speaker 1: And what do you want to do?
Speaker 1: and then we play.
Speaker 1: yeah the way I punked Scott over the weekend.
Speaker 0: I won one out of three which is and the thing is when you play a customizable game right collectible or not There is a rock-paper-scissors element to that.
Speaker 0: in stratego the rock-paper-scissors is very strong.
Speaker 1: We've done a show on Stratego.
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 0: yes, okay in magic the gathering at least when I played it the rock-paper-scissors is pretty strong.
Speaker 0: you had You know COP red and the other guy had a red deck.
Speaker 0: that's rock-paper-scissors.
Speaker 0: I win.
Speaker 0: I mean come on.
Speaker 1: so I had the sideboard full of COP.
Speaker 0: that was one strategy.
Speaker 0: was the sideboard full of COPs?
Speaker 1: I remember when I played it, and I played a tournament for so long.
Speaker 1: I played it a non-tournament.
Speaker 1: I was at a friend's house.
Speaker 1: We played the first game, and then I was like all right I'm swapping four cars in my sideboard.
Speaker 1: He was like fuck you no sideboards.
Speaker 1: I was like what sideboard they punched me.
Speaker 0: yeah see me and all my friends.
Speaker 0: We you know we all read like the you know the magazine.
Speaker 0: so we sort of knew the tournament rules and played with them thinking We were all smart.
Speaker 0: and then at the tournament the rules are actually different because we were the dumbass.
Speaker 0: punk.
Speaker 0: kids are behind the times with no internets.
Speaker 1: See actually I mostly.
Speaker 1: we had a lot of fun playing star as opposed to anything else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, I think we're done.
Speaker 1: I think we said all we need to say about collectible games.
Speaker 1: They're kind of poop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, collectible games not good collecting in general not so admirable not so exciting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not really.
Speaker 0: It's it's not worth the money.
Speaker 0: You can get a lot better gaming without collecting.
Speaker 0: There are a lot better ways to spend your money besides collecting.
Speaker 0: even if you're profiting from your collecting There's probably with all that time and effort you put into that you could probably be making more money with a job.
Speaker 0: It's it's really just bad.
Speaker 0: That's so that collectible type things have eaten up and the collecting bug has eaten up so much of geekery And it's caused a lot of side effects and other areas of geekery.
Speaker 1: Look at anime like no one.
Speaker 1: there aren't many anime Chachki collectors anymore and how many people actually still play magic?
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is like look collectible gaming has done significant damage to actual sort of bet.
Speaker 0: quote better gaming.
Speaker 0: You know, I mean if there wasn't any collectible gaming they you know.
Speaker 1: at one hand it brought a lot of people into gaming at the same time that that argument reeks a little bit of what I heard a lot.
Speaker 1: when magic was super popular and Dungeons & Dragons people were basically saying Magic is ruining.
Speaker 1: I try to run my game but everyone just wants to play magic instead and they all have their decks out and blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: and I'm just whining because Actually, I'm a crappy DM and my players are bored and that's why they're playing magic.
Speaker 0: Yeah There is an aspect I'm not talking about there I want to do.
Speaker 0: I'm not talking about it on the.
Speaker 0: on the.
Speaker 0: you know The human individual level I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: on the industry level, you know The gaming industry has has moved in a certain direction because of the popularity and the money It can make the collectible games.
Speaker 0: The video game industry has moved in a certain direction because of you know, the MMOs We just saw that in your in your news with you know valve and such right.
Speaker 0: the the the comic book industry has moved in A certain way because there are people collecting comic books as opposed to just caring about reading them.
Speaker 0: that's why you see the same comic book come out with three different covers because they know that some nerd will buy all three covers and they can make more money off of him.
Speaker 0: and You know collectible gaming is damaged gaming in that same way.
Speaker 0: And yeah, it's not the happiest thing and I really even if there's a really good collectible game I do not suggest that anyone play it unless it's if it's really good.
Speaker 0: It was really good by.
Speaker 1: a bunch of complete sets are enough.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like we tried to do that with the penny arcade game We just bought one set and we played it.
Speaker 0: It was a terrible game.
Speaker 1: That's like what I think that is in terms of dollars spent per unit.
Speaker 1: bad the best deal ever.
Speaker 0: if you like bad game if you like bad games, yes by the penny arcade collectible card game and Basically, it's it's fair and it's a terrible game.
Speaker 0: and I went it.
Speaker 0: we did a show on it didn't we?
Speaker 0: Yes, we did a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I think we're done.
Speaker 0: We're done.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has Everything.
Speaker 0: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.