Speaker 1: It's Wednesday May 14th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight we review the ice.
Speaker 1: oh hey be Let's do this.
Speaker 1: How's this morning?
Speaker 1: It was a little weird mostly because well rim went to work later than usual right.
Speaker 1: so yeah, I'm late.
Speaker 1: It's great taking that like 705 train, so I woke up You know at my normal time, but like people were using the showers.
Speaker 1: I was like uh And then I remembered that my I was being made to work late.
Speaker 1: So I said you know what I'm just gonna take like the eight something train the 817 all right all right.
Speaker 1: So I think they 17.
Speaker 0: I don't think I've ever taken a train that late.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think they'd 17 um but also in addition to that right I was sort of like.
Speaker 1: you know I took my sweet time because I had so much time for the 817 right But in taking my sweet time.
Speaker 1: I took more time with say reading email than I took with say eating.
Speaker 0: You know that happens.
Speaker 0: I'll be like oh, man.
Speaker 0: I showered quickly.
Speaker 0: I'm done.
Speaker 0: I got some free time this morning, and I do this many mornings, so I'll go.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go read the internet for a couple minutes, and I sit down and like all right I got 15 minutes to do this, and then I'll be good,
Speaker 1: and then you look at the clock yet And it's like it's
Speaker 0: been like 25 minutes like ah That is never not happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah So I pretty much Ran out of the house with a piece of rye bread in my mouth And I was as I was opening the door to my car.
Speaker 1: I had this piece of rye bread in my mouth.
Speaker 1: all I could think of was school girls with toast.
Speaker 0: It's totally rain.
Speaker 1: We're late for school ray from the end of Ava I don't know But that's it's a. it's a classic thing that they do in a lot of those school girl late for school.
Speaker 0: There's something about a girl a school girl running with toast in her mouth And it happens all the time.
Speaker 1: so in addition to that right check this out, right?
Speaker 1: I Was at my parents house like a couple weeks ago, and I brought some laundry.
Speaker 1: my mom did the laundry right?
Speaker 0: Wow I haven't had that luxury in life.
Speaker 1: my mom will do your laundry if you want.
Speaker 0: my mom hasn't done my laundry in like A decade.
Speaker 1: I would if I had a dryer.
Speaker 1: I would never give my mom even a single sock, but I don't have a dryer.
Speaker 1: so socks She she washed.
Speaker 1: let's get a drive the machine put in the machine that they the machine was.
Speaker 0: just buy a house And then buy a dryer.
Speaker 0: dishwasher put it in the house, I think dryer takes precedence.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that does, but both are.
Speaker 1: It's a close to it is anyway, so When she did this laundry she must have cleaned a pair of my father's jeans.
Speaker 1: Cuz when I got home that pulled a pair of jeans out of the basket, and they were much too large for me.
Speaker 1: I was like huh alrighty, and then I went back to my parents house last weekend, and I said oh, yeah I forgot I have a pair of your jeans, and he's like oh, why didn't you bring them like I forgot?
Speaker 1: he's like well You know I'm driving out somewhere such-and-such for work in a few days.
Speaker 1: You know I'll let you know and then you could just like leave the jeans like you know in the screen door or something right?
Speaker 1: So you left me a voicemail last night like let me know if you're gonna leave the jeans.
Speaker 1: if you're not good I'm not gonna bother stopping over right.
Speaker 1: so our this morning with all that free time I remembered.
Speaker 1: so I called my dad, and I said yeah, I'm gonna leave the jeans there, but then I Work and I get a phone call.
Speaker 1: I like who the hell's calling me I pick it up, and he's like where the jeans.
Speaker 0: you know you know what the answer is Hobo must have stolen.
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: They're in my bedroom on the floor.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, the thing is he has a key to my house.
Speaker 1: He doesn't have it on him, so I was just like ah I made you Take a little tiny detour from your trip to stop at the house.
Speaker 1: I didn't leave the jeans.
Speaker 0: at least it's not that bad a detour because the one of them it like.
Speaker 0: Probably the best benefit of living in Beacon for us You know with gig nights and traveling all the time is that we know we always have this discussion.
Speaker 0: We always think why don't we just move to Brooklyn?
Speaker 0: god damn it?
Speaker 0: We should live in Brooklyn.
Speaker 0: Brooklyn is awesome blah blah blah, and then we always realize suddenly if you look at a map There's pretty much no way out of Brooklyn.
Speaker 0: The subway yeah, but now with a car?
Speaker 0: no no not really.
Speaker 0: and In Beacon we live pretty much at the junction of two of the like the biggest freeways in the area.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's hard to get to 95 which is one of the most maybe the most important highway in the area.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's not.
Speaker 1: it's very much like we can get to all the highways except that one.
Speaker 0: It's like there's two things we can get to every highway except 95 and we can get to every city except Philadelphia.
Speaker 1: yep well cuz 95 is like the Philadelphia, Iowa, but yeah, yeah, there are some.
Speaker 0: I was actually I was reading about the freeway projects that are coming up.
Speaker 0: There's some long-term projects that'll make it a lot easier for us to get to 95.
Speaker 1: yeah the main problem is that the shortest way to get to 95 involves going closer to New York City and the hiccups.
Speaker 1: Hiccup yeah the traffic involved in going near New York City makes it not worth it.
Speaker 1: So it's you're better off avoiding the city.
Speaker 1: so you avoid the city Avoid the city and you want to get to 95. that means you have to take the Garden State into Jersey then take like.
Speaker 1: Then we have to switch over to 95 where the Garden State 95 really close to each other.
Speaker 0: a little hint for any non New Yorkers.
Speaker 0: that's always the faster way.
Speaker 0: yeah unless it's four in the morning And there's no baseball game.
Speaker 1: the problem is is that puts us way south you know on 95.
Speaker 1: So it's like the place that we there are places that are north of that juncture on 95.
Speaker 1: We might want to get to.
Speaker 1: that become difficult to get to yeah But at the same time it actually is really really fast to get to like Otacon and Kotsukkad like oh Yeah, we're going anywhere Jersey, and you know mid Jersey and south then it's it's not a problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course we have the problem now of all right.
Speaker 0: so say we want to go hang out with Scott Johnson in Wildwood some Weekend all right.
Speaker 0: well We're in New York City.
Speaker 0: So we take the train back home on Friday an hour north And then we get in a car and drive an hour south, and then we continue driving.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's nowhere easy to leave a car.
Speaker 0: Nope, I mean and the thing is I'd say oh well I'll just drive into Manhattan because there's a parking garage not right next to where I work cause of a jillion dollars And it's full.
Speaker 0: I could get in.
Speaker 0: you know early I work and most of a lot of my co-workers drive in anyway.
Speaker 0: Wow yeah, but the problem There is that my car is not doing so well now I discovered that the just actually today that the source of my problem.
Speaker 0: Is that my transmission?
Speaker 0: No, it's not so happy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I'd have to take Scott's car, but Scott won't let me drive his car Destroy it.
Speaker 1: look at your car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my car.
Speaker 0: That's destroyed mostly because it's oh you also crashed it like twice.
Speaker 0: Well, it was crashed into twice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I I know car.
Speaker 1: have I ever driven?
Speaker 1: has ever been crashed by me Or been crashed into?
Speaker 0: at the same time you've driven a pitiful fraction of the number of miles I've driven in my life.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh I've driven plenty's not so much plenty.
Speaker 0: all those weekends I'd be driving back and forth between Rochester and Detroit.
Speaker 0: That time that crazy road trip from Poughkeepsie to Lansing and then two days later from Detroit to Wildwood.
Speaker 1: Regardless You know if you had some fancy new car.
Speaker 1: I don't think you would be letting unsafe drivers drive it.
Speaker 0: I'd let you drive it in a second, and you're a pretty crappy driver all things considered.
Speaker 1: What are you talking about?
Speaker 1: maybe look who's talking mr.. Crash you dig talking to mr.. No crash.
Speaker 0: what I've never caused an accident ever.
Speaker 1: You've been in accidents.
Speaker 1: I have been in no Scott.
Speaker 0: one of those accidents my car was parked in a parking garage and someone rammed into it while I wasn't there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's never happened to me cuz.
Speaker 1: yes because that was clearly my well you parked in the parking garage Yeah, and in the wrong spot.
Speaker 0: Yes at my job Exactly.
Speaker 0: anyway bring on your anime news captain.
Speaker 0: It's anime day.
Speaker 1: Oh shits.
Speaker 1: Oh, I don't have anime news.
Speaker 1: That's right There isn't really any but I do have.
Speaker 1: it's a time for a geek bite.
Speaker 1: I got it right didn't?
Speaker 1: I didn't say back but I've invite.
Speaker 1: so Scott's box.
Speaker 1: I talked about a lot of things last time and people complained like we thought you were actually gonna review the things in the box, and I'm like listen I Just got the box.
Speaker 1: you expect me to read all that like instantly.
Speaker 1: There's got to be reasonable expectations here people.
Speaker 1: all right.
Speaker 0: well You kind of reviewed everything a little bit the first time you did the box.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: I did it the second time also.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the second time you did a lot more of well This is this and this is this and this is this.
Speaker 0: and a lot less of the why and the interest And a lot more of the.
Speaker 0: this is the name of this.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll maybe I'll go back and I'll listen to both boxes.
Speaker 1: I think you should maybe I will but regardless you know to please you people who are looking for the reviews right here sort of I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna dig into the box.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna tell you I read some of the stuff.
Speaker 1: of course I'm gonna tell you what it was like.
Speaker 1: so one of the things I read was This Avengers Kree's Kroll war.
Speaker 0: you might remember when I told sounds excellent.
Speaker 1: You might remember when I pulled this out of the box that I said the reason I bought this is because of all the Marvel Comics, I've read in my day good and bad.
Speaker 1: you know they.
Speaker 1: a lot of them refer to the Kree's Kroll war you know as as an major event in history that was super important and Such and that I had never actually read.
Speaker 1: you know what happened during this Kree's Kroll war that was so important that people keep Talking about it years later and keep referring to it in comics years later.
Speaker 1: good and bad.
Speaker 1: so I saw that there was a trade paperback of the Kree's Kroll war and I ordered it and I've read it.
Speaker 1: and Well I don't want to Peter on the bush.
Speaker 1: good God is the Kree's Kroll war terrible and painful to read?
Speaker 0: Why is it terrible?
Speaker 0: is it just stupid is it?
Speaker 0: is there something especially bad about it?
Speaker 0: I'm curious.
Speaker 0: as a non-superhero Comic reader, I don't really how bad could it be?
Speaker 1: well Let me let me do a quote from the introduction here.
Speaker 1: the introduction is by Roy Thomas Who is the writer of the Kree's Kroll war and let me take a one sentence?
Speaker 1: I want to quote one sentence from this introduction.
Speaker 1: the sentence is Quote and if I may be unabashedly immodest for a moment.
Speaker 1: I think it holds up fairly well.
Speaker 1: end quote.
Speaker 1: This doesn't hold up Like a dime.
Speaker 1: I can't even think of feather.
Speaker 1: This can't hold up a fucking feather.
Speaker 1: all right.
Speaker 1: basically the deal here right is Primarily this should be about a war between the two alien races the Kree and the Skrull.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: No, I mean there isn't a war between the Kree and the Skrull going on, but barely I mean it's sort of.
Speaker 1: they say it happens and then at some point they Semi resolve it and then Kree and Skrull people sort of get involved.
Speaker 1: Mostly, it's just a bunch of random Avengers Adventures, it's really hard to say and they're all really late Avengers adventures.
Speaker 1: Yes And They're all pretty lame Adventures if I may say so myself, it's pretty much.
Speaker 1: There's a bad guy.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, so I mean there's this one part It's like the worst of all is this incredibly unrelated part where one of the Avengers is the vision.
Speaker 1: He's like this Android, right?
Speaker 0: I've suddenly remembered the vision.
Speaker 0: yeah as opposed to a vision.
Speaker 1: Well the vision that you know the Avengers vision see is I have a vision.
Speaker 0: I have a vision of nothing but small mushrooms.
Speaker 1: as far as the eye He is an Android and the big it's like that the vision they keep saying.
Speaker 1: Oh, he's the Android.
Speaker 1: He has no emotions, right and he's.
Speaker 1: and it's so stupid because okay It's one thing to make an emotionless Android and I hate Star Trek But I know that that next generation has the emotionless Android.
Speaker 0: Well, well, well data didn't have emotions, but then he got emotions.
Speaker 0: All right, luckily he died right.
Speaker 1: but I Saw, you know from the maybe one or two episodes of that I seen he was actually an Android with no emotions, right?
Speaker 0: Wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute I think I see where you're going with this.
Speaker 0: you telling me that in a comic the characters will declare something like He is the emotionless one.
Speaker 0: He is the one who has no emotions But yet in the actual writing of that character There's plenty of emotions and that those declarative statements are just crap.
Speaker 1: Are you reading the mind of Scott rim?
Speaker 1: has the mind reading skills?
Speaker 0: I think based on my experience with it's like the whole Iron Man thing.
Speaker 0: I mean, I hear the Iron Man movies awesome, and I want to see it.
Speaker 0: but the the defense of the Iron Man comics I usually hear is but he was an alcoholic and it was interesting because he fought with his alcohol.
Speaker 1: Listen, listen, all right on the Iron Man alcoholism.
Speaker 1: I listened to a review of Of this a trade paperback of Iron Man.
Speaker 1: actually a hardcover Iron Man demon in a bottle.
Speaker 1: right get see the metaphor.
Speaker 1: See the metaphor.
Speaker 1: they're demon in a bottle because he's a guy Alcoholism demon in a bottle being a Superhero comic.
Speaker 0: there's literally a demon in a bottle that he literally fights.
Speaker 1: No, that wasn't it.
Speaker 0: That's that's surprising
Speaker 1: Yes But I listened to a review of that by Comic geek speak the comic geek speak podcast where they like superhero comics, right and most of those people Didn't like it and they complained that the alcoholism really only came into play and like one issue of the trade paperback And it was kind of just you know, oh, he's alcoholic.
Speaker 1: Oh, he's over it black.
Speaker 1: So people were like, oh I had man.
Speaker 1: the alcoholism is such a great story And the comic not so much really for at least according to people who know better than I do.
Speaker 0: There's a term for this.
Speaker 0: you see You know say you really really want straws, but they're just out of your reach.
Speaker 0: What do you do?
Speaker 0: What do you kind of grasp for him?
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the vision right.
Speaker 1: not only does the vision You know show emotion despite, you know, everyone's saying oh, he's the guy with no emotion He'll.
Speaker 1: actually there's a scene in which he's like, you know Trying not to kiss the Scarlet Witch cuz.
Speaker 1: he's like.
Speaker 1: and he's like wait wait wait Yes, okay.
Speaker 1: He's like no I mustn't I have no emotion Right.
Speaker 1: So that's pretty bad right there.
Speaker 1: Then you've got like this big long is seen in one of the issues where ant-man who recently left the Avengers Becomes small and goes inside the vision to see what's wrong with him Which has absolutely nothing to do with crease and or scrolls and or wars.
Speaker 0: Well, it's possible.
Speaker 0: Was there a Cree inside him?
Speaker 0: No, how about a scroll?
Speaker 1: No Not at all.
Speaker 0: This sounds excellent.
Speaker 0: How's the art?
Speaker 1: It's it's actually pretty typical art for the day.
Speaker 1: It's mostly you know If you it's sort of if you look at the art with the untrained eye of like.
Speaker 1: oh this is bad old art.
Speaker 1: But really the art is okay.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: it's limited by the printing techniques of the olden days You know just like all superhero art of those days was you know?
Speaker 1: I guess you know some of the character designs that were old-school and though, you know, like this is not.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know cats in America looks alright actually, but he's barely in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so yeah.
Speaker 1: There's also a lot of stupid shit going on.
Speaker 1: For example, right Scrolls.
Speaker 1: The thing about Scrolls is that they're shapeshifters, right?
Speaker 1: So there's all sorts of cool stuff you can do with that and Marvel actually with their modern comics.
Speaker 1: There's there's like this secret invasion thing going on where the Scrolls are actually playing a big part and there's lots of Shapeshifting action going on.
Speaker 1: but in this the original crease scroll war the scrolls are shape-shifted into cows and Then they uncowed Aha, which is sort of a reference to the Scrolls previous appearance at a Fantastic Four comic because they actually said as much in the comic.
Speaker 1: But you know to sort of let me know that was what happened, but seriously cows They could have shaped it and all sorts of things but cows.
Speaker 1: Ah So yeah, it's just.
Speaker 1: the writing is just you know full of unnecessary narration.
Speaker 1: There's a fight of random bad guys in every issue.
Speaker 1: There's no real Reason to care about the characters or anything.
Speaker 1: It's stereotypical bad old superhero comics.
Speaker 1: and Actually reading it, you know cuz I thought at the very least reading this would give me sort of a backdrop for all of the Some of the better comics that have read that have given reference to this crease scroll war.
Speaker 1: I got nothing out of it.
Speaker 1: you there's no reason to actually read the crease scroll war.
Speaker 1: all you have to you in fact what you think what you Imagine the crease scroll war might have been like, you know it.
Speaker 1: when other comics reference It is better than the reality of what it was.
Speaker 1: Don't even bother with this unless the only reason to read this would be if you're one of those people who has super strong Nostalgia for superhero comics of old and that enjoyment of that nostalgia is enough to pull you through Really bad writing.
Speaker 0: so Scott said before he went into that that there was no anime news.
Speaker 0: But no, there is some very important anime news that really you all really need to know.
Speaker 0: This is this is this is a tragedy.
Speaker 0: You see there is a company Super techno arts.
Speaker 1: Oh, I heard of them.
Speaker 0: There's an anime Jojo's Bizarre Adventure.
Speaker 0: now if there's one thing I can say about Jojo's Bizarre Adventure, it is bizarre.
Speaker 1: It's also Jojo's.
Speaker 0: it is.
Speaker 0: It's weird because I want to say it's excellent But I don't know why because it's not but it's one of those things that's dumb and bad and at the same time Wonderful.
Speaker 1: See this actually because I was always weird.
Speaker 1: I would go to anime conventions before I really knew a lot about anime, right and you would go like the Bandai booth.
Speaker 1: They had all the Bandai stuff and you go to the genie on booth and they still exist.
Speaker 1: nail the genie on stuff, right?
Speaker 1: But there's always this one small booth and that one small booth had like one statue of a weird-looking anime character And it was like this anime company and all this anime company had to their name was Jojo's Bizarre Adventure.
Speaker 1: So I always thought because there was just one company and they were the only u.s Company that had this one show Right and the show was called Jojo's Bizarre Adventure and the character design of that one statue they had look kind of lame.
Speaker 1: You know Knowing all that I thought huh?
Speaker 1: It's just this one bad show.
Speaker 1: That's obviously unpopular than no one likes No one cares about and that's why this is one weird tiny shit company trying to sell it.
Speaker 1: But whatever screw them I don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: Well, it's actually a little more.
Speaker 0: I mean cuz.
Speaker 1: yeah, that's what I thought back in the day.
Speaker 0: But then you know you get to RIT.
Speaker 0: At RIT anime because they had the gigantic library of new they had a few VHS's and old anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah a few God.
Speaker 0: we got to find some pictures.
Speaker 1: I've had a few VHS's of Jojo's.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it was one of those things where all the old-school people in the club would be like, haha Jojo's they'd cuz.
Speaker 0: you know young kids would come up to the library and they'd be like What should I watch?
Speaker 1: and the first thing they would always tell them to watch is marmalade boy, which is not a good thing.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends on who you ask cuz.
Speaker 0: if you went over to the tape Nazi and like his faction in the anime club government They'd always say marmalade boy If you're already seen it, they'd say candy candy.
Speaker 0: and if you'd already seen that they'd say Kimoguri orange road.
Speaker 0: If you're already seen all three, well, they take you into the back and give you their secret fan subs Yeah of similar shows, but if you went to anyone else They'd either get it.
Speaker 0: No one wanted to give the obvious never.
Speaker 0: no one would ever say like just watch cowboy bebop Duh, or just watch eska flown a. they'd always give the kind of.
Speaker 0: here's the show that you would never think to watch But that you might like.
Speaker 0: so watch it and if you like it I will know what else to recommend to you.
Speaker 0: And if you hate it I will also know what else to recommend you.
Speaker 1: usually what people ended up doing is they would sift through the tapes.
Speaker 1: Right, as least what I did like, you know before I was cool I would sift through the tapes find something with an appealing title because basically have a blank VHS.
Speaker 0: That's how you picked up.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: well there was goo goo goo.
Speaker 1: I didn't pick up guys.
Speaker 0: I remember seeing it all the time.
Speaker 0: It'd be like goo goo goo.
Speaker 1: I remember that.
Speaker 1: be in the library.
Speaker 1: I would pick up a tape based on the name on the side of the tape and then show it and show it to someone.
Speaker 1: It'd be like is this good?
Speaker 1: Is this good?
Speaker 1: And that's how.
Speaker 1: that's how I rolled in those days I think a lot of people rolled that way also.
Speaker 0: Yep, but you'd start to learn like.
Speaker 0: but this was one of those shows where people would be like Jojo's Bizarre Adventure and then they'd come back the next week and they'd either be like So where can I get more of that?
Speaker 0: or they'd say never ever fucking recommend anime to be again?
Speaker 0: And there was really no middle ground.
Speaker 1: not much.
Speaker 0: I like Jojo, but I Don't know if I like it in an ironic sense or not.
Speaker 0: I think I like it only in an ironic sense.
Speaker 0: I
Speaker 1: haven't read or watched enough of it to really know but what I do know about it sort of the meta information Is that there's like a whole bunch of different manga series and it's sort of Convoluting and hard to figure out which ones to read in what order.
Speaker 1: Convoluting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the TV shows and Movies if there are any I don't even know there's a movie or at least one.
Speaker 0: well, let me put it this way because I don't want to turn this into the Jojo show, but the super techno arts was releasing.
Speaker 0: well, they released the OAV and Basically, they went dark.
Speaker 0: if you go to their website as of now It says index of root CGI bin and robots dot text.
Speaker 1: All right, someone screwed up the web.
Speaker 0: So now they're gone.
Speaker 0: They're done.
Speaker 0: They're no longer distributing Jojo's Bizarre Adventure due to quote an unspecified issue in Japan.
Speaker 0: and that is the end of it, uh-huh Alrighty, then I'm not gonna read into it because I don't know enough about this company to be able to say what their status was.
Speaker 1: No, I have no idea what the deal was.
Speaker 1: All I knew is that it was always weird.
Speaker 1: There was one company that owned one anime.
Speaker 1: It was like they just they were just one license and that was all they were.
Speaker 1: and it was always sort of weird.
Speaker 1: and Because of that because of that weirdness I like didn't trust their show.
Speaker 1: and I think actually because of that weirdness You know, I think a lot of you know, people are people are fans of Jojo and I think because of that weird situation It actually is what held that show back.
Speaker 1: They had.
Speaker 1: now I think it's too late.
Speaker 0: They released a lot more than Jojo.
Speaker 0: Really they also had sci-fi Harry and Shadow.
Speaker 1: Whoa, I didn't know they had shadow.
Speaker 1: that changes everything.
Speaker 0: three OAVs shadow is action erotica shadow with an axe Alternative title hyper shinobi animation shadow.
Speaker 1: Ooh, that's a better name at least.
Speaker 0: Yeah looks kind of recent.
Speaker 0: I'm getting this from anime news network.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about this company.
Speaker 0: Sci-fi Harry is a Korean.
Speaker 1: It sounds like it could be funny.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: I'm dumb.
Speaker 0: Neo-psychic experiment.
Speaker 0: sci-fi Harry is a drama drama horror mystery psychological supernatural show.
Speaker 1: It sounds like my kind of action like the same kind of deal is like the opener is actually by John dark.
Speaker 0: I kind of like John.
Speaker 1: a lot of those anime that they would show on like the sci-fi channel, you know Sort of like not quite at the quality level of Akira, but the same sort of feeling.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll have to acquire these two shows and review them and then end the horrible trifecta with an actual review of Jojo.
Speaker 1: We'll do this super techno arts.
Speaker 0: Try try Trilogy, that's a very Dave and Joel idea, but I think we should do it I would have made anyway.
Speaker 0: You can buy Jojo what's out there and I'm sure anything that is unreleased will get translated or whatever.
Speaker 0: I don't know I don't care but I find this interesting.
Speaker 0: I'm curious what the unspecified issue is.
Speaker 0: Things of the day.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna say a lot about this.
Speaker 0: you may like this you may not but I can tell you one thing It's power level is over 9,000.
Speaker 1: I know it's exactly 9,000.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I guess it is.
Speaker 0: you were supposed to say 9,000. no, no, I did.
Speaker 1: I said 9,000.
Speaker 1: I just didn't say 9,000.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you didn't say it.
Speaker 1: then 9,000.
Speaker 0: There we go It is exactly 9,000.
Speaker 0: Anyway, why is that to be 9,000?
Speaker 1: My power level is 10,000 bitches.
Speaker 1: Take that I Forged 9,000 guys, you're like.
Speaker 1: you're like fleas.
Speaker 1: I pick you away.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to remember what like super sane Vegeta whatever his power was.
Speaker 1: I never actually watched more than say 90 minutes of Dragon Ball in my life.
Speaker 0: So I watched a series of episodes and in every one of them Some someone was fighting some other people and Krillin was on the ground going.
Speaker 1: I remember once it was on the TV and we were in Jay's diner and it was literally just a Fat guy would say something.
Speaker 1: He's like Fat guy would say something and that was the whole episode.
Speaker 1: That was over but death chaos.
Speaker 0: 9,000 is Something from like the old days of the internet.
Speaker 0: This is from back when there was no dig videos There wasn't even a YouTube and if if you wanted to find funny videos You pretty much went around and like there'd always be the one guy in your group who had like this collection of random funny Videos and then people would like trade funny videos and keep them on local hard drive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you'd have your hard drive and on your hard drive.
Speaker 1: You would have all these little video clips.
Speaker 1: They still have a bunch of them and you'd be like and someone would come over you like Hey check out my video clips and you didn't have YouTube's and you'd always like know him by the titles of the file.
Speaker 0: So he'd be like, hey man, you want you want a copy of but hot dog that a VI.
Speaker 0: no No, man, I got puddle jumper.
Speaker 1: Yeah puddle jumper is a good one.
Speaker 0: But this like before College Humor was around and There's this whole fun story that I think we could do a separate show on like the birth of College Humor in the history Of College Humor, but a lot of the lot of that stuff was from RIT and this video death chaos 9,000 was filmed almost entirely at RIT not only at
Speaker 1: RIT But most of it was filmed in the colony apartment complex where we lived for the most of our RIT stay.
Speaker 0: Yes, and except for the there's some scenes from Perkins.
Speaker 0: There's this one road that's in Perkins and One thing I want to say is you'll see a lot of fighting.
Speaker 0: That is the reason why Scott when he was injured at one point and went to the school doctor They asked him and made him sign a form certified.
Speaker 1: No, that was not exactly.
Speaker 1: that's not the story.
Speaker 1: The story is I went to the school doctor because I like hurt my leg, right?
Speaker 0: And they asked you if you were in a fight club.
Speaker 1: No, they didn't.
Speaker 1: what happened told me later on, right?
Speaker 1: I was sitting at home on the computer and there was a knock at the door and it was two campus safety Officers and they said we received a report that you hurt your leg and I'm like, yeah They're like.
Speaker 1: we have to ask you if you're in a fight club.
Speaker 0: So basically the story I told was right except you decided to add the unnecessary detail.
Speaker 1: You mean the add.
Speaker 1: the most important detail wasn't the doctor who asked it was campus safety came and found me later.
Speaker 0: Well, you were asked by the school.
Speaker 0: But yes a fight club and I think your response was something.
Speaker 0: Are you kidding?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty much like The campus safety guys answer was no.
Speaker 1: Yeah Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you think I'm in a fight now.
Speaker 0: had I been in the room?
Speaker 0: I pretty much probably would have piped up from somewhere in the apartment.
Speaker 0: the crap Scott.
Speaker 1: They got you better come clean Yeah, but here's the thing that I don't understand right, okay Of course, I wasn't in a fight club.
Speaker 0: However, there were fight clubs that are IT.
Speaker 1: not only that right, but if someone has a private fight club How is that illegal?
Speaker 0: Well, I it's not illegal as long as everybody has the police as long as everyone can sense.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know the legality.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's really I just you know I thought about it just now for the first time like even if there was a Against our policies that's for sure.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying like I just thought right now like if there was a fight club what of it?
Speaker 1: It's like we're not allowed to have a fight club if we want to.
Speaker 0: Well, I remember the time we were busted for all of us.
Speaker 0: We're basically trying to kill katsu but that that's a story for another time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I remember the campus safety guy runs over.
Speaker 0: stop it.
Speaker 0: Jesus.
Speaker 0: What are you kids doing?
Speaker 0: And then we all stopped and we're like what?
Speaker 0: yeah He's our friend and he looks at costume conscious like yeah Yeah, can we keep doing this?
Speaker 0: he's like.
Speaker 0: no Definitely not go away Disperse.
Speaker 1: I don't remember the guy coming over.
Speaker 1: I just remember I was sort of getting tired.
Speaker 0: We were.
Speaker 0: no we were dispersed by campus safety.
Speaker 0: Maybe it was a separate time.
Speaker 1: It might have been a separate time.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that was not the first nor the last time we did that.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I think I only did that one time.
Speaker 0: thousand RIT was like that in many ways but not like that in many ways because we don't take this as a as a Representative of what all of RIT was like as you could be at RIT and not run afoul of this.
Speaker 0: However, that is a big part of RIT's culture.
Speaker 0: all the things you were gonna say That is a subset of RIT that does indeed exist and you should be aware because I'll say this all the guys you see in That video we knew them now not in the.
Speaker 1: I didn't know.
Speaker 0: I knew maybe like let me finish Not in the like.
Speaker 0: you talk to them or you're friends with them or anything like that.
Speaker 0: But as in you see these guys and it's like I saw those guys on a semi-regular basis while I lived out.
Speaker 1: Alright, there's maybe one guy in that whole video that I somewhat recognize really.
Speaker 0: I remember specifically the guy in the hat who does the little heel click.
Speaker 0: I saw that guy a lot All right, I like I'd walk past him all the time and I always thought that's the guy from Death Cast 9000 alrighty.
Speaker 0: But Anyway That's all I got.
Speaker 1: Okay, so last night we watched some anime right and we're gonna talk about one of those anime right soon.
Speaker 1: But first I'm a big fan.
Speaker 1: I don't know why of Like kids anime like anime meant for like kindergarten kids.
Speaker 0: Scott will watch this one episode of furikapa like only because it's the only episode of furikapa.
Speaker 0: I have Furikapa Do.
Speaker 1: Furikapa is a great show.
Speaker 1: Go I learned I learned Japanese words from furikapa.
Speaker 0: Well, that's like yeah That's like Sesame Street.
Speaker 0: Like the word for today is mitten exactly.
Speaker 1: and then There are other ones like that penguin.
Speaker 1: no mondai.
Speaker 1: That was all right penguin.
Speaker 0: No mondai is fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: Then there was what was the other one with the the bunnies the Soggy some of all the construction working bunnies.
Speaker 0: that show is awesome times a thousand.
Speaker 1: I like that one, you know.
Speaker 0: No, that show was awesome because it's a little kid show and it's all these bunnies like in construction.
Speaker 0: But and they go all yakuza and fight Exactly.
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah Doraemon actually is okay I don't hate Doraemon, but I'm not as big a fan of it as I like some of these other ones.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so Emily was showing me this one Called cheese sweet home.
Speaker 1: now how she's sweet home and I'm linking to episode 1 of cheese sweet home on YouTube Subtitles.
Speaker 1: It's only like three minutes long.
Speaker 1: So you might as well watch it.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you one thing.
Speaker 0: You don't need subtitles.
Speaker 0: No, you know if well if you watch enough anime, you don't need some time, but basically she's sweet home.
Speaker 1: I think the alternate title and more accurate title to cheese sweet home is Uh Cute cat the anime cute kitty neko neko.
Speaker 1: we that's pretty much this whole three minutes.
Speaker 1: here is cute cat And you know what?
Speaker 1: There's a whole bunch of episodes of cute cat Like.
Speaker 1: I think there's like many many episodes of this.
Speaker 1: So if you like cute cat cheese sweet home Hard to go wrong.
Speaker 0: It's a good show.
Speaker 0: I like it.
Speaker 1: It's not bad I'm.
Speaker 1: I could watch more cute cat if I had nothing better to do.
Speaker 0: Of course cheese sweet home is tainted a little bit by the show We're reviewing tonight because to get the show we watched last night out of our heads kind of like how if you eat something bad you try to like rinse it out with bleach or Maybe whiskey or something.
Speaker 1: That's all you but I use all you.
Speaker 1: I'll stick to my waters.
Speaker 0: So we decided to watch a little bit of cheese sweet home.
Speaker 0: But all I could think was I'm just waiting for the lesbians in the cooter.
Speaker 1: Good God.
Speaker 1: All right, so so We watch.
Speaker 1: we are go.
Speaker 1: he turned on my old the old computer.
Speaker 1: We went to the you know hard drive full of anime and we said let's pick one of these episodes and watch it.
Speaker 1: So one of the episodes there was project ice now.
Speaker 0: It is actually just called ice.
Speaker 0: It's an OAV actually or ice the last generation now.
Speaker 0: This is important because after we had watched whatever it was that we watched We we we had to find out what the to use bad words the fucking deal was.
Speaker 0: what the fuck.
Speaker 0: So we went to the anime news network.
Speaker 0: We went to project, you know the P and we're looking for project ice.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're gonna jump for this right away.
Speaker 0: We couldn't find it.
Speaker 0: But while we were looking for it I noticed another anime I was of which I was hitherto unaware.
Speaker 0: This show is entitled no way out But it has an alternate Japanese title and because we were under project whatever looking for project ice I noticed the great the epic project boobs.
Speaker 0: Okay now project boobs.
Speaker 0: I got to read this description to you and then we'll leave it at that Because the fact that an anime called project boobs exists is not surprising in the least Unendingly hilarious to me, okay Yuki Miyagawa is a secret agent for a government organization.
Speaker 0: She and her colleagues Reiko kara yukiko and Kana Morishita are ordered to spy on a pharmaceutical company Under that is under suspicion producing illegal drugs.
Speaker 0: All right However, their activities are known to the company and they are caught by the researchers who molest them under the pretext of conducting Experiments, uh-oh, it's more than one episode direct.
Speaker 0: I'll leave it at that but It's not like a movie.
Speaker 0: it's it's project.
Speaker 0: it's directed by Suito machida.
Speaker 0: I don't know if that's a pen name or what.
Speaker 0: who is famous for?
Speaker 0: do you know the milthing man?
Speaker 1: So in OAV at least it's a clever title.
Speaker 0: Oh No toy key.
Speaker 0: All right enough with the funny hentai.
Speaker 1: Alright project ice perhaps worse than a funny hentai.
Speaker 0: now I'm 70 people rated this show on the animators network.
Speaker 0: I want to point something out.
Speaker 0: a non-zero number of people rated this with the highest possible rating.
Speaker 1: That is quite frightening.
Speaker 1: So project ice.
Speaker 1: basically the show starts out kind of interesting.
Speaker 1: Well, well, okay Well, it starts out where there's like a scantily clad girl, right?
Speaker 1: You're like, uh Right, and then a second later like she wakes up out of bed and like her brothers at the kitchen table, right and you're like Okay, this is pretty stereotypical it's gonna be like a pervy show but
Speaker 0: then
Speaker 1: but
Speaker 0: then I think we'll actually go through The.
Speaker 0: what happens in this?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think so.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then but to do the brief, you know Well, I think we'll go in long form here But briefly just to get you idea of where this goes.
Speaker 0: from there We end up in lesbian futuristic fits to the North Star world.
Speaker 1: Why are you giving away?
Speaker 1: All right, you got who.
Speaker 1: you got to pull that out later.
Speaker 0: I know I gotta pull that.
Speaker 1: I was trying to stop you.
Speaker 0: No, you don't pull that out later.
Speaker 1: No, you got it.
Speaker 1: You gotta save the surprises.
Speaker 0: No, I think the surprise is how you get from there to there.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so she starts talking to her brother and once they start talking you're actually like, huh?
Speaker 1: All right, they're not saying the stereotypical anime things.
Speaker 1: This is a kind of interested in this character.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to know what's going on here a little bit.
Speaker 1: You know, what's the deal with these people and you know that there's like an interesting thing happening here.
Speaker 0: All right Well, I'm also intrigued by the fact that her character design is straight out of golden boy.
Speaker 0: It looks like all those old.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like this really old-school character design, you know, the big hair big glasses Backgrounds also feel old-school, but they're definitely using much newer school animation technology.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but like everything's kind of washed out.
Speaker 1: and it's kind of weird though because the brothers character design was much more modern So they didn't really match up but that was kind of interesting in a way.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so this is a spoiler.
Speaker 1: but who gives a shit cuz you're not supposed to watch this show.
Speaker 1: It's terrible.
Speaker 1: She she goes outside.
Speaker 1: She's on her way somewhere.
Speaker 1: I forget where.
Speaker 1: and You see like this weird mad obvious magical girl type character appear right and they're sort of looking at each other.
Speaker 1: ish, right?
Speaker 0: But then she's immediately hit by a truck and that's the end of that.
Speaker 1: she's dead and you're like what the fuck.
Speaker 0: So fast-forward to lesbian future fist of the North Star.
Speaker 0: Okay So before we get into the more detail now.
Speaker 1: so far this isn't painful yet because how many anime start with one thing Switch to something else and then eventually they tie it back to that original thing.
Speaker 1: That's you know, I can that's an Anime storytelling technique a trope that I'm not a fan of but it's been around a while.
Speaker 1: It can be done.
Speaker 0: Well, it doesn't automatically make things bad, you know, it's it's acceptable all right, but that this show is one of those shows where you're watching and then it it's like it was directed or Made by yeah, I think here's the here's the creative process.
Speaker 0: What if you made a show where like a woman gets hit by a truck and then there's lesbians, right?
Speaker 0: But then there's these robots, but the robots are all you know futurey and they're piloted by women But then they pull out guns, but the guns are like the technology the men.
Speaker 0: and there's all these twins.
Speaker 0: But then a woman shoved something up her cooter and becomes a giant crystal, right?
Speaker 0: And that's like the plot you see because then there's a baby but and and it's all about these babies in this ice.
Speaker 0: But but we gotta have robots and we gotta have planes.
Speaker 0: We gotta have lesbians Don't forget the lesbians and it's set in like, I don't know the future.
Speaker 0: and and there's giant robots fighting but maybe there's some virtual reality and and make it look like last exile, but not all the time.
Speaker 0: and Let's have a different character designer for every single character and all the men are dead Just like why the last man except that baby who has a penis Claire's day.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, so basically Everything rim just said.
Speaker 1: but what happens next is you get this flurry of scenes that are sort of Unrelated and you see all these characters.
Speaker 1: They all have really distinctive character designs.
Speaker 1: They're not well designed.
Speaker 1: They're all designed differently and Most of them seem kind of Blair.
Speaker 1: and you just get this flurry of characters thrown at you in this flurry of different settings.
Speaker 1: You don't know what time it is.
Speaker 1: You don't know where they are.
Speaker 1: You don't know what they're doing.
Speaker 1: You don't know anything.
Speaker 1: you see all these characters all over the place doing seemingly unrelated things.
Speaker 1: You know two girls with bikes on a highway a bunch of girls in a truck Yeah, a maid something else going on.
Speaker 1: You don't know and it just makes no sense until eventually the maid girl like Grabs this thing.
Speaker 1: Let's save that because you already gave it away.
Speaker 0: Anyway, no, but before because I feel like we should do.
Speaker 1: there's nothing to happen before that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there is.
Speaker 0: I feel like we should do a more Dave and Joel approach.
Speaker 0: actually just go through the whole plot So no one thinks to watch it.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like MD guys for plot doesn't start until this happens It starts before that.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of stuff Like you're forgetting a ton of.
Speaker 1: we're gonna end up talking more about how to talk about this terrible show than actually Talking about how terrible it was.
Speaker 0: I think a better way to go about it is to actually just go through the plot step by step.
Speaker 1: I am going through a step by step.
Speaker 0: Oh, you're forgetting something.
Speaker 1: What am I forgetting?
Speaker 0: This is our nations.
Speaker 1: What about the United Nations?
Speaker 0: and what happens with them?
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, and there's a bunch of other.
Speaker 1: well, that's why they do it so quickly that it's it's like you don't even notice.
Speaker 0: Before we get into all that I'd like to point out that part of the reason I'm interested because this show is directed by Makoto Kobayashi.
Speaker 0: now this person hasn't really directed much But if you look at their page on the anime news network if you're so inclined It's primarily mechanical design mecha design Conceptual design for robot shows and mecha shows like let's see Gundam double zeta Giant robo the gankutsu a robots the final fantasy unlimited mechanical stuff Venus Wars Trinity blood all these show steam boys super extra guy.
Speaker 1: That's not a bad resume of mecha design and you know what.
Speaker 0: but show has a bunch of really interesting mecha design.
Speaker 0: It's too bad.
Speaker 1: I'm not I mean, it's not the best man ever.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem with the mecha design.
Speaker 0: So they've got last exile like you'll see him and you'll go.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's so last exile.
Speaker 0: But then they've also got guy my lefts Effectively and then they've got Akira bikes times a thousand with the most unrealistic winches I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's really really inconsistent.
Speaker 1: this whole anime feels Like a whole bunch of people each individually made.
Speaker 1: they're like, hey you yeah make an anime scene on your own.
Speaker 1: What kind of scene?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: just make a scene of anime and everyone made a scene of a different anime and then you?
Speaker 1: Sort of pasted all the scenes together.
Speaker 1: the scary part is is no AV.
Speaker 1: They expect people to buy this and this entire thing on one incredibly expensive DVD.
Speaker 0: So, let's see I mean the opening scene where I immediately decided all right The show is gonna be a porny show is.
Speaker 0: it starts with a top-down shot of this old golden boy character design woman?
Speaker 0: Wearing a thong and there's a butt and the offense like there's a but there's a but there's a but we're gonna linger.
Speaker 0: But And then you know it cuts to this future world and Pretty much right away They introduced a million characters and the one that really stands out like all the characters are different character designs Like we said, but one of them this guy.
Speaker 0: now I say guy cuz it's actually a girl but it's I'm going with dude.
Speaker 1: I'm also going with dude the dude with blue hair whose character design stands out because it has blue hair.
Speaker 0: Not just that but the eyes are drawn differently and the face is different and the neck is way too small.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz it.
Speaker 1: basically it looks like a dude except this boobs under the uniform and that's it.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like how in utenna the way they made the characters is just they made every character a girl and then they randomly Just pick characters and remove the breasts and left everything as is.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: That was the old joke at our hair.
Speaker 0: pop There you go toga.
Speaker 1: This is the opposite of Utenna where they would just they made all the characters and then just added boobs to all of them.
Speaker 0: So they introduced a billion characters.
Speaker 0: There's also the triplets.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they basically they don't really do anything, but you see hey, there's triplets.
Speaker 0: Why are they this long as seen?
Speaker 0: or the character in blue is going on and on about how you have to love people?
Speaker 0: And don't kill don't ever kill blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: We should just you know incapacitate and pacifism blah blah blah and just keeps talking and talking And all the other characters are even ignoring this person.
Speaker 0: I don't even remember any of the characters names except mint cuz.
Speaker 1: that's the person with blue hair and it's mint.
Speaker 1: That's why it matches with the hair color.
Speaker 1: That's the only reason I can remember it.
Speaker 0: But all these characters are there and then they cut to the United Nations or the United States or the United States under the guise of the United Nations coming forward with all these crazy battleships to Japan and Basically announcing all right.
Speaker 0: Well Japan because of our mutual defense treaty in order to protect you we're going to invade you and Japan responds over I guess a loudspeaker with No Yeah, and now here's the thing.
Speaker 0: and they start.
Speaker 0: they set up like this big fight and it's like the Army's coming in and the Other armies like getting ready to fight.
Speaker 1: What does it have to do with the girl in the beginning who was the only character even slightly cared about hook ahead by?
Speaker 0: What does it have to do with all these other characters who are in some sort of military thing and they all have different colored Hair and they're all.
Speaker 0: they're all talking and going on some sort of mission, but their mission is to deal with Isis Which is totally yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the ice wait wait before we get to the ice.
Speaker 0: But then they cut away from the UN US Japan thing and they never go back to it.
Speaker 0: They not only they never go back to it, but it didn't even make sense to begin with.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so then they cut to this maid and right before this I remember saying well didn't they do the girls with bikes first?
Speaker 0: I don't remember if they did or not So I'll save that for later.
Speaker 0: But they cut to this maid and right before that I had said You know The only thing the show is missing is like a bunch of maids and then it cuts to a maid and she's got a briefcase.
Speaker 0: So she opens this briefcase and we see a dildo.
Speaker 1: But well, we see a lot of weird shit and they're all dildo.
Speaker 1: It could be dildos.
Speaker 1: They're all dildo.
Speaker 1: It could be weapons It could be some sort of weird something.
Speaker 0: There's a.
Speaker 1: it's obviously something special and it looks like dildos.
Speaker 0: They're all dildos, but my brain used to anime says Obviously, these are not actually dildos They are something else.
Speaker 0: and sure enough she picks one of them up and while you could say yeah It's it's very phallic, you know, all cylindrical objects are phallic.
Speaker 1: So that doesn't really count for my but it had sort of science stuff attached to it.
Speaker 1: Like it's not like a pile of pink ooze a vial of pink ooze and some buttons and some switches.
Speaker 1: So I was like, oh it must be some sort of like, you know chemical spraying thing of magic powers.
Speaker 0: So she pulls it out and immediately starts caressing it.
Speaker 0: Well, well, she starts caressing it and oh crap.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, oh man, and I think to myself, you know If this were a horrible hentai to steal a word from Dave That's going up her cooter Right.
Speaker 1: So eventually before I can finish thinking that right up the cooter Wasn't right at the cooter right away first, right?
Speaker 1: She starts running away because someone's chasing her right and it's like Characters have arrived and they're chasing her for some reason.
Speaker 1: So the whole time I'm thinking aha she's got the secret science and people are coming to get the secret side.
Speaker 1: or maybe I?
Speaker 0: Actually what I thought I figured she's a terrorist and she's gonna like use this thing to turn into some sort of Biobot terrorism thing cuz yeah, they kind of like oh, there's bioterrorism.
Speaker 0: Yeah ice.
Speaker 0: Oh, no There's some ice happening in such-and-such.
Speaker 1: We got to go stop them and then she gets out on the floor puts the thing in the cooter and sprays the pink stuff Up there and then we cut away.
Speaker 1: and then at that point I remembered.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that's right It's that like apparently at the beginning of the show when you see the girl who gets hit by the truck.
Speaker 1: That is in a time and place where men exist, but we've since learned men no longer exists.
Speaker 1: It's like why the last man they all died.
Speaker 1: So I was like, oh that has something to do with men not existing.
Speaker 1: Maybe that like impregnates her or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah Pink sperm.
Speaker 0: so we cut back to all those characters.
Speaker 0: They introduced her on a bus.
Speaker 0: Well, it looks like a bus.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really.
Speaker 1: it's like an army bus.
Speaker 0: It's like a bus with a zeppelin attached to it and it's flying and driving and there's a girl in the front waving a Shinto Stick and then oh, yeah, the shit does and the other characters come up.
Speaker 0: They're like stop waving that stupid stick.
Speaker 0: It doesn't do.
Speaker 0: she's just like yeah waving the stick Yeah, but it cuts to them again and they're like, oh shit ice Alright, so I assume so the ice obviously that made turned into some kind of terrorist Biorobot because she's impregnated and they're gonna go fight her.
Speaker 0: but then I don't know what happened.
Speaker 0: So it cuts to the.
Speaker 0: I were like this giant pink crystal and in the setting is a blue crystal.
Speaker 0: it was pink and in the center of this pink crystal is That girl and they and the ice.
Speaker 0: these people are all there and I don't remember if they were the same characters or not But they surround this crystal in like this force field.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it was a blue crystal But then suddenly there's like two ices and two force field.
Speaker 1: Well, it's very weird because like though you'll see they they sat surrounded with a force field, right?
Speaker 1: But then they'll cut and they'll show you like this monster is coming out of the ice and they're fighting it or something.
Speaker 1: But then they'll cut and it's like it's surrounded by a force field.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like.
Speaker 1: it's almost like there's two different dimensions you're seeing and it's like two alternate universes one in which the ice is doing one thing and one in which the ice is surrounded by a force field.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's that at all because they mentioned way back like oh, there's two ices two units, whatever.
Speaker 1: I think it was just a really shittily directed scene That in the end it was revealed that yes It was a really shittily directed scene.
Speaker 1: Apparently there were two teams.
Speaker 1: one team was going to deal with one ice incident and another team was going to deal with another ice Incident.
Speaker 1: so you have the one team that puts a force field around the maid We just saw and another team that's somewhere else that a team we've never seen before somewhere else dealing with ice.
Speaker 1: We've never seen before and they'd sort of switch back between these two scenes.
Speaker 1: So you really can't understand what the fuck at all is supposed to be happening.
Speaker 0: So what we see is basically we see our teams around this ice and they're all looking at it like ice ice.
Speaker 0: It's an ice baby.
Speaker 0: Well, speaking of ice ice baby, yeah, so suddenly one of the girls Sees a baby and it's crawling around next to the ice and it's got a got a wee wee.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's happy.
Speaker 0: It's like yay, and she freaks out pulls out the machine gun and Shoots the baby like with a million bullets.
Speaker 1: And then it's how the baby was just something she saw or if it was actually there.
Speaker 1: I couldn't either.
Speaker 0: but she shoots the baby and then she turns and shoots the ice.
Speaker 0: and apparently the first rule of ice club is you do not shoot the ice because as soon as she shoots it it cracks and Like roots come out and fucking kill everybody.
Speaker 0: and here's the thing.
Speaker 0: All right, the show decides to randomly kill all these characters.
Speaker 0: It did it in an Unnecessarily and unexpectedly gory way.
Speaker 1: It was pretty gruesome like they're chopping heads off and exploding goo everywhere.
Speaker 0: It was pretty bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it really didn't fit the show at all to have that kind of go cuts back to all the people who were still alive.
Speaker 0: And they're surrounding an ice.
Speaker 0: and then there's these little robots and out of the blue one of them appears and melts the head of one of the three triplets and then like almost all the characters we knew die.
Speaker 0: and then One of the triplets pulls out a little pistol and shoots the ice.
Speaker 1: Well, they were stupid.
Speaker 1: It was like it was like oh you dumb rookie you fire didn't you know?
Speaker 1: It would you know.
Speaker 0: bounce off the wall and then it hit the ice and then up shit and the ice pops and the same Thing happens and fucking everybody dies.
Speaker 1: Well, a lot of people die except this is one person and it was kind of weird.
Speaker 1: It's like on the bus or all the characters are hanging out.
Speaker 1: There was one person who wasn't.
Speaker 1: they were in the bus also a dude, but not really not really a dude But looked like a dude effectively and this person was in a cage on the bus Locked up and they had lots of guns in the cage.
Speaker 1: But then who locks someone in a cage with the guns?
Speaker 0: now They pull out like before like in the lead-up to all this.
Speaker 0: they pull out this gigantic gun and they pull out these Pinochet bullets and
Speaker 1: like one of them is a different color than the others
Speaker 0: and they go over and they unlock that girl's cage And they're like, here are the bullets
Speaker 1: letting you out
Speaker 0: now and then later
Speaker 1: on like this person some sort of dangerous weapon that needs to be let
Speaker 0: out.
Speaker 0: and later on this Person has the gun and loads it and is about to shoot the giant thing that was released from the ice Which is really stupid looking by the way And then gives this whole speech about and now I who remains will use the wicked Technology left behind.
Speaker 0: the evil legacy of men and she means men in the has a wee wee way very literally.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean remember why the last man there's no men left and then she shoots the penis bullet at the monster.
Speaker 0: The penis bullet by the way is an atomic bomb pretty much and the explosion the size of the explosion from the penis bullet is Unreasonably large.
Speaker 0: It's just not reasonable at all now to back up from the penis bullet at some point along the way.
Speaker 0: Show randomly cuts to these two girls on motorcycles like wandering around by themselves.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure exactly how they came into the show.
Speaker 1: one of the girls on the Motorcycle right was the magical girl you saw at the beginning when the truck crashed into the character We still have not seen again.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: the other one seems to be her sister or something and they had these Motorcycles and the magical girl seems to be up to something and the other girl is just sort of always standing near the bikes acting upset and They sort of cut to them every once in a while.
Speaker 1: Like what are they there for?
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 1: What are they?
Speaker 0: They find some canned crab and that's important.
Speaker 0: That's really important.
Speaker 1: I forgot about the crab.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she finds the canned crab.
Speaker 0: She's like, oh snap canned crab and everyone she meets you eat canned crab canned crab and they're like what?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but But that was totally unrelated to what's going on.
Speaker 0: But then this ice like gets out and it decides that what it wants to do is get on the freeway.
Speaker 0: So it just starts flying down the freeway and the girl with the penis bullets is standing on it shooting it and it doesn't seem To care.
Speaker 1: All right She's standing on the monster riding it like a surfboard down the highway and eventually Passes by the girls with the bikes and the monster grabs one of the girls and just holds it.
Speaker 0: and magical girl and then the magical girls like ah, and then the other girl with the penis bullets is like All right, and just cuts.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, don't forget like two characters have gun swords.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah,
Speaker 0: but and just like cuts her out of the thing and holds her and then you know thing blows up and one thing leads to another but The girl she saves the magical girl grabs her hand Puts it on her boob and basically says alright wanna have sex now
Speaker 1: And she's just like,
Speaker 0: uh, I'm not a lesbian And the other girls like.
Speaker 1: so what we're like friends is like friends, you know share bodies with each other.
Speaker 1: She's like no they don't.
Speaker 0: and where I come from friends just talk to each other.
Speaker 0: Yeah and and the thing is when she cried like she grabs her boob and With the other girls hand and then you realize that all the characters in the show have enormous Kazongas, no, some of them don't but well don't.
Speaker 0: they're hidden under gigantic armor.
Speaker 0: exactly They're there, you know, they're there.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean on the anime's news ever cuz genres romance science fiction themes Yuri, so yeah, Yuri's big.
Speaker 0: in this show There's a lot of Yuri going on in the world with no when they cut to like the the princess like evil Overlord woman.
Speaker 0: and there's the throwaway scene where she's like send me a couple of young girls.
Speaker 0: I'm bored.
Speaker 0: And then it turns out that she has a million ices Like in her office full of maids.
Speaker 0: and she has a million maids.
Speaker 1: and the only other notable thing left to say about the show?
Speaker 1: Is the scene with the can crab base?
Speaker 0: All right, so you think the show has already gone in every direction it could.
Speaker 0: But you know what.
Speaker 0: there hasn't been enough Miyazaki there hasn't been enough like Nausicaa Valley of the Wind in this.
Speaker 1: yeah, we've had every other kind of anime.
Speaker 0: We've had mecha's and you know magical girls maids Yuri boobs penis guns up the cooter.
Speaker 1: You know every genre of anime except the Miyazaki genre.
Speaker 0: So what do they do?
Speaker 0: is they go all Nausicaa?
Speaker 1: Basically, the magical girl has her can crab and like these birds come and you're just like Oh birdie birdie.
Speaker 0: You forget she the girl who she tried to have sex with who saved her who is also the girl with a penis gun who?
Speaker 0: Was locked up.
Speaker 0: She's like, I'm gonna take you to see my special place But special place is not a euphemism.
Speaker 0: It's just a place.
Speaker 1: Yes and She sort of Tosses the can crab on the ground and his birdies come and his little birdies like birdie birdie birdie and they're eating the can Crab and it's like oh, isn't that nice?
Speaker 1: these weird alien birds are eating the crab and the other girls like So.
Speaker 1: and then you see these birds from far away are coming and they're Gigantic, you don't know they're gigantic.
Speaker 1: He just looks like this birds more birds coming.
Speaker 1: It's like oh more birds are coming.
Speaker 1: Right and then but for some reason the girl with the do is locked in the cage and has the gun.
Speaker 1: You know, the penis gun is like, ah, oh my god.
Speaker 1: We should get out of here.
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh there must be a lot of birds coming and they look maybe they're dangerous birds or something, right?
Speaker 1: Then the magical girls like no, it's okay.
Speaker 1: and Eventually the birds get there.
Speaker 0: now the fun.
Speaker 0: and then you realize the birds are gigantic.
Speaker 0: The one job one of the giant like the gigantic birds and I say gigantic.
Speaker 0: I mean Gargantuan like bigger than any dinosaur ever and that they come and they look at.
Speaker 0: one of them looks around and reaches down and picks up a piece of this crab meat.
Speaker 0: now that is the equivalent of me reaching down with my mouth and Picking up like a single bacteria like a deer tick and eating it and enjoying it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like this giant bird.
Speaker 1: He's this tiny tiny tiny tiny piece of crab.
Speaker 0: She's like, oh and then a tiny little baby bird goes needs the crab and then it cuts to one of the birds and the bird He's still a crab and goes bird bird bird bird bird bird and then it rolls and becomes a green blob.
Speaker 0: Yep, and so it's a green blob.
Speaker 1: all the little birds turn into green blobs and then all the big birds They all turn into big birds don't turn into green blobs.
Speaker 1: They sort of stand in this formation.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah, they stand in formation and then a Giant forest grows out of all the birds and they all turn into flower.
Speaker 1: I'll turn into plants and flowers and trees.
Speaker 0: but then if you pick a flower it turns into a tiny little bird and flies away and the scene has all this music and there's feathers and flower petals flying everywhere and They're saying those kind of heavy things that people in Nausicaa would say.
Speaker 0: and there's this.
Speaker 0: The science doesn't work that way.
Speaker 0: But that's what the the characters say stuff about.
Speaker 0: the earth is poisoned and we're full of poison.
Speaker 0: But these birds are pure and blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: and then the other characters like but this it doesn't work that way.
Speaker 0: Now then
Speaker 1: a bunch of shit
Speaker 0: in the middle of all this where you know They can't just end on it and anything even remotely artistic or poignant even though it's faux poignant at best It cuts to the girl who was with the magical girl who is from the above looking down and sees this going on and I point out that earlier on there's actually one good scene probably only good scene where she stumbles upon I guess the wreck of one of those buses or something and attached to it are all these rocket launchers.
Speaker 0: and she sees him and she goes.
Speaker 0: ah And the next scene with her.
Speaker 0: basically she's covered her bike in rocket launchers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was pretty funny.
Speaker 0: But then you see her and she's looking down.
Speaker 0: she sees this going on and She says well, I'm totally going to kill those two and she pulls out one of the rocket launchers and then the episode ends.
Speaker 0: Yep, I don't know what there really.
Speaker 1: there was a weird scene involving a character I never saw before right somehow involved with the girl who is in the opening scene that got hit by the truck like somehow like it was looked like some sort of afterlife netherworld kind of place and Something about someone possessing someone or something.
Speaker 1: I don't know and it made no sense whatsoever.
Speaker 1: So the one character that there might have been a reason to care about a little tiny bit ends up Do doing something that I can't understand?
Speaker 1: this show Was awful is pretty terrible.
Speaker 1: Maybe one of the worst shows I ever seen.
Speaker 0: I don't know why I watched the whole thing because it's one of those things where all right This is dumb.
Speaker 0: But I at least want to know what the deal is.
Speaker 0: and then not only do not find out the deal But I imagine I posit that the deal is just bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it really I gotta say Yeah so to not leave you hanging.
Speaker 0: at the end the girl who is the the penis gun girl in her head has a vision of The girl from the real world from the opening and it turns out that that girl from the oh, is that how it went?
Speaker 0: Yes Is actually from the past from when there were still men and she magically has all the memories of the penis girl.
Speaker 0: Well, the penis gun girl, I don't think there are any penis girls.
Speaker 1: I hope to God there aren't Although it's gotta go to every genre.
Speaker 1: I really know you look at the credits of this show and it's made by all these people who have Experienced in the anime industry, but they're all key animators mecha designers lower-level Animators and that's not necessarily a bad thing.
Speaker 1: But you the the lack of experience shows and it really is this sort of hacked together Sort of I guess some moderately well animated piece of junk.
Speaker 1: There's the writing.
Speaker 1: there's no writing to speak of.
Speaker 1: It's just a big.
Speaker 1: well It's just a big mess.
Speaker 0: the person who wrote the screenplay for this Yasushi Hirano, uh did among other things Mobile suit Zeta Gundam the script.
Speaker 0: All right, not bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah the script of that and the script of this All right, well the screenplay I guess.
Speaker 1: oh, so that's not actually writing the story that's just Taking the story and adapting it.
Speaker 1: for you know, it's a screenplay for yes.
Speaker 0: Also the screenplay for eight men after which I kind of like yeah, it's not too bad that bad.
Speaker 1: No, no, it's it's not as good as I guess the original Tobor the eighth man, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, they added a lot of Early.
Speaker 0: Well early 90s.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that shows from like 94.
Speaker 0: Oh god.
Speaker 0: Oh wow 93.
Speaker 1: anyway This shows project ice or ice is a bad OAV.
Speaker 1: stay away from it.
Speaker 1: It makes no sense.
Speaker 1: It's just a bunch of random anime shit sort of slapped together and somehow forced to relate to each other in a way.
Speaker 1: that makes no sense and it is not worth the Large amount of time it takes to watch it or not.
Speaker 1: It's not even worth the free download of illegalness.
Speaker 0: So, uh Yeah Yeah Stay tuned next week.
Speaker 0: We'll review something good.
Speaker 0: Maybe This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm.
Speaker 1: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.