Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, July 22nd.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm Rip and this is Geek Nights!
Speaker 0: Tonight, Mega Man!
Speaker 1: *sings to the music*.
Speaker 0: Let's do this!
Speaker 0: Seeing as tribes 2 is indisputably the greatest FPS of all time, but the game died.
Speaker 0: You know, best game till they fucked it up.
Speaker 0: We've been trying to get a game on, but it's not that easy considering that all the official servers are down and it's a big.
Speaker 0: you know the technology is old and you got to get a copy of the game and the keys and the patches and the whole.
Speaker 0: it's a big mess it's.
Speaker 0: you know even though it's the best game ever it's very hard to get it working.
Speaker 0: so in my desire to play some FPS action I resorted to playing the second best FPS ever natural selection and hot.
Speaker 0: then playing the second best FPS ever which is actually very easy to play because there's plenty of servers and plenty of people playing all the time.
Speaker 0: it just works.
Speaker 0: it's a half-life 1 mod.
Speaker 0: it just works and it's free.
Speaker 0: and it's everyone has half-life 1. everyone has steam.
Speaker 0: it's easy to.
Speaker 0: so playing NS the second best game FPS game but it's easy to play is better than struggling to play an inadequate game of tribes 2.
Speaker 0: I mean if I could get a real game of tribes 2 on NS would be ignored.
Speaker 0: but seeing as that is very difficult and NS is very easy and has got played see I'd kind of as much as I love NS.
Speaker 1: I kind of about it because once I had tribes installed I realized that playing tribes alone with like 18 bots is more fun than playing pretty much any other FPS with people.
Speaker 0: it's not more fun than that ass.
Speaker 1: well the thing is NS.
Speaker 1: yeah only if you can get a good game on and there's like what two servers.
Speaker 1: so if they're both full what are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: I've had no trouble.
Speaker 0: actually I've had a little bit of trouble getting into him but I just sort of refresh a little bit and I wait for someone to drop out and I get right in and then I'm I stay in and it's good.
Speaker 0: but in my playing NS it was.
Speaker 0: I didn't get anything else done.
Speaker 0: I just played a whole bunch of NS.
Speaker 1: see I didn't play so much NS because I knew better.
Speaker 1: I knew that.
Speaker 0: yeah you played Civ 4 instead.
Speaker 1: yeah but I play Civ 4 on the train.
Speaker 1: uh-huh I only play.
Speaker 1: I've only played Civ 4 at home once in recent memory.
Speaker 1: that was when I was playing online with the rest of the crew.
Speaker 0: it doesn't matter I am a man in a desert and NS has provided is like an oasis and it was quite refreshing.
Speaker 0: and I even the last game I played on Sunday night was like one of the best games NS ever played around the Tanith map and you know that met.
Speaker 0: you're in that.
Speaker 0: the were the Marines.
Speaker 0: the marine base room has the two doors and the two walls and there's the the resource tower between them and everyone stands up on that computer console and the aliens come in and they're bio bomb in the RT and you can't get out and you just make this crazy last stand every time because it's so great.
Speaker 0: but see we played that and we were at the last stand in the marine base and I was like oh man this is the end just like always.
Speaker 0: and it felt again.
Speaker 0: that classic feeling of this is how it always goes.
Speaker 0: this is how it should be.
Speaker 0: but one key difference was that we actually had one of the hives locked down it's pretty much the base and one hive.
Speaker 0: but that hive was locked down with seizures and turrets and everything.
Speaker 0: so what actually ended up happening is because of our phase gates because of our excellent commander and because of people actually listening to the commander he slowly gave out weapons as we built up the resources for our two resource towers and he said if you have a weapon don't go anywhere.
Speaker 0: and most people actually didn't go anywhere.
Speaker 0: they just stayed in the base and they stayed in the hive and we defended from the alien.
Speaker 1: that's crazy.
Speaker 1: no one ever follows orders.
Speaker 0: we stated we defended from the aliens.
Speaker 0: just constantly rushing and bile bombing for a good must have been like five to ten minutes.
Speaker 0: and what actually happened was even though we had so few resource towers the aliens had so many because we actually killed Onos.
Speaker 0: is that you kill an Onos at 75 res?
Speaker 0: it takes a few minutes for that to build back up.
Speaker 0: so after we were able to actually drain them of resources.
Speaker 0: but meanwhile we didn't have that many resource or a good rate of resource increase.
Speaker 0: but we had saved up so we actually had more power than they did.
Speaker 0: we had jet packs and HMGs and grenade launchers.
Speaker 1: see it definitely sounds like it was a case of very organized and resilient Marines coupled with good commander and mediocre aliens.
Speaker 0: well the aliens were good but they didn't.
Speaker 0: they didn't have the resolve that the Marines had and slowly but surely we dominated the entire map.
Speaker 0: and it was.
Speaker 0: it took a good 15 to 20 minutes to conquer back everything.
Speaker 0: I think the entire game was over half hour but ah that was that was.
Speaker 0: that wasn't just water refreshing the parched man in the desert.
Speaker 0: that was something more.
Speaker 0: I guess there's nothing more refreshing than water.
Speaker 1: you know we're still working toward having a tribe server that we can all play on in the front row crew and we'll teach you guys about what FPS is used to be like.
Speaker 1: but in the meantime it's much more likely that we can all just play NS together.
Speaker 1: I think we tried once before.
Speaker 0: we tried once to teach NS right so we actually got like six listeners and us on a server however however but it was a public server so we're gonna make our own server but our computers suck.
Speaker 1: we didn't have a public IP and we just gave up right away and just decided to pick some empty server.
Speaker 1: and there must be a lot of people who go to play NS and just watch for a server that isn't full because well isn't empty.
Speaker 1: well isn't full or empty.
Speaker 1: yeah look for a server with people that isn't full that's not bots yeah.
Speaker 0: so as soon as people saw that our server had like seven non bots on it they all came rushing in the best.
Speaker 0: suddenly this one dude out.
Speaker 1: I was on my team I'm in the aliens and we're just kind of playing and this guy in the voice chat just start saying what the fuck everyone sucks.
Speaker 1: why won't anyone build anything?
Speaker 1: why don't we have any RTS?
Speaker 1: I'm the breeds one.
Speaker 1: yet I'm like the Marines suck - it's like what's going on.
Speaker 0: that's what we get for trying to do a private learning tutorial game on a public server but we're just gonna have to run our own.
Speaker 1: sir I think imagine we want to make all the listeners be Marines.
Speaker 0: yes you got to teach one side at a time.
Speaker 1: yes so you start coaching them and then I'm an alien.
Speaker 1: I walk in I'm like and you're like this is a skulk and I walk in as a skulk.
Speaker 0: observe the skulk observe what it does to hungry Joe over there and they do the same thing when everyone's the aliens a marine walks in he go this is a marine.
Speaker 0: but yeah I think that problem was he gave whoever was playing that game a bad impression was because they suck so much.
Speaker 0: but the other you know people came in.
Speaker 0: we're actually trying to play a game.
Speaker 0: they had to actually just sort of order them around and it became for the people who didn't know what they were doing a follow orders game which is certainly not because if you know what you're doing you don't need someone to tell you what to do all the time.
Speaker 1: well at the same time actually like when I first played NS and I was bad at it what I liked more than anything was the fact that I was given orders to follow because it's kind of like when you play tie fighter you like in a game where you get on ambiguous orders and following them is a good thing.
Speaker 1: yeah you feel good when you don't know what to do and you don't understand anything and this voice from above gives you a welder and says go weld that thing.
Speaker 1: these two guys will protect you while you do it.
Speaker 0: yeah we have to learn how to follow.
Speaker 0: you know you get you got to do the trip boot camp before you do that.
Speaker 0: yeah if someone's yelling go to instead of.
Speaker 0: I didn't send you to boot camp in the real military just sent you straight to Iraq and then they started telling you what to do you like.
Speaker 0: oh god it sucks is the worst thing ever.
Speaker 1: if you want to place a man ask with us.
Speaker 1: sadly I don't know how much I'll be playing until I don't know September.
Speaker 0: I'm not probably gonna be playing much until September either.
Speaker 0: I mean you know starting now I really got you know shit to do.
Speaker 0: yeah con season is pretty much used up my last gas to play at us.
Speaker 1: yeah but come this winter we're gonna be playing some NS.
Speaker 1: so if you want to get your groove on ahead of time head over to guns for back to school.
Speaker 1: the best little NS server.
Speaker 0: yeah there's that server.
Speaker 0: guns for back to school.
Speaker 1: that is bad.
Speaker 0: the server I play on the most that if I can get in it's always full.
Speaker 1: that server was awesome when we first found out about NS back at RIT and it is been awesome continuously until this day.
Speaker 0: those people also run TF 2 servers for you people who still play TF 2 even though it's no good.
Speaker 1: oh god TF 2 yeah.
Speaker 0: but guns for back to school is good people.
Speaker 0: they have pretty much the best FPS servers there are.
Speaker 1: I think NS has some of the best FPS community there is.
Speaker 0: well that's the other thing.
Speaker 0: you play NS right.
Speaker 0: it's a complicated game.
Speaker 0: it's not easy to understand if you're not you know hardcore there's a lot of things to learn.
Speaker 0: it doesn't have the best user interface but because it's such an old game there's not a lot of new players.
Speaker 0: everyone in there is really experienced and everyone in there actually cares about the game and it's a serious game and you're not gonna find a lot of schmucks.
Speaker 0: you know going like in counter-strike where it's just like oh it's your mom you suck faggot know something loud and you die.
Speaker 0: fuck you does.
Speaker 0: that shit doesn't happen so bad.
Speaker 0: you get a lot of like just although we've talked it's not super mature but people are in there actually playing the game somewhat seriously.
Speaker 1: not only that it's more than what like when you know you've lost or won a lot of times funny things just because there's a certain etiquette to playing NS that is separate from the how to win of NS.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: you remember in the early days of natural selection when the people were losing and it was pretty much a foregone conclusion that you were gonna lose.
Speaker 0: you would push f4 to go to the ready room.
Speaker 0: the game be over.
Speaker 0: now that you don't do that anymore that's that's a faux pas if you push f4 to go to the ready room.
Speaker 0: in fact many servers won't let you.
Speaker 0: instead when you're done pretty much what you do is you recycle everything and you hide and you try to survive for as long as you can just hiding.
Speaker 1: and it's you know what I've had some good times being a gorge with three defense towers hiding an event somewhere for ten minutes and the reason you know you might sound really stupid like you've already lost.
Speaker 0: why not just go die and end it quickly?
Speaker 0: right but no hiding is something it's it's like.
Speaker 0: it's something you must do.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like those people in as much as I hated them.
Speaker 0: you know even though they were doing the same thing when we were playing that Jedi Knight 2 and people would have the duals they would always bow and I would just stab them and win.
Speaker 0: well that was part of the etiquette too yeah and that the thing is is like.
Speaker 0: for some reason I didn't like that Jedi Knight etiquette.
Speaker 0: I just stabbed people.
Speaker 0: but in NS the etiquette of hiding at the end and you know doing a victory egg and stuff like that was all.
Speaker 0: there was something about that.
Speaker 0: that was I don't know I like better.
Speaker 1: yeah but this isn't a show about NS.
Speaker 1: we've done at least one show about NS.
Speaker 0: we also did a show on BattleTech which you were gonna do a show on today.
Speaker 0: then I was like oh shit we did a show.
Speaker 1: I was excited about that.
Speaker 1: I feel like we should just do a BattleTech show again.
Speaker 1: I might say different things I don't know.
Speaker 0: I had to listen to the old BattleTech show.
Speaker 1: I guess I hope I mentioned that Scott always makes very ineffectual mechs that are covered in nothing but small lasers.
Speaker 0: I think you did mention that in the original battle.
Speaker 1: I mentioned that like every day.
Speaker 0: yes oh just one side note here really quick.
Speaker 0: there were some rules of the World of Warcraft miniatures game on their website.
Speaker 1: oh yeah these are the rules that they would not tell us about when we were press.
Speaker 0: I looked at the rules not so not so well considering you can take a look and judge for yourself but the rules that I've seen.
Speaker 0: not so.
Speaker 1: when we walked up with our little press badges all they could tell us was look how shiny these miniatures are.
Speaker 1: look how realistic they are.
Speaker 0: they were shiny.
Speaker 1: look at these.
Speaker 0: these are that Pokemon miniatures game.
Speaker 0: that is the really good Pokemon miniatures and like if I could get like a spare tomb out of there.
Speaker 0: I totally would.
Speaker 0: but you know if I really if I like to World of Warcraft and I wanted to have some World of Warcraft creatures I would you know buy some individual minis but I don't have a lot of confidence in this game.
Speaker 1: but anyway some of you might be want thinking that we're about to talk about e3 but now there's nothing to say about e3.
Speaker 1: it was pretty lame.
Speaker 1: nothing important was announced and that's the.
Speaker 0: yeah I'm not even gonna do news on e3 because it was so bleh.
Speaker 1: I already talked about the Netflix Xbox you know the last week's yeah and people are making a buzz about all the lame stuff that happened at the Nintendo panel.
Speaker 1: but eh eh is what I say also but I do want to talk about the fact that you know there's always more Castlevania games coming.
Speaker 1: it's got like at any given point.
Speaker 1: there's another but the two Castlevania games that have been announced there are clips for my link to one of them looks like more of the same thing and the other one looks really really really bad and I don't know why.
Speaker 1: why would they do this?
Speaker 0: I'm not really understanding what's been going on with the Castlevania like like licensed in Castlevania actually really illustrates something that we're gonna talk about in Scott's bit was the real news.
Speaker 1: yeah I'm gonna bring up because Castlevania really started floundering when it entered the 3d console world.
Speaker 0: I know they had this formula of 2d side scrolling whipping game right and in Castlevania 2 they added some weird shit that didn't go over that.
Speaker 0: well except for rim.
Speaker 0: who's the only person who loved it?
Speaker 0: hey can't fuck you.
Speaker 1: Castlevania 2 was the best NES.
Speaker 1: Castlevania.
Speaker 0: I guess it might have had the best music.
Speaker 1: Castlevania 3 was the second best.
Speaker 0: first of all Castlevania.
Speaker 0: well everyone knows that that PlayStation 1 even though yeah everyone considers the PlayStation 1 with the Symphony of the Night right to be like the best one is the one I haven't played.
Speaker 0: I played all the other side scrolling.
Speaker 0: Castlevania is good.
Speaker 1: I haven't played the GBA ones but Chris I honestly Castlevania the night was a special case in that it was this confluence of.
Speaker 1: I mean for one that the music in that game that soundtrack was something that was unheard of in gaming at the time - in the era when suddenly 2d games disappeared and everything was 3d bullshit.
Speaker 1: someone made a good 2d game a really good 2d game yep which was the thing everyone had always been saying why don't you just make an awesome 2d game?
Speaker 0: I know it's it's people.
Speaker 0: they have a game and it's in a particular genre and then they have this need to like take that game license and put it in other things right and I guess it works for Mario but it doesn't really work for anything else.
Speaker 1: how long were people clamoring for a new 2d Mario?
Speaker 0: I know right we finally got one and it was okay but it was a little easy a little quick.
Speaker 1: yeah I was about to say a little easy a quick.
Speaker 0: yeah actually I try.
Speaker 0: I was.
Speaker 0: I was well on my way to getting all the big coins in that game.
Speaker 1: so it was.
Speaker 1: I realized I didn't care.
Speaker 0: I also stopped carrying around like world 4.
Speaker 1: yeah the annoying part was not that I you know the coins were kind of hard to get all of them but the fact that I beat the entire game pretty much without trying and without really dying yeah as opposed to Mario 3 where I can't even beat that game half the time let alone.
Speaker 0: well I can pretty much get to the final world all the time but it's pretty much a matter of will I run out of stuff before I beat the final castle because I'm.
Speaker 0: there are a few levels in the in the final world that I'm not so good at and like the flying ships one sometimes I'll die a few times and I mean I have plenty of lives.
Speaker 0: but if I don't have any goodies left in my goodie bin and I'm at the final castle what the fuck am I gonna do?
Speaker 0: I can't.
Speaker 0: I can't beat it when I'm small I'm not that good.
Speaker 1: the final castle actually is pretty easy compared to everything else.
Speaker 0: thing is I've done to see.
Speaker 0: because of the way I play Mario 3 I've played the early levels a whole bunch in the late levels almost none.
Speaker 0: so I can beat the final castle and I know it.
Speaker 0: but I don't know it perfectly.
Speaker 0: so you know it's sort of like you know you do the final castle.
Speaker 0: I've played that level fewer times than any other level in the game except for maybe some world six and seven levels.
Speaker 1: but but anyway yeah the other confluence was that they took this 2d game and they added this kind of you know the weapon the way the game worked.
Speaker 1: they added the perfect measure for that kind of person the kind of person who would be drawn into that to make it this just epically legendary game that is loved to this day by gamers of all stripes.
Speaker 1: yep so uh anyway Castlevania judgment for the Wii is as far as I can tell a mediocre 3d fighting game.
Speaker 0: yeah I don't know why.
Speaker 0: who thought of this like hey we need a Castlevania for the Wii.
Speaker 0: I know let's make a fighting game with one fact in fact why don't I just make a side scroller with a whip?
Speaker 1: it looks a lot like Castlevania 64.
Speaker 0: yeah well Castlevania 64 trim didn't even really know existed.
Speaker 1: I just showed it to him because pretty much when the entire war was was announced was when I was already a PC gamer and just gave up on.
Speaker 0: see people always forget.
Speaker 0: you know they remember Superman 64 cuz has legendary terribleness but Castlevania 64 and Shadowgate 64 are also legendarily terrible.
Speaker 0: it's legendarily a word.
Speaker 1: yes it is now never forget but I have nothing more to say about it.
Speaker 1: it looks terrible yeah.
Speaker 1: but then Castlevania order of ecclesias ecclesia ecclesiastica doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: it's basically basically more of the same.
Speaker 0: it is just more side scrolling Castlevania the door just like all the other DS and GBA games.
Speaker 1: now my only worry is that if I were to rank the the modern side scrolling Castlevania's it would pretty much be DS Symphony Night portrait of ruin in that order and a lot of people are gonna hate me for that.
Speaker 1: but I think DS was a better game.
Speaker 0: you didn't play all the GBA ones but I think the GBA ones from what I can tell I don't know for sure because I didn't play them.
Speaker 0: I think there's three of them and I think they were just like you know the DS one except of course no dual screen action.
Speaker 0: but they were the same kind of gameplay only less because it was GBA.
Speaker 1: but my problem is that DS was really good and portrait of ruin wasn't quite as good.
Speaker 1: I didn't really like it nearly.
Speaker 0: I didn't like it nearly as much either because he wasn't as big a game it didn't feel as epic and large and it didn't really have the same sort of stuff going on.
Speaker 0: and that dual character thing was just sort of annoying it wasn't.
Speaker 1: yeah of course it kind of made up for that by having the awesome bonus playthrough modes.
Speaker 0: yeah it did.
Speaker 0: and then Castlevania.
Speaker 0: one of the the DS said Belmont mode right well it had Julius mode.
Speaker 1: right Julius mode but the this one had the armor mode and it had the vampire mode and all.
Speaker 1: it was awesome.
Speaker 0: yeah those are good.
Speaker 0: the thing is with that kind of game I don't feel like playing it again even with the different mode it's got.
Speaker 0: you know I don't know what it is.
Speaker 1: see I kind of did but the problem is it wasn't as good as DS.
Speaker 1: so if this third one isn't as good as porch if it isn't better than portrait of ruin I see the trend and I'm bowing out of these games forever.
Speaker 0: well I think what you could do is you would go and try to find that GBA cartridge that has the 2g to the first two GBA ones on it because that's a super bargain.
Speaker 0: and then if those are good get the third GBA.
Speaker 1: I'll just play DS and Symphony of the night again.
Speaker 0: but hey yeah anyway.
Speaker 0: so speaking of people taking old genres and then to old games and try to mess them up capcom has finally done the opposite.
Speaker 0: I hope they start a trend for the future here.
Speaker 0: you probably all know this.
Speaker 0: but Megaman 9 yeah not Megaman X 9 not Megaman.
Speaker 0: you know battle network 9 not Megaman 9.
Speaker 0: 3d no Megaman not Megaman legends 2 or 3.
Speaker 0: Megaman 9 as it was.
Speaker 1: no Megaman legend.
Speaker 1: everyone.
Speaker 0: for anyone who doesn't know there were six Megaman games.
Speaker 0: for the NES.
Speaker 0: there was one for the Super Nintendo which is Megaman 7 and there's one for the PlayStation which is Megaman 8 and the one for the SNES and the one for PlayStation actually got fancier than the originals.
Speaker 0: you know one through six were all the same kind of game.
Speaker 0: they all looked the same.
Speaker 1: well pretty much I would say this two through six are almost exactly the same ones lighting and once a little wonky.
Speaker 1: you know what what balls.
Speaker 1: I've never beaten it.
Speaker 0: I've beaten one but it was really hard especially the yellow blob guy.
Speaker 0: three added the slide and four or five added the charge regular gun but they were pretty much the same game.
Speaker 0: then Megaman 7 was a little different.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: it was mostly the same gameplay but it was updated you know was not totally the same.
Speaker 0: it was a lot more like Megaman X in the way controlled and such.
Speaker 0: and then Megaman 8 was just a PlayStation monstrosity with this horrible anime at the front of it.
Speaker 0: good God but but Megaman 9 for Wii 360 and PlayStation and they're gonna be.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be a download game.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be just like Megaman 1 through 6 only new and hard.
Speaker 1: this is fascinating because this is the kind of thing like I kind of hinted at earlier gamers.
Speaker 1: what pretty much when the N64 came out and all these games were different.
Speaker 1: I remember there was this giant outcry even back then for someone to just make one of the old 2d games make the Legend of Zelda or make a Final Fantasy or something with the memory and the power of the Nintendo 64.
Speaker 0: that's something I always said was like hey all right you know everyone's gone to making these 3d games and I think the reason they went to 3d and shied away from 2d is because systems like the Neo Geo the turbo graphics the Atari Jaguar especially when they made 2d games they made really big fancy 2d games.
Speaker 0: the people weren't into them.
Speaker 0: they went for the 3d games and 3d game sold.
Speaker 0: so people stayed with 3d and 2d games really only did well on the handhelds where they were necessary.
Speaker 0: but even now we're getting 3d games on the handhelds too.
Speaker 0: but I always said hey if you have such a powerful machine right with so much memory why don't you just make Super Metroid a game on the exactly the same as Super Metroid in terms of the way it plays?
Speaker 0: you know a side-scrolling.
Speaker 0: explore Planet Zeebs Metroid your Sam is turned into a ballgame.
Speaker 0: but just make the map like five times as big with like five times as many bosses and five times many secrets.
Speaker 1: and now great there are reasons.
Speaker 1: I mean you've.
Speaker 1: one argument is that it does take a long time to develop that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: well it doesn't take a lot of time to develop the technology.
Speaker 0: it takes a lot of time to make all those maps cuz whether it's 2d or 3d.
Speaker 0: you know it's a lay out the maps and that's a human job that takes a long time to get a test them in the hole.
Speaker 1: but at the same time 2d games require far less playtesting than 3d games.
Speaker 0: that is definitely true.
Speaker 0: it also cost a lot less money.
Speaker 0: now it looks like Mega Man 9 is gonna be the same size in terms of.
Speaker 1: you know how big the levels are compared to fine because being older and wiser I realize that I alright.
Speaker 1: so Final Fantasy 4 was 40 hours long.
Speaker 1: I don't need to play Final Fantasy 4 for 140 hours.
Speaker 0: not a Final Fantasy game that's for sure but Mega Man game with 18 robot masters.
Speaker 0: I would not be disappointed.
Speaker 0: 16 robot master.
Speaker 1: in that case I think you have to add something more.
Speaker 1: maybe here's my vision.
Speaker 0: we have so many different weapons and levels would be larger and actually require you to use the different weapon.
Speaker 1: my vision would be a co-op 2d games Mega Man 0 except not shitty.
Speaker 1: I just imagine Mega Man 9 could also add a co-op mode.
Speaker 0: that'd be alright.
Speaker 0: yeah there are a lot of things you could do with it but generally the idea is that there is a strong strong feeling at least within me and I hope within many other people that all we want is direct.
Speaker 0: I mean we want you know a lot of games now are sequels of old games but just make them like the old games.
Speaker 0: only different means nothing.
Speaker 0: people always you know game reviewers especially without his game doesn't innovate.
Speaker 0: what you don't always need to innovate I mean if you just took Super Metroid and made new levels even if it wasn't any bigger than Super Metroid it was just more Super Metroid.
Speaker 0: Super Metroid is great.
Speaker 0: let me look what's wrong with more Super Metroid.
Speaker 0: if I got a guy ice cream if I like strawberry ice cream I might get strawberry ice cream again next time.
Speaker 0: it's not any different than last time but it's still good.
Speaker 0: I could still eat more of it.
Speaker 1: well there's also the idea of incremental improvements.
Speaker 1: I mean look at Warcraft Warcraft to Warcraft 3 or command and conquer command and conquer - they took a game it worked but technology got better and you know they learn more about game design and they said all right let's make that game but fix the things we know are wrong with
Speaker 0: it.
Speaker 0: yeah and that's the thing with Castlevania.
Speaker 0: look Castlevania you know the DS ones are not really that much of a departure from Castlevania one.
Speaker 0: it's a side scrolling whipping game at heart and there's some extra stuff added on there mostly technological niceties and it's still great.
Speaker 0: and you know trying to go away from that trying to make Castlevania 64 results in badness.
Speaker 1: see I think the problem is a lot of game designers and a lot of game buyers who aren't I guess I don't want to use the term like hard savvy people who really are fans of games more so than just playing them the people who care about them and think about it.
Speaker 1: or gaming is not a distraction but it's actually a hobby.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm when you when there's a new game it seems like people who aren't like that or will look at it and say all right this new game has made previous games obsolete.
Speaker 1: I've made a new genre.
Speaker 1: I've made a 3d punching game so 2d punching games are obsolete.
Speaker 1: I want to make a 4d punching game 3d punch yeah which is you know 20 different guys to punch.
Speaker 0: that's the same as the NES punch out.
Speaker 1: or well we've got 3d.
Speaker 1: 2d side scrollers are obsolete.
Speaker 1: that's like saying well we've got the TV so radio is now obsolete.
Speaker 1: right granted a lot of people are saying that.
Speaker 1: that's why podcasting is still struggling so much.
Speaker 1: but it's much like how 2d games can coexist and have a place because they are a kind of game.
Speaker 1: among 3d games radio has a place among video because you can't always watch something while you're doing something there.
Speaker 0: even remember there are people out there who are modifying game ROMs those people they made to Zelda one game that wasn't set with all new maps.
Speaker 0: now to see.
Speaker 1: yeah it's stupid hard hard as ball.
Speaker 0: there's some guys who are making a Metroid 2 but they're making it on the Super Metroid engine.
Speaker 0: there are those people who make those Mario world levels the super hard Mario 1 levels.
Speaker 0: there is a big.
Speaker 0: you know the reason that those those things are so popular.
Speaker 0: but can you know they're not stupidly popular?
Speaker 0: but this is because they're very inaccessible.
Speaker 0: if one of the big game companies actually made that sort of activity accessible.
Speaker 0: I think it would really explode.
Speaker 0: and Megaman 9 I think when you're gonna see how high its sales are will demonstrate that.
Speaker 1: but I gotta stress again this game is not going to be the Mario remake where it was easy as crap.
Speaker 0: no this is good.
Speaker 1: Megaman 9 is very hard.
Speaker 0: it's just as hard as all the other men.
Speaker 1: we didn't want to do Megaman but easy.
Speaker 1: we want players to get better and we want them to remember.
Speaker 1: I've always tried to challenge players and I think there are gamers who miss being challenged by games.
Speaker 0: yes there are hello.
Speaker 0: I'm here.
Speaker 1: I'm so looking forward to this.
Speaker 1: I wasn't even a huge fan of Megaman games.
Speaker 0: I thought you hated Megaman.
Speaker 1: I respect Megaman games for being good.
Speaker 1: I enjoyed them and played them but they're.
Speaker 0: that kind of game is not my bag just like it's not really anything for Castlevania except for the shooting instead of whipping.
Speaker 1: yeah it's a little bit different in that much mainly the fact of course I point out that some people don't get it and because the thing I really didn't like was the basic gun that Megaman had and the way the game played before.
Speaker 1: you had other things I didn't really like but quote some guy who doesn't know anything.
Speaker 1: of course Megaman 9 is hard.
Speaker 1: I just wish they made it hard using something like enemy routes or bullet hells to get you in a tough situation instead of just gimping the controls to a shoot forward position.
Speaker 1: okay yeah I gotta say one more thing.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna bring this up real quick.
Speaker 1: the news everyone seems to be losing their shit about the fact that there's gonna be achievements in World of Warcraft and World of Warcraft is nothing but achievements.
Speaker 1: what difference does it make if they put a label on them but people posted in our forum pointing out hey oh my god achievements in World of Warcraft?
Speaker 1: yeah we knew about this a month ago.
Speaker 0: next yeah I mean and seriously what difference does it make?
Speaker 0: you play World of Warcraft now you go on a quest you beat the quest they give you a you know a loot for your quest going.
Speaker 0: right now you're gonna go on the quest and it's gonna say congratulations you beat a quest and it'll give you a little badge the little sticker that you can wear on your on your on your merit badge sleeve thingy that you wear completed merit badges.
Speaker 1: you now have the complete 50 quests quest or the mags distance fallen without dying quests.
Speaker 1: I just.
Speaker 1: I feel more and more like this is.
Speaker 1: I mean I'm not saying Wow is dead or Blizzard is dead because it's just very far from the truth.
Speaker 0: I just think.
Speaker 0: I just say why is it news?
Speaker 0: the game has not changed in any way.
Speaker 0: the only difference is that they're giving up merit badges.
Speaker 1: well here's the thing the game.
Speaker 1: what is happening is that like ever I mean ever quest was the unassailable God back in the day and not that much.
Speaker 1: but they'll come out every other MMO.
Speaker 0: yeah yeah cuz it just cuz it.
Speaker 0: that's like saying you know captain of the you know the second string football team.
Speaker 1: yeah but I mean there were different eras.
Speaker 1: there were different MMOs that were kind of the king and eventually valedictorian of the world of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: school is going to fall eventually.
Speaker 1: World of Warcraft is not going to be the thing and some other game is going to make enough incremental improvements to destroy the World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: World of Warcraft 2 no universe of Warcraft I've actually got.
Speaker 1: there's a couple of world of Starcraft on the horizon that we'll talk about later but Diablo 3 Diablo 3 is not the same genre of game.
Speaker 1: I believe it is in the click on things John.
Speaker 0: well that is true.
Speaker 0: however there's a. there's actually Diablo.
Speaker 1: I'd say it's actually a worse game than World of Warcraft if such a thing as possible but I feel as though they're adding this only in reaction to certain other games that might be doing this.
Speaker 0: indeed they're trying to.
Speaker 1: they're trying to prevent the small wound that they currently have from becoming infected and causing their gangrenous like to fall off anyway.
Speaker 0: I don't think you don't worry about them dying anytime soon.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I give them three or four years.
Speaker 1: it's time for things.
Speaker 1: things of the day.
Speaker 0: doo doo doo okay doo doo.
Speaker 1: Vega posted this in our farm and this is so utterly adorable that I can't help but make it a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: it's just a cute little animation of cloud and it's got a fantasy 7 cloud yes not lucky to and it's got this kind of really really cute beatbox going on and it's got this really really cute song and it's really really really cute.
Speaker 0: I mean there are some other videos that were like related on YouTube that were sort of the same thing but they weren't as good as this one.
Speaker 0: it's the only good one.
Speaker 1: this one is just so utterly cute.
Speaker 1: I don't know what I can say.
Speaker 0: yep my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: you've probably seen this all over the Internet's.
Speaker 0: it's pretty much been everywhere but it's actually pretty cool.
Speaker 0: people have lately because JavaScript technology is getting so much better and Firefox and a guy went to school at RIT with who I'm actually sad when I found out he didn't graduate.
Speaker 0: it's like a big JavaScript evangelist at Mozilla and there's all sorts of stuff going on.
Speaker 0: some guy found out it was actually possible to make a game that would play in JavaScript but it would all be displayed in the favicon.
Speaker 0: he just kept changing the favicon.
Speaker 0: so you can now play defender in the favicon.
Speaker 0: so you know when you visit a web page like you visit Google and this blue G just up next to the URL that lets you know you're at Google.
Speaker 0: well now you can defender plays up there and that little square.
Speaker 1: if you go to this website here's on the website and you just you know wazzy around and hit n and you're playing defender.
Speaker 0: it's not good defender but I mean it's pretty much defender.
Speaker 0: you can't teleport but you can go left.
Speaker 0: you can go right you can shoot the aliens the aliens come down grab the humans and try to fly away.
Speaker 0: you try to rescue the humans.
Speaker 0: that's defender.
Speaker 0: I don't know what else to call it.
Speaker 1: oh oh we almost forgot to talk about this.
Speaker 1: we have to bring this up before we get into the main bit.
Speaker 1: so Sonic unleash they're making a Sonic game.
Speaker 1: okay yeah despite the fact that you know now they got to take old games and just remake them.
Speaker 1: when we saw the gameplay footage from this game it is basically they have made Sonic the Hedgehog exactly what it always should have been but they were only limited by technology.
Speaker 1: it is just Sonic the Hedgehog running and it's awesome.
Speaker 0: I mean I watched the.
Speaker 0: if you watch the gameplay footage video on game trailers or whatever of this game you go okay there you have an example of how you can take a game keep what makes the game good at its core fully intact and even improve upon it while also updating the graphics and the technology and the sound and the controls and everything else.
Speaker 0: it's a. it looked like a Sonic game unlike you know some of the other games recently like Sonic Adventure and other shit like that.
Speaker 0: this is a Sonic game through and through even though the technology was you know crazy advanced.
Speaker 0: it like totally modern.
Speaker 1: it gives me this very parkour feel.
Speaker 0: yeah so it really.
Speaker 0: I saw that and I was like I'm buying that game.
Speaker 0: thank God it's for the Wii.
Speaker 1: so the news is not that the Sonic game is coming or that it looked completely utterly amazingly.
Speaker 1: oh my god awesome.
Speaker 1: the news is that in fact it is only 50 percent awesome.
Speaker 1: you see by day Sonic the Hedgehog is running parkour yamakaze whatever you want to call it through the city by night.
Speaker 1: it's final fight.
Speaker 0: it's lumbering stretchy werewolf final fight way to steal Kotaku's description there.
Speaker 1: but that's exactly what it is you might think.
Speaker 1: what do you mean?
Speaker 1: stretchy werewolf?
Speaker 1: look at this picture.
Speaker 0: the story apparently is in this game.
Speaker 0: the game starts where dr.
Speaker 0: Robotnik.
Speaker 0: I guess whatever you want to call him I call him dr.
Speaker 0: you can call him egg.
Speaker 0: whatever you want to call him I don't.
Speaker 0: yeah dr.
Speaker 0: Robotnik is the guy's name.
Speaker 0: there's only one guy Sonic.
Speaker 0: people shove it.
Speaker 0: he comes and he throws a cast emerald at Sonic.
Speaker 0: Sonic turns into like some sort of where Sonic.
Speaker 0: so like a where Hedgehog.
Speaker 0: so already a hedgehog you can't like and throw up of some variety a double hedgehog.
Speaker 0: there you go.
Speaker 0: so at night he turns in like this slow evil horrible beast that fights and punches and kicks and slashes but during the day.
Speaker 1: Sonic the Hedgehog doing his awesomeness except it doesn't look like he fights.
Speaker 1: it looks like he just stretches.
Speaker 0: this is definitely a case of try to do too much of it.
Speaker 1: try to do.
Speaker 0: you should have just kept the awesome Sonic daytime action and just done like 20 levels of that.
Speaker 0: you would have had a hit a super runaway hit a plus perfect game.
Speaker 0: first Sonic game I would have bought since like the 16-bit era but instead maybe I'll rent it discount bin something just to play the daytime part because we know the daytime parts are excellent.
Speaker 1: even just seeing it there's nothing.
Speaker 0: I should hire some kid to beat the nighttime parts for me and I'll play all the daytime part.
Speaker 1: there is nothing they could do as far as I can see to ruin the daytime part.
Speaker 1: based on what little I've seen it is epic.
Speaker 0: someone should release a hack daytime only Sonic Unleashed kind of like the Phantom Edit exactly alright.
Speaker 1: so I can't believe.
Speaker 1: we haven't actually talked about this.
Speaker 0: I don't know have we?
Speaker 0: we might have messed up alright and I'll double-check because we did a show on Battletech and we were gonna do a show on Battletech and we realized oops we did one already.
Speaker 0: then we saw it.
Speaker 0: hey let's do the show.
Speaker 0: natural selection oops we did one already.
Speaker 0: there was nothing to show on.
Speaker 0: there's a day news about Megaman 9 pretty big.
Speaker 0: why don't we do show on Megaman?
Speaker 1: guess what we've ever done?
Speaker 0: a show on Megaman that's good.
Speaker 0: so Megaman 2 is the best video game of all time.
Speaker 0: I don't care what you say.
Speaker 1: playing this port of Megaman on the computer in the back of my fifth grade elementary school port of miss.
Speaker 0: what was that like a port of Megaman?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: it was just.
Speaker 1: it was Megaman on the PC.
Speaker 0: really I paid Megaman X the official DOS version.
Speaker 0: it was a Capcom.
Speaker 0: Capcom sold it in comp USA on a CD-ROM and it came with the six button controller that you could also use for Street Fighter on your computer which I also.
Speaker 0: I have Street Fighter 2 turbo for the computer.
Speaker 0: I still have it.
Speaker 0: championship edition no it's Street Fighter 2 it's super Street Fighter 2 turbo.
Speaker 0: that's what it is.
Speaker 0: it comes after championship edition.
Speaker 0: it has the four extra people you know in Akuma and the whole thing.
Speaker 0: but anyway Megaman Megaman when I was a kid right you know I wanted NES for a long time as every kid did and I got one like a year or so later than some of the other kids.
Speaker 0: he may be two years later you know cuz waiting for the birthday to come around and the whole bit you know and parents being cheap and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: but it's okay I got it in time.
Speaker 1: I was all cool but see I didn't get Megaman one.
Speaker 0: I got Megaman - I'm finishing my story.
Speaker 0: okay I also got Megaman - okay because my birthday you know they gave me you know the NES and the Mario.
Speaker 0: I think a birthday was like on a Monday or something.
Speaker 0: I forget what the situation was like.
Speaker 0: people were over maybe the day before so they gave me the NES and the Mario dot-com on that day but the next morning it was like okay you can have the Megaman - now Megaman - not only did I play the hell out of that game I mean and it wasn't like now where it's like.
Speaker 0: I know the password.
Speaker 0: just go to the end or I could just look up and see what order to fight the guys in right.
Speaker 1: it's kind of obvious.
Speaker 0: metal man beats wood man I know but well fireman actually man actually beats wood man even better.
Speaker 1: yeah metal man beats everything.
Speaker 0: I remember a day when like I could I couldn't beat airman even though airman was supposed to be easiest level because I couldn't deal with the jumping parts or the platforming.
Speaker 0: I wasn't that good yet because I mean this is the first time I ever had an NES.
Speaker 0: it took me a long time to beat that game but I remember one morning before Saturday morning cartoons I got to the end and that alien came up and it was just like oh shit oh shit.
Speaker 0: hey well man it was good.
Speaker 0: and then I finally I tried every item until eventually I figured out to use the bubble and I beat that alien and it was crazy.
Speaker 0: it was like.
Speaker 0: it was like a if he.
Speaker 0: if you know people have spiritual video game experiences.
Speaker 0: that was it.
Speaker 1: yes now is - Scott what bionic commandos.
Speaker 0: but now beating Megaman - is sort of like a reflex.
Speaker 0: now I can just do it but in those days it was.
Speaker 0: I mean when that dragon shows up and you're a little kid you just say you see that gigantic dragon just come out of the darkness behind you.
Speaker 0: holy shit.
Speaker 0: that's like because the whole game has just been sort of.
Speaker 0: you know little bad guys you know how to deal with robot masters you know how to use your items you know but when you see that dragon appeared it's that huge.
Speaker 0: we see that big tank appear in the next level.
Speaker 0: ah and like that gigantic gigantic tall chasm that you fall down into the abyss with spite with instant kill spikes lining all of the walls or in quick man's lover yet to fall through the incredible fast-moving lasers.
Speaker 1: you know that that level more than anything in most video games ever played.
Speaker 1: there's a certain feeling.
Speaker 1: you get this very very specific feeling.
Speaker 1: old-school gamers are much more familiar with this than a lot of new school games.
Speaker 1: don't quite give you this this visceral fear of if you screw up at all you're going to die.
Speaker 1: this level of tension that gets to the point that when you finally make it or when you finally die you're gripping the controller so hard that you might have broken it.
Speaker 0: that's the one thing I think that makes.
Speaker 0: that sets Mega Man apart from some of the other platformers like say the Castlevania's and the Mario's is that you have these situations where you know you are pretty much incredibly close to instant death and they give you this margin of safety that you can get through.
Speaker 0: I mean you don't have to be a hundred percent precise to beat quick man's area but you have to be ninety percent.
Speaker 0: yeah you gotta be nine you know you're.
Speaker 0: you go there you die a few times but then when you it is possible to get through it's not so hard that you're just frustrated want to kill yourself.
Speaker 0: but then again it's not so easy that you can just do it with nothing.
Speaker 0: so when you actually succeed and you will if you persist it feels really really really good.
Speaker 0: of course if you already know how to do it you can do it every time.
Speaker 0: it feels a little bit less good but it's good nonetheless.
Speaker 1: my strategy I'd always actually beat him first without any items.
Speaker 0: that's a good way to go.
Speaker 0: the other thing is that the game you know gives you a lot of options.
Speaker 0: I mean it's like you can use flash man to pause quick man's instant kill lasers in his level to get through more easily.
Speaker 0: but and that's a valid move except if you have the flash man weapon you know the flash pause whatever it's called.
Speaker 0: if you use that on quick man himself you can drain half of his life bar without taking any damage yourself.
Speaker 0: so if you can get through the lasers without getting hit you're much better off by saving that move for cook man himself.
Speaker 1: so what is it about these Megaman games?
Speaker 0: I think we need to explain what a Megaman game is the original Megaman series which is a much simpler side-scrolling series pretty much every year in the US.
Speaker 1: it was 87 89 90 92 92 94 95.
Speaker 0: the Megaman X was a more technologically advanced game and it's not Megaman 10. anyone who says that is stupid.
Speaker 0: you know what the hell you're talking about.
Speaker 1: now there will be a Megaman 10.
Speaker 0: Megaman X is basically like okay we have the Super Nintendo now.
Speaker 0: alright let's make a Megaman game that is you know set in the future is actually different character.
Speaker 0: he's the Megaman of the future.
Speaker 0: right dr.
Speaker 0: light is dead.
Speaker 0: you know it's past the end of the world now but it's the same universe.
Speaker 0: and this is the robot that dr.
Speaker 0: light made and was in hibernation and then woke up.
Speaker 0: and it's.
Speaker 0: he's sort of like Megaman and it's the same kind of game.
Speaker 0: you know pick the levels you know go in you know fight the robot masters get to the boss but the bad guy is not dr.
Speaker 0: wily.
Speaker 0: it's like Sigma or whatever and there's a lot more to it.
Speaker 0: you can re-enter levels that you've already beaten to go and get items you may have left behind and in addition to the weapons you get from beating the robot masters.
Speaker 0: there are like five power-ups like you need Megaman X's better helmet his better body.
Speaker 0: armor is better gloves is better shoes you know is better pants.
Speaker 0: the whole thing and they give you even more different abilities.
Speaker 0: and this it basically does with Super Metroid is to regular Metroid.
Speaker 0: you know it just adds a lot more stuff to it.
Speaker 0: it's not too much but it's not so little that it does nothing either.
Speaker 1: see I'll admit though I mean I enjoy playing a Megaman game I can't stand the Megaman X game.
Speaker 0: well I think what it is the Megaman style of game.
Speaker 0: yeah Megaman X one is is good stuff but as it goes on he gets like Megaman X three four five.
Speaker 0: it gets to be sort of annoying a little cluttered a little messy.
Speaker 0: it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not the smooth experience of one of the original Megaman games and it doesn't have the charm that you know.
Speaker 0: Megaman X and Megaman one two three.
Speaker 0: had you know that there's something missing there?
Speaker 0: I think that's another great thing about all the Megaman games.
Speaker 0: they sort of keep that you know especially when you're a kid and when games has still had a sneak to them of surprise and not knowing what lies beyond.
Speaker 0: I mean I talked about the dragon appearing from the darkness.
Speaker 0: well how about Megaman - you get to the end.
Speaker 0: they make you fight all the robot masters again ghosts of them.
Speaker 0: you mean that's doesn't seem like a big deal but it was like whoa totally crazy.
Speaker 0: and then that's like a skull in the final level and then another skull appears.
Speaker 0: it's the real final level.
Speaker 0: it's like oh my god think about that.
Speaker 1: that's kind of a cliche in a lot of games today.
Speaker 1: you know the square boss of the sort of first you beat the boss and then there's another but back then that shit didn't happen.
Speaker 0: no it didn't happen.
Speaker 1: I mean half it.
Speaker 1: I'm as a kid when that happened when I saw that I remember like I dropped the controller I started yelling for my brother and he comes and I'm like he's like what what I'm like?
Speaker 1: look he's like what I'm like.
Speaker 0: there's there's another level there's another skull or Megaman 3. right you beat all the robot masters and then these four new levels appear and each level has two of these clone robot thingies that actually take the place of robot masters from Megaman 2. so it's like you're playing Megaman 3 and all of a sudden Bubble Man shows up and you're like oh fuck oh fuck it's Bubble Man.
Speaker 1: oh my god I know how dangerous that bubble is.
Speaker 0: well you know Bubble Man is not too hard.
Speaker 0: but seeing Bubble Man in Megaman 3 is like oh shit and it had a lot of those oh shits that other games really didn't have.
Speaker 0: I mean you didn't play Castlevania 4 and say oh shit there's something for Castlevania 1. you didn't even play like you know SNES Zelda and say oh shit it's Digdogger.
Speaker 0: oh shit because Digdogger wasn't in there it didn't.
Speaker 0: it didn't have.
Speaker 0: that you know.
Speaker 0: bring it back action that Megaman had.
Speaker 1: My fondest memories are actually from Megaman 3 partly because I rented it and I wanted to buy it.
Speaker 1: my parents wouldn't buy it for me.
Speaker 0: I had Megaman 3. only ones I owned were actually 2 and 3.
Speaker 0: I played 4, 5 and 6 emulated.
Speaker 0: I played one emulated but now I have actually all of them on that Game Boy disc GameCube disc.
Speaker 0: I actually have the other GameCube disc that has all the Megaman X's so I have every Megaman.
Speaker 1: So this kid in my neighborhood decided that he didn't want Megaman 3 anymore so he wondered if I wanted to trade him a game for him.
Speaker 0: What were you gonna trade him?
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: Find a stick?
Speaker 1: I traded him.
Speaker 1: I'm one thing led to another and I traded him.
Speaker 1: hide lied.
Speaker 0: Oh hide lied.
Speaker 0: the game that's great on paper bad in reality.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you.
Speaker 1: the long story short is that his mom came over and we ended up being forced to give Megaman 3 back.
Speaker 1: Which was fine.
Speaker 1: cuz it turned out he'd actually stolen Megaman 3 from some other kid.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Megaman 3 actually had this bug in it.
Speaker 1: Oh it had an awesome bug.
Speaker 0: The second player could hold button downs in their controller.
Speaker 0: I think you hold left.
Speaker 0: You had to hold something.
Speaker 0: select I don't remember.
Speaker 1: No it was left.
Speaker 1: and then what would happen is if you fell into a pit.
Speaker 1: you would you know you died but not immediately.
Speaker 0: Well you died.
Speaker 0: it went doo doo doo but you weren't dead.
Speaker 1: No no in the game code you didn't die immediately like it did the doo doo doo but the game code for and the level start over didn't kick in right away.
Speaker 0: Right you had zero health and you were dead but you were still alive.
Speaker 0: you could walk around.
Speaker 0: you could also jump stupidly high for some reason.
Speaker 1: Well no no there was a lot more complicated than that.
Speaker 1: so one if you jump in like you're holding it and you jump into the pit you don't even go doo doo doo.
Speaker 1: you just can stand in there and kind of jump back out but then if you let go you die.
Speaker 1: and if you get the timing right where you die and you have no life but then you jump out the music stops.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Everything gets all weird and then as long as left's being held down you can jump super high but you can't shoot.
Speaker 1: so usually you wanted to go.
Speaker 0: I thought you could shoot.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: No no you couldn't.
Speaker 1: so usually if you wanted to play around with this you had to go beat needle man first.
Speaker 1: that way you could use his needle gun and basically like your normal weapon.
Speaker 1: so you could still go around and break through things and do all your stuff.
Speaker 0: I used that a few times you know playing around mostly with friends but I haven't done it in so long.
Speaker 1: See I played the game legitimately a lot of the time but I use that bug a lot just to explore.
Speaker 1: you could do some weird shit.
Speaker 0: You could especially in some of those levels that had the Mega Man 2 bosses in them because they were like.
Speaker 0: there's a huge part where it was just big empty tracks of space.
Speaker 0: Mega Man 3 actually added Rush the dog which people thought was a big deal and they were all crazy about it.
Speaker 0: but I was like what's the difference?
Speaker 0: Mega Man 2 had the 1, 2, 3 items and Rush is no different than the 1, 2, 3 items.
Speaker 0: it just looks like a dog.
Speaker 0: it doesn't make it any different.
Speaker 0: Proto Man's also the fucking bomb.
Speaker 0: That's something else.
Speaker 0: Mega Man 3 the added Proto Man.
Speaker 0: I mean you're going through a game normal as everything and then suddenly this is weird whistling music and this guy shows up and you shoot him and he goes away and he doesn't die and he just comes back every once in a while.
Speaker 0: and it's super mysterious.
Speaker 0: I love mysterious people.
Speaker 0: don't put mysterious unexplained shit in games like that anymore.
Speaker 0: it's always sort of obvious and transparent and it doesn't really evoke that feeling of curiosity or mysteriousness.
Speaker 1: Or it's Kojima.
Speaker 0: Or it's Kojima.
Speaker 0: One time I was playing Mega Man 2 and there was a babysitter over.
Speaker 0: I was that young right and I was fighting Bubble Man and I jump up and I actually the.
Speaker 0: you know there's the doors that go to the boss rooms.
Speaker 0: the door opened and I left the boss room.
Speaker 0: it went tick tick tick tick tick.
Speaker 1: it's always scary when that happens and I was like weird like that.
Speaker 0: so I'm like oh shit oh shit oh shit.
Speaker 0: I thought I found some amazing secret right.
Speaker 0: so then I go back through back into the boss room.
Speaker 0: it goes tick tick tick tick tick.
Speaker 0: I'm in this boss room and it looks mostly like Bubble Man's boss room but it's not.
Speaker 0: there's like a ladder and there's some platforms but they're invisible but I can walk on them and I can sort of.
Speaker 0: I figured out the layout of the room by jumping around climbing the ladders trying to walk every which way and it's sort of like this symmetrical room with four platforms on each side and two ladders.
Speaker 0: and I just played around in his room for like an hour thinking I had found some like amazing hidden secret and I was like oh my god oh my god.
Speaker 1: we've said this.
Speaker 0: it was just a glitch in the system.
Speaker 1: yeah but back in the day just because of the nature of old games gamers like I mean nowadays if you're playing Metal Gear 4 and it glitches you just reboot you reset it because the game's broken and you want to keep playing but glitches.
Speaker 1: back then before they were demystified to the world and two gamers were kind of this mystery world.
Speaker 0: well look at Metroid 1.
Speaker 0: I mean come on.
Speaker 1: okay I spent more time exploring Metroid 1 for weird stuff than I ever did trying to beat it.
Speaker 1: that's probably why I never actually beat it.
Speaker 0: yeah I've beaten it but you know it's much more.
Speaker 0: Metroid 1 at least is more fun to go looking for.
Speaker 0: the hack super Metroid is for beating.
Speaker 0: yeah so is Metroid 2?
Speaker 1: Mega Man 2 is probably the best one so far though.
Speaker 0: yeah I think the other thing I would say about Mega Man 2 is that he just has this you know charm to the styling of it.
Speaker 0: I mean you know 20x dx.
Speaker 0: really good music wood man flash man.
Speaker 0: I mean this is how it's how you're not talking about Bob and George.
Speaker 0: well this is a terrible comic.
Speaker 0: can actually make you know some funny ones because Mega Man is such a great source material but they weren't that funny.
Speaker 0: flash man is funny a flash man joke.
Speaker 0: it's a flash man.
Speaker 0: we're in trench coat.
Speaker 0: I mean come on that's that's not it is obvious but it's still funny.
Speaker 1: see it would be funny if it was wood man and it's like who you're dressed up as he was like at a costume party let's say and wood man is dressed up as flash man because there's wood under.
Speaker 1: there are not reading Bob and George.
Speaker 0: terrible quick man and not satisfying ladies.
Speaker 1: oh yeah cuz that was a clever joke.
Speaker 1: where's the air man joke?
Speaker 1: where's the guts man?
Speaker 0: joke guts man.
Speaker 0: he's got guts it's not a joke it's man that's not man.
Speaker 1: you know what I got to say this talk about mystification.
Speaker 1: when I finally got a hold of Mega Man one like I. this was before game facts.
Speaker 1: I didn't even have an instruction book and no one none of my friends owned it.
Speaker 1: so I remember I'm playing it and I kept seeing guts man and I knew from other Mega Man's.
Speaker 1: you know well all the one other Mega Man from Mega Man - all right when you beat a robot master you get his power.
Speaker 1: I couldn't for the life of me imagine what guts man's power was.
Speaker 0: these throw rocks I guess something like that something like that.
Speaker 1: I was desperate I constantly tried but I sucked.
Speaker 1: so bad that game.
Speaker 1: I never even saw guts man.
Speaker 0: that's something about Mega Man one.
Speaker 0: actually it only has six robot masters whereas Mega Man - as eight and that's pretty much the limit they're so hard they're all.
Speaker 0: they're stupid hard and the levels that come after even harder like where you have to fight that yellow guy with the giant eyeball.
Speaker 0: oh is he hard?
Speaker 0: it's like the heart one of the hardest bosses ever.
Speaker 0: I mean you got to be cutting even if you have full weapons and full ammo and full health.
Speaker 0: that yellow guy who breaks into pieces is stupid hard even though it's basically just a memorization game.
Speaker 1: memorizing it's the first step.
Speaker 1: the second step is doing well.
Speaker 0: a lot of Mega Man games in general are memorization but you know what.
Speaker 0: it's not the kind of memorization in Ikaruga where you have to memorize the exact pattern to move.
Speaker 0: it's you memorize.
Speaker 0: you know it's pretty easy to memorize so they don't give you too much and you don't have to memorize like this per really precise thing.
Speaker 0: you just sort of had to remember in general like okay this screen has instant death lasers so I have to go to the bottom as quickly as possible and I can't go for that tempting e-tank over there.
Speaker 1: there's also a lot of you know all right there's a ton of different ways to get past any given normal enemy and there's like.
Speaker 1: there's the normal enemies and then the slightly bigger enemies.
Speaker 1: they all have different patterns and part of the game is how do I get by this guy without taking a bunch of damage like looking Heat Man's level right.
Speaker 0: there's a part in Heat Man's level.
Speaker 0: there's a gigantic pit and you can.
Speaker 0: there are blocks that appear and disappear and you can jump and be really good with your jumping to get across.
Speaker 0: or you can use the number two item and drain your number two energy to use this sort of jet to get across and it's totally up to you.
Speaker 0: but there are advantages and disadvantages to both.
Speaker 1: plus instead of being an instant death game with a life meter one of the things that was great was that you didn't have to do every part of a level or every part of a boss fight perfectly.
Speaker 1: there's this.
Speaker 1: the margin of error was big enough to keep the game really interesting and then it gave that extra danger of every now and then there was a sudden death thing and those things were real scary as a result.
Speaker 0: but yeah the music in Mega Man is probably some of the best music even in the even in some of the bad Mega Man games like the ending music to Mega Man 5. that's one of the best ending songs there is.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean Mega Man 5.
Speaker 0: I like it because of his proto madness but it's not really the best Mega Man game really at all.
Speaker 1: but two and three I think are definitely my favorite.
Speaker 0: two and three are definitely where it's at.
Speaker 0: that is the popular maybe not?
Speaker 0: well you know there's.
Speaker 0: that is the popular conception and it is not wrong.
Speaker 1: the problem is why can't 9 be on the DS?
Speaker 1: that's a good question cuz I play my ideas more than anything else.
Speaker 1: it's the perfect game for the DS.
Speaker 0: yeah I guess they just want to have it on the TV to make it you know just like the olden days which is fine.
Speaker 1: cuz I'm probably gonna play the hell out of it.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna play the hell out of it for sure.
Speaker 1: actually I have this terrible urge to play Mega Man 2 right now.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be playing it.
Speaker 0: let me just quickly go through some of the non regular Mega Man games.
Speaker 1: about Mega Man and base.
Speaker 0: that's sort of like Mega Man 10 ish kind of came after eight.
Speaker 0: it's not I know but it's not Mega Man X series.
Speaker 0: it's definitely the regular Mega Man series but it's a little bit different.
Speaker 0: you know it's not Mega Man 9 it's this is Mega Man 9 and about
Speaker 1: Mega Man the Wily Wars on the Sega Mega Drive the
Speaker 0: Sega Genesis Mega Man game is actually just Mega Man 1 2 & 3 on a single cartridge with updated graphics
Speaker 1: yep as well as the Wily Tower minigame.
Speaker 0: that's a bad game it's not?
Speaker 1: I can't be as bad as tingles tower fucking Broncos within the met.
Speaker 0: they were Mega Man games to the Game Boy.
Speaker 0: or you can actually get Mega Man 2 for the original Game Boy.
Speaker 0: but the way it worked is it was you played for robot masters then for others.
Speaker 0: instead if you can is that of being able to choose from all eight right away and the levels are very simplified and not quite as good as real Mega Man 2. but the Mega Man Game Boy games are good in their own right.
Speaker 1: but if you really want to play portable Mega Man wow they had a two three four and five on the Game Boy.
Speaker 0: I know you should get Mega Man zero and that series for the GBA which is very supposed to be very old-school.
Speaker 0: it's very super Nintendo II very really hard kind of Mega Man but me it's a little closer to a Mega Man X than a regular Mega Man.
Speaker 0: but I've heard good things about them.
Speaker 0: you then ever played them.
Speaker 0: Mega Man Legends is abomination.
Speaker 0: terrible 3d RPG for the PlayStation the n64 and such.
Speaker 0: avoid it at all costs.
Speaker 0: some people like it.
Speaker 0: they're all fool.
Speaker 1: wait is that the game?
Speaker 1: where it starts there's a fire and you have to put the fire out.
Speaker 0: and the thing that might be that game?
Speaker 0: because I remember way back it's a 3d Mega Man but it doesn't look like Mega Man.
Speaker 0: it looks like this weird stick blue guy and you have the camera behind Mega Man.
Speaker 1: yep yep way back I bought when the ps1 came out.
Speaker 1: I bought it not to play ps1 games.
Speaker 0: in fact it was fun to play DDR.
Speaker 0: yes but you had that.
Speaker 0: I remember you had that game.
Speaker 1: yes because it.
Speaker 1: basically I bought this ps1.
Speaker 1: I didn't own a single PlayStation game and I had no intention of ever owning a single.
Speaker 1: but we were at our IT.
Speaker 1: well I was at home.
Speaker 1: it was the summer after our freshman year.
Speaker 1: yeah so I bought it at K Mart because it was on sale for a hundred.
Speaker 0: working at Kmart.
Speaker 1: yeah I was working construction at the Kmart which was that was an interesting summer.
Speaker 1: let me tell you this is the intercom phone.
Speaker 1: huh you know knowing the intercom code at a Kmart and knowing that the intercom code is the same at every Kmart everywhere and knowing that nothing can be done to prevent you from doing something hilarious makes for a really fun summer you sure does.
Speaker 1: but anyway.
Speaker 1: so I bought this thing and I bought it solely to put up six pin mod chip in it so I could play import DDR games.
Speaker 1: so uh I realized alright I've got this ps1 does it work?
Speaker 1: and then my follow-on was now that I put the mod chip in it does it still work?
Speaker 1: so what I did is I went on winmx and I just looked for any ISO of ps1 game and I found Megaman something I'm like alright fine I download it I put it in.
Speaker 1: that was like the worst game I've ever touched it's not.
Speaker 0: no maybe you never touch some of the worst ones but it's a really bad game.
Speaker 0: I played it.
Speaker 0: actually I had a friend who had a PlayStation one with the mod chip in the early days way back like we're talking my dad he was like this is what you spent two hours soldering for.
Speaker 1: this looks like shit.
Speaker 0: this is.
Speaker 1: and I was like don't worry this wasn't what I bought this for.
Speaker 1: I bought it for a stupid dancing game the junior high school.
Speaker 0: he would go to blockbuster Brent PlayStation games.
Speaker 0: copy them to CD.
Speaker 0: ours never turned them.
Speaker 0: that's how I played Megaman legends.
Speaker 1: that's actually how I got all my DDR games when I found out that importing a DDR game was like 80 bucks.
Speaker 1: so I signed up for our red octane.
Speaker 0: red octane was still a game rental service.
Speaker 1: octane was just Netflix for games.
Speaker 1: so basically I put in my queue every single mix of DDR ever released in Japan for the ps1 the every every week.
Speaker 1: one would come I'd rip it and mail it back the same day and then I had all of them.
Speaker 0: yep but I see there's also Megaman battle network which is sort of like this weird RPG ish game they got going on.
Speaker 0: that is doesn't that really have much to do with Megaman except it's sort of like as much to do with the Megaman.
Speaker 1: Megaman one was released on the IBM PC in 1990.
Speaker 1: Megaman 3 was released on the IBM PC in 1991.
Speaker 0: how about that?
Speaker 1: yeah because I had this memory like I said earlier and I just couldn't.
Speaker 1: I was thinking about it and I couldn't fathom where it came from.
Speaker 0: Megaman X was on there too.
Speaker 1: I had it yeah and Rockman strategy but only in China yeah.
Speaker 0: so people don't realize this.
Speaker 0: I guess that you know.
Speaker 0: you might know that in Japan Megaman is actually Rockman but I mean it's Rockman.
Speaker 0: his sister role proto man's name is is what I think it's actually still proto man.
Speaker 0: I forget.
Speaker 0: I don't know I forget but yeah it's like everyone.
Speaker 0: it's like rock roll bass treble it's like this whole music.
Speaker 0: you know theme going on and people don't seem to get that.
Speaker 0: you know this sort of like a joke.
Speaker 0: there's all these Japanese puns in Megaman and sort of like.
Speaker 0: we try we sort of get a dynamic.
Speaker 0: what's it called dynamic?
Speaker 0: equivalents going on with with the with the heat man and such like that where it's still the same sort of joke.
Speaker 0: everyone is called man but those are their their names.
Speaker 0: they also people don't remember that.
Speaker 0: I think Megaman 4 was.
Speaker 0: you know people voted on what the robot masters.
Speaker 0: was it a man or five?
Speaker 1: because I remember that contest in Nintendo power and I was so excited about it and I was like oh man I'm gonna win this.
Speaker 1: I forget what I submitted but I submitted something.
Speaker 0: really see things.
Speaker 0: I don't know how that worked right because wouldn't the Japanese decide what was the robot messages were gonna be?
Speaker 1: I didn't know either.
Speaker 1: all I know is Nintendo power showed the a bunch of submissions and they were the dumbest things.
Speaker 0: oh my god.
Speaker 0: well what kind of submissions did you see?
Speaker 1: I don't even remember.
Speaker 1: I just really in.
Speaker 0: the game was pretty bad.
Speaker 0: I mean tomahawk man.
Speaker 0: oh man.
Speaker 1: I'm just looking at Megaman 4 and Megaman 4 has a scary cover in America.
Speaker 1: I guess I never saw that's.
Speaker 0: the other thing is that look at the cover of say Megaman 2 is really it frightened me as a kid and I was like that's not what Megaman looks like.
Speaker 0: what's up with this is freaky but it's sort of freaky in this way where you can't look away.
Speaker 0: Megaman 1 is even scarier.
Speaker 0: look at the shit.
Speaker 1: Megaman 5 looks okay for Megaman 4.
Speaker 0: go look at the box art of Megaman 1 and Megaman 2 in the United States.
Speaker 0: good guy.
Speaker 1: hey compared to Megaman 4 I don't know.
Speaker 1: cuz I can deal with Megaman 1 which I'm looking at right now.
Speaker 1: he's holding that gun really weird and I don't like his biceps one.
Speaker 0: it totally looks like a Logan runs or Tron kind of thing.
Speaker 1: Logan's run Logan.
Speaker 1: Logan didn't run.
Speaker 0: more than that kind of styling of you know 70s 80s sci-fi movie cover.
Speaker 0: but Megaman 2 is even weird.
Speaker 1: it's pretty much every Megaman cover up until 5 in America looks stupid and weird.
Speaker 0: Oh Megaman 3 looked okay yeah but anyway I guess we could talk about Megaman all.
Speaker 1: no look at his face.
Speaker 1: look at Megaman's face.
Speaker 1: that is not cool.
Speaker 0: anyway that's fine.
Speaker 0: Megaman 3 is alright.
Speaker 0: no yeah it is.
Speaker 0: but anyway yeah there's.
Speaker 0: I don't know what else you can say about Megaman.
Speaker 0: what's your?
Speaker 0: what's your favorite robot master?
Speaker 1: I would have to be a quick man.
Speaker 0: you think quick man's your baby.
Speaker 1: he was the coolest.
Speaker 1: he looked the coolest level the best weapon.
Speaker 0: the coolest might be Gemini or magnet man.
Speaker 1: Gemini man at the best music but I actually do.
Speaker 0: my favorite level would probably be like the music you were just singing there I think with shadow man.
Speaker 1: I thought that was Gemini man.
Speaker 0: I don't remember his Gemini man.
Speaker 0: I might be.
Speaker 1: I'll bet you a dollar.
Speaker 0: maybe what was shadow man?
Speaker 0: that I forget.
Speaker 0: but yeah it's really tough.
Speaker 0: I like bubble man.
Speaker 0: he's way cool.
Speaker 0: his levels way cool.
Speaker 0: especially crash man.
Speaker 0: I love.
Speaker 0: he has two drills.
Speaker 0: that's pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: I love crash man's weapon even though it's not really that useful except for getting through things.
Speaker 0: yeah well it was a boss or two.
Speaker 1: yeah but it was so cool to use cuz it stuck to stuff.
Speaker 0: yeah it was really good.
Speaker 0: the two drills I mean hi girls oh yeah Oh Megaman send your Megaman comments into to us.
Speaker 0: people have been joining the forums lately so I just want to remind you if you have hot mail or whatever you might not when you join the forums you might not get an email that says can most people when you join the forums but be an email that says congratulations you've joined the forums.
Speaker 0: if you have hotmail you might not get that email.
Speaker 0: but if you did not get the email still pretend you got the email and just come sign into the forums.
Speaker 1: yes it is very rare that we deny anyone.
Speaker 0: yeah I've been denying someone lately.
Speaker 0: they've been trying to use bug me not to register.
Speaker 0: I've been denying that.
Speaker 1: yeah and before we end I will point this out again because we don't have.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: we're doing this sabbatical schedule for a while but at pecs the penny arcade expo in Seattle over Labor Day weekend we're going to be there.
Speaker 1: we're going to be VIPs.
Speaker 1: we're doing a panel entitled beyond dungeons and dragons.
Speaker 0: we're going to be talking about the burning wheel the inspectors the primetime adventures all the indie RPG scene that most people do not respect or pay attention to.
Speaker 0: we're gonna be letting loose.
Speaker 1: this is going to be I think one hell of a panel.
Speaker 0: so I hope so.
Speaker 0: and also to all you west coasters you're finally gonna get to meet us plus several people live in say San Diego but you're going to a convention right now.
Speaker 0: so what are you worried?
Speaker 1: yeah but at the same time also I'll point out that Scott and I are actually going to be in town for the entire day pretty much on Monday after the con yep.
Speaker 0: so if anyone is cool and you want to meet us I thought we were going to be there all day Thursday but we're not because you know the way the plane tickets worked out but we'll be there pretty much Labor Day in Seattle for us.
Speaker 0: so anyone wants to hang out Labor Day in Seattle?
Speaker 1: yeah we'll figure that out depending on how many of you respond.
Speaker 1: what we're going to do?
Speaker 0: yeah we can go to maybe some geeky stores buy some Space Needles food that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: but Saturday August 30th from 6 p.m.
Speaker 1: to 7 p.m.
Speaker 1: in the satellite theater room 307. hmm and I want to say this is a real good panel.
Speaker 1: you don't want to miss it.
Speaker 0: also was I gonna say right on Connecticut two weeks from now in Hartford Connecticut.
Speaker 1: that's hard for Connecticut over the first weekend in August.
Speaker 1: so the first second and third yes we're gonna be there.
Speaker 0: we're mostly gonna be doing mad panels on Saturday but Friday and maybe Sun and well Sunday maybe Friday we're gonna be doing mad gaming.
Speaker 0: we're actually gonna have other associates of ours doing gaming in the awesome awesome gaming rooms there.
Speaker 1: so even if you don't like anime or anime cons or webcomics or any of that come to Connecticut.
Speaker 1: they have better gaming than most gaming cons.
Speaker 0: yeah the people who run the game room they're real great.
Speaker 0: there's a great selection of games.
Speaker 0: you could bring your own games and just we're gonna be running demos.
Speaker 0: we're gonna be teaching people how to play games that they might not know how to play.
Speaker 1: just come on by to the geek nights tables.
Speaker 1: you won't be able to miss them.
Speaker 1: there'll be at least one gigantic banner there yep and it'll be awesome times.
Speaker 1: this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays we have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: you can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.