Speaker 1: It's Tuesday March 25th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm sky and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 1: We're all Let's do this You know today.
Speaker 1: It was one of those days where ended up taking a different train home The same train I say possibly.
Speaker 1: I took a somewhat later train.
Speaker 1: the funny thing is I take the 410 home usually and if I Miss that because I stay late at work and a lot of times It'll be like 358 and then suddenly someone will be like hey.
Speaker 1: Can you do this real quick, and I'm like.
Speaker 0: That's why I always leave work with like a buffer time.
Speaker 0: that way if someone asked me to do something I you know if it takes me ten minutes.
Speaker 0: I can still make it, but I work seven.
Speaker 1: tough for Can't leave early really yeah, but I get like an hour plus lunch, so it works out, but son It's like I got to do this, and it wasn't even like it was crap work.
Speaker 1: There's actually something I wanted to do.
Speaker 1: it just came at a somewhat inopportune time So I did it and I stayed late, and it's like it.
Speaker 1: once it hits like 404 I pretty much have to get up and go or I'm not gonna make the train.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm Man, it's so great though that I can walk to the train in like five minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I gotta take a little subway to the tree.
Speaker 1: It's not even like five minutes from leaving work.
Speaker 1: It's five minutes from when I log out of my computer.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: You work across the street from the train station.
Speaker 1: The best thing ever.
Speaker 1: yeah, well, I think the best thing ever would be working from home, but I can do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess I technically could but you know I wouldn't.
Speaker 1: if I could if I was gonna work from home I wouldn't want to work from home more than like a day or two a week, or I'd probably go crazy.
Speaker 0: No, I could work from home every day because I just wouldn't be sitting in front of the computer all day like I am at Work.
Speaker 0: I would be.
Speaker 0: you know I do work.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it's more that by going like I like going into the city And I don't mind my train ride or anything it just be nice to like every other Friday Be able to wake up at 659 to be at work at 7.
Speaker 1: Yeah Of course I used to do that at IBM.
Speaker 1: I'd wake up at like Show up to work unshaven and flannel.
Speaker 0: yeah Yeah, anyway.
Speaker 1: So I had to take this late train home And it pretty much.
Speaker 1: if I miss the 410 the next one is the 445. the 445 gets home 15 minutes before the 509.
Speaker 1: The 509 because the 509 is like the most ultra express.
Speaker 1: it pretty much goes Grand Central Harlem beacon.
Speaker 0: yeah, that's does it even do.
Speaker 0: Harlem Because the the one after the 509 the 528 goes Grand Central Beacon.
Speaker 1: I've taken that train a couple times.
Speaker 1: That's a real nice train, but it's at 528.
Speaker 0: So the 509 is much is better still.
Speaker 1: the 509 is like the best train You can take if you work it into your schedule.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I ended up taking the 509 because I don't want to take the 445. the 509 gets me there at about the same time and I have more time to dick around in the city in less time On a train.
Speaker 0: yeah, I'll take the 445 if I can get on it because it's still get home 15 minutes earlier.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah But I decide it's also easier to get out of the parking lot on the 445 because there's less beacon people on it because there's people for the other stuff.
Speaker 1: That's true, but anyway, so I get on the train.
Speaker 1: I'm walking like all right got to find a seat.
Speaker 1: this trains always ultra crowded and there's Scott.
Speaker 0: So
Speaker 1: I walk up and I say something to him and I this I can't say like haha Scott because the same thing happens To me ever be like a situation where you do not expect anyone to speak to you at all Because there's no chance of anyone, you know being around there's no chance of anyone like interacting with you.
Speaker 1: you're just sitting there in a foreign place doing something and suddenly someone like says something to you and you're Yeah, Scott went up and I went haha.
Speaker 1: then I sat down next to him.
Speaker 0: I went after.
Speaker 0: you went haha loudly.
Speaker 1: I was like, hey, he goes huh?
Speaker 0: No, you're like.
Speaker 0: you were like, haha.
Speaker 0: Suddenly, it wasn't that loud like the haha guy.
Speaker 1: No, I don't believe I went ha ha.
Speaker 0: No, not Nelson the haha guy.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's more of a haha You're all.
Speaker 0: you're almost like that.
Speaker 1: I don't think I was.
Speaker 0: they were.
Speaker 1: I think you were just too Used to the quiet train in my very quiet utterance of huh?
Speaker 1: No, I think it jumped you.
Speaker 0: you had a loud, haha I don't think so.
Speaker 1: But anyway anyway, so because I took this train it's like alright.
Speaker 1: What am I gonna do in the city?
Speaker 1: I want to get something accomplished.
Speaker 1: I don't want to just like go down and eat a bunch of samosa and then get like a coffee or a corona or something.
Speaker 1: So I go over to the H&M and I find out that linen suits are on sale and hot damn.
Speaker 1: Do I like linen?
Speaker 1: Of all the things you can make a shirt out of number one is silk.
Speaker 1: Silk is like the best thing ever, but number two is linen.
Speaker 1: I'll wear linen any time any place any day and I got these two awesome linen blazers for like 40 bucks.
Speaker 0: What do you need them for to wear?
Speaker 0: Why don't you have clothes?
Speaker 1: not enough?
Speaker 0: How do you not have enough clothes?
Speaker 1: I only own like three blazers.
Speaker 1: I needed a couple different.
Speaker 0: I own one and I never use it.
Speaker 1: I Work at a place where I have to wear blazers like often I have to dress up.
Speaker 1: I gotta look nice.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't work at such a place.
Speaker 1: I prefer to work at such a place.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like one thing that bothered me about you prefer to spend money on useless clothing.
Speaker 1: I don't know but I think I look good in a blazer and I like to wear that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: You care about what you look like when you're sitting in an office where no one cares Everyone cares and everyone's very stylish in my office.
Speaker 1: Actually, except for they're all you're all vain Assholes, no, we're just very vain.
Speaker 1: I said vain Yes, but you added something to that.
Speaker 1: I'm all about vain.
Speaker 1: Vanity is a virtue not a sin.
Speaker 0: No, it's not a sin because no such thing as a sin, but vanity is a waste of time and resources.
Speaker 0: I I would wear pajamas.
Speaker 0: All right, everyone in my work would wear pajamas.
Speaker 0: Anybody didn't wear pajamas.
Speaker 0: I'd be like, are you going somewhere special today?
Speaker 0: Is there like a wedding or something?
Speaker 0: What's going on?
Speaker 1: Well part of it too is that I realized that I dress really nice for work and when I go out But then on the weekends when like all my friends are over I'm doing stuff around town I dress basically like a hobo.
Speaker 0: I would add the world would be best if I dressed like a hobo all the time.
Speaker 1: There's one time Scott and I went to a restaurant in town and I Think they balked at serving us at first because it looked like some punk kid and a hobo Watered into this nice restaurant like off the street.
Speaker 0: Why I always wear the cheapest clothes that are comfortable and keep warm.
Speaker 0: that is the requirements.
Speaker 0: comfort number one Keeping warm.
Speaker 0: number two Comfort cheap is number three.
Speaker 1: comfort is number one.
Speaker 1: But number two is looking good.
Speaker 0: looking good is not even on the list.
Speaker 0: the clothes could be like, all right Perlin in like live.
Speaker 1: let's have a comparison here.
Speaker 1: How many times has a girl and any point in your life said to you?
Speaker 1: Hey, you look sexy in that Zero because I don't care.
Speaker 1: Ah I'm pointing out a correlation.
Speaker 0: Yeah a correlation.
Speaker 0: where the correlation is you care.
Speaker 0: I don't okay.
Speaker 1: Anyway to all of you out there a lot of people don't really look at what their clothes are made out of and I It kind of matters.
Speaker 1: for example a shirt that's made out of 99% polyester is not a good shirt.
Speaker 1: It is not going to be comfortable or look good.
Speaker 0: What are you talking about?
Speaker 0: This goes awesome.
Speaker 1: This goes awesome.
Speaker 1: Polyester makes you smell.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you just don't wear it too long.
Speaker 1: No, you gotta wear an undershirt under it or you will say Your.
Speaker 1: but I gotta tell you linen is such an underused Fabric for clothing and I'm all about barely
Speaker 0: not because you were able to get a whole bunch of it
Speaker 1: Yes, but not many people wear linen compared to how many people wear like rayon and stuff or like rayon linen mixtures This I'm
Speaker 0: pretty sure.
Speaker 0: the cotton is like the number one most worn and cotton is crap except for underwear.
Speaker 0: cotton is awesome for everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I likes me some wool too, but not as much as linen.
Speaker 0: Seinfeld it's gonna learn you something.
Speaker 0: gabardine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no No, you know what?
Speaker 1: I learned from Seinfeld velour.
Speaker 0: No Episode where that he gets the Yankees to work on no, and then then it fails Catastrophically, it's the worst thing.
Speaker 0: that's good.
Speaker 0: Someone does not use the washing machine privately.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, that's cuz it rained.
Speaker 0: That you know, it doesn't happen to me Cuz you don't do anything outside.
Speaker 1: You're like a witch anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so what do you got in the news?
Speaker 0: Alright, so there's sort of like this big combo news.
Speaker 0: Do we even tie?
Speaker 0: I feel like part of its old and part of its new.
Speaker 1: Basically part of it's something.
Speaker 1: part of its blue.
Speaker 0: There's the rock band right and the rock band is so it has a licensing deal with fenders.
Speaker 0: So all the guitars in rock band are like Stratocaster isn't telecasters and whatnot?
Speaker 1: I don't remember if it was a Stratocaster or a telecast.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not hard to tell the difference wasn't?
Speaker 1: the Stratocaster has sort of like this like Combination of the perfect car.
Speaker 0: the telecaster doesn't have that Top from which to strike.
Speaker 1: it's sort of stubbier and I once killed a man with an electric guitar.
Speaker 0: It's like for your pickups in the restraint line, but the Stratocaster sort of angle anyway, the And the guitar heroes ever since Guitar Hero 1 has a licensing deal with Gibson's.
Speaker 0: They have the Gibson guitars like the Les Paul.
Speaker 1: and so I point out that the only reason that Gibson is inferior in my eyes Because I don't know enough about guitars to know or care and I don't even think I can tell the difference if I listen to.
Speaker 1: but Meatloaf talked a lot about one of the two and did not talk a lot about the other of the two.
Speaker 1: and I base all Of my guitar knowledge on meatloaf.
Speaker 0: I based it on.
Speaker 0: I like the way the shape of a Stratocaster better than I like the shape of the other guitars.
Speaker 0: about the Telecaster, I know it's kind of kind of stubby.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it kind of is.
Speaker 0: Yeah anyway So that's the way it's been.
Speaker 0: but basically the story that's in the news is Gibson suing pretty much every maker of toy guitars and guitar heroes and rock bands for patent infringement, but I'm saying the real story has something to do with a. they got into a fight with the Guitar hero people about the licensing somehow because I think you're not gonna see Gibson licensing on the next guitar hero.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling
Speaker 1: I mean this might be reminiscent of what happened way back with Final Fantasy and Nintendo Where I mean there were a lot of reasons for Final Fantasy being pulled from Nintendo and put on other platforms, but Independent of those there was a personal falling out between the two companies.
Speaker 0: Yes, I think you know, it's sort of like Gibson.
Speaker 0: You know this patent or whatever bullshit.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure the patent argument they're making is bullshit.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna fly and everyone's just gonna laugh them away.
Speaker 1: Well, remember anytime a crazy patent thing like this comes up.
Speaker 1: There are only two but well, there's three But really there's only two possible and likely outcomes either the patent is found to be crap proving once again, the patents are like this or crap or The patent is enforced which makes everyone angry.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's win-win.
Speaker 0: so Basically Gibson I think is pissed off at the guitar hero people for screwing them on the licensing deal or something.
Speaker 0: They weren't happy and now they're basically taking their patent and they still want to make money because you know Fender and the other company is doing just fine And so they're gonna go stomp it all over everybody and I think really because of guitar hero and rock band and such Mostly because a guitar hero.
Speaker 0: suddenly these, you know guitar making companies which has just been sitting around quietly for years and years You know producing their guitars are suddenly like making a lot more money than they're used to and now they're starting to get crazy.
Speaker 0: But they're mostly their business is making guitars.
Speaker 0: They don't know what the hell they're doing.
Speaker 1: I don't think I need to point out the absolute hilarity and irony of the fact that the guitar Industry is getting boosted by fake guitars and people pretending to play the guitar.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, well, you know.
Speaker 0: and the one hand it does boost it in that You know people play the fake guitar and it generates interest in playing the real guitar.
Speaker 0: Then they find out and then they go to buy a real guitar and they're probably gonna buy You know one of the ones that they like looking at.
Speaker 1: if you thought that fourth and fifth Quote-unquote colored fret was giving you trouble.
Speaker 1: Wait till you try to play a real guitar kids.
Speaker 0: Well, some of the stuff in guitar here on the super hard modes is harder than some stuff on a real guitar harder But not analogous.
Speaker 0: No, not analogous at all.
Speaker 0: anyway The combination news with that.
Speaker 0: It's sort of that's a newer news that you probably may have not heard that Is that the rock band is coming to the Wii, right?
Speaker 0: So the rock band was only on the other systems But now it's gonna be on the Wii.
Speaker 1: now We've been holding out on a lot of this stuff because what console is gonna have it all?
Speaker 1: I don't want to buy an Xbox And blah and find out the blind.
Speaker 1: then everything's coming out on the Wii that I care about.
Speaker 0: So yep, so it's alright.
Speaker 0: So the thing is is that the guitar hero guitar the one that we already have is not gonna work With the rock band on the Wii.
Speaker 1: now, I don't think I need to say that that's bullshit.
Speaker 1: So I think instead is that we're so not buying that second guitar hero guitar now.
Speaker 0: No, there's no way we're buying a second guitar hero guitar.
Speaker 1: In fact, does anyone want to buy a guitar hero from us?
Speaker 1: Hey, I bought it.
Speaker 1: You never paid me back.
Speaker 0: I guess but I mailed away to get the replacement disc.
Speaker 1: Yeah, doesn't matter I'm so done with guitar hero.
Speaker 1: Like I just I know I said, oh, I'm gonna get good at this You know what?
Speaker 1: I take that back.
Speaker 1: I don't think I'm ever gonna play that game again.
Speaker 0: Well, I did I got good at it.
Speaker 0: But the thing is the hardest part of guitar hero 3 when it gets to like expert mode is so hard It's just not worth it.
Speaker 0: Like I play play guitar hero 3 to the point where I probably could beat guitar hero 2 which is much easier.
Speaker 0: an expert I'm pretty sure I could beat all of rock band an expert at least with the guitar instrument.
Speaker 0: But there's no way it's worth it to beat the harder parts of guitar hero 3 I guess and I really don't care about unlocking characters and such a lot unlocked all the songs.
Speaker 0: That's enough.
Speaker 1: I just feel like rock band in terms of enjoy cuz think about it The only time even though I never played rock band.
Speaker 1: I played it a couple times.
Speaker 1: I can say this in our crew I don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean I see a lot of crews this way because we've gone to parties where there were a lot of Non front row crew people there and it's always the same thing.
Speaker 1: a lot of people have guitar hero, but they don't play it that much and People who own guitar hero either become super good at it and play it all the time or almost never play it.
Speaker 1: But then when there's a party and there's too many people to work for everyone at the party to engage everyone at the same time You know when there's like just way too many people for you all to like watch a movie or play a game at once Then they'll have like guitar hero on in the living room and they'll be like five or six people Kind of alternating and playing it at any one time.
Speaker 1: It kind of keeps the dynamic of a party going and it's really this kind of party in game.
Speaker 1: But it can have it most.
Speaker 1: two people.
Speaker 1: rock band not only has four people It has four wildly different roles and these well not wildly different.
Speaker 0: there's two guitar rolls.
Speaker 0: Well, so it's the same game only added draw added one drum and one microphone which is a lot.
Speaker 0: It's a lot.
Speaker 0: but I actually I think a problem of rock band is that pretty much everyone just wants to play the drum.
Speaker 0: No one wants to.
Speaker 1: actually I see too because a lot of people say they never want to play the drum because unlike the other Ones it's actually a little bit difficult because it's kind of like a real instrument.
Speaker 1: But in terms of it also has this kind of spectator enjoyment?
Speaker 1: watching someone play guitar hero is not entertaining at all.
Speaker 1: Watching someone play rock band is often entertaining.
Speaker 0: Well only mostly for the singing part.
Speaker 0: if someone can sing it's sort of it the same as watching someone do carrier.
Speaker 1: Oh listening to someone do karaoke But I'm saying it adds that element.
Speaker 1: and as a cruise hanging out party game in the background rock band is much better than guitar.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I think the thing is is the people who make the rock band basically blamed the guitar hero people saying it's their fault For not for making it not work.
Speaker 0: and I'm like, uh, wait a minute.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, that's not gonna fly with me.
Speaker 0: You know sure that you know, maybe they made the guitar hero guitar in a shitty way, which I'll believe.
Speaker 0: Oh, they did I'll easily believe.
Speaker 1: but we pointed out that the way the guitar hero guitar works on the Wii is Broken.
Speaker 1: it is straight-up broken.
Speaker 0: Yep, but the rock band people came to the Wii Second.
Speaker 0: therefore there is no reason that they could not have made the rock band guitar Compatible guitar.
Speaker 1: they might have tried and said wow, it doesn't work the way it should.
Speaker 1: it's broken.
Speaker 0: screw this guitar hero.
Speaker 0: They made it work.
Speaker 0: You know, it's not only even so I'd rat it's it.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like that issue.
Speaker 0: Are you gonna make it backwards compatible in this case?
Speaker 0: I think that making it backwards compatible would have been more valuable to the consumer than making it.
Speaker 0: You know, I basically now Think of all the guitar hero.
Speaker 0: guitar under the hood may work in a shitty way.
Speaker 1: It plays the game just fine, but now they're gonna get people to buy more of their guitars.
Speaker 1: Maybe no one's gonna say never mind on rock band.
Speaker 1: I have to buy a different guitar.
Speaker 1: I think if anything people are gonna say wow screw guitar hero.
Speaker 0: I think what it actually does is people who are not in the know, right?
Speaker 0: People aren't hardcore about it.
Speaker 0: They're probably not buying both guitar hero and rock band.
Speaker 0: That's not you know, but I Think that people who are in the know since they know that these things aren't compatible You're gonna see and you've already seen it already Is that people just buy the guitar heroes and the rock bands now on the 360 because of the downloadable?
Speaker 0: Content and because the guitar.
Speaker 0: it's the only system where all the guitars are compatible.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it also helps that most people who are into this sort of thing have a 360 I know but opposed to a ps3.
Speaker 0: but people who are into this thing They're specifically saying hi, it's time to buy rhythm games.
Speaker 0: Which system will I buy the rhythm games for?
Speaker 0: Oh that one?
Speaker 1: Yes, well the thing is if I already had an Xbox I would get it on the Xbox.
Speaker 1: The only reason I haven't is because I know I won't have time to play Xbox games anytime soon.
Speaker 1: So I'm not gonna get an Xbox so I'll play it on the Wii.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but actually the sudden funny happened today, you know, I have this Sony credit card that I got long ago.
Speaker 0: randomly I basically said I need a credit card.
Speaker 0: I went to a credit card website and there were like choices of cards and I was like Sony free gadgets.
Speaker 0: Whatever right that was before way before Sony was evil.
Speaker 0: You're like ps1 days for talking here.
Speaker 0: so I got that card and now I get like points and I can use the points to get Sony stuff.
Speaker 0: and if I Go to like the store and buy a Sony product like let's say I buy a hundred dollar Sony product, right?
Speaker 0: I can go to fill out a form and spend 10,000 points and then Sony will give me a refund on the you know.
Speaker 0: So it's.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: it's basically like one penny per point.
Speaker 0: But if I go to the Sony rewards catalog, which is a special catalog I can just buy things with points and if I don't have enough points, they'll just charge my credit card the extra money.
Speaker 0: The thing is if you actually calculate the you know, one penny per point in the you know rewards catalog.
Speaker 0: The rewards catalog is hideously overpriced.
Speaker 0: However, they there was a deal.
Speaker 0: I got in the email and the deal said Buy an HDTV on the list in the rewards catalog and we'll give you a free ps3.
Speaker 1: God, damn it.
Speaker 1: We're gonna get a ps3?
Speaker 1: No, we're not.
Speaker 0: why not?
Speaker 0: because I went and I looked at the HDTVs in the rewards.
Speaker 1: Can they cost exactly the price of an HDTV plus the cost of a 360 or a ps3?
Speaker 0: The cheapest one was two hundred thousand points, which is tooth wall.
Speaker 0: two hundred fifty thousand points, which is twenty five hundred dollars Minus the price of a ps3 $1,900.
Speaker 0: right that HDTV was like a $900 HDTV.
Speaker 0: Wow Yeah, the rewards catalog is the ultimate ripoff.
Speaker 1: Luckily when I got my credit card thing I want the Geico credit card because I used to drive to work a lot.
Speaker 1: So I got three percent off gas.
Speaker 0: That's a little bit of a help.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking I'm gonna get a second credit card that has a different kind of reward thing.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll get the Linux credit card.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the Geico one is good because all my car stuff gets like super discount.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is I don't have that much car stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I did and triple-a discounts on a lot of that.
Speaker 1: Even I don't have to play You know, I went.
Speaker 0: I bought new tires right at the all-season tires.
Speaker 0: I took off the snow tires.
Speaker 0: You know, my dad was like here.
Speaker 0: take my little triple-a card because there's a triple-a discount at the tire store, right?
Speaker 0: So I go over to the tire store and I'm like, yeah Isn't there a triple-a discount?
Speaker 0: the guys just like yup, and he just takes it off didn't ask to see my card or anything.
Speaker 0: You don't need the triple-a card.
Speaker 1: actually, actually, I don't know if they fixed this but as of a few years ago My triple-a actually expired last millennium.
Speaker 0: mine did.
Speaker 0: mine expired in like 2001.
Speaker 1: I kept the card though because when I'm an old man I can show young kids and be like this was my triple-a card and they'll see the dates and it'll say 1998 whoa, and they'll go.
Speaker 1: Wow old man Wow Yeah, but so I let it expire and a couple of years ago I needed some maps right and you could.
Speaker 1: I mean now it's not as much of a deal because now like MapQuest has awesome maps
Speaker 0: and Google Maps has also awesome as about two bad directions, but good maps
Speaker 1: Yeah, but back in the day like in the 90s and the early 2000s MapQuest directions were garbage Compared to the triple-a directions.
Speaker 1: if you wanted directions you went to triple-a and if you were a member they were free.
Speaker 1: In fact, someone would sit down with you draw the whole route.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you went to the triple-a store like they would get out a triptych They would print out a custom map for you and take a highlighter and highlight your whole route and they'd even warn you like There might be traffic here.
Speaker 1: If there is get off this exit.
Speaker 1: Here's the alternate route to avoid the traffic.
Speaker 1: if you want to avoid tolls go this way.
Speaker 1: There's a good place to eat right here here and here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we did.
Speaker 0: We got the triptych on when we drove to Florida a couple times.
Speaker 0: So basically you just drive turn the page drive turn the page.
Speaker 0: It's it's great.
Speaker 0: Actually.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but now we have GPS's.
Speaker 0: That's sort of dead.
Speaker 1: Well, then they started letting you get triptychs on the internet And what you had to do is put in your card number.
Speaker 1: I Discovered that the authentication does not check to see if your account is valid.
Speaker 1: It merely checks to see if your triple-a number matches the checksum that is integrated into your triple-a number Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Hence if you if you even know a triple-a number that is valid this might have changed.
Speaker 1: You can get triptychs completely forever for free.
Speaker 1: Yep, just so you know Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So anyway, I got some news here if you're done.
Speaker 0: So I'm done.
Speaker 1: Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles is dead to me in all incarnations.
Speaker 1: check out this BS.
Speaker 1: So first off.
Speaker 1: well I got to take that back a little bit.
Speaker 1: the GameCube Crystal Chronicles much like the GameCube Wario.
Speaker 1: Where was the only worthwhile game in the series?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and here's the.
Speaker 1: here's the issue.
Speaker 1: So they're gonna be two Crystal Chronicles games on the Wii really Just gonna be.
Speaker 0: one have confused them.
Speaker 1: there is Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles black Which is just my life as a king and that is the WiiWare one.
Speaker 1: that's already out in Japan and it'll be out Actually was released today in Japan.
Speaker 1: Whoa, and it'll be out in the u.s.
Speaker 1: In May.
Speaker 1: Okay, and it cost 1,500 Wii points.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Now then the real Crystal Chronicles game is going to be Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles not Ring of Fates.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at the wrong ring of Fates of the DS one.
Speaker 1: Yes Da da da my life is a king.
Speaker 1: and then Crystal Chronicles the Crystal Bearers.
Speaker 1: Here we go.
Speaker 0: Ah Crystal Bearers is the.
Speaker 0: so that's gonna be a real Wii game on a Wii disc.
Speaker 1: Yes Now which bullshit should I talk about first?
Speaker 0: Well, we can talk about how Ring of Fates we own it and it sucks.
Speaker 1: All right, here's the deal.
Speaker 1: We're gonna review Ring of Fates probably next week or the week after for the DS.
Speaker 1: But I'm gonna start by saying don't buy it.
Speaker 1: Good God.
Speaker 0: Good God do not buy it.
Speaker 0: I pre-ordered but we bought too too many copies.
Speaker 1: I pre-ordered two copies because we figured all right.
Speaker 1: We'll go for this because the first one was a good time and then later I pre-ordered a third copy But it was delayed because it was sold out.
Speaker 1: Our first pre-orders came and the third one was for Emily.
Speaker 1: We played about five minutes of it and I canceled that pre-order for Emily.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I gotta get rid of my copy.
Speaker 1: Do you guys want anyone out there want the Crystal Chronicles for the DS?
Speaker 0: It's sort of like it's.
Speaker 0: it's hard for us to take your money to give you something that's gonna hurt you.
Speaker 0: It's like it's like selling you poison with the word food written on it.
Speaker 0: but if you really want it, I guess that we can give it to somebody.
Speaker 1: but Just to let you know that game is crap and we're gonna talk about exactly in every detail why it is crap.
Speaker 1: Now the problem here is that they have done the same thing to the Crystal Chronicles Franchise that they have done to the Wario Ware franchise because the game that's coming out on the Wii Let me read here.
Speaker 1: I'll go down.
Speaker 1: I'm delaying because I got a bunch of windows open.
Speaker 1: I'm scrolling down here to a statement that was made in an interview about the Crystal Chronicles Crystal Bearers.
Speaker 1: for the Wii The Crystal Bearers is intended to be a more Single-player experience.
Speaker 1: quote, yeah as opposed to the GameCube install and installment which focused on cooperative play Players are expected to be able to use crafted items in multiplayer mode and items won in multiplayer within the single-player game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, new items and accessories are intended to be shown visually on the characters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's one thing.
Speaker 1: Oh The game director stated that he wanted a more world weary protagonist.
Speaker 1: He wanted him to seem rugged.
Speaker 1: They intended the game to have a more mature design Now in other words more like all the other regular Final Fantasies.
Speaker 1: So here's where I take issue with this.
Speaker 1: much like how Wario Ware came out on the GameCube Which was the best war like.
Speaker 1: that is one of the best games ever made.
Speaker 1: if you have friends over and you need to play A game together that is like the best freaking game.
Speaker 1: Yep, and Crystal Chronicles for the GameCube was not the best game in the world But what it was was a proof of concept of something amazing Like.
Speaker 1: what it was was something that could have become this whole new amazing Genre of gaming that would have completely revolutionized console.
Speaker 0: It was sort of taking the River City Ransom kind of thing to the next level and I think we've talked about this before.
Speaker 1: But the the only good part about Crystal Chronicles on the GameCube was the fact that it was multiplayer Completely and there basically was no single-player game worth talking about Much like how Wario Ware on the GameCube was a multiplayer game with no single-player gameplay worth talking about.
Speaker 1: Nintendo looked at both of these franchises and said well Obviously these games are popular due to their single-player content and no one cares about the multiplayer.
Speaker 1: Let's totally fuck the multiplayer and remake the games and focus on the single-player crap that no one likes.
Speaker 0: Well, I think you know.
Speaker 0: my guess on this is that you know, you gotta remember Nintendo is mostly focusing.
Speaker 0: You know, the games are made in Japan for Japanese people and we just sort of get the ports, you know.
Speaker 0: So if something's popular in Japan Nintendo makes it and then whether we get it is pretty much just a decision.
Speaker 0: whether Huh?
Speaker 0: Do you think Americans will like this or not?
Speaker 0: They're not making the games for us ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah They don't take us in.
Speaker 0: Nintendo doesn't take the United States market and our ideas into consideration in during the development process.
Speaker 1: Really there's also the problem that well aside from having to worry about Japanese sensibilities Nintendo is one of the most risk-averse companies to have ever existed.
Speaker 0: But you know these games are made by Square Enix.
Speaker 0: It's just pretty much the same exact situation and Square Enix is basically as far as they're concerned.
Speaker 0: It seems Final Fantasy is Final Fantasy and Crystal Chronicles is just Final Fantasy Nintendo version.
Speaker 0: So I guess Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles isn't going the way they wanted.
Speaker 0: So they just want to make it more like regular Final Fantasy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but even though the only Because the regular Final Fantasies do really well over in Japan and so did the Dragon Quest.
Speaker 0: So they want to make the Crystal Chronicles more like those.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is to me Crystal Chronicles used to mean OMG multiplayer co-op.
Speaker 1: now Crystal Chronicles means more Final Fantasy.
Speaker 1: So that's two new Crystal Chronicle games that are dead to me.
Speaker 1: What about the third one?
Speaker 1: this WiiWare game seems like a good idea.
Speaker 1: It has nothing to do with Final Fantasy or even barely Crystal Chronicles.
Speaker 1: It's basically as far as I can tell the good part of Actraiser.
Speaker 0: wait, but I like Actraiser.
Speaker 0: Ah, well, especially the good part.
Speaker 1: Well turns out there are a number of races in the game But you only get to play as one of them unless You buy the other races with Wii shop points.
Speaker 0: But doesn't it?
Speaker 0: well, it's a WiiWare game.
Speaker 0: So that's a pay we shop points for.
Speaker 1: in the first you have to pay for the game But then if you want extra clothes or special things or any of the other races you have to pay more Wii shop points.
Speaker 0: So how much how many points does the game cost?
Speaker 0: 1500 that's $15.
Speaker 0: All right How many points to the other races and things cause?
Speaker 1: they're going to cost 100 to 300 points to construct homes for them to start.
Speaker 0: So how many races are there total I think for so is it like a hundred points per race.
Speaker 0: like you start with one.
Speaker 0: There's four races you pay 300 to get the other three.
Speaker 0: I mean theoretically.
Speaker 1: All right, the cost isn't so bad.
Speaker 0: No, no, here's my is the question though, right?
Speaker 0: Basically, it's not the cost.
Speaker 0: That's a problem.
Speaker 0: The problem is the way they structure the cost.
Speaker 0: I mean think about this, right?
Speaker 0: It's basically gonna cost you $18 to get the game with all three races as far as I can tell, right?
Speaker 0: What if they just charge $20 flat for the game with all races?
Speaker 0: and didn't you know, like piecemeal it with the micro Transactions, I'm what.
Speaker 0: no one would complain.
Speaker 0: No one would complain and they would make more money there.
Speaker 1: This is why I don't think they'll make more money.
Speaker 1: I think this is gonna work really really well because I have very little faith in our fellow gamers.
Speaker 0: What do you know?
Speaker 1: No, look if they would have made the game to don't know cuz you're forgetting, you know You know that this is just the test and if people buy those races at all They're gonna sell everything you could imagine little hats little booties little things for these characters special.
Speaker 0: They're charging for other things just besides unlocking the race.
Speaker 1: I I have a feeling that the races are a test and if people will pay for the races Then they're going to sell you costumes and everything else in the world.
Speaker 1: I think that that basically they're getting their foot in the door on the idea of Getting people to buy a game and once they bought into that game Forcing them to buy in with cash as opposed to just with liking.
Speaker 0: It's really not cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but why?
Speaker 0: even I want to buy this game.
Speaker 0: Well, what kind of game is it?
Speaker 0: Well, it's a game where you buy stuff with real money and you get fake stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a great game.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean this isn't even like World of Warcraft or at least like you go out in the context of the game and you fight And you get it.
Speaker 1: That's like if in World of Warcraft you could go to the old shop and swipe your credit card.
Speaker 1: Well, you can.
Speaker 0: it's just it's sort of you know, not official.
Speaker 0: It's from Chinese.
Speaker 1: I'm saying this would be like if it was built into the game.
Speaker 1: What level D character do you want?
Speaker 1: It's five dollars per level swipe.
Speaker 0: Yeah Wow, I don't know.
Speaker 0: What's what's?
Speaker 0: even the point of playing that kind of game is basically it's really not a game at all.
Speaker 0: It's just a psychological trap to get people to give you pay money to change pictures on a screen.
Speaker 1: I'm worried because this could be it could have been a good idea this game because it might be like Actraiser because half of Actraiser Was amazing and half of Actraiser.
Speaker 0: Well, I just paid $15 to play the single race Actraiser.
Speaker 1: I Might I got to see the game first.
Speaker 1: I'm only talking about all this meta stuff.
Speaker 1: I'm not talking about the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so yeah as far as I can see They have taken Crystal Chronicles and run it into the ground and as far as I am concerned as fast and as hard as they Possibly could have.
Speaker 0: yeah, they made it.
Speaker 0: It was it sword to the top.
Speaker 0: then they let it stagnate for a long time and they drove it into the ground.
Speaker 0: They really they.
Speaker 0: I need some saving graces.
Speaker 0: We need like four swords.
Speaker 0: We wear or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah because I mean Remember Wario aware for the GameCube and how great that was.
Speaker 1: and remember that feeling of disgust when you when you realize that you could Win two-thirds of the minigames in Wario aware for the Wii by just randomly waggling and the rest of the games were just stupid And there was no multiplayer worth a damn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: They need to pass the wiimote.
Speaker 1: That's like salt on the wound.
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day, so this guy had an idea that is so clever.
Speaker 1: I can't believe I like.
Speaker 1: I never thought of it.
Speaker 1: But then again, that's why this guy is clever and I am not quite as clever.
Speaker 1: What he did is he made a level in some level editor in Super Mario World really hard level and then he beat it.
Speaker 1: It took him a hundred and thirty four try.
Speaker 0: that's a really hard level.
Speaker 1: what he then did is superimpose simultaneously all of his attempts in a video and you can watch the video and You really need to see it to understand what this means.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's very hard for me to describe it with words But you'll see like a Mario.
Speaker 1: that's normal and he blurs a little bit because there's a lot of Mario's there in slight Deviations what the guy did but then it'll get to like a hard part and suddenly that one Mario explodes into a sea of Like 30 Mario's who all die in different ways, but
Speaker 0: one of the Mario's like lives
Speaker 1: Well by one.
Speaker 1: usually it's like the 40 or 50 Mario's from all the different attempts where he made it past that point.
Speaker 0: Yeah But they're all in the same spot.
Speaker 0: because you know He basically he played the level like a hundred something times and like 30 of those times he made this jump.
Speaker 0: So all the times when he made this jump, you know looks on the screen like one Mario.
Speaker 1: Yep, because remember all these all the old like 2d Mario games were Deterministic.
Speaker 1: as in if you figure out the way to beat world 1-1 in Super Mario World or Mario 1 Perfectly you can do it every time like the Koopa will always be in the same spot The timer will always count down at the exact same point.
Speaker 1: The Piranha Plant will always appear exactly when you know, it will appear Yep.
Speaker 0: So it looks like there's like one Mario and occasionally a whole bunch of other Mario's explode out of it and it's really really interesting.
Speaker 0: I think this is like the best way to demonstrate like levels.
Speaker 1: This is so cool.
Speaker 0: It's really cool.
Speaker 1: That's all I got.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 0: So, you know, this isn't video game related, but I don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're not gonna do Sinistar There's a picture.
Speaker 0: It's it's not really thinking the name of this for a Photoshop.
Speaker 1: I think it is anyway.
Speaker 0: See everyone knows that like pictures of food and advertisements are not real like, you know They always talk about how them, you know on the McDonald's commercials the buns have like the seeds glued on And they spritz water on it to make it glow and you're like the bun is just like, you know The burger is just like a piece of fake like clay that's painted to make it look like a really juicy burger.
Speaker 0: And you know, the tomato is like a plastic tomato and you know that all that business.
Speaker 0: But you know in general, it's not just like McDonald's.
Speaker 0: It's like every picture of food you ever see on a food package or in an advertisement.
Speaker 0: there's basically people whose job it is to photograph food and figure out ways to photograph food and Model food and get it to look really good.
Speaker 1: The worst thing and I've heard about this from multiple sources is if you're an actor and you're in a scene in a film Where there's food that you're eating?
Speaker 1: Because the things they do to that food to make it look good on screen do not often make it appetizing No, and also you have to fake eating over and over and over again throughout all the takes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sometimes sometimes It depends on how they film it obvious Sometimes they'll put like a pile of fake food.
Speaker 0: But that like they're like that one real drumstick there that you can sort of chew on, you know, something like that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so this guy in Germany had a really smart idea.
Speaker 0: he went to the grocery store in Germany and he bought all sorts of products that had pictures of The what was supposedly inside the product.
Speaker 0: so a lot of these are like soups where there be a picture of the soup and then he makes the soup and he takes a picture of what the soup actually looks like.
Speaker 0: or There'll be some sort of like TV dinner as a picture on the box of what the TV dinner is supposed to look like.
Speaker 0: and Then he actually opens the TV dinner and takes a picture of what's really inside there.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you that Enten Fleisch does not look like whatever Enten Fleisch is.
Speaker 0: The worst one is the herring salad.
Speaker 0: The herring salad is like the most disgusting thing I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: it looks like a peto bismol with chunks in it.
Speaker 1: These are.
Speaker 1: the only one that I think really stands out to me is the pistachios because the actual picture looks good.
Speaker 1: But the fake pistachios that they put like the picture of the pistachios that they try to sell you the pistachios with Look fake and scary.
Speaker 1: They look like aliens.
Speaker 0: They do.
Speaker 0: it's kind of funny.
Speaker 0: It's like there's a photograph of pistachio nuts and I'm like, huh?
Speaker 0: It looks like pistachio nuts.
Speaker 0: and then the you know These computer-generated pistachio nuts that are on the package look like scary like pod people.
Speaker 0: pistachio nuts.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's really.
Speaker 0: some of these are just sort of like oh that's what I expected.
Speaker 0: some of them are kind of like It's a little bit off but you know, it's still edible.
Speaker 0: some of them are like wow I'm nauseous just looking at that.
Speaker 0: and some of them are just like oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Look there's a slight difference.
Speaker 0: I think the thing that's most often seen I think is that in the photographs?
Speaker 0: They'll put all sorts of extra stuff.
Speaker 0: You know at times you look at like a cereal box and it won't just be like it's like Strawberries and great smiling kids.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't see flakes.
Speaker 0: You see flakes with milk and fruits and nuts and all kinds of exploding things but in the box is just flakes and a lot of these is like this one that shows rice with all sorts of like Vegetable bits in it all over the place, but really inside is the clumper rice, you know.
Speaker 0: or this other one which shows like Like a soup with all sorts of yummy different bits in it.
Speaker 0: But really it's just the soup and the yummy bits are like, you know, you have to add them yourself, you know.
Speaker 0: And yeah This is really something everyone should look at and I think if I had the time and effort I would do repeat this for American food products to compare them to the German.
Speaker 0: It's also funny to learn about some German food products.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Germany has a lot of food products that look interesting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all this rice milk looks really interesting.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of things with like cubed or sliced ham and I really like cubed and sliced ham.
Speaker 0: I don't but you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, so brawl.
Speaker 0: so we got to talk about the brawls.
Speaker 1: Well, we can't we have.
Speaker 1: we can't avoid talking about it.
Speaker 1: No, you're all gonna keep bothering us.
Speaker 1: No we talk about.
Speaker 0: should we talk about like the older smash brothers?
Speaker 1: Also, we can do that a little.
Speaker 1: this would be a real laid-back show.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So I think the most pressing question I'm sure people are wondering is who do you play as now?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I basically You know, I mean in the old brawl in the old I keep calling them brawls.
Speaker 0: in the older Smash Brothers game I was pretty much all Samus all the time with occasionally using other characters just to get the feel see I never really played the N64 like I played it maybe twice in my entire life.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's kind of scary that like I played the n64 one in high school a whole bunch and Then we get to college and rims like oh I never played that and like why the crew had never played Smash Brothers Didn't even know how to play.
Speaker 1: I'd never even heard of the game.
Speaker 0: Ah, it was like, ah, what the hell?
Speaker 0: What the hell's going on this.
Speaker 1: I'd heard of it But the thing is I skipped the n64 generation of consoles like Goldeneye, right?
Speaker 1: I did but I didn't like it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I had real FPS.
Speaker 0: is Golden eyes great.
Speaker 0: It's not a real FPS But it's great thing.
Speaker 1: Goldeneye would have been great if I didn't have a cable modem and real FPS.
Speaker 0: It's great.
Speaker 0: It's different kind of game.
Speaker 0: Just like Smash Brothers is great I mean, it's not a fighting.
Speaker 0: it's a guess if you could call it a fighting game But you can't really.
Speaker 0: you don't compare it to Soul Calibur.
Speaker 0: It's but it's not the.
Speaker 1: the Goldeneye experience was kind of.
Speaker 1: it was like it.
Speaker 1: It was a lot like the Xbox experience.
Speaker 1: today with Halo like before those live got really really good But it doesn't hold a candle to like the mega TF.
Speaker 1: action quake days has been at least in my eyes.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is is that the original Smash Brothers what in its day was a great game and it's still a great game.
Speaker 0: They've just the newer ones.
Speaker 0: They're the same game only better and they.
Speaker 1: why can't Nintendo do this more often?
Speaker 1: Alright, here's a game We pretty much hit on the formula right away.
Speaker 1: Let's make moderate improvements over time forever.
Speaker 0: Yeah The thing is is other people do that and they get flack from all the game.
Speaker 0: reviewers like you didn't make big enough improvements.
Speaker 1: blah blah because Nintendo was good enough already.
Speaker 1: but more importantly Nintendo has a level of investment and social currency in their characters.
Speaker 1: That defies logic.
Speaker 0: I think the other thing about Smash Brothers, right?
Speaker 0: That still is amazing to me is that no one is else has tried to make a game like this.
Speaker 0: I mean there was a Naruto game kind of like this and there was that jump superstars.
Speaker 0: There's a little bit like Smash Brothers But not really like Smash Brothers the only game like Smash Brothers and no one else is even stepping into that arena at all.
Speaker 1: I thought I saw that someone was doing that.
Speaker 0: actually I didn't see.
Speaker 1: I saw some rumor.
Speaker 1: I didn't read the article or something.
Speaker 0: I believe it.
Speaker 1: if I see it I saw it on my blackberry like in the Google Reader while I was eating and I didn't want to try to load the webpage.
Speaker 1: I just skipped it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I haven't seen any other games try to step on the into the Smash Brothers toes at all.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much the only game that is like it anyway, but yeah in the second in Smash Brothers Melee I like.
Speaker 1: that was my first real Smash Brothers.
Speaker 1: So I learned how to play and I pretty much ended up playing Falco and peach and I'd alternate between the two.
Speaker 0: I was still playing Samus mostly but also, you know other characters randomly kind of.
Speaker 0: but in the new one Like I find myself not using Samus so much.
Speaker 0: He's a little slower.
Speaker 0: You know the fact with the switching to the to the zero suit Samus.
Speaker 0: I really don't like the zero suit Samus That's very annoying.
Speaker 0: But I kind of I really want to use the final smash if I get it and you kind of have to use it.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I played a lot.
Speaker 1: there's some characters I have yet to play like wolf.
Speaker 1: I just didn't even bother with him.
Speaker 1: I didn't even know who he was.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't know who wolf was.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 0: I was like when I was trying to I went I got a fact to unlock the characters and it was like wolf.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, who the hell is that?
Speaker 0: I Didn't play the star foxes that had wolf I guess.
Speaker 0: Ah and Lucas Yeah, well Ness I never liked in the first place.
Speaker 0: cuz his up and B move is no good.
Speaker 1: I like his moves a lot.
Speaker 1: It's just difficult.
Speaker 1: He's one of those and he's like trying to drive the stupid cappuccino In in the initial the arcade game.
Speaker 0: worse than that worse than that, but people are good with him.
Speaker 1: Oh, man Yeah, it's an art to behold kind of like people who are good with ice climbers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Lucas is just nest but even worse.
Speaker 1: No Lucas is like baby mode Ness.
Speaker 1: He's like if you can't handle Ness you can try Lucas, but it's up and B move.
Speaker 0: I can't get it to go at all.
Speaker 0: I can sometimes get it to go.
Speaker 1: My only beef with Lucas is that as a character he's so lame and pathetic and meanwhile Ness is all badass.
Speaker 1: Ness reeks of red from the original Pokemon like out you wouldn't believe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Lucas is totally yellow caviar Yeah, and I never.
Speaker 1: that's when I stopped reading that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's talk about Smash Brothers in general, right?
Speaker 0: So Smash Brothers is sort of like a fighting game But it's sort of not because the only way to win is not to bring the other guys health meter down to zero But to get a ring out and that's the only way to get to get kills, right?
Speaker 0: and You basically when you hit other people their percentage goes up and once their percentage gets really high If you hit them with a smash move, they're much more likely to go flying off the screen Much farther.
Speaker 1: Yep, and if like some characters can recover better and yeah, so I get hit into a wall You're not gonna fly off no matter how many times you get hit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's some special like alright, dude You're at 300% you're gone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like Kirby with his puff puff.
Speaker 0: You know flying is a lot harder to get off the screen, you know, cuz you get him really far.
Speaker 0: But then he goes puff puff puff puff and he comes right back and it's like, ah, see hit him again And he goes puff puff puff and he comes back again.
Speaker 1: Oh speaking of Kirby.
Speaker 1: I got I got to point out something very important.
Speaker 1: Mmm, I am like pretty much every gamer in America forever said King today day.
Speaker 1: I've called him King today day my entire life.
Speaker 0: I've also called him King today day my entire.
Speaker 1: Never met a human being who did not call him King today day or if they did they kept that fact secret.
Speaker 0: but in Smash Brothers one one key component of the game is that when you select a character the Narrator says the character's name and this removes all ambiguity as to the correct pronunciation also created.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna give you all a little secret from the Smash Brothers brawl.
Speaker 0: Well, we're just kind of rambling all about smash all over the place melee.
Speaker 1: So what happens if I choose Pichu but you choose Ness right as I choose Pichu P. Yes, P.
Speaker 0: Yes Yeah, great.
Speaker 1: Well, actually he doesn't say the two he goes P. Yes P. Yes, great That was like the best part.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were sort of rambling all over the place about Smash Brothers.
Speaker 0: I mean like who doesn't already know what there is to know about Smash Brothers?
Speaker 0: King Dedede?
Speaker 0: Yeah, King Dedede.
Speaker 0: I guess that's his name.
Speaker 1: I have a lot of trouble saying it but then again how many people had trouble saying the Nintendo Wii?
Speaker 1: and who says Revolution?
Speaker 0: now nobody.
Speaker 0: people still say Firefox everyone could.
Speaker 0: no one says Phoenix anymore.
Speaker 1: I still say capstone and physical plant but none of you care.
Speaker 0: That's only good.
Speaker 0: You have to try really hard.
Speaker 1: Yeah Especially because when I was there I had to fill out forms to those organizations and it had the bad names on them all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway Smash Brothers See you it's a fighting game.
Speaker 0: now One thing that makes Smash Brothers better than other fighting games is that you can have more than two people at a time Which is awesome.
Speaker 1: Right you get four friends in there at once and also just the the brilliant Way that the camera kind of zooms in and out and handles.
Speaker 1: this makes it just.
Speaker 1: it's so perfect like they perfected.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I split screen bullshit.
Speaker 1: It's four people on the screen at once and it just zooms out to make sure everyone fits at any time.
Speaker 1: If it comes down to two people fighting it zooms way in.
Speaker 0: well I think part of it.
Speaker 0: the excellent camera also works with the function of the game Which is knock someone off the screen.
Speaker 0: So, you know the camera doesn't have to go follow you if you go off the screen because you're dying out there.
Speaker 0: But you know, it has a little arrow telling you where you went to so you can still try to make your way back.
Speaker 0: You know if you have that ability, but I play metatight.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: I just wanted to get a non sequitur right in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's great.
Speaker 0: The other thing about Smash Bros.
Speaker 0: I think is great.
Speaker 0: Is that unlike some other fighting?
Speaker 1: Such an objective review.
Speaker 1: I just imagine it's like.
Speaker 1: and another thing that's great about Smash Brothers.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right You know even Soul Calibur 2 the greatest normal fighting game.
Speaker 0: That's 3d, right?
Speaker 0: You pick any one character and they have like a zillion moves.
Speaker 0: and while the basic moves are pretty intuitive You know, every character has you know, some complicated moves that require Sequences of button presses or combinations of button presses and they're not the same for every character.
Speaker 1: You have to learn them and don't forget stances and all that crazy.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, I played nothing but Voldo forever.
Speaker 1: I'm the Voldo man and yet I don't know all of his moves to this day.
Speaker 0: I have played nothing.
Speaker 0: but you know Siegfried nightmare pretty much, you know, I've played the other characters But Siegfried's nightmare has been my man since the original soul edge course.
Speaker 1: I think Scott and I are both working the kinds of people or the kinds of gamers who?
Speaker 1: Whenever there's a game where you choose like a character to be like you have a choice to be a character.
Speaker 1: Whether or not it matters like what the characters powers are.
Speaker 1: We tend to one be very loyal to like one character and choose a character.
Speaker 0: We like based on other things.
Speaker 1: Yes, I choose my character based solely on how cool I think that character is.
Speaker 0: You think all those really cool?
Speaker 1: Well, here's the weird thing.
Speaker 0: Well, there's the exception.
Speaker 1: The reason I played Voldo is because Voldo was really intuitive to me for some reason like the way he moves.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it was, but I like.
Speaker 1: I'd never played like Soul Calibur one that much.
Speaker 1: I never really liked all the old Soul Calipers cuz.
Speaker 1: I was more of a Bushido blade kid Terrible.
Speaker 1: Bushido blade is great.
Speaker 1: You can all die in a fire sucks.
Speaker 1: But so I played Soul Calibur.
Speaker 0: just to clarify before people come at me I like the idea of Bushido blade which is you know, oh man, you hit a guy with the sword He actually gets hurt real semi realistically and dies.
Speaker 0: the actual execution of Bushido blade I think is not it doesn't?
Speaker 1: you played Bushido blade three.
Speaker 0: I played Bushido blade one and two.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you should have played three.
Speaker 1: It's better.
Speaker 0: It might be but the actual execution of one and two is not make for the greatest game.
Speaker 1: Well, if any of you out there try to argue that Bushido blade one was better.
Speaker 1: No, you're wrong but For some reason like I played I was like, ooh, I'll be sick for you.
Speaker 1: Yeah whatever and I play it as everyone.
Speaker 1: and then I played as Voldo and I won and I won and I won and I won and it was kind of creepy and everyone's like ring.
Speaker 1: Why are you playing Voldo?
Speaker 1: Like I don't know and it became my thing.
Speaker 1: and While I probably would have liked to be I don't know Rafael I feel like that's the character I would have picked if I had been picking.
Speaker 1: Voldo chose me More due to the reputation of people going.
Speaker 1: Oh god rim plays Voldo.
Speaker 1: It's very fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, plus, you know and I don't even know like a quarter of the moves of Siegfried slash nightmare, but I win a lot.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm not great.
Speaker 0: Like if I play in a tournament, I'll get my ass kicked but against in casual play I win a lot.
Speaker 0: Here's another thing annoying giant sword.
Speaker 1: I'm definitely comparing apples to oranges a little bit.
Speaker 1: but the all games all game not just fighting games video games every possible game that could ever exist.
Speaker 1: there are like limits and ceilings and there's a point in which you were playing the game the best the game could possibly be played within the limitations of the game itself or in the context of the game.
Speaker 1: and The thing about Smash Brothers.
Speaker 1: and a lot of people don't really realize this except the people who are really good at the game.
Speaker 1: the ceiling for goodness in Smash Brothers all the Smash Brothers games is Crazy high like to the point that most people who play that game will never even get close to the full potential of any of the Characters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean basically the thing I was gonna say before that I was trying to get to is that Smash Brothers unlike all the other fighting games or Typical fighting games is that every character has the same moves?
Speaker 0: You don't to learn new controls for each character.
Speaker 0: Everyone is the same set of moves.
Speaker 0: You know B is special moves a is normal moves.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: a and up is you know an upward attack a in the side is a sideways attack.
Speaker 0: A and tap to the side is a smash a and tap to the up as a smash Etc right B and up is usually some sort of recovery move, you know.
Speaker 0: or upward special move Always like the weird move Yeah, just be on its own is sort of the normal special move like shoot a fireball princess peaches butt smash like my favorite thing.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty good one.
Speaker 0: But the depending on what character you choose those moves are gonna be different.
Speaker 0: the damage is gonna be different Their speed is different.
Speaker 0: Their size is different Their jumping is different, you know, and that's that's what makes Smash Brothers great Is that you don't have to relearn the game to change characters?
Speaker 0: Which is why people play different characters a lot more than they do than in other fighting games and it.
Speaker 0: it makes it a lot More fun and gives you a lot more replay value because it's easy to switch it up But you still to be good with the character you sort of have to learn.
Speaker 0: You know how to use all their moves effectively and yep now actually what we'll get to this.
Speaker 1: but pretty much the the factors that matter the most unlike other games were knowing all the moves and memorization.
Speaker 1: a lot of things count for a lot.
Speaker 1: in Smash Brothers it pretty much comes down to timing.
Speaker 1: Knowing the timing of smashes the timing of attacks and precision control with the character you are using and that's it.
Speaker 1: That's all the timing and rapid reflexes.
Speaker 0: and knowing the timing of various moves and the effectiveness of various moves is Really the key to winning.
Speaker 1: and the level of precision you need to be very good at that game is a lot more than you Might think.
Speaker 0: yeah, the thing about Smash Brothers is this right people always go all games on balance blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: This character is better than that characters, but it's unfair blah That's all bullshit.
Speaker 0: now I'm not gonna say that all the characters are exactly equal because in order to say that I would have to perfectly be the grand Master of the game and a hundred percent with everything, but eventually we will find out.
Speaker 0: eventually we'll find out.
Speaker 0: but basically the thing about the game is that some Characters are harder to use.
Speaker 0: like it is harder to play as ice climbers than it is to play as Mario.
Speaker 0: If you have two people of equal skill right and none of them are particularly skilled with any character They just have the same general Smash Brothers knowledge.
Speaker 0: and one guy chooses Mario and one guy chooses ice climber.
Speaker 0: I'm probably gonna bet on the Mario guy.
Speaker 0: if there's a third guy who's Pikachu I'm probably gonna bet on him, you know, but it's just because ice climber is harder to use.
Speaker 0: So someone at skill level 10 playing ice climber might only be like at a power level of a hundred.
Speaker 0: But someone at skill level 10 with Mario might be a power level You know, but meanwhile, what if someone is the master of Smash Brothers?
Speaker 0: Well, maybe someone who's the grand master of Smash Brothers.
Speaker 0: if they play with Mario the power level might be 10,000 but if they play with ice climbers the power level might be 100,000. because the ice climber because they can draw out the hidden power of the ice climbers with their skill.
Speaker 0: and I think really the winning at Smash Brothers comes down to skill the Luck because there is a lot of luck in the game unless you do the Fox no items final destination The the exact combination of characters and map that has been selected.
Speaker 0: I know if there's a big map and one guy is a fast character with ranged attacks and one guy is a slow character with Close-up attacks.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be really hard for the slow character to win on a big map.
Speaker 1: Yes, but at the same time much like with Texas Hold'em and you know games like that I mean you can win it's if you're really good.
Speaker 0: if someone was really good They probably even beat me in that kind of situation over time.
Speaker 1: in aggregate The better players will win a higher percentage of the game.
Speaker 0: Yep, which is why I think if there's a Smash Brothers tournament I would always have random characters and random maps and I would just have a losers bracket to account for the randomness.
Speaker 1: If I didn't do randomness, I would just do a triple elimination.
Speaker 1: The problem is that requires a ludicrous amount of planning.
Speaker 0: No, I could just do a round robin where everyone sort of plays.
Speaker 0: You know everyone and then you see who had got the most wins and then those people do.
Speaker 0: is you know You have a you do that kind of method.
Speaker 0: Actually, this this newest Smash Brothers is a built-in tournament mode, which I we have to try out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we haven't tried that yet.
Speaker 1: We're not reviewing the game so much cuz what it's Smash Brothers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, come on.
Speaker 0: What else you gonna say about?
Speaker 0: All right, here's what we got to say with the new Smash Brothers.
Speaker 0: There's a lot more characters.
Speaker 0: They're really cool.
Speaker 1: I like met a knight.
Speaker 0: the subspace emissary sucks, but so not worth playing.
Speaker 0: It's not worth playing but it's the easiest way to unlock the characters in the map.
Speaker 0: It's not worth it.
Speaker 1: It's just a stupid grind.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but to unlock the characters the maps any other way is even worse.
Speaker 1: Just keep playing.
Speaker 0: just basically go online and figure out the minimum work You have to do to unlock.
Speaker 0: you only want to unlock the characters and the maps are multiplayer everything else.
Speaker 0: Don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: trophies who gives a shit, you know stickers who gives a shit?
Speaker 0: Just ignore all that bullshit because all you really care about is the multiplayer action and to make that All you need are the maps and the character.
Speaker 1: You might want the stuff for the map editor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the map editor, you know people are putting it down, but I'm in a map that looks like a penis.
Speaker 1: So I Was gonna bring that up to make fun of you, but now that you brought it up I got nothing so that validates the worthiness of the map editor right away.
Speaker 0: the online play.
Speaker 0: who gives a shit?
Speaker 0: It's all about the local play.
Speaker 0: the online play is just not worth it because you know, it's just you might as well.
Speaker 0: It's no different than playing against the CPU.
Speaker 0: Well, except that I can't talk to the baby You don't know who they are.
Speaker 1: Maybe just because I'm better at Smash Brothers than I used to be.
Speaker 1: but I was practicing over the previous weekend and I got to the point where pretty much the AI Cannot win even on the hardest AI setting.
Speaker 1: the AI is so stupid.
Speaker 0: play three against one.
Speaker 0: you verse three.
Speaker 0: I want a team against you.
Speaker 1: I didn't do that yet.
Speaker 0: That's how to get really good.
Speaker 1: Yeah pretty much I played a lot of one verse one until I could never lose and then I played a lot of to like to Verse one and a lot of for free-for-all.
Speaker 1: see I never lost.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got to do three versus one where it's three computers all attacking you and only you and not each other.
Speaker 1: Actually, I just got to play against humans.
Speaker 1: that too because there are a lot of cheap ways to kill the AI Cuz.
Speaker 1: it'll get confused and you can just knock it off the edge and kind of hold it off the edge until it dies.
Speaker 0: The thing is playing against humans You need to find in order to get the higher level of skill like to be a master.
Speaker 0: You need to play against people who are masters like that and they're not easy to come by if you keep playing with just your.
Speaker 1: That's why I'm gonna go to uh, I know some people some peeps back at our ITs and we go out there for torque on.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be hitting up some Conrad for some Smash Brothers brawl.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I know that he is better than me.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: What else is different in this one.
Speaker 0: They changed the the home run thing.
Speaker 0: I think they made it a little better a little more interesting.
Speaker 1: It's a lot more fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah I like how.
Speaker 1: it's not just Wow be Yoshi and kick it a whole bunch with the stupid downward kick and everyone else just kind of sucks.
Speaker 0: Yep See what else did they do?
Speaker 0: there's this tournament mode.
Speaker 1: we talked about that.
Speaker 0: I know I'm trying to think assist trophies are hilarious.
Speaker 0: This is trophies are pretty good, but it's not worth it to try and unlock.
Speaker 0: I like how the hammer get unlocked.
Speaker 1: the hammer is so much gimpier that used to be but now there's the golden hammer.
Speaker 1: That is just amazing and cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's the final.
Speaker 0: All right, we gotta talk about the final smash, right?
Speaker 1: I like this final smash a lot.
Speaker 0: There's the final smash and there's that other thing.
Speaker 0: I forget what it's called the the thing from Kirby the three-piece item.
Speaker 0: Basically the final smash is this you'll be playing and there's an item called the final smash or the smash ball right and basically this ball will float onto the screen and Everyone will try to beat up the ball.
Speaker 0: like normally when there's an item you pick it up and then you use it But the smash ball you have to beat it up So you'll just.
Speaker 0: it usually floats so usually means you have to jump up there and hit it.
Speaker 0: now You have to do more a lot of damage to it because you want it.
Speaker 0: basically Hitting it doesn't help you.
Speaker 0: you want to be the person who breaks it.
Speaker 0: So if rim hits it a whole bunch and then I tap it and it breaks It's it.
Speaker 0: rim might as well not a hit it because I got.
Speaker 1: yet if Scott doesn't use his smash in time I can knock it out of him and then I can hit it.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: But anyway, when you if you're the person who does the final, you know straw that breaks the smash ball You glow and you have the super smash like mega final smash power.
Speaker 1: They're all different.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna get into that.
Speaker 0: like all the different every character has a different final smash.
Speaker 0: Basically what it amounts to is you push B and then you're probably gonna kill somebody.
Speaker 0: but depending on your character it ranges from Instantly kill everyone in the screen pretty much guaranteed to kill someone guaranteed with a lot of skill.
Speaker 0: yeah, like super Wario or Supersonic it's actually kind of hard to kill what supersonic is one of the best ones.
Speaker 0: super Wario is a little harder.
Speaker 1: supersonic is Okay, but it's never killed me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well supersonic, you know Basically, it's just he starts flying around the screen and you had to control it to really pull on the stick to keep him On the screen, but you just sort of run into people and they get really hurt a lot.
Speaker 1: I like meta nights is pretty much if you pull it off.
Speaker 1: Somebody's gonna get hurt.
Speaker 0: real bad Yeah, but like super Wario you have to fly around the screen.
Speaker 0: It's a little easier than flying supersonic.
Speaker 0: You actually have to beat people up by pushing a and such and it's much harder to actually kill people that somebody.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I think what this the smash ball does is it's sort of it really Does something interesting to the game?
Speaker 0: It makes a little bit more random because you know a character who is more Able to go around the map say Pikachu versus Donkey Kong is probably gonna be able to get the final smash more often.
Speaker 0: But at
Speaker 1: the same time
Speaker 0: onto the map a lot
Speaker 1: enough of them come down the balls coming off to her in Aggregate, you know people are gonna get him and it evens out in the end and everyone's smash power is kind of balanced with all the other powers of their character and their likelihood of getting the ball.
Speaker 1: and it also Serves this interesting purpose of if there's a stalemate which really only happens among really crappy inexperienced players or just even in a real head-up game like the games going and suddenly it appears and Let me tell you the tension when there's four people surrounding that thing try and desperately to get it.
Speaker 1: Ah That adds so much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean because you know a lot of times you'd be playing this game and inexperienced kind of players would you know?
Speaker 0: Just like sit there from far away shooting each other like Fox will start shooting his laser at someone.
Speaker 0: They'd be really timid and standoffish Especially when it was coming down to like, you know, the last life people would be really cowardly on a big map.
Speaker 0: They would keep running away and only attacking when they had a big advantage like a hammer or something.
Speaker 0: And then when someone else had a hammer you just run away, you know When his ball comes onto the screen suddenly it's like wow if I get that ball is a good chance I'm just gonna kill the guy.
Speaker 0: So everyone goes for the ball and you really you're just sort of forced to either Fight for it or not and it really it sort of forces everyone to play.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah Okay, if you want to be a rim would often have that strategy because in stock games and the old Smash Brothers I'd be Falco and I'd or Pikachu and I'd hide in the top right corner.
Speaker 0: Yeah, every now and then because you play we play stock instead of time which is a game of survival.
Speaker 0: It's who lives to the end not who gets the most kills.
Speaker 0: So rim would just run away and avoid getting hit as much as he could and hopefully at the end He would be.
Speaker 0: you know of more lives than the other guy and I have like one more life.
Speaker 1: So I just grab him and jump off the edge or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: So this when the smash ball comes that's sort of like oh shit You can't just run and hide.
Speaker 0: now You actually have to get in the fight or someone's just gonna kill you instantly.
Speaker 0: no matter with this giant item pretty much The other item they added is like this.
Speaker 0: I think it comes from Kirby.
Speaker 0: I'm not exactly sure what it's called.
Speaker 0: It's three pieces, right?
Speaker 0: And if you get one of the pieces you said an icon appears that shows that you have one of the pieces Which is great because then you'll have situation where someone says oh crap room has two of them.
Speaker 1: Don't let me get the third one.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Let's go.
Speaker 1: Fuck him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and If you get all three pieces You sort of zoom out and you have this target and you can shoot someone on the screen with it and then kill them.
Speaker 1: It's difficult but not impossible to dodge.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's difficult and it pretty much if it hits it's an instant kill.
Speaker 0: Nothing you could do about it.
Speaker 0: I've seen people kill all three people with this item and basically when these pieces of this item start appearing because they always appear as a set like You know if one appears the rest of them are gonna appear pretty soon if they're not already.
Speaker 0: So it forces everyone to go in and start fighting over the three pieces because you're only other choices.
Speaker 0: The other guy would just pick up all three pieces and kill you.
Speaker 1: now Of course the some of the greatest fun occurs When there's a golden hammer somewhere on the map and those pieces and then a ball appears.
Speaker 0: generally You'd grab the hammer smash the ball.
Speaker 0: Yet get.
Speaker 0: use the hammer to clear everyone out.
Speaker 0: get all three pieces kill someone then push B and kill everyone else.
Speaker 0: Or just lose or just lose.
Speaker 0: be one of those other guys who doesn't get all the pieces.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I don't think we need to say much more.
Speaker 1: Smash Brothers is Smash Brothers.
Speaker 1: It's great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm rather enjoying it that.
Speaker 0: the only negative comment I can make about this new Smash Brothers.
Speaker 0: Is that Unlike previous Smash Brothers, which were sort of like in you know A hundred percent intuitive pick up and play like it wasn't a hundred percent intuitive Like you'll know all the moves and be good but it's a hundred percent intuitive in.
Speaker 0: you'll know You know what to do.
Speaker 0: there won't be any secrets.
Speaker 0: this new one It requires some knowledge.
Speaker 0: Like if you don't know what the Smash Ball does You're then the other person does.
Speaker 0: then suddenly the game is not working out so well, really Yeah, or if you don't know that those items are important and someone else does Yeah, the game doesn't work.
Speaker 0: So the game.
Speaker 0: I think the one bit the biggest negative about it besides the crappy subspace emissary mode Is that it requires some prerequisite knowledge for all players or the game is somewhat broken in a way.
Speaker 1: Luckily that definitely does I mean.
Speaker 1: by doing this it kind of caters to the people like the hardcore.
Speaker 1: people are really into this sort of thing and It's not like it's insurmountable.
Speaker 1: Hey hit that thing.
Speaker 0: people learned it in about like, you know A handful of games.
Speaker 0: people who came over learned what all the things do mostly because we told them.
Speaker 0: I could have kept it a Longer.
Speaker 1: I think they would have figured they want to figure it out.
Speaker 0: They were starting to figure it out, which is why I told them.
Speaker 1: Well, I think on that note we should stop because I kind of want to play some brawl.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe but yeah everyone if you have a Wii, how could you not have Smash Brothers?
Speaker 1: if you have a Wii You already have it.
Speaker 1: That's just.
Speaker 0: I'm assuming that yeah, so why do we even need to like review this?
Speaker 0: I mean, is it worth it to buy a Wii to get Smash Brothers?
Speaker 0: Well, probably not.
Speaker 0: Not that if you're not on its own But if you wanted some other Wii games to Smash Brothers definitely makes the Wii a better buy.
Speaker 1: if you can find one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you haven't, you know, maybe you don't have a Wii or it's hard to get a Wii I don't know.
Speaker 0: But if you haven't played the older Smash Brothers It's worth it to play the n64 and GameCube ones.
Speaker 1: but be warned Just know if you play this game at home or with your friends.
Speaker 1: That's one thing.
Speaker 1: if you go to a convention and play it in any sort of tournament or just play it at a convention Be prepared to find out that you are not good at that game at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's like a whole nother level of play.
Speaker 1: That's sort of like well like four tiers of goodness and Scott and I are barely at the second tier and the third tier is like Able to play at a convention without people laughing at you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the fourth tier is like winning trophies all around the world.
Speaker 0: I can you know tournaments.
Speaker 1: Yeah Think about that.
Speaker 1: tier three Not get made fun of when you play not even win just not lose so badly that you get made fun of.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't think I would get made fun of.
Speaker 0: but I mean if I played in a tournament with real players at this Game, like I would probably just be like dead dead, you know holding my own a little bit dead like
Speaker 1: watching videos of people who were good at this and
Speaker 0: then it probably just be like shake Hands and say good game.
Speaker 0: sort of like when I played in a magic tournament when I was a punk middle school kid I got killed by poison one.
Speaker 0: some guy just you know blows me away because I'm just some punk kid and I just lose to Him.
Speaker 0: but you know, then he shake hands.
Speaker 0: He's like good game, but really I was terrible.
Speaker 1: Alright, but anyway, I think we're done.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front road crew comm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Speaker 0: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: Don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night as if it happened only yesterday.
Speaker 0: I Was barely 17 and I once killed a boy with a fender.
Speaker 0: I Don't remember if it was a telecaster or a Stratocaster But I do remember that it had a heart of chrome and a voice like a horny angel.
Speaker 0: I Don't remember if it was a telecaster or a Stratocaster, but I do remember that it wasn't at all easy.
Speaker 0: It required the perfect combination of the right power cords and the precise angle from which to strike.
Speaker 1: The guitar bled for about a week afterward and the blood was zoo dark and rich like wild berries.
Speaker 0: The blood of the guitar was Chuck Berry red.
Speaker 0: The guitar bled for about a week afterward, but it rung out Beautifully and I was able to play notes that I had never even heard before.
Speaker 1: So I Took my guitar and I smashed it against the wall.
Speaker 1: I Smashed it against the floor.
Speaker 1: I Smashed it against the body of a varsity cheerleader Smashed it against the hood of a car Smashed it against the 1981 Harley Davidson.
Speaker 0: the Harley howled in pain the guitar And I ran up the stairs to my parents bedroom.
Speaker 0: Mommy and daddy was sleeping in the moonlight.
Speaker 0: Slowly I opened the door Creeping in the shadows right up to the foot of their bed.
Speaker 0: I raised the guitar high above my head and just as I was about to bring the guitar Crashing down upon the center of the bed.
Speaker 0: My father woke up screaming stop Wait a minute Stop it boy What do you think you're doing?
Speaker 0: that's no way to treat an expensive musical instrument and I said god damn it daddy You know, I love you, but you got a hell of a lot to learn about Rock-and-roll.