Speaker 0: It's Thursday, April 17th.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Sky.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, the Olympics, Tibet, and China.
Speaker 1: Dun dun dun.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I'm pretty sure I've decided to just get a PC and put Windows on it to do video because...
Speaker 0: At least for now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at least for now.
Speaker 1: Mostly because I realized you could buy a Windows license for Newegg, the System Builders edition, for very cheap.
Speaker 1: I mean, Windows Vista Ultimate is usually like $300 something, but Newegg, the System Builders edition, is like $150.
Speaker 1: And the only limitation is that you can't then install it on a different motherboard.
Speaker 1: So as long as I don't change the motherboard, I'm alright.
Speaker 1: So as long as I don't install it, then the motherboard explodes and I need to RMA it, I'll be okay.
Speaker 0: So what are you going to do down the road when you want to upgrade?
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: I don't know, if you want to use this computer at some point, move the motherboard?
Speaker 1: I'm sure by the time I want to change the motherboard.
Speaker 1: I mean, I've had this motherboard in my current computer for five years.
Speaker 1: The computer before that, five years.
Speaker 1: So I think that this one will last five years, maybe even longer.
Speaker 1: I mean, my current computer could keep going if I didn't need to do the video editing, right?
Speaker 0: Well, in the very least, I mean, I think this will get us through the first, I don't know, year or so of Geek Night's video.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it should.
Speaker 0: Beyond that, we'll be fabulously famous and wealthy and we'll just buy Avid.
Speaker 1: Or something, but like, I've complained about this before and it's probably better for Monday, so I can keep it short.
Speaker 1: But, you know, building a computer, I realized two things.
Speaker 1: You know, I haven't built a computer in a long time.
Speaker 0: You know, I just sort of- And I knew everything about consumer level computer technology.
Speaker 0: I knew the difference between the different chips on the different video cards and it was like, oh, man.
Speaker 1: They're really, they're making it more difficult because there's a lot more, you know, mostly in the power supply department where I have complained about that before many times.
Speaker 1: But I realized, though, they've made it more difficult.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, it's actually a better idea to do it than ever.
Speaker 1: I mean, you can get a computer like with a quad core crazy fuck holy shit on Newegg and build it for like under a thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: Was that the technical?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The computer that costs about a thousand dollars on Newegg costs like twenty five hundred from Dell.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's really getting sick.
Speaker 1: I bought two five hundred gigabyte drives.
Speaker 1: That's a terabyte for two hundred dollars.
Speaker 1: I remember when we were talking about, oh, my God, a terabyte is only a thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll get one.
Speaker 0: I remember not too long ago thinking, oh, my God, five hundred megabyte hard drive.
Speaker 1: So it's it's really getting crazy.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty close to making a decision.
Speaker 1: But what's funny is the CPU that I picked out.
Speaker 1: is it in the morning in stock now out of stock.
Speaker 1: So as soon as it comes back in stock, I'll probably make a move.
Speaker 0: One thing that's actually really helping us is that because we got just like the cheapest camera that'll do the job for now.
Speaker 0: No HD, which means we don't need nearly as much power or space any time soon.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, we're going for a large audience here.
Speaker 1: We're not going for, you know, like HD super production stuff.
Speaker 0: You know, quantity, not quality.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So we're good.
Speaker 1: We're doing YouTube's, you know, stuff like that.
Speaker 1: So the video just has to be better than everyone else's video.
Speaker 1: But it doesn't have to be HD.
Speaker 0: The thing is, we've recorded something.
Speaker 0: We did this whole test thing and we didn't edit it together yet, because there's nothing to edit with yet.
Speaker 0: But all I can say is if we even just put up what we recorded now on YouTube, it kind of frightens me how good it looks compared to a lot of YouTube's.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though it's not.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't put it.
Speaker 1: I think it's definitely beta.
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't even know if I want to bother saving it after we.
Speaker 1: Well, we should save it, but I don't think we should.
Speaker 0: I think the thing that's going to really help us out is that every YouTube, even if it's technically well done, very often has terrible audio.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're going to have good audios on our video.
Speaker 1: Half a video is audio.
Speaker 0: They just use the microphone and the camera.
Speaker 0: And actually I was looking at lavaliers and all that sort of thing, because we need those for our panels and things at conventions anyway.
Speaker 0: We really need all the kind of walk around the room wireless live mic solution because the kinds of things we do.
Speaker 0: And it's time, I think, to purchase something like that.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: Also in the news, the New York Comic-Con starts tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Actually, well, it kind of started today.
Speaker 0: We actually there's the ICV to conference.
Speaker 0: that seems to be before every read exhibitions thing.
Speaker 0: And we actually had passes.
Speaker 0: We just didn't go because I had to go to work and I didn't want to take two days off of work.
Speaker 0: I think I'll go to it for the next New York Comic-Con.
Speaker 0: But I we skipped it for the last New York Anime Festival and we skipped it for this Comic-Con.
Speaker 0: So I feel like I got to go at some point.
Speaker 1: You can go, but I'm going to tell.
Speaker 0: That's why you go.
Speaker 0: There's cocktails.
Speaker 1: That's fun.
Speaker 0: Also, I imagine most of the press who go to those things are not quite like us.
Speaker 0: And I could foresee us asking the questions that everyone else in the room goes, my word.
Speaker 0: What sort of man is that and what kind of publication does he work for?
Speaker 1: And they'll take our badges away and kick us out.
Speaker 0: Maybe not.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we'll be hanging out there.
Speaker 1: You might see us, you know, we're probably not going to spend too much time on the show floor.
Speaker 0: If you want to find us, either try to scam your way into the press room or look at the schedule and try to think, who would Rim and Scott care about to cover as press as opposed to actually pay attention to for fun?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Go find the Ninja Consultants in the podcast area.
Speaker 1: We might be in the podcast area quite a bit, you know, even though we don't have a table there.
Speaker 1: We might be an artist's alley buying arts because the artist's alley is pretty big.
Speaker 0: You know, I feel like I should not have my press badge on if I'm buying art.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: I think I'm going to like when I'm doing stuff that's not press, I'm going to sort of like hide the badge.
Speaker 1: Because like when you had the press badge out, you have to be, you know, non-biased, non-partisan.
Speaker 1: You have to be like totally just.
Speaker 0: there is no smiling if you are press.
Speaker 0: Thank you very much.
Speaker 0: Whoever it was who was sitting in our panel at the New York Anime Festival, just talking to themselves the whole time.
Speaker 0: Those press guys, I forget who those press guys were.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: But you just sort of, when you're press, you have to be serious business doing journalism.
Speaker 1: When you're not press, then you can be like, oh my God, your stuff is amazing or you suck.
Speaker 1: You know, that's what Engadget always complains.
Speaker 1: because Engadget, you know, they take it seriously.
Speaker 1: Like they act like they're serious journalists and they are serious journalists and they go to like, you know, see Steve Jobs and all these people are clapping and they're sitting there not clapping.
Speaker 1: And they're like, what the fuck, guys?
Speaker 1: Are you journalists or not?
Speaker 1: What the fuck?
Speaker 0: Well, the answer is clearly not.
Speaker 1: Yes, clearly.
Speaker 1: But so when we are acting as entertainers, you know, bringing digital content to the masses, we look to Penny Arcade for our inspiration of how we should act.
Speaker 1: And when we are acting as press, which we don't do too often, we will look to Engadget because they're the best, so why not do what they do?
Speaker 1: You know,
Speaker 0: it's complicated because we've nominally covered, like we've been press at pretty much every convention we've been to, but there's always kind of like we've got the press badge or we've got the press thing, but we also have like at the New York Anime Festival, we have the professional badge, which was the gold like Willy Wonka ticket.
Speaker 0: So it's like, it's weird.
Speaker 1: Except for trying to get in five minutes early and then...
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they seem to only let the most menial grunts in at that point early.
Speaker 1: I know, I don't get it.
Speaker 0: Of course, it was just that one guy too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was that one guy.
Speaker 0: Oh, well.
Speaker 0: But anyway, we've already gotten some news news news news news news.
Speaker 1: Last thing I want to say, for your best chance of seeing us, you should go to the Kinokuniya Bookstores in Bryant Park around 3 p.m.
Speaker 1: on Sunday.
Speaker 0: Yes, you probably want to get there early.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you'll probably see us at the convention, you know, late on Friday, you know, some early on Saturday because late on Saturday I'm going over to Queens.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then I'll be there late on Saturday.
Speaker 0: We're going to kind of hand off.
Speaker 1: And then Sunday you'll probably see us there a bit until, you know, around 2 p.m.
Speaker 1: and then we're going to go over to Kinokuniya's.
Speaker 0: We'll probably be at Kinokuniya well before 2 p.m.
Speaker 1: to set up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe.
Speaker 1: I don't know if we have to set up anything.
Speaker 0: We got to be there.
Speaker 0: This is the biggest kind of non-anime con outside in the real world thing we've done yet.
Speaker 0: I mean, we do gigantic panels and these big like main event style things, but they're always in the anime con for the anime fans or at the gaming con where no one goes to panels ever.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So now we're in the real world.
Speaker 1: That's still your best chance of seeing us.
Speaker 1: That's where you should go.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Plus, I think it'd be funny if you guys don't bother the Ninja Consultants looking for us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that'd be hilarious.
Speaker 1: Everyone go to the Ninja Consultants table in the podcast alley.
Speaker 0: And just ask for us.
Speaker 1: Also do the same thing at the Comic Geek speak table.
Speaker 1: Just ask, "Hey, have you seen Raymond Scott of Geek
Speaker 1: Nights?".
Speaker 1: We're looking for them.
Speaker 1: Just bother all the podcasters asking where we are.
Speaker 0: In fact, bother everyone at the con.
Speaker 0: Like, "Hey, we're the Geek Nights guys.
Speaker 0: I heard the Geek Nights guys are here.
Speaker 0: Oh my God, have you seen the Geek Nights
Speaker 0: guys?".
Speaker 1: That would be awesome.
Speaker 0: That would be really funny.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: We should get people to do that at every convention.
Speaker 1: Just go around asking people where we are.
Speaker 0: Are we going to get to the point where instead of buying ads, we pay street money like the candidates do in Pennsylvania?
Speaker 1: That's such a clever form.
Speaker 1: I wonder if any marketeer has ever thought of that.
Speaker 1: They've thought of some clever stuff.
Speaker 1: People who did internet stores, they have boxes with their company's name on it.
Speaker 1: And they'll just give them to a doorman and have them sit on the curb to make it look like people are buying their shit.
Speaker 1: And it's sort of like buying an ad on the street.
Speaker 1: They'll have people on the subway discuss their products loudly.
Speaker 1: They've tried that.
Speaker 0: There was a big one I remember, because I had a bar when this happened once, where they would hire people to sit there, like a very beautiful woman, and order kind of conspicuously very specific alcohols.
Speaker 0: And then talk about them and flirt with people and get them to buy.
Speaker 0: And it was the dumbest thing.
Speaker 0: And actually, I only knew because like a week or two after I was at this bar, I saw a thing on the internet about these people and it was the same freaking alcohol.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah, go around the New York Comic Con.
Speaker 0: Appointedly did not say what kind of alcohol it was.
Speaker 1: And even if you know where we are, ask people who are complete strangers and don't know us where we are.
Speaker 0: If nothing else, you'll be really annoying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, if you ask someone who doesn't know Geek Nights, just ask a random person at Artist Alley, "Hey, have you seen the Geek Nights guys
Speaker 1: anywhere?".
Speaker 1: They'd be like, "Who are you talking
Speaker 1: about?".
Speaker 1: But it sort of gives the impression that you think they should know.
Speaker 0: It gives the impression that we have listeners.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, no, it's like that way that person is like,
Speaker 1: "Huh.".
Speaker 1: They see that there's a person asking them where someone is.
Speaker 1: Thus, this complete stranger must expect this other complete stranger to know these people.
Speaker 1: So it's sort of like, you know, if you asked, "Do you know where Stan Lee
Speaker 1: is?".
Speaker 1: Well, even if they didn't, you know, he's such a famous person.
Speaker 1: So it's sort of like you're pretending that we're famous.
Speaker 1: Thus, it causes them to think, "Huh, those guys must be
Speaker 1: famous.".
Speaker 0: Bonus points if you go to con people and ask why the hell Geek Nights isn't doing panels, even though it's actually they kind of asked us to.
Speaker 0: We just didn't because we didn't expect to be going.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's also like 200 bajillion panels.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Plus, I guess we actually had some panels that we could have done, but we kind of want to test those first.
Speaker 0: So you'll be seeing all our new panels at like, Connecticut.
Speaker 1: I just think the most humorous thing about this whole convention for us is that I basically wasn't going to go.
Speaker 1: I was going to go maybe just like last year for a few hours on Friday and then leave.
Speaker 0: And then Tokyo FM was like, "Hey, just a CMR
Speaker 0: thing.".
Speaker 1: Then suddenly, usually we plan conventions.
Speaker 1: Like, we're planning Otacon now.
Speaker 1: It's months away.
Speaker 0: No, we planned Otacon like four months ago.
Speaker 1: Right, but New York Comic Con like weeks before we get thrown into it.
Speaker 1: And it's like, I'm like, "Goddamn
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, "Yeah, I'm not going to go.
Speaker 0: Hey, could you go for this one
Speaker 0: event?".
Speaker 0: "I feel like we should just...".
Speaker 0: "All right, I'll go for this one
Speaker 0: event.".
Speaker 0: "Hey, by the way, we really want you to be press.
Speaker 0: Here's your press
Speaker 0: badges.".
Speaker 0: "All right, I'll go
Speaker 0: Saturday.".
Speaker 0: "Hey, there's this awesome event
Speaker 0: Friday.".
Speaker 1: "Well, God damn
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: "I feel like we should just not try for conventions anymore because they'll just come to us
Speaker 1: now.".
Speaker 1: "Like, we'll just be thrown into
Speaker 1: them.".
Speaker 1: "All right, let's do
Speaker 1: news.".
Speaker 0: "Anyway, so what do you got in the
Speaker 0: news?".
Speaker 1: "Oh, well, here's actually, this is more of a Monday news, but I'm just full of tech
Speaker 1: today.".
Speaker 0: "I only pushed you into the news because I forgot what my news was and I had to reopen
Speaker 0: Firefox.".
Speaker 0: "But then I remembered that it's about
Speaker 0: logicielle.".
Speaker 1: "Oh, okay, well anyway, Microsoft patented
Speaker 1: something.".
Speaker 1: "And his is the article, the only gadget article about the
Speaker 1: patent.".
Speaker 1: "And this is an example of patents that don't
Speaker 1: suck.".
Speaker 1: "Like, this is a worthwhile patent and if this product comes to be, I can see myself buying
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: "What it is, is a computer mouse,
Speaker 1: right?".
Speaker 1: "But the mouse, like, wraps around your hand, like, across your palm and over the back of your
Speaker 1: hand.".
Speaker 1: "And there's a button on the side, like, under your thumb,
Speaker 1: right?".
Speaker 1: "So, like, if you made a fist, you'd be gripping
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: "And it'd be like having a joystick in your hand that's not attached to
Speaker 1: anything.".
Speaker 1: "But if you open your hand, you can type on the
Speaker 1: keyboard.".
Speaker 1: "So, when you turn your hand sideways, it sort of activates the
Speaker 1: mouse.".
Speaker 1: "And then you sort of move your hand around like a joystick and push the button to click on
Speaker 1: things.".
Speaker 1: "But then you turn your hand sideways again and you type it on the
Speaker 1: keyboard.".
Speaker 1: "So you don't have to move your hand back and forth to the mouse and the
Speaker 1: "You just sort of pick your hand up, click on things, and then put your hand down and
Speaker 1: type.".
Speaker 1: "And for someone who's, you know, for a normal person, this isn't really too
Speaker 1: useful.".
Speaker 1: "But for someone who sits at the computer for a long time, this is like, 'Oh my God, I hope this is
Speaker 1: real.'".
Speaker 1: "And I hope it works as well as it looks like it's gonna
Speaker 1: work.".
Speaker 1: "And I hope it's as comfortable as I could imagine it
Speaker 1: being.".
Speaker 1: "'Cause
Speaker 1: goddamn.".
Speaker 0: "It's tricky, 'cause this is one of those things where you'll use it and you'll either go,".
Speaker 0: "'Aw, man, it's perfect,' or it'll just be completely useless and suck in every
Speaker 0: way.".
Speaker 1: "Yeah.".
Speaker 0: "Like the mouse man back in the
Speaker 0: day?".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, I'm not having a high
Speaker 1: expectation.".
Speaker 0: "Or the, uh, Cyberman
Speaker 0: mouse?".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, I don't have a high expectation for
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: "I have a high hope for it, because I see the potential
Speaker 1: here.".
Speaker 1: "But yet, as we know, people are very bad at fulfilling
Speaker 1: potential.".
Speaker 1: "Nintendo.".
Speaker 0: "So, was that your
Speaker 0: news?".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, that's my
Speaker 1: news.".
Speaker 1: "That's
Speaker 1: it?".
Speaker 1: "Yeah.".
Speaker 1: "All
Speaker 1: right.".
Speaker 1: "When you see it, you go, 'Oh, it's pretty
Speaker 1: cool.'".
Speaker 0: "I have something much...".
Speaker 0: "Vive le roi!
Speaker 1: Vive le
Speaker 1: roi!".
Speaker 1: "Stop doing
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 0: "I couldn't help
Speaker 0: myself.".
Speaker 0: "You see, ze friends are up in an uproar over something involving the
Speaker 0: language.".
Speaker 0: "I shouldn't do that.
Speaker 0: It's
Speaker 0: bad.".
Speaker 0: "I make in front of the French, like, on a day-to-day basis, more so now than I have in the rest of my life
Speaker 0: combined.".
Speaker 0: "And it's
Speaker 0: surprising.".
Speaker 1: "They're really easy
Speaker 1: targets.".
Speaker 0: "But not really, because I know a lot about French
Speaker 0: history.".
Speaker 0: "I like France.
Speaker 0: I like the language.
Speaker 0: I studied it.
Speaker 0: I speak it badly, but I like
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 1: "Oh, you like ze guillotine,
Speaker 1: eh?".
Speaker 0: "No, not so much the
Speaker 0: guillotine.".
Speaker 1: "You like ze escargot and the
Speaker 1: chablis?".
Speaker 0: "Escargot and the
Speaker 0: chablis.".
Speaker 0: "That's
Speaker 0: right.".
Speaker 0: "But, uh, basically, the French, if nothing else...".
Speaker 0: "I think Eddie Izzard said it
Speaker 0: best.".
Speaker 0: "The French are, you know, very, very
Speaker 0: French.".
Speaker 0: "And they really care about their
Speaker 0: language.".
Speaker 0: "But when I say they...".
Speaker 1: "Well, some of them
Speaker 1: do.".
Speaker 0: "When I say they, I mean the proper
Speaker 0: French.".
Speaker 0: "You see, France has had this long-standing issue where there are people in the government and people in the nation...".
Speaker 0: "...who feel that the purity of the French language must be maintained at all
Speaker 0: costs.".
Speaker 0: "And the rest of the people in France pretty much just speak
Speaker 0: English.".
Speaker 0: "What they do is they speak, they call it
Speaker 0: franglais.".
Speaker 0: "There's a couple different words.
Speaker 0: I don't know what they call it now, but that's what they called it like five years
Speaker 0: ago.".
Speaker 0: "But they'll speak French, kinda, but they'll kinda slip in and out of
Speaker 0: English.".
Speaker 0: "And they use mostly English words for technology things, like most of the world
Speaker 0: does.".
Speaker 0: "Because who's gonna say 'l'ordinaire' when you can say 'computer' or 'PC' or like everyone else in the
Speaker 0: world?".
Speaker 0: "Except maybe Japan, but they say 'persicot' which is close
Speaker 0: enough.".
Speaker 0: "But that's not my news.
Speaker 0: Oh yes, that's my
Speaker 0: news.".
Speaker 0: "The French are prickly about their
Speaker 0: language.".
Speaker 0: "The news is that...".
Speaker 1: "The Russians like
Speaker 1: vodka.".
Speaker 0: "Eurovision is
Speaker 0: coming.".
Speaker 1: "Oh man, awesome
Speaker 1: music.".
Speaker 0: "We somewhat recently found out about
Speaker 0: Eurovision.".
Speaker 1: "Well, I knew about it like on one level, but I recently learned about it on a deeper
Speaker 1: level.".
Speaker 0: "We knew about it in the same way that you know like there was a guy named
Speaker 0: Napoleon.".
Speaker 0: "But we didn't know the in-depth, we didn't really understand it until that string of things of the day a while
Speaker 0: ago.".
Speaker 1: "Yep, that's
Speaker 1: right.".
Speaker 0: "Well, the current offering from France for the upcoming Eurovision happens to be in
Speaker 0: English.".
Speaker 0: "And good God, have people in France lost their shit over
Speaker 0: this.".
Speaker 1: "Oh come on, every other country is like putting English songs
Speaker 1: up.".
Speaker 0: "So Marc Favre de Chalons, who heads a group that is dedicated to quote defending French against the growing use of English,".
Speaker 0: "very specifically says 'a song represents the soul of a
Speaker 0: country.'".
Speaker 0: "It appears logical that the song representing France should be a French song sung in French,
Speaker 0: no?".
Speaker 0: "He goes on to denounce uniformity and hegemony of the English language in the world
Speaker 0: today.".
Speaker 0: "And this article is full of gems of
Speaker 0: quotations.".
Speaker 0: "They're calling this France's newest
Speaker 0: Waterloo.".
Speaker 1: "No classe in
Speaker 1: France.".
Speaker 0: "We have one vegan guy, and they torment him
Speaker 0: mercilessly.".
Speaker 0: "And we have one French guy, and they torment him
Speaker 0: "I think you see where they're going with
Speaker 0: this.".
Speaker 0: "They haven't figured out what to make fun of me
Speaker 0: for.".
Speaker 0: "Being
Speaker 0: nerdy?".
Speaker 0: "I'm not that nerdy
Speaker 0: though.".
Speaker 0: "Believe me, they're starting to make fun of me for game theory, but that's another
Speaker 0: story.".
Speaker 0: "People come up to me like 'ah, time to maximize our utility for the--'".
Speaker 0: "I'm like shut
Speaker 0: up.".
Speaker 1: "But
Speaker 1: anyway.".
Speaker 1: "Wait, no classe, I make the same Simpsons joke
Speaker 1: again.".
Speaker 1: "Nope.".
Speaker 0: "I just find this very interesting in France here, because on one hand, people, like the government and everyone, they want France to remain French, and French to remain French is the language that people should speak, and France shouldn't go away, but French shouldn't go
Speaker 0: away.".
Speaker 0: "But it seems like because the media and the people chose this song, that the majority of people in France don't care, and just kind of speak English
Speaker 0: anyway.".
Speaker 1: "Yep.".
Speaker 1: "Is that
Speaker 1: it?".
Speaker 0: "That's all I
Speaker 0: got.".
Speaker 0: "Things of the
Speaker 0: day.".
Speaker 0: "This is kind of old, you might have seen it if you perused 'colleg humor' on a regular
Speaker 0: basis.".
Speaker 1: "The 'colleg
Speaker 1: humor'?".
Speaker 0: "But this is very high
Speaker 0: quality.".
Speaker 1: "I'm pretty sure this might have been a thing of the day in the past, but it might not have
Speaker 1: been.".
Speaker 0: "I couldn't find
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 1: "I think we might have said this is going to be a thing of the day and then
Speaker 1: forgot.".
Speaker 0: "Probably, we've done that a lot, we'll see something, we're like 'man this is too good, let's save it' and then we just forget
Speaker 0: completely.".
Speaker 1: "I wasn't going to save it, I was going to use it right away, but I--".
Speaker 0: "Something else must have come
Speaker 0: up.".
Speaker 1: "I don't know if we actually used it or
Speaker 1: not.".
Speaker 0: "I don't think so, but anyway--".
Speaker 1: "I couldn't find it by
Speaker 1: searching.".
Speaker 0: "This is a stop motion animation involving food, a food fight if you will, and I don't think I need to say what it entails because you'll figure it out pretty quick, but it covers about 40 years of
Speaker 0: history.".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, I mean depending on how much you know about history, you'll be able to figure out what's
Speaker 1: what.".
Speaker 1: "And actually, I think that basically what you could do is you could show this scene by scene to a person and say any person, because there's no language,
Speaker 1: right?".
Speaker 1: "And say what part of history was that, you know, what is that
Speaker 1: representing?".
Speaker 1: "And if they can't tell you, then you could judge how much someone knows of history by how many of them they get
Speaker 1: right.".
Speaker 0: "I mean, you could debate whether or not, like, what specifically the falafel represents, but in a general sense, it's pretty obvious what the falafel
Speaker 0: represents.".
Speaker 1: "I know what the falafels
Speaker 1: represent.".
Speaker 0: "Yeah, but like between the two different kinds of sushi, or--".
Speaker 0: "Yeah, anyway, this is pretty funny and poignant and cool and well done.
Speaker 0: My hat is
Speaker 0: off.".
Speaker 0: "It also looks like it was made in the
Speaker 0: 70s.".
Speaker 1: "So I don't want to let this become the whole episode, so we're not gonna let this
Speaker 1: happen.".
Speaker 1: "This is not the whole episode, although we could do a whole episode on
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 0: "I don't know what Scott's doing, so I'm ready to make it a whole episode.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna
Speaker 0: ravel.".
Speaker 1: "No, there's a lady, and there's a hubbub on the internet.
Speaker 1: I think it was a lady,
Speaker 1: anyway.".
Speaker 1: "So she was at Bloomingdale's, right?
Speaker 1: The original Bloomingdale's,
Speaker 1: right?".
Speaker 1: "And she had her nine-year-old kid with her,
Speaker 1: "And she lived somewhere, you know, like you had to take the subway and then a bus--".
Speaker 0: "Oh, I know what this
Speaker 0: is.".
Speaker 1: "--to get to her house,
Speaker 1: right?".
Speaker 1: "So her kid was nine years old, and, you know, she's like, 'You know
Speaker 1: what?'.
Speaker 1: "And she gave him a metro card, right?
Speaker 1: And some money.
Speaker 1: And, you know, she knew where the address
Speaker 1: is.".
Speaker 1: "And she says, 'All right, I'm going.
Speaker 1: You find your own way
Speaker 1: home.'.
Speaker 1: And, of course, the kid got
Speaker 1: home.".
Speaker 1: "And, of course, you know, half of the people in the world--I don't know if it's half, but there's one
Speaker 1: contingent.".
Speaker 1: "And the contingent's like, 'You're crazy!
Speaker 1: You should be in jail letting your kid, nine-year-old kid alone in the
Speaker 1: city.'".
Speaker 1: "Oh my
Speaker 1: God!".
Speaker 1: "And the other half of the people are like, 'Yeah!
Speaker 0: Woo!'".
Speaker 0: "The funny thing is, I actually see a lot of young kids just, like, taking the bus or taking the
Speaker 0: subway.".
Speaker 0: "Well, yeah.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 1: know.".
Speaker 1: "But, you know, really, I'm obviously--all I'll say for now is I'm definitely on the side of letting the kids roam
Speaker 1: free.".
Speaker 1: "You know what I
Speaker 1: mean?".
Speaker 1: "Well, with that reason--".
Speaker 1: "I'm not going to start the argument.
Speaker 1: Basically, if you want to know why I'm on this side, watch The
Speaker 1: Sandlot.".
Speaker 0: "I think the base issue--again, we won't make this whole show, but to kind of put it into a very clear--".
Speaker 0: "The issue that always comes up with us is that kids want to have fun, because that's what kids
Speaker 0: do.".
Speaker 0: "And it seems like in a lot of places, adults will systematically take away or downplay every possible safe or interesting or harmless thing that kids could
Speaker 0: "And then they wonder why the kids start doing the harmful
Speaker 0: things.".
Speaker 0: "It's like, 'Alright, I'm a kid, and I want to go ride my bikes and hang out with my
Speaker 0: friends.'".
Speaker 0: "Oh, can't go outside by myself
Speaker 0: unsupervised.".
Speaker 0: "Alright, I want a
Speaker 0: skateboard.".
Speaker 0: "Oh, it's dangerous, and there's laws against it in a lot of
Speaker 0: places.".
Speaker 0: "Fine, I'll go to the
Speaker 0: arcade.".
Speaker 0: "No more
Speaker 0: arcades.".
Speaker 0: "Go to the roller
Speaker 0: rink.".
Speaker 0: "Shut down, because we don't want kids going
Speaker 0: there.".
Speaker 0: "Alright, I'll play video
Speaker 0: games.".
Speaker 0: "Video games make you a
Speaker 0: murderer.".
Speaker 1: "Stop sitting in the house all the time playing video
Speaker 1: games.".
Speaker 0: "But don't go
Speaker 0: outside.".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, don't go outside alone and
Speaker 1: roam.".
Speaker 0: "Don't smoke that
Speaker 0: weed.".
Speaker 0: "And you know what they end up
Speaker 0: on?".
Speaker 0: "They're huffing
Speaker 0: paint.".
Speaker 0: "Like Darth Vader in that anime we watched
Speaker 0: yesterday.".
Speaker 1: "Yep.".
Speaker 1: "Or drinking cough
Speaker 1: syrup.".
Speaker 0: "What was Wormy at
Speaker 0: RIT?".
Speaker 1: "He's all about the
Speaker 1: tussin.".
Speaker 0: "He made a parody
Speaker 0: video.".
Speaker 0: "I gotta see if it's
Speaker 0: online.".
Speaker 0: "If not, I feel like we should just remake
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: "You know, there used to be these anti-drug
Speaker 0: commercials.".
Speaker 0: "They were like, 'Baseball, my
Speaker 0: anti-drug.'.
Speaker 0: "Or like, 'Getting high on homework, that's my
Speaker 0: anti-drug.'".
Speaker 0: "And he made one and he's standing there all shabby looking with a bottle of
Speaker 0: NyQuil.".
Speaker 0: "And he's like, 'NyQuil, my
Speaker 0: anti-drug.'.
Speaker 0: "And he proceeds to chug it and wig
Speaker 0: out.".
Speaker 1: "To prevent this from becoming the episode, I will sum this up with one
Speaker 1: thing.".
Speaker 1: "Well, two things
Speaker 1: actually.".
Speaker 1: "Number one, I think really what the root problem is, is that the parents are actually very
Speaker 1: selfish.".
Speaker 1: "They don't, you know, there's obviously with anything you let your kid do, there's a risk of
Speaker 1: danger.".
Speaker 1: "And perhaps some reward of fun or something
Speaker 1: else.".
Speaker 1: "And the parents are
Speaker 1: selfish.".
Speaker 1: "They don't ever want to worry about their
Speaker 1: kid.".
Speaker 1: "Thus, even if the risk of something hurting their kid is incredibly
Speaker 1: small.".
Speaker 1: "They selfishly remove all risk from anything happening to their kid so that they never have to
Speaker 1: worry.".
Speaker 0: "But I mean, when I was a kid, I roamed pretty much completely
Speaker 0: free.".
Speaker 0: "Except when we lived in downtown
Speaker 0: Detroit.".
Speaker 1: "I roamed pretty freely, but
Speaker 1: anyway.".
Speaker 0: "If you live in downtown Detroit, you shouldn't be roaming too
Speaker 0: free.".
Speaker 1: "So I'm linking you to this new blog,
Speaker 1: freerangekids.wordpress.com.".
Speaker 0: "That title, while I get what they're doing, I see what they did
Speaker 0: there.".
Speaker 0: "All I can think is free range
Speaker 0: cattle.".
Speaker 1: "Right, and the tagline is 'Let's give our children the freedom we
Speaker 1: had!'.
Speaker 1: "So I'm linking you to this
Speaker 1: blog.".
Speaker 0: "That's one frightening
Speaker 0: thing.".
Speaker 1: "You should pay attention to this
Speaker 1: blog.".
Speaker 0: "How
Speaker 0: come?".
Speaker 0: "Alright, I was in high school a long time
Speaker 0: ago.".
Speaker 0: "God, like a decade
Speaker 0: "And you know
Speaker 0: what?".
Speaker 0: "When I got out of high school-".
Speaker 1: "Stop, you're turning the whole episode into
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 0: "I gotta say
Speaker 0: this.".
Speaker 0: "I remember thinking back, and now when I go, 'Wow, all the freedoms I had in high school are gone, and high school
Speaker 0: sucks.'".
Speaker 0: "But then, I remember when I was in high school, my parents said to me," "'Wow, all the freedoms we had when we were in high school are gone, it must suck for you to be in high
Speaker 0: school.'".
Speaker 1: "There are many causes, I think the number one cause is the
Speaker 1: media.".
Speaker 1: "Okay, let's go on with the
Speaker 1: episode.".
Speaker 0: "Of course, I'm glad there's no more smoking deck in my high
Speaker 0: school.".
Speaker 0: "Me too, me
Speaker 0: too.".
Speaker 0: "So what is the
Speaker 0: episode?".
Speaker 1: "Some things were good to get rid
Speaker 1: of.".
Speaker 0: "This is more of a hot button issue for Scott, but I have a much more academic position on
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, uh, I don't know, what was the, I forget, what was the
Speaker 1: topic?".
Speaker 1: "You really forget?
Speaker 0: You wanted to do
Speaker 0: it?".
Speaker 0: "I was all fine with doing Seinfeld, or what if I was a
Speaker 0: spaceship?".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, uh, what was it, I forget, uh...".
Speaker 0: "The, uh, the
Speaker 0: Olympics?".
Speaker 0: "Oh,
Speaker 0: right.".
Speaker 0: "For
Speaker 0: chance?".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, Olympics,
Speaker 1: alright.".
Speaker 0: "You wanna summarize, or shall
Speaker 0: I?".
Speaker 1: "Well, we should talk about the Olympics first, and then obviously-".
Speaker 0: "Alright, so-".
Speaker 1: "We're gonna talk about the current events
Speaker 1: Olympics.".
Speaker 0: "So a long time ago, the Kingdom of Tibet-".
Speaker 1: "Well, no, a long time ago,
Speaker 1: Athens.".
Speaker 1: "Athens, Greek, discuses, tracks and fields,
Speaker 1: awesomeness.".
Speaker 0: "Alright, Scott, I'm curious, what is the continuity, uh, I'm curious how much you know about the
Speaker 0: Olympics?".
Speaker 0: "Between the ancient Greek Olympics, and the modern Olympics, 'cause there's no direct
Speaker 0: continuity.".
Speaker 1: "No, there isn't,
Speaker 1: basically.".
Speaker 0: "So when did the modern Olympics movement
Speaker 0: start?".
Speaker 0: "Ish, I don't need a year, I want like, a half, like a double decade, I'd be fine with, maybe even a
Speaker 0: century.".
Speaker 1: "Oh, it's definitely the 20th
Speaker 1: century.".
Speaker 1: "Okay.".
Speaker 1: "Um, it was probably in the 30s, maybe the
Speaker 1: 40s.".
Speaker 0: "France had a lot to do with
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 1: "Yeah.".
Speaker 0: "It was definitely before World War
Speaker 0: II.".
Speaker 1: "I know, it was before World War II, that's why I was saying 30s and
Speaker 1: 40s.".
Speaker 0: "Because I gotta say, my favorite thing, is the, so many people, when all this hubbub began, were saying things, and I saw-" "There's a picture on FARC, of a guy holding up a sign, that says, 'Would we have gone to the Olympics with
Speaker 0: Hitler?'".
Speaker 0: "And it's like, uh-".
Speaker 1: "No, we didn't go to the Olympics with Hitler, in
Speaker 1: fact.".
Speaker 0: "Well, we did, and we
Speaker 0: won.".
Speaker 1: "Oh, no, I, oh, sorry, did Hitler not go to the Olympics with
Speaker 1: us?".
Speaker 0: "We went to the Olympics, Nazi Germany, and we
Speaker 0: won.".
Speaker 0: "Well, it's actually more complicated than that, but, anyway,
Speaker 0: continue.".
Speaker 1: "Oh, I was right, the Russians, we didn't go at
Speaker 1: all.".
Speaker 1: "Yes.".
Speaker 1: "And they didn't go with us either, four years
Speaker 1: later.".
Speaker 0: "Yes, the Soviets was the problem, not so much the, uh,
Speaker 0: Nazis.".
Speaker 1: "But anyway, I'm not gonna teach you the history of the Olympics, because, uh, as we have just demonstrated, I am not a scholar on
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 1: "I am more of a-".
Speaker 0: "Not that I am either, I was just in the position of being the accuser, thus being immune to all, uh,
Speaker 0: inquiry.".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, what year did it start,
Speaker 1: Rem?".
Speaker 0: "Odd
Speaker 0: 8.".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, uh, was
Speaker 1: it?".
Speaker 0: "Anyway,
Speaker 0: continue.".
Speaker 1: "Did you just look that
Speaker 1: up?".
Speaker 0: "Just
Speaker 0: continue.".
Speaker 1: "Anyway, I knew it was the early 20th century, but anyway, the Olympics, on paper, I feel, are really
Speaker 1: awesome.".
Speaker 1: "In that, you basically have a competition, uh, of, it's a friendly competition though, not a horrible war, it's a competition of
Speaker 1: greatness.".
Speaker 1: "And it's basically, you know, humans showing what humans have achieved, you know, in terms of the human body, in the whole world getting together, and sort of being like, yeah, people are awesome, all at
Speaker 1: once.".
Speaker 1: "And that's what the Olympics is on paper.
Speaker 1: And, on paper, I like the Olympics a lot, even though, from event to event, I find some events more qualified than
Speaker 1: others.".
Speaker 1: "For example, um, a really good Olympic event, the
Speaker 1: javelin.".
Speaker 1: "A really bad Olympic event,
Speaker 1: curling.".
Speaker 0: "What's wrong with
Speaker 0: curling?".
Speaker 1: "Shush.".
Speaker 0: "What you always, you always bring up, we'll have a nice conversation, we'll have a nice dinner, and then out of the blue, you'll disparage
Speaker 0: curling.".
Speaker 1: "That's
Speaker 1: right.".
Speaker 0: "Curling's
Speaker 0: fine.".
Speaker 1: "Curling is my...".
Speaker 0: "The only problem with curling, curling, curling, is the fact that I remember a few years ago, there seemed to be this kind of concentrated media effort to make curling
Speaker 0: popular.".
Speaker 0: "And I saw this, like they were trying to get people to care about curling.
Speaker 0: It obviously failed, and I haven't seen them try it since, but ever since then, Scott has just bitched and moaned about
Speaker 0: curling.".
Speaker 1: "I never liked
Speaker 1: curling.".
Speaker 0: "Maybe it's because, I don't know, in Michigan, we'd curl sometimes.
Speaker 0: It's not that bad of a
Speaker 0: sport.".
Speaker 1: "They should replace curling with candlestick bowling.
Speaker 1: That's all I'm gonna
Speaker 1: say.".
Speaker 0: "I think they're equivalent
Speaker 0: sports.".
Speaker 1: "No, I think candlestick bowling...".
Speaker 0: "Have you ever been candlestick
Speaker 0: bowling?"?
Speaker 1: "No.".
Speaker 0: "Have you ever been
Speaker 0: curling?"?
Speaker 1: "Yes.".
Speaker 1: "When?".
Speaker 1: "One
Speaker 1: time.".
Speaker 1: "When?".
Speaker 1: "My friend's dad was all
Speaker 1: curling.".
Speaker 0: "What position did you
Speaker 0: play?".
Speaker 1: "I threw the little rock.
Speaker 0: One
Speaker 0: time.".
Speaker 0: "How big was the
Speaker 0: rock?".
Speaker 1: "Big and
Speaker 1: heavy.".
Speaker 1: "Real
Speaker 1: big.".
Speaker 0: "Anyway...".
Speaker 1: "Bigger than I can pick
Speaker 1: up.".
Speaker 0: "So, the Olympics...".
Speaker 1: "I just sorta had to shuffle it out
Speaker 1: there.".
Speaker 0: "Which would've begun in
Speaker 0: 1894.".
Speaker 1: "Yep.".
Speaker 1: "Oh, really?
Speaker 1: Wow.".
Speaker 1: "Damn, I was off by six
Speaker 1: years.".
Speaker 1: "So, on paper, I like the
Speaker 1: Olympics.".
Speaker 0: "Six years?
Speaker 0: Anyway, go
Speaker 0: on.".
Speaker 0: "You were like, yeah, the '20s, the
Speaker 0: '30s?".
Speaker 1: "No, but I mean, I guess the century,
Speaker 1: right?".
Speaker 1: "Anyway, on paper, they're awesome,
Speaker 1: "In reality, in recent years at least, they're not as
Speaker 1: awesome.".
Speaker 1: "Because, basically, in addition to the on-paper parts of the Olympics,".
Speaker 1: "they have sort of added this, you know, just like every other sport in the world,".
Speaker 1: "the consumerism, the marketing, the sponsorship, the money, the corporatism...".
Speaker 0: "The level of just violent aggression that the International Olympic Committee" "has taken toward the trademarks, the copyrights, the broadcast rights,".
Speaker 0: "of something that nominally should be available to all the people of the
Speaker 0: world.".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, if anything, right, if you look at the spirit of the Olympics,".
Speaker 1: "you have to say, 'This is something that everyone in the world should be able to take part in at no
Speaker 1: cost.'".
Speaker 1: "Just, you know, sort of a coming together of all the peoples and saying, 'People are
Speaker 1: awesome.'".
Speaker 1: "Hooray.".
Speaker 0: "But, instead, the Olympics are this...".
Speaker 0: "I mean, I remember stories of, like, Olympic diners, you know, 'cause Greece and such,".
Speaker 0: "run by Greek people, being shut down by the Olympics as they move into a given city,".
Speaker 0: "because they're so crazy about their copyrights and their trademarks and their
Speaker 0: whatchamacallits.".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, it's really not
Speaker 1: cool.".
Speaker 0: "Also the fact that, I'll admit I have a selfish reason, in the
Speaker 0: U.S.,
Speaker 0: we get completely gypped on the
Speaker 0: Olympics.".
Speaker 0: "We don't get to see any Olympic sport that I care about at
Speaker 0: all.".
Speaker 1: "If you have a satellite dish, I'm pretty sure you can watch all the cool
Speaker 1: events.".
Speaker 0: "Yes, if I have a satellite
Speaker 0: dish.".
Speaker 1: "But if you don't have a dish, you're pretty much on network TV,".
Speaker 1: "unless you watch, like, during the day, you can see some cool events, maybe,".
Speaker 1: "but mostly you're just gonna see the U.S.
Speaker 1: people participating,".
Speaker 1: "especially the ones who are probably gonna
Speaker 1: win.".
Speaker 0: "And even then, only in the sports that they think Americans care
Speaker 0: about.".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, or the sports that they think they can market and make
Speaker 1: popular.".
Speaker 1: "Or in the championship
Speaker 1: rounds.".
Speaker 1: "You're never gonna see, like, you know, the low-end rounds,".
Speaker 1: "like, you know, the first heats,".
Speaker 1: "or, like, you know, the qualifiers or anything like
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 1: "You're only gonna see, like, the big ones,".
Speaker 1: "like, whoever wins this gets a gold medal, oh my
Speaker 1: God.".
Speaker 1: "Anyway, the second thing about the Olympics is that,".
Speaker 1: "if you really think about it, and think about it hard,".
Speaker 1: "the Olympics is the only,".
Speaker 1: "even though it's not, you know, following its spirit,".
Speaker 1: "it's the only world stage,
Speaker 1: really.".
Speaker 1: "I mean, what other, if you wanted to somehow get a message out,".
Speaker 1: "to the whole civilized world,".
Speaker 1: "every continent, every country,
Speaker 1: right?".
Speaker 1: "Pretty much every
Speaker 1: country.".
Speaker 1: "Even if you make a speech at the U.N.
Speaker 1: or something,".
Speaker 1: "it's not gonna get out there unless it's so...".
Speaker 0: "Even if, I don't think anyone out there could even name".
Speaker 0: "anyone who works for the
Speaker 0: U.N.".
Speaker 0: "Right.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's really, really hard" "to get a message out to the whole world,".
Speaker 1: "but the Olympics, you know, being as they are a sport,".
Speaker 1: "they are circuses.
Speaker 1: I mean, people pay attention to circuses".
Speaker 1: "a lot more than they do to, you know, politics and things and
Speaker 1: war.".
Speaker 1: "So, if you can...".
Speaker 0: "And
Speaker 0: bread.".
Speaker 1: "Right.
Speaker 1: So, if you can get your message" "attached to the world circus,".
Speaker 1: "which is pretty much what the Olympics is,".
Speaker 1: "the only world circus,".
Speaker 1: "that is a way to get your message out to the whole world,".
Speaker 1: "that is more effective than perhaps
Speaker 1: anything.".
Speaker 1: "And thus, throughout the history of the Olympics," "many protests and many world issues" "have attached themselves to the
Speaker 1: Olympics.".
Speaker 1: "And I don't think that, you know, think about, you know,".
Speaker 1: "the Black Panthers, you know,".
Speaker 1: "Russia not going to us, us not going to Russia,".
Speaker 1: "you know, Nazi Germany, the killing of the Israelis,".
Speaker 1: "remember that, the little terrorism going
Speaker 1: on?".
Speaker 0: "Very clear details.
Speaker 0: I wrote a paper on it in high
Speaker 0: school.".
Speaker 0: "Right.".
Speaker 1: "All these things have attached themselves to the Olympics,".
Speaker 1: "and while many of them are terrible and some of them are good,".
Speaker 1: "I think that is also part of the spirit of the new Olympics,".
Speaker 1: "not so much, you know, the Athenian Olympics,".
Speaker 1: "but the new Olympics, I think that, you know,".
Speaker 1: "using it as a stage to get a message to the world" "is also, you know, part of what the Olympics
Speaker 1: is.".
Speaker 1: "Now, that brings us to today,".
Speaker 1: "where we have the shit going down in
Speaker 1: Tibet.".
Speaker 1: "Basically...".
Speaker 0: "That was a very eloquent way of putting
Speaker 0: that.".
Speaker 1: "I think that's the only way to put
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 0: "Yeah.
Speaker 0: Now, the thing is,".
Speaker 0: "the Tibet issue is not, shall we say,
Speaker 0: new.".
Speaker 1: "No, it is quite...".
Speaker 0: "This has been going on for some
Speaker 0: time.".
Speaker 1: "No, also the Chinese human rights issue in general,".
Speaker 1: "is not
Speaker 1: new.".
Speaker 1: "In fact, it's as old as, um,
Speaker 1: Mao.".
Speaker 0: "Now, there...".
Speaker 0: "It's all about Chiang
Speaker 0: Kai-shek.".
Speaker 1: "But unlike Mao, it is not
Speaker 1: dead.".
Speaker 0: "Rofl
Speaker 0: Mao?".
Speaker 1: "Yes.
Speaker 1: Only without the
Speaker 1: rofling.".
Speaker 0: "I think we should preface all of this by,".
Speaker 0: "I don't really want to talk about the history of
Speaker 0: China.".
Speaker 0: "I don't want to talk about the history of the
Speaker 0: Olympics.".
Speaker 0: "I don't want to talk about the history of
Speaker 0: Tibet.".
Speaker 0: "I don't want to talk about the...".
Speaker 0: "Because there's also a really important conflated issue,".
Speaker 0: "that on one hand, the human rights issues" "have always been kind of a nagging sore point".
Speaker 0: "with a lot of people in the
Speaker 0: world.".
Speaker 0: "At least in the
Speaker 0: West.".
Speaker 0: "Because, as we discovered," "there were violent protests everywhere the torch went,".
Speaker 0: "until it got to South America,".
Speaker 0: "and then no one gave a
Speaker 0: shit.".
Speaker 0: "And there was no protest at
Speaker 0: all.".
Speaker 1: "Yep.
Speaker 1: I mean, I...".
Speaker 1: "I'm gonna say it right
Speaker 1: now.".
Speaker 1: "Human rights in China is
Speaker 1: ass.".
Speaker 1: "China needs to clean that shit
Speaker 1: up.".
Speaker 0: "The thing is, I have all these other things to talk
Speaker 0: about.".
Speaker 0: "Like, China and India are in a similar vote,".
Speaker 0: "but yet they're handling everything completely
Speaker 0: differently.".
Speaker 0: "And yet also, there's a conflated issue,".
Speaker 0: "of that a lot of people in America,".
Speaker 0: "in Europe in particular,".
Speaker 0: "while, nominally, they're against the human rights violations,".
Speaker 0: "and while, popularly, they're against the oppression of Tibet,".
Speaker 0: "because the Tibet thing is a very popular issue to be behind,".
Speaker 0: "rather or not, I mean, I'm behind it too,".
Speaker 0: "but a lot of people, I think, are behind it,".
Speaker 0: "because it's a very easy thing to be
Speaker 0: for.".
Speaker 1: "Well, I mean, it's sort of, it's one of those things,".
Speaker 1: "where it's so outrageously one person is wrong,".
Speaker 1: "and one person is right, or so it seems,".
Speaker 1: "and the fact that the person who's right is not winning," "is just like, come
Speaker 1: on!".
Speaker 0: "But there's this conflating factor,".
Speaker 0: "that a lot of people, in America in particular," "are very paranoid about China anyway, economically,".
Speaker 0: "especially because the American economy,".
Speaker 0: "if you haven't noticed, is in the pooper,".
Speaker 0: "in years that Dave and Joel
Speaker 0: isn't.".
Speaker 0: "Relatively
Speaker 0: speaking."
Speaker 0: "Well, it depends on where you live,".
Speaker 0: "but the dollar is falling like a rock,".
Speaker 0: "and China has actually been playing hardball,".
Speaker 0: "in that their currency is undervalued,".
Speaker 0: "compared to the dollar,".
Speaker 0: "and there's all this shady stuff going on,".
Speaker 0: "and I think a lot of people who say they're for Tibet,".
Speaker 0: "and against the human rights violations," "and are jumping on the Olympics bandwagon," "actually are just xenophobic".
Speaker 0: "about China's emergence as an economic power,".
Speaker 0: "and this is kind of--".
Speaker 0: "I'm not saying the majority,".
Speaker 0: "but I know there are people like
Speaker 0: this.".
Speaker 1: "I'm sure there are some people like that,".
Speaker 1: "but I think the majority of people--".
Speaker 0: "Because the level of misinformation".
Speaker 0: "I've seen from a lot of the pictures".
Speaker 0: "of people with protest signs at the
Speaker 0: torch.".
Speaker 0: "Plus, but let's get--".
Speaker 1: "I think what it is is that, you know,".
Speaker 1: "Tibet has always been an issue".
Speaker 1: "that people all knew about, right,".
Speaker 1: "and they were all on the side of Tibet,".
Speaker 1: "or at least, you know,".
Speaker 1: "but there was never really an opportunity" "to do something about it,".
Speaker 1: "until the Olympics happened to be scheduled in Beijing,".
Speaker 1: "and now, you know,".
Speaker 1: "if they would have acted way long ago,".
Speaker 1: "like when the Olympics were first announced to be there,".
Speaker 1: "then they could have just moved them,".
Speaker 1: "but now it's sort of like,".
Speaker 1: "haha, it's too late, let's
Speaker 1: go!".
Speaker 0: "They could have always moved them to Peking,".
Speaker 0: "Nah, because at my work,".
Speaker 0: "someone made fun of someone else,".
Speaker 0: "by making a joke like that,".
Speaker 0: "because the other person--".
Speaker 1: "I can see how that can be a funny
Speaker 1: joke.".
Speaker 0: "The other person didn't know,".
Speaker 0: "and the person making the joke" "made it with the look in the eyes,".
Speaker 0: "that I've seen this look before,".
Speaker 0: "of I know that no one gets this joke from me,".
Speaker 0: "and they have the chortle of self-satisfaction,".
Speaker 0: "but I got it, so I look him in the eye,".
Speaker 0: "and I chortle,".
Speaker 0: "and then we started laughing out loud,".
Speaker 0: "and the third person's like,".
Speaker 0: "What?
Speaker 0: What the hell's wrong with
Speaker 0: you?".
Speaker 0: "What?".
Speaker 1: "I got the joke on a delay,".
Speaker 1: "because I didn't see it
Speaker 1: coming.".
Speaker 1: "You snuck it in there a little
Speaker 1: quickly.".
Speaker 0: "Because I've been thinking about it all day,".
Speaker 0: "it was really
Speaker 0: funny.".
Speaker 1: "It was a good joke,
Speaker 1: yeah.".
Speaker 0: "So I totally stole it,".
Speaker 0: "I don't think I made that
Speaker 0: up.".
Speaker 1: "It's like the Olympics are in Beijing,".
Speaker 1: "and there's all these protests,".
Speaker 1: "oh, why don't they just move them to
Speaker 1: Peking?".
Speaker 0: "Yes, that scout was the
Speaker 0: joke.".
Speaker 1: "I know,
Speaker 1: right?".
Speaker 0: "But I also don't want to--".
Speaker 0: "Well, I guess I kind of have to talk,".
Speaker 0: "but the way I look at this,".
Speaker 0: "there's a lot of ways to look at the Olympic protests,".
Speaker 0: "I would be against the protests of the Olympics,".
Speaker 0: "on the grounds that the Olympics are supposed to be,".
Speaker 0: "in theory, this worldwide coming together,".
Speaker 0: "despite
Speaker 0: everything.".
Speaker 0: "Nothing should stop the Olympics,".
Speaker 0: "except the Cold War,".
Speaker 0: "because we were dumbasses,".
Speaker 0: "but I
Speaker 0: digress.".
Speaker 0: "But at the same time, the Olympics are so corporate,".
Speaker 0: "and so money-driven,".
Speaker 0: "that I have almost no sympathy for the IOC,".
Speaker 0: "or the Olympics at all,".
Speaker 0: "and the only people I have any sympathy at all for,".
Speaker 0: "are the
Speaker 0: athletes.".
Speaker 1: "Right, I think, really, I'm totally--".
Speaker 1: "And not even the athletes in the West,".
Speaker 0: "only the athletes from those countries,".
Speaker 0: "where the Olympics are a big
Speaker 0: deal.".
Speaker 0: "Like, the guy from the poor country,".
Speaker 0: "in the Serbia area or in Africa,".
Speaker 0: "who trains his whole life,".
Speaker 0: "and he's the only person from his country,".
Speaker 0: "representing them in one race,".
Speaker 0: "and he gets the
Speaker 0: bronze.".
Speaker 0: "That's a big deal to those
Speaker 0: people.".
Speaker 1: "But at the same time--".
Speaker 1: "I feel bad, though,
Speaker 1: also.".
Speaker 1: "The Olympics is every four years,".
Speaker 1: "so if you participate in one of those sports,".
Speaker 1: "you have maybe two, three
Speaker 1: tries.".
Speaker 1: "Three tries is crazy,".
Speaker 1: "to win a gold medal,".
Speaker 1: "because after that, you're going to be too
Speaker 1: old.".
Speaker 0: "Most of these sports, too,".
Speaker 0: "have no other serious outlet,".
Speaker 0: "other than the
Speaker 0: Olympics.".
Speaker 0: "There's sports like hockey,".
Speaker 0: "where the NHL is where all the real hockey players" "end up,".
Speaker 1: "I think the only--".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, but the gold medal in hockey is pretty
Speaker 1: meaningful.".
Speaker 0: "Yes, but what I'm saying is that,".
Speaker 0: "a lot of other sports,".
Speaker 0: "there aren't these gigantic places".
Speaker 0: "to prove that you're the best,".
Speaker 0: "where people will
Speaker 0: notice.".
Speaker 1: "They do, but no one
Speaker 1: notices.".
Speaker 1: "They're like the World Cup or whatever,".
Speaker 0: "but they're like--".
Speaker 0: "Well, that's not a good example,".
Speaker 0: "because the whole world notices that,".
Speaker 0: "just not
Speaker 0: us.".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, pretty
Speaker 1: much.".
Speaker 1: "Anyway, so I feel bad--".
Speaker 1: "Look, there's a guy in the US,".
Speaker 1: "who may be the greatest swimmer ever,".
Speaker 1: "and he's going to the Olympics this year,".
Speaker 1: "and he could win,".
Speaker 1: "he could prove that he's the best swimmer ever,".
Speaker 1: "but if the Olympics don't happen,".
Speaker 1: "or in some way damaged,".
Speaker 1: "he's not going to have another shot,".
Speaker 1: "to prove he's the best swimmer
Speaker 1: ever.".
Speaker 1: "I mean, imagine if for some reason--".
Speaker 1: "We know Tiger Woods is probably the best golfer ever,".
Speaker 1: "but he is still--".
Speaker 1: "He's on his way to winning more than anyone else
Speaker 1: ever.".
Speaker 1: "What if suddenly the PGA is canceled,".
Speaker 1: "because of people attacking it for something the PGA didn't
Speaker 1: do?".
Speaker 1: "Then that's like--".
Speaker 1: "I don't feel bad for maybe the PGA,".
Speaker 1: "but I feel bad for Tiger
Speaker 1: Woods.".
Speaker 0: "Yeah, because then at the same time,".
Speaker 0: "it's like, yeah, the IOC, they did agree to put it in
Speaker 0: Beijing.".
Speaker 1: "Right, they did, I
Speaker 1: know.".
Speaker 0: "It's not like they couldn't have foreseen this
Speaker 0: happening.".
Speaker 1: "So it's like, if athletes are whipping out Tibetan flags,".
Speaker 1: "totally
Speaker 1: awesome.".
Speaker 1: "And people running with the torch,".
Speaker 1: "whipping out Tibetan flags--".
Speaker 0: "Which has already
Speaker 0: happened.".
Speaker 1: "Totally awesome,
Speaker 1: right?".
Speaker 1: "People trying to put out the torch,".
Speaker 1: "that goes a little over the line for me,".
Speaker 1: "because you're assaulting this person,".
Speaker 1: "who just wants to carry a
Speaker 1: torch.".
Speaker 1: "People standing near the torch protesting,".
Speaker 1: "totally
Speaker 1: awesome.".
Speaker 1: "To me--" "People going to the Olympics and
Speaker 1: protesting.".
Speaker 0: "It always bothers me that whenever there's a real issue,".
Speaker 0: "that you could really--".
Speaker 0: "like, there's an easy way to stand behind it,".
Speaker 0: "and protest or
Speaker 0: anything.".
Speaker 0: "It seems like the majority of people protest,".
Speaker 0: "in this really shoddy, just-making-themselves,".
Speaker 0: "almost-look-bad
Speaker 0: way.".
Speaker 0: "To me, the best protest they could have had," "is if no one attacked the torch,".
Speaker 0: "and there weren't these giant yelling
Speaker 0: mobs.".
Speaker 0: "If there was just--".
Speaker 1: "If no one showed
Speaker 1: up.".
Speaker 0: "Or just a silent crowd turns its back,".
Speaker 0: "as they present the
Speaker 0: torch.".
Speaker 1: "See, there you
Speaker 1: go.".
Speaker 0: "But no one does anything cool like that,".
Speaker 0: "No one really
Speaker 0: protests.".
Speaker 1: "But because, to do something complicated,".
Speaker 1: "with the larger group you have,".
Speaker 1: "it becomes more and more
Speaker 1: difficult.".
Speaker 1: "That's why you can get a million people to chant,".
Speaker 1: "like, 'Kill, kill, kill,' but it's--".
Speaker 1: "Or, 'Free Tibet,' but--".
Speaker 0: "It's a lot harder to get them to
Speaker 0: chant.".
Speaker 0: "It's a lot harder to get--".
Speaker 0: "Come and see the violence inherent in the
Speaker 0: system.".
Speaker 1: "And it's even harder to get them to say,".
Speaker 1: "E to the X, T, X, T, Y, to--".
Speaker 0: "1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 9, Z, K, N, cosine, tangent, sine--".
Speaker 1: "Aye, aye, times 3,
Speaker 1: anyway.".
Speaker 0: "Let's go, let's go, we totally stole that from
Speaker 0: MIT.".
Speaker 1: "Yeah!".
Speaker 1: "I love
Speaker 1: RIT.".
Speaker 1: "Yep.".
Speaker 1: "So, the thing is, this whole thing,".
Speaker 1: "and totally for free in Tibet,".
Speaker 1: "I really don't know why China tries to hold on Tibet,".
Speaker 1: "it just makes them look bad, it doesn't get them
Speaker 1: much.".
Speaker 1: "But, really, some of the protesters,".
Speaker 1: "I feel like there is the spirit of the Olympics,".
Speaker 1: "and the athletes participating in the Olympics," "have been made a victim, perhaps
Speaker 1: unnecessarily.".
Speaker 0: "But, at the same time,".
Speaker 0: "I feel as though the spirit of the Olympics," "has been all but dead for a long, long
Speaker 0: time.".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, and I think what they're sort of doing,".
Speaker 1: "is they're going and kicking the tombstone over it,".
Speaker 1: "and I'm like,
Speaker 1: 'Ahh.'".
Speaker 1: "Plus, at the same time," "Don't make me feel
Speaker 1: worse.".
Speaker 0: "There is kind of the idea,".
Speaker 0: "I'm not advocating anything,".
Speaker 0: "but the idea that,".
Speaker 0: "well, if something is morally opposed to you,".
Speaker 0: "it's almost like you look at cultural relativism,".
Speaker 0: "like, if there's something bad going on,".
Speaker 0: "why should you respect someone,".
Speaker 0: "like, alright, let's not talk about this for today,".
Speaker 0: "and just chill,".
Speaker 0: "and I'll ignore the bad thing,".
Speaker 0: "and then we'll talk about the bad thing again
Speaker 0: tomorrow.".
Speaker 0: "I feel like the freedom of speech always
Speaker 0: trumps.".
Speaker 1: "Well, I think the reason that in the end,".
Speaker 1: "I have to go to the protester's side,".
Speaker 1: "even though I feel the spirit of the Olympics," "is an unfair victim,".
Speaker 1: "is that if you told me that sacrificing the Olympics,".
Speaker 1: "would free Tibet,".
Speaker 1: "make the Olympics a martyr,".
Speaker 1: "Tibet is free,".
Speaker 1: "I'd say,
Speaker 1: okay.".
Speaker 1: "That's a good trade
Speaker 1: there.".
Speaker 0: "That's
Speaker 0: fair.".
Speaker 0: "It's just,".
Speaker 0: "I always err on freedom of speech anyway,".
Speaker 0: "and regardless of all of it,".
Speaker 0: "I feel as though,".
Speaker 1: "Freedom of speech, ironically enough," "something China doesn't
Speaker 1: have.".
Speaker 0: "I also feel as though China brought this on themselves,".
Speaker 0: "not for any reason other than the fact," "that when this started,".
Speaker 0: "all China would have had to do," "was open up a dialogue,".
Speaker 0: "and say something like,".
Speaker 0: "Wow, the world has risen up,".
Speaker 0: "and said we're going to,".
Speaker 0: "let's let the Olympics happen,".
Speaker 0: "for the athletes,".
Speaker 0: "and then we're going to seriously sit down,".
Speaker 0: "and solve Tibet,".
Speaker 0: "so that everyone can be
Speaker 0: happy.".
Speaker 0: "But instead, China said," "they said these stupid
Speaker 0: statements.".
Speaker 1: "The only statement,".
Speaker 1: "they said like a hundred
Speaker 1: statements.".
Speaker 0: "They said it hurts the feelings of the Chinese,".
Speaker 0: "and one China,".
Speaker 1: "and that's all they
Speaker 1: said.".
Speaker 1: "The only non-stupid thing they said was," "you're holding the Olympics hostage,".
Speaker 1: "which is
Speaker 1: true.".
Speaker 0: "But at the same time,".
Speaker 0: "like Scott said," "if holding the Olympics hostage,".
Speaker 0: "this is for people who have been,".
Speaker 0: "so disempowered for so long,".
Speaker 0: "I mean, no matter how angry you were about Tibet,".
Speaker 0: "there was nothing you could do,".
Speaker 0: "suddenly, there's a very easy way,".
Speaker 0: "to do a lot of harm to China,".
Speaker 0: "in terms of getting something
Speaker 0: accomplished.".
Speaker 1: "The thing that really bothers me the most,".
Speaker 1: "about China in general,".
Speaker 1: "is that a lot of the things China does,".
Speaker 1: "you know, they do a lot of smart things,".
Speaker 1: "for themselves,
Speaker 1: right?".
Speaker 1: "But they do a lot of stupid things,".
Speaker 1: "for like these seemingly like reasons of
Speaker 1: pride.".
Speaker 1: "Like, why are you still acting that way with
Speaker 1: Taiwan?".
Speaker 1: "Like, just give it up and you'll be
Speaker 1: fine.".
Speaker 1: "Just say, okay, we don't
Speaker 1: care.".
Speaker 1: "Go be your own
Speaker 1: country.".
Speaker 1: "You know, it wouldn't hurt
Speaker 1: China.".
Speaker 1: "It would help them a lot to say
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 1: "But the only reason they don't is,".
Speaker 1: "you know, some nationalistic crazy
Speaker 1: reasons.".
Speaker 0: "The only smart thing they've ever done,".
Speaker 0: "in that regard was with Hong Kong,".
Speaker 0: "how they largely left Hong Kong
Speaker 0: alone.".
Speaker 1: "Yeah, if they would have just let Tibet go,".
Speaker 1: "it wouldn't hurt China, really,".
Speaker 1: "except for their
Speaker 1: pride.".
Speaker 0: "Imagine if, if I were China,".
Speaker 0: "let's say, all right,".
Speaker 0: "if I were the premier of China,".
Speaker 0: "what I would have done,".
Speaker 0: "is I would have made a big deal,".
Speaker 0: "like we're going to talk about this,".
Speaker 0: "and I would step forward and say," "you know, I've heard blah, blah, blah,".
Speaker 0: "it's time for all of this to end,".
Speaker 0: "this will be the Tibetan Olympics,".
Speaker 0: "and we will end it with the turning over,".
Speaker 0: "of civil authority to the nation of
Speaker 0: Tibet.".
Speaker 0: "Like, I would have made a big deal about
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: "That would have turned China into,".
Speaker 0: "the amount of goodwill that that would have
Speaker 0: generated.".
Speaker 1: "And if you did that,".
Speaker 1: "you wouldn't even have to clean up your civil rights,".
Speaker 1: "even though I still think you
Speaker 1: should.".
Speaker 0: "No, but China, the Olympics then,".
Speaker 0: "would have become like this historical Olympics,".
Speaker 0: "like times a
Speaker 0: billion.".
Speaker 0: "And China would stand to gain nothing,".
Speaker 0: "but, I don't know, everything,".
Speaker 0: "by doing something like that,".
Speaker 0: "but instead, you've hurt the feelings of China,".
Speaker 0: "and won China,".
Speaker 0: "and don't you dare hurt the
Speaker 0: Olympics.".
Speaker 0: "I don't know why China has,".
Speaker 0: "I don't even know what kind of accent that
Speaker 0: was.".
Speaker 0: "Don't you dare hurt the
Speaker 0: Olympics.".
Speaker 0: "You're very
Speaker 0: angry.".
Speaker 1: "And it's like, you know,".
Speaker 1: "China has all their non-free speech,".
Speaker 1: "and human rights violations and
Speaker 1: such.".
Speaker 1: I mean, that sort of made sense when you're like an evil communist dictatorship, right?
Speaker 1: And you sort of, you know, if the people know too much and they escape your propaganda, then it'll fall apart, sort of like what happened in Russia or what could happen in North Korea, which is even worse.
Speaker 0: Someday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, someday.
Speaker 0: Man, North Korea is one of the only things in the world that actually frightens me.
Speaker 0: It's pretty scary.
Speaker 0: Not because I'm afraid of their WMDs or anything, because I know they don't have anything.
Speaker 0: Just because the idea that a 1984-ish Orwellian state exists.
Speaker 0: It's right there.
Speaker 0: There are people stuck in it who probably don't know a lot about the outside world, and to date, no one's really been able to do anything about it.
Speaker 1: But China doesn't need to be doing these human rights violations today.
Speaker 1: I mean, the Internet's there.
Speaker 1: They have a great firewall, but that's really -- it's not helping.
Speaker 1: I mean, they could just give it up, and it wouldn't ruin anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's tricky, but China is a thing for another -- They would be just fine.
Speaker 1: China's a thing -- They'd be better off letting it go.
Speaker 0: For another show.
Speaker 0: Because, frankly, it's Thursday.
Speaker 0: I'm really hungry, and we have a reason to celebrate, so I kind of want to go get a whole bunch of food.
Speaker 0: Unrelated -- we got some good news in between the front bit and the second bit of the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So let's just eat?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: See you at the New York Comic-Con.
Speaker 0: Don't forget to bother the Ninja Consultants.
Speaker 1: Oh, God.
Speaker 0: This has been "Geek Nights" with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com, where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say "feeds" plural because "Geek Nights" airs four nights a week, covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com, or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says "Send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Speaker 1: "Geek Nights" is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution non-commercial, share-alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it, as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: "Geek Nights" is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.