Speaker 0: It's Wednesday December 3rd.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk a bit about the fantastic ordinary victories.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: so I've been watching the Sequel to know down my cantabile in Paris just kind of follows for the.
Speaker 1: did you finish the first one?
Speaker 0: Yes a while ago.
Speaker 1: Well, that's a lot of watching now.
Speaker 0: It's only a 24 episode show.
Speaker 0: I think it's still.
Speaker 1: that's a. you know It's a normal-sized show that takes a while.
Speaker 0: It takes.
Speaker 0: I don't know three days on a train.
Speaker 1: How many episodes do you watch?
Speaker 1: You must just be watch as immediately as one stops you start the next one skip all the openers and closers.
Speaker 0: I skip the openers and closers because honestly normally it's weird especially back in the anime club.
Speaker 0: I used to watch openers a lot more often than I do now, but I've realized that it just.
Speaker 0: it depends on the anime.
Speaker 0: I mean slayers DVD problems aside.
Speaker 0: I kind of like that opener and I'll watch it.
Speaker 1: It's okay.
Speaker 0: I'll watch it about half the time.
Speaker 1: I think there's something about if you watch the.
Speaker 1: oh at least When you watch a show at you know.
Speaker 1: if you watched it in Japan every week It wouldn't really be that much of a difference.
Speaker 1: but there's something about when you watch a show in a marathon or close to a marathon and the opener and the closer play over and over again the songs get in your head and They have some sort of additional impact when they inevitably play the song during the climax of the final episode.
Speaker 0: of course Some shows just don't have like the Nodama opener at least isn't Fantastic.
Speaker 1: is it a music show an opener and a closer or 90% music?
Speaker 1: shouldn't it be awesome?
Speaker 0: Oh, the music's good, but it's just kind of some generic cell shaded 3d stuff of instruments floating around.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's not like a all cool and stylized.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: It's not all cool and stylized.
Speaker 0: It's not that not the good kind of opener.
Speaker 0: But the only thing I have to say about Nodama in Paris is that while it's good, and I'm very much enjoying it I'll probably eventually review this kind of the show as a whole.
Speaker 0: but The problem it has is that they moved to Paris and there's all new cast other than the main two and the new cast So far is so lame compared to the original cast.
Speaker 1: well see that's something I always wonder like if that new cast had been the first cast you Experienced and then the first show was the sequel would you?
Speaker 1: is it actually a worst cast or is it just because?
Speaker 1: Attached to the first one and this is the second one that it.
Speaker 1: you know if you had watched him in reverse order would these?
Speaker 1: Do the original cast seem worse than the second?
Speaker 0: you know it's very difficult while that's probably true in this case at least so far.
Speaker 1: See I'm not saying it's always one of the other.
Speaker 1: I'm saying that it's.
Speaker 1: it's difficult to tell whether it's one of the other but like in this case it definitely just.
Speaker 0: they're not as Interesting.
Speaker 0: they're kind of like oh, we've taken characters you had before and mixed them around a little bit But they're not really that interesting or different or new.
Speaker 0: They're just there.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean, it's not as bad as the Death Note syndrome where they went from the best Protagonist or I guess antagonist depending on which side you're on and how much of a jerk you are To something kind of lame.
Speaker 1: It wasn't lame But it was.
Speaker 1: I mean if I mean imagine if Death Note was just the second half right That would still be better than the vast majority of manga If it had started with the second half characters and then turned into the first half.
Speaker 0: I think it would have been better.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like riding the smaller roller coaster before you're at the big roller.
Speaker 1: I know it's very.
Speaker 1: it's very hard to measure these things because it's it's like you want to try to measure them absolutely But it's all like relative.
Speaker 1: It's like you put your hand Wait wait wait Scott.
Speaker 0: Are you are you admitting that there is no objective truth as to what media are good and bad?
Speaker 0: No, but we're measuring here.
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 1: is the The differing emotional impact of works of entertainment based on the order in which they are consumed?
Speaker 0: Okay, and it's very interesting it is yeah, I see how you get backed out of that one.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: I didn't back.
Speaker 0: Anyway, do you have any anime news?
Speaker 1: because I don't know I have.
Speaker 1: I have a very strange comics news.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure what to make of this or I'm not?
Speaker 1: you know I'm not fully aware of all the details either right?
Speaker 1: so I'm gonna add in a lot of fluff to sort of you know.
Speaker 0: Is it the Batman's dying?
Speaker 1: Batman's dead.
Speaker 1: why gotta die?
Speaker 1: It?
Speaker 1: wasn't he dying like way back in the day when he was like an old man with his broken back in a wheelchair and Someone else's Batman?
Speaker 0: well the fourth or fifth comment on FARC about this story basically said yeah, that didn't actually happen Don't worry about I think I'm gonna quote.
Speaker 1: I forget who said this but it was one I think someone who was a writer at Marvel and he basically said your job is to Found them at the end.
Speaker 1: It's like that's the job as a Marvel or DC writer anyway.
Speaker 1: So check this out.
Speaker 1: There's a comics publisher called Devil's due press.
Speaker 1: right and I've actually I actually liked them a lot.
Speaker 1: See back in the day and not back in the day.
Speaker 1: But like in the early 2000s when I started reading comics again I actually started reading comics again because I saw Ghost in the Shell 2 the issue on the shelf and borders.
Speaker 1: but then my friend Ian took me to where the comic book store was at and You know, I started with familiar things, you know things like Voltron or Transformers or Thunder, you know familiar things like that.
Speaker 1: and Devil's due Press actually was doing the GI Joe's and the Transformers and things like that.
Speaker 1: They actually did the.
Speaker 1: you know I think the Voltron series started out as image but then went to Devil's due Press.
Speaker 1: So I've known about them for a while and they actually did a comic called drafted Remy.
Speaker 1: read that right?
Speaker 1: Ah Maybe yeah, it was the one with the the aliens coming to draft everyone on earth into the space war.
Speaker 0: Oh, I read a little bit of it and I'll be honest.
Speaker 0: I didn't like it at all.
Speaker 1: I liked it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's not like the greatest thing ever.
Speaker 1: But I just I thought it was pretty clever.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I really think the concept was good.
Speaker 0: The characters were mad.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it's like some of the.
Speaker 1: The first issue is a lot better But when you read like the whole trade It's like that they bring in the rest of the cast and not as sort of like.
Speaker 1: the first issue is a lot anyway Right, so they're not a bad comics publisher.
Speaker 1: They're doing some cool stuff, right?
Speaker 1: Now let's go over to our can studio press.
Speaker 1: they're the people that publish mouse guard and a bunch of other stuff.
Speaker 1: You know all about mouse card.
Speaker 1: No one needs to tell you right but something weird was going on.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: mouse guard was like where the fourth issue of the current series was like missing in action.
Speaker 1: It's like what the hell.
Speaker 1: and then suddenly it appeared this month like aha here it is, right?
Speaker 1: I just got it and it's like why was there this huge delay?
Speaker 1: usually You know, David Peterson's really good about and obviously When you know the situation you'll see.
Speaker 1: aha What happened here?
Speaker 1: right is there was a company called I think Kuni Ochi or Kuno Ichi.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's an American company actually not a Japanese company despite the Japanese ish name.
Speaker 1: And actually there was a guy Japanese ish.
Speaker 1: Yeah There was a guy who was in charge of devil's dew or a high up there and he left and made the company Kuni Ochi or kunai.
Speaker 1: I don't have it in front of me I don't know what.
Speaker 1: I'll just say kuno ichi for now because I like saying that.
Speaker 1: better and Recently there was some shake-ups and some you know money and some other things right and there were rumors going around.
Speaker 1: the devil's dew was Gonna buy our can studio press that does mouse guard but actually it was the Kuni Ochi that was trying to buy Arcadia studio press and then like devil's dew and our kids and Kuno Ichi were like sharing offices and they weren't sharing offices and then they like traded CEOs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so what's the end result of all this?
Speaker 1: well the end result is that mouse guard is back.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure the Kuni Ochi company is buying our cast studio press most likely or they did.
Speaker 1: I'm I couldn't get an article that actually said yes, or no.
Speaker 1: I just said you know talks this and that and Some people who were working for very closely related companies moved around and Devil's dew is sort of having some troubles in the money banks.
Speaker 1: wise you know the GI Joe comics Got the license got moved over to IDW and they're trying to come up with their own properties instead of you know Where they've traditionally relied on licensed properties, so they might they might you know be gone pretty soon.
Speaker 1: But the Kuni Ochi company owns our kids studio press and mouse guard so I don't think that's in any danger Especially considering its high qualities.
Speaker 1: You know they'll always find a home for mouse guard.
Speaker 1: there won't be a problem.
Speaker 0: Yes, I would hope because my only vested interest in this is reading the rest of mouse guard.
Speaker 1: Yeah pretty much.
Speaker 1: Yeah Man, it's just sort of like these interesting shake-ups that happen at like these little comic companies And it's like huh did you wonder like what the drama behind this was?
Speaker 1: well?
Speaker 0: It's still Nothing compared to the shake-ups and drama in the anime industry.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're even like the.
Speaker 1: the backpack company goes under and it's like what happened an anime cup.
Speaker 0: They never go under like a normal company.
Speaker 0: It's never like up.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: We're going bankrupt.
Speaker 0: Yes, it's fly.
Speaker 0: It's always like they disappear, and there's like a cryptic message on the website.
Speaker 0: And then some like if you get the cryptic message some kind of form is like I used to work there the CEO Exploded.
Speaker 1: yeah, at least with this there's like news articles on comic book websites, so it's one step up.
Speaker 0: so There's a new anime that I I saw the title a couple times But I didn't realize what it was until the second teaser trailer was announced.
Speaker 0: Isakai no say Kishi Monogatari now.
Speaker 1: It's a lot of words.
Speaker 1: I hear in Yeah, well Sorry means like side story.
Speaker 0: right you know what this is.
Speaker 0: it is a spin-off of something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, it is a spin-off of Tenshi muyo up.
Speaker 0: great why?
Speaker 1: We've only had like two or three of those already, and they were terrible I know, but it even I don't even like the regular Tenshi But I at least I know the Tenshi GXP is a thousand times worse than that even.
Speaker 0: well well the thing is well.
Speaker 0: Tenshi GXP was was far worse a sin than it could would have otherwise been because of the fact that it had Such a great opening song.
Speaker 1: it did a really great.
Speaker 1: Oh, we should put that in the episode.
Speaker 0: song was wasted MP3.
Speaker 1: we should put that in the episode so people can hear the amazing opener of Tenshi GXP.
Speaker 0: best opening song worst anime Oh my god.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like the noir syndrome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that had a really good opening song.
Speaker 0: Well it was no K anime that went downhill a lot better than Tenshi GXP.
Speaker 0: yes.
Speaker 0: However, I point out that Tenshi GXP started low and didn't have anywhere to go from.
Speaker 0: Noir started real high and took exactly one episode to ruin everything.
Speaker 0: yeah The popcorn was like the last cool moment wasn't that?
Speaker 0: like an episode two.
Speaker 0: I don't remember anyway, so yes They're making.
Speaker 0: here's the deal.
Speaker 0: no Tenshi characters are even in.
Speaker 0: this doesn't look like it's in an altar So it's Photon.
Speaker 0: It's even worse than that.
Speaker 0: Tenshi Masaki is not the main character.
Speaker 0: instead Kenshi Masaki his half brother hitherto unknown is the main character.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, but it does nothing to do with the characters that people care about.
Speaker 0: no and furthermore I.
Speaker 1: so this is like if I made a transformers right and it doesn't have optimus dime.
Speaker 1: it's about Rob to miss dime and Degetre on.
Speaker 0: hey it could be hiding.
Speaker 0: There's a small chance.
Speaker 0: It could be optimus rhyme in which case it would be awesome, but that's not that that's a real thing.
Speaker 1: yes This is a made-up thing.
Speaker 0: the big difference I've always said it seems like with Tenshi in particular because remember the original tenshi Oh av was directed by person a. I forget all their names at this point I've stricken the second guy from my memory, but then The other dude directed all the other tenshi stuff, and it's like all he's been trying to do is Recapture that he even directed tenshi GXP and this new thing.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: I don't know who's directing this new thing in the tenchi in Tokyo.
Speaker 0: Oh my god Tenshi in Tokyo was.
Speaker 1: I remember I would watch tsunami But I never watched tenshi because I hated it.
Speaker 1: But I would always see the commercials like during Robotech like tenshi in Tokyo next week OMG.
Speaker 1: And I'd be like whatever see.
Speaker 1: I remember a more innocent time where and then multi would show me some robot X.
Speaker 0: I'm all tar.
Speaker 0: I miss him Horatio.
Speaker 1: I knew him But that's like you've had a space.
Speaker 1: go show about dull car and race dose.
Speaker 0: I like the tenshi OAV joke ran out.
Speaker 0: there were a lot of people really really looking forward to a tenshi in Tokyo because it's a new tenshi and It took about 30 seconds for everyone to stop pretending.
Speaker 0: It was good and admit that it was bad.
Speaker 0: But I've one more a little bit of news.
Speaker 0: this one is much more interesting and about something good for a change.
Speaker 1: Another news, what are you doing Murakami?
Speaker 0: Yeah is opening a new studio all right in LA.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh he's gonna have two floors and 30 employees.
Speaker 1: He's got the money.
Speaker 0: Yes I'm excited to see what comes of this.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it would be lots of Super flat things.
Speaker 0: see maybe he'll move one step further some sort of ultra flat.
Speaker 1: yeah, double double double plus.
Speaker 1: I don't think we've yet to maybe help.
Speaker 1: Maybe he'll start doing things that are the opposite of flat.
Speaker 0: the closest thing to a definition of super flat I've ever heard is something made by Murakami something that looks like Murakami stuff Yes, and even then looks like his super flight stuff.
Speaker 0: Yes a jet engine technology situation.
Speaker 1: oh great.
Speaker 0: So things of the day of anime news network is what it is, but an anime news Nina is awesome.
Speaker 1: But oh I gotta read some anime news Nina, but I miss them.
Speaker 0: you did, but they have done something.
Speaker 0: I don't remember if we talked about it or not, but it's over now.
Speaker 0: so instead of saying hey You should enter this I can say hey check out the winners.
Speaker 0: They had a contest to depict Hatsune Miku in whatever way you thought best And the five best would receive a really cool figurine of Hatsune Miku.
Speaker 0: And now they have posted all of the entries and the winners and the winners are really really good Isn't that something?
Speaker 1: where it's like this is the anime news network.
Speaker 1: It's a site that's supposed to report on news about anime.
Speaker 1: Hatsune Miku Really if you think about it has nothing to do with anime.
Speaker 0: I point out that she is in fact the closest link between anime in the real world We've got because she is the first step.
Speaker 0: She is Macross Plus.
Speaker 1: Hatsune Miku is a cartoon mascot.
Speaker 1: Am I wrong?
Speaker 1: No anime news network reporting on Hatsune Miku is effectively the same as if say a magazine about American television cartoons reported on the Philadelphia fanatic, you know, it's a mascot of something a cartoon mascot.
Speaker 1: It's the same thing.
Speaker 0: There's a little bit more to it than that.
Speaker 1: It happens to be Japanese.
Speaker 0: It's really well, there's a big overlap.
Speaker 0: I mean think about it.
Speaker 0: anime fandom has a huge overlap with Hatsune Miku fandom.
Speaker 1: so why?
Speaker 1: yeah, but that's the it's.
Speaker 1: it's so strange how like Mascots can have this overlap with this one fandom, but in the same fandom in other countries.
Speaker 1: the overlap doesn't happen.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends on what I mean.
Speaker 0: the Philly fanatic has very little to do with many geekeries other than sports geekery but Hatsune Miku has to do with lots of different kind of geeky fandoms because the you know people draw on the little toms and getting into the kind of Open creative content.
Speaker 0: everyone has their own take on her.
Speaker 1: I will say though if you I see lots of mr.
Speaker 1: Metz around Mr.
Speaker 0: Metz fan art.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm going to use a phrase incorrectly, but this begs the question Begs what question?
Speaker 0: um I'm sure there are erotic work.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen any erotic mr.
Speaker 1: Metz.
Speaker 1: No, I have not perhaps.
Speaker 0: We should seek some out for I'm sure I am sure that it is out there even though even a non Erotic mr..
Speaker 1: Metz has many exposed bats and balls.
Speaker 0: Anyway Scott I want you to feast your eyes over my shoulder on this stunning entry into the contest.
Speaker 1: That's mine.
Speaker 0: What are you doing?
Speaker 0: Let's just say that the quality of the entries ranges from the absurd to the good And I'll leave it at that.
Speaker 0: I will say I'm a fan of Hatsune Miku so long as she does not.
Speaker 0: I also like Hatsune Miku so long as she does Not take over a giant space station and control our society through idol music.
Speaker 1: I also like mr.
Speaker 1: Metz, but I don't actually like He sucks.
Speaker 1: Did you know the Philly fanatic was created by the same person who made Miss Piggy?
Speaker 0: No, I did not know that.
Speaker 1: I know that.
Speaker 1: see how smart I am.
Speaker 0: How did you know that?
Speaker 1: because I've read the Internet's.
Speaker 0: so what you look this up one day?
Speaker 1: No, I saw it was posted some day.
Speaker 1: Okay, all right For me this is a. this is a Nokia commercial, so just beware of that.
Speaker 1: however Basically they took an old video and appropriated it as a commercial and the old video is is good.
Speaker 1: It's like if I took I don't know all your base, and then at the end of the video I just put like geek nights.
Speaker 1: That's basically what's going on here and the video that they have decided to put Nokia at the end of the Nokia logo at the end of is a video of Bruce Lee playing ping-pong with nunchucks.
Speaker 0: Oh, I've seen that thing.
Speaker 0: that that's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: That's all you need to know.
Speaker 1: if you haven't seen enough Bruce Lee's I mean Just watch it.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I can at least tell you that I cannot find any erotic fanfiction or fan art about mr.
Speaker 0: Matt.
Speaker 1: did you find regular art of mr.
Speaker 1: Matt?
Speaker 0: not so much mostly I found pictures.
Speaker 0: however he spells Found a picture of mr.
Speaker 0: Matt and the Philly fanatic is coming up behind him to do something.
Speaker 1: actually you know you can rent.
Speaker 1: I don't know about other mascots, but I'm a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: I'm sure you can with others, but I know for a fact you can rent mr.
Speaker 1: Matt.
Speaker 1: you can just call him up and pay money and he'll show up right wherever you want him to show up.
Speaker 1: and There was to an Indian couple.
Speaker 1: they were getting married and there were huge Mets fans And they invited mr.
Speaker 1: Matt to the wedding and you can go and you can find this video of mr.
Speaker 1: Matt like having the best time in the universe at this wedding.
Speaker 1: It's like it's like the greatest thing ever.
Speaker 1: So if I you know if I married some Mets fan someday, I would consider calling mr.
Speaker 1: Matt because you know there's like a bunch of different people in the costume.
Speaker 1: obviously You know this is not the same person all the time.
Speaker 0: It would be cheaper Scott.
Speaker 0: Just get a bootleg mr.
Speaker 0: Matt costume.
Speaker 1: no The real the this because you you're not waiting for the costume you're paying for the at the best mr.
Speaker 1: Matt person.
Speaker 0: so you want the real mr.
Speaker 0: Matt.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's like not just anyone in the costume would like you know.
Speaker 0: act that way at the wedding because it's so difficult to kind Of caper around with a giant baseball on your head to keep her around properly.
Speaker 1: It's very difficult.
Speaker 0: So there's an art to it.
Speaker 1: There's that there's a certain to say qua So if you're saying if I put you in the Philly fanatic costume you could do just as good a job.
Speaker 0: You know what I think I can.
Speaker 1: you think you can?
Speaker 0: I think I can.
Speaker 1: you definitely could not.
Speaker 0: I don't think you understand.
Speaker 1: Yes, I don't think you understand how much skill is required for the proper case.
Speaker 0: You understand just how much study I have put into capering.
Speaker 1: Oh Saying you're an expert mascot.
Speaker 0: I think that I could mask out pretty well.
Speaker 1: I think you're a terrible mascot and don't even know the first thing about mascot.
Speaker 0: I know the baby.
Speaker 1: I don't think you can even deal with the heat of the costume for more than one minute.
Speaker 0: I don't think you could dance to the baby elephant walk.
Speaker 1: I could dance the baby elephant Yeah, but not in the giant costume.
Speaker 0: I think I could.
Speaker 0: good luck with that plus the man who can't even do a push.
Speaker 1: You can even giant you can even balance the baseball on your head.
Speaker 1: It would fall off your tiny neck.
Speaker 0: Do we need to call mr.
Speaker 0: Matt here and have him?
Speaker 1: You know that might not.
Speaker 1: mr.
Speaker 1: Matt doesn't talk.
Speaker 1: You really wouldn't help in deciding anything.
Speaker 0: I see this is where you do not understand the art of being mr.
Speaker 0: Matt because the artistry The Qualities come from the fact that he can convey so much meaning with no word.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: He would say is he would just say anything.
Speaker 1: that needs to be.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: Any argument any disputes ever should be decided with baseball and that is you know, it's pretty much all mr.
Speaker 1: Matt can say.
Speaker 0: well Were we to decide this by baseball?
Speaker 1: I think I would still win now because we we need eight peoples and I would just to be me and eight mr Matt's and you would be you and eight.
Speaker 0: so you're assuming that mr.
Speaker 0: Matt can play baseball.
Speaker 1: What are you talking about?
Speaker 1: He's made of baseball.
Speaker 0: being made of something does not mean you're good at it.
Speaker 1: Yes, it does.
Speaker 0: Anyway How could it not?
Speaker 0: so what are we reviewing tonight?
Speaker 1: He lives in the stadium?
Speaker 1: I think he's.
Speaker 1: he knows enough to win.
Speaker 0: I still can't find any erotic fan art So let's just move on 34.
Speaker 0: Oh My god, I'll have for channel.
Speaker 0: do it.
Speaker 0: All right, or Chen already did.
Speaker 0: ordinary victories by Manolo larcenette.
Speaker 1: Pronounce it properly.
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: It's a French dude with the French comic.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure this is just volume one and there are further volumes, but I believe he's French Belgian But either they are not in English or I do not own them.
Speaker 0: Yes, in fact, he is French Belgian and the second volume in English is available on Amazon right now.
Speaker 0: No buy it Okay.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So now I think that tells me everything you need to know about this.
Speaker 1: It is a French comic that is good enough to.
Speaker 1: where someone will buy the second volume French Belgian.
Speaker 1: oh Excuse me.
Speaker 1: Oh, maybe I should say it's not a French comic or a Franco Belgian comic.
Speaker 1: It's a bond a design a Manga and anger everyone.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right all right, so before I did realize something though because not that long ago Emily and I kind of perused through the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles OAV Mm-hmm, that might seem unrelated.
Speaker 1: Why did you do that?
Speaker 0: That might seem unrelated but I also read this comic and I realized something important about reviewing things because currently the way we review shows or Comics or any sort of media here on geek nights?
Speaker 0: Is that if it's something bad will basically say it's bad and why it's bad and spoil it But not fully because you know, we've kind of avoid spoiling things.
Speaker 1: We're reviewing things to get people to try them out or avoid and it seems to work because there's a lot of people tell us You know, oh you told me to read watchman.
Speaker 1: I bought it.
Speaker 1: You're right.
Speaker 1: You know, you told me to watch cowboy bebop.
Speaker 0: You're right and when something's good We tend to do a kind of pre like a review where we don't spoil anything because we're not trying to all we talk about it.
Speaker 1: We're trying to just try to make you excited about it enough to buy it.
Speaker 1: because yes No, it is in your best interest to do so.
Speaker 0: the problem here is that that necessitates if we want to talk about something in any real depth to either have a spoiler line which no one wants or do more Final thought style episodes which while they're fun to do now They're on this half schedule doing any number of those at a time really kind of eats into talking about new stuff in a big Way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you should see the pile of Unconsumed media in my room, but Dave and Joel made me realize that there's one kind of review.
Speaker 0: We don't do Mm-hmm the review where something is bad and the best enjoyment to be gotten from it is Someone else reviewing it to the point of spoiling it entirely.
Speaker 0: But you one do not have to watch it and two can live humorously and vicariously through them.
Speaker 1: But that is the job of Dave and Joel and not the job of ribbon skirt.
Speaker 0: However, I know that none of these people have done the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles OAV.
Speaker 1: They did have an old order Did they?
Speaker 1: that's how I found out about.
Speaker 0: Oh when they do it when you aren't listening I haven't listened.
Speaker 1: How do you think I found out about that crazy stupid thing?
Speaker 0: I'll be honest I have not listened to any podcast outside of it's all politics.
Speaker 1: I also stop.
Speaker 1: I stop listening to the vast majority of podcast.
Speaker 0: I listened to the penny arcade and politics and that's it.
Speaker 1: I listen to penny arcade twit One ESPN show and I got the onion video.
Speaker 1: That's about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess pseudopod, but I don't know.
Speaker 1: I kind of wore out a horn even when I was trying listen trying to listen to pseudopod.
Speaker 1: I couldn't listen to enough even though I loved it.
Speaker 0: I listen to every one but then I just I guess I got burned out on horror.
Speaker 0: I've heard so many horror stories that like they don't even.
Speaker 1: yeah I'm not scared.
Speaker 1: the only one that ever like got me even a little bit of a hospital one.
Speaker 1: Yeah with the MRI.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but anyway, I don't know I kind of want to do a review like that about something.
Speaker 1: Well, not about this because this doesn't suck.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't ordinary victories.
Speaker 0: If you don't listen any further from this point Can you find the add the original name of it?
Speaker 1: Cuz that's that's sort of the translated name.
Speaker 1: That's.
Speaker 0: and as I flounder to remember the name Emily actually hands the book to me open to the page where it says that it Was.
Speaker 0: I wasn't actually looking at the book.
Speaker 0: Realize it'll be in the book.
Speaker 0: and then I looked at the book and I'm looking at all these other things.
Speaker 0: it is combat ordinary aha, which translates to Ordinary combat.
Speaker 1: Yeah as opposed to ordinary victories.
Speaker 1: It's like a different meaning there, but I think they didn't want to call it ordinary combat because that would sound you know That would be like, huh?
Speaker 1: But anyway, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I feel like they should have just left it in the original language because anyone who speaks English Will understand what combat ordinary means but it won't carry the kind of I don't know the the weird Baggage of the English language if it said ordinary combat.
Speaker 1: This is something for our friend the the Oda King and his Dynamic equivalent school to figure out.
Speaker 0: we should ask him.
Speaker 1: But anyway, this is I don't know if he's a French expert.
Speaker 0: though before we go any further if you don't listen any further This is fantastic.
Speaker 0: You should read it.
Speaker 0: Don't even worry about what it's about.
Speaker 0: Just buy it and read it.
Speaker 0: It's really really really good.
Speaker 1: Yep, I mean really what got me about this comic, right?
Speaker 1: well, let me do a little like a really short summary of the plot.
Speaker 1: right you have this guy and He is I guess he's.
Speaker 1: they're Italian or French or something.
Speaker 1: I can't I can't really tell.
Speaker 0: he's into Photography.
Speaker 1: He's a photographer Journalistic photographer.
Speaker 1: right takes pictures of all sorts of horrible things, you know, like starving kids and whatnot.
Speaker 1: but he has a lot of psychological problems for various reasons and Basically, he's at a time in his life where things are changing up, you know, he decides to stop seeing the psychology people.
Speaker 0: You know, he's well, that's actually the the books.
Speaker 0: Well, the comic starts out really strong.
Speaker 0: He's laying in the chair and it pretty it comes in kind of in media res.
Speaker 0: So that's why I've decided to stop my therapy and the the therapist.
Speaker 0: I love the way he's drawn.
Speaker 0: just kind of looks there.
Speaker 1: It looks like a little Durky Freud kind of guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but he just doesn't react and the guy gets nervous.
Speaker 0: He's like, uh, so that's it.
Speaker 0: And then the therapist says, all right Well, I'll set your appointment for next month and it really throws him off guard.
Speaker 0: and just the way Yeah the way that's put together in this first page will hook you right away into this comment because the whole thing is Clever and well-written and realistic and engaging just like that.
Speaker 1: yep, you know and the guy goes through some tough times in his life where things are changing up and Over the course of that, you know, it's like all these these issues that you know affect you know, pretty much everyone sort of come into play.
Speaker 1: and what really got me is how many of the issues are things which we Talk about or think about frequently such as you know Things like Mike Tyson syndrome where you have like this horrible human being who has like incredible talents or Mike You know, Michael Jackson's the same way Or the exact opposite where you have these like really great people who are in so talented Really or in fact, you know, they're really friendly and great and you you love being with them But they're actually horrible people and it's like, you know what how are you supposed to you know deal with these people in your everyday life?
Speaker 1: and what are you supposed to think?
Speaker 1: and It's it's good.
Speaker 1: They don't.
Speaker 1: whether they answer it or whether the answer is satisfactory is is up to you.
Speaker 0: I Just the art is real.
Speaker 0: I mean one thing about the main character and you'll find out right away that part of the reason he's going to therapy is That he succumbs to panic attacks and he's I mean he's going to therapy for many years I think it says eight years and he still hasn't really gotten over it.
Speaker 0: In fact, it's gotten worse.
Speaker 0: He doesn't understand what it is that triggers him and this that more than anything really kind of throws him off balance despite the fact that all these kind of Ordinary battles like the battles that people fight in their daily lives are also confronting him.
Speaker 0: and then beyond all that He's also got this.
Speaker 0: but I guess artistically I really like the way they portray those those episodes.
Speaker 0: He has the art style will change and the panels get red and his eyes are really sketchy and it.
Speaker 0: you'll have to look at The comic to see what I mean.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's really.
Speaker 1: it's like, you know, it's sort of the.
Speaker 1: it's an art style I see in a lot of you know French and Belgian comics, you know little sort of slightly sketchy squiggly characters, right?
Speaker 1: But it totally works.
Speaker 1: I mean you can you recognize every character perfectly every time.
Speaker 1: you never have that issue of is this that guy or is this another?
Speaker 1: You see a person you know who they are, you know and just it really, you know gets across exactly what it's trying to say.
Speaker 1: The paneling isn't crazy experimental or anything like that but it.
Speaker 1: it definitely works in controlling the pace properly and You know, it's I really I mean.
Speaker 1: But isn't it say on the cover that it like won something like one of the best something ever one of the five best Graphic novels of all time as picked by time.
Speaker 1: Yeah how time magazine?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yeah I don't know if it's one of the five best graphic novels of all time, but it's maybe one of the best 20.
Speaker 0: I would definitely put it on the must-have.
Speaker 0: must must read lists.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're someone who appreciates comics of all shapes and sizes This is a comic you really can't not have.
Speaker 0: I mean the only warning I really have about it Is that don't go into it?
Speaker 0: I mean, it's light-hearted at times and it's realistic in his portrayal of just about everything that it addresses But it is not the most non depressing works to put it like.
Speaker 1: Okay, I mean we've already talked summarized the plot a little bit.
Speaker 1: It's obviously going to be depressing.
Speaker 1: This is not going to be like happy times at the sunshine Part one.
Speaker 0: I mean it's broken up into parts and it does have a lot of humor though.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of jokes going around And hangs out with his friend and they call each other.
Speaker 1: This is brother.
Speaker 0: It really portrays those kinds of relationships.
Speaker 0: Well, they George George and you know all the kind of weird things friends do where they call each other something funny.
Speaker 0: here They have like these the rituals that they engage in when they meet each other.
Speaker 0: They.
Speaker 0: basically it's kind of like we do things like that where you yell some kind of catchphrase.
Speaker 0: only there's this big fat joints.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's one thing that's that really a lot of comics mess up, you know Even great ones is that the dialogue between people is either like melodramatic or corny or not, you know realistic.
Speaker 1: But the dialogue between the people in this comic is exact is exactly like, you know, dialogue of real people.
Speaker 1: I mean even something like Scott Pilgrim where the dialogue is sort of like Like.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's it's it's or it's.
Speaker 1: it's like real dialogue But it's sort of like I don't know micro or macro In Scott Pilgrim particular.
Speaker 0: I think the dialogue is it very much evokes what?
Speaker 0: People like that or people who are into like our culture the way we talk to each other.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: it's like it takes like Scott.
Speaker 0: No one actually talks like you know, except possibly Conrad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like they take like the real diet.
Speaker 1: They take real dialogue, but it's exaggerated right in a way You know, they take certain aspects of it in hand and you know Bring them out and take the normal talk and sort of push it down.
Speaker 1: But this this just has actual real dialogue.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: that's how people talk That's what they say, which is pretty amazing considering it's a translation from the French, you know And it still comes across that way.
Speaker 1: That's that's a real good translation job right there.
Speaker 0: and also the dialogue not just natural but the characters and the way they interact is just Incredibly realistic.
Speaker 0: and I I often am caught off guard by characters just by the way they react to things because they're there.
Speaker 0: They're very fleshed out which is something that really I guess adds a lot to this comic.
Speaker 0: I mean that hit one of the issues that his father isn't doing so well, he's having trouble with memory.
Speaker 0: They're hinting that he might have Alzheimer's and they go through this as time goes on.
Speaker 0: but when he meets his dad near the beginning of the comic that the dad kind of points off to a freighter in the distance and Remarks that apparently they go by every day.
Speaker 0: But yet every day he forgets that they're there that they'll come and he's always amazed when he sees them and the son doesn't really Know how to react and he's kind of nervous.
Speaker 0: and they have this kind of halting conversation.
Speaker 0: And then the dad start gets really feeble suddenly and repeats himself you see that freighter yonder.
Speaker 0: Well, your mom tells me and the guy really freaks out at this point and then the dad just starts laughing.
Speaker 0: Hey, I can still crack a joke.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty good It was a good
Speaker 0: scene But at the same time then there's a lot of atmosphere because the last panel on that page you'll get a lot of panels like This where it'll show two characters talking or kind of be focused on what's going on for a while But then the last panel on a page will often cut away to something else like something in the background or something Something that isn't really pertinent to the scene directly, but was part of the atmosphere.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's the same thing a lot of anime do where like in between scenes will give you like the five seconds of the sky and then Like three seconds of the tree
Speaker 0: except for the the old boring sci-fi space anime where you'll get the four minutes of the empty space.
Speaker 1: It's so great.
Speaker 1: but
Speaker 0: what I like is that Most of the time when they it'll end on one of those panels and then you'll see that same thing in a much more important light later like a Chapter or something will end on almost the same scene to kind of bring you back to the moment that led to this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's also kind of weird how everything in this comic, you know, there's nothing Supernatural or magical going on.
Speaker 1: There's no superpowers.
Speaker 1: There's no magic spells.
Speaker 1: No curses.
Speaker 1: No nothing, right?
Speaker 1: It's it's totally just story of people in the real world.
Speaker 1: That's it, but Even so there's almost there's sort of like a magical quality in around.
Speaker 1: You know certain things like especially like when he's at his house and he's wandering around outside.
Speaker 1: It almost feels like you know, one of those, you know person wandering in the magic woods kind of things Even though it's just a guy in the woods outside his house.
Speaker 1: I don't know I don't know if you felt the same thing.
Speaker 0: It was a little surreal when he meets that old man in the woods.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because definitely he meets an old man in the woods who got two old men in the woods.
Speaker 1: Well the first one bad one one good one.
Speaker 0: I'm the good one that I'm referring to it.
Speaker 1: Well, it's sort of good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, yes.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to avoid spoiling this book for obvious reasons.
Speaker 0: Yeah He appears sage-like almost you would you if you didn't get to the point in the book where yes He's a real person.
Speaker 1: you think he was like a magic wizard.
Speaker 0: Very easy to believe that he was a figment of the main character's imagination because the guy is walking around and this man will kind of appear out of nowhere in the woods and He always has something very wise or pertinent to say about what's going on in the man's life.
Speaker 0: but then there is plot as to who that man actually is and and why he's the way he is and it.
Speaker 0: I Don't want to speak any more about anything in this comic without ruining.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I remember a scene where like someone was dreaming and they woke up but it's like they push.
Speaker 1: they showed.
Speaker 1: the way the paneling was is that you you sort of Accepted the dream as what was happening for real.
Speaker 1: and then the person wakes up and it actually Like.
Speaker 1: I actually felt like I was waking, you know Like the same startling of waking up from like a dream that seems like it's real like oh shit I was like, ah, that was that was pretty good.
Speaker 1: You know a lot of comics try to do like dream sequences and they don't.
Speaker 1: they don't quite work as well as that.
Speaker 0: I Much else we can say.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's fantastic.
Speaker 0: It was great.
Speaker 1: How much Emma should it cost?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It says on the bot and the book you have it, but that's that's the Suggested retail price.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what most people are gonna pay 1595. that's not bad or mature.
Speaker 1: It's published by I think NBM which is the same people who published, you know dungeon.
Speaker 1: They do a lot of the translation of the you know, Franco Belgian comics.
Speaker 0: well, in fact if I go on Amazon it recommends buying the second book of this and Dungeon and the rabbi's cat.
Speaker 0: so it's definitely in the same kind of.
Speaker 0: It's a comic for people who like the things that we suggest.
Speaker 1: G. There's a big surprise.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's a reason that I bought it.
Speaker 1: maybe because I already bought dungeon in the rabbi's.
Speaker 0: so partly in light of the fact that we Want to read more of it before we talk about it any sort of spoilery depth and also because I think it's worth all Of you reading I guess untainted I don't want to really push people into interpreting or seeing this comic in a certain way because It's one of the greats.
Speaker 0: It's what already I can see that.
Speaker 0: This is gonna be one of the comments.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you apparently you just revealed to me.
Speaker 1: You didn't finish reading the volume.
Speaker 1: Like I told you to.
Speaker 0: no I didn't get I didn't have time.
Speaker 0: I read the first part of it, which was amazing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, good job.
Speaker 0: Anyway, okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it definitely we got to order that volume - I wonder how many volumes there actually are in total.
Speaker 1: I hope it's like not.
Speaker 1: I hope it's enough but like not too many, you know It's like.
Speaker 1: I feel something like this could go on, you know for a while and still be quality But if it went on too long, it would be sort of like, you know, what what else do you have to go with here?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I'll definitely read as much as I can get my hands on in the English.
Speaker 0: Well, anyway, what I was saying is that we will probably revisit this at some point in the future Almost definitely.
Speaker 0: So go out and read it.
Speaker 0: Don't don't even worry about whether or not you think you're gonna like it.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.