Speaker 0: It's Tuesday April 15th.
Speaker 0: I'm red.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk about Aerobiz Yoshi's cookie and gem fire.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: I was playing some of that Wesnoth on the train today that there was not a lot.
Speaker 0: there wasn't all that.
Speaker 1: yeah We talked about the game a long time ago.
Speaker 1: It's I think it's still the best open-source game ever ever.
Speaker 1: It's pretty still a good game.
Speaker 1: since we talked about it.
Speaker 1: actually they've made a lot of changes to it for the better.
Speaker 0: I like how the skeletons will juggle their own heads if they're bored.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they added.
Speaker 1: you know they added graphical changes You know little animations to all the sprites, but they've also made a lot of game changes And I think it's definitely you know.
Speaker 1: if it was good before it's pretty good now now.
Speaker 0: We had an official front row crew server for Wesnoth that was being managed by Alex.
Speaker 0: it It was used a lot like a crazy lot for a couple weeks way back in the day And then it kind of fell into disrepair, but it's back in a big way, so yep We've talked about the show before.
Speaker 0: go find the old episode But you've never heard of battle for Wesnoth.
Speaker 0: Wesnoth like WES as in Wes and then noth as in a noth n-o-t-h.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you know you can always tell a good game because some games.
Speaker 1: You'll play you'll finish you put them down They're gone forever.
Speaker 1: You know some games like you pick them up, and you've been on five minutes and some games They just sort of they might not you know might put them down But you'll go back to them again later at some point in the future Maybe a month or two you know and you keep coming back repeatedly.
Speaker 1: You don't stick with them for a long time at any you know.
Speaker 1: But you'll play it not play play it not play it.
Speaker 1: I think though that shells you at a game is got some quality going on and Wesnoth is that kind of game.
Speaker 0: Check it out download it and remember.
Speaker 0: There's an FRC server.
Speaker 0: You can play as each other.
Speaker 1: It's not that for a critic.
Speaker 0: I have something like that.
Speaker 1: just point your Wesnoth game.
Speaker 1: Go to multiplayer say join server type.
Speaker 1: was not that for a credit?
Speaker 1: accomplish enter.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll post in the forum, and I'm there.
Speaker 0: I'll warn you though.
Speaker 0: some of the people in the forums are pretty good Not me.
Speaker 0: oh yeah, Scott and I not so good.
Speaker 1: Oh you suck of course I I've actually what I won one game And I semi won another game just because what ends up happening is is two good players You know and then maybe a bad player, and then me right who's sort of not?
Speaker 1: I'm not terrible, but I'm not good right.
Speaker 1: so They the good players end up fighting each other, and I just sort of like turtle up and slowly Slowly build up my resources and just sort of hold fast And then eventually when one of them decimates the other I swoop in like a vulture and then somehow I sort of Technically win.
Speaker 0: one way to do that is to be the undead right and You build a couple of strong defensive units And then you build a bajillion zombies.
Speaker 0: you build a few bats to keep flying around like grab the city run away grab a city Run away, but you make sure you have a positive income.
Speaker 0: And then every round you build as many zombies as you can Make a sea of them and then when you figure it's time to slowly start marching
Speaker 1: them I would just have a line of zombies the way you do a line of mechs in
Speaker 0: or a lot of fanatics and sieve -
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah,
Speaker 0: but I'd like to talk about another game real quick.
Speaker 0: I'd like to Give this game the old nail through the heart because I think it's over for most of you at least But a lot of you were playing.
Speaker 0: I carry him.
Speaker 1: Oh you want to bring that up.
Speaker 0: I want to bring that up because this this happens more often than you'd expect in the front row crew where Everyone will get it like hey check this game out Scott.
Speaker 0: I'll say I'll play it and people start to play it, but rib always says hey I don't know about that game always says that game's not gonna be.
Speaker 0: you won't be playing that game after a week.
Speaker 0: I didn't say I was gonna be playing the game, but there were other times where that was the case like mech warrior mage night.
Speaker 1: That's one case.
Speaker 0: I carry him name another one anyway.
Speaker 1: That's it isn't it?
Speaker 0: you only got two.
Speaker 0: It's more than one.
Speaker 1: You're like Oh, it's a big trend.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: It's - that's just with Scott.
Speaker 0: if we do the whole I mean if we talk about all the games and other people we but they're all still playing World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: I was about to bring up World of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: They're still playing it even though It's no different than I care, but I carry him.
Speaker 0: I mean it was like oh this game's cool.
Speaker 0: I was like all right, and I made an account.
Speaker 0: I logged in and I was looking.
Speaker 0: I was thinking all right If this game's good Then there's gonna be some strategy.
Speaker 0: so I looked in the forums and I tried to read a little bit about what strategies there were and I discovered that it didn't matter what you did ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: I mean you know it started out where the game was kind of interesting in that.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's like a web game.
Speaker 1: You know I don't have to sit there for hours and hours playing it.
Speaker 1: I just visit the website occasionally And then I click on a few things and then I can leave and then come back a little bit later.
Speaker 1: You know basically log in spend all my resources log out come back like that night Maybe twice a day.
Speaker 0: see I didn't even think of it.
Speaker 0: from the game perspective I thought all right.
Speaker 0: either this is a trick to get the sunk cost fallacy and use it to make money off of people or It's a legitimate person trying to make something cool.
Speaker 0: So what I did is I read the terms of service And I determined immediately that this game was designed solely to hook you in and once you get to the point where You'd feel bad about abandoning everything.
Speaker 0: You've built is about the point where it really sucks to keep playing Unless you pay for some little conveniences.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, I pretty well in terms of service a complete bullshit in terms.
Speaker 0: I don't want to get into how awful they are.
Speaker 1: yeah after a day or two I sort of realized that the game was pretty much just.
Speaker 1: you know click wait for things to level up Wait for things to level up And there was no.
Speaker 1: the main problem with the game is there's no losing.
Speaker 1: so if like if there's no way to lose you just Slowly approach, and there's no winning either.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: How do you win?
Speaker 1: There is no winning?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I think we've learned.
Speaker 0: there's a very famous movie that taught us very well very much.
Speaker 0: So how to win at games like I carry him.
Speaker 0: the only winning move is not to play.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's the second time in a week.
Speaker 0: I've quoted that movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah But anyway, yeah that game that game I discovered it was dumb and like a few days and then I stopped playing it a few days after that.
Speaker 0: But I like how you can kind of see the trend of like.
Speaker 0: you know the classic graph of Innovators early adopters the mainstream the trailing edge, and you saw it in the crew and in the forums.
Speaker 0: It was like oh, we're gonna play this game And then all the cool people in the forums and everyone in the forums But then all the people who started playing it quit, and then there's this kind of trailing off.
Speaker 0: There's a few people are sticking with it to the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah There's the same people playing World of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: I think That's the main problem.
Speaker 1: Is that like?
Speaker 1: what kind of game doesn't have an end like that?
Speaker 1: I mean if it's if it's a role playing see it depends.
Speaker 0: I would like a game that didn't have an end like like Civ - I would usually keep playing Well after the game said hey, you're done.
Speaker 0: Here's you.
Speaker 1: yeah, but you had a goal like if you took over the world.
Speaker 0: Actually, I was usually really pissed if I took over the world because that that there was nothing left to do.
Speaker 1: exactly There's an end.
Speaker 1: This is there's a point at which even if you you know if this it's not a you know like even if the game doesn't Pop up and say game over.
Speaker 1: It's like there is nothing more for me.
Speaker 0: It's like Sim City.
Speaker 0: alright I have filled the last square with the best arcology.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I have the entire board filled with arcologies.
Speaker 1: There's electricity and water everywhere and everything is perfect.
Speaker 1: What could I possibly do now and at that point?
Speaker 0: It's not even fun to make the disasters happen.
Speaker 0: you see the arcologies fall down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they don't even sort of fall down in a cool way.
Speaker 1: They just sort of go boom.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's one thing that the Sim City games always lacked was the ability to zoom in on individual citizens panicking.
Speaker 1: I think the newer Sim cities that we never played have that cuz 2000s last only play.
Speaker 0: yeah, cuz.
Speaker 0: I think that was the best one in terms of a simulation game of a city.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway Plus I've heard the newest Sim City is like the crappest crap that ever crapped.
Speaker 1: I've no idea.
Speaker 1: I've heard it try out the civilization revolutions for the DS.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm gonna try.
Speaker 0: I'm excited about that.
Speaker 0: I'll admit it.
Speaker 1: We'll see alright, so yeah, I'm not I'm not confident It could suck, but I wouldn't be disappointed if it sucked because I have a low expectation.
Speaker 0: I think it has a better chance of not sucking than Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles, which I guess in my heart.
Speaker 0: I Expected the the DS game to be awful like I knew in my heart.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like I want to believe in cool things But at the same time I have logic and the logic says no no and I believed okay This game's gonna be awesome, but my heart knew and I lied to myself.
Speaker 0: I knew that game was gonna suck and I spent money on it.
Speaker 0: I got it, and I played it and I went.
Speaker 0: ah I was right except that I lied to myself.
Speaker 0: So I was wrong, but I was right in the end, but I have 40 less dollars Mmm.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: that's all I had to say about that.
Speaker 0: I got a non video game news.
Speaker 0: It's related my video.
Speaker 1: my news is also non video.
Speaker 0: It's related tangentially in that we talked about this a lot on Monday, and we talked about it a lot on Thursday.
Speaker 0: Don't talk about it so much on Tuesday.
Speaker 0: but a lot of you gamers out there with your Xbox and and your PlayStation threes have the HDTVs and you need cable to hook up the HDTVs to your boxes.
Speaker 1: You just use an HDMI cable.
Speaker 1: the end of story.
Speaker 0: monster cables are crap.
Speaker 1: well Just in case you didn't know that an HDMI cable is a digital cable That means you either have a cable that works or a cable that doesn't work.
Speaker 1: if the cable works It's just as good as every other cable that works.
Speaker 1: if you can get an HDMI cable for a dollar That is long enough.
Speaker 1: I guess the length is different.
Speaker 1: right and it works, and then someone else has an HDMI cable That's $500 is the same length and also works.
Speaker 1: There is no difference in performance between the two cables.
Speaker 1: none zero.
Speaker 0: even further if you have analog cables Monster cables are not better than pretty much code hangers nothing You.
Speaker 0: there is no human perceptible difference and in fact a lot of people I've seen say that they're actually worse because they made kind of shot elite.
Speaker 0: alright, but monster has a habit of selling cables to people who are uninformed or stupid.
Speaker 0: yep and pursuant to this they also have a policy of finding anyone who might compete with them in any way and Throwing vague legal threats at them until they go away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they've battled quite a few quite a history of you know threatening people with lawsuits and then sort of settling.
Speaker 0: well It just so happens that they tried to sue someone someone over at Blue Jeans cable.
Speaker 0: They sent one of those.
Speaker 0: you're violating our patents and our blue jeans cable.
Speaker 1: sell bullshit cables Also, or a real cable.
Speaker 0: I didn't even look, but I respect for this guy regardless.
Speaker 0: the guy runs blue jean cable.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna look for blue jean cables because the deal is they sent him this record violating our patents our copyrights.
Speaker 0: We're going to serve you for everything.
Speaker 0: you should shut down me.
Speaker 0: Let's see I don't know what kind of voice that was.
Speaker 0: I was doing.
Speaker 0: I guess that's what monster cable sounds like to me.
Speaker 0: But he responded with a letter that you should read in its entirety.
Speaker 0: You know you're watching someone who has never played a video game in their life trying to play like I don't know Soulcalibur against the person who won the most recent Soulcalibur tournament or Watching someone who doesn't understand how to add one-on-one Debating a mathematician like seeing someone owned so thoroughly and so utterly to see such a one-sided engagement Much like what would happen if you were really good at one most fall 2097 in the news report afterward.
Speaker 1: Yeah, oh, you know.
Speaker 1: I'm going at my blue jeans.
Speaker 1: cable is cables are reasonably priced.
Speaker 0: Oh Huh what I never would have expected that considering that this guy seems smart and rational and cool.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so he responded with a very long letter Explaining one that needs to be a lawyer a good lawyer for a long time now.
Speaker 0: He makes cables because there's a lot of money in cables.
Speaker 1: I guess there is but and kind of a weird switch like lawyering cabling.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's a stock guy at my work who also is a chef.
Speaker 0: That's okay But lawyer cable isn't.
Speaker 0: no why not anyway, so this letter is so Wonderful to read as it bit by bit you ever see a buck a forum post.
Speaker 0: That's so bad and so misinformed that you want to just like take it Sentenced by sentence and attack each sentence on its own and just destroy it as much as you can.
Speaker 0: this lawyer does this and It's a beautiful thing to behold.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna follow this to its bitter horrible end because monster cable isn't.
Speaker 0: They're screwed.
Speaker 0: if they ignore this and they give up on this guy The internet will know and people will start to realize hopefully that their cables are not what they say They are and if they actually go forward with trying to sue this guy They're fucked.
Speaker 1: the thing is if you read the actual thing the guy wrote I read almost the whole thing.
Speaker 1: He didn't actually attack, you know Monster for any sort of false advertising.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he bet he implied it heavily though.
Speaker 0: He basically said Regardless of the many many many many many points.
Speaker 0: I have made above know that if you pursue action against me I will bring up many many many many many as yet unstated and obvious defenses.
Speaker 1: Haha, yeah, but most of the thing he actually wrote was talking about how your patents are untenable.
Speaker 1: and wow, you're basically saying that I'm infringing upon you because I made an RCA cable.
Speaker 1: and You know all the things that you're basically patenting are common to all RCA.
Speaker 0: Okay, I like particularly where he points out that they said he violated multiple different trademarks.
Speaker 0: But each of those trademarks was so different from the other traits.
Speaker 1: Like if I made knives and you made knives and I sued you because your knife was sharpened on one side even like that.
Speaker 0: It's like if I said I'm suing you because you violate these five trademarks.
Speaker 0: I have a trademark on a knife with a red handle on a knife with a blue handle and a knife with a green handle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and my and it's like I cannot have infringed upon all of those.
Speaker 0: It's it's wonderful to behold.
Speaker 1: anyway, this guy will sell you a Ten foot XLR cable for thirty three fifty.
Speaker 1: Is that good?
Speaker 0: That's okay.
Speaker 0: That's pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if it's quality, that's great.
Speaker 1: It seems like it's pretty quality balanced.
Speaker 0: Well, of course it is All right, that's all I got.
Speaker 0: I just wanted to point out I guess I haven't brought it up on Wednesday.
Speaker 0: I'm sure I will at some point.
Speaker 0: don't buy fancy digital cables.
Speaker 0: They're all the same.
Speaker 1: don't buy the cheapest cables.
Speaker 1: You can possibly find for everything no matter what.
Speaker 1: Can you think of any instance where you'd want want to pay more for digital cables?
Speaker 1: I don't know even for analog cables.
Speaker 1: You can buy the cheap ones.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: if you're running say a long audio run right in an electronically noisy room.
Speaker 0: You gotta get shielded cables.
Speaker 0: It's very expensive.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, I guess if you're also doing like some sort of live musical thing You might want better cable.
Speaker 0: Yes, or if they're gonna be in a public place being stepped on or anything like that Yeah, then you need sturdier cables, but for your little home entertainment center Just buy cheap cable.
Speaker 0: and if you think you can tell the difference well It's it you can't anyway.
Speaker 0: That's all I got.
Speaker 1: you should read the article then that talks about how the people thought that the same wine With the more expensive price label on it tasted better than the same wine with I think the the pen and teller with a bullshit Show where they did the water.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was all hose water But they said all this water is $50 fancy.
Speaker 0: Well that coat hanger study where they show that people couldn't tell the difference between a coat hanger and a monster cable.
Speaker 1: All right, so do you remember the last time we're at uber con like three something years ago?
Speaker 1: It was a while ago.
Speaker 0: That was the time where we interviewed Luke Crane But I got super drunk and then we lost the power cable to the compressor and I drove home in a blizzard.
Speaker 1: Yep, that one.
Speaker 0: that was an awesome time.
Speaker 1: Do you do you already know my news is now?
Speaker 1: mister didn't know.
Speaker 0: my news was Oh, you're talking about the mosque our game.
Speaker 1: Yes, right Yeah, I can't believe you didn't think of it for anyway when we were before we interviewed Luke Crane, right?
Speaker 1: You know, we sort of like, you know, we're hey, there's a little we're hanging at the bar a little bit You know, then we sort of hung out in the hotel lobby and some chairs, you know talking stuff cuz Luke Crane and his crew.
Speaker 0: It's funny.
Speaker 0: He's he's a rock star Game-master and I say that a lot and Scott says it a lot, but he had like an entourage following him.
Speaker 1: Well, no, it was pretty much him in tour.
Speaker 1: Those other people were from our chaos studio Press.
Speaker 0: you might have been drunk and not realizing it No But they have like he was whoever he went like Torwood follow him and they would follow him.
Speaker 0: and it was.
Speaker 0: it was like if You look from a distance.
Speaker 0: You'd see like one guy walking and then this crowd like would be up and follow.
Speaker 1: Uh, it wasn't really an entourage.
Speaker 1: It was he was talking to some people who were unrelated to him You know doing business dealings and yeah, just making chitchat.
Speaker 1: It wasn't an entourage.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point is our chaos studio.
Speaker 1: Press are the people who publish the Mouse Guard the comic book.
Speaker 1: We did an episode on.
Speaker 1: it didn't wait.
Speaker 0: It's fantastic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you haven't read Mouse Guard guess all about the weasel sanctuary Up in that business.
Speaker 1: You can just go to your local bookstore or Amazon and the hardcover of the whole first Mouse Guard series is now available.
Speaker 1: How easy is that right?
Speaker 1: Mouse Guard fall 1152?
Speaker 1: Of course, I'm reading Mouse Guard winter 1152 because you're all cool cuz I'm cooler than you.
Speaker 1: And Mouse Guard is by David Peterson.
Speaker 1: Well when we were sitting around with Luke crane and the arcade studio press guys I was like, oh man Mouse Guard is awesome You guys are cool.
Speaker 1: and then Luke crane was like if you guys ever want a Mouse Guard RPG I totally make that.
Speaker 1: and well today I think yep.
Speaker 1: today they announced what do you know?
Speaker 1: He made that when we weren't looking.
Speaker 1: I got.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it took him all that time Or if it took a while for them to get the deals done.
Speaker 1: who knows what?
Speaker 1: but that that idle chitchat became reality.
Speaker 1: And today here it is.
Speaker 1: Let me read for you the press copy the ad copy.
Speaker 1: Oh, uh-huh in August.
Speaker 1: so basically Otacon times packs times.
Speaker 1: It will be everyone's duty to join the Mouse Guard and defend the mouse territories against predators and dangers and role-playing game the Mouse Guard conflict series.
Speaker 1: The game is intended for all ages levels of gameplay experience designed by award-winning game designer.
Speaker 1: Luke crane is based on a simplified burning wheel.
Speaker 1: I'm just I'm paraphrasing now Includes art and extensive background material on the mouse territory is specially prepared by David Peterson the Mouse Guard creator.
Speaker 1: two hundred and forty page hardcover thirty dollars That's it.
Speaker 0: All right Guaranteed buying.
Speaker 0: this is definitely going to be a good game.
Speaker 1: Duh, can you imagine though think about this?
Speaker 1: It's such a perfect role-playing game because it's like, okay We're mice's right you got the inter mice in.
Speaker 0: I believe the technical term is Mises Mises.
Speaker 1: you go outside.
Speaker 1: You know me sport.
Speaker 1: Okay, you crawl around on the ground An owl shows up.
Speaker 1: You don't worry about like monsters and stuff, you know, you don't have the unrealistic bullshit of random encounters.
Speaker 1: I think you have the totally make sense random encounters.
Speaker 1: Of course is gonna be animals in the woods.
Speaker 0: I think what works More to the game's credit is that the setting of Mouse Guard is very neat.
Speaker 0: that too I mean, I don't want to say cool It's really neat and I like it.
Speaker 0: and it fits kind of with the burning wheel like the base burning wheel Setting that you're expected to kind of use.
Speaker 1: Also, the the book is gonna be eight by eight, you know, like a little square book the same as the Mouse Guard books themselves.
Speaker 1: So you can put it right up there next to your other Mouse Guard hardcovers Right in between your burning wheel books and your Mouse Guard books.
Speaker 1: It'll go right in there.
Speaker 1: So yeah guaranteed buying in August.
Speaker 1: I'll remind you again in August.
Speaker 1: Maybe we'll ask the crane about it.
Speaker 0: Maybe maybe Have you gotten a lot of key.
Speaker 0: if you have any questions for Luke crane keep posting them in the forum because we're gonna do An interview whenever we have time we could just be to just have.
Speaker 1: we just make the Luke crane burning wheel Podcast just talk to him like once a month.
Speaker 0: That's not that bad of an idea actually.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like like, you know, 15 minutes of Luke crane every month That's not bad at all.
Speaker 1: Not really now, huh?
Speaker 0: anyway.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: on July 31st Something was released into the world something frightening something that perhaps a video game a video game from a day 1995. video games were very different from how they are now.
Speaker 1: It was pre internets, right?
Speaker 0: So and in 95 wasn't really pre internet.
Speaker 1: I mean it could have been I had a cable modem.
Speaker 1: It was either a very early PlayStation game or a late SNES game or maybe a Sega Saturn Game, it was definitely a PC game Must have been an earlier sort of mid CD-ROM game.
Speaker 0: about that.
Speaker 0: in fact was the era might have been like met warrior 2 of the Multi media game now.
Speaker 0: This was not the first kind of Multimedia era game or the digitized games.
Speaker 1: a lot of them did indeed come out 95.
Speaker 1: I'm no fool.
Speaker 0: It was probably I would say I mean people are gonna quibble him say no Technically, this was the first digitized game and blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: And there was that game on the SNES.
Speaker 0: so there were two games like that on the SNES but on the PC.
Speaker 0: Under a Killing Moon was the first Multimedia with real actors game that people and or directive.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: No, that was the sequel.
Speaker 1: I know that's what I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: game was awful.
Speaker 0: Yeah Under a Killing Moon was at least okay because it had James Earl Jones in it and Margo Kidder.
Speaker 1: Didn't the other one also have James?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I never even played it.
Speaker 0: I'm just like the demo.
Speaker 0: I'm just casting aspersions all about.
Speaker 0: I think I assume it sucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who knows if it sucked there.
Speaker 1: I played the demo anyway.
Speaker 0: Thanks Murphy.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah in 95 Phantasmagoria was released.
Speaker 0: you do not remember phantasmagoria.
Speaker 0: This game was Awful, but at the same time it was touted as a revolutionary Genre.
Speaker 0: changing like the world of gaming will never be the same.
Speaker 0: This game was hyped up like you wouldn't freakin believe.
Speaker 1: it was super hyped up.
Speaker 0: This was an adult game.
Speaker 0: this not not adult in the porn way but adult in for mature audience and not in the mature porn way.
Speaker 0: But how come?
Speaker 0: every way we have of saying something is for a mature audience implies pornography.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I mean if you go to any convention video games, whatever and they say yeah, that's the mature gaming room You know, it's porn games.
Speaker 0: if they say that's the adult showing room, you know, it's porn.
Speaker 0: It's never anything but porn yeah, but uh this game.
Speaker 0: I Played this game all the way through.
Speaker 0: so did my mom and my little brother.
Speaker 0: My dad took one look at it and said why do you want to watch a video?
Speaker 0: That's two inches by three inches and blurry.
Speaker 0: Dad it's a game.
Speaker 0: He said no, it's not It's not a game.
Speaker 0: Show me the game.
Speaker 0: Show me what you're doing to play and I'm like, well, I'm watching this video right now.
Speaker 0: He's like, huh?
Speaker 0: That's a game.
Speaker 0: But look now I get to click on stuff.
Speaker 0: Oh, so that little cursor changes when you're over something to click on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so what do you do?
Speaker 0: Click out all the things.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's a great game a lot like that Monty Python game I play.
Speaker 0: I had that game.
Speaker 0: I had two of those games.
Speaker 1: I laid one.
Speaker 0: Fantasmagoria was amazing.
Speaker 0: No amazingly bad in that one is.
Speaker 0: I forgot until recently how Frighteningly violent this game is.
Speaker 0: this game is just a series of poorly Snuff film.
Speaker 0: it's silly violent, but it really while it's silly.
Speaker 0: It's also Super bloody and super violent.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's like bright red blood with the zipper hanging out, you know, it's not like The killer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it depends though because there's the one scene where he breaks the woman's neck and it's actually just really disturbing and not even Funny.
Speaker 0: yeah, but the story whatever.
Speaker 0: one thing this game had I want to point out Is that the end sequence was actually kind of cool, you know in a lot of games now There's like there'll be an FMV but oh shit press a.
Speaker 1: oh Yeah, the the the much hated by Zero punctuation.
Speaker 0: this game had that before.
Speaker 0: all those other games had that.
Speaker 1: well I might not who knows if it was the first game to have that but surly Certainly this game had it before.
Speaker 1: it was a huge trend.
Speaker 0: the cool thing It didn't have the whole game which was on seven CDs.
Speaker 1: I point out It still doesn't beat Wing Commander.
Speaker 1: for how many was that?
Speaker 0: This did not.
Speaker 0: I don't even know.
Speaker 0: You did not have that until the end of the game.
Speaker 0: The end of the game was like this 10 minute 20 minute long FMV where you had to do that through the whole thing.
Speaker 0: and let me tell you there were like a billion violent ways to die Mmm, but what I have?
Speaker 1: much in the style of Shadowgate.
Speaker 0: ah Shadowgate.
Speaker 0: What I have for you here my thing of the day are two examples of video from this game not three three examples because One is not safe for work.
Speaker 0: It is one of the death scenes.
Speaker 0: I point out the acting.
Speaker 0: it is most excellent.
Speaker 0: to especially note how the guy swaggers in it.
Speaker 0: Words cannot express.
Speaker 1: Wow phantasmagoria was seven CDs, but wing commander 4 was only six CDs.
Speaker 1: So it actually beats it out by one.
Speaker 0: but the next video I have is the original Trailer that was used to hype this game up.
Speaker 1: We're like e3 or something I don't even know.
Speaker 0: all I know is that these the people making this game thought this game was serious business.
Speaker 1: I'm sure they did cuz at the time, you know, you just look at it and go holy shit
Speaker 0: You know what at the time I did and so did my mom because we looked and like wow This game is really violent and video games were never like that before.
Speaker 1: Wow It's really a video game.
Speaker 0: It was.
Speaker 0: technically it was.
Speaker 0: there were puzzles.
Speaker 1: Well, then technically YouTube's a video game.
Speaker 1: It's interactive right.
Speaker 1: you click play and stop.
Speaker 0: there were actually puzzles.
Speaker 0: the puzzles were like, all right I need blood to finish this horrible ritual at the end of the game.
Speaker 0: Oh, look, I have a piece of glass.
Speaker 0: I will cut my wrist with the glass to drop blood on the plate.
Speaker 1: That's a wonderful game.
Speaker 1: All right My thing of the day on my third video is the opening movie.
Speaker 0: It's epic.
Speaker 1: Anyway, my thing of the day you this has been on everywhere on the internet.
Speaker 1: This is like all over the place.
Speaker 1: If you haven't seen this video by the time you're listening to this then you are not connected to the internet.
Speaker 1: You are not an internet person and you need to step it up.
Speaker 0: if you have seen this video I had not seen the video.
Speaker 0: No, right, of course.
Speaker 0: I was at work working.
Speaker 1: If you had been if you'd if we had like waited more 10 more minutes before starting the show you would have found the video.
Speaker 0: I think I can tell you a different measure.
Speaker 0: that's very close to what Scott was saying.
Speaker 0: This video is not easily found near the top of dig yet as of the recording of this show and Thus one more note that dig is no longer.
Speaker 0: I mean dig got really crappy and it's almost useless now, but at least it had stuff that was internet II real early.
Speaker 0: Now it doesn't even have that.
Speaker 0: it's like the signal-to-noise ratio is hit zero.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I guess this video has been everywhere on the internet I mean like.
Speaker 1: I saw it at like three different sites, you know, but it's still a good video.
Speaker 1: There's a reason it got so popular today and it's worth watching.
Speaker 1: if you haven't seen it if you have seen it Well, then you're just gonna hear me talk about it.
Speaker 1: basically what they did is they took an RC car in a parking garage and They put some things on the hanging off the side of the RC car right like little dangly bits and they drove the RC car past a bunch of wine bottles with various amounts of liquid in them and with the dangly bits hit the Wine bottles.
Speaker 1: they would make a noise, you know.
Speaker 1: And so they would line up and space the bottles out to create music and then drive the car Past all the bottles at a steady rate, you know to get the music to play.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: and at the end of the song they actually put wine bottles on both sides of the car to sort of hit You know go faster than you normally could with the notes and they did the Mario song which is why it's a Tuesday thing of the day and Really?
Speaker 1: They did a much better job.
Speaker 1: that like I was thinking it'd be like, you know, dude, dude, dude But it's actually like wow, these must be Japanese people.
Speaker 0: see the amount of anything You know, it could just be college kids at a tech school.
Speaker 1: No if you get to see I think it's Japanese.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I haven't actually seen it yet.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it's Japanese people.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it might be I can't really tell the videos sort of granny if we know it's not South Korean.
Speaker 1: because no No, actually at the end the URL is exit excite China.
Speaker 1: So there I think they're Chinese people.
Speaker 0: I was gonna say I know it's not South Korea because it didn't involve our Starcraft.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Chinese people did this in their parking garage, which is a pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so awesomeness.
Speaker 0: So when I was a kid, there was a video game on the Super Nintendo.
Speaker 0: in fact, this game actually had a sequel and The sequel was different but not better to the point that I liked both of these games and played them both all The time and not just by myself, but with my brother and friends.
Speaker 0: I would play these games Constantly hours and hours hours.
Speaker 0: We would sit in my brother's room where the SNES was playing these games Yelling at each other getting super into it.
Speaker 0: These games were called Aerobiz.
Speaker 0: this game was a simulator of global Commercial Airlines and the management of such.
Speaker 0: from the perspective of the CEO.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean basically you.
Speaker 1: it was sort of like sim airplane company Like imagine if you were in.
Speaker 1: you were not only the president of say, I don't know Delta Airlines But you were actually every single employee of Delta Airlines except for the pilots and the stewardesses.
Speaker 0: not even that.
Speaker 0: no You're really just the CEO.
Speaker 0: You have all these other advisors that do all the real work.
Speaker 1: They don't actually do work.
Speaker 1: They just tell you what to do.
Speaker 1: They don't put them in places and they make numbers change, but you don't think you actually have to make all the decisions.
Speaker 0: But all the decisions you make are the highest level of decisions like they'll advise.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, how much should a ticket cost from here to here?
Speaker 1: That's not a very high level decision.
Speaker 0: No, you don't even specify direct prices.
Speaker 0: You specify how much are we going to mark this up?
Speaker 0: Yeah I'll tell you this what you want to do is mark everything up all the fucking way.
Speaker 0: But it most of the decisions you make are like, all right It's it's the third quarter and we're down in Asia and international travel routes and because of the war going on in Africa It's really hard like we're having trouble getting people to fly out to whatever.
Speaker 0: Well, I think we should do an advertising campaign stressing the the wide network of our bluff.
Speaker 0: I think we should buy this bank bankrupt hotel in Dubai and revamp it and then try to get people to fly there.
Speaker 0: well I think we should buy this charter airline that's going out of business and then sell off all its stock.
Speaker 0: and then you get to Decide which of these things you want to do and then you pick routes and you do things.
Speaker 0: and am I gonna go with?
Speaker 0: Airbus or I'm gonna go with?
Speaker 0: I don't know DC but oh the DC nines are coming out soon But maybe I'll go with that discount.
Speaker 1: can we all go to discount Russian airplanes?
Speaker 0: Tupolev made the shittiest fucking airplanes.
Speaker 0: Good God You know what?
Speaker 0: They weren't even that cheap.
Speaker 0: Like there was no reason to use their shitty like.
Speaker 0: I'd always play and be like, oh, man Perestroika.
Speaker 0: now I can buy from Eastern Bloc companies.
Speaker 0: Wow Everything they have is awful awful awful awful And they pollute.
Speaker 0: You know what though?
Speaker 0: I often use them anyway because eventually they'd come to me and offer me like 60% discounts if I buy in bulk.
Speaker 0: so I'd buy like 40 Tupolev like to you whatever piece of shits and I just use those in like Africa where no one cared anyway But it would only crashed.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I didn't even care.
Speaker 0: The thing is I love these games mine.
Speaker 0: You think it's just like our rims being weird.
Speaker 0: No Me and my brother would play these games all the time with our friends and we get super into him and I've never in my life met a single other human being Who is liked these games.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's a matter of people hating the game.
Speaker 1: It's just a matter of.
Speaker 1: it was sort of an obscure game that like you bought for the SNES But no one else bought for the SNES.
Speaker 1: I Something else.
Speaker 0: I've never even met anyone who thought a game like that would be interesting.
Speaker 0: No I tried to get Scott and everyone to play it in our IT and they'd sit down with me and we'd play for like Ten minutes and then they'd say this game is boring and stupid.
Speaker 1: Well, I wasn't.
Speaker 1: it's not really, you know.
Speaker 1: to be honest It's not a stupid game.
Speaker 1: It's just the play is really slow and You don't get a lot of indications if you're doing well or poorly.
Speaker 0: You get the yearly marketing reports and the quarterly marketing reports that aren't as full featured.
Speaker 1: But give you a nice rough outline and you get this Yeah, but it's like, you know, unless you played the game a lot, you know, you know I mean like I see all I'm profiting hooray, but you're profiting more.
Speaker 1: so to go.
Speaker 0: Well, that's because I've made an international route that no one else had and thus with my monopoly I raised prices.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Here's the kind of shit that you know, nobody bothers.
Speaker 0: It wasn't really a game of knowledge of the game.
Speaker 0: it was just a game of looking at boring charts and making marketing decisions based on those boring charts and sending people to negotiate for Airport, it's not a game people hate on.
Speaker 1: it's just a game that you were way into.
Speaker 1: that was really obscure And no one not many people know or care about.
Speaker 0: I just I feel sad because a lot of games that I liked Or I'm good at or I think are cool.
Speaker 0: No one else likes.
Speaker 1: I don't have too many games like that.
Speaker 0: You have one very in particular.
Speaker 1: you've been bitching about it lately because I bought Yoshi's cookie on the virtual console.
Speaker 0: Cookies terrible game.
Speaker 1: Yoshi's cookie is a fantastic game.
Speaker 1: It's great.
Speaker 0: It's a week if all those puzzled upon kind of games are a hundred times better than Yoshi's cookie.
Speaker 1: No, listen Yoshi's cookie.
Speaker 1: The multiplayer is I think if you're looking at puzzle game Multiplayers, right?
Speaker 1: Number one is pride Tetris.
Speaker 1: Number two is probably Dr.
Speaker 1: Mario and number three is probably she's cooking.
Speaker 0: I highly doubt that.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, what's been Yoshi's cookie?
Speaker 0: That's a little fine.
Speaker 1: No, not really totally.
Speaker 0: No our puzzle bobble.
Speaker 0: No Puyo pops not better.
Speaker 0: No, what about that cool?
Speaker 0: all those cool modes of Tetris?
Speaker 1: Those are all just Tetris, but they're slightly skewed.
Speaker 1: That doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: Anyway, Yoshi's cookie, right?
Speaker 1: the mole and I can tell you the single-player the multiplayer is.
Speaker 1: so it's really cool because the way it works is You have everyone has I think a five by five grid although yeah, I think it's a five by five grid and The five by five grid is filled with cookies of all different shapes and sizes and you want to line up five in a row of the same kind of cookie horizontally or vertically, right and Every time you make a row like a Yoshi cookie shows up.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know It's a cookie with Yoshi's that's shaped like Yoshi's head and you also get some points and you have this like thermometer that fills up as you start to fill up the screen, okay, and So what you can do is the only movements you're allowed to make is you can sort of rotate any Horizontal or vertical row to the left or to the right or up or down?
Speaker 1: So and that's all you can do.
Speaker 1: So, you know you move one cookie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay You're moving four other cookies along with it and that's you know.
Speaker 1: So it's sort of difficult to like arrange the cookies exactly the way you want with sort of like those sliding puzzles You know, it's like well if I want to get this over there I got to move all these other things around.
Speaker 1: and So it's sort of a race in one fashion of who can line up cookies the fastest.
Speaker 1: but there's an additional strategy on top of that in which if you line up five Yoshi cookies a Magic power will happen and the magic power is determined by what it says at the top of the screen.
Speaker 1: So one player is red and one player is blue, right?
Speaker 1: And the magic power either has a red ring or a blue ring around it.
Speaker 1: So if it has a red ring, that means it will happen to the red player and as a blue ring It'll happen to the blue player.
Speaker 1: So if you line up the Yoshi cookies at say a bad time, right?
Speaker 1: You might actually give points to the other guy or take away points from yourself.
Speaker 1: So you start out to wait to use the power at the right time.
Speaker 1: But if you're waiting there to line up your fifth Yoshi cookie, right?
Speaker 1: You got four or five Yoshi cookies.
Speaker 1: You're just waiting to move the last one into place for the power to change.
Speaker 1: The other guy could be making a whole bunch of lines and scoring while you're sitting there and waiting for this thing to change.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I much prefer my Marketing graphs, but it's on top of that, right?
Speaker 1: Okay, so I'm not gonna wait for it to change.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna actually try to complete lines of cookies You know to try to keep my score going up and then when the power changes then I'll line up the ocean cookies really quick.
Speaker 1: The problem with that is that okay, you keep making lines.
Speaker 1: You keep getting more Yoshi cookies.
Speaker 1: Eventually, you're gonna line them up no matter what you're gonna you know Because moving one cookie moves for others.
Speaker 1: it gets pretty hairy in there managing all them cookies.
Speaker 1: and it's actually.
Speaker 1: it's a really good multiplayer puzzle game.
Speaker 1: a single-player is Okay, but not as great.
Speaker 1: But the multiplayer is really hot, but no one ever wants to play with me.
Speaker 0: Yeah See I think what I notice is that There's a trend and I know a lot of gamers have games like this where You whatever reason a game tickles your fancy and you really like it.
Speaker 0: So you play it enough to become non trivially good at it Like you become really good at it, but no one else really gets into it.
Speaker 0: so you never really get to use all these intricate skills and things you've figured out or care about.
Speaker 0: and The worst thing is if you ever convince someone to play with you You're so good that they're not going to invest the crazy amount of time that you invested to get that good at the game.
Speaker 0: so you pretty much have made a self-limiting world where unless you happen to run into the one person out there who Independently cared about that game as much as you did and achieved a similar level of skill.
Speaker 0: You're never ever ever gonna be able to show this off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like you found a great game, but it's either hated or So unpopular.
Speaker 1: right that if you invest in it and there's a multiplayer aspect You're not.
Speaker 1: there's no one to play against.
Speaker 0: Popular with air hockey is a big example of this.
Speaker 0: if you actually try to get good at air hockey you'll pretty much immediately find out that you're now a thousand times better than everyone, you know, and League air hockey players are difficult to find.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're not that difficult to find the email though.
Speaker 1: So we did an air hockey episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah But it's it's difficult to like get them together to play air hockey with you conveniently Mmm, or like you're never gonna find anyone who's gonna play Yoshi's cookie with you.
Speaker 0: You got to get him to come to the house or go to their house bust open the Yoshi's cookie Sit down and have your deathmatch.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah, she's cookie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mom.
Speaker 0: I guess my sad thing is that I have a lot of games like that.
Speaker 1: I don't have.
Speaker 1: I can't really.
Speaker 1: I'm sure I might have other games like that, but I can't think of them.
Speaker 1: It's much eat because I guess people, you know They like a more known.
Speaker 1: well, they're not liking games that other people like.
Speaker 1: there's no more.
Speaker 0: but you never even got good at that.
Speaker 0: No, no, I don't think anyone can get good at it.
Speaker 0: I think it's random.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I see board games that I like that.
Speaker 1: No one else.
Speaker 0: you really really you're like.
Speaker 0: you bought battle or you're like Yeah, and I was like wow this game sucks.
Speaker 1: Well, I'd heard so much great things about it and I still think it's better than you think it is.
Speaker 1: But it's not.
Speaker 1: it's not great.
Speaker 0: But I always say I'll play it if you'll set it up.
Speaker 1: Yeah set up is very annoying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, I'm editor return to my original plan of.
Speaker 1: well It has a bunch of miniatures we can paint with or something, but we're awful at that.
Speaker 1: You always try you could practice on shitty battle or pieces.
Speaker 0: You're always trying to get us to play the Egyptian slot machine.
Speaker 1: I'm not always trying to get you to play the always suggested kinda Actually the Dracula game.
Speaker 1: I could actually you know, I whenever I suggest it It's like only it's sort of half Sarcastically but half I kind of like.
Speaker 0: I only like it if I'm Dracula and if I don't have to set it up or tear It down.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like I kind of I really don't like the combat and I don't like the when the game takes too long.
Speaker 1: But I do.
Speaker 1: I really like Dracula's hidden movement and the chase for Dracula.
Speaker 0: I like that part a lot Debated a lot how to take that Dracula game and make it really good cuz it's so.
Speaker 1: so it's like I kind of want to Play it just for that, you know hidden card movement part.
Speaker 1: That's really awesome.
Speaker 0: I just have this problem a lot more with Scott.
Speaker 0: then Scott with video games like gem fire.
Speaker 1: And oh, that's another example where it's not because people hate gem fires because it was an obscure game gear game And you were probably the only people who bought it.
Speaker 0: It was on the Super Nintendo and the Nintendo.
Speaker 1: What's the?
Speaker 1: what's the game gear?
Speaker 0: one crystal warrior?
Speaker 0: Oh, that's the same one though Not even close that game crystal warriors for the game gear was basically advanced wars with fantasy piece.
Speaker 1: So it was the gem fire.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 1: No, I said.
Speaker 1: so What was the gem fire?
Speaker 0: fire?
Speaker 0: was the game where you have a map of something that's vaguely Britain?
Speaker 1: All right that.
Speaker 0: Okay, gem fires from a whole class of games.
Speaker 1: Wait.
Speaker 1: Wait, what was the cuz?
Speaker 1: see gem fire?
Speaker 1: I don't like.
Speaker 1: I tried to play it.
Speaker 1: I didn't like it.
Speaker 1: But what was that PC one?
Speaker 1: That was a TSR game.
Speaker 0: Oh A Fantasy fantasy empires.
Speaker 1: I actually like that one.
Speaker 0: No, no, you don't you think you do?
Speaker 1: I liked it when he played it.
Speaker 0: you liked it because you did not play it long enough.
Speaker 0: I invested Countless months into that game.
Speaker 0: I played it for maybe a half hour.
Speaker 0: I am probably better than any living human being at that game.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you I liked it for a half hour.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you and I had we continued that game that we had started with all of our friends.
Speaker 0: It would have taken weeks of daily play for it to breach its bitter bitter conclusion You wanted you would have ended.
Speaker 0: play a broken man.
Speaker 0: Tell you gem fire is a really good game though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you played it for like five minutes and said I played it a few more times than that.
Speaker 0: Oh you didn't And you didn't read the instruction book.
Speaker 0: You didn't know.
Speaker 1: I don't have the instruction book.
Speaker 0: That's the problem.
Speaker 0: See there's this whole class of games.
Speaker 0: there was one that simulated the Revolutionary War in the u.s.
Speaker 0: And there was gem fire.
Speaker 0: they're all made for the same people they all look the same and They were games of there's territories and they're all numbered.
Speaker 0: you look at these games you go Oh, it's one of those games because it's always like.
Speaker 1: it looks a lot like no banagas ambition and romance No bungas ambition and romance of the three kingdoms.
Speaker 1: Those are the same kind of game.
Speaker 0: but gem fire like these games on the SNES were like the best implementation that could have been done with the technology at the time and they're a lot better than those other games.
Speaker 0: and they were games of like.
Speaker 0: there'd be like five factions and you have to deal with like the crown and then you have your like vassals that control different territories and you invest in agriculture defense and you raise armies and then you fight with each other with the politics and It was a really fun game.
Speaker 0: I've beaten every possible scenario with every possible family and gotten every possible ending.
Speaker 1: really Yes, Wow Including I think you went that far.
Speaker 0: I did because I've.
Speaker 1: was that when you're a punk kid?
Speaker 0: No, that was when I was living in fish kill.
Speaker 0: Oh god I've never ever other than when I was a kid been able to play this game against another human being.
Speaker 0: no one has ever Accepted a play with this game.
Speaker 1: Yeah See I have a hard time because it's like.
Speaker 1: you refer to it as like games.
Speaker 1: you like that No one else likes.
Speaker 1: and that sort of implies that it's because you like a game that you know.
Speaker 1: Most people are.
Speaker 1: you know hate like what's the game?
Speaker 1: A lot of people hate.
Speaker 1: Let me try to think Die katana, right?
Speaker 1: So if I decide if I like die katana, which I don't I don't like die katana I get on.
Speaker 0: it wasn't that bad.
Speaker 1: It's pretty bad.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: there were expectations that it did not meet.
Speaker 1: a fine.
Speaker 1: Uh a fester's quest.
Speaker 0: that game was bad.
Speaker 1: So if I liked fester's quest that would be.
Speaker 1: I like a game that no one else likes.
Speaker 1: but if I like, you know Gem fire gem fire.
Speaker 1: It's not no one's hating on gem No one else likes.
Speaker 0: Yeah know about a game.
Speaker 0: You don't like it.
Speaker 1: I know but it's sort of this this sort of false.
Speaker 0: No one will play it because I Well, no one will play.
Speaker 1: it is different even still I mean, oh cuz you'll go out there.
Speaker 0: gem fire is trivial to get.
Speaker 0: I know a lot of you gonna think oh and you're gonna get the ROM.
Speaker 0: You're gonna be like, alright, I'll play this game.
Speaker 0: I can be all cool like rim thinks and I'll go play this game and I'll email and be like, yeah I played that game.
Speaker 0: You're not really gonna play it.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna learn about it.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna Yoshi's cookie it and figure out the strategy.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna think about how awesome the game would be if you played it with another human being.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz the game sucks against the AI.
Speaker 0: cuz AI is stupid.
Speaker 0: You'll figure out how to beat the AI like that.
Speaker 0: Of course I'm also weird in that I really really like all those Second sequels.
Speaker 0: like my favorite Mario game is almost Mario - it ends up being Mario 3, but it's almost Mario - yeah My favorite Zelda game is still Zelda -.
Speaker 0: my favorite Castlevania game is far and away Actually is the DS one but number two right after it is Simon's quest.
Speaker 0: I love that game.
Speaker 1: Oh, you've all the worst ones.
Speaker 0: the game is great.
Speaker 1: Hey Mario - you know slash doki-doki panic is a good game.
Speaker 0: Don't say that doki-doki panic was a terrible game.
Speaker 1: I'm saying, you know, I said, you know, I'm just using the doki-doki panic to you know Which Mario - I'm talking about?
Speaker 0: Well, because no one knows Mario - is Mario - they notice Mario - J or the lost levels Which by the way is sucked balls.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but Mario - is better than Mario - USA is better than Mario - J and it's better than some other Mario games like Mario's time machine or Mario is missing and some others.
Speaker 1: but Other than that Mario 3 Mario World Mario 1 all better than Mario - it is way down there.
Speaker 1: Castlevania - awesome, probably the worst Castlevania.
Speaker 0: Have you fucking played how many Castlevania's you play?
Speaker 0: There's one two Four wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Speaker 0: What about three?
Speaker 0: I didn't play that never played three.
Speaker 0: now, you know anything about it?
Speaker 1: It looks a lot like one not really.
Speaker 1: Anyway, one two four deep two DS games And The Genesis one.
Speaker 1: Dracula X the only fail in Castlevania 64.
Speaker 1: Oh, I know Castlevania 64 is the worst Castlevania.
Speaker 1: Castlevania 2 is the second worst.
Speaker 0: I think the only failing of Castlevania 2 is that the boss battles are weak.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it's just not good.
Speaker 1: It's a really good game.
Speaker 0: It's really fun.
Speaker 0: And Zelda 2 is fucking epic.
Speaker 1: Zelda 2 is a good game.
Speaker 1: It's probably the worst Zelda game what?
Speaker 1: Okay, Minish Cap is worse.
Speaker 1: It is the third worst Zelda game.
Speaker 0: actually I didn't really enjoy those like Game Boy Color ones that much I like the game.
Speaker 1: I like all portable Zelda's that Minish Cap a lot.
Speaker 0: Minish Cap would have been fun if I hadn't played other Zelda games before like if I hadn't really played other Zelda games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if that's the first Zelda if you're gonna play Minish Cap make it the first Zelda game you ever play.
Speaker 1: that way It's like awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz it is awesome If you haven't played others, I actually I like those Game Boy ones like the most.
Speaker 0: main thing is I think what it was is Zelda 2 unlike most other Zelda's had a couple of these really really Epic tasks in terms of the sheer amount of pain and effort.
Speaker 1: and and the pain is that made it unfun.
Speaker 0: No, the pain was awesome because pain directly translates into accomplishment.
Speaker 0: I mean if you beat the Silver Surfer The pain is not worth it.
Speaker 0: If you're not going to beat the Silver Surfer Don't play it because the pain will only add up and you will never get the end.
Speaker 0: if you know if you are willing to Beat the Silver Surfer then all of that pain turns into glorious glorious triumph.
Speaker 1: You and you just wasted like how much time in your life.
Speaker 0: Well, that's a bad example because it would take most of an adult's life active life to beat the Silver Surfer legitimately but Zelda 2 had the hammer.
Speaker 0: Going after the hammer is one of the many cherished memories You don't already like.
Speaker 0: if you're not And know how to get the hammer you will have that moment where you get to a screen and you've been playing for like two Hours and you have one life left and that screen looks different because there's all these pillars.
Speaker 0: in the background.
Speaker 0: It's really tall and you see the hammer and in front of it You see those fucking red rhino guys with maces.
Speaker 1: It's one, you know upright red like stark red alligator and he doesn't have a mace.
Speaker 1: He's throwing axes at you Other than those jumpy nights at the end of the game pretty much one of the hardest guys and if you get hit by those Axes you are fucked and throwing axes at you rapidly like imagine if I had hatched my.
Speaker 1: I could just make hatchets Appear out of the sky and then fling them at you like an Olympian throws the discus.
Speaker 1: No in a rapid succession.
Speaker 0: that your shield means nothing to him.
Speaker 0: No an axe your shield is nothing and you probably like you're you'll be like.
Speaker 0: What do I do?
Speaker 0: and you might have enough magic left to cast jump?
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe I remember I or shield.
Speaker 0: I got there fairy.
Speaker 1: the fairy doesn't help you.
Speaker 0: Well, he would but you don't have a magic.
Speaker 1: Well, no the fairy can't pick up the hammer depends.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I just jump jump over him and I run and there's the hammer and I grab it and link is standing there holding Up going dee dee dee.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, the axe guy is right next to link paused as it goes.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: as I grab the hammer It hits me and I die game over.
Speaker 0: I remember as a kid I cried I Cried.
Speaker 0: I remember other Zelda game has ever made me cry except Almost with sadness at a couple of points, but never with real world pain and desperation.
Speaker 0: My mother runs in.
Speaker 0: what's wrong?
Speaker 0: What's wrong?
Speaker 1: Ah Come on.
Speaker 1: the game basically Right limits you to this incredibly small area and the only way out of the small area is if you get the hammer to break The rocks but getting the hammer.
Speaker 1: you have to go on this epic quest through all these dangerous dangerous caves and this maze And if you don't know your way through the maze it could take you forever to get through the maze and it's really really hard And long and then if you actually make it out with the hammer Suddenly the whole game opens up to you like I can go places Yes,
Speaker 0: and all just because it was so hard to get the hammer.
Speaker 0: You've been seeing these rocks the whole game and then you finally get the instruction book.
Speaker 1: you need the hammer to break the rocks
Speaker 0: and you I after crying and all that I finally get the hammer and I go to that rock and I hit a and the rock disappears and I take a pause and I take a step and Suddenly I'm in this new world.
Speaker 1: It's like even Metroid.
Speaker 1: imagine like if you know there were only like ten doors that would open with the regular gun and all the other doors are missile doors and the missiles were like By a hind like a hundred bosses
Speaker 0: like to the point that you would call your friend and say hey Joey I'm going for the hammer.
Speaker 0: You want to watch I got the missiles.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I Oh Those were good days before I was demystified about everything in the world.
Speaker 1: video games had to be like that again.
Speaker 1: I don't know how I don't know how either.
Speaker 0: I think the moral is there's any any of you out there Play and or like gem fire Yoshi's cookie or arrow biz or if you're epic Aerobiz supersonic.
Speaker 1: Supersonic I think is better than regular.
Speaker 0: It was better in some ways but they took the stock element out.
Speaker 0: good.
Speaker 0: You couldn't buy stock in other airlines.
Speaker 1: good There's less bullshit to worry about In the airplanes which have enough trouble concentrating on to begin with.
Speaker 1: Yeah, are there any games?
Speaker 1: they're like you like that are just super obscure and no one's heard of.
Speaker 0: or games that you like that Everyone else gives you shit about.
Speaker 0: yeah Simon's quest.
Speaker 0: nope I think we're done.
Speaker 0: I'm actually kind of hungry now.
Speaker 1: Me too.
Speaker 1: I'm real hungry.
Speaker 1: cop-out episode for the win.
Speaker 0: Wasn't that cop-out?
Speaker 0: We've had copper out episodes cop outer.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm.
Speaker 1: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 1: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.