Speaker 1: It's Tuesday July 8th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm sky and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We talk about one of the greatest games in the history of gaming.
Speaker 1: until they fucked it up tribes - Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Warm today Warm yesterday even warmer today man was it warm.
Speaker 1: I mean I'm not one to complain.
Speaker 1: I love it I'm not.
Speaker 1: I do not get me wrong.
Speaker 1: I am not complaining about it being warm.
Speaker 1: I love it to be about 99 degrees and dry.
Speaker 0: I think it's been pretty clear that when we say warm today We're not complaining and when we say woman.
Speaker 0: We are complaining quite a bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was really weird.
Speaker 0: I was in Florida.
Speaker 0: It was warm.
Speaker 0: I got off the plane in New York Just as warm.
Speaker 1: well I remember very clearly because I went down to the beach over the weekend Wildwood with scojo and everyone.
Speaker 1: and as We drive down it was so hot and we didn't have air conditioning.
Speaker 0: It was like why didn't you have air conditioning?
Speaker 1: Well, we didn't take my car which has no air conditioning because my car also the transmission is no longer cooled.
Speaker 1: Yep, so we took Emily's car, but we didn't realize the air conditioning hasn't worked on that car in a long time Uh-huh, and Alex's car the air conditioning doesn't work either Huh?
Speaker 0: I'm not my the only person with air conditioning in the car until I buy a new car.
Speaker 1: Yes Alrighty, but so we know we drive down.
Speaker 1: It's crazy hot crazy hot.
Speaker 1: we get to Wildwood.
Speaker 1: We open the door.
Speaker 1: It's actually pretty chilly in Wildwood.
Speaker 0: Cuz you know what the difference was?
Speaker 0: you were closer to the waters.
Speaker 1: Well, no It was actually just a really cool weekend.
Speaker 1: all things considered until the day we got up like the day We left it actually got stupidly hot again.
Speaker 0: No see in Florida It was weird because like every day there was rain.
Speaker 0: But it was like these really tiny storms like in terms of the amount of ground they covered But the intensity of the storms was big.
Speaker 0: so it's like for like an hour every day.
Speaker 0: It would grain like crazy, but which hour that was?
Speaker 0: you had no idea.
Speaker 1: That was how it was with all the times.
Speaker 1: I visited Florida with my family.
Speaker 1: We'd know that at some point during the day.
Speaker 0: Well usually I've only ever really been to Florida like in the winter or in this.
Speaker 0: you know I never went in this in the middle of the summer before.
Speaker 1: I think that's it cuz I've only ever been to Florida in the Dead of summer.
Speaker 0: see I've never been there in the summer.
Speaker 1: I've been there in the winter in the spring and literally I was down there for like a week and a half and every single Day for about ten minutes.
Speaker 1: It would rain harder than you can imagine.
Speaker 0: The thing is I looked at the weather map while I was there and there was a. I saw a green Precipitation markings all the way up from Maine to Florida, and I was just feeling good.
Speaker 0: I was trying to think of you on the beach getting rained on except.
Speaker 1: It didn't rain on us.
Speaker 0: well That's either what other channel said.
Speaker 1: so well the thing is it was actually really cool every morning.
Speaker 1: It would rain right and scare Okay, and scare everyone off the beach or people would go home or whatever and then the Sun would come out and it'd be amazing.
Speaker 0: Did you go to El Russo's?
Speaker 1: actually we did.
Speaker 1: oh, man, I played some DDR.
Speaker 1: I played some air hockey.
Speaker 1: No, I got to say supernova 2 is pretty hot Tenth mix of DDR.
Speaker 0: at this point it is I Hung out with old people.
Speaker 1: I hung out with young people.
Speaker 0: They were old.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got to say one thing.
Speaker 1: I don't know if any of you air hockey people are still listening But I know a lot of.
Speaker 1: at least for a time a bunch of people in the National Air Hockey League found out about us when we talked about air hockey.
Speaker 1: But one thing we learned from you people was the that the Masters the Pete like most of the people who compete on the professional Level use this alternative grip kind of like how in ping-pong.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 0: I think it's not an alternative grip.
Speaker 0: I think it's the grip and we were using an alternative grip.
Speaker 1: well No, it's like how in ping-pong.
Speaker 1: most people who play ping-pong play with a standard grip.
Speaker 1: But all the super super pros mostly use the Chinese grip mm-hmm And I think it's kind of like that because I never I've never seen anyone do that except these tournament people.
Speaker 1: so I tried it.
Speaker 1: I've seriously tried it.
Speaker 1: I could pretty much pick where I wanted the puck to go.
Speaker 1: every time I could hit it as Hard as I could ever hit it with all my arm strength with the flick of the road because it's really air hockey is one Of those wrist games like throwing a baseball is all in the wrist.
Speaker 0: air hockey is also all in the wrist.
Speaker 0: You know the things that involve arm are like throwing a football is arm Shooting a basketball is wrist.
Speaker 0: I guess hitting a tennis ball is arm and wrist combined.
Speaker 1: actually no It's just arm.
Speaker 1: if you're using your wrist you're doing it wrong.
Speaker 0: You got to like rotate the racket into position.
Speaker 0: You don't hit it with the wrist, but you have to have the racket at the correct angle with the wrist.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm not good.
Speaker 1: That's lame Good way.
Speaker 1: if anyone out there is trying to learn tennis to get good at tennis quicker is to wear like a Rollerblading wrist guard.
Speaker 1: that won't let you move your wrist.
Speaker 1: You'll be able to get become a lot better in a hurry Anyway, but yeah air hockey is definitely all wrist action.
Speaker 1: So I don't think you'll ever have a chance of beating me again.
Speaker 1: I think I've pulled ahead.
Speaker 1: I think I pulled ahead because you won't play air hockey anytime.
Speaker 1: I'm not playing air hockey, but I practiced for over the weekend and Wait until I get an air hockey table, then you're in big trouble.
Speaker 1: What do you get?
Speaker 1: an air hockey table that I share in my house?
Speaker 0: I'll get my own house my own air hockey table.
Speaker 0: We'll see after I win my air hockey lottery.
Speaker 0: No, I'm just what I'm gonna do.
Speaker 0: my strategy is I'm gonna watch the videos of those guys because they had their triangle technique And I'm gonna basically do everything they do and just keep doing it no matter how much I lose and no matter how much anything No matter how uncomfortable it is Until I get it right.
Speaker 0: because if one human being can do it I also have an arm that works.
Speaker 1: what can also do it much like Lance Armstrong eventually will run across the Genetic freak who has like a double arm Then we lose.
Speaker 0: I mean I. if I if you know the guy can bicycle I can also do it.
Speaker 0: I watch his legs and I move my legs in exactly the same way and I just keep doing it forever and ever and ever Until I achieve the best my physical body can possibly do.
Speaker 0: if his lungs happen to be twice the size of mine That's the end of it.
Speaker 0: What I can't go to the doctor is a doctor.
Speaker 0: I need double lungs So I can beat Lance Armstrong in the Tour de France is better than axes.
Speaker 0: twice as good I need Z day.
Speaker 0: I Can do archery.
Speaker 1: So speaking of games that only use the wrist there is in fact another class of sports that only uses the index finger.
Speaker 0: Oh Burn you just.
Speaker 0: you're really lightening up with this today.
Speaker 0: It's a second huge burn.
Speaker 0: You've laid out this game.
Speaker 1: So so activism vision and Makers of pitfall, but we don't care about that at all because blizzard Announced someone was a makers of Warcraft one.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'll say this when I heard this I Honestly thought it was a joke and when I saw the link, I thought it was a hoax.
Speaker 1: There were it took three sources for me to accept that this is true.
Speaker 1: But blizzard is making a third sequel to click.
Speaker 0: It's not a third sequel It's the second second sequel to the franchise of clicking.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I can't believe they're making another Diablo.
Speaker 0: Everyone knew they were gonna do it.
Speaker 0: I mean they're making Starcraft 2. they made World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: Diablo 3 is obvious.
Speaker 0: They pretty much you know, they've settled down into just you know, these three Franchises really and they're just gonna continue to produce games pretty much in these franchises and I really don't see them doing Much else you see on the horizon.
Speaker 0: They're pretty much only gonna make Warcraft Starcraft and Diablo games from here on out.
Speaker 0: lizard makes a game that isn't in one of those three franchises.
Speaker 0: I'll be shocked.
Speaker 1: I just don't understand.
Speaker 1: I mean Diablo 1.
Speaker 1: I'll put it this way and some of you might get around love about this, but Diablo 1 was a shit game.
Speaker 1: Well, I never played shit game.
Speaker 0: I never played Diablo 1 because I was in the PC gaming area at the time But I had like a shitty PC and I didn't buy it or what.
Speaker 0: I don't even remember but I was a game I never played but I saw and it was really popular.
Speaker 0: and I knew it was popular But I didn't play it.
Speaker 1: when Diablo 1 came out Some of my friends played.
Speaker 1: in fact a lot of the people I knew played it But I and by I I mean me and all the smart people I knew we saw the game We played at other people's houses a little bit and we realized right away that Diablo is the equivalent of playing hero quest alone by yourself in your mom's basement.
Speaker 1: The only difference is that sometimes in Diablo you would cheat people cheated hero quest.
Speaker 0: Yes No, but I mean Diablo 2 came out when I was like late high.
Speaker 0: It must have been 99 I think because I was late in the high school years I had my own.
Speaker 0: I had a better computer my Pentium 3450 with my bx6 r2 motherboard the best motherboard ever except to slow.
Speaker 0: but it's price still works.
Speaker 0: I have it and Diablo 2 came out and I said money at that time.
Speaker 0: So I said I'm gonna buy it and at the time is pretty good because you know what unlike a lot of other Nerds at that time of my life.
Speaker 0: I hadn't really played hero quest.
Speaker 0: if you said what's hero quest I would have been like.
Speaker 0: that sounds familiar.
Speaker 0: I have no idea what it is Scott.
Speaker 1: Diablo 2 didn't come out until No way.
Speaker 1: Sorry 2000. in 2001 it became quote one of the most popular on games ever.
Speaker 1: and when I say quote that is an Uncited citation needed thing.
Speaker 0: on what month did it come out in?
Speaker 0: 2000 doesn't even say this article is terrible So it must have come out either.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I definitely.
Speaker 0: I think it came out early in 2000 because I must have June 29th Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: good game captain Scott.
Speaker 0: see I saw here.
Speaker 0: I graduated from high school I got the game then I played it and then I went to Israel for a month.
Speaker 0: I came back I played it and then I went to RIT.
Speaker 1: See I did play Diablo 1 and what I remember is the Diablo 1 was terrible and I remember very.
Speaker 1: it's kind of like nowadays where I Really don't like Wow and I kind of make fun of it a lot and I kind of look down and found people who really Get into it because the game is so simple and all these sorts of.
Speaker 1: But when Diablo 1 was out, I remember looking if people played it and I'd ask them the same things.
Speaker 1: I asked about Wow.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: Why are you playing this game here?
Speaker 1: Here's how it works.
Speaker 1: Ready?
Speaker 1: Click click click click Pushing click like that.
Speaker 1: Oh I won.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I played Diablo 2. now I figured out exactly which months I played it in.
Speaker 0: the reason I played it and the reason it was fun in those days Is because a I hadn't really played that kind of thing before.
Speaker 0: B there wasn't much else for me to do until I got to RIT and such.
Speaker 0: because as soon I know as soon as I played Counter-Strike Diablo 2 pretty much went in the trash bin and never played it again.
Speaker 0: But because I had a 56k modem and it was pretty much the only game that worked with Multiplayer with real-time on my 56k modem.
Speaker 1: I was still playing weapons factory I had a cable.
Speaker 0: if I had a cable modem.
Speaker 0: I probably never would have played Diablo 2.
Speaker 1: I guess it's just I saw through Diablo 1 when it first came out and I didn't.
Speaker 0: I didn't play Davos I didn't know.
Speaker 1: so when I didn't even notice when Diablo 2 came out and what I really want I mean, I think Dave and Joel and fast karate said it best and I'm not even gonna try to parrot what they said, but What could Diablo 3 possibly be?
Speaker 1: if it's probably gonna be I imagine well done.
Speaker 1: if it's like the other Diablo games It's going to be a super generic super lame Super easy clicking game.
Speaker 0: click on the bad guy.
Speaker 0: Okay now click on the other bad guy.
Speaker 0: if you're about to die Just push the health potion by one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, click on the bad guy again.
Speaker 0: Click on the bad guy again, if you level up pick any of the squares.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really matter which square you pick to upgrade.
Speaker 0: Click on the bad guy again.
Speaker 0: If you're about to die and you're out of healing potions push the town button.
Speaker 0: go to town.
Speaker 0: if you're in town Sort your shit out.
Speaker 0: It's just it's work.
Speaker 0: It's not even like a strategy of what how to sort your shit out.
Speaker 0: It's pick the best shit you can afford and the best shit you have.
Speaker 0: Get rid of everything else.
Speaker 0: conserve space Potions.
Speaker 0: buy more town potions.
Speaker 1: repeat like it was such an inane game like there was no gameplay at all.
Speaker 1: I would say that it's practically zero engaging gameplay in Diablo.
Speaker 0: It's I think it's it's really in the same genre as gauntlet only worse.
Speaker 0: I mean on the one hand you sort of have the the Upgrading bits and the managing equipment stuff which a lot of people find fun and I could see how you know Psychologically, it's so it's semi can be rewarding.
Speaker 0: but as a game Gauntlet is more complex at least in gauntlet You have to like, you know navigate mazes that are actually not just you know, sort of go to the next screen They're actually navigate the maze.
Speaker 0: You're there.
Speaker 0: The bad guys are actually sort of difficult.
Speaker 0: You have to manage your you know potions fighting death.
Speaker 0: You can't return to town or anything.
Speaker 1: I think part of the reason why I saw through Diablo was because of that shadowrun game on the SNES because combat in that game was Yeah, I never played that either I didn't really existed.
Speaker 0: so I got sorry I played through that game to the end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't even know that game existed so well into college.
Speaker 1: I actually remember very clear when I discovered that not only could I talk to that Fox girl But I could join my girl in your party and then she died.
Speaker 1: Fox girl, right?
Speaker 1: She didn't die.
Speaker 1: She died once.
Speaker 1: I turned the game off started again, and I discovered that it is almost impossible to keep her alive, right?
Speaker 0: So the hubbub about Diablo 3 right here is the way I see it.
Speaker 0: either it's gonna be like the old Diablos in which case why would I play?
Speaker 0: or This is my prediction actually is that it's going to be Just like World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: However, it's gonna be a little bit simpler a little bit less stuff, right?
Speaker 0: But you know basically the same idea but of course it'll have the different.
Speaker 0: love the classic Diablo three-quarter overhead of you and not the World of Warcraft behind the avatar view.
Speaker 0: And it's going to be like one big elaborate Co-op Wow raid.
Speaker 0: that's what it's gonna be.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be one big really fancy Wow raid.
Speaker 0: So if you like Wow raids, you're probably gonna love Diablo.
Speaker 0: You mean, you know just getting in line to pay 50 bucks We're not if you haven't guessed that?
Speaker 1: Now I got to say one other thing.
Speaker 1: Dave and Jill also brought this up So I don't think it really needs.
Speaker 1: I don't need to say much about it But their term raffle gate is something that needs to be used more on the internet The the fact that people are seriously and earnestly complaining about the fact that the new Diablo game looks good.
Speaker 0: Well, this is one thing.
Speaker 0: that's actually one thing.
Speaker 0: while I was playing Diablo 2 and before I decided it was stupid back in The day, you know played Counter-Strike instead.
Speaker 0: I was actually angry at the game because everything was dark and like.
Speaker 0: there were no colors and it was hard to see bad guys and tell things apart and a lot of bad guys are the same bad guy only a Different color.
Speaker 0: and it was really like I understood that like.
Speaker 0: hey, you know the darkness sort of goes along with the Diablo theme but really it made the game sort of ugly and hard to play.
Speaker 0: and now that the game is actually Colorful and the bad guys aren't just the same bad guy with a different color and all that shit and People are complaining about that Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: Actually, that's one thing that I can guarantee is probably the only thing that's good about Diablo 3 Is that there's actually colors.
Speaker 1: now the real question that's on everyone's mind I think is whether or not the chat gem is going to be there the what remember that gem?
Speaker 1: This is a big part of the Diablo mystique or Experience.
Speaker 0: all right.
Speaker 1: There was that gem you could click on in the chat screen in Diablo 2.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: I didn't really.
Speaker 0: I didn't really chat.
Speaker 1: people freaked out about that thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna spoil the game for you all.
Speaker 1: It didn't do anything.
Speaker 1: Okay, it had no effect on the game at all.
Speaker 1: All right, not like those buttons and Raptor call of the shadows that did do something.
Speaker 0: I said I'm really chatted.
Speaker 0: I mostly click click clicked on bad guys.
Speaker 1: So you're so once again.
Speaker 1: you had the opportunity to play a cheating version of click hero quest online But instead you chose to play it by yourself.
Speaker 0: I played it with other people.
Speaker 0: Also, I just didn't chat.
Speaker 1: They might as well have been bots then.
Speaker 0: Well, no, because basically what you would do is you would go online right and they had to say like battle net.
Speaker 0: Well, no, they had two sets of servers, right?
Speaker 0: They had the battle net and they had the not but in the end the open right and the battle net.
Speaker 0: there was no cheating.
Speaker 0: Yes, there was.
Speaker 0: well Technically there was supposed to be no cheating because there are blizzard servers that were controlled that were completely full of cheating.
Speaker 0: BS, of course But I would go in there and I would get killed and I'd be like fuck this cuz in on the battle net.
Speaker 0: It's like when you died you died.
Speaker 0: It was serious business, right?
Speaker 0: And then they had the open battle net which is sort of like do whatever the hell you want We don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: You can actually bring your character from your single-player game into that action and I would go in there and I would just kill nubs And take all their shit.
Speaker 0: that way I could get a lot more shit with a lot less clicking.
Speaker 0: And that's what I did.
Speaker 0: the hand with the online action.
Speaker 0: We get a lot of people arguing with us all the time about issues sort of like what we just said about Diablo and World of Warcraft where we're talking about How Oh games got to be a test of skill games gotta have a strategy games got to be hard or else It's you know, not a game.
Speaker 0: It's crap.
Speaker 0: It's you know, people fight with us over this.
Speaker 0: So like, oh no, it's it's fun.
Speaker 0: I don't care if it's not a fair even game when they change the team fortress - it's it's still fun.
Speaker 0: I like it that you can't tell me I don't like it whatever and People really really have a hard time understanding exactly What we're saying.
Speaker 0: and I think maybe this little article that showed up might help you understand a little bit.
Speaker 0: basically, this dude is Complaining.
Speaker 0: Well, he's I don't know if he's complaining but he's basically saying that game developers sort of the way he sees it game developers have this idea that Games have to be strategic games, right?
Speaker 0: Which is what we say, right and he thinks that you know It's all game developers since they like strategic play put something that at least appears to be strategic play into pretty much all their games.
Speaker 0: and what he's saying is that you can make games that don't have strategic play games that are not a just a series of interesting decisions or skill tests and There's nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 0: and there's a lot of games out there that are sort of would be good if they would just Not try to be strategy or not Try to include strategic elements.
Speaker 0: and on the one hand I agree with them and on the other hand I disagree with them because on the one hand I'm someone who really likes strategy games first and foremost right, and there are a lot of games out there that either pretend to be strategy games and aren't or just aren't.
Speaker 0: and You know those games are games I don't like.
Speaker 0: so when he's saying oh games don't have to be strategy games I'm saying no, I want strategy games.
Speaker 0: I want real strategy games.
Speaker 1: See what I think he's saying.
Speaker 1: the idea here is that you can create Experiences that aren't necessarily what we would look at as a traditional game exactly.
Speaker 1: They're more like a movie.
Speaker 1: It seems like every time someone mixes game and movie They just take half of each and do both kind of weekly and those you get modern Final Fantasy games.
Speaker 0: And this is this is where I agree with him and that he's saying stop trying to be a strategy game.
Speaker 0: You know there are plenty of good games out there that aren't strategy games, and he some examples he gives are like brain training or Grand Theft Auto or Guitar Hero or the sims.
Speaker 0: right the sims is just a sandbox.
Speaker 0: It's not a winning and losing game.
Speaker 0: It's not a you know series of interesting decisions game.
Speaker 0: There's no strategy to the sims.
Speaker 0: It's just do what you want and have fun.
Speaker 0: It's a. it's just entertainment software.
Speaker 0: There's not really a game to it.
Speaker 0: You know in the in the definition of game that involves tests of skill and competition but in the definition of game that is you know entertaining pastime And there are a lot of games out there that because developers like strategic play or have strategy on the brain.
Speaker 0: You know like.
Speaker 0: look at like Metal Gear Solid 4.
Speaker 0: You know they put in the stealthy bits, and they put in.
Speaker 0: you know some of the movie bits And I guess people like that even if I don't like Metal Gear right, but other people do.
Speaker 0: But they also put in.
Speaker 0: you know why does it have to be a game where you win and lose?
Speaker 0: And you gotta you know guide him to the to the thing with a chance of being caught.
Speaker 0: why not just make it a game Where Solid Snake's gonna win?
Speaker 0: it's a movie, but you can sort of control the action scenes to make them awesome.
Speaker 1: You know people maybe even you could lose But it's kind of like if you took a Final Fantasy game And it was mostly the decisions and talking with characters that changed the story in different ways.
Speaker 1: you made an adventure game But then you could still have combat or something like that But maybe only the so-called boss fights not get rid of the level and instead of the combat being fight Or cast this magic spell.
Speaker 0: the combat would be much simpler decisions You know such as you know attack run away, or you know Beyond guard or surround.
Speaker 0: you know much fewer simpler commands that were more of a choose your own adventure thing and less of a Manage lots.
Speaker 1: I do know this sort of thing is very very popular in Japan.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean that antenna game for the Sega Saturn is basically just to choose your own adventure book And with possible with multiple possible endings.
Speaker 0: right chrono triggers actually close to it if you take the combat out.
Speaker 0: so I disagree with this guy in that I like strategy games.
Speaker 0: I want more real strategy.
Speaker 0: if you haven't noticed from past geek nights episodes.
Speaker 0: That's what we like.
Speaker 1: well That's I mean that's partly the reason why despite all the German board games We know most of them sit unplayed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz while there is a strategy there It's not much in many of them or none at all.
Speaker 1: Well that if you go by a game theory perspective a strategy a winning strategy is one Which is predetermined and will always win and once you figure that out.
Speaker 1: There's no point in ever playing the game again.
Speaker 0: Yes, because then you're not making a decision because a strategy in the game theory Speak a strategy is the set of decisions you will make.
Speaker 0: and if that set of decisions is already if you're if you already Determined your strategy when the game begins, and you're not going to change it, then you're already done playing the game.
Speaker 0: There's no more decisions for you to make.
Speaker 0: it's already locked in.
Speaker 1: that would happen to us.
Speaker 1: a lot playing.
Speaker 1: We me Scott and Alex would play Puerto Rico over and over and over again one summer and it got to the point where We would play about I don't know ten rounds in and we'd stop and pretty much agree.
Speaker 1: Yep Alex won this one.
Speaker 1: Let's start over.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you wouldn't even bother finishing the game because we knew we knew exactly all the decisions We'd make right up to the end.
Speaker 0: yep, so on the one hand I want strategy games, and I want games to actually be a series of interesting not much so much interesting But difficult and meaningful non arbitrary non random decisions.
Speaker 0: that interesting is good as well.
Speaker 0: Entertaining is also good.
Speaker 0: throw all those in there.
Speaker 0: but if someone's gonna make a game you know some sort of entertaining piece of software.
Speaker 0: if that is their goal to make entertaining software and Their Strategy gaming doesn't really have to play a role There's no need for in many cases a sandbox.
Speaker 0: you know type of entertaining software is great.
Speaker 0: a a just a story.
Speaker 0: Entertaining software maybe with you know some choosing of adventures and not necessarily winning and losing.
Speaker 0: Strategy is great and people need to sort of embrace that and stop trying to ham-fist bad or fake strategy into Everything you know.
Speaker 0: So yeah, this is an interesting read.
Speaker 0: you check it out.
Speaker 1: So before I do my thing of the day Scott should probably get his out first since I kind of lead right into the gist Of what we're talking about today.
Speaker 0: all right rim.
Speaker 0: So you know those.
Speaker 0: you know people like to play the miniatures games the war hammers and such right.
Speaker 1: yeah I was interested in them, but never really my bag.
Speaker 0: for most I mean one of the big reasons not to play those is because they take too long and mostly because they're really expensive.
Speaker 0: right and You know if if the only thing holding you back is the expensiveness right even after you buy your miniatures Let's say you even buy the paints and the brushes and you do the whole thing right.
Speaker 0: There's still the expense of the terrain.
Speaker 0: right now there's a lot of ways to get terrain on the cheap you know going to the craft store and whatnot but Here is the cheapest way of all to get the highest quality terrain of all Papercraft terrains.
Speaker 0: oh Yeah, it's about time of course now.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: there's only three terrains at least on this page.
Speaker 0: But I'm sure this is something that's going to take off quite a bit.
Speaker 0: and these terrains actually don't look Like they're supposed to be used for say a war hammer.
Speaker 0: They look like they're supposed to be used for say you know D&D because it used miniatures now because it's like Wood crates.
Speaker 0: here are some one inch by one inch by one inch wooden crate paper crafts.
Speaker 0: Here are some two inch by one inch by one inch.
Speaker 0: Tombs you know paper craft.
Speaker 1: I can put them right next to the see.
Speaker 1: For all the years that RIT and all the years we really wanted that what it?
Speaker 0: what was it called?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that three-dimensional thing.
Speaker 0: basically it was you would buy these sets.
Speaker 0: It was like mage something something I forget, but it was basically you bought these sets of already pre-made pre-painted like Actual dungeon bits.
Speaker 1: no I was actually going to go a shade cheaper and talk about how I never owned a hex or a square.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because they were too expensive.
Speaker 1: and then finally finally after all these years Randomly I found one for really really cheap, so I bought the offset one right.
Speaker 1: yep We used it once and then Burning wheel happened, and I have yet to even unroll it in almost a year.
Speaker 0: We could play some battle day.
Speaker 1: That'll take.
Speaker 1: suck you suck.
Speaker 1: I'm done with battle day That'll take is only awesome in the college days.
Speaker 1: What do you have?
Speaker 1: infinite free time?
Speaker 1: I miss those days.
Speaker 0: we become idly rich when you play battle.
Speaker 1: ten probably okay in fact if we became idly rich Don't say it sucks.
Speaker 0: Just say you know it's not.
Speaker 1: nobody does suck.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: There's a difference between.
Speaker 0: it's not a bad game.
Speaker 0: This is not a convenient game that that fits with your current life's the way we played.
Speaker 0: it was a bad game That's true, but battle tech on paper is not a bad game.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: You know what else isn't a bad game on paper?
Speaker 1: communism.
Speaker 0: It's a good game.
Speaker 0: anyway, this is not a good you.
Speaker 0: actually I mean you wouldn't want to rule the world with battle tag.
Speaker 0: Yes, there's a constitution of our country isn't that the battle tag compendium?
Speaker 1: I think the problem was that we played now.
Speaker 0: roll 2d6 to find out if I kick you in the head or in the net.
Speaker 1: We didn't worry so much about money.
Speaker 1: So we just like oh everyone make an 80-ton mech and let's fight until someone's still standing.
Speaker 0: so you really have to play the campaign.
Speaker 0: We never did with the money Even.
Speaker 0: I think that's cuz.
Speaker 0: a big part of battle tech really is that you know the whole world and the you know the society And we never got into that enough to really make it happen.
Speaker 1: you would make it like up to 40-ton mechs With nothing but small lasers and run around being ineffectual till eventually you got headshotted by a gauss rifle.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, I'd make 180-ton mech that had as much gauss rifle as it could.
Speaker 0: I basically couldn't get over the fact that my strategy works so well in mech warrior 2 But never worked on in the board game because in the board game everything was kind of broken.
Speaker 1: I basically would just sit there with a gauss rifle Only front armor one jump jet just so I could turn around Really quickly in case someone got behind me and a targeting computer, and I just brace myself and fire brace myself and fire.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're not really allowed to use a targeting computer in the a lot of things anyway.
Speaker 0: So yeah, check it out papercraft stuff for your miniatures and other Relative miniature gaming needs.
Speaker 1: so I have for you You did a lot of work on this.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: I'm proud of this.
Speaker 1: it's in my blog not for any reason to get people to read my blog because I point out that the The most recent thing other than what I have put in my blog that I'm linking to is my thing of the day Was when I reviewed the wow CCG on April 23rd.
Speaker 0: now didn't hear that on the show.
Speaker 0: yes Before that was in March that I posted there's a game that pretends to have strategy.
Speaker 0: that doesn't in fact in my could we make say a CCG or even just a card game a non collectible card game.
Speaker 0: right that wasn't a Game of strategy.
Speaker 0: that was perhaps a sandbox or something else kind of game easily some sort of role-playing game Yeah, like a nano fiction.
Speaker 0: Well, no no fictionary is still a winning losing game.
Speaker 1: We're talking about a role-playing card game Pure role playing cards, but anyway anyway, so Basically there are two webcomics that have been very near and dear to me in my life.
Speaker 1: one is penny arcade Obviously best webcomic ever bar none.
Speaker 1: The other one it was the bad boys of computer science not the best comic all things considered But it was very close to the way the front row crew was at RIT Which is probably the reason it has so much appeal to me.
Speaker 1: imagine you found a webcomic that was to a large degree Effectively about you and the conversations the characters had were often conversations that you and your friends had on a daily basis.
Speaker 1: So between these two comics you can kind of see the entire story of tribes 2 from the very Innocent beginning to the dizzying Heights to the tragic tragic end.
Speaker 1: so I have for you in order 18 webcomics that in their wholeness show you everything that was tribes - I Almost cried making this because I look back and much like taiko said I can account for almost.
Speaker 1: I think I could account for a full quarter of the gaming I've ever Experienced and remembered and enjoyed as being a result of tribes -
Speaker 0: I mean I was reading the latest volume the printed volume of penny Arcade I think is number five the case of the mummies gold.
Speaker 0: and in it taiko said that a full 15% of his gaming fond gaming memories come from tribes and Really, I'm really feeling that there's a big because there was a tribes.
Speaker 0: whatever the fuck it was It wasn't really tribes 3 just sucked.
Speaker 0: and now we have this legions thing.
Speaker 0: That's on instant action.
Speaker 0: calm That's basically tribes light, but it's not really the full-on tribe.
Speaker 1: Also, it doesn't have reverse mouse thus.
Speaker 1: I cannot play it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe they added that you should check But I've almost already given up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean cuz I installed tribes 2 again the other day me too.
Speaker 1: I spent an hour just flying around Remembering how great it was right?
Speaker 0: I also installed it.
Speaker 0: We're gonna try to get some tribes to action.
Speaker 0: But I'm feeling you know in at least our local community and also I'm feeling it from the penny arcade guys That there is this great desire for tribes action that is like this under current in the PC gaming world At least there's there's a group of people who want this action.
Speaker 0: even if the group isn't large we exist And I think we feel strongly enough about the awesomeness of tribes that we're willing to put forth the effort to make it happen even if it only amounts to getting a tribes to server up and Playing even with not not enough people.
Speaker 1: if if it somehow came to be that I could just play straight-up Unpatched original release tribes to online with other people and other people actually played I would probably give up all other FPS is for the rest of FPS.
Speaker 0: If there were enough people playing all the time, I wouldn't need another FPS ever.
Speaker 0: I mean unless they saw.
Speaker 0: I mean it is pot.
Speaker 0: I mean as awesome as tribes 2 is as perfect as it is, right?
Speaker 0: the improvements could be made I Mean you could up the graphics that you could make the strike slightly more controllable.
Speaker 0: You could.
Speaker 0: you could update the the game engine to sort of be more modern.
Speaker 0: So it's easier to set the controls the void the the talking to other people, you know with the radio Yeah, microphones could you know and headsets could be supported a little bit better with a better protocol.
Speaker 1: They were supported better in tribes 2 than any game out at the time.
Speaker 0: good guy tribes 2 is the only FPS where you can play online with voice and in 56k modem and you'll be just fine as long as you you know.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess now you'll be just fine.
Speaker 1: So In case you couldn't guess what we're talking about on March 21st possibly the greatest team-based Stateless multiplayer capture-the-flag first-person shooter ever was released.
Speaker 1: Scott bought it immediately like cuz.
Speaker 1: the hype before this game was Unjustifiable at the time like the.
Speaker 1: the amount of just people were going crazy about this game And I was leery because I was not terribly familiar with the whole tribes Star Siege thing.
Speaker 0: Well, let me let me sum it up real quick here, right?
Speaker 0: There was a game Called Star Siege, right?
Speaker 0: Actually, I just found this out from Wikipedia just now there's a game called Earth's siege and it went on Earth's siege and then Earth's siege 2. and who gives a shit right the Really started with Star Siege and Star Siege was a mech game, right?
Speaker 0: Just like mech warrior 2. because remember mech warrior 2 was a game of the year and I think 95 if I remember maybe 97 it doesn't matter It was like huge game.
Speaker 0: mech warrior 2 absolutely huge took over the PC gaming world and mech games are big back then real big.
Speaker 0: So Star Siege is another mech game wasn't quite mech warrior 2 But it came later than that and it had better graphics and what you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: Then from Star Siege came Star Siege colon tribes Which was tribes 1 and now this game.
Speaker 1: that was 1999. that game in and of itself Had a relatively small but Extremely dedicated fan base much like, you know mega TF and weapons factory All day.
Speaker 1: It was one of those games that people who got it and realized what it was and the potential that was there Clung to it like grim death.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was also one of those games where they're you know There there are certain aspects to a game that when they come out with newer versions people don't like certain things that have changed.
Speaker 0: They cling to the old version like people who still play CS 1.6 instead of source because there are things about the old CS that you know, there's certain things about it that they love so much that they don't like that when it's not the same You know, it's like this source is a different game to them.
Speaker 0: Like there are people clinging to beta 7 when CS 1 came out, you know, so tribes 1 is one of those things where a lot of the people were dedicated to.
Speaker 0: it really clung to like the way Controlled the way it handled the way certain weapons worked and they really didn't like, you know anything about that changing.
Speaker 0: but tribes 2 came out in 2001 and So let me tell you a story.
Speaker 1: This game, you know it was hyped up and hyped up and hyped up and everyone was talking about how this is gonna be like the best fucking game Ever and I was very incredulous at this point.
Speaker 1: But Scott who had money at the time relative to me bought it right away and it sold out almost immediately.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean I was playing counter-strike at the time.
Speaker 0: Tribes is a big deal, right?
Speaker 0: I mean at the time the internet was pretty.
Speaker 0: you know It was like.
Speaker 0: these were days where the my internet usage would be read slash dot read penny arcade Read but read bad boys.
Speaker 0: the computer sides read a pit theater.
Speaker 1: We would be in front of networked computers Almost six or seven hours a day.
Speaker 0: and you know nowadays most of my computer uses like the web browsers The I am that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: back then most of my computer uses play multiplayer game.
Speaker 1: Yes Music and movies message people and I am to tell them which server I was about to play a game on exactly.
Speaker 0: So when this new game was coming it got mad hype and I was like, I'm ready for it.
Speaker 0: This is a big deal.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be in on this brand new game because I came into counter-strike, you know Like like beta 5 beta 6 beta 7 something like that and you know I was a little late to the game.
Speaker 0: people were better than me.
Speaker 0: I'm like, I'm gonna get this game day comes out and be the best.
Speaker 1: So Scott gets it and he brings it out and you know to his dorm room and he plays it and he plays it.
Speaker 0: I know the first thing about tribes - like I think we've talked about tribes - on the show before but we've never really We never let loose.
Speaker 0: yeah the thing about tribes - I turn this game on and I like, okay Okay, I do the train.
Speaker 0: I start a map and the map is loading now.
Speaker 0: You gotta understand Let's play.
Speaker 0: There's a penny in three four fifty.
Speaker 0: Yes the same one.
Speaker 0: I just mentioned.
Speaker 0: So the game didn't load that quickly and I couldn't turn the graphics all the way up.
Speaker 0: But when a map was loading and you're waiting It pretty built up this music like.
Speaker 0: And Then as soon as the map was loaded like this guitar like full metal comes in like did it did it and this game Built you up and psyched you up for kicking some ass like no game since doom.
Speaker 0: Pretty much because you know doom was the only other game that I can think of that ever did this, you know Doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo and then you know.
Speaker 1: So, I mean, they'll talk about that a little bit before we get into this, the whole story, but basically we'll try one of the things that tribes had was dynamic music, like dynamic loop based music.
Speaker 1: The music would speed up, slow down, change flawlessly and seamlessly based on not only the map loading in the game, starting and everything, but what was going on around you while you were playing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, a lot of FP, a single player FPS is today have music like half-life two.
Speaker 0: They, and, uh, you know, the games like that, they purposefully put music in at specific points in the game, but it's a match what
Speaker 1: ha like seamless, like you're playing half-life two and you'll
Speaker 0: turn around a corner, obviously when you turned around that corner that triggered a wave of bad guys and it triggered some music
Speaker 1: and you hear the music, you think, Oh, this is one of those.
Speaker 0: It's all choreographed, right?
Speaker 0: And tribes too.
Speaker 0: I mean, sure.
Speaker 0: We could probably do it better nowadays with our better technology, but remember this was That was a long freaking time ago.
Speaker 0: And what other multiplayer FPS has had music at all.
Speaker 0: They don't have music.
Speaker 0: A lot of them.
Speaker 0: Counter-Strike doesn't have music.
Speaker 1: All you hear is it does bang, bang, bang, bang, bang.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: Jesus Christ.
Speaker 1: Hacks.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: Fuck Christ.
Speaker 0: Hacks.
Speaker 0: Doom headshot.
Speaker 0: That's the music it has, you know?
Speaker 0: Dominating.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Not much music going on there.
Speaker 1: It was so seamless and dynamic and tribes is tribes.
Speaker 1: Who's one of those games.
Speaker 1: One of those rare games that would pump you up to a level that was almost unreasonable and unsafe.
Speaker 0: It was one of the only multiplayer FPS that actually had like atmosphere and intensity and energy, you know, in addition to the actual gameplay, which you want me to, I'm going to begin.
Speaker 0: All right, let me list for you the things that tribes two had going on.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But let me, let me tell you the basics.
Speaker 0: If anyone has never really understood what tribes is all about, tribes in FPS, right?
Speaker 0: You're?
Speaker 0: the basic game is capture the flag.
Speaker 0: You shoot the bad guys and the other teams, you can get their flag and get it back to your base while your flag is still at your base.
Speaker 1: Now there's a couple of things.
Speaker 1: It made a lot of really big leaps in terms of what an FPS was.
Speaker 0: Now the second thing you have to know about tribes is that the maps are big, really, really big, like huge.
Speaker 0: We're talking.
Speaker 0: If you walk from your flag to their flag and no one interferes with you, if you just walk whole W and just walk, it might take you a good 10, 15, depending on the map.
Speaker 0: It could even take in your heavy armor.
Speaker 0: If you're in heavy armor, it could take the whole game for you to walk to the other base.
Speaker 0: The map is so big, especially if there's a hill to walk up, all you'll be there forever.
Speaker 0: You might not even be able to walk up the hill.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: They're outside of their buildings and there, and because the maps are so big, it's not, they're not all complicated buildings, like a game like quake one or two, all the maps are sort of in structures, you know, in tribes, this outside and inside, inside a building.
Speaker 0: The buildings are actually relatively complex buildings with hallways and tunnels and ups and downs.
Speaker 1: And it was just seamless as in there's this big world, you know, Hills and trees and all this stuff.
Speaker 1: And your base is there with a bunch of over entrances and inside the base of the generators and hallways and all that, all your shit.
Speaker 0: It wasn't like say descent, three descent, three head outside and inside, it was a free space sort of 3d shooting, go outside and inside, but the outside, it's almost like you could feel and you knew the game engine was switching when you went outside or inside, even though it was a seamless move, you know, you could tell the game was changing what it was doing internally tribes too.
Speaker 0: It was the same game outside or inside.
Speaker 0: It was the same thing.
Speaker 0: And outside when you're not in a nice base, you know, a building, it's just hills and valleys and terrain, mountains and little rivers.
Speaker 1: He does water and tick miles effectively.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, you, a lot of times, you know, even if you had the best computer and you had enough horsepower to turn the viewing distance all the way up so you could see as far as you could see, a lot of times the enemy base would be like a speck on the horizon.
Speaker 0: If that, so how, how does a game like that play?
Speaker 0: I mean, wouldn't you hardly ever run into anyone else?
Speaker 0: You would take, you know, every would be so slow.
Speaker 0: You want a fast FPS.
Speaker 0: We're always talking about how we want fast FPS is right.
Speaker 1: Well, one thing was the game was 32 on 32.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It was like sometimes we 40 on 40 on crazy math, you know, servers.
Speaker 0: You had a lot of people in.
Speaker 0: So even though the map was big, you really couldn't sort of hide from everyone to everyone had a jet pack.
Speaker 0: So you could go real fast.
Speaker 0: And I realized that's one thing that these FPS is that we like, like the old quakes and the tribes have that even counter strike doesn't have in that not only was shooting skill based, but maneuvering, moving required more than just pushing the button to move.
Speaker 1: I mean, look at counter strike.
Speaker 1: moving requires nothing.
Speaker 1: The guys entirely jump strafe and forward and counter strike is click on his head before he clicks on your head.
Speaker 0: Moving in counter strike is standard FPS.
Speaker 0: Moving this, you can jump and duck, but that's about it.
Speaker 0: There's not much to the moving.
Speaker 1: Team forgers two is even less slow.
Speaker 0: You push a button and you were going to move in the direction you want to move unless there's a wall in the way.
Speaker 1: But then let's look back at old games.
Speaker 1: A action quake was so fast that moving was critical, not just for shooting and dodging, but just for aiming and everything.
Speaker 0: There were also maneuvers to execute, you know, like you rocket jumps and grenade jumps.
Speaker 0: And there were, you know, the most grappling hook.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The most difficult maneuvering I can think of in counter strike is in Italy.
Speaker 0: When you try to jump up the crates to get in that window, you know, if you're on the the counter, pretty much once you get that down, you've mastered moving in counter strike.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But in tribes to moving was an endeavor like you could practice moving that you had to manage.
Speaker 1: I would play a map by myself and just practice like dodging things.
Speaker 1: Like I'd circle strafe down valleys, like shooting my spin fuser at a tree while I was going down to try to hit it every time.
Speaker 0: It's like not only you had to manage because what it forced you to do was you have a jetpack, but the jetpack has energy and you can't just hold the jetpack down because it'll run out of energy.
Speaker 0: It'll putter, it'll sputter and then you can't move really quickly anymore.
Speaker 0: All you could do is walk and walk in was basically dying.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Basically, if you were walking, you were going so slow that someone just blow your brains out.
Speaker 0: If anyone was around, the idea was to move fast all the time and but to also move in the direction you wanted to.
Speaker 0: But because of the physics, because the momentum, you know, if you landed on a hill and you tried to suddenly turn around to go uphill, that you basically slowed yourself down to a stop if you did it wrong and you'd get killed.
Speaker 1: So this led to crazy, amazing fights between people where like two people are coming up a hill, they see each other, there's some sort of posturing.
Speaker 1: One guy like drops around the hill, but then turns around and chucks a bunch of grenades up.
Speaker 0: On the other hand, if someone sees you land on a hill, they can just shoot below you on the hill, knowing that if you want to keep your speed, you're going to have to move downhill.
Speaker 0: So they shoot downhill from you.
Speaker 0: And by the time their shot gets there, you've hit it and you've died.
Speaker 1: Now, because of all this and the way you'd move, you know, you kind of jet run, jet ski, jet ski, ski, jet, run and all around.
Speaker 0: Skiing was a technique of using going down hills to, you know, with, you know, skis in quotes.
Speaker 0: You didn't actually have skis, but you would use the jet pack and the jump button and in a way to build up an incredible velocity to which you can, if you did it properly, you could traverse extreme distances, which you need to do on these incredibly large maps in a very short amount of time.
Speaker 1: But only in places where the terrain let you.
Speaker 0: I mean, well, you had to.
Speaker 0: you had to do it properly.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, good player can, you know, keep speed on more different varieties of terrain, but also know the map and guide themselves along the terrain, you know, to more advantageous position.
Speaker 1: But don't get us wrong.
Speaker 1: This wasn't like bunny hopping in the old Quake games.
Speaker 1: This was built into the game.
Speaker 1: This was.
Speaker 1: they even told you this is how to ski.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And this is how to tutorial.
Speaker 0: The only single player component of tribes two are these three crappy tutorial missions.
Speaker 1: Was it five?
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: But they basically say, push the button to ski down this hill, dumbass, and you'll learn how to go fast.
Speaker 1: But the end result of all that the way movement was, was that when people were fighting, it had this incredibly gritty, like realistic, militarily like it felt so real and so immersive.
Speaker 0: OK, so you had this jet packs, the skiing, the big terrain, the big maps.
Speaker 0: What else did you have?
Speaker 1: Well, let's talk about vehicles.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So there are three for the vehicles where the we can get in all the details later.
Speaker 1: But the fact that this game had a large number of vehicles that were critical to strategy and incredibly well-designed and the game useful, the game was basically to the point, I mean, now the one problem with the vehicles is that they controlled sort of crappily.
Speaker 0: They controlled better than Half-Life vehicles, but not as well as, say, Halo or Unreal Tournament vehicles.
Speaker 0: So the control on the vehicles, it was the best at the time.
Speaker 1: I got around it by writing a script and I actually used a joystick when I piloted.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but considering what we have today, it's not perfect.
Speaker 0: But regardless, the vehicles in every other aspect, besides controlling them, were beautiful, absolutely beautiful.
Speaker 1: And also they weren't like it's not like, oh, they're 100 percent necessary because like you just can't get over there.
Speaker 1: But they were very strategically interesting.
Speaker 1: You would have strategies like you'll send a bomber and a bomber, remember, needs a crew of three, including the tail gunner, the bomber and the pilot.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: OK, sorry.
Speaker 0: These are the vehicles.
Speaker 0: This is the hover bike.
Speaker 0: The way the hover brake works is if you are in light armor, because you can have light, medium or heavy armor.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: And you're not carrying a heavy pack.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: You could get on the hover bike and the hover bike let you go on the ground only, but it let you go ludicrously quickly without, you know, having to, you know, use your jet pack or anything.
Speaker 1: I mean, it was so fast that and more than once I would see someone who wasn't that good at the game.
Speaker 1: come flying toward our base at high speed, not be able to slow down in time, slam into the wall and die.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's it was stupidly fast.
Speaker 0: Like if you wanted to go from here to there as quickly as possible and you were in light armor, the hover bike was the way to go.
Speaker 0: I would often take the hover bike and a satchel charge, which is a big bomb on my back, drive the hover bike straight across the map, jump off the bike while at full speed, maintaining momentum with the amazing physics engine, use the jet pack to get into position, drop the bomb on their flag or in their generator room or somewhere, continue at the ludicrous speed, you know, turn around as out of my escape route.
Speaker 0: And as soon as the bomb was set, boom.
Speaker 0: And that was.
Speaker 0: I would spend like games just doing that repeatedly to harass the enemy the whole time while everyone else got the flag or whatever.
Speaker 1: But yeah, there was the the tank, the tank, which was just.
Speaker 1: it was a tank and it required a crew of two.
Speaker 1: And it was great.
Speaker 0: Well, it was.
Speaker 0: it was a little bit slow, but it was.
Speaker 0: that was the point.
Speaker 0: you could get stuck on bad terrain.
Speaker 0: So you had to drive it carefully.
Speaker 1: Oh, driving like that.
Speaker 1: You could also.
Speaker 1: there's a mini base.
Speaker 1: that was this gigantic rig.
Speaker 1: You'd have to drive on the back.
Speaker 1: How many times I'd be trying to drive the base and I'd drive it like up a hill and then I wouldn't make it and it would fall over backwards and kill.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about him one at a time here.
Speaker 1: We don't need to go into depth.
Speaker 0: That's why I want to go to some death.
Speaker 1: We'll go into death later.
Speaker 1: Remember, you're just trying to overview all the things.
Speaker 1: drive to head.
Speaker 0: OK, so I know I said there's the tank, there was the mobile base, which you would basically drive it out, then deploy it and it would stay in one spot.
Speaker 0: And it was sort of like an outpost for you.
Speaker 0: And if you
Speaker 1: want an idea of like the kinds of like the way this game would work, you would often have a base go out there with like a two tank escort and you would have a full eight or nine players like milling about or how doing stuff all around this mobile base, like just doing the kinds of things that you would expect troops to be doing in a real war,
Speaker 0: getting filling up their health, recharging their
Speaker 1: own terms of like.
Speaker 1: the base is going out and you have like the tanks providing escort because people are trying to blow this thing up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the tanks tanks basically had a driver and a giant gun, as you would expect.
Speaker 0: And one person was the gunner and one person was the driver set up out there.
Speaker 1: You've got all these support people going around, like putting land, spike turrets and radars at the perimeter area and kind of securing it.
Speaker 1: Maybe one guy goes up and clears the mountains of any snipers that might be hanging around in the area.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you had the strike, which was a one man fighter jet thing.
Speaker 0: You had the bomber, which is one person flies the bomber.
Speaker 0: One person drops the bombs, which were the biggest explosives in the game.
Speaker 1: Oh, those.
Speaker 1: the only thing more satisfying than dropping those bombs was firing that fucking mortar.
Speaker 0: Yeah, getting indoors.
Speaker 0: And then they had the bomber had one person could stand on the back of the bomber to protect it.
Speaker 0: And then there was the troop transport, which was basically a big, slow plane.
Speaker 0: But like five or six dudes could stand on it.
Speaker 1: Heavy guys, too.
Speaker 1: That's the only thing that heavy guys could ride.
Speaker 0: So it's basically the only way to get guys in heavy armor to the other side of the map in a hurry.
Speaker 0: But it was also a big target.
Speaker 1: Now, the other thing that tribes had was moving on right from the vehicles.
Speaker 1: And I want to get back to the vehicles because they illustrate the point beautifully.
Speaker 1: I talk a lot about strategic depth and tactical depth and all those sorts of things in a game like tribe or like Team Fortress 2.
Speaker 1: The number of strategies on a map or at a given time or the number of tactical options is extremely limited.
Speaker 0: Like you could have a listen, even with the new added stuff.
Speaker 0: OK, how does the pyro have?
Speaker 0: you can choose two different pyro loadouts?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: And you can choose, you know, between two or three or four weapons, maybe.
Speaker 0: And you maybe have a secondary attack or something like that.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Let me go through all the stuff that you had in tribes to just without vehicles.
Speaker 1: OK, so just loadout tactic.
Speaker 1: This is just loadout.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So you could choose light, medium or heavy armor.
Speaker 1: And they all like.
Speaker 1: light is super fast and can't carry much and kind of weak and heavy.
Speaker 0: Obviously, obviously, OK, depending on the armor you picked was how many weapons and which weapons you could carry.
Speaker 0: So you could actually customize your loadout down to which weapons you had.
Speaker 0: So there was, you know, I could choose to have the blaster, the spin fuser and the missile launcher or the blaster, the spin fuser, the missile launcher, the sniper rifle, the chain gun, the Gauss gun.
Speaker 0: You could choose your specific loadout of weapons.
Speaker 0: You could even say just the spin fuser, please.
Speaker 0: No other weapons.
Speaker 1: So what you would do is basically you could save preset.
Speaker 1: So I had like 10 different presets.
Speaker 0: One game came with 10 default preset.
Speaker 1: I made 10 more.
Speaker 0: You could make your own.
Speaker 0: You could say this is the exact configuration of equipment I want.
Speaker 0: And all right.
Speaker 0: So not only was there weapons, some weapons are ammo based, some ones are energy based.
Speaker 0: There were packs.
Speaker 0: Everyone had a pack and you could only choose one pack.
Speaker 0: There was the shield pack, which is pretty much if you activate it, you're pretty much invincible for as long as it's activated.
Speaker 0: But it used your energy.
Speaker 0: You had the energy pack.
Speaker 0: It doubled your energy, which is really good if you want your light, because then you could jet twice as far.
Speaker 0: But it was also really good to get the sniper rifle.
Speaker 1: Well, you had to have it.
Speaker 1: You couldn't use the sniper.
Speaker 0: That's true, because the sniper rifle used a shit ton of energy because it was an energy weapon.
Speaker 0: But say an ammo based weapon doesn't use energy.
Speaker 0: You have an ammo pack to increase your ammo.
Speaker 0: There are a whole bunch of packs, the satchel charge, the bomb.
Speaker 0: I was talking about that I would drop off in the enemy base.
Speaker 1: There was also a whole separate meta game of stuff where you would pick like.
Speaker 1: you could pick up a spike turret or a spider turret or a mini refueling station.
Speaker 1: You could go out and stick these things in place.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: You could pick to have equipment instead of, you know, in addition to your weapons, like, you know, a turret which you could install somewhere on the map that would shoot at other people.
Speaker 0: Or you could have beacons.
Speaker 0: I think everyone has a beacon or two.
Speaker 1: started with a bunch of those.
Speaker 1: Those are everyone.
Speaker 0: Every single player has beacons, mines, grenades, and I think one health pack.
Speaker 1: And don't forget the targeting laser.
Speaker 0: Oh, and everyone has a targeting laser.
Speaker 1: We'll get to that.
Speaker 0: We'll get to that.
Speaker 0: God.
Speaker 0: So the mind so much.
Speaker 0: Look how much shit we're not even half through.
Speaker 0: And this is just some of the shit that everyone has by default.
Speaker 0: How much stuff you have on you by default.
Speaker 1: Now, in addition to that, we said you have a base right on a given map, right?
Speaker 1: You have your base, which is a big building.
Speaker 1: And somewhere in that building is your flag.
Speaker 1: Somewhere else in that building is your generator and the generator.
Speaker 1: Maybe you have multiple generators power things like shields that protect like safe areas of the base or turrets.
Speaker 1: And yes, turrets, because you see in the base all over the place by default and you could put more and move stuff around were turrets.
Speaker 1: And also outside of your bases, there would usually be a bunch of these like towers.
Speaker 1: And in the towers were these giant turrets.
Speaker 1: And you could get a pack that all these different kinds of turret heads and you would fly over there and install it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: For example, outside of the base built into the map is this missile turret.
Speaker 0: And it works in a certain way.
Speaker 0: And I can go out there, I can fly over to it and change it from a missile turret to like a laser turret, an electric turret.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And the electricity turret, what it does, the missile turret locks on to flying things and fires a homing missile.
Speaker 0: The the electricity turret shoots anything in the air and drains energy out of it.
Speaker 0: So if guys are trying to jet jet pack into the base, this is drain all their energy emptying their jet packs.
Speaker 0: They land on the ground and they wouldn't be able to jet.
Speaker 0: And then we blow their brains out.
Speaker 1: Now, in addition to all that, one of the things you could carry was a repair pack.
Speaker 1: And I mentioned generators, because one thing you could do in this game, one of the most important things is that you could destroy anything, anything that moved.
Speaker 0: You could destroy turrets, you could destroy generators, you could destroy the things.
Speaker 0: Basically, there are these things all over the map, vehicles you can destroy.
Speaker 0: There are these things on the map that basically when you want to change your equipment or sort of refresh yourself, like you would spawn, you would immediately enter one of these little stations to sort of equip yourself.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like right now I have nothing.
Speaker 0: But you chose the load out of medium armor, grenade launcher, whatever.
Speaker 0: You're right.
Speaker 0: You walk into one of these stations.
Speaker 0: It goes whoosh, whoosh.
Speaker 0: Now you have your load out.
Speaker 1: It's sort of, you know, so if someone was a spy and they broke into your base, they could destroy all that stuff or break the generators.
Speaker 1: If the generators are down, none of those things work.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So you need to repair the generator in order to.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So they destroyed your generator.
Speaker 1: They might still be in your base.
Speaker 1: Not only security systems aren't working, you have to go in there and get them yourself.
Speaker 1: But you got to keep people defending the now undefended flag because all the turrets around it aren't working.
Speaker 1: Now, also, I keep talking about these turrets.
Speaker 1: There was this.
Speaker 1: there was this command interface to the game.
Speaker 1: You could.
Speaker 1: anyone could look at it at any time.
Speaker 1: The way clans would play is they'd have like their clan leader.
Speaker 0: I still don't believe this.
Speaker 1: Clans played this way.
Speaker 0: Clans, clans.
Speaker 0: I never played with a clan ever.
Speaker 1: Clans played this way.
Speaker 0: What clan did you play with?
Speaker 1: I want to look on YouTube before I see some videos.
Speaker 1: There's this interface.
Speaker 1: There was the interface, though, that would show you everything you could see, because another thing you could put on the map or radar installations.
Speaker 1: And you also started with radar.
Speaker 0: And so they were built in radar installations, sort of like, you know, just like the turrets that are built into the map.
Speaker 0: But just like the turrets, you could deploy little tiny turrets, you know, by hand.
Speaker 0: You could also deploy little sensors by hand.
Speaker 1: But you out there also provide like wherever you were provided a radar radius.
Speaker 1: And also like if a strike was flying, strikes provided this wide radar.
Speaker 1: So you could have a strike flying around the map as recon.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And in the map, because it was so big, you were always the good guys.
Speaker 1: So you'd see all.
Speaker 1: any time there was an ally anywhere in the distance, you'd see like a little green triangle to kind of give you a bearing on where they were.
Speaker 1: If an enemy was in radar range, you would see a red triangle.
Speaker 1: If no radar saw them, unless you saw them with your own eyes, you couldn't see them.
Speaker 1: And furthermore, there's so much to this.
Speaker 1: If you went into that control thing, you could see anything that any radar could see on this big map.
Speaker 1: And you could give orders to people from that map.
Speaker 1: You could also select any turret that your team controlled and take it over and run it manually.
Speaker 0: So if there's a giant missile turret that's built into the map, you could take manual control of that turret to shoot it, guys, instead of letting it do its own thing.
Speaker 0: So between the radar and these turrets and the vehicles and repairing and by the way, if your generators go out, you have no sensors, which means you won't be able to see on your heads up, you know, like that be someone's name would be above them.
Speaker 0: Like if you were on the other side of a hill, you're basically looking at dirt right as you're climbing this hill.
Speaker 0: But if there's a bad guy on the other side of the hill and you have a radar nearby, you'll see his name, you know, sort of floating over his head.
Speaker 0: But you'll know he's on the other side of the hill.
Speaker 0: You have radar, just like Counter Strike, even have radar a lot of times, right?
Speaker 0: But if your sensors are down, you didn't have the radar.
Speaker 0: So imagine if your generators go out, you have no radar, you have no sensors.
Speaker 0: Now you don't know where bad guys are.
Speaker 0: They could be in your base.
Speaker 0: You don't even know where I'm in your base killing you dudes.
Speaker 0: And you don't know where I am.
Speaker 0: I'm just hiding.
Speaker 1: So let's talk a little bit.
Speaker 1: I mean, that we haven't even really touched on everything.
Speaker 1: But what did all this turn into?
Speaker 1: What was play like?
Speaker 1: Like the kinds of strategies or things you would do are a map starts.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, maybe everyone will say, like, I'm going to do this, I'm going to do this.
Speaker 1: People would say, well, you do this, I'll do this and you do this.
Speaker 1: Then the map would start.
Speaker 1: And one strat like one thing, I would go out with another guy and I just go around the map placing radar and obviously skirmishing with people and getting radar in these good positions.
Speaker 1: And then I'd go back.
Speaker 1: Maybe I bring like one of those resupply things with me and I fly all the way out behind the enemy base, this hidden area, and I make a little resupply like place.
Speaker 0: You really you really like doing those support roles of sort of, you know, play with all the infrastructure and build turrets, build stations to help people out.
Speaker 0: You know, other people would be capturing the flag and killing guys, but you would be sort of deploying all the equipment all over the map to make it as easy as possible.
Speaker 0: You know, and then you drive one of those mobile bases out to the halfway point of the base defense, defending a base pair thing.
Speaker 1: You always have like a one or two people who I guess were your engineers who would go around placing and maintaining infrastructure.
Speaker 1: You'd have two or three more people who like maybe one heavy guy who stands near the generator.
Speaker 0: And engineers weren't like TF two where it's build a turret and a dispenser and that's it.
Speaker 1: Engineers were all right.
Speaker 0: There was lots and lots of stuff near the flag.
Speaker 1: Now I'm going to go place these three radars and then, oh, shit, the North Sector turret is down.
Speaker 1: I got to go repair that.
Speaker 1: Guys, the enemies are all over that turret.
Speaker 1: I need an airstrike.
Speaker 1: So then the bomber comes in and takes out all the enemies over there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they can even destroy your vehicle dispensing machine and you had to go repair that shit.
Speaker 1: So, I mean, strategies you would see would be like you two or three snipers go out and surround the enemy base, like in the hills in the distance, and they wait for the signal.
Speaker 1: And the signal is suddenly a bomber flies over dropping bombs everywhere.
Speaker 1: Holy shit.
Speaker 1: So the bomber is taking everything out.
Speaker 1: So you see suddenly the enemy troops are like, ah, shit, and you see him going to their vehicle thing to get some strikes to go off, you know, basically fighter jets and take out this bomber.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, the snipers kill everyone who goes anywhere near that vehicle dispenser.
Speaker 1: And then while you've blown everything up with the bomber and you wouldn't let him build strikes, that's when the troop transport escorted by a strike arrives full of heavies.
Speaker 1: They're in the base firing mortars through the doors, generators are out.
Speaker 1: You've got the flag.
Speaker 1: You give the flag to the quick guy who jumps on the bike that someone else had placed hidden behind a tree near the enemy base early in the game, and he drives back to the base and you can't.
Speaker 1: That's one cap.
Speaker 1: Got another half hour to go.
Speaker 0: Yes, it has to be play the full on game.
Speaker 0: There are actually a lot of times you would play this game without, you know, bases, really.
Speaker 0: It would just be capture the flag, you know, with jet packs.
Speaker 0: And there would be some equipment lying about the map that you could pick up.
Speaker 0: And it was more of a sort of relatively pure FPS.
Speaker 0: And you didn't have the vehicle.
Speaker 1: A lot of don't.
Speaker 1: let me, you know, despite all that strategy that that the stress, knowing the strategy of yes, we'll send a strike escorted bomber to bomb them while we play snipers.
Speaker 1: And then we every single one of those people also had to have crazy mad FPS skills or they were worthless.
Speaker 0: Well, no, but I mean, I'm saying is that the game had had the scale to it.
Speaker 0: The game we're describing is the full load out of 40 on 40 giant map.
Speaker 0: But even the game also had smaller maps that didn't even have bases.
Speaker 0: It had media maps that where you could play on foot, but there were really no vehicles.
Speaker 0: It was sort of just a on foot only map where you had all the equipment, but you didn't have vehicles.
Speaker 1: My favorite mode was siege.
Speaker 1: It was 32 on 32 or 40 on 40.
Speaker 1: And it was literally.
Speaker 1: one team attacks this base.
Speaker 0: One team defends that one team would be on top of the hill and one team would be on the bottom of the hill.
Speaker 0: And you'd basically you'd be.
Speaker 0: one team is pure offense and one team is pure defense.
Speaker 0: And that's it.
Speaker 0: There's also rabbit mode, which would be get the flag and hold on to it as long as you can.
Speaker 1: All the sort of fun things you can do with an FPS.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But in terms of just the pure FPS side of it, you know, whatever, if you're doing the crazy like I am the part of the second squad that attacks as soon as the generators are out from the rear mountains, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 1: The individual combat, the way you would fight was in and of itself one of the best FPS ever.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, you know, some people look at it on the surface level and they're like, OK, I'm going across this map alone and I encounter this dude and he starts dueling me, you know, and we sort of start jumping up and down, shooting at each other.
Speaker 0: And they're like, oh, man, that's pretty stupid.
Speaker 0: You know, why would I stop?
Speaker 0: I just keep going.
Speaker 0: You know, I don't want to have all these little one on one dualies all over the place.
Speaker 0: I want to have a big war.
Speaker 0: You know, the thing you don't realize is that.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: OK, start running away.
Speaker 0: You'll just die.
Speaker 0: if you basically ran into someone in that game, your choices are pretty much either kill them or the other thing was with all the strategy and the way the game would go.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So you are off in like a remote sector like there.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's this remote base and you're stopping by there.
Speaker 0: That was another thing.
Speaker 0: is it was really cool.
Speaker 0: is that the maps are so big.
Speaker 0: there would be sub bases and even sub sub bases.
Speaker 0: And they were actually complicated little structures that might even have basements and upstairs and towers and the whole thing.
Speaker 1: There'd be a lot of times I'd be playing a game and someone would give the call to everyone saying, yeah, the base in the north is totally overrun.
Speaker 1: And we'd have to organize a strike team to go out and clear.
Speaker 0: That's like getting one big base, but also had these little bases that they weren't totally unimportant.
Speaker 0: I mean, people would stop there to, you know, basically recharge and regroup and get their equipment back and all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: But they were all over the map.
Speaker 0: And, you know, sometimes these sort of these neutral bases, you would sort of want to take them for your own and not let the other team, you know, get too much control over them.
Speaker 1: But all right.
Speaker 1: So I'm on my way to my remote outpost to load up and then I'm going to go.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm going to take out the enemy's radar like that's my plan.
Speaker 1: And then I want to snipe.
Speaker 1: I'm going to do this thing to hurt the enemy.
Speaker 1: And I run across.
Speaker 1: I see in the distance in the radar that out in this remote sector where there's no one else nearby, there's another bad guy.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I see him in the distance.
Speaker 1: He's probably like 20 clicks away.
Speaker 1: I don't know what his loadout is.
Speaker 1: For all I know, he's a heavy with mortars.
Speaker 1: who's going to completely fuck me.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Heavy with mortars.
Speaker 0: If you get close, you can get them easily.
Speaker 1: But if you're well, the thing is a heavy with mortars, if you're just a light.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: He's also heavy with plasma and spin that plasma plasma will fuck you up.
Speaker 0: But the thing about it, let me explain the mortars, right?
Speaker 0: Everyone in the game has a laser target or every single person.
Speaker 1: What he would do is if you target something.
Speaker 0: Well, the way we work is you would choose the weapon.
Speaker 1: So I say, oh, what it would do.
Speaker 1: And then you say what it would do and start talking to you, aim it and you shoot it.
Speaker 0: And suddenly you paint a target.
Speaker 1: Everyone knows how that works.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 0: But everyone can see this gigantic, incredibly bright green laser going from you to what you're aiming at.
Speaker 0: It is so obvious.
Speaker 0: It is like everyone in the universe can see this laser when you fire it.
Speaker 0: It is like, oh, there is no hiding when you pull this thing out at whatsoever.
Speaker 1: The real thing is what it is, is you paint a target and anyone else on your team, if they are whatever weapon they're wielding.
Speaker 1: If it is a weapon that could hit that target, it'll show in the sky a reticle and that is with that weapon.
Speaker 1: If you aim at that reticle, you will hit whatever.
Speaker 0: that thing is really only work with the mortar.
Speaker 1: No, it also worked with the missile and the missile and the close range.
Speaker 1: It worked with everything else, too.
Speaker 0: Did it really work with anything else?
Speaker 1: Like only if you had line of sight, like the spin fuser wouldn't show you where to shoot if you couldn't hit it.
Speaker 0: I thought it was mostly used with the mortar and the missile.
Speaker 1: Well, those are the things you're supposed to.
Speaker 0: And the missile really locks on to things, like mostly.
Speaker 0: the missile was mostly for locking on to things in the air and it could lock on to anything in the air on its own.
Speaker 1: The missile could only lock on to something that you had radar sight on.
Speaker 0: Right, if you had radar on it.
Speaker 0: That's what I was about to say.
Speaker 1: Yes, but it could also lock on anything that was targeted with the laser target.
Speaker 1: So you could say your radar is down and you can't see that whatever.
Speaker 1: that's coming to get it with a missile from the turret.
Speaker 1: You paint it and suddenly that turret starts shooting missiles at it.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: But the thing that was so satisfying about that mortar is that you more like you always have a few guys with the mortars or something.
Speaker 0: And the mortar in this game is basically you can only have it if you have heavy armor and it fires this sort of rocket, but it's a bouncy rocket.
Speaker 1: Well, it's a mortar.
Speaker 0: It's slow and it has this huge plume of green smoke that follows.
Speaker 1: It is one of the most satisfying weapons I've ever fired in a game.
Speaker 0: It goes like to doom and this thing goes.
Speaker 1: And it goes off into the distance like a mile.
Speaker 0: It goes stupidly far like you could shoot it halfway across the map, literally.
Speaker 1: So what you would do is like someone say like say all the enemies built their that that drive their rig.
Speaker 1: They have a remote base set up somewhere and they're doing stuff there.
Speaker 1: So your little sniper guy says, hey, guys, I'm going to paint that base.
Speaker 1: You ready to destroy it?
Speaker 1: And everyone says, yes, Shazbot, let's go.
Speaker 1: So he paints it and then all the people with mortars see the radical in the sky.
Speaker 1: They all start shelling this thing.
Speaker 0: It's like for they for like a minute, for a second, they see this green laser appear, this bright green laser.
Speaker 0: And then so they start chasing after who's shooting the green laser?
Speaker 0: because they really have no other option.
Speaker 0: So they go after the sniper and he runs away by the time they get to him.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, from behind them in the sky, just this shower of green smoke.
Speaker 0: And then like the biggest, biggest explosions you've ever seen just destroy everything.
Speaker 0: Now, what's really frightening and the reason why the transport is so incredible, if you can get a heavy armor with a mortar to the other side of the game, to the enemy base inside, you fire those mortars inside and bounce around like crazy.
Speaker 1: And it's so spectacular, basically a nuke.
Speaker 1: It is so amazing.
Speaker 0: You go into the generator room and you just fire like three of them at the walls.
Speaker 0: You don't even need to aim.
Speaker 0: And they just bounce around all over the place with just ridiculous explosions.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: It's basically like like the Fourth of July in your closet.
Speaker 0: is what it's like.
Speaker 1: If the Fourth of July involves being shot at by toxic mortars.
Speaker 0: Like set up an entire fireworks display in your closet while you're in there.
Speaker 1: I do also want to say that equally satisfying was the sniper rifle, which was just perfect in every way.
Speaker 1: Like the way sniping worked in that game was so good.
Speaker 1: Counter striking those games are just too small for sniping to make any sense.
Speaker 1: But in this game, it's true.
Speaker 1: Like literally, if you were a sniper, it was kind of like a real sniper where you kind of went out either by yourself.
Speaker 1: You could use the stealth action or you come with a partner like in some really important game.
Speaker 1: Sometimes like a sniper would go out, but he'd have with him like a medium guy because he'd be kind of bait.
Speaker 1: And then when they came to flush out the sniper nest, oh, shit, there's a medium guy here.
Speaker 1: But you'd like hide in the mountains, pick your target, wait for the critical moment.
Speaker 1: Like, you know, your flag guys coming to do his capture thing.
Speaker 1: So you shoot that heavy and kill him like 10 seconds before your guy arrives.
Speaker 0: That is one thing is like he's great as counter strike is right.
Speaker 0: They have these and it's even Team Fortress two and even the original team fortresses.
Speaker 0: They had the long range and the short range weapons.
Speaker 0: And it sort of makes sense, right?
Speaker 0: You know, there should be long range and short range.
Speaker 0: But really, all those games.
Speaker 0: I mean, even though in Counter Strike, like, say, a P90 or a TMP is not effective at, quote, long range.
Speaker 0: I mean, even the longest range in Counter Strike isn't really long range in terms of me aiming.
Speaker 0: It's just long range in terms of, you know, this weapon has really inaccurate bullets in tribes, too.
Speaker 0: Is the is one of the only games or tribes in general where it long and short range actually makes sense because the rap is so big that 90 percent of the weapons are completely useless.
Speaker 0: I mean, you cannot fire a spin fuser across the map and hope to hit anything.
Speaker 0: It's just not going to happen.
Speaker 0: You really have to use a mortar or a sniper rifle or maybe a missile if you can lock on.
Speaker 0: And that's it.
Speaker 0: Like the plasma gun.
Speaker 0: If you're more than say, you know, like a little bit away from what you're shooting at, it's useless.
Speaker 0: It is a short range only weapon.
Speaker 0: And range makes sense.
Speaker 0: And it actually means something which is not true for any other FPS I can think of.
Speaker 1: Now, if you need any indication of, I guess, how immersed into this game we were, at least how how immersed I was, this actually happened like this.
Speaker 1: This is something that happened so literally and so exactly as I'm about to describe it, that it's a little embarrassing.
Speaker 1: But I scared the ever living shit out of my roommate is a good story.
Speaker 1: So when you play tribes like turrets lock on and they make noise like and that noise was so like, I would really freak out in the game because you hear it.
Speaker 1: And when you hear it, you know, a turd is locking on to.
Speaker 0: usually the maps are somewhat symmetrical.
Speaker 0: You knew where the enemy turrets were, right?
Speaker 0: You would only really go over there.
Speaker 0: You would try to find a path to circle around back or you'd go so fast that the turrets couldn't lock on you or you would basically try to avoid turrets in any way you could.
Speaker 0: But sometimes they would hide like a like a, you know, a wall mount, a spider clam turret, spider clam turret somewhere.
Speaker 1: And you'd be like, fuck, but there was a generator to be down.
Speaker 1: But then as you were coming in, they would be they would fix them and then to get how many times that happened to be like I'd be in the enemy base, like ready to do some business.
Speaker 1: The generators are out and suddenly the lights turn back on and I hear like three turrets locking on to me and I just go fuck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: So I'm playing this game a lot.
Speaker 1: You know, I hear that sound, especially because of the kind of roles I played.
Speaker 1: I've run afoul of turrets a lot.
Speaker 1: And I'd like my reaction to a turret was this kind of, oh, shit, I get out of the.
Speaker 1: So I'm sleeping, I'm in my dorm room, in my bunk bed above my computer, and I am asleep.
Speaker 1: I'm sound asleep and I'm woken up by the exact sound that that turret makes.
Speaker 1: And I kid you not, I yelled turret, but swung around, knocked the arm that keeps you from falling out of your bed off my bed and then fell out of my bed onto the floor, knocked my computer chair over.
Speaker 1: It is crash bang and I turn it.
Speaker 1: I'm laying on the ground, fucking hurt because it's a giant bruise in my side.
Speaker 1: And I look around and I look out the window and I see that there's some cherry picker out there doing some work on something.
Speaker 0: The arm of the cherry picker moves, it goes every time it moved, it made the noise of a turret.
Speaker 1: And then I look up and I see my roommate staring at me and he says, are you OK?
Speaker 1: And I say, false alarm.
Speaker 1: And I went back to bed.
Speaker 1: I had a bruise for like a week.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that can happen.
Speaker 1: We would walk around campus just going.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, you know, we had to go in order to get back to the dorm room quickly enough to play more tribes.
Speaker 1: I mean, Scott bought the game right away.
Speaker 1: I saw the game and I went out the next day.
Speaker 1: I bought like the second to last copy at that Best Buy.
Speaker 0: The GameStop was sold out and I had so little money.
Speaker 0: It's sold out on preorders even.
Speaker 0: I have a PC game at a GameStop.
Speaker 1: I spent it was 2001.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: I spent money that I was intending to spend on textbooks.
Speaker 1: I did not buy textbooks because I bought tribes, too.
Speaker 1: It was worth every penny.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, my favorite.
Speaker 1: My favorite roles and play in the game.
Speaker 1: I love being the strike pilot.
Speaker 1: I get my joystick out.
Speaker 1: I get in a strike and I escort bombers and I take out other strikes and I'd strafe like if this if the guy was getting it with the flag, I just strafe him as soon as he got on top of me.
Speaker 0: And it really, really makes me sad to think about like exactly how much how long this game lived, because I mean, we bought it in March of 01.
Speaker 0: That's when it came out.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: By the next year, when you're living in colony, the game was dead.
Speaker 1: That game was so lasted maybe less than five months before we played it in colony quite a bit.
Speaker 0: In fact, I don't remember that.
Speaker 1: Yes, we did.
Speaker 1: In fact, I upgraded my computer and was able to play it better.
Speaker 0: I don't remember playing it in colony at all.
Speaker 0: I remember.
Speaker 0: I remember playing it, you know, freshman year after it came out, I remember playing it at home over that summer.
Speaker 0: And then that was all I remember.
Speaker 1: We definitely played it in colony quite a bit.
Speaker 0: I don't remember it.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I don't know.
Speaker 1: How you couldn't.
Speaker 1: That was some of the best times.
Speaker 0: Now they both play on the same server because both are compared to definitely in the freshman year where the game was fresh.
Speaker 1: How could you not remember, Scott?
Speaker 1: We would both our computers were in the living room.
Speaker 1: We would play on the same server on the same team like every time.
Speaker 0: I remember doing Counter-Strike like that.
Speaker 0: I remember doing tribes like that.
Speaker 0: I remember being dead by then.
Speaker 1: That's really weird.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I don't think I want to talk about what like why tribes to fell and what happened to it because basically they kept.
Speaker 1: we don't we don't even need.
Speaker 1: it's so sad.
Speaker 1: It wasn't even just the patches.
Speaker 1: It was the modding community and the fact that the developers basically listened to all the people telling them what to do with their game instead of just leaving well enough alone.
Speaker 0: Here is something interesting about tribes.
Speaker 0: to is the first game, at least as far as I could tell, where it came with a built in and decent matchmaking system for, you know, starting servers, joining games, leaving games, finding servers to play on this whole community thing.
Speaker 0: It had a forum built into the game and email email built into the game.
Speaker 0: I had tribes email address.
Speaker 1: clans were built into the game, like playing the game as a clan, your clan leadership and all that stuff and voting and everything we had into the game.
Speaker 0: We had an RIT logo in the game on our clan, like, you know, the tiger and the whole thing was in the game.
Speaker 0: You can go to our RIT clan page if it was still up and people could join and leave the clan and you could pick the clan leader and vote and kick in the whole chat rooms, even for the whole everything, a whole gaming community built into the game, not like games today, where if there's a community, it's on the website, it's separate.
Speaker 0: This is, you know, your tabs in the game were pretty much list of servers, chat room, your email, the forum, your clan.
Speaker 0: It was crazy.
Speaker 0: And the problem is they paid attention to that forum and they did what people in the forum asked, and that ruined the game.
Speaker 1: But that game was just so good.
Speaker 0: It was so good.
Speaker 0: I mean, look at how many Webcomics there are about this game.
Speaker 1: I mean, in a short I spent about 10 minutes and I found 18 Webcomics about tribes, too.
Speaker 0: If I'd included tribes one and this is only two Webcomics, bad boys, computer science and penny arcade.
Speaker 1: I didn't even look anywhere else.
Speaker 0: You didn't even look at any other gaming Webcomics.
Speaker 0: Maybe there's some PVPs about it.
Speaker 0: Maybe there's.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there's plenty other gaming comics out there.
Speaker 0: That have tribes, too.
Speaker 1: I mean, if I if I were to rank and that's just comics, it was just comics.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much tribes to weapons factory, Counter-Strike, Mega TF, Natural Selection.
Speaker 1: That's fucking hit Action Quake.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So we've got.
Speaker 0: there was also like some mods to tribes, too.
Speaker 0: They were all awful.
Speaker 0: Well, there was.
Speaker 0: there was the legacy one that was like so it would play more like tribes one.
Speaker 0: Remember that?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was in the dying days that that started picking up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, stuff like that.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of reasons that tribes, too, started to collapse.
Speaker 1: I mean, patches didn't just make the game worse.
Speaker 1: They actually broke the game, like at least five or six of the patches they released actually broke the game to where it would not start.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then suddenly no one was playing tribes because they'd broken the game.
Speaker 0: And the only way to like this huge, huge, huge, huge number of servers and number of users.
Speaker 0: when the game was brand new and within a few months, it was really.
Speaker 0: it was actually hard to find a full game of 40 people.
Speaker 0: But the best times are when those servers are full.
Speaker 1: It lasted longer than a few months.
Speaker 0: I remember very distinctly it was still being played, I guess, you know, later.
Speaker 1: You considering you don't remember us playing in colony, you really have no right to talk.
Speaker 0: I don't remember being played in colony anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, tribes, too, for the.
Speaker 0: I don't know what else to say.
Speaker 1: So anyone who thinks that Team Fortress two is a good FPS, you don't know what you're talking about.
Speaker 0: God, if you've never played tribes to if you've never played a full game of tribes to meet a lot of people who played tribes to didn't even realize all the stuff that could be done.
Speaker 1: I mean, I know there was a like the clan interface for like the commanding troops until about a month after I was I clicked on.
Speaker 0: most people played and never used a grenade or a mine at all.
Speaker 0: They didn't realize they had them, but they're.
Speaker 0: everyone has them and they're super important.
Speaker 0: They're actually different kinds of grenades.
Speaker 0: They're flash grenades and explosive grenades and the whole thing.
Speaker 0: They're different kinds of mines, too.
Speaker 0: I think I forget which kinds, though.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's OK, we're done.
Speaker 1: I'm just going to start going crazy about this game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I love tribes to tribes to all tribes to combine.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: it's like that one time we played Crystal Chronicles over the course of an entire weekend.
Speaker 1: It just it will.
Speaker 1: it will live in my heart as some of the greatest gaming I've ever had.
Speaker 0: So we're trying to get tribes to go in again.
Speaker 0: We got the client worked as somebody in the forum posted like a how to thing.
Speaker 0: So I followed it and I got the game to work.
Speaker 0: I just need a server to play on.
Speaker 0: And we're in business because the authentication servers and all that stuff are down now.
Speaker 0: See what you need to do to play is you need to play the single player land mode.
Speaker 0: But then when you're on the server selection screen that looks for land servers, you push the insert key on your keyboard and you type in an IP address.
Speaker 0: And that allows you to play on, you know, remote servers.
Speaker 0: But you need to know the IP address of the servers.
Speaker 0: And I have been able to find any.
Speaker 0: so someone can find a working tribe server.
Speaker 0: because I found some websites that were like, here's an IP address for a tribes to server.
Speaker 0: No, the server is not there anymore.
Speaker 0: So anyone could set up a server or knows where a server is at or anything.
Speaker 1: We're working on it, especially with the current schedule of you guys.
Speaker 0: We will probably want like if if and when this comes up, we will schedule a time and we will play tribes, but you can set up the client as a how to and it's you can download the game for free and the whole thing.
Speaker 1: So this has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays we have video games, board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights and Thursdays are the catch alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.