Speaker 0: It's Wednesday March 19th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm sky, and this is geek knives tonight.
Speaker 0: We talked about a comic with dungeon Dungeon.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So tomorrow, it's not gonna be a show probably most likely.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's probably gonna be a show.
Speaker 0: I might just do it with Emily.
Speaker 1: you gonna do with Emily.
Speaker 0: I just might.
Speaker 0: we'll see tired I am.
Speaker 1: no my work has decided that The tech department in the media department Which is pretty much the cool half of the people at work Gonna do some bowling action.
Speaker 1: and bowling is not the greatest thing in the world, but you know bowling with work little Co-worker rivalry.
Speaker 1: try to support the the tech peeps.
Speaker 1: It'll be pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 0: I remember the last time when bowling with the front row crew.
Speaker 0: that was a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well you know I think if like I joined a bowling league I'd get bored.
Speaker 1: But you know bowling once in a while sure whatever throw heavy rock at some sticks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, honestly the main reason I didn't bowl for a long time was that bowling alleys are by and large Disgusting.
Speaker 1: that is that is.
Speaker 1: a major problem is if they there are in existence bowling alleys that are not disgusting But they are few and far between.
Speaker 1: most of them are sleazy holes for sort of scary Shlubby unpleasant people.
Speaker 0: one thing that really helped at RIT in particular is when New York State finally banned smoking pretty much inside.
Speaker 1: That helps so much.
Speaker 1: Before that bowling alleys are like the smokiest of.
Speaker 1: you might as well just call the smoking huts.
Speaker 1: I mean there.
Speaker 1: if you go to a bowling alley that isn't super new most likely like you know the machines that you know Take you know make the bowling balls roll.
Speaker 1: You know back come back to you.
Speaker 1: and These you know.
Speaker 1: the seats that are sort of built into the bowling alley are just like they have ashtrays all built in all of them.
Speaker 0: I just remember that it was always tricky to find good DDR and every now and then like I remember the extreme machine the first one in art at RIT was in a bowling alley.
Speaker 0: yes, and We we went there once and the smoke was so bad.
Speaker 0: We I about passed out trying to dance on that stupid thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz bowling alleys are one of the few places every bowling alley has like a few arcade machines.
Speaker 1: It's one of the few places still left where you can play some arcade games in the US.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course God that place it had like the worst food ever.
Speaker 1: you don't eat food in the bowling alley you crazy.
Speaker 0: No, I never actually ate it, but the fact that it was there Well, I mean I guess you get.
Speaker 1: if you really wanted to you can get like a soda or something.
Speaker 0: Well, there was a pretty nice bowling alley.
Speaker 0: know where I grew up and we whenever there's a half-day of school There were oftentimes we'd all kind of meet at the bowling alley, but we wouldn't actually Bowl.
Speaker 0: We play arcade games like kick us out.
Speaker 1: Remember when I was when I was way little.
Speaker 1: There was a period of time where my mom would Bowl and then they had like a daycare at the bowling alley and they had He-man castle and I seemed her this is I was must have been stupidly young like one or two at the time.
Speaker 1: Well must have been at least two because it was in Connecticut.
Speaker 1: So two or three I'm.
Speaker 1: I was stupidly young and I don't remember very clearly But I seem to remember that perhaps I was responsible for breaking the he-man castle.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow You're that fucker.
Speaker 0: and maybe Actually, I took a bowling class at RIT.
Speaker 1: Yeah, me too.
Speaker 1: I take the same class only not with you with random people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those right around the time.
Speaker 0: My car was broken down and then while it was broken down.
Speaker 0: We drove to Chicago.
Speaker 1: No, this is this.
Speaker 1: I took it in like my final year.
Speaker 1: I held it out.
Speaker 0: That class actually taught me that I really really really don't like bowling.
Speaker 1: It taught me Throw the ball straight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll get about a 150 every time.
Speaker 0: What it actually taught me was if you just bowl twice a week You'll you're just gonna constantly get better until you're as good as anyone else out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well the pros will be a little bit better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the level beyond that is the people who actually can tell how like depending how much oil is on the stupid thing Or correct for the different.
Speaker 1: they got the ball that's the exact right way and they got the gloves and the shoes and the.
Speaker 0: but my average went from 70 up to about 160 and then after I stopped going to that class it went right back down to 70.
Speaker 1: I think mine is pretty much right where it is.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's gonna move a whole lot in my life because I never get a bowl enough to get it up and I'm Gonna you know lose this or it would take a long time of not playing for me to lose the throw the ball straight.
Speaker 0: Well, you know you seem to have a lot more innate bowling talent than I ever do.
Speaker 1: perhaps I do but maybe that's from how many times and I was a kid and whatever that like how many I I'm guessing about half the birthday parties.
Speaker 1: I went to as a kid were bowling out.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 0: I went to major magics almost every time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we went to bowling alleys about half the time and it was usually duck pin bowling But whatever, of course I have recently discovered through friends who live northern of us about the candlestick bowling that I thought was you know No longer so existent.
Speaker 1: but the candlestick bowling still exists in the Massachusetts and other places and I want to do it real bad next time we head up that way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, man candlestick bowling is the hot but in the news this was mentioned briefly But now it's getting closer and closer to actually happening and I kind of want to talk about this a little bit.
Speaker 0: Slayers as you know is one of the like Classic classic anime.
Speaker 0: it's like hilarious comedy.
Speaker 0: if you haven't seen it You should.
Speaker 1: it is pretty much the fantasy comedy anime plus.
Speaker 1: Can you think of another fantasy comedy anime?
Speaker 0: I mean you might watch it nowadays and go.
Speaker 0: that's kind of cliched.
Speaker 0: But this is one of those shows that started a lot of those cliches.
Speaker 1: is the cliche?
Speaker 1: It wouldn't have been cliche if slayers didn't exist.
Speaker 1: I mean if I made if slayers didn't exist and I made a comedy fantasy.
Speaker 0: now The Gallery that one of the has a sweat bubble, you know, the like the sweat bubble like oh, I'm nervous.
Speaker 1: This is Emma's have been your favorite joke in the whole show.
Speaker 1: It was well that in koala My favorite joke in the whole show was go get through real quick.
Speaker 0: She grabs a sweat beat and beats him with it.
Speaker 0: But anyway, and also the fish man, you know, the fish man keep coming back.
Speaker 0: I know the fish man is the best But slayers is most excellent as in slightly I don't like the OEVs as much but slayers slayers next slayers.
Speaker 0: Try one after the other.
Speaker 1: We've done shows on slayers before at least once or twice.
Speaker 0: However, there was big news that try gun was getting a movie and also slayers was getting another season.
Speaker 0: and unlike most times When a show that was good suddenly they say hey, there's another one like hey, we're making another tenchi.
Speaker 0: Moo.
Speaker 0: Yo You're all want to see another tenchi.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't you never mind the fact that we got a different director who actually sucks?
Speaker 1: Well, who's the director of the slayers anime?
Speaker 0: the slayers anime is being done right on every account.
Speaker 0: They've got apparently most of the original cast.
Speaker 0: They've got the original like everything is set for this to be perfect and they have now announced the title of this new slayers.
Speaker 0: It was slayers slayers.
Speaker 0: next slayers try and I'm sure it's gonna be renamed because it's currently slayers Revolution.
Speaker 0: All right, so I think we can look forward to seeing slayers we in a couple of years.
Speaker 1: Why I just let it go.
Speaker 0: I couldn't let it go.
Speaker 1: Hey, so slayers next try revolution.
Speaker 1: I guess sort of almost goes together to mean something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can.
Speaker 1: you can if you try real hard Of course.
Speaker 0: then there's all the OAV titles like gorgeous Excellence and then there's the movie which is just layer.
Speaker 1: next try gorgeous.
Speaker 1: Excellent revolution.
Speaker 1: the movie the motion picture motion picture.
Speaker 0: Sorry me pros Island, right?
Speaker 0: Ah but this is probably not true, but according to the anime news network a statement was made tonic tongue-in-cheek that Zellows is actually the main character and not Lena.
Speaker 0: and while that is probably not true.
Speaker 0: That would be so awesome Zellows is the best character ever in anything except I don't think ever actually saw him that much.
Speaker 0: Zellows doesn't in what you saw.
Speaker 1: He's not in the first season at all.
Speaker 1: Hello Isn't that the guy who's made of rocks?
Speaker 1: no, that's Zell goddess, okay Zellows I was close to service.
Speaker 0: L Zellows is the awesome.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 0: Awesome guy who's so awesome?
Speaker 1: Prince what's-his-face?
Speaker 0: Prince?
Speaker 0: Phil is awesome in a different way with his pacifist crush.
Speaker 0: Okay, so yeah, that's all I got.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I tried to find a news.
Speaker 1: there were some news items like the initial is gonna be an initial d-manga.
Speaker 1: Makoto Shinkai has something new Bandai visual is sucking more than usual Etc, etc.
Speaker 1: But I got nothing much to say about those that I didn't just say.
Speaker 1: so I'm gonna do a geek bite a geek bite.
Speaker 1: What I have here that I that I ordered based on title alone is crayon Shinshan the manga volume 1 in English Published by CMX.
Speaker 1: if you don't know CMX is actually DC Comics in disguise.
Speaker 0: We talked about that last week.
Speaker 0: I think yep.
Speaker 1: And if you don't crayon Shinshan is by Yoshito Usui.
Speaker 1: now I knew the name crayon Shinshan.
Speaker 1: How could you be an anime fan and not at least have that ring a bell?
Speaker 0: I'm sure some of you were going.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if I see if I could recognize crayon Shinshan, I could pick him out of a lineup at the police station.
Speaker 1: But and I knew that it was infamous for being dirty and I knew it was a comedy But I'd never read it and I'd never watched the anime.
Speaker 1: So I said, you know what?
Speaker 1: I owe it as an anime fan I owe it to myself to at least get volume 1 of the manga.
Speaker 1: now Now see what the deal is.
Speaker 1: just to know even if it's not good, even if I don't like it.
Speaker 1: It's such a big sort of famous kind of anime.
Speaker 1: You gotta why I gotta watch or read or something to know.
Speaker 0: a lot of people because this happens a lot in anime Especially just because there's so much out there now.
Speaker 0: But you see a lot of people.
Speaker 0: people see Harlock and Mital and Totoro all over the place.
Speaker 1: People even cut as much anymore, but but you see him like.
Speaker 0: you see it and you go.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's that character.
Speaker 0: How many people have seen any of that?
Speaker 1: not enough now at least not in this country?
Speaker 0: Yeah, not nearly enough Of course, I do point out again I found it funny that when Emily's friend from Japan was visiting he Noted that our anime collection is the collection of old fogies and we watch old weird stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he should have gone to go see what Gerald is watching.
Speaker 0: well You should show me thing of the day, but we'll get to that.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: So crayon Shinshan for people who don't know this is basically what the deal is.
Speaker 1: There's this mom and she's sort of like a really normal kind of person like she acts the way Moms with kids do you know?
Speaker 1: and and it's it's pretty realistic like even for being Jap.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's the translation cuz.
Speaker 1: I definitely can tell that the people who translated this did a great deal of adaptation.
Speaker 1: But you know, even though it's Japanese it really feels like she's you know US mom with an annoying kid.
Speaker 1: and the thing is this kid Crayon Shinshan, I guess Shinshan crayon, I guess is just sort of like, you know the name of the manga.
Speaker 1: the kids name is Shinshan is Like the worst behaved kid in the entire universe.
Speaker 0: Welcome to that show.
Speaker 1: slash manga Like you imagine like try to imagine how bad a kid could be right like stealing killing Right.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: He's not doing stuff on that level.
Speaker 1: It's not bad in the like baby Hitler It's bad in the bad in the problem John and he makes mom's life as miserable as possible.
Speaker 0: I think I can sum up what it's like to be around someone like that.
Speaker 0: cuz people like that exist You know, they do.
Speaker 0: I can sum it up in one sound Right and it's like.
Speaker 1: so let me give you an example.
Speaker 1: all this book is is a bunch of little short stories like.
Speaker 1: they're like each one is like two or three pages of manga that tell a short little vignette of.
Speaker 1: you know Shinshan and his mom sometimes his dad and sometimes it's really cute dog that sort of gets in on at the action.
Speaker 1: Here's the one.
Speaker 1: he goes to the store as a tricycle, right?
Speaker 1: so he's like buy me buy me buy me buy me buy me buy me right.
Speaker 1: and Well, and the mom's like hell.
Speaker 1: no, right?
Speaker 1: Like you do so Shinshan picks up his mom's skirt looks under it and it's like polka dots.
Speaker 1: It's pretty bad right there Alright, so the mom is just like embarrassed in the store, right?
Speaker 1: So inch, but she's still not buying the tricycle.
Speaker 1: So Shinshan goes starts walking towards this other Complete stranger hot lady in the store and it says I wonder what color her panties are Mom's like, is that a threat?
Speaker 0: That those are the kind of scenes.
Speaker 0: I'll admit I love that kind of humor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the bluff calling mom that sort of thing on
Speaker 1: the next panel says the tricycle was delivered the next day And he goes on from there and there's a couple pages of him you know making trouble with the tricycle like crashing it into things and being stupid and really pissing mom off.
Speaker 1: and Yeah, um, you know it some of it was funny Some of it was just sort of blatantly dirty Some of it wasn't just sort of frustrating, you know, it was sort of it made you feel good.
Speaker 0: Well, I know you seem to have a problem where whenever you're watching a movie any movie any reading a comic anything and a character Does something you think is stupid you just go?
Speaker 0: And it bothers you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's not so much stupid going on here It's mostly just Shinshan makes life frustrating.
Speaker 1: you laugh, but you feel frustrated with the mom, but then the mom Overreacts and she's kind of crazy.
Speaker 0: Frustrated you were when we tried to watch bringing up baby.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was pretty fresh.
Speaker 1: Yeah this comic I actually think I don't know if I buy more because it seems like it's just the same Joke twisted slightly different over and over again.
Speaker 1: So like why should I get more?
Speaker 1: It's just you know, it's just more of the same but it's worth it to buy the one volume totally worth it Especially since this thing costs eight dollars and I paid way less than eight dollars.
Speaker 1: I paid probably like five dollars, but yeah, it's totally worth it.
Speaker 1: and I actually think Contrary to you know, what I guess might be the target audience.
Speaker 1: I think this comic would really appeal to moms Because they would totally identify with the mom in the cabin.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna try to get.
Speaker 1: see if my mom will read this.
Speaker 1: see if she'll she'll probably have much nostalgia for raising me and my siblings.
Speaker 0: So I guess the moral is by crayon Shinshan for your mom.
Speaker 1: Yeah by just you know one volume I wouldn't buy more than one volume unless you really like it.
Speaker 1: but by one volume Why the hell not?
Speaker 0: are you really like your mom?
Speaker 0: Anyway things of the day now, we've reviewed utana a while ago, but we reviewed it in one of those You know, we talked a lot about why the show is good But we didn't really go into a lot of detail because it's a show that totally Totally can be spoiled a thousand times over and also so complicated that would take us like four shows to actually talk about it.
Speaker 0: So, uh, this is related to that only tangentially.
Speaker 0: But as I have to point out that you didn't listen to that review listen to it.
Speaker 0: If you haven't seen shoujo kakame utana, and you're an anime fan again, what the hell's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: That's like one of the greatest anime ever made.
Speaker 0: No anyway the one thing about utana is that a lot of people watch it and they finish it and All man and like every anime fan you want more but you know, there's no more.
Speaker 1: so they go to the movie.
Speaker 1: You're going to the movie.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to the movie now.
Speaker 0: everyone wanted more cowboy bebop But they knew that they shouldn't and couldn't get more.
Speaker 1: and then they made a movie.
Speaker 0: the movie came out.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I was like, oh man, but the movie came out with the knowledge that you really won't get any more now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the movie was sort of not.
Speaker 1: it was good, but it wasn't as good as the series.
Speaker 0: Well, it was just a long episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty long high production value episode.
Speaker 0: That was it.
Speaker 0: Yep, but with utana Oh, I want more and then you might see oh, there's a movie.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna say right now don't watch that movie Just stay far away from attending the movie.
Speaker 1: It has nothing to do with the 10 of the TV show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, there's one thing to do with it The same characters in the same setting kinda kinda but Actually, I should link on to an aside.
Speaker 0: But if you want to actually want to see the utana movie I'll link you at some point maybe in the forum to an anime music video from the movie.
Speaker 0: Watch that pretend that was the movie and get on with your life.
Speaker 0: But uh, there is one other thing.
Speaker 0: utana was Manga, I forget the manga cuz the manga is so different that you would read the manga as like a precursor Like.
Speaker 0: this is the core of what became that because the manga was all Chiyo Saito II and the show was all Chiyo Saito and Ikuhara and the movie was all Ikuhara and only the middle was good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the manga is okay.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying I like Chiyo Saito a lot.
Speaker 1: I like the part.
Speaker 1: I like the manga volumes that do the funny stories like the multi power curry.
Speaker 0: But a lot of people want more 10 and there's not much more utana out there.
Speaker 1: did someone did some fan makes a mutana?
Speaker 0: Oh, no, I'm talking about something as far as you haven't brought up yet because the drama the stage show the musical.
Speaker 0: Um that is going to be wiped from my mind.
Speaker 0: No, I can't unwatch that.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I'm really dead.
Speaker 1: I don't know where you're going now.
Speaker 0: There was a Sega Saturn game.
Speaker 0: Oh You're right there was and the Sega Saturn game from what I have been told from everyone who has ever played it is absolutely fantastic.
Speaker 0: so in the spirit of like the utana show so perfect and awesome and hilarious that Well besides never been translated in English as far as I've seen.
Speaker 1: I've got a translated Sega Saturn game.
Speaker 1: It's not an easy feat.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Found some quote-unquote roms.
Speaker 0: I once forgot it to work a little bit, but that was a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I should try again.
Speaker 0: I'm sure I'd have better luck.
Speaker 1: Yeah You have a better luck if buying a Japanese take a Saturn in the game and yeah And like doing one of those proxy yahoo auction things.
Speaker 0: I have a script to this day.
Speaker 0: I have a text file.
Speaker 0: That is the script to the game.
Speaker 0: Oh, then yeah, I'm all ready to play this game.
Speaker 0: But My thing of the day in case you didn't know that game exists my thing of the day is the opener to that game and If you're still interested after the opener a good five minutes of the initial gameplay You
Speaker 1: should put a bounty out to anyone who can get you the game.
Speaker 0: if anyone gets me I'll say this if anyone gets me the utana Sega Saturn game in a playable form in English I'll give you like 200 bucks.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, if you just get me the game and it plays I'll give you something far less.
Speaker 0: prior geek night's t-shirt.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which don't exist yet.
Speaker 0: Hey, they will someday.
Speaker 0: Actually when you guys finally see the design for our first t-shirt is pretty hot.
Speaker 1: So my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: as far as period.
Speaker 0: to your thing of the day I got to say one last thing.
Speaker 0: It's so sad.
Speaker 0: the toga gets to show his nipples and Akio gets to show his nipples like more So than anyone's ever showed nipples before.
Speaker 0: but no one lets I own just show his nipples.
Speaker 0: Okay, I'm done.
Speaker 1: I thought you're gonna say no one gets to see you tennis nipples wouldn't that?
Speaker 1: Wouldn't that be more what people want anyway?
Speaker 1: Anyway, so a lot of people are like, you know, what's the first anime?
Speaker 1: and just sort of say astro boy, you know That's.
Speaker 1: that's true in the sense that astro boy Was the first anime.
Speaker 1: that was like a TV series, you know, you know There's an episode on.
Speaker 1: you know new episodes all the time.
Speaker 1: It continued.
Speaker 1: There was it wasn't very serial each episode.
Speaker 1: it was very episodic But it was the first like anime TV show that you know carried on.
Speaker 1: But that doesn't mean there was no animation in Japan before Tezuka.
Speaker 1: There were people in Japan making animations before Tezuka.
Speaker 1: here is one of maybe it's not the best because I don't have a lot to compare it to but this particular incredibly old Japanese animation is Sort of a Steamboat Willie quality to it and it is.
Speaker 1: it has many things for the American anime fan to enjoy despite not having a translation Okay.
Speaker 1: So basically here's the deal.
Speaker 1: This is a Anime black and white.
Speaker 1: it was made in the year 1934. the title of it is something something I can't read 1936. so it's a story about two years in the future and basically the story is this Cute animated characters live on an island and they're happy.
Speaker 1: Evil someone comes to bomb them.
Speaker 1: You'll see who the someone is.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna spoil as evil someone evil someone.
Speaker 0: Oh my They.
Speaker 1: and then they fight the evil someone and all the you know.
Speaker 1: Basically, you won't recognize it unless you know about Japanese fairy tales But all the you know folklore heroes of Japanese fairy tales.
Speaker 1: So think it would be the same as if like Humpty Dumpty and Mother Goose and the three little pigs came to save the day.
Speaker 1: it's it's sort of like that but Japanese and they come to save the day and there's a little bit of voice acting and as a Little bit of music and the sound effects are actually not so bad and the animation is pretty impressive for 1934 I guess and this is well worth watching all eight minutes of I Guarantee it.
Speaker 1: This is not only historic not only educational but it is still entertaining after About 70 80 years.
Speaker 0: I do have to say one thing though The semi main tiger guy is really creepy.
Speaker 1: The tiger is really fucking creepy.
Speaker 1: The snakes are kind of cool Especially the one part where they're like head up head down head up head there where they do a little dance And they have the machine gun lightning tongues.
Speaker 1: That's pretty good.
Speaker 1: There's some other parts in there that are pretty good, too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is good stuff.
Speaker 1: people you should totally check out this.
Speaker 1: actually I don't know if I ever made it a thing of the day, but there is sort of like this Museum ish like movie company.
Speaker 1: I forgot I have a link in my delicious somewhere way back where they sell like a DVD set that has like all the ancient Animes like this, I guess 1934 is ancient and like all in one DVD set, but it's a ludicrous amount of money.
Speaker 1: So I've never bought it, but I might buy it
Speaker 0: Right, so we're not talking about anime tonight, we'll probably talk about anime next week on Wednesday, but we have something Something we've waited mostly because we wanted to make sure that both of us had read all of it in its entirety.
Speaker 1: We actually have one more volume of it coming.
Speaker 1: Yeah yeah, but anyway the Did I do a geek back on this.
Speaker 1: a geek bite on this.
Speaker 0: previously you might have but now we can review this in fullness.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: well we were going to review is a comic.
Speaker 1: it's actually a French comic called dungeon Written by.
Speaker 1: I still don't know how to pronounce this dude's name even though I have like a whole bunch of comics written by him.
Speaker 1: is it like John's far?
Speaker 1: I think the last name has to be far, but the first name is either like Joan or John or so and it's not Joanne.
Speaker 1: I think it's like John's far.
Speaker 1: I think is the correct way to pronounce it.
Speaker 1: I'm probably wrong, but whatever.
Speaker 1: This is the same guy who wrote like the ramp the Eisner award-winning rabbi's cat Professor's daughter Klezmer which is amazing.
Speaker 1: I can't think of any others, but they're all awesome.
Speaker 0: Now the thing about this comic is that they're a whole but like it's almost it's kind of hard to figure out the order.
Speaker 0: Luckily, there's a little guide in the front of most of them and also we're gonna tell you right now Pretty much it's.
Speaker 0: it's about a dungeon and it's set like.
Speaker 0: there's the main comic Which is like during the zenith the height of the dungeon and then there's parade which is just more fun going on during that good Part of the dungeon and then there's the early years and then there's the Twilight and then there's the other one.
Speaker 0: We haven't read the side stories the monsters.
Speaker 1: Yes, basically if you like, you know, if you like things like like dungeon keeper or sort of like Trying to think of something else similar to this
Speaker 0: pretty much dungeon keeper
Speaker 1: yeah, basically anything where it's sort of like there's a happy dungeon and it's like there's a bunch of monsters and It's sort of like a comedic fantasy.
Speaker 1: Everyone's hanging out in the dungeon.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of cool characters.
Speaker 1: There's lots of stuff.
Speaker 1: It's a big complicated dungeon and all sorts of little happy adventures happen in this dungeon and it's it's just a good time all around You know, you got what's his name Marvin.
Speaker 1: the dinosaur is the best you got.
Speaker 1: Herbert the duck.
Speaker 0: He's more of a dragon than a dinosaur is.
Speaker 1: yeah, but he loses wings and then he's sort of dinosaur.
Speaker 0: ish Then he is.
Speaker 0: he's still a dragon.
Speaker 0: He's a breath weapon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess okay.
Speaker 1: He's a dragon.
Speaker 1: You got my favorite characters on go.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think my favorite character in the end is either the dungeon keeper or the duck.
Speaker 0: Really really really like Marvin the dungeon keeper is high-quality.
Speaker 1: Marvin's alright, but Zongo is by far the best.
Speaker 1: There's no competition for Zongo.
Speaker 0: This is actually about all told Theoretically, it's about this dungeon and the dungeon is like a typical fantasy dungeon But it's run like a business and it just it.
Speaker 0: It's a comic that takes itself seriously in that totally non serious way that as a result makes it really really good.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's basically.
Speaker 1: each volume is sort of like two stories almost and Each story is like it's a comedic story.
Speaker 1: But at the same time they have some sort of like lesson and moral in the story and it's it's sort of It's impressively highbrow for something that is so like slapstick and silly at most of the time.
Speaker 0: So I think we'll start with the good stuff and work our way down to the bad parts.
Speaker 1: All right, so Done I'm not exactly sure.
Speaker 1: like the quote.
Speaker 1: correct reading order.
Speaker 0: forget that we're going to order from good to bad All right.
Speaker 1: So dungeon zenith is the two volumes that are about the like the height of the dungeon when the dungeon is at its peak Operating efficiency.
Speaker 1: Yep, volume one duck heart and volume two the barbarian princess These this is like the best dungeon right here volumes.
Speaker 0: the one sad thing is that I read and so did Scott we read duck heart first volume one and That was far and away the best that dungeon ever had to offer.
Speaker 1: it is Definitely the best the dungeon has to offer.
Speaker 1: so if you're not but see the thing don't get us or like.
Speaker 1: it might sound like we're saying that this is a good comic and Then it sort of goes downhill.
Speaker 1: No, it's a fantastic comic that goes downhill to okay Is she kind of a?
Speaker 0: the thing is if nothing else volume one by itself of zenith duck heart zenith zenith?
Speaker 0: No is Absolutely Amazing.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's so great.
Speaker 0: The first half it's really in two halves.
Speaker 0: The first half is utterly utterly just weird and offbeat and hilarious I mean when you I don't want to ruin it, but when you find out what the deal is with the elephants I laughed out loud
Speaker 1: when you find out what the deal is with the sword
Speaker 0: with pretty much everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah Everyone's great, especially especially Horace.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty much one of those stories We're like, there's a whole bunch of little things, right?
Speaker 1: but they're all really like.
Speaker 1: they're things that you really are really easy to fall in love with like the characters and the Little quirks and things even.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: Zongo is basically a guy who appears in maybe five panels at most and all he ever says Is Zongo.
Speaker 1: yet somehow?
Speaker 1: Like I like him that much, you know.
Speaker 1: and Then the magic of it is sort of like how all these little things that you really like end up coming together to you know Create something that is greater than the whole in ways that you did not expect at all.
Speaker 0: Like it jumps around a lot and the humor is really goonie and I said offbeat but I that bears repeating it.
Speaker 0: It'll throw some curveballs at you while you're reading it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Sometimes you might not even notice there was a joke like there'll be some sort of pun joke and you won't get it.
Speaker 1: and Then some character who will like point out the joke, but pretty much the second half.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 0: The first half is really funny and weird And the second half is it really borders on the Philosophical and it it has such a different tone that you almost feel like you're reading a different comic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well because the setting sort of changes.
Speaker 1: they take you out of the dungeon in the second half and there's your sorta.
Speaker 1: You're in the dungeons there, but you're going around the world a lot looking at things and you know seeing what's outside the dungeon.
Speaker 1: So it doesn't really have the same sort of feeling as the first half.
Speaker 1: and you know It's sort of instead of following sort of like all the stuff going on in the dungeon.
Speaker 1: it really is a more narrowly focused story on a few characters on sort of a journey, but The journeys that the journey stories in dungeon are weird because it's not like beginning end It's like beginning get somewhere then sort of turn and go in a direction that you didn't expect but sort of make sense.
Speaker 1: And I guess keep turning around until eventually there's like a resting place.
Speaker 0: I mean it the second half just it's all.
Speaker 0: it's almost like an exercise in philosophy.
Speaker 0: And it it.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: that might sound strange.
Speaker 0: It's really hard for me to explain it without ruining a whole bunch of things.
Speaker 0: But when you get to the point where he's learning how to fight I won't even say who he is.
Speaker 0: and then they fight the goblins and they go through the doors.
Speaker 1: Oh, that was a great.
Speaker 1: I love that part.
Speaker 0: That part is so weird though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's good though.
Speaker 1: I love that part That's greatest.
Speaker 0: But I think like that and just the whole thing with the two islands where two people are sent to two different islands For a long time to cultivate two different civilizations and then eventually the civilizations come into conflict and it's nothing more than a lesson.
Speaker 0: and it It goes over that so quickly and it's it's weird.
Speaker 1: That's one thing is it?
Speaker 1: the comic really feels like what are those paintings that that the?
Speaker 1: what's that guy who does the paintings?
Speaker 1: It's just like a whole lot of stuff crammed in really tight and like you can sit there for hours Just looking at all the little things.
Speaker 1: He's painted in there.
Speaker 1: You know what I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah This is sort of like one of those like the dungeon.
Speaker 1: It feels like the dungeon itself is a lot of things is a huge dungeon but like each room is like a you know a dungeon room with you know traps and treasures and monsters and each one is different and interesting in its own way.
Speaker 1: and It's sort of like the whole comic is this big painting with a lot of stuff crammed in really tight But each thing that's crammed in really tight has a lot of substance to it, you know.
Speaker 1: So in a couple pages you get like a heaping portion of comic there, you know.
Speaker 1: And it really I like it a lot
Speaker 0: and I think what the thing I like the most about the second half Is that the dialogue between because it kind of turns into one of those but not really a buddy cop comic But two buddies who were very different But they get along and a really like togas and bato and ghost in the shell in the movies like the kind of the way they talk to each other and how they they quote things at each other and they snipe at each other And they've got each other's backs with this kind of unspoken camaraderie.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: All right, so that dungeon Z. That's dungeon Z is one you wanna talk about.
Speaker 0: dungeon Z is - it's more of the same and it's almost as good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much It's not it doesn't.
Speaker 0: it seems like after the philosophical bit in the very beginning It pretty much goes away from that and no comic goes back to that.
Speaker 0: None of them.
Speaker 1: No dungeon parade is More, you know All four of the comics dungeons zenith one and two and parade one and two deal with the dungeon and sort of the same set Of characters.
Speaker 1: that are the ones that you really like.
Speaker 1: and I guess chronologically story wise the two parade volumes are in between The zenith volume.
Speaker 1: so it's like zenith one parade one parade two zenith two is the story order.
Speaker 1: But it doesn't really matter that much.
Speaker 1: you can read these four volumes.
Speaker 1: as long as you read the ones before the twos It'll totally make sense and it won't matter.
Speaker 1: and You know while zenith one is by far the best of these four volumes if you like zenith one I recommend that you buy all four of these volumes.
Speaker 1: Yes Most definitely because zenith two is still very very good and parade one and two are also very very good.
Speaker 1: But nah, there's a little bit.
Speaker 1: it's something missing from them.
Speaker 1: But it's not.
Speaker 1: it's not enough missing to make it not worth buying.
Speaker 0: No, this might sound it's.
Speaker 0: it's almost like zenith Was good in it like in its own right and parade was only good because I had read zenith.
Speaker 1: I have to agree with that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz Parade on its own didn't really make me like the characters so much but it was more of one of those.
Speaker 1: I like the characters so much because of zenith one and two.
Speaker 1: that just reading more stories about these Characters was good enough.
Speaker 0: Even if they weren't the best stories in the universe Normal stories that like when the wizard in zenith two gets that this eyeball and it like it Lee it pops and starts leaking.
Speaker 0: The like the four panels of him reacting to it leaking are our comedy goal super comedy.
Speaker 0: I'm reading through it right now.
Speaker 0: So I'm remembering all the things that yeah rim has all the volumes.
Speaker 1: That's why I might be talking about them in a rather vague manner.
Speaker 1: Cuz I read them a few weeks ago and I haven't looked at him since.
Speaker 0: but this is one of those things that Upon reviewing it I really want to avoid talking about what actually happens because you really got to experience it and I feel like spoilers aren't just worthy.
Speaker 0: Now there's another volume called that I made up anymore doesn't even make sense.
Speaker 1: No, there's another volume called dungeon the early years.
Speaker 0: No, alright.
Speaker 1: Alright now dungeon the early years is about One of the characters and in the dungeon story and it takes place way before the dungeon even exists.
Speaker 0: Now here's the gripe I have with everything after what we've already talked about.
Speaker 0: They have nothing to do with dungeon.
Speaker 1: Well thing it had.
Speaker 1: it sort of gives you a subtle hint as to how the dungeon sort of came to be.
Speaker 1: But other than that, it really has nothing to do with dungeon.
Speaker 1: it feels like there should have been an early years volume 2 that's missing and I really didn't like it that much.
Speaker 1: It was kind of so.
Speaker 0: so I can add some good moments.
Speaker 0: But it and it.
Speaker 0: it might have been a good story on its own but it didn't live up to dungeon.
Speaker 0: And I expected like founding the dungeon or stuff with all the characters young.
Speaker 0: But no, it's just this completely unrelated story that happens to involve a few cameos.
Speaker 1: Basically, it's weird in that.
Speaker 1: I feel like it's.
Speaker 1: I guess I'll say that later.
Speaker 1: But yeah the the early years it is.
Speaker 1: I think it's too early a year and that the thing I like so much about dungeon were all these characters that made me like and since and the setting and the.
Speaker 1: the prologue Barely scratched the the characters or the setting at all.
Speaker 1: So I had a hard time liking it.
Speaker 1: Maybe it was because I was expecting something and maybe if I hadn't read if I read the early years first Maybe I would have felt differently about it because I wouldn't have had.
Speaker 1: you know This sort of desire for more of the good dungeon in me, you know, but I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah early years if you read Zenith and parade and like them you might want to like You know peak at early years before you pay for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the only good thing about the early years at all was Alexandra.
Speaker 1: yeah, pretty much and even that it like it didn't really give you.
Speaker 1: it's sort of like there's a mystery and Then the solution to the mystery is sort of anti-climactic and sort of okay.
Speaker 1: It's not like oh That's what that was that they were alluding to.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like oh Alright just okay.
Speaker 1: Alright, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So like when you want to when you have a prologue to something you want to see like the crazy hidden past Secrets like oh snaps.
Speaker 1: That's what that was like you because they they hint at the secret pass.
Speaker 1: You expect the secret pass to be something crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's something mundane and boring.
Speaker 0: I guess the early years could have been good if it hadn't had anything to do with dungeon.
Speaker 0: I guess yeah, even then it needed more.
Speaker 1: Yeah The other volumes you've got is dungeon Like the.
Speaker 0: I like Twilight.
Speaker 0: now, I gotta make this clear again Zenith Zenith Awesome parade more the same mostly the early years.
Speaker 0: Okay, Twilight now if the early years had nothing to do with dungeon Twilight has nothing to do with dungeon.
Speaker 1: Well, basically here's the thing, right?
Speaker 1: I Expected dungeon Twilight to be about the downfall of the dungeon, right?
Speaker 1: Because it's like, okay, this is the end of the dungeon.
Speaker 1: that would be a good expectation, but basically what happens is At the beginning of dungeon Twilight the dungeon has been down fallen for a long time and now you're talking post Apocalyptic future here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is like a way future and I'm like, ah it's sort of like You read.
Speaker 0: it's like that dragon movie or it was gonna be so awesome and they're like 40 years later.
Speaker 0: It's like oh you've skipped the only part.
Speaker 0: I wanted to see.
Speaker 1: yeah You know how a lot lots of fantasy rate of fire.
Speaker 0: That was the name that that movies suck.
Speaker 1: Don't watch lots and lots of fantasy, you know.
Speaker 1: universes fictional fantasy of course They're fictional.
Speaker 1: their fantasy universes have sort of this common thing where there was a great war in the past or there's going to be A great war in the future something along the you know, some great event some cataclysm some something, right?
Speaker 1: But you never actually see that that's something that is like part of the history or part of you know Some omen in the future like a Ragnarok kind of thing that never you never actually see the story of that.
Speaker 1: Alright, it's like if you read I guess Lord of the Rings is the only one where they actually you know.
Speaker 1: You get to read about the big events, you know.
Speaker 0: But the thing is though you read about the big events in the Lord of the Rings But the past the great and glorious past that was so actually epic that makes the actual Lord of the Rings look like piddly nothing.
Speaker 0: You don't want to actually read that because it's not that interesting summer aliens.
Speaker 1: Okay, it's okay But it's worth reading if you're.
Speaker 0: if you're you know, oh, yeah I guess it's more than the stories like the.
Speaker 0: it's kind of like.
Speaker 0: you're better off reading about the story of the fall because the story of the ancient great things or The ancient super powerful things often are much more difficult to make interesting.
Speaker 1: Yes, but this dungeon Twilight is well after the fall of the dungeon.
Speaker 1: I wanted to read about the fall of the dungeon because they sort of hint and you can piece together What happened at the fall of the dungeon and it's really awesome and I wish the comic was about what happened then.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they not.
Speaker 0: they make a big reveal where basically I saw it coming a mile away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they make the big reveal and all I could think was the same thing Scott thought which was why wasn't this about that?
Speaker 0: Now it was cool that they skipped a bunch of it because they make the reveal but they don't actually say what happened.
Speaker 0: It's just heavily implied from the dialogue between the two characters exactly what happened.
Speaker 0: But and that would have been a really cool mechanic or device, but it's used to such crap effect and they pretty much immediately say well never mind that and and that's where it gets really bad because Twilight vol 2 Okay, here's the deal.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: So Twilight vol 1 there was a crazy.
Speaker 1: the dungeon fell, right?
Speaker 1: It's obvious from the cover of the book the dungeon fell, right?
Speaker 1: So you wish you could have read about the dungeon falling because you love the dungeon, but instead you basically the last Remaining, you know pieces of the dungeon that are still in existence in the world.
Speaker 1: they sort of give it another go and that's dungeon Twilight vol 1. and it's It's bad and it's not what you want But it's not as bad as Twilight vol 2. because at the end of Twilight vol 1 You know, it's sort of getting close to a climax like at the pace it was going.
Speaker 1: I figured that around the middle of Twilight vol 2 it was gonna get crazy go nuts and maybe it would have been great.
Speaker 1: But instead I'm like the first few pages.
Speaker 1: we're talking like three pages of Twilight vol 2. they're like Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah that all that stuff that happened in Twilight vol 1 whatever It's it finished and now a completely unrelated thing We're gonna give you right now and it's so just.
Speaker 0: I hate to say this, but it's crap.
Speaker 1: It's it's pretty bad.
Speaker 0: I didn't even read it.
Speaker 1: I got I read it all but I Was pretty much just going and I was sort of frustrated and grumbly until it was.
Speaker 0: I lost interest.
Speaker 0: So I kept like.
Speaker 1: I definitely lost interest.
Speaker 1: I said hey, I'd be like, but I read it.
Speaker 0: Anyway page page flip flip flip flip.
Speaker 0: the only the only redeeming part at all Is that the dragon girl is really really cute?
Speaker 0: Yeah dragon girls cute But that's all that comic has to offer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's basically all the characters in that are not the characters that you've got.
Speaker 0: There seems to be a common theme here in Twilight.
Speaker 0: The only good thing was the cute dragon girl and in early years.
Speaker 0: The only good thing was the cute snake girl, right?
Speaker 1: So basically, I guess that shows that what made dungeon zenith and parade so great was not great plots.
Speaker 1: It was great characters and a great setting and watching all those things interact and getting you to really like all these things.
Speaker 1: and They didn't.
Speaker 1: that's why parade worked.
Speaker 1: because even though the stories and parade weren't so great it was all these, you know characters you like.
Speaker 1: so it totally worked.
Speaker 1: and early years and Twilight went so far away from those characters and setting that There's nothing to like anymore because it was just the same kind of bleh plots and parade But without the stuff you liked.
Speaker 0: So yeah Buy what we told you to buy and don't buy the rest unless you're really really desperate now.
Speaker 1: This might.
Speaker 1: this isn't impossible to find.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure what's in print and what's not in print But I was able to get all the volumes.
Speaker 1: so I don't see any reason you shouldn't be able to get all the volumes.
Speaker 1: Um, there's one other volume dungeon monsters, which is sort of like let me read from Wikipedia here.
Speaker 1: It features secondary characters from throughout the story.
Speaker 1: Monsters stories can be set anywhere in the timeline and feature occasional appearances by the major characters.
Speaker 1: So that might be interesting because I there might be like I haven't read it.
Speaker 1: It's coming in the mail, you know, like a month or so.
Speaker 1: But it might have like a Zango story or you know Because that's the thing is in the main part of dungeon the side characters were all so awesome.
Speaker 1: They were the secondary characters in the main and Zenith were better than the main characters in any other part.
Speaker 1: So if there are little vignette stories about them I might like that.
Speaker 1: so the verdict on monsters is still out.
Speaker 1: But as for the rest you stick to the Zenith in the parade if you like the Zenith.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio.
Speaker 1: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 1: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.