Speaker 1: It's Monday, February 4th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: Giants won the Super Bowl And this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 1: We avoid talking about the Super Bowl as much as possible and talk about network attached storage.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Man what a boring weekend.
Speaker 1: nothing interesting happened at all and I have almost nothing to say.
Speaker 1: Oh nothing really no sort of leader bit.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not like there was some sort of sporting event.
Speaker 0: No, there's.
Speaker 0: no.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's a parade tomorrow, but that's that's you know happens all it's not.
Speaker 1: There's a ticker tape parade.
Speaker 1: what every five minutes?
Speaker 0: You know cares about parade?
Speaker 1: who cares about gonna stand out in the cold for an hour to see a bunch of people walk by?
Speaker 1: I don't even know who they are.
Speaker 0: I mean some guy You know.
Speaker 0: he escaped a bunch of people trying to kill him and then he just threw this piece of whatnot And then some other guy caught it.
Speaker 0: There's no effect on the world, you know, it only slowed down Wall Street all morning.
Speaker 0: That's all Huh?
Speaker 1: So yeah Giants won.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Giants won.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I know a lot of you out there being geeks.
Speaker 1: Don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: You don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: You're probably thinking why are they talking about football and all you people from other countries are like, that's not football.
Speaker 0: soccer is football Football American.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: And you know what it is.
Speaker 0: and you're saying it's a stupid sport.
Speaker 0: rugby He's better than that.
Speaker 1: It's a stupid sport, you know I'll say this I used to always think yeah rugby is a real man's sport.
Speaker 1: forget football rugby.
Speaker 0: rugby is a real Footballs a real man's sport.
Speaker 1: But once I watched a bunch of rugby and I played some rugby and I learned that playing rugby sucks because it just hurts.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: Watching rugby is more like watching a brawl.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a real man's sport.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna dis run.
Speaker 0: see the thing is people who are rugby It's sort of like this right?
Speaker 0: They some guy was talking about this when it comes to comics fans, too, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, you know what?
Speaker 0: I know rugby fans go rugby is awesome.
Speaker 0: football sucks, but football fans like rugby is cool.
Speaker 0: But football is also cool.
Speaker 0: It's like People who are anti-underwear.
Speaker 0: perfect comic would be like.
Speaker 0: comics are cool, but not underwear.
Speaker 0: perfect comics, you know.
Speaker 0: But the underwear perfect constant Blake underwear.
Speaker 0: perfect comics are cool.
Speaker 0: Some of those non-underwear perfect comics It depends on the underwear pervert.
Speaker 0: It does it does.
Speaker 1: I mean, I remember though those two guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm here to buy a silvery right nothing else.
Speaker 0: But you know, it's it's the the pretentious people are more likely to discount the thing that they feel is lower.
Speaker 0: Well, you know like the NASCAR fan will respect Formula One, but the Formula One fan will often look down upon the NASCAR.
Speaker 1: Ah, but then again, I think there's a lot of NASCAR fans who look down on the Formula.
Speaker 0: I don't think they look down at.
Speaker 0: they'd probably just don't care about or know about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think a good analogy Well a straight-up analogy is snowboarders and skiers - because yeah, look at snowboarders like yeah, you're nothing And that's the correct opinion.
Speaker 0: But snowboarders like skiers, whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I know it's probably not important to most people but when you know it Sports fandom is like inherited.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not just that.
Speaker 1: I mean Scott is he's got sports in the blood.
Speaker 1: I mean his dad and his parents visit.
Speaker 0: you have people you have a family.
Speaker 0: they came from Eastern Europe to New York.
Speaker 0: Your grandfather was a fan of the New York Giants and your father was a fan of the New York Giants.
Speaker 0: I don't know how I know.
Speaker 0: a lot of other people pick their sports teams in other ways.
Speaker 0: You know, they some like a lot of people my age or Chicago Bulls fans because the Bulls were you know Very good when they were kids, you know, and I was almost a Bulls fan, too.
Speaker 0: Yeah A lot of people are Cowboys fans because the Cowboys were very good when we were kids and they're front runners and they were kids And they stuck with that team, you know
Speaker 1: People who they look at who's winning or who's good and they're fans of the good team.
Speaker 0: You know, maybe they you know, some people like I know some people who like the Pittsburgh Penguins just because they like penguins.
Speaker 0: No, they like the logo or there's something or they pick the team that happens to be near where they live.
Speaker 0: You know, they they move to Indianapolis and now they're Colts fans, you know, it's how it happens.
Speaker 0: But when your fit your entire family is like together on something you pass along the fandom to your children.
Speaker 0: It has another meaning beyond a guy throwing a piece of rubber tradition tradition.
Speaker 1: But you know it's because I think my my family on my dad's side pretty much like my great-grandparents came from Belgium moved to Detroit and We've been hockey fans.
Speaker 1: my family's been hockey fans as long as they've been in this country and You know my parents had Rangers season tickets in the 70s before.
Speaker 0: they were zillion dollars.
Speaker 1: A lot of my relatives saw Red Wings games in the Coliseum the most dangerous fucking arena in the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah But just you know, we've said this before but I know we have a lot of new listeners.
Speaker 1: So you might be if you're thinking hey geek nights You're not real geeks talking about sports.
Speaker 1: now that talking about sports does not make you not a geek makes you not a nerd.
Speaker 1: There's a big difference.
Speaker 0: because I mean think about all those guys.
Speaker 0: turn on your local sports radio station, right?
Speaker 0: You're gonna hear especially in New York or in Boston, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, well, Joey Jojo was 24/7 Last year.
Speaker 0: they have these TV shows.
Speaker 0: They had these radio shows where they got guys, you know sports guys call in and they're like Oh, what do you think about this?
Speaker 0: What do you think about that?
Speaker 0: I think this.
Speaker 0: I think that right?
Speaker 0: These people are sports geeks.
Speaker 0: Just like you're you're a computer geek or science geek or an anime geek.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in fact, there are sports nerds to watch out for sports nerds.
Speaker 1: Sports nerds are possibly the guys who are not drunk but yet still body-painted.
Speaker 1: Yes The not drunk I think is key there.
Speaker 0: you watch out for them.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So it's that's good.
Speaker 1: We might talk about the the sporting event in a little bit more detail.
Speaker 1: But before we get in the future probably maybe Thursday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now we were like, oh next Thursday, but we're going to katsu khan.
Speaker 0: Yeah week from Thursday katsu khan be there Not on the Thursday will be there the Thursday.
Speaker 1: you'll be there the Friday Saturday Sunday if you want to hang out with us And you show up on the Thursday.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna have time to talk to you.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be setting up stuff on like the stages and and then we're gonna lock yourself We hanging out in the in the game cats.
Speaker 1: Mostly what we're gonna do is we're gonna stand there while everyone else wheels in all the arcade cabinets And then we're going to test the rampart machine all night.
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: Yes, it needs adequate testing.
Speaker 0: How do we know the track balls are fully functional?
Speaker 0: you got it what the tournament wouldn't be fair if we didn't thoroughly check to Make sure.
Speaker 1: but tomorrow is actually an important day.
Speaker 1: See, it's nice because Scott and I take a tape parade.
Speaker 1: both have reasons to be excited about tomorrow.
Speaker 1: I mean for Scott though.
Speaker 1: I also am excited.
Speaker 1: There's going to be a ticker tape parade One of those old I think as Scott said key to the city type actions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically they go from Battery Park Which if you don't know is the bottom of the city where you can see the Statue of Liberty.
Speaker 0: and they go north You know down Broadway past where the old Trade Center used to be well up Broadway up Broadway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I always say down whenever I say I walk down the street, you know, even if it's north I always say walking down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I actually say walk up the street, but I get messed up if I'm going east or west I don't always use down.
Speaker 0: But even though I know I should I don't say I later allies across the way and there is a portion of that street That is known as the Canyon of Heroes We just aptly named.
Speaker 0: that's why they had the praise there, right?
Speaker 0: It's all.
Speaker 0: you should always also go there because it's there's a reason they called the Canyon of Heroes And they go through the Canyon of Heroes and then they go to the city hall Where they have a little key to the city type thing and then they're going back to Jersey where the stadium is.
Speaker 0: we need Stadium Jersey.
Speaker 1: if only we could have because there's no more real estate.
Speaker 1: But at the same time if there were extra-dimensional spaces Where what better place to have the sports arena than just connected to Grand Central or something?
Speaker 1: If only we could have some sort of floating stadium just right above Manhattan.
Speaker 0: No, I think you just put it out in Queens next to Shea Stadium.
Speaker 1: Well, are we just make a barge right off of Manhattan and we wheel it in?
Speaker 1: every time There's a some sort of big sporting event.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's not gonna work.
Speaker 0: it would sink when 80,000 people got on it.
Speaker 1: No, you just have some ballast.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe not ballast.
Speaker 1: you need some some lifts.
Speaker 1: Yeah have it floating.
Speaker 1: It's a dirigible.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so this parade, you know, New York City it I'm probably gonna go to the parade.
Speaker 1: I have work to do unlike people.
Speaker 0: I know I have work to do but I might go with some co-workers at the parade.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only reason I won't is that I'm way uptown and to go.
Speaker 1: compared to where the parade's gonna be Yeah, taking it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but and taking the subway I think to the parade is not gonna be a fun experience.
Speaker 0: Maybe fun.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't think I'd really get out of subway.
Speaker 1: I I've worries about all the people are gonna be trying to get down.
Speaker 0: take the six train to Brooklyn Bridge I'll get out.
Speaker 0: I'll walk.
Speaker 1: But tomorrow there was also something else going on.
Speaker 0: It is Super Tuesday the pretty much Why they call it Super Tuesday?
Speaker 1: because the Giants won the Super Bowl.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: Yes, that is in fact the etymology of the word word.
Speaker 1: You see when the Giants won the Super Bowl yesterday the term Super Tuesday.
Speaker 0: No, I think it just has to do with the Super Bowl in general.
Speaker 1: no, it has nothing to do with that It does.
Speaker 0: it's a Tuesday at the Super Bowl.
Speaker 1: But you realize that now there have been other Super Tuesday anyway.
Speaker 1: Basically every primary in this country that matters is happening tomorrow.
Speaker 1: And pretty much if you're a Republican, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: don't even bother voting because it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: There's no way to tell but with the Democrats.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna say who to vote for.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I am gonna say who to vote for.
Speaker 1: I hereby officially endorsed Barack Obama for president of the United States.
Speaker 0: I hereby endorse My mom.
Speaker 0: my mom would be better than these candidates.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: I will also endorse your mom but secondarily to your mother and to my mother.
Speaker 1: your mom So tertiary Lee nice mom for president Anyone but Scott Johnson's mom.
Speaker 1: actually, you know what I think.
Speaker 0: Scott Johnson's mom We better than any can.
Speaker 0: Scott Johnson's mom polls pretty well clean up this country.
Speaker 1: If I know other thing the name recognition I mean who is brought up more in conversation among the front row crew than Scott Johnson's mom your mom.
Speaker 1: Anyway if you are registered as a Democrat or if you're in a state where you can vote in any primary or caucus or what?
Speaker 1: Have you if you care the caucus stay home?
Speaker 0: It's not worth it.
Speaker 1: No caucuses are awesome.
Speaker 0: You don't if you don't have all day you really don't know.
Speaker 1: most caucuses are at night.
Speaker 1: But I can say this if you have never been to a caucus caucuses are awesome.
Speaker 1: They're super fun Especially if you have nothing better to do.
Speaker 0: no Especially what I'm afraid to go to.
Speaker 1: if you were there to cause trouble if you were there to be Yelling about Mike Revell the whole time then a caucus is where you run Paul people.
Speaker 0: Don't go to the caucus to stay home.
Speaker 1: But Seriously the the deal with this election is pretty much if young people turn out then Barack Obama's probably going to win the nomination.
Speaker 1: If young people don't turn out then Hillary Clinton is probably going to win.
Speaker 0: young people go to the caucuses old people stay home.
Speaker 1: I really I mean, I really want Barack to win.
Speaker 1: But at the same time if the worst thing that can happen is Hillary Clinton is president I think the country is doing pretty well and all there's a lot of haters But I think a lot of you are unreasonable.
Speaker 0: I'd rather have Mike Revell.
Speaker 0: Mike Revell is actually pretty weird Mike Revell because I agree with him on 99% of everything.
Speaker 0: but then he says blah blah blah crazy fair tax and I'm like what the fuck is wrong with you.
Speaker 1: I feel like if I could just sit down with him for five minutes and be like, here's why fair tax is stupid.
Speaker 0: Why doesn't he just sit down like Alan Greenspan for five minutes to be like?
Speaker 0: it changes mind.
Speaker 0: So fair taxes, you know what I'd vote for her.
Speaker 1: I really don't get how the internet is backing Ron Paul But early on Mike Revell and Ron Paul were kind of this equal level of like internet and nowhere else.
Speaker 1: Are they known or popular?
Speaker 1: Why is the internet which is nominally pretty well informed for Ron Paul?
Speaker 1: Who is 90% crazy and 10% smart as opposed to Mike Revell who is 90% smart and 10% crazy Because the Internet's 90% crazy conspiracy theories.
Speaker 1: Anyway I'll put it this way if you want Barack Obama to get the nomination Go out and vote in the primary because pretty much no one under the age of 30 votes in primaries.
Speaker 1: So, uh, if you go and vote that's actually a really big deal.
Speaker 1: So that is that is my political message of the day.
Speaker 0: Your real vote isn't gonna matter later.
Speaker 1: Trust me No, it's not.
Speaker 1: because.
Speaker 0: so your only chance you have of making any difference whatsoever because nothing else you do will make a difference Is to vote tomorrow, that's all you've got.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because unless I can't vote tomorrow though I'm an independent and it doesn't matter cuz it's New York and I have no choice.
Speaker 0: Anyway, my vote can't matter no matter what well mine can which is why I'll go to the parade instead.
Speaker 1: my vote.
Speaker 1: You see the thing is and I'll go For two hours.
Speaker 1: I actually changed my party membership from independent to Democrat just for this and you know What gasps the day after tomorrow?
Speaker 1: I'm switching it either to independent or to Golisano's party independence party.
Speaker 1: Yeah independent or independence.
Speaker 1: Things I like.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's sort of like that trick.
Speaker 1: No one special Nobody's special, you know It's too bad.
Speaker 1: all the other parties with good names are always evil.
Speaker 1: every time anytime you see a political party That's a name.
Speaker 0: institution party is our worst party.
Speaker 1: or like the freedom or anytime a party has a good word in the name It is probably something bad.
Speaker 0: I know it's like in theory the Constitution Party.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh man, they want to restore the Constitution.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: No go look at what the Constitution Party believes.
Speaker 0: They're all complete nutjobs like the nuttiest religious nutjobs you'll ever come up with.
Speaker 0: but they call themselves the Constitution Party.
Speaker 0: great way to be honest.
Speaker 1: Anyway in a news that you probably actually expect us to talk about We'll just do in one news today.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is this is actually a pretty big important news in terms of Regardless of what happens the landscape of Internet has possibly changed forever, which is something that happens more and more often.
Speaker 1: but Yeah, who right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was one of those like big names like they've been.
Speaker 1: they're one of those huge internet companies.
Speaker 1: They do a lot.
Speaker 1: They're kind of like these stalwart.
Speaker 1: Well, uh Microsoft just said hey, we want to buy.
Speaker 1: you will offer you this ludicrous amount of money.
Speaker 1: Give us your company.
Speaker 0: It's actually a little more complicated than that but that we're not gonna go into the details like it's not.
Speaker 0: it didn't happen yet It'll take a long time.
Speaker 0: How exactly something what it could it might not even happen.
Speaker 1: and things like this.
Speaker 1: I mean companies make offers like that on a like.
Speaker 1: they make offers a lot like that on regular basis but the fact that this one is credible and Serious and the fact that Yahoo couldn't immediately say no and it's it's not a hostile takeover like that Monty Python thing But it's closer to a possible hostile takeover than you might otherwise expect.
Speaker 0: I mean imagine if you had a company right that was worth five hundred dollars.
Speaker 0: We're just you know, theoretically right and you had.
Speaker 0: you're on the stock market or a publicly traded company, right?
Speaker 0: Well, if your company is worth five hundred dollars someone with five hundred dollars could buy your company.
Speaker 0: They could go to the stock market and if everyone who had shares is willing to sell them They could buy your entire company and there's nothing you the founder of the company could do about it.
Speaker 0: You're a publicly traded company, right?
Speaker 0: Unless you had 51% of the shares and refused to sell them.
Speaker 0: now Basically they did is they went to Yahoo and they said we would like to buy you and Yahoo was like All right.
Speaker 0: How much money?
Speaker 0: and the amount of money they said?
Speaker 0: Was enough money where if they wanted to they could have done a hostile takeover on the stock market, but they didn't.
Speaker 1: now beyond that Yahoo No one knows if this is related or not, it's probably unrelated because no one used this anyway, but Yahoo's music service is done.
Speaker 1: They're basically shutting it down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, who should done a lot of it seems like Yahoo.
Speaker 0: They their search.
Speaker 0: it still exists because that was the first thing they ever did but it's not really used that much anymore.
Speaker 0: Their maps are okay, but Google Maps seems to have mostly beaten them right.
Speaker 0: their mail is wicked popular.
Speaker 0: I think it's the most popular webmail.
Speaker 0: you compare it, you know As good as Gmail is.
Speaker 0: it's scary that hotmail and Yahoo mail is still way more popular than Gmail.
Speaker 0: way Lots, right.
Speaker 1: Well, I think a lot of that cuz Like.
Speaker 1: it's weird, but adults don't get it even at my work.
Speaker 1: We're like everyone's like crazy Technological and everyone.
Speaker 1: so few people use Gmail.
Speaker 1: They all use like the account that Comcast gave them or like whatever email account they got last and no one switches.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's it's.
Speaker 0: it's very hard for people to switch out of email.
Speaker 0: It's also hard for people to switch out of instant messaging and MSN and Yahoo are Combined would be the basically the instant messaging Kings and I mean as we can use Google Talk and aim.
Speaker 0: but and aim I think is the single biggest.
Speaker 0: but MSN and Yahoo together would be bigger.
Speaker 0: and then you look Yahoo has sort of like these content you know, like they have Yahoo News and Yahoo Finance things like that and They have Yahoo's advertising thing which is kind of meager compared to Microsoft or Google but it's not insignificant.
Speaker 0: and then the rest of the stuff that Yahoo has that you care about right is the things they bought like flicker and Delicious and such like that.
Speaker 0: and yeah It's been really good about buying that stuff like flicker and delicious and then not fucking it up like they buy it.
Speaker 0: They let it go and that's it.
Speaker 0: But flicker doesn't make money.
Speaker 0: flicker hemorrhages money.
Speaker 0: Delicious doesn't really make money either.
Speaker 0: It's not a Bookmarking.
Speaker 0: There's not much money in that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at the same time What does Yahoo really have to offer anymore?
Speaker 1: Like seriously from it not from a business standpoint, but from us as technological people.
Speaker 0: Delicious and flicker.
Speaker 1: Yeah things that Yahoo didn't make they just bought right The reason.
Speaker 0: you know Microsoft probably buying them up so they can combine their advertising thing You know their web advertising with the I'll advertising to take on Google, you know.
Speaker 0: It's like Microsoft exists, right.
Speaker 0: and then you know, because it's like Google isn't even competing with Microsoft directly.
Speaker 0: You know, they're a search engine.
Speaker 0: Microsoft makes Windows and Office, you know, these are not competing companies, right?
Speaker 1: Well, Microsoft has a search right?
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but I mean, you know, but Microsoft for some reason sort of like Turned its whole company away from Windows and Office and all that shit Right in order to fight with Google a non-competing company.
Speaker 0: and sure Google has.
Speaker 0: you know things that do sort of fight Around with Microsoft like they've got the Gmail the Google Docs and and these sorts of things, right?
Speaker 0: But you know Google.
Speaker 0: none of those things really are that successful.
Speaker 0: They're not that you know widespread.
Speaker 0: No one really uses a lot of those things.
Speaker 0: Google only.
Speaker 0: really their search and their ads are Successful and now their mobile stuff is starting to be successful and the Gmail only a little bit and all the other stuff is kind of right.
Speaker 0: so Microsoft is like rearing up to compete with these people that weren't fighting with them.
Speaker 1: Well, I think part of it.
Speaker 0: It's like turning this giant ship around to shoot at someone who wasn't shooting at you.
Speaker 1: Well, I think what Microsoft realized is that they have this big old clunking ship, right and they're going along and nothing can touch them.
Speaker 1: But then they started to notice that there's all these coves They can't get into with their big ship and in those coves was treasure and they saw Google whipping into all these coves.
Speaker 0: And then they realized that Google only got treasure from like two coves.
Speaker 1: That was it.
Speaker 1: well the thing is there's more coves in the future.
Speaker 0: theoretically, I mean granted I Google analogy is breaking down.
Speaker 1: Well, that's going down with the ship.
Speaker 1: The real problem here is that there are two sides to this.
Speaker 1: there's the make of money from a business side and the provide useful technology side.
Speaker 1: and if I look at it from a From a personal perspective as in me as a technologist as a technology professional as a human being as a user of the Internet Google provides Almost everything I need to use my computer.
Speaker 1: between Google and Linus Torvalds I have the internet.
Speaker 0: all I worry about with this news here, right?
Speaker 0: Really won't hurt me at all.
Speaker 0: The only thing I worry about is the state of delicious in the state of flicker.
Speaker 0: I mean if flicker gets fucked up by Microsoft theoretically, which wouldn't even if it happened.
Speaker 0: It wouldn't happen for a year more than a year from now, right?
Speaker 0: I would just move to Google's Picasa and I'd be fine.
Speaker 0: You know, it's not as nice as flicker, but whatever it works, right?
Speaker 0: If delicious is screwed, I don't know what the fuck I would do.
Speaker 1: we'd have to make a competitor I don't know just for us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they they better not fuck up delicious.
Speaker 0: That's all I'm saying.
Speaker 1: No, if they screw it up, we'll just make our own for us.
Speaker 1: And if anyone else wants to use it great We'll become a web 2.5 billionaires.
Speaker 1: And if no one else uses it, well, we have our own personal delicious.
Speaker 1: That's all I care about.
Speaker 1: We'll call it geek issues geek nights dot something.
Speaker 0: I just.
Speaker 0: It's a Google needs a delicious competitor of some kind.
Speaker 0: I don't care if they put their Google ads on it.
Speaker 1: You know, I pretty much block Google ads.
Speaker 0: Yeah, me too.
Speaker 0: But that's why I said it.
Speaker 0: I don't care if they put the ads on it cuz I won't see it.
Speaker 1: But the thing is I mean Google provides most of the stuff I need and Yahoo indirectly provides a few other things, but they're not things I need.
Speaker 1: but From a business standpoint Google.
Speaker 1: It's I don't know how they're gonna make money in the long run because advertising is is Slowly but surely I think becoming something dead.
Speaker 0: We'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: and there's also the problem of alright We've got Microsoft Yahoo and Google.
Speaker 1: Oh wait now we've got Micro who?
Speaker 1: and Google great yah soft.
Speaker 1: Yeah That sounds vaguely sinister.
Speaker 1: Yeah now I've also heard rumblings now.
Speaker 1: This is from.
Speaker 1: it was on Reuters, but it was on Reuters quoting an as-yet-unnamed anonymous source saying that Yahoo has tentatively responded by approaching Google about the two of them partnering up and Doubling their advertising together instead of letting Microsoft in on the action.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean Microsoft, you know It's sort of decided that it wants to be in that business that it never was in.
Speaker 0: So if Google and Yahoo team up with that I don't think anyone the SEC would allow that or the FTC or whoever it is Right, because that's just monopoly the end.
Speaker 0: You can't they can't let that happen, right?
Speaker 0: They let the double-click business happen.
Speaker 0: They can't let Yahoo Google, but if they did Microsoft would be basically like, okay, we have to go back to Windows Office.
Speaker 0: We can't compete in that area.
Speaker 1: See at the same time if Google bought Yahoo, that would be like a nerd's wet dream.
Speaker 1: ignore the business side But just for a nerd.
Speaker 1: now Google's gonna be in control of flicker and all that business.
Speaker 0: Everything's gonna be great But Google delicious and then flicker and picasa hooking up together.
Speaker 0: good times.
Speaker 1: I just I don't know what the future of any of these companies is gonna be.
Speaker 1: to be perfectly honest I feel like the internet is Changing so quickly that good.
Speaker 1: The only thing Google has is the fact that they're massive and they have a lot of power and money to back up their technology To make it work.
Speaker 1: things.
Speaker 1: that I mean we Scott and I could make something like Google Google apps just fine But we could never afford to put together the infrastructure to support it.
Speaker 1: Yep That's all Google has to offer really is the fact that they already have money.
Speaker 1: All Microsoft has to offer is that they already have money and they have installed base.
Speaker 1: All Yahoo has to offer is that they had money so they bought a bunch of stuff that was useful to people.
Speaker 0: And Yahoo does have a lot of stuff that is used by a lot of people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's not stuff that we really care about.
Speaker 1: I think most of that is just a Yahoo Games is not bad?
Speaker 1: No, it isn't.
Speaker 1: but I think a lot of what Yahoo has is just name recognition.
Speaker 1: people who?
Speaker 1: Were in there the poor were adults in the 90s think back and oh, yeah Yahoo Yeah, it was just like one of those names one of those internet things.
Speaker 1: So when they think I got to do something they either think Google or they think Yahoo.
Speaker 1: Yep Wow, I guess we didn't have much to say because we're not business analysts.
Speaker 1: We don't know what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: No, you don't know shit.
Speaker 1: football Things of the day the bears know.
Speaker 0: There's law laws last year.
Speaker 1: I'd like to yell hockey but it's really not appropriate.
Speaker 1: what would have been one of those inappropriate yellings.
Speaker 0: Hockey is the awesome and Hockey's actually better than football.
Speaker 0: Yes, you know, but the Rangers are not so good.
Speaker 1: The specific RIT hockey Yeah The one.
Speaker 0: the one great thing about the Super Bowl is when the Super Bowl is over The only sports left are hockey and basketball.
Speaker 0: who gives a shit about basketball?
Speaker 0: So it's pretty much just hockey now hockey only until baseball season starts and the Red Wings is doing pretty well.
Speaker 0: Okay, you're doing pretty well, but that Oh vegkin the guys just oh my god Here we go.
Speaker 0: easy thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Unlike some other professional sports baseball The NFL is not so stupid when it comes to the Internet's, you know They might take your videos off of YouTube or they might not.
Speaker 1: you know They won't let you show your football game in a big screen at the church.
Speaker 0: But no, they won't.
Speaker 0: but at NFL comm slash videos where they have a few tasteful ads that you can ignore They give you all the highlights of pretty much every freaking game and all the coverage and all the all this stuff.
Speaker 0: You can just watch it right there on the website for free NFL comm slash videos.
Speaker 0: It's real simple.
Speaker 1: now if you didn't watch the Super Bowl Even if you don't really like sports I'd recommend you watch some of these highlights because some crazy things happen near the end of this game.
Speaker 0: Right, even if you don't care about football, even if you don't even care about you know Less about the team is playing.
Speaker 0: if you care if you in fact hate football watch this.
Speaker 0: Anyway, because you watch and just watch like the highlights reels like the Giants defensive highlights reel or like the Eli Miracle play that's the best play.
Speaker 0: the whole game right there Watch.
Speaker 1: I watch that at work like three times.
Speaker 0: just watch.
Speaker 0: and even if you don't know what's going on Or even though a lot of the drama of the play is knowing the exact situation and why that basically won in the game.
Speaker 0: But just watch what the people do in the play.
Speaker 0: It's it's feats of strength.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know You go to the circus and you watch the trapeze guy and he does something amazing and you think wow Think about what he had to do to do that.
Speaker 0: That's an amazing human being can accomplish.
Speaker 0: That is amazing.
Speaker 0: And then you watch, you know Sasuke or you know aka ninja warrior and you watch these guys doing the obstacle course and you say wow Look a human being accomplished that amazing feat, you know a guy ran the mile in four minutes.
Speaker 0: You know Muhammad Ali beat the shit out of that guy.
Speaker 1: and then you watch.
Speaker 1: what was that quote that we just recently heard from?
Speaker 0: There was a Mike Tyson quote that was very applicable to this Super Bowl and that's Everyone has a plan until they get punched in the face Right or something along those lines.
Speaker 0: I might have paraphrased it.
Speaker 0: but watch like these highlight reels and see what the people do in the game.
Speaker 0: But then you maybe if you hate football or you just don't care you'll understand why people like it so much.
Speaker 0: in a small way Because you watch a game and you know while a lot of the game might not be as exciting as all that you watch and you see someone execute an amazing feat.
Speaker 0: that is Just unbelievable that a human can accomplish that.
Speaker 0: and yet Against when a whole bunch of guys, you know, 11 12 other guys are trying to stop them from doing it They managed to do it anyway, and it's like holy shit.
Speaker 0: Look at what that guy just did.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: So speaking of football it has been argued that the aa-12 is the world's deadliest shotgun by the internet.
Speaker 0: I don't know much about what I don't you know, I know about weapons.
Speaker 0: when I know from counter-strike I was about to say my knowledge is extended by counter-strike and a little out of strike movies and a few YouTube.
Speaker 1: It depends on the movies.
Speaker 1: I mean Rambo taught me that machine guns never run out of ammo and never miss.
Speaker 0: yeah, but you know, you learn.
Speaker 0: you'll learn some stuff from you, you know, but I do not have a Military fanboy level of weapons knowledge.
Speaker 0: So enlighten me now.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is this video my thing of the day is not specifically the weapon though.
Speaker 1: I want to say the this video in this weapon basically just show the thing that all science including military science is always improving and this is a pretty Crazy shotgun, especially when they get to the part about 3/4 the way through the video Where they point out that this shotgun doesn't just shoot shotgun shells, but also Grenades,
Speaker 0: yeah anything that you can put in a shotgun shell it can shoot.
Speaker 0: So if they make a grenade that goes in a shotgun shell you can shoot it.
Speaker 1: So when the zombies come tracked is gone down.
Speaker 1: This is like the best anti-zombie gun ever.
Speaker 0: P90 and possibly the Would not be good against zombies.
Speaker 1: Yes, it would single single tap, right?
Speaker 1: Just pop pop pop shot to the head as long as you can aim.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you gotta aim but this thing you don't to aim for shit.
Speaker 0: No, it's very easy to aim.
Speaker 0: This would be the best zombie weapon.
Speaker 0: The only thing I worry is that if you shoot the shells too quickly That you will in fact have to keep reloading and it doesn't look like you can reload that quick.
Speaker 1: No, you can't reload this thing quickly.
Speaker 0: I mean, well, I guess if you had a separate like, you know Cuz it looks like a tommy gun.
Speaker 0: where has you know, like the round of shells, right?
Speaker 1: You call the drum the drum.
Speaker 0: Yes, thank you.
Speaker 0: See shit.
Speaker 0: See how much you know about guns.
Speaker 0: You could probably Tiny bit more because I'd say I have a gun.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, if you had separate loaded drums, you could price switch the drums out and keep going But if you had to refill a drum that would take a while.
Speaker 1: I think this thing though has like no recalls like this crazy cool weapon.
Speaker 1: But my thing of the day is not so much that the weapon exists or the video But it's the the person in the video because you see guy the bald guy.
Speaker 0: He's a scary dude.
Speaker 1: This is some Discovery Channel, you know those documentaries on like the History Channel or the Discovery Channel that are basically Check this thing out.
Speaker 1: We're gonna show you a video and then talk about how cool it is But you're not gonna actually learn anything useful.
Speaker 1: It's just gonna be videos of some guy shooting something or in the History Channel Videos of black and white footage from World War two while we talk in generic terms about the war and nothing interesting or new but this guy
Speaker 0: is
Speaker 1: At least he's acting as if he is not in fact one one of those Military fanboys the military otaku.
Speaker 1: they check out this weapon.
Speaker 1: I can kick some ass with this weapon like you feel the guy.
Speaker 1: he has the Probably minor hard-on talking about these weapons and I've seen other videos with this guy before.
Speaker 1: This guy scares me a little bit and I hope that he's acting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this guy is a. He's one of those guys where he's like, you know, he's.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like.
Speaker 0: ever see Full Metal Panic, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, you mean Full Metal Alchemist?
Speaker 0: No Full Metal Panic.
Speaker 1: Oh, oh, yeah, I guess a real movie as opposed to a geek movie.
Speaker 0: Well panic wasn't a geek.
Speaker 0: It was an anime.
Speaker 1: I Was thinking about Full Metal Jacket.
Speaker 0: No Full Metal Panic.
Speaker 1: I didn't actually see that.
Speaker 0: but you know Full Metal Panic is about this military guy who has to like hide in high school.
Speaker 0: But yeah, he's totally a military fanboy and he freaks everyone out all the time.
Speaker 0: That's what this guy's like.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I actually grew up near a lot of people who are kind of like that, you know, Michigan militia that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: survivalist.
Speaker 1: enough jobs Yeah, these people are scary and that is the gist of this video.
Speaker 1: but enough talk about scary military fanboys.
Speaker 1: Check out this weapon.
Speaker 1: it can fire a blow anyway, so, uh All right, I got in a giggly fit there.
Speaker 1: but Network attached storage.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's what we're gonna talk about tonight.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna go in a great detail of like how to set it up.
Speaker 1: free ness free ness.
Speaker 0: But these are the solutions of the free ness ness.
Speaker 0: light open filer by drobo by a buffalo thing.
Speaker 0: There's all kinds of things.
Speaker 1: buffalo buffalo buffalo buffalo buffalo buffalo buffalo buffalo right.
Speaker 0: What is a naz?
Speaker 0: naz is nas.
Speaker 0: it stands for network attached storage.
Speaker 0: now don't confuse it with San Storage area network.
Speaker 1: the difference pretty much from a from your perspective Is that a naz is a little box full of hard drives connected to a network and you can just get files off of it.
Speaker 1: Yes, an is what a company like the companies I have worked for puts their like mission critical production data on terabytes and terabytes Worth well the floor area like yeah, and then like multiple servers will connect to it with fiber optics.
Speaker 1: The.
Speaker 0: the technical difference between a San and a naz is that when you connect to a naz, right?
Speaker 0: Your computer thinks of it as a network drive.
Speaker 0: It doesn't just you know, it goes.
Speaker 0: All right, I'm gonna use NFS I'm gonna use Samba.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna use something like that some network file transferring sharing folder protocol To connect to some drives in some other computer somewhere just to read and write files.
Speaker 1: Yeah with this and mount those things as though there are local says you can and all this stuff.
Speaker 1: But if under the hood under the hood though, it's still using one of those protocols Yeah, well the thing is they use a protocol that basically make them operating system or access method agnostic.
Speaker 1: Yes in that they don't care what you're running because you connect to it via a known standard protocol But a San.
Speaker 0: Theoretically on paper the diff it unlike a naz your computer actually thinks it's a local drive.
Speaker 1: Like the way they'll work.
Speaker 1: like we had a lot of those the hospital haven't been my current company and we had him at IBM Where you have a big box full of like a raid six of a crazy number of hard drives And there's fiber coming out of the back and you connect servers Directly to that.
Speaker 1: and like you'll have a cluster of database servers and they all serve the database.
Speaker 1: But all of them share a common file system and the file system is handled by the sand.
Speaker 1: and it's crazy.
Speaker 1: You're never gonna have one.
Speaker 0: You're never gonna use a sand but a NAS.
Speaker 0: if you have more than one computer in your house Or if you have friends who come over to your house or anything like that Or if you're in college or if you're in college.
Speaker 0: a NAS is a very good thing to have and nowadays They are very cheap and they're getting very popular.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna tell you a little about NAS.
Speaker 0: Alright, so a NAS is network attached storage.
Speaker 0: You could just if you wanted to.
Speaker 0: you can turn any two computer into a NAS.
Speaker 0: All you need is a computer and a single hard drive and you could do a NAS.
Speaker 0: It is you can use a free NAS NAS lite open filer that any of these operating systems will set up a NAS easily for you though.
Speaker 0: I mean you can just install Ubuntu and then manually, you know set up file sharing and then you've got a NAS, you know You don't have to do it with.
Speaker 0: you know You don't have to dedicate an entire Operating system to the NAS unless you want to have a box.
Speaker 0: that's a NAS and nothing else.
Speaker 1: Yeah but before we talk about all like the how to set it up or what you'd want to do or you know all the different intricacies of Not sans but NAS is talk about why you would want one.
Speaker 1: very Layman's terms like what do they give you us?
Speaker 1: I mean I could just Share my Samba and Scott could share his Samba and the Mac downstairs could share it Sam.
Speaker 1: But we can all connect to whatever we want.
Speaker 1: So how is it better?
Speaker 0: Well, let's say, you know, I want to give you some mp3s, right?
Speaker 0: Well now I got to open up your Samba and drag the files over to you and put them on your hard drive and now They're on my hard drive and your hard drive.
Speaker 0: and then you know, you want to get some files for me.
Speaker 0: So, you know open up mine you copy files from you to me And then we got to go down to the Mac and now I want to get some files.
Speaker 0: Do I go to rim?
Speaker 0: do I go to Scott?
Speaker 0: Where do I go?
Speaker 1: or Scott Johnson comes over and we want to give him like all our ROMs?
Speaker 1: Well, the ROMs are on five different computers.
Speaker 1: You got to connect to all of them.
Speaker 1: figure out what you want grab it.
Speaker 1: Would it be nice if there was just a central box called I don't know naz.local and you connect to it and all the important files you would ever share are on there.
Speaker 0: yes, you have one box full of hard drives just sitting somewhere in your house hidden away and You know on your computer the one you actually use.
Speaker 0: all you have in there is like the operating system and the software that you use.
Speaker 0: You know your Firefox your games, whatever and your mp3s, you know your documents all that other stuff that you use.
Speaker 0: You know your files.
Speaker 0: you keep them on this central drive somewhere else, you know, and it'll probably be a raid.
Speaker 0: So it'll be.
Speaker 0: you know, you have backups of it.
Speaker 0: It'll be nice and safe.
Speaker 0: And even if your computer gets fried all your data is safe.
Speaker 0: on this other drive on your computer There's just software that you can download again And also now it's all from CD again.
Speaker 0: Who cares like?
Speaker 1: you can have your home directories or all sorts of things on there so that every computer in your house Can get all your data all the time without you having to do anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah You don't have to worry about.
Speaker 0: is the mp3 on this computer that computer?
Speaker 0: all your mp3s are in one's Drive in one place accessible from any computer in the house.
Speaker 0: You can bring.
Speaker 0: someone brings a laptop in up.
Speaker 0: They just connect.
Speaker 0: all their files are there that they you know, you let them have access to.
Speaker 0: you know with the guest account Whatever they can get all the music all the movies one place easy to access, you know rim download something.
Speaker 0: It goes on to the Nez.
Speaker 0: when I want to go watch a video I go up in the video folder on the Nez.
Speaker 0: Oh, look all the things rim downloaded are already in there.
Speaker 0: I don't have to.
Speaker 0: you know, they're there.
Speaker 0: I don't have to go and look it around.
Speaker 0: What did rim download?
Speaker 0: What did I download?
Speaker 0: What's downloaded on the other computer?
Speaker 1: now if you're living with other people which that's why we said college is a Big place for this or you got roommates or you got a family.
Speaker 1: and you know I have my mp3 collection Scott as his mp3 collection.
Speaker 1: Emily and Alex both have their mp3 collections.
Speaker 1: What if we Consolidated all of our kiss?
Speaker 1: look right now.
Speaker 1: I have a separate collection from Scott.
Speaker 1: So on my computer I have every song.
Speaker 0: we don't actually have a nasty.
Speaker 1: No I have every song from initial D ever and Scott has the exact same collection of mp3s.
Speaker 1: that's super redundant and waste a lot of space and Administration and all sorts of what if we just took our mp3 collections merge them together so that there was the authoritative one?
Speaker 0: That would take a long time.
Speaker 1: But once it's done or if we'd like all new music we get we put on the sand or the NAS, right?
Speaker 0: So I keep mine, it's slowly but surely we put more and more music over there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like we move collections of things over there.
Speaker 1: It's like all the initial D music.
Speaker 1: fine We know we both have the same files.
Speaker 1: or I just downloaded the whole lutena ost.
Speaker 1: so we both delete all of our antenna crap and then we just get it from the sand or the NAS.
Speaker 1: and Eventually, there's nuts.
Speaker 1: and I say sand because in my work, I've never done anything but like the highest of enterprise.
Speaker 1: So yeah, but I deal we're never going to have a sand.
Speaker 0: people give up now unless you even if you win a lot You're never gonna have one.
Speaker 1: I mean look we do geek nights right at most like the most we're ever gonna have is gonna be a rack with like Three servers in it and one router and maybe one switch and that would pretty much be everything we'll ever need forever.
Speaker 1: Yep, you might upgrade those servers.
Speaker 0: thing about NAS is is that you know when we were in college we were thinking wow soon It'll be to the point where for a thousand dollars You can have a terabyte.
Speaker 0: now you can buy single drives that are a terabyte.
Speaker 0: You can get like five of those things for like a thousand dollars, you know it's.
Speaker 0: you're getting to the point where you can have a lot of storage and a small amount of physical space for really cheap and You buy a NAS and you'll be able to store your videos and your music and everything forever in one nice easy place.
Speaker 0: When it'll be nice that you get backups and you get raid and it's safe.
Speaker 1: Well, you the thing is it depends if you're.
Speaker 1: if you're backing stuff up to it Independently of other collections then yeah, you have backups of the things you have backed.
Speaker 0: That's sort of what Apple's new time capsule is all about.
Speaker 1: It's just an ass yep, but if you put all your files on it, then you have the one kind of backup the live backup in that if a Drive dies or something the raid takes care of it.
Speaker 1: You replace the drive and everything's cool, but you don't have backup backup.
Speaker 0: So I was assuming that you were smart enough to back up the NAS to somewhere else.
Speaker 1: Well, the problem is there's no media other than tapes that could fit the whole thing on another NAS.
Speaker 1: So yeah What I was gonna say is if you're cool and you got money and you really want to have your data safe You have a NAS and all your files are on it Then you have another NAS that's running maybe a slower like slower drives that are more reliable or a more reliable slower kind of raid.
Speaker 1: there's all sorts of things you could do and You back up Periodically and they're there did.
Speaker 1: we should do a show on exactly how to back up data like the schema.
Speaker 0: Another good idea is if you just keep your files on your local computer, right?
Speaker 0: It's because it's probably it's faster than that.
Speaker 1: I mean look I have like 700 gigs of space on my computer.
Speaker 1: now I'm like an eighth of that.
Speaker 0: you keep your files on your computer.
Speaker 0: You just back them up to the NAS with the time capsule is supposed to be If your computer hard drives crash, you can just get all your files from the NAS again.
Speaker 1: You can also read only access all the files from other computers.
Speaker 1: So the laptop can get all.
Speaker 1: your mp3 is via the backup read only But yet the master copy is still on your computer to update and change and whatever.
Speaker 1: then the updates get replicated every night or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yep There's not much more to say than that other than that.
Speaker 1: We're coming into the time where I feel like every technologically proficient Geeky household that has money and they're getting cheap to her.
Speaker 1: You can always pretty cheaply.
Speaker 0: We're also getting to the point where people are.
Speaker 0: they're not using so much software, you know You're using Firefox and web-based stuff more and more.
Speaker 0: you have less software on your computer.
Speaker 0: What computer you use matters less and less, you know, and it you know.
Speaker 0: people have laptops They're moving around they're changing computers all the time.
Speaker 0: I use Google Apps so much but you know the less people use local installed software the less people are stuck to any one computer.
Speaker 0: and if you really want to free yourself from having to use a specific computer And NAS is a great way to do that because you can use any Computer and as long as you can connect to your NAS it's like you're you know at your personal computer Even though it could be like your friend's computer, you know, cuz you got Firefox You can connect all your shit on the web and you connect to the NAS.
Speaker 0: But what else do you need?
Speaker 1: It's like your home and also I know a lot of you because most new motherboards support gigabit Ethernet just like straight up.
Speaker 1: I mean my motherboard does but I haven't used it.
Speaker 1: cuz I've no reason to switch when you give it switch, but Geeks what you can do and this is something that I will do eventually like we ever get something like this I'll do it.
Speaker 0: I don't get a house gigabit wiring.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is I don't need gigabit for the main network.
Speaker 1: That's kind of silly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because the gigabit is faster than the cable modem So it wouldn't help.
Speaker 1: but what you can have is a parallel network And if you're a geek you can run wires all over your house.
Speaker 1: Anyways, you don't care though wireless things like the time capsule are actually really cool.
Speaker 1: Don't discount them You're.
Speaker 1: you don't need that good performance.
Speaker 0: Wireless is fast enough for you people.
Speaker 1: Trust me pretty much I mean if you're streaming like HD, whatever then you're probably need a wire.
Speaker 1: but what you do for cool, right?
Speaker 1: If you want it like you're one of those people's like man I want to use all the cool stuff my computer has.
Speaker 1: I want to do it.
Speaker 1: You have a two-tiered network where you have the normal switch, right?
Speaker 1: You can do this with one switch.
Speaker 1: if you get a good switch You have the normal switch Connects to the router connects to the FiOS or the cable modem or whatever and all your computers connect to that.
Speaker 1: That's your normal network, but all these new motherboards you notice have two network holes.
Speaker 1: You have a second network That is connected to by all your computers in the house and is not connected anywhere else not accessible to the internet.
Speaker 1: Nothing completely private and your run gigabit over that and the only thing on there is your local NAS and all your computers.
Speaker 1: Yep, so then you have a full backplane so you can stream as much as you want as fast as you possibly can faster The computer can hand you.
Speaker 0: because right think about if you had one network, right?
Speaker 0: You only had one network and the NAS was on it.
Speaker 0: Well, let's say I'm downloading something from BitTorrent on.
Speaker 0: that's on the normal network.
Speaker 0: And then I'm also listening to music on the NAS.
Speaker 0: Well, now I'm downloading from two places into my computer through this normal sized network hole.
Speaker 1: A switch doesn't help you if your one computer is doing everything.
Speaker 0: Yes, you have one computer downloading from something in the house and it's also downloading from the internet.
Speaker 0: That's gonna clog that up cool right quick.
Speaker 0: But if the downloading from the thing in the house is on a separate network and the BitTorrent is on another network It's gonna be not interfering with each other.
Speaker 0: You're gonna have you know, they're using different bandwidth there.
Speaker 1: Also, it's just I don't know maybe it's cuz I'm a network geek but I like setting up complex network setups and something like that.
Speaker 0: It's not a bad network setup for an advanced house.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is that's the kind of thing that enterprise, you know, whatever That's.
Speaker 1: that's what you do.
Speaker 1: You have the backplane of data transfer and the kind of front plane or that the main network of everything else.
Speaker 0: I think a normal person though.
Speaker 0: Just a regular gigabit LAN in the house would be just fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, definitely Yeah, but it's something cool you can do and that's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you want a Nez you can either just built like I said build a computer with some hard drives in it and then install some software that does network sharing and you're done.
Speaker 0: or many companies like Buffalo and Drobo and There's a whole bunch of companies.
Speaker 0: I forget the names of the other ones.
Speaker 0: they sell these boxes Right and sometimes the boxes come with drives and sometimes they don't and you just put drives in the box.
Speaker 0: if it doesn't come with Them it's a little tiny box.
Speaker 0: you plug the box in you connect to the network.
Speaker 0: It takes care of the rest for you.
Speaker 0: you're done Right.
Speaker 0: and the boxes?
Speaker 0: you can be anywhere from like a few hundred to like a thousand dollars Maybe even more depending on how many drives and what features it has.
Speaker 0: and just do your research on them.
Speaker 0: You know, the Drobo is probably the simplest one because like USB, you know When it has some pretty advanced features, it looks cool.
Speaker 0: But this is other ones and if you want a Nez and you don't want to bother setting it up You can just buy a pre-built one and it's the easy way out.
Speaker 1: Yep We'll probably show in the future on.
Speaker 1: you know How to set one up and how to go about all that business, but that is a much less interesting much more.
Speaker 0: We'll do this then do this Shows on the specific network sharing protocols like NFS and Samba and such.
Speaker 1: We also have to do a show on a like data schema and data storage and how you like information.
Speaker 1: I'll say this because this is kind of important the way that you structure how you save your data is becoming more and more Important because it is more and more difficult to get the data you want and to get it efficiently and to maintain it efficiently And to back it up efficient.
Speaker 0: That's why people are using things like Google desktop and Beagle and tracker D.
Speaker 1: None of that is necessary if you store your data in a reasonable and intelligent schema.
Speaker 0: No, but it can be helpful.
Speaker 0: Even if you in story.
Speaker 1: Yes, it definitely can but things like backups are so much easier If your data is put together in some sort of verifiable way.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: and on that note as I say at the end of almost every episode Dinner's almost done and I'm hungry and I can smell it.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four Different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: For the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.