Speaker 1: It's Monday June 2nd.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm Red.
Speaker 1: This is geek night tonight.
Speaker 1: denial of service attacks.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So over the weekend, we did something that until now has really never been done in the history of humanity.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it was kind of amazing and I can't believe we pulled it off.
Speaker 1: why do I?
Speaker 1: I don't a brag but I was the person who suggested it and I'm betting that without my Constant prodding it would not have occurred.
Speaker 0: I don't know about constant prodding.
Speaker 1: I prodded.
Speaker 1: I prodded at least four times.
Speaker 0: It was pretty much Hey, let's do it.
Speaker 0: And then we all went around getting everybody Your eyes before that moment.
Speaker 1: I had prodded to do it like three times when you just weren't there.
Speaker 1: I was prodding not you.
Speaker 1: I was prodding James and other people's.
Speaker 0: But yeah, we over the weekend.
Speaker 0: Well, actually it was a crazy weekend.
Speaker 0: first on Friday We stayed in the city and we interviewed Hal Cali, you know with Brian Nishi Tokyo FM all that fun stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll talk about that a little bit later.
Speaker 0: for that We ate once again at that place right next to Grand Central Central Cafe slash Pershing Square.
Speaker 1: Yep I really want to get that breakfast.
Speaker 0: Well this weekend at the mocha.
Speaker 1: Nah, it's out true.
Speaker 0: I think that's gonna happen Yep, but then immediately in the morning, we attempted to drive out to James and Lisa's wedding, huh?
Speaker 0: Which was somewhat held up by the fact that Scott suddenly decided out of the blue.
Speaker 1: We're like, alright It wasn't out of the blue.
Speaker 1: Basically what had happened in the morning?
Speaker 0: I'm like, alright, I'm gonna pack and then we'll go and Scott's like, oh, yeah Well, I got I'm out of deodorant.
Speaker 0: So we got to go to the grocery store so I can buy some.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, and I got to get an oil change on the way.
Speaker 0: So I'll stop and do that.
Speaker 1: Well, basically what I tried to get an oil change earlier and I failed.
Speaker 1: You know when I had a day off and then I failed and failed and then I realized hey We're gonna pass by one on our way kinda.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I'm like, hey, you know, we'll just we'll just go and get it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we're gonna pass by and it happens to me next to a grocery store.
Speaker 1: So how convenient?
Speaker 0: yeah Except we're gonna pass by a valvoline on a Saturday late morning Which is pretty much when everyone in the world decides to get oil change.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I decided not to get an oil change which was a good thing.
Speaker 1: as it turns out.
Speaker 0: Yes, but the problem here is that because we'd gotten off the freeway to get the oil change Scott got on the wrong road.
Speaker 1: Well, basically we live on interstate 84. any 84 crosses with 87 and those are like the two ways to get upstate are either take 87 and then 90 or take 84 to 17 to 86. no to 81 81 86 is 70.
Speaker 1: I know 86 slash 17. see the real trick 81 to 690 90.
Speaker 0: the real trick is 690.
Speaker 1: that takes you around Syracuse.
Speaker 0: Yep, you don't want to get on 481.
Speaker 1: Well you do if you want to go out even to the crazy places.
Speaker 0: Well, you see it on 41, I guess if you're going east, but who would be going east?
Speaker 1: Well, you can.
Speaker 1: you can also take 86. you can go to 390 instead of 690 Doesn't go all the way there yet.
Speaker 0: So it's like freeway freeway freeway and then like 25 miles of 35 mile an hour one-horse towns.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, the point is is that since I'm just just I knew that we were going to try to take 17 8 86 up instead of taking you know, 87 to 90 which and it is a much faster route to take these 17 slash 86.
Speaker 0: Yep, because I go back actually kind of often cuz no Emily's family's out in Rochester.
Speaker 1: That's the way we came home.
Speaker 1: The only issue was is because just being over in You know the place where we got off for the oil change when I'm over there My natural instinct is just get on 87 north and I did and I'm like, oops
Speaker 0: Yeah, the worst thing is he's going toward 87 north.
Speaker 0: I'm like Scott.
Speaker 0: Why are you getting on the throughway?
Speaker 0: and by then it was way too late for him to get off the throughway and the next?
Speaker 0: Exit was in Poughkeepsie at which point we might as well just stay on the stupid through way and go through all the.
Speaker 1: yeah I was like rim.
Speaker 1: if we lived in Poughkeepsie, would you have gone south and then gone?
Speaker 1: You know West 17 or would you go just north?
Speaker 0: Well, if I here's the problem if I lived in Poughkeepsie, I would have gone south Really?
Speaker 0: The reason is if you're in Poughkeepsie, you can't just get on the throughway.
Speaker 0: You actually have to take 299 way across and that's like the worst road to be on.
Speaker 0: It's true because we were.
Speaker 0: you know, we're at the same latitude longitude Latitude latitude as Poughkeepsie, but if you want to go east-west to get to Poughkeepsie, you actually have to drive a ways.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway, so We just be took a slower way there But we still got there before almost everybody.
Speaker 0: Scott Johnson who actually went to Rochester the day before, you know The old stomping ground.
Speaker 1: Yeah, only the people who had to be there earlier or decided to be there earlier We're there before us.
Speaker 0: I think the best party's crew people.
Speaker 1: I'm sure family people were there first.
Speaker 0: I worried like we're running so late whatever.
Speaker 0: Nah, because we also independently of all that we're.
Speaker 0: I was super slow waking up and I I didn't even packed it here.
Speaker 0: It's Scott and we're just like whatever and we're slow and then we're about to go.
Speaker 0: We're just gonna grab Emily and get on the road and we see oh There's Alex.
Speaker 0: He hasn't got left yet.
Speaker 0: There's his van.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it was good because you know Despite getting there early.
Speaker 1: We had a lot of time.
Speaker 1: just sit around and do nothing Which is great considering we haven't had a lot of that lately, you know I was able to sit around and read comics and not worry about anything because I was in a hotel with the broken Wi-Fi and Alright, and that brings us to the next point Which is we're gonna we're gonna change some stuff up here because we have no time
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Now if we were just gonna keep doing gig nights as is forever We'd probably would have kept the old format.
Speaker 0: But basically we've been for a long time.
Speaker 0: We got a lot of side projects and I think that most of them are pretty much as cool as geek nights.
Speaker 0: But by doing geek nights four nights a week we really can't do any of those other projects in a reasonable span of time and in addition to that the The quality of geek nights degrades as we continue to force ourselves to.
Speaker 1: you know Sort of use all our ideas up really quickly.
Speaker 0: Well part of it was that I think the catalyst was one that Scott his work schedule changed so he gets home like way late And you get home way early.
Speaker 0: So I get home at like five something.
Speaker 1: But you're also waking up way early.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, so that mismatch there of shifting sort of you know an hour in each direction sort of screwed us up a bit Which would have been fine.
Speaker 0: but the other problem was you know we got the camera we ought to make some video and we got all these programming projects and we're doing more and more live stuff and we're we're kind of expanding in every direction and Basically, it's either do all of that or do four nights of geek nights four nights a week Like we've been doing for the last 500 episodes.
Speaker 1: Yes, so we have decided that you know, I mean you can't reasonably expect.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyone who thinks that geek nights is gonna continue without changing forever.
Speaker 1: You're sadly mistake.
Speaker 0: I wonder if you people realize that we almost completely changed the format and the music and everything at the beginning of season two.
Speaker 1: Well, we wanted to.
Speaker 0: we almost did.
Speaker 0: I had the music all set up and I always didn't do it.
Speaker 1: news didn't do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we should do it eventually maybe for season for season 100 I don't know.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so yeah temporarily what we're gonna do is we're gonna do two episodes a week.
Speaker 1: So that's gonna be this week will be a Monday and a Wednesday show and next week We'll make a Tuesday and a Thursday show.
Speaker 1: So actually each of the four separate geek nights shows will come out to once every other week.
Speaker 1: So it'll be Monday.
Speaker 1: wait two weeks.
Speaker 1: There'll be another Monday.
Speaker 1: Wait two weeks will be another Monday.
Speaker 1: So think of it as four podcasts that are separate and each one is bi-weekly.
Speaker 0: That's a little frightening though because pretty much the only other anime podcasts out there, you know anime world order and fast karate I mean fast karate updated kind of a similar rate, but they might put out more shows than us now.
Speaker 1: Well, at least they might put out more animation.
Speaker 1: well Yeah, they do two shows a week.
Speaker 1: So our animation they'll put up the same number of shows as us But they will be putting out more anime shows because they'll do an anime show every week in a game show every week.
Speaker 1: But we will.
Speaker 0: we have the technology and also the Thursday shows coming out, but regardless We don't know how long this will be.
Speaker 0: It's a temporary thing.
Speaker 0: Think of it as like a mini sabbatical except for spending our sabbatical working.
Speaker 0: But
Speaker 1: also now you know how all the time we would say things like we're gonna have merch we're gonna have video We're gonna have this and that and the other thing and with those things never appear Those things are actually going to appear although I was still will not commit to any timeline.
Speaker 0: Yes No, I gotta say wait till you guys see our first t-shirt and Wait till you see our second t-shirt, which is now just a concept.
Speaker 0: But the concept is so badass that I'm looking forward to it already.
Speaker 1: And what do you see?
Speaker 1: some of these videos?
Speaker 1: I mean The videos aren't gonna be like, you know, super awesome to begin with not gonna be college humor quality No, but we're working up to it and I think they'll entertain you regardless.
Speaker 0: Yeah Right.
Speaker 0: So but anyway also over the weekend, you know, like I said, we were James and Lisa's wedding.
Speaker 0: I don't know if we should even wait and use like a whole Thursday show about the wedding itself.
Speaker 1: We could do it next week.
Speaker 0: It was kind of an epic confluence something that hasn't happened in a long time where Basically with very few exceptions the entire front row crew was in one place at one time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like even you know, there are even people I haven't seen in like years who we were really close with but we sort of You know got distanced and then it's like oh my god I can't believe you're here and then it was like I'd.
Speaker 1: you know, I talked to them yesterday.
Speaker 0: I mean God who is missing in that picture?
Speaker 1: We're missing like Nuri Nuri Evan and that's it.
Speaker 0: I can't think of anyone else.
Speaker 0: we're missing from that picture.
Speaker 1: Of course the one person that they think was missing is gonna be like crying that someone's gonna be out there.
Speaker 0: You know who you are?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the one thing I can say about the wedding for now is that it was very very geeky But it was also very subtly and classily geeky.
Speaker 0: I mean the vase we brought back.
Speaker 0: there are all these little touches like the cufflinks with the with the GBA's and the Gameboys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it wasn't like, you know You go to a bar mitzvah and the theme is like overt like there's just Nintendo characters all over the place like a kid's birthday Party where you have little hats that have Mario on them and plates with Pokemon on them.
Speaker 1: It wasn't like that, but I had a video game themed wedding.
Speaker 1: But if you were not a nerd and you did not look closely You would not have known it would have looked like just a generic wedding, you know flowers and colors also, we danced to Numa Numa and the bride got Rick rolled.
Speaker 1: that was And that was the Rick rolling was not even a front row crew.
Speaker 1: Responsibleness.
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't but that's that's part of it was that the family and the families involved have some geekery going on.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's for sure.
Speaker 0: It was it was epic Yeah, also the front row crew in together like that outside of the context of the geek house and beacon which I guess You know.
Speaker 0: Scott always says hey, it doesn't matter where we are We just hang out.
Speaker 0: but context matters a lot.
Speaker 0: because the context of the geek house You kind of fall into these mores of these tropes where we watch the YouTube videos and we watch the Horatio We play the D&D and we do this and that and this and that and then we go eat at the cafe Maya But suddenly we're in a different context and everything changed.
Speaker 1: I think the also the combination of people also matters, you know It's like when you see someone you haven't seen in a long time You're gonna be talking to them a lot more Every other week.
Speaker 0: I talked to like Steve Pomeroy in any depth.
Speaker 0: I was still working at IBM.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the last time I talked to him like in person was years ago But I you know, I am to maybe like less than 20 times since then.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's kind of crazy.
Speaker 0: so there will be some some epic pictures coming up, of course, the other thing that probably added the experience was the Serious amount of alcohol consumption zero by me.
Speaker 0: Yeah zero by Scott.
Speaker 0: I made up for that.
Speaker 0: great All right, so this is the new improved gig night.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we can talk long like this because we're only doing two a week and we still have the same out.
Speaker 1: It's you know storage space to fill up.
Speaker 1: So yeah, it doesn't matter this episodes go a little weird.
Speaker 0: Who gives a shit the moment we started like we decided?
Speaker 0: All right, we're gonna split this up and we're gonna cut back on the shows.
Speaker 0: I pretty much have things to talk about as this kind of opening bit for like the next two weeks of the normal schedule.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm thinking is that by doing the fewer shows right it's like I only have to watch one anime every two weeks.
Speaker 1: So not only am I saving that sort of one hour of time from not doing the show one week But I'm having to watch less anime in order to keep up you know with having something to talk about.
Speaker 1: and that is where the real time savings is gonna come in and that's where that is the Act that the time the time where we actually sit down and record.
Speaker 1: Getting that hour back isn't really gonna help me put out a video.
Speaker 0: not having to watch two anime series Not having to not watch two anime series exactly.
Speaker 1: It's gonna allow me to watch Make a video.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm almost done with princess tutu and I'm working through Kazen.
Speaker 0: Oh, yo Jimbo pretty quick.
Speaker 1: All right Anyway, we're good to come.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the only thing though.
Speaker 0: Oh, so, you know, we're doing the show the different schedule.
Speaker 0: well now like we always said the show quality should go up because Theoretically we have more time to research and put stuff together and it'll be kind of badass.
Speaker 0: but Because this is the first of those shows.
Speaker 0: We did not save any time from this show.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean We spent the last three four days in the middle of nowhere with no internet.
Speaker 1: So there's no.
Speaker 1: How are we gonna prepare for this particular episode?
Speaker 0: I think that is why we have to do the separate show about the wedding because that is basically going to be two shows first The wedding and the crew and everything but second the fact that Geneva, New York I don't want to really disparage the town, but does anyone live there?
Speaker 1: I think I've realized how the economy works though They all.
Speaker 1: they just sell wine to other the rest of the world.
Speaker 0: wine and weddings wine and weddings.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it was a pretty desolate play.
Speaker 0: I mean we thought oh, there's a cute little Main Street.
Speaker 0: Let's go down.
Speaker 1: and there was a really good cafe.
Speaker 1: other means there was anyway.
Speaker 1: So we should get into some technologies before people go crazy.
Speaker 0: I have any tech news.
Speaker 1: I do indeed Ram have you been in my room lately?
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I don't really go into your room.
Speaker 0: that often I mean what the studio is in my room and my room is also the room that has enough like we can hang out in It.
Speaker 0: it's big.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of floor space.
Speaker 0: So why would I go to your room on the other side of the house read some comics?
Speaker 0: Well, I guess yeah, but I haven't read any comics lately.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe you should know You'll bring the comics out and you'll give them to me and then when I'm done with them you take them back.
Speaker 1: I don't always take it back.
Speaker 1: Anyway in my room.
Speaker 1: There's a computer case and on top of that computer case I believe are no less than six power supplies four of which Definitely work one of which might work and one definitely doesn't.
Speaker 1: one of them is really high-quality One.
Speaker 1: a couple of them one is dented, but I think it works, but it's scary.
Speaker 1: one's also works But it's scary and is very.
Speaker 1: they range from lots of watts to not so many watts and there's an also another Really good perfectly working one downstairs in under the stairs.
Speaker 1: So I get a lot of power supplies.
Speaker 1: I Don't nearly have that many computers now.
Speaker 0: beyond that we have multiple motherboards some work Some don't piles of ran all these hard drives.
Speaker 0: They're completely useless.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I still have that 12-inch CRT.
Speaker 0: That came with the first computer I ever owned.
Speaker 0: I used it in college as my aim and win amp monitor.
Speaker 1: I built that new computer and the new computer was mostly new parts.
Speaker 1: I didn't port over a lot of parts from old computers, you know, I mostly ported over data from old computers.
Speaker 1: So when I tried to take the old computer out of the case and Transplant it and I sort of broke things and you know, I'm a lot of the parts I have just don't work.
Speaker 0: I just we used to be a lot more careful.
Speaker 0: I remember when I know I like any computer part would get used and all man.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean when I was in high school, I had a thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: I bought a computer that was like, holy shit.
Speaker 1: But now it's like I bought a computer.
Speaker 0: All right Yeah But the other thing is get work.
Speaker 0: technology is moving fast enough to where we have.
Speaker 0: we have more Obsolete computer technology than modern computer technology in this house.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so and of all that obsolete computer technology I had to get Alex to give us a motherboard so to be able to make one fully working computer.
Speaker 1: That's mostly working and we could have used Shehzar but we didn't because that's not a hundred percent working.
Speaker 0: everything works, but one of the USB headers It's still not a hundred percent work in the Northbridge fan.
Speaker 1: It's not a hundred percent work It is.
Speaker 1: I wanted to make a hundred percent working machine anyway.
Speaker 1: So I got all these computer parts some working some not but not enough to actually do anything useful with.
Speaker 1: So what do I do with them?
Speaker 1: So I was thinking of finding one of those places where they build computers and then give them to people who don't have computers.
Speaker 1: But I couldn't actually find one of those places near here.
Speaker 1: I think they're in California those places.
Speaker 1: so I was like, huh?
Speaker 1: What do I do?
Speaker 1: I can't just throw it out.
Speaker 1: I mean you can't you know throw out computer parts just like you can't throw out a television, you know, it's big fancy electronics.
Speaker 1: They're not disposable things in the trash.
Speaker 1: You have to get rid of them Especially like you have to get rid of car batteries in a special way and get rid of tires.
Speaker 0: I know a lot of you out there probably do just throw these things away, but you really shouldn't be.
Speaker 0: they're not good to be In the garbage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not something as power supply.
Speaker 1: especially it's not something you can put in the trash or a CRT.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a stick of RAM isn't gonna be so bad but even then you don't want to throw that out in the trash right and plus think about how Complicated piece of machinery that is and you're just gonna throw it out.
Speaker 1: Like it's it's such a complicated thing.
Speaker 1: It has value just even if it's not working now.
Speaker 0: We've had trouble in the past.
Speaker 0: I mean we had the 1974 color RCA that sat outside on our back porch for almost a month because we couldn't figure out how to throw it away And no one would take it.
Speaker 1: It still worked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was the scariest thing.
Speaker 0: We plug that bastard back in outside and we turn it on and it works fine And it gets to get signal after being rained on.
Speaker 0: rained on multiple times.
Speaker 1: So I've been trying to find a way to get rid of them and I found some electronics recycling places And but then none of them are really of one of them.
Speaker 1: I called it the phone number and no one picked up like it didn't exist anymore.
Speaker 1: It's like great.
Speaker 1: The post office is gonna have a thing soon.
Speaker 1: I think I talked about this before.
Speaker 1: Where you go they have special envelopes and you put like an old cell phone in it or something and you met and you just Put it in the mailbox and for free they will take it someplace to be taken care of and that's cool.
Speaker 1: But it doesn't work for a power supply even though it might work for say a CPU or a cell phone.
Speaker 1: So what am I supposed to do with these power supplies?
Speaker 1: Well Best buy might come to the rescue.
Speaker 1: They've got this plan where right now.
Speaker 1: It's only they're testing it out.
Speaker 1: We're in like a hundred or so stores in specific areas like Baltimore and somewhere else.
Speaker 1: I didn't check if we're on the list I don't know we're not yet and what they?
Speaker 1: there's a limit of two items per person per day or something like that.
Speaker 1: So you just I get a whole bunch of people to come into the store like three people to get rid of six power supplies And they're gonna test to see if this program of them taking away, you know And recite recycling your old computer bits is a good idea for them because for them the benefit they get is they get you in The store, you know, and I'm sure also
Speaker 0: it might work is the last time I went into a Best Buy I ended up buying some anime because that's really the best place to buy anime nowadays.
Speaker 1: Yeah, except for Amazon.
Speaker 0: Um, I don't know.
Speaker 0: cuz Best Buy always has the crazy box set sales.
Speaker 1: Amazon sells the box.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much the same price.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I didn't see Eska flown a for 25.
Speaker 1: I think what it is $28.
Speaker 1: I think what it is is that an Amazon you're not really like.
Speaker 1: it's hard to think of all the anime.
Speaker 1: So when you see them on the shelf, it's a lot easier to go all this show.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I remember that but on Amazon you have to actually actively search for it in order to find out.
Speaker 0: plus the last Few times I searched for a particular show on Amazon randomly.
Speaker 0: They were still really expensive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway.
Speaker 1: So yeah, this this might be might be cool.
Speaker 1: The thing is I'm questioning, right?
Speaker 1: How do I know if I give them a working power supply to recycle?
Speaker 1: Are they just gonna recycle it anyway?
Speaker 1: Or are they gonna say hey this works and try to sell it or as an open box at the same time.
Speaker 0: What do you care?
Speaker 0: Well, cuz they're taking the burden onto themselves to deal with this thing.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: However, the thing is why doesn't GameStop just say game recycling Give us your games to recycle and we would you know, it's it's you know.
Speaker 1: And then they sell them to someone else and make money off.
Speaker 0: well I think the the value of a game is much more long-term and useful and and apparent to the average person.
Speaker 0: I mean think most of the people going to Best Buy are gonna bring their old broken computer or their broken LCD and then they're gonna buy a new LCD.
Speaker 0: Best Buy is hoping that people like us don't come.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's another good point.
Speaker 1: right if I show up with six power supplies, right that counts as six items.
Speaker 1: What if someone shows up with a computer in a case that has a power supply and a motherboard and two hard drives in it?
Speaker 1: That's actually like five items.
Speaker 0: There's the front panel the back panel the side panel I know.
Speaker 0: so so you know what you do.
Speaker 0: the answer is you bring a case with six power supplies mounted.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah You got it.
Speaker 0: So I'm getting rid of this computer.
Speaker 0: I wonder if they'll even open it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just have like three motherboards and like wow, this computer is really heavy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's yeah, no, I got you know, SLI video cards.
Speaker 0: I have an SLI motherboard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I could get rid of these things and say Craigslist or eBay, especially the working ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just so much.
Speaker 1: It's just so much work to do that that it's not even worth it considering the problem how obsolete most.
Speaker 0: Anytime we try to use Craigslist to not even to sell things but to give away things.
Speaker 0: The people who respond I don't know if they're stupid or what but they'll respond and say they basically either won't under like they don't even understand Apparently what it is you were giving away or they say yeah, I'd like it with no follow-up information.
Speaker 0: And then they don't respond when you email them back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm like, alright, so, where do you want to meet?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Where do you want to meet?
Speaker 1: It's up to you.
Speaker 1: You decide I'll be there.
Speaker 1: Oh No, we'll meet at this place at this time.
Speaker 1: No reply, are you gonna show up there?
Speaker 1: No reply.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not worth that effort.
Speaker 1: I'd rather just get rid of it then have to you know spend time dealing with these people now.
Speaker 0: Is there any sort of limit on the size of things you like?
Speaker 0: Could I roll a fridge over there?
Speaker 1: I didn't see anything like that.
Speaker 1: But Roy, I imagine a fridge might not be accepted.
Speaker 0: Could I have taken the 1974 color RCA?
Speaker 1: That's a good question.
Speaker 1: I think it's mostly targeted at like, you know digital cam.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, like that.
Speaker 0: What is their policy?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: it wasn't put there.
Speaker 1: I'd have to go look into that but it would be interesting to see what the policy is.
Speaker 1: You know, will they even take a power supply?
Speaker 0: Yeah, will they take batteries?
Speaker 0: Will they take electronics?
Speaker 0: I ripped out of my car.
Speaker 1: There really needs to be an easier way to get rid of this shit.
Speaker 1: That's all I'm saying.
Speaker 0: Well, eventually, I think our society will get to the point where it'll be a lot like other recycling because one of the biggest problems with Recycling was that early on it took effort.
Speaker 0: You had to split up the different Glasses and plastics and things and most people wouldn't bother and it was a giant pain.
Speaker 1: Now they have a machine that does that.
Speaker 0: Yes, and that alone.
Speaker 0: how that machine any other activism got more people to recycle.
Speaker 0: if you just I put it in a thing And someone else takes care of it.
Speaker 0: and that's the way it needs to be.
Speaker 0: to get more people to recycle stuff like this.
Speaker 1: and how The machine how recycling sorting machines work is way cool Like it's got magnets to pull the metal apart from the glass and then it's gets way cool way cool.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so the FCC Probably my favorite government organization.
Speaker 1: Oh, they're fantastic.
Speaker 0: I love them But Despite all their problems they've decided now I'll get to the the rub if you will in this.
Speaker 0: they have decided that one thing they would like to do is take an unused piece of the 25 megahertz wireless spectrum and Auction it off such that whoever wins What must offer free internet access over that spectrum and in return like the rest of the spectrum?
Speaker 0: That's associated with it.
Speaker 0: They can use for whatever commercial business they want.
Speaker 1: No, I'm liking that.
Speaker 1: now The the thing is what quality of service they can offer.
Speaker 1: Yes, we have giving you free one byte per second internet access.
Speaker 1: Congratulations.
Speaker 0: Well, the evidence behind this is partly that a lot of people are saying that it'll get broadband More it'll get more penetration in broadband markets, especially in rural areas and that sort of that is definitely needed.
Speaker 0: Definitely have semi broadband out there.
Speaker 0: But once again the rub here is that at the same time?
Speaker 0: Whoever offers this free internet must censor it and allow absolutely no obscene material to be Over those that can't be.
Speaker 0: now Why is the FCC still?
Speaker 0: why don't they just give up?
Speaker 0: Why do we still even try?
Speaker 1: I mean, what is the law that the FCC uses to base?
Speaker 1: You know the idea that it has the power to actually censor the call It does.
Speaker 0: the FCC is.
Speaker 0: their mandate is to regulate the airwaves and it has been Accepted and assumed by the courts forever that that includes monitoring the the obscenity on the airwaves.
Speaker 1: The SEC's job should just be the technology of the airwaves and if they want to monitor any obscenity or perhaps You know people doing you know it to say the say the content of my radio broadcast is criminal Then the FBI should be all over that not the FCC.
Speaker 0: Yes I mean, I'm definitely of the mind that the FCC should regulate the airwaves.
Speaker 0: Otherwise the airwaves become yeah Cuz.
Speaker 1: then I'll broadcast on FM 93.2 and Rimmel broadcast an FM 93.2 and it'll be totally useless.
Speaker 1: cuz everyone in the cars were here and they will not be cool, but I Think you think oh we'll have a lot to say about this.
Speaker 0: But what can I say other than that good God one it's impossible.
Speaker 0: We already can't censor anything because there's no real definition of obscenity that works.
Speaker 0: and the legal definition of obscenity is Yeah, it's totally subjective.
Speaker 1: Yep Plus, you know, how are they gonna any filtering mechanism?
Speaker 1: They come up with.
Speaker 1: someone will find a way around it.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is even if they try to filter and even though you can't figure out how to filter and whatever, you know Everyone's different definition.
Speaker 1: You're gonna filter out geek nights because we say fuck sometimes but in a filter at the penny arcade.
Speaker 0: Luckily, the interesting part is that all the carriers who are looking into these auctions pretty much said wow We're not gonna bid on that.
Speaker 0: That's come.
Speaker 0: Why would we even consider dealing with all that crap?
Speaker 1: I see Yes, no one's gonna buy that spectrum if they're forced.
Speaker 1: I mean someone might buy it, you know to offer free internet.
Speaker 1: No one's gonna be willing to deal with all this censoring bullshit.
Speaker 0: Well, who wants to put up with that?
Speaker 0: Actually, this is the part that's kind of said.
Speaker 0: now from what I've read the wireless carriers are not Avoiding it because of the censorship.
Speaker 0: They're avoiding it because they don't want to have to offer the free part.
Speaker 1: Well, of course, they don't want to offer the free part either.
Speaker 0: But I'm sure the winning bidder would also have to provide to build out the system to serve 50% of the US population within four years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's that's quite an expense.
Speaker 1: 95% within ten years that is.
Speaker 1: that's crazy that even without the censorship that they have cost of Building up that kind of network far outweighs the value of pretty much giving someone the entire spectrum.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically the issue here is that while there's the censorship part and the FCC once again stepping What I think is beyond the reasonable bounds of its power.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter because what they are asking for is technologically unfeasible impossible and unreasonable.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I think I like how.
Speaker 1: The part I like is just what they did with the other spectrum where they put in sort of clauses like you have to keep It open, you know and it's questions as to whether Verizon's actually doing what they're supposed to do But Google's on top of that.
Speaker 1: So it's all good and you know where it's.
Speaker 1: you don't have to build.
Speaker 1: They don't force you to build any particular kind of network.
Speaker 1: They just said whatever you do You got to make sure that whatever you use that spectrum for you know, other people can get in on that, you know.
Speaker 1: So I think we're gonna see some good stuff soon from that area.
Speaker 1: So if you haven't noticed our voices have been going down sort of with this show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, unlike conventions where we lose we expect to have our voices get hurt a little bit because we'll do you know Connecticut?
Speaker 0: I really want like 10 or 11 panels this year.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be crazy.
Speaker 0: And we always do like all these events we wreck ourselves, but it's expected.
Speaker 0: but I always forget Whenever the front row crew gets together in any quantity We lose our voices because we spend the whole Weekend pretty much from when we wake up in the morning till we fall asleep talking loud.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm with a bunch of people.
Speaker 1: I want to talk to all of them constantly Non-stop for three days and we happen to spend a lot of that time in a room with a lot of people also talking.
Speaker 1: So you're gonna talk loudly.
Speaker 0: it's one.
Speaker 0: you're gonna lose the voice.
Speaker 0: It was actually was really interesting because I remember in the early days of the FRC when we'd all be hanging out in like our colony apartment.
Speaker 0: anyone who wasn't already kind of With or savvy to the way we were like they'd walk in and it was this wall of sound.
Speaker 0: There are eight people gaga in a room and all of them are talking at the same time all the time and it never ends.
Speaker 0: It's kind of dwindle lately because we've got the smaller crew that lives in beacon and the smaller crew we play burning wheel with.
Speaker 0: so we we see this group of people all the time and There are very few Controversial issues left and we all know everything going on in each other's lives.
Speaker 0: So we don't have the wall of sound anymore, but suddenly new people every old story got told again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if you haven't seen someone in two years Imagine how much you have to say to them.
Speaker 0: a lot god, especially considering we have something weird happen to us pretty much every week.
Speaker 1: Yep, you hear it all in the show.
Speaker 0: Anyway, right so things of the day I'll be short and sweet cuz we're going long and like I said my throat starting to go but I Like accordions and accordion music and if you have a problem with that you can die in a fire.
Speaker 0: accordions are really cool instruments Yeah, and this guy if you don't believe that.
Speaker 0: even if you don't like accordions watch this video.
Speaker 0: It's one of those colleague humor videos, but it's a guy playing flight of the bumblebee.
Speaker 1: Okay That's it.
Speaker 0: Was that your rendition of flight of the bumblebee?
Speaker 0: Yes, I mean remember accordions are serious business.
Speaker 0: You can play the melody and the chord harmonies Simultaneously and all.
Speaker 1: yeah you have to cut and while you're doing that right you're playing what the Harmony with one hand the melody with the other hand and you have to move your arms back and forth the whole time.
Speaker 0: Hey, it's easier than the bagpipes.
Speaker 0: You gotta just keep blowing.
Speaker 1: Well that bagpipes all about lung power.
Speaker 1: the accordion has more coordination required than the bagpipe.
Speaker 0: It depends on what you're playing.
Speaker 1: But yeah, yeah I see, you know, you can't really.
Speaker 1: I never heard anyone play a bagpipe like did it, you know, it's usually like D You know Danny boy, whatever.
Speaker 1: I don't even know how that song goes.
Speaker 0: I'm not even gonna try to sing.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I sound.
Speaker 0: I sound like one of those smokers.
Speaker 0: It's what?
Speaker 1: yeah No, you're not.
Speaker 0: Wow, I think I know why smokers talk that way.
Speaker 0: It actually is easier to talk like this than to talk in my normal voice right now.
Speaker 1: Not really.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so OpenOffice if it it's kind of taking a backseat lately because we have things like, you know, Google Docs and such.
Speaker 1: But OpenOffice still has a place in the world.
Speaker 1: I mean if you need a full office suite with you know The full office applications the spreadsheet the word processor all that business and you don't want to pay the ludicrous price for Microsoft Office.
Speaker 1: OpenOffice is pretty much the only viable choice, you know.
Speaker 1: But it has its problems in terms of performance in terms of sort of crummy user interface, right?
Speaker 1: So I found this thing it's called like red office.
Speaker 1: I think I don't remember.
Speaker 1: it's the computers in the other room.
Speaker 1: I have a Remembering what a website I looked at.
Speaker 1: Where's your laptop in the other room?
Speaker 1: anyway And basically what this is just OpenOffice with a replacement user interface.
Speaker 1: That's far superior According to the screenshots.
Speaker 1: I looked at.
Speaker 1: so if you like OpenOffice and you want a free office suite To install on your computer, but you hate the OpenOffice user interface because it sucks and it does suck This looks like a good alternative.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 1: So check out this story.
Speaker 1: This story gave us the idea of what to talk about today.
Speaker 1: So, you know the the dig guys right.
Speaker 1: they have their revision 3 company which sort of does all their video podcasts?
Speaker 1: you know the dig nation the Tekzilla Control all chicken.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they still do that one.
Speaker 1: They got a bunch of TV video shows over there, right and they want to deliver those TV shows.
Speaker 1: They put some of them on bit torrent.
Speaker 1: So if you want to get dignity with bit torrent you can.
Speaker 1: and they have a bit torrent server.
Speaker 1: There's a company out there called media defender.
Speaker 1: Media defender is a company that is paid for by the evil record companies and I think I'm safe and saying evil now.
Speaker 1: And what media defender does is they go out looking for bit torrent servers that are serving up, you know illegal copyrighted content by the record companies.
Speaker 1: and when they find those servers dishing up illegal content they Attack them with like hacks and DD OS's like to bring down the bit torrent servers.
Speaker 1: It's basically vigilante justice in a way only so much the justice and a whole lot of the vigilante.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean they'll basically flood bit torrent networks with bad and spurious information to prevent anyone from downloading from them and hopefully to bring down The actual trackers and everything.
Speaker 1: Yep So of course media defenders sent some packets over to the revision 3 bit torrent server to say hey what's going on over here?
Speaker 1: you know, we want to see if there's any illegal bit torrents on this bit torrent server and Revision 3 because it's run by smart tech.
Speaker 1: people saw these packets coming from this media defender and they're like what the fuck is This shit.
Speaker 1: so they blocked that shit.
Speaker 1: So media defender was like, oh Someone is trying to block our shit.
Speaker 0: They must be evil pie.
Speaker 1: They must be evil pirates.
Speaker 1: So basically media defender Launched a You know denial of service attack against revision threes bit torrent server.
Speaker 1: a perfectly legitimate company with a perfectly legitimate bit torrent server was attacked by this other company in the name of evil and vigilante justice.
Speaker 0: now this.
Speaker 0: The idea of this sort of thing has always been a very controversial issue even among white hats.
Speaker 0: Just the idea that all right, like.
Speaker 0: here's an example.
Speaker 0: There's the problem out there.
Speaker 0: This is a little bit of a stretch But where there'll be zombie networks and bad computers spewing out spam and all this sort of thing or a worm that makes people spam Bots, what if a good hacker makes a bot that goes around or a worm that goes around?
Speaker 0: Attacking or getting rid of bad computers and cleaning up the internet?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they're the.
Speaker 0: the battle lines are pretty much 50/50 on either side of whether or not that's ethical.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's sort of like if I go around and I force everyone to get tetanus shots.
Speaker 1: You know, I am doing a good thing.
Speaker 1: There is no question about that.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty much eliminating tetanus from the human population.
Speaker 0: But at the same time 1% of people are allergic to the vaccine and die.
Speaker 1: Okay, but forget the allergic.
Speaker 0: No But it's the same parallel because if you even if you write a good white hat worm One percent of the computers out there gonna get totally hosed by it.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 1: And in addition to that You know, you're sort of infringing them on people's freedom to do with their computer what they want.
Speaker 1: You know, why is stealing wrong?
Speaker 1: because you're not respecting someone's right to property.
Speaker 1: So someone else doesn't respect a third party's right to property.
Speaker 1: So you fix it by not respecting a right to property.
Speaker 1: It's like punching someone who punched you.
Speaker 1: You know, you're just you're stupid at their level.
Speaker 1: So should you do it or not?
Speaker 1: Who knows we're working on that one.
Speaker 1: But anyway, well this gave us the idea to talk about.
Speaker 1: you know The ever-famous denial of service attack which is quite popular and off discussed on the Internet.
Speaker 1: So most people don't really understand what a denial of service attack is.
Speaker 0: now if you hold out We're not going to talk about the actual revision 3-3 because there's a lot more news going on about that And we're pretty much you can get that anywhere on the internet.
Speaker 0: We're gonna wait until there's kind of some sort of response.
Speaker 0: I mean, I know the FBI is investigating it and we're not sure what's going to happen but Media defender basically broke the law.
Speaker 0: It's just a question of whether or not the law is going to actually apply to them or not.
Speaker 0: Yep, but as for a denial of service attack a denial of service Basically all it means it's exactly what it sounds like Of service you deny someone their service.
Speaker 1: Yep So if someone's serving something say a web page and they want to serve others They want to serve the web page to other people.
Speaker 0: say someone has a service like their private computer that happens to be connected to the internet.
Speaker 0: You would you do something to deny them access to their own computer?
Speaker 1: Yep, pretty much any service anything that a computer does you deny that you say, haha It's like it's like going to someone's house and turning off their TV.
Speaker 1: You're denying them their television, you know.
Speaker 1: And that's what a denial of service attack is there many many many ways to do it.
Speaker 1: The most popular way is usually by flooding them with so much shit.
Speaker 1: They can't handle it.
Speaker 1: For example Let's say I got a little web server, right and it's not so strong it's a little web server.
Speaker 1: that could you know.
Speaker 1: and I put up a funny picture on that web server and you go to the website and you see the funny picture and you go Hahaha, but someone else sees the funny picture and they go.
Speaker 1: Hey, I don't like that picture.
Speaker 1: I don't want this picture getting out.
Speaker 1: so what they do is they find by some method they Request that picture like thousands and thousands of times.
Speaker 1: They give me the picture.
Speaker 1: Give me the picture And because it's only the little web server that could it goes.
Speaker 1: here's the picture.
Speaker 1: Here's the picture.
Speaker 1: is the picture?
Speaker 1: Oh my god, stop asking.
Speaker 1: It's like imagine if you're at a counter at McDonald's and you're you know Serving out the burgers and like a thousand people cram into the store and they all want Big Macs.
Speaker 1: It's like ah, ah, I can't give Big Macs to any of you.
Speaker 1: There's too many.
Speaker 1: I can't handle it.
Speaker 0: Now the actual the way I mean the the technical details of denial of service attacks would probably warrant an entire separate show.
Speaker 0: I mean they actually.
Speaker 0: they range from the very simple just in the olden days of I write a script that pings you a million Times I send a sin flood Which is just a. I send you a million sin packets TCP wise trying to get you to open all those connections.
Speaker 0: you know our sessions.
Speaker 0: and then there are the much more kind of complicated ones like say I send a bunch of fragmentary TCP IP packets with overlapping gigantic payloads and As a result because of the way I craft the data either inject bad code or just hang up your computer use up all your Memory, maybe just lock up all your sockets.
Speaker 0: You can't actually use your internet anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's quite a number of attack vectors when it comes to denial of service But a lot of people actually when it comes to denial of service They always talk about the DD OS.
Speaker 1: not just do s but D Do s and that's sort of like a become a colloquial term in a way, but they're not the same thing.
Speaker 1: No, a DD OS actually is a distributed denial of service Which is a very which is much more specific than denial of service.
Speaker 0: This is also the more common kind of attack nowadays because all these attacks and spam and a lot of things They don't come from like the one evil computer out there and Soviet Russia.
Speaker 1: Yeah If I do a sin flood say from my computer to rims computer When it's all cleared up because it will be cleared up eventually.
Speaker 1: I can't keep it going forever.
Speaker 1: You know, he's gonna say hey all these sin pack.
Speaker 1: is it coming from Scott, haha, hey Scott Hey Scott, please are on their way.
Speaker 1: I see my fist.
Speaker 1: You see your face.
Speaker 1: They're like two meeting.
Speaker 0: Yes, if I do s you in the house, I think you'll.
Speaker 0: course.
Speaker 0: I think my do s would be I just unplug your your cable from the switch I would go flick the circuit breaker and then break the switch off so you couldn't flick it back or I would just go administrative Administratively disable your port on the switch.
Speaker 0: No, that would take you a while to figure out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at least a couple minutes, yeah anyway a distributed denial of service is when you get a whole bunch of computers all over the place to do a little bit each at The same time so you can't defend against against that as easily.
Speaker 0: cuz alright an attack comes in from one computer.
Speaker 0: I just Route that port to a null somewhere.
Speaker 0: I block it and then I'm done I'm safe and I still can use my network.
Speaker 0: But if the attacks are coming from effectively random IP addresses all around the world I can block them by blocking the entire world and thus I have just denied myself my own service.
Speaker 1: Yep, what's even worse is that a lot of these distributed denial-of-service attacks, but there were there are ways to defend against them but what ends up happening is because it's so difficult to you know determine the difference between illegitimate requests for service and legitimate requests for service.
Speaker 0: I mean is my web server being attacked?
Speaker 0: or did penny arcade just linked to me, right?
Speaker 1: I mean if penny arcade links to you You're gonna have people from all over the world Asking for your web page and on the network level.
Speaker 1: if you look at the packets That's what it's gonna look like if someone sets up a zombie network around the world of zombie windows 98 machines And they all ask for your web page.
Speaker 1: How can you tell the difference between that and You getting linked to on slashdot or penny arcade.
Speaker 1: There's no way to tell the difference.
Speaker 1: So any defense that would solve the DDoS would also defend against getting linked to on penny arcade and being popular Which is not something you want to defend against.
Speaker 0: in a well-designed network though or a well-designed server There are ways to defend against most kinds of DDoS attacks in a way that won't deny that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: I mean well because there are defining characteristics of DDoS attacks, but you also just have to be clever.
Speaker 0: I mean most of you out there probably use IP tables and some well.
Speaker 0: I guess most of you who are actually technically proficient with Linux know about IP tables or maybe IP chains and all these things.
Speaker 0: But if you're clever you can use hash tables and IP tables and you can set up rules such as
Speaker 1: If
Speaker 0: I receive more than 10,000 packets in a minute that are incoming new connections from this range of IP addresses Then I want to throttle those such connections and log that something bad might be happening.
Speaker 1: yep,
Speaker 0: and all sorts of you can write very complicated rules that will effectively protect you or at least Say you're gonna get hit like say, you know Your computer can only handle so many requests you set of rules like that to kind of Throttle it as demand increases to where instead of your server crashing or going down You just not everyone gets in all at once and you kind of at least some people will be able to get in instead of No one can get in
Speaker 1: also depending on the service that you're offering.
Speaker 1: like if you're offering a web service, you know This is web pages There are a lot of things you can do on that higher level above the networking level to defend against an attack.
Speaker 1: for example if you might see in the The the user strings of you know, all these web requests.
Speaker 1: Hey, these are all Windows 98 machines You can just be like.
Speaker 1: hey, no Windows 98 machines right now.
Speaker 1: I can obviously tell there's a virus going down.
Speaker 1: You know, this doesn't look like a normal traffic pattern because I'd be seeing a lot more.
Speaker 1: you know Vista and XP machines if this was normal traffic is obviously a virus.
Speaker 1: or You can like have your work here.
Speaker 1: If you have a blog that's dynamically generated and because it's dynamically generating the page every time someone visits You're getting bogged down.
Speaker 1: so you can have some sort of mechanism that caches the web page.
Speaker 1: traffic is high.
Speaker 0: Actually what you do you?
Speaker 0: if you?
Speaker 0: I mean usually you should have some sort of caching.
Speaker 1: anyway You should but you can like get rid of images when traffic is high.
Speaker 0: What you do is you use the hash tables and have the hash tables kick off scripts that do this.
Speaker 0: So say your website is dynamic because you have a lot of dynamic content and if requests exceed a certain amount It replaces your page with a static page until it goes down.
Speaker 0: But the other the real tricky part is a lot of people.
Speaker 0: they they get halfway there.
Speaker 0: They don't think they're clever plan all the way through and they set up rules like that.
Speaker 0: The problem is if you set up these rules incorrectly, you'll basically end up do s in yourself.
Speaker 0: Let's say I I'm clever and I say alright any to any packet beyond the 10,000th packet in a given amount of time From any given port or whatever.
Speaker 0: I want to not let that pack it in and I want to log it.
Speaker 0: That just means if you get do est you're now going to eat up all your system I/o logging all those do s packets when you should just be dropping them.
Speaker 1: Yep, or you might even let's say let's say you don't even do you know logging to the disk, right?
Speaker 1: You do.
Speaker 1: we have a separate like syslog ng server.
Speaker 1: Well now you got a problem of network slow down and if that logging server is not at a back land Your networks in a slow down even more.
Speaker 1: you might be dropping packets before they even get to the NIC.
Speaker 1: Could be bad news.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's actually it's a pretty complicated issue.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: We should probably do separate shows on one how do s attacks actually work?
Speaker 0: and then another one probably on like basic computer defense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know my company we have a problem with this because there was you know, there's some sort of like weird You know, we can't even tell if they're attacks, you know, but it's like hey There's a bunch of traffic coming from China to this one machine.
Speaker 1: What the fuck?
Speaker 1: You know, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Is it attack?
Speaker 1: Is there anyone we hate in China?
Speaker 0: I don't get it The easiest way with a small company To figure out what's going on.
Speaker 0: if you especially with internal servers as opposed to web servers Just turn it off and see who calls.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I did.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know how many times I did that at IBM were like the hell.
Speaker 0: did this server do where to come from?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: unplug the network cable immediately.
Speaker 0: My phone rings and and I pretty much say are you calling about of something?
Speaker 0: He says yeah, my DNS server went down.
Speaker 0: Well, you shouldn't be running your DNS server off of this box.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but like our company we have one machine that sort of does this like ping post web service thing.
Speaker 1: So basically other companies that you don't have accounts with us are constantly sending and receiving like XML to and from this machine all the time.
Speaker 1: a lot of it like constantly and If someone attacks that machine, you know through that service It's really hard because it's like hey, are they just making a lot of legitimate requests or are they destroying us?
Speaker 0: All right, so you're getting this XML.
Speaker 0: you might think oh Well, maybe you should.
Speaker 0: will write rules and the XML handlers that look at the data and you know Like with web forms you can write things that pretty trivially can tell Like a spam filter if it's legitimate data or not.
Speaker 0: Yeah like on a forum like you just look to see if Usernames have more than eight or nine consecutive consonants and things like that or numbers and all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 1: But now since we're checking we're doing this test to every XML thing that comes in.
Speaker 1: It's eating up the CPU because they're doing all these extra tests to see what's valid and what's not.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the higher layer you try to do this checking on the more you're setting yourself up to be screwed
Speaker 1: Yep, but on the lower layer you have less information with which to determine what's legitimate and what's not legitimate And it's much more difficult to actually do the filtering.
Speaker 1: So it's yeah, it's a big problem all around at least for defending for attacking.
Speaker 1: It's quite easy.
Speaker 0: Yes attacking is easy and fun Pretty much.
Speaker 1: all you do is get a lot of computers all around the world put a virus on them and have some sort of controlling software and Then just type in someone's IP address and put
Speaker 0: the real problem that so many computers are out there now And so many people are so technologically behind that I think a lot of people Don't realize that their computers are spam bots and that their computer is slow because it's sending spam out 24/7.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they just they just saw my computer slow time to get a new one sort of like, you know They think of it like a car.
Speaker 0: so so they'll take their computer back to Best Buy.
Speaker 0: Best Buy will take their computer for free Sell it to someone else after you know taking the spyware off and then they'll sell them a new computer.
Speaker 1: That's fantastic.
Speaker 0: Ah, I think we'll end on this because frankly we're one while we're doing the new format.
Speaker 0: Like I said, we didn't get kind of the rest period before so this is kind of like a nor The last normal episode of geek nights.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we're not gonna do a show tomorrow.
Speaker 1: No show tomorrow none Zero.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Also, I'm really hungry and I really I think one of the upcoming Mondays.
Speaker 0: Let us know.
Speaker 0: do you want to hear about the technical details of DOS and DDoS attacks or Do you want to hear about the practicalities of defending against them?
Speaker 0: Mmm, either one I think would be an interesting topic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think those are good.
Speaker 1: I'm liking sort of like the.
Speaker 1: I think people in general are interested in the hacking and defending from hacking topics because Even if they're not, you know actually interested in them, it's like ooh hacking sort of.
Speaker 1: has this mystique You know, we'd like to hear about.
Speaker 0: actually maybe we should do.
Speaker 0: there's a third Monday option now hacking mystique We get.
Speaker 0: well, there's a fourth Monday option now.
Speaker 0: We could talk about what's like cyber warfare on the technical level Like what it really is.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 0: But I think right now I'm gonna talk about a chimney and maybe some chimichangas.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper math and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.