Speaker 0:
Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, June 24th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm sky and this is geek night.
Speaker 1: tonight We talk about the board game.
Speaker 0: shadows over Camelot come a lot.
Speaker 1: It's only a model.
Speaker 1: Let's do this So before any you in the forum get on to some sort of flame war about this since you've been fighting about everything lately Mountain biking is a sport.
Speaker 1: It is indeed and I bring it up only because if I talk about mountain biking I am sure beyond a shadow of a doubt that half you people are gonna make a whole thread about it.
Speaker 1: It's not a sport.
Speaker 1: bla bla bla direct competition bla even though yeah direct competition.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I've been mountain biking and biking for most of my life pretty much forever and this summer I decided all right.
Speaker 1: I haven't been biking so much in the last few years, and I really want to get it back.
Speaker 1: Why don't I just go buy a brand new bike?
Speaker 1: I'll buy like the best goddamn bike.
Speaker 0: The best goddamn bike is a bajillion dollars.
Speaker 1: you gotta buy Well the best goddamn bike.
Speaker 1: that isn't a professional like cyclists bike.
Speaker 1: because Yeah, that's what I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: I don't need a bike that cost more than my car when I bought it new.
Speaker 0: no you need like an $800 bike.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the thing some Back when I was riding bike technology was a lot different.
Speaker 1: I mean we're talking 14 years ago when I got this bike.
Speaker 1: this bike still works barely.
Speaker 1: But I decided all right Maybe I'll get one of those full suspension bikes cuz I know there's pros and cons.
Speaker 1: back then it was mostly cons.
Speaker 1: They just sucked pretty much.
Speaker 1: They bobble all the time when your roads.
Speaker 1: They slowed you down.
Speaker 1: They were a lot heavier than normal bikes.
Speaker 1: all these problems, but now you know they should be pretty good.
Speaker 1: So I decided to go to a bike shop, and I walk in and I'm like yeah What's the best full suspension Schwinn you got?
Speaker 1: he said don't care Schwinn hair yeah?
Speaker 1: I was like why the hell?
Speaker 1: not she was like the best bike, and he's like yeah She went was the best bike a decade ago.
Speaker 1: now she went sells in Walmart.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was like oh That's what I'm talking about like if you ever find the link again for that lawnmowers story There's a guy who made high-quality lawnmowers.
Speaker 0: He'd lawn Walmart wanted to buy his lawnmowers to sell them in Walmart.
Speaker 0: They said you're gonna have to reduce the quality so we can lower the price.
Speaker 0: He said hell no I'm gonna stay my high-quality ways.
Speaker 0: Schwinn obviously did the opposite and said hell yes Walmart.
Speaker 1: Actually what it looks like Schwinn did is they didn't.
Speaker 1: their their high-end bikes are still as high-end as they were before I guess Relatively.
Speaker 1: they just introduced all these low-end bikes that have the shoe and logo stuck all over him.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 0: It's like when I was a kid bike brands were like Shrin and Huffy and now bike brands are well Ken Dale Shrek and Cannondale and specialized specialized.
Speaker 1: I don't know whatever I knew it's.
Speaker 0: it's interesting though that there's such.
Speaker 0: You know Competition and change in the bike, you know making industry.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: I mean little things like when I bought my bike way back.
Speaker 1: Well when my dad bought my bike, yeah Disc brakes were this crazy stupid thing that no one but idiots who were super rich had on their bikes.
Speaker 1: pretty much now Pretty much any mountain bike worth of damn has disc brakes.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, it's almost useless and actually really dangerous.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I mean well, I mean they weren't really dangerous.
Speaker 0: yes they were.
Speaker 0: they invented.
Speaker 1: yes they were.
Speaker 1: they were stupidly dangerous.
Speaker 1: people Just put up with it.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Here's the deal linear.
Speaker 1: Well, there's a ball God.
Speaker 1: I don't want to.
Speaker 1: this is the bike show.
Speaker 1: But alright, I'll only talk about brakes.
Speaker 1: His linear pole is the horseshoe and well not a linear pole was the newest one of those kinds.
Speaker 1: There was the there's the horseshoe pole there was the side pole.
Speaker 1: all these different kinds of brakes and the linear were pretty much the best but they still go on the rim and That makes them completely stop working if the rim gets wet or you go through mud.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: This breaks continue to work.
Speaker 1: That's really key.
Speaker 0: when you you know, I don't know mountain biking I mean stuff could get in a little disc thingy But it's.
Speaker 1: it's a lot less likely and even when stuff gets in there it deals with it a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, plus the radius of the disc is much smaller than the radius of the rim.
Speaker 0: So it you know, it'll be quickly cleaned up.
Speaker 1: the real key though Just in case anyone's curious why disc brakes are necessary just in case you wondered is well one.
Speaker 1: if you're biking You really should only be using your front brake and if you're using your rear brake all the time Then you never learn how to bike properly, but to buy.
Speaker 1: if you're going downhill with normal brakes They'll heat up and stop working kind of like if you're in a cheap car with old drum brakes or like crappy brakes And you're going downhill and kind of ride the brake the whole time instead of downshifting.
Speaker 1: your brakes won't work.
Speaker 0: when you get to the bottom Yeah, and most on most bikes the brake is this piece of two pieces of rubber that gets squished up against the rim.
Speaker 0: So if you just hold the brakes down and you're going really fast down a hill the wheel keeps spinning and spinning and spinning And you're just slowing down, but you're not stop
Speaker 1: Keeps on turning
Speaker 0: Okay, and the pieces of rubber on the brake heat up from all the friction and they melt and they get.
Speaker 0: you know They don't they're not hard anymore.
Speaker 1: They get not to mention the fact that my rooms haven't been straight for about six years.
Speaker 0: Yeah So they turn into liquid and you can't stop.
Speaker 1: yep, but to skip all that it was like, alright I'm gonna go buy a brand new bike.
Speaker 1: and I talked to this bike guy and I was pretty much like.
Speaker 1: so I haven't Known anything new about bikes for a decade.
Speaker 1: He's like, ah, alright well, and he taught me all about what's going on now with bikes.
Speaker 1: and Then I was like and I you know, I didn't even look at the prices I looked at the Schwinn's and a high-end hardtail Schwinn was under a thousand dollars like fully loaded.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, alright, this can't be that bad.
Speaker 1: So I'm there and I'm looking.
Speaker 1: he's like well test ride this one.
Speaker 1: This is pretty much the best full suspension bike we have and I rode it around and it was absolutely amazing.
Speaker 1: It was like night and day like riding the kind where there's like only half a fork in the front.
Speaker 1: Yeah lefty made out of carbon fiber.
Speaker 1: the thing weighed so little.
Speaker 1: I could pick the whole bike up with two fingers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, like up up up and it was great.
Speaker 1: and I rode it around the parking lot And I took it to some trails and I'm biking around and it was a transcendent experience though it was a little weird because the full suspension like it had this brain thing like an inertial damper that could tell if I Was putting the pressure on it Like if I was trying to jump and would lock the suspension, but it would unlock if the bumps came from the bottom.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, it worked.
Speaker 1: It was scary.
Speaker 1: How well it worked.
Speaker 0: a lot of those things are kind of see.
Speaker 0: the thing is a lot of bikes where they have all The fancy features.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they also have some gimmicky features to get rich people who don't know any better.
Speaker 0: to case in point the automatic Transmission, yeah, well automatic transmission bikes have a purpose and a place but not Yeah, not on any bike.
Speaker 0: No, if you're like a you know, lazy person doesn't bother switching gears going around the city.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, lazy person city bike has an internal three-speed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not not an automatic transmission with a complicated mechanism.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, so I walk back in.
Speaker 1: I'm like man that bikes great.
Speaker 1: I want it and he was like, alright Let me figure out how much it costs because it wasn't just like it what he couldn't.
Speaker 1: there's no sticker on it.
Speaker 1: he has to go figure out how much it caused based on what specific like model and make it was.
Speaker 1: and He comes back.
Speaker 0: He's like, well, it's six thousand and I was like, alright, never mind, dude You know usually the craziest bike in the store is something like four thousand.
Speaker 1: said I don't know.
Speaker 1: if he had said like $2,000 I might have just bought it.
Speaker 0: That's to air on chair.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: That is a crazy amount of money.
Speaker 1: I might have regretted it, but I might have just bought it because that was in the realm of expectation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when he said six thousand and he wasn't done like.
Speaker 0: I could buy a motorcycle.
Speaker 0: Why would I buy a non motored cycle for motorcycle motorcycle?
Speaker 1: I could buy three of my current car.
Speaker 1: I could buy six air on chairs.
Speaker 0: You could buy Three Eighteen probably twenty ps3.
Speaker 1: You know what I could buy a hell of a lot of video games.
Speaker 0: That sure is all good.
Speaker 1: So Instead I why said alright.
Speaker 1: Well, I'll be back and I test wrote a whole but I spent the whole day there test riding bikes.
Speaker 0: He was probably go home kid.
Speaker 1: No, cuz he he pretty much was like, I'm gonna sell this guy bike.
Speaker 1: He didn't know he didn't.
Speaker 1: not yet.
Speaker 1: Not yet.
Speaker 1: But the thing is I did all this test riding.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the bike store was rocking.
Speaker 1: actually they have like eight salespeople and like all these other tags, it's a really good bike store.
Speaker 0: One that's way out there by the airport.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's really the only good bike store.
Speaker 0: There's one that's closer that the wooden one with the old guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and there's the other one that went out of business.
Speaker 0: That's the same one is the old one with the old guy.
Speaker 1: only it's a different branch and the ski house claims to be an Authorized Schwinn dealer, but I'm dubious.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm not going to the ski house for a bike house.
Speaker 1: Go in there for skis, but actually it's getting about time to get some skis.
Speaker 1: but I was inspired by how expensive bikes are to Repair my old bike yet again, and I took it out riding yesterday.
Speaker 1: I biked around town I did some trail riding and then I went across the Newburgh Beacon Bridge and back And on the other side I saw a mansion for sale for not that much money and I'm really curious.
Speaker 1: But that's a story for another time.
Speaker 0: It's probably haunted.
Speaker 1: You know how awesome that would be.
Speaker 1: pretty awesome one.
Speaker 1: James Randi would pay for the mansion.
Speaker 0: no He would.
Speaker 1: well once I proved it was haunted.
Speaker 1: You give me a million dollars.
Speaker 0: What if it was?
Speaker 0: Then it's a free house.
Speaker 1: It'd be awesome hanging out with the ghosts.
Speaker 0: What's up ghosts?
Speaker 0: How you doing?
Speaker 1: All right, that was kind of a long rant But I think it's relevant because mountain biking is a sport and sports are games and it's Tuesday night.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh Okay, shall we do some news type?
Speaker 1: actually as we got some news, I mean I just want to talk about so far Next time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so there's been a lot happening in the plastic instrument world lately.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think Scott was the one who posited on the forums that if any game any game has the Beatles Led Zeppelin and Queen in it Simultaneously, it will be the winner.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean cuz check out.
Speaker 0: here's the problem, right?
Speaker 0: You've actually got Competition actual competition going on between now.
Speaker 0: three Plastic instrument game makers.
Speaker 0: see the original plastic instrument game was well plastic instrument and rhythm game.
Speaker 0: King was Konami and Konami is still the king with the DDR and the beat mania.
Speaker 0: But they did guitar freaks way back in the day.
Speaker 1: Yes, which was one of those proof of concept.
Speaker 1: But no one liked it.
Speaker 1: Well a few a few people liked it.
Speaker 0: They liked it a lot and then Guitar Hero came along and that was like, oh, okay Now we got a guitar game.
Speaker 0: that's actually, you know quality.
Speaker 1: and if you want our thoughts on Guitar Hero I think we reviewed Guitar Hero 3 anyway.
Speaker 0: The point is, you know, the rock band came along and added the drums But now the Guitar Hero is coming along again.
Speaker 0: the next well forgetting about the DS one.
Speaker 0: We don't give a shit about that even though it's available today and it's I don't recommend it.
Speaker 0: It looks really dumb.
Speaker 0: I have very slow confidence.
Speaker 1: I know who's buying that.
Speaker 1: Reviewers and grandmas who hear about Guitar Hero and buy it for the kid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can see that being like the punk kids guitar here anyway Right, so the next Guitar Hero is gonna have drums and they're actually better than the rock band drums.
Speaker 0: There's only gonna be three, you know normal top wise drums instead of rock bands.
Speaker 0: for but it looks like the pedal is superior And there's two symbols.
Speaker 0: but you can sort of hold the symbols that you know.
Speaker 0: Do cool stuff like hit the symbol and then you know grab it with your hand to make it stop that kind of thing.
Speaker 1: the drum kit to me is the only part that matters.
Speaker 1: because Maybe well, maybe to first one to me personally.
Speaker 1: I really Guitar hero was awesome until I actually owned it and played it more than transiently and I died.
Speaker 1: That game is not fun and not worth it.
Speaker 1: and not It's not really fun.
Speaker 1: It is Rockwell.
Speaker 1: one rock band is a lot more fun even guitar wise it is.
Speaker 1: That's because Guitar Hero 3 turned into what DDR like 7th mix turned into.
Speaker 0: that's exactly right.
Speaker 0: Guitar hero 2 is a lot more like the 4th mix plus of guitar heroes.
Speaker 1: Yeah but the drums drum sets in these games are the only instrument with the exception of singing.
Speaker 1: that has a chance of Translating into real skill playing drums in a game like.
Speaker 1: well, I guess drum hero if someone ever makes one or any of these games Will make you a decent like entry-level drummer.
Speaker 1: you'll learn real drumming technique.
Speaker 0: The problem is real drums are not set up in quite that position.
Speaker 0: So you sort of have to actually Don't get into it.
Speaker 1: drum sets are a complicated topic in and out there quite indeed.
Speaker 0: but learning basic rhythms and Interested in like, you know.
Speaker 0: because in a drum set every one of those drums like a separate its own separate thing And they just sort of put them all near each other.
Speaker 0: and I've always sort of wondered like, you know Why don't people put them in different place?
Speaker 0: They do.
Speaker 1: there's all.
Speaker 1: there's a whole different philosophies of different I'm not even gonna get into but there's all these different Nate like different Philosophies and names and like.
Speaker 1: we could use the blah blah blah method which gives you better access to your symbols.
Speaker 1: Some people use the double or the triple thumpers and yeah, it's interesting stuff there.
Speaker 1: the drums anyway, not To qualify that I can't drum worth a god me either.
Speaker 0: I can drum with like one drum.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, actually I could do a bass drum the kind like you.
Speaker 1: can you really?
Speaker 1: yeah, can you really yeah, why not?
Speaker 0: Okay, I got the good rhythms and all you got to do is hit it to the rhythms.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you gotta use both hands simultaneously sometimes with different rhythms.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I could do that.
Speaker 1: All right I'm kidding play some quads quince.
Speaker 1: Anyways, alright, so right.
Speaker 0: So guitar hero is really upping the drums and upping the guitar and from the information we have their drums and guitars are actually Technically superior to a rock band has now, but we don't know what rock bands doing.
Speaker 0: But they've got to do some sort of improvements.
Speaker 1: It's just gonna be an arms race till eventually the game will come with a piece of Freddie Mercury's rotted corpse, maybe the Konami who made the original guitar freaks and DDR and beat mania and such.
Speaker 0: They're actually coming with their own drums and shit now up out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: This is crazy to me.
Speaker 1: The only explanation is one Konami is crazy or two.
Speaker 1: They are going to come in with the artillery.
Speaker 1: that's gonna wipe everyone else out of that mark.
Speaker 0: Well, we'll say cuz Konami has the rhythms, but I don't know if they have the music or the equipments, you know Cuz even though Konami has made the great rhythm games in the past.
Speaker 0: like DDR Their equipment for said games has always been lackluster.
Speaker 0: Well except for any arcade EDR Konami should really make a new drum set type thing for the arcade Out.
Speaker 0: that stupid MTV drumscape thing.
Speaker 0: That's everywhere.
Speaker 1: That game is awful It is you know what Konami could.
Speaker 1: if I were Konami I would pick a winner.
Speaker 1: I'd pick one of the two and make a deal with them to license their game into the official arcade cabinet.
Speaker 0: I know here the reason I want to talk about no.
Speaker 1: No, I would sell these cabinets to bars and Karaoke clubs.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's so much money to be made there Konami.
Speaker 1: Yes, how much money cuz.
Speaker 0: Konami can make the arcade machines.
Speaker 0: well actually Red octane harmon whoever it can also make the arcade machines.
Speaker 0: They made the in the grooves remember Yeah, but so they could do it as well.
Speaker 1: fault in the groove because the machines were amazing.
Speaker 1: the game Played like it was made by fan boy.
Speaker 1: It was indeed was not immediately apparent to us in the groove was the awesomest thing until we played it for the second year In a row, right?
Speaker 0: So the reason I want to talk about this?
Speaker 0: because it's a great example of Who uses open systems.
Speaker 0: and who uses closed system?
Speaker 0: see Konami came out and they said we there should be a standard For these plastic instruments so people don't have to rebuy it.
Speaker 0: Of course, that's what's best for the consumer because an open standard is always best for the consumer, right?
Speaker 0: But the guitar hero and rock band people said no.
Speaker 0: Well rock band people have always said well as the guitar heroes people's fault is not compatible and there are the guitar hero People just don't say anything.
Speaker 0: huh, all right, so Basically, this is a perfect example.
Speaker 0: because look when you're the most popular guy in town, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say you're the guitar hero guy, right?
Speaker 0: You don't want your plastic instruments to be compatible with other people's games.
Speaker 0: You know why sunk?
Speaker 0: because well, no if you're the most popular game in town people are gonna buy your shit, right?
Speaker 0: If you make your instruments work with other people's stuff, then people will buy those other games Instead of your game, so if they connect that Well, I guess when I said sunk cost I should have been more clear.
Speaker 1: if someone already owns one plastic drum set They're not going to buy a second plastic drum exact.
Speaker 0: Well, they're much less likely to buy a second plastic.
Speaker 0: Well, we're excluding college kids, right?
Speaker 1: Therefore if you oh, oh my god, what I said college kids Because I'm not a college kid anymore.
Speaker 0: No, you're not.
Speaker 0: Let me finish my shit.
Speaker 0: No, so if they make the drum set and the guitar a standard that anyone can do then people can actually easily Compete with them because everyone will buy the popular game and you know in the popular set and then they'll buy.
Speaker 0: Whichever game actually ends up being the best game.
Speaker 0: if they don't make it an open thing then people will buy theirs because the most popular and Then they won't buy and they'll be much less likely to buy any of the others just because they don't want to sink their Money into yet another plastic drum set.
Speaker 1: and even aside from the money cost owning multiple plastic drum sets those things Where are you gonna put it right unless you have a lot of a lot of space?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the people who are down low the losers in town, right?
Speaker 0: They were not so popular.
Speaker 0: They want there to be a standard because if there's a standard and everyone has the same drum set, whatever then They can actually compete.
Speaker 0: You know people will be willing to buy their game and they will judge which rhythm game is the best rather than I'm buying The one that is most popular because that is the one that is most likely to give me the most value for my money Regardless of whether it's actually, you know the best game in the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's the saddest thing because an open standard would pretty much guarantee that whoever makes the best rhythm games would win.
Speaker 0: Yeah, think about it.
Speaker 0: If there was an open standard, right?
Speaker 0: It wouldn't be.
Speaker 0: I buy the drum set that works at the most popular game because that's the safe bet It would be I buy the highest quality drum set to be all this competition.
Speaker 0: if who makes the best ones, you know.
Speaker 0: But they're all the same in terms of the feature set kind of like in DDR pads back in the day where you could buy the Two weeks is DDR pads are just normal PlayStation controllers and whatnot, right?
Speaker 0: There's open competition and there's different people making DDR pads and some of them are better than others and some of them are more expensive Than others until red octane pretty much came in and said look it's done.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 1: Yep It's either this or the arcade.
Speaker 0: Yep But anyway, yeah The other thing is that There was this sort of speculation going on that there might be some Beatles action in the next round of games.
Speaker 0: We'll see what comes of that.
Speaker 0: That's all I can say.
Speaker 1: that would I feel like that would really only fit rock band.
Speaker 0: It would because you know, I mean, you know the Beatles played guitars.
Speaker 0: But I mean, well then again the next guitar hero is gonna have some drums.
Speaker 0: We'll see if it has.
Speaker 1: at the same time the whole guitar hero thing.
Speaker 1: It's always guitar solo rock metal something I don't.
Speaker 1: I don't know there's no guitar solos in the Beatles.
Speaker 1: Well, there are not not like that.
Speaker 1: No, not no.
Speaker 1: Squeed Lee's and me Lee's.
Speaker 0: there are some occasional But it's not not like metal Squeed Lee's and me Lee's.
Speaker 0: it is totally a different kind of thing.
Speaker 1: I think we should call them something different.
Speaker 0: if you want to simulate the Beatles experience for fun It really needs to be a full four-piece set action, you know vocals guitar bass drums the whole thing You know.
Speaker 0: plus, I mean if you can only play guitar and drums in guitar in the next guitar hero And there's no singing or anything.
Speaker 0: All right, then, you know, what if you're you know, what if you want to be George?
Speaker 0: You sort of left out Plus.
Speaker 1: I feel as though Guitar hero had a lot of momentum and a lot of style and a lot of class and everything was going for him.
Speaker 1: And then in Guitar Hero 3 it's like they didn't understand what made their games popular.
Speaker 0: Well, no, it's because that was actually made by different people.
Speaker 0: the people who made Guitar Hero 1 and 2 left and made rock band.
Speaker 1: Yes, exactly.
Speaker 1: But the people making the decisions for the brand didn't understand what made it popular which was one those developers And to that style, right?
Speaker 0: Oh Things are okay.
Speaker 0: It'll it'll turn out.
Speaker 0: I think in the end, you know, I mean, I don't really have a huge need to play.
Speaker 0: You know plastic instruments games so much anymore.
Speaker 0: I mean, I have Guitar Hero 3 and I have plastic guitar for it And that's that sort of sates any desire I might have you know for pretty much a long time.
Speaker 0: So until there's like a full this is the be-all end-all.
Speaker 0: I can just refrain from buying any of these things and maybe I can play it at conventions or something You know to test them out see which ones are good which ones are bad
Speaker 1: Alright, so I'm not gonna talk about this very long But I have to bring it up because it's been poking around in the forums simmering if you will Smoldering under all right.
Speaker 1: enough of that.
Speaker 1: How the pyro?
Speaker 1: they added weapons to you?
Speaker 0: Why do you keep talking about this?
Speaker 0: This is always what you talk about.
Speaker 1: There's no other video game news I want to talk about and because I realize what I must do all right.
Speaker 1: so basically the whole the whole deal here for the people who don't seem to understand of what it is that bothers us and specifically me about this whole achievement getting weapons thing and Team Fortress 2. is that a?
Speaker 1: Originally when Team Fortress 2 first came out I it was fun, but I realized right away that the game was not going to be a quote.
Speaker 1: hardcore team-based capture-the-flag first-person shooter.
Speaker 1: That's quite a qualified genre there, but I think it's a. it's an existing genre.
Speaker 0: It is an existing genre that is sort of that's had like a game.
Speaker 0: It's down there with the adventure games.
Speaker 0: pretty much.
Speaker 0: in fact I think it's lower than the adventure games because I'm in a recent adventure game resurgence.
Speaker 1: I mean if you can differentiate between Technical all these different kinds of metal and I can differentiate with all the different kinds of team-based FPS But the hardcore what I just said Really, I don't know if it's viable in the modern world.
Speaker 1: And I don't blame T fortress for not being weapons factory or mega TF because that kind of game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know if there's a market for it anymore.
Speaker 0: I think there would be.
Speaker 0: as long as you streamline the interface you could still keep the gameplay.
Speaker 0: But if the interface of olden days cannot stick around well a modern interface on that game.
Speaker 0: It would totally work.
Speaker 1: We'll get to that in a minute.
Speaker 1: Because while in the end and this is after a lot of play and I can pretty much speak quiet within a qualified manner now Without having to say well, we'll have to see how it all turns out Team fortress 2 was not that game But what it had going for it was that it could have.
Speaker 1: it could be a good game in and of itself in a genre That is separate from that Emphasizing the team-based part a lot more and de-emphasizing the first-person shooter part.
Speaker 0: The problem was is the maps Reduced all decisions to obvious.
Speaker 1: Yes the game one.
Speaker 1: the game things that are winning with the game.
Speaker 1: the style I've said this before we keep saying it.
Speaker 1: I'll never say it again because I don't think it needs to be said again the style a team fortress 2 is Full of wind to a degree that I cannot express to you So perfect.
Speaker 0: the interface was also really terrific compared to pretty much every other FPS has ever existed.
Speaker 0: It is actually accessible and it worked.
Speaker 1: the style and the interface and the grass all that stuff was there.
Speaker 1: the only problems with the game were that the maps were too small for Strategy or FPSing to matter.
Speaker 1: the weapons were too inaccurate for FPSing to matter.
Speaker 1: when I say matter I mean matter in the quote-unquote hardcore full-on way.
Speaker 1: the skill caps were pretty low and Beyond all that everyone really only had one weapon.
Speaker 1: Yep may end like one special ability.
Speaker 1: that was kind of weeks.
Speaker 1: as a result there weren't a lot of strategic options and there weren't a lot of FPS skill options and the maps were so small that the Game ended up being very not fun.
Speaker 1: If you were good at FPS is at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean if you play, you know team fortress 2 I mean at the.
Speaker 0: you know, the day it came out and you actually had coordinated intelligent teams It was pretty much gonna be a stalemate, you know Where only randomness would decide because the maps are so small that the optimal strategy is obvious And it's just a matter of getting everyone to actually do it.
Speaker 1: I mean if you're playing on eight on eight, there is an absolute perfect defense for the capture the flag to fort Yep, but skipping all that.
Speaker 1: I was of the mind that all you had to do was either now Depending on which direction you went.
Speaker 1: It's like each of these things would have taken the game in a different direction.
Speaker 1: I think all of them could have been good if They had made the maps a lot bigger and a lot more varied and a lot more open and made a lot more Capture the flag maps.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then the game was great.
Speaker 1: because when they made CTF well That map was amazing and I suddenly had all this new hope for the game.
Speaker 1: and then pretty much No one played that map after the first two weeks and now it's pretty much gone great.
Speaker 1: So, alright, or if they had given everyone one more weapon one more special ability one more tactical decision to make it didn't need to me the hardcore craziness of having eight different kinds of grenades and four different shotguns, but One more thing and everything would have been great.
Speaker 1: It would have added a lot of strategic and a lot of tacticality to make up a bunch of perfectly chromulant words Mm-hmm, and that would have even made up for the low skill cap on the straight-up FPS.
Speaker 1: It wouldn't have been a hardcore FPS But it would have been a hardcore team-based strategy game that happens to be first-person as long as they change up the maps, too Yes, but even if they had just done that like all these little things would have fixed it.
Speaker 1: So suddenly I find out that they're doing the last of those.
Speaker 1: they're giving everyone one more thing or two more things.
Speaker 1: But then they pull this bullshit on me that I have to level up to get him That now the game is stateful as opposed to stateless and that wasn't even in my conception.
Speaker 1: This is this brand new.
Speaker 1: It's like they took the game that was in a genre.
Speaker 1: It was a team-based First-person nominally strategic game and they pulled it out of that and they made it something different.
Speaker 1: It's in a different genre of game to the point that I don't know what to do with it anymore Because I played with a new pyro the backburner the thing where you can shoot air.
Speaker 1: That added so much to.
Speaker 1: I cannot express to you how much that adds to the game.
Speaker 1: strategically it almost made Capture the flag on to Ford viable almost even with the crappy map design.
Speaker 1: It was viable yeah, but no, I have to level up to get the flare gun and all and extinguisher and all these other things and The read basically, I don't need to say why.
Speaker 1: I've said why a million times but they've taken a game That was an even stateless first-person team-based game and they made it uneven and stateful.
Speaker 1: and the oven unevenness Decided solely by the arbitrary amount of time you spend leveling up by getting these achievements.
Speaker 1: and I Guess I'm ranting here.
Speaker 1: So I'll wrap it up.
Speaker 1: I don't even care about the achievements.
Speaker 1: I'm not Scott.
Speaker 1: achievements are great Go nuts.
Speaker 1: The problem is when the achievements matter for what otherwise was a stateless multiplayer versus game.
Speaker 1: The fact it doesn't matter that the weapons may not be technically a hundred percent better than the weapons that you get if you haven't Leveled up.
Speaker 1: they're different.
Speaker 1: They're different enough to matter.
Speaker 1: if they're not different enough to matter There's no reason to have them and everyone says they are.
Speaker 1: I've played a little bit.
Speaker 1: They definitely are but by forcing you to level up to get them.
Speaker 1: You've made the game stateful.
Speaker 1: It's not fair or balanced anymore, and I don't know what to do.
Speaker 1: Anyway to get to wrap all this up.
Speaker 1: I figured out I want to do to fix this.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm We've got to just make a goddamn mod.
Speaker 0: I think we do because water is poison really.
Speaker 0: he pointed it out to me and I didn't realize this before right?
Speaker 0: All the FPS is that we really liked throughout history.
Speaker 0: Have all the multiplayer ones with the exception of tribes to the exception of tribes to have all been mods.
Speaker 0: Counter-strike was a mod even though it's not a mod now.
Speaker 0: It was a mod back in the day.
Speaker 1: Natural selection action quake weapons factory mega TF team fortress capture the flag lithium death net hell.
Speaker 1: Even deathmatch was sucked and no one played it.
Speaker 1: when it came out people played lithium deathmatch Which was a mod.
Speaker 0: every game every FPS that we have ever enjoyed in the history of the world With the exceptions of tribes 2 and maybe golden eye and a rim doesn't like golden eye though I
Speaker 1: like to golden eye when it was
Speaker 0: out The exception of those two every FPS ever that wasn't single-player that we liked was a mod.
Speaker 0: Team fortress 2 is not a mod It's not and I realized that hey We just had to mod it because it's now what we want is never gonna happen.
Speaker 0: All we need to do is you need to make bigger maps.
Speaker 0: So you need map making action.
Speaker 0: We don't make better maps - we need to make everything faster.
Speaker 0: So, you know, we have to keep the ratios of speed the same.
Speaker 0: The Scout should still be twice as fast as you know The there are four times as fast the heavier ever much but everyone's speed needs to be raised equally that way You know, you have to have faster reaction times and whatnot.
Speaker 0: You need to make.
Speaker 0: if we can we should make the models a little smaller.
Speaker 0: if we can't do that It's you know, bigger map should be enough.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Also, you got to make the hitboxes smaller.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if we can do that and Make all the weapons more accurate or otherwise not be able to hit anything.
Speaker 1: and beyond that I've got two minds.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure which way to go with this yet but either make the game in this kind of team fortress the way they originally designed the game balanced and Clean methodology where every class as a very small very specific subset of strategies and weapons.
Speaker 1: or Go all out and try Scott's idea of what if you make a modern hardcore FPS?
Speaker 1: And I think weapons factory was the last team based about that whole thing I said before that long string of words if you made that but you took these style and mostly the interface of Teamfortress so it doesn't completely suck to play the game.
Speaker 1: If you're not a stupid nerd you sit there for an hour scripting.
Speaker 0: I definitely think that it's you know, the best way to go right now just be to take Team Fortress 2 in its state Unlock all the achievements.
Speaker 0: also everyone gets all the weapons, right?
Speaker 0: So we'd have to wait for them to make the weapons for the rest of the classes because you know You don't want.
Speaker 0: you know this bullshit where they put it out.
Speaker 0: want it for one class at a time.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, no, no, cuz that's no good.
Speaker 0: It's got to be.
Speaker 0: every class is the same amount of stuff, right?
Speaker 0: Then you know bigger maps up the speed up the accuracy and it dad that should be good enough right at least to start.
Speaker 1: I mean as has been proven by CTF.
Speaker 1: Well bigger maps alone make the game twice as good immediately.
Speaker 1: Yep Just bigger maps with more paths to the point that there is no optimal defense or offense And then everything else is just icing on the cake from there.
Speaker 1: Yep so I'm not going to talk about Team Fortress 2 again kind of like how Jack Thompson put the kibosh on that.
Speaker 1: He I don't think he'll ever remember my rule I can't talk about Jack Thompson unless he tops himself by an order of magnitude and he hasn't yet.
Speaker 1: Hey Team Fortress 2.
Speaker 1: I'm not talking about until we or someone we know stop shit talking.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess we haven't shit talked yet, but we're going to be shortly and starts modding Team Fortress 2.
Speaker 1: Yeah Maybe I'll start writing up my RFC for the hardcore.
Speaker 0: Don't need an RFC for this one.
Speaker 0: in our know It's not.
Speaker 1: I want to see.
Speaker 1: I want to define the parameters that specify Team base multiplayer stateless capture-the-flag First-person shooter, it's I it's a suspect doc or it's?
Speaker 0: it's not an RFC and RFC is the wrong kind of document.
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day things of the day.
Speaker 1: All right, so I'm gonna totally cop out here.
Speaker 1: But I think it's relevant because we talked about Bimani and I've been really feeling the the DDR groove lately.
Speaker 1: I've also been feeling that my desire to play DDR has been rising constantly.
Speaker 1: despite this the floor in our living room is not strong enough to support us and Playing on the deck isn't really an option.
Speaker 0: That's sort of the reason Alice.
Speaker 1: I haven't gotten we fit or anything Yeah, but I really want to play DDR.
Speaker 1: and if you really want to play DDR I recommend you watch these two videos, which I don't think DDR season.
Speaker 0: That's for sure things of the day.
Speaker 1: DJ 8-ball is perhaps my favorite Freestyler.
Speaker 1: you see there are two ways to play DDR.
Speaker 1: well three ways.
Speaker 1: one is the fanboy shuffle and you suck - is Playing to do really well with all your friends.
Speaker 1: and three is playing not to get perfect scores But to show off.
Speaker 1: for anyone who's watching Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That is my favorite way of dancing.
Speaker 1: It'll always will be.
Speaker 1: messing around on the machine is so much more fun than trying to get a triple-a whatever plus It hurts a lot less.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well depending.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think what you do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or if you fail at doing plus Now who?
Speaker 1: that is my baby's mom, okay DJ Paul is famous for one being awesome.
Speaker 1: for two exemplifying everything I love about DDR.
Speaker 1: three for the Nintendo foot, which you'll see in cafe, which is also one of my favorite DDR songs.
Speaker 1: And four for pretending that he had a leg injury for the time up to a tournament Deciding to go on anyway in a show of good faith and effort and for a cheer from the crowd walking up with his crutch cane Revealing at the last second that he is not in fact injured at all and then doing his routine with the cane.
Speaker 1: Yep He is my hero.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, DJ Paul is.
Speaker 0: he was pretty terrific.
Speaker 0: He's kind of old-school and with the DDR back in the third fourth mix days I don't know if he's still around.
Speaker 0: maybe he'll.
Speaker 0: he'll find us from the show or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean our other.
Speaker 0: there are other DDR freestyle people are equally awesome.
Speaker 0: Disrespecting them.
Speaker 1: No, but we are definitely like art, you know people have different styles of DDR.
Speaker 1: Our style is the third mix Korean through fifth mix style.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: That is where we live and that is our home.
Speaker 0: fourth mix plus being the pinnacle of all DDR.
Speaker 0: God always will be.
Speaker 1: I Can't express to you how much I would love to own a fourth mix plus machine.
Speaker 0: I would pay a thousand two thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: Sadly, they cost about eight thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: Well, we've more than one bicycle So check this out.
Speaker 0: there was a Wii update this week that changed a few things around.
Speaker 0: nothing really exciting But all those people who are doing the Wii homebrew with the Twilight hack.
Speaker 0: They were like, oh no this broke our Twilight hacks sorrow.
Speaker 0: Well in a very short amount of time they un Broke the hacks.
Speaker 0: in other words, you can hack your Wii again.
Speaker 0: Not only can you hack your Wii again there's a video here that was posted that I watched that shows how ludicrously easy it is to hack the Wii and Get your own get.
Speaker 0: basically you put this homebrew channel on your Wii and then the homebrew channel can read Programs you put on your SD card and then you can run Programs on the Wii through the SD card and they demonstrate quake.
Speaker 0: one Played with the Wiimote and such and I think I'm gonna go for it.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna do it now.
Speaker 1: Now what's the sudden turd about?
Speaker 1: how come you're suddenly interested in this?
Speaker 0: because I saw video and it's so stupidly easy.
Speaker 0: and Nintendo did it and Nintendo didn't update and the update didn't ruin anyone's wheeze Even though it's sort of broke them for like a little bit.
Speaker 0: So I'm Feeling like it's pretty safe.
Speaker 0: Like I'm not gonna say it's safe, you know 100%.
Speaker 0: you know, you do risk losing your Wii forever but you know Why not?
Speaker 0: I can make the Wii pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's gonna hurt now.
Speaker 1: It bothers me that Nintendo Doesn't want this to happen and isn't embracing this sort of development because I mean, I guess I'm not surprised but why Nintendo?
Speaker 1: Why must you at every opportunity fall just one step short of true glory?
Speaker 1: They're always one step short of making the perfect console the perfect game the perfect everything.
Speaker 0: Pretty much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the thing is like, huh?
Speaker 0: I've got this thing here and you know this.
Speaker 0: It's like trying to think of something that they can demonstrate the unfulfilled potential.
Speaker 0: It's like if you had a Ferrari right and the Ferrari could go 200 miles an hour and had six gears and Whenever you drove it, you only got up to fifth gear and then you sort of slowed down.
Speaker 0: You never you never use that sixth gear.
Speaker 0: You never you never went to the max speed of the Ferrari.
Speaker 0: You just like yeah, we got it, but we're not gonna use our full strength.
Speaker 0: You haven't seen my full strength You know what?
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna suddenly reveal my full strength in the last episode Like I should.
Speaker 0: I'm just never gonna reveal it ever at all.
Speaker 0: I don't need it and it's like ah, you bastards.
Speaker 0: I need that full strength.
Speaker 0: I can see that full strength right there.
Speaker 1: So tonight over the weekend, of course the visigoths came out.
Speaker 1: They didn't goth up the house too much.
Speaker 0: They weren't here as much as they were in the past as we move the game over to Alex's apartment.
Speaker 1: But we played our burning wheel and among other things Scott Johnson and Laura brought a couple of games some political game that While it was dumb and ended up being great only because it was late at night and whenever playing it again.
Speaker 1: Also because a lot of silly things happened due to the way the rules were.
Speaker 1: yeah broken rules Yes, but sometimes broken.
Speaker 1: maybe it's weird but people like us You know people are really into these kind of hardcore rules lawyer II specific, you know real German strategy games.
Speaker 1: When a game's rules are actually broken and like broken in a crazy way It's almost Entertaining in and of itself to play that game Trying to break the game and enjoying the chaos that ensues.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean think about it right?
Speaker 0: the rules of a board game are the words written in the book that comes with the game.
Speaker 0: You understand the words that are written in this book.
Speaker 0: the rules of a video game are the code the soft the code that is written to create the Software the zeros and ones on the game disk or in the install or wherever us.
Speaker 1: Putting a game in a. putting a board game in a weird state is like getting into the minus world in Mario 1.
Speaker 0: exactly It's like, you know, basically the definition of cheating is if you break the rules.
Speaker 0: So if you do something to a video game that either, you know modifies the code which is basically like taking an eraser to the rule book and writing your own rules as cheating or Doing something that goes against the software somehow like a game genie well, I guess that's sort of rewriting.
Speaker 0: but anyway that is cheating.
Speaker 0: in a video game and A board game doing something that is contradictory to the words written in the book is cheating.
Speaker 1: It's also sadly trivial.
Speaker 0: All right, I move.
Speaker 1: Everyone's a queen.
Speaker 1: Let's see what happens.
Speaker 0: I'll just put my guy on boardwalk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know it's the first turn of the game and I couldn't have possibly rolled that high number, but whatever No, so it's how I roll.
Speaker 0: I roll my d100 from Monopoly.
Speaker 0: I Wish okay make the game maybe actually good.
Speaker 0: Huh, right we want to play Monopoly with like 2d 20s.
Speaker 1: I think it would have to be no 2d 20s.
Speaker 1: we'd have to look at the board right and turn into it into a circular graph and then figure out a Probability curve of roles that would make the auctions the most fair.
Speaker 0: they can be so in a video game You can sometimes do things that aren't cheating.
Speaker 0: They're perfectly within the software's, you know rules and software's ability that the game is.
Speaker 0: But you can.
Speaker 0: they're not sort of intended.
Speaker 0: you sort of break the game in a way like in Metroid 1 is great Examples of doing like, you know door wall ball jump things to go to you know rooms.
Speaker 0: or in Mario 64 Were you like scooting up the stairs real fast to beat in the game in nine minutes?
Speaker 0: You're not cheating.
Speaker 0: You're doing something that is within the rules of the game because the software of the game is the rules of the game.
Speaker 0: But you're still sort of it's not intended.
Speaker 0: and you can do the same with board games, you know the rules of the board game either in Word or in spirit intend for you to do one thing.
Speaker 0: But by being a lawyer and by following the word the words in the in the rule book to the letter you can sort of glitch the board games and Get away and that you might be the only people in the world who find amusement in doing well.
Speaker 0: It's usually also the sign of a very bad board game because poorly written rules is usually a bad game and usually only play it.
Speaker 1: Asians came up and infinitely passed around cards and early on.
Speaker 1: We almost broke the game by everyone passing.
Speaker 1: Yep So, but the other game they brought over that we did in fact play was none other than shadows over Camelot.
Speaker 0: shadows over camera is a game that we have gotten over camelot, right?
Speaker 0: It's a game we had played once before the Chevalier de la tabula Ronda.
Speaker 0: It's also a very Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: It's also a very popular game.
Speaker 0: It gets talked about a lot and you know It's got that popular King Arthur theme and it's got a pretty high production value.
Speaker 0: and it's it's sold even in little tiny game stores.
Speaker 0: So we figured hey, we've played this game twice.
Speaker 0: We pretty much know everything there is to know about this game.
Speaker 0: now Let's do a show on it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now we played this game once a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I was not long ago.
Speaker 1: That was always years ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, man I was back when we little over a year ago.
Speaker 1: that was back when we used to go to Mars to play board games and Those two cool people were there who we haven't seen since that fateful night.
Speaker 1: Yep, that which is kind of sad because they were really cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we actually went over to their apartment and played board games.
Speaker 1: Yep, and there was a camelot.
Speaker 1: Yes, and we brought Pete along as well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we did.
Speaker 1: That was a good time.
Speaker 1: We also played one other game.
Speaker 1: Do we play with them said Starfarers of Catan?
Speaker 1: Yeah That was a good time even though that game is also broken.
Speaker 0: But I really like those little quest cards, but once you memorize them forget it.
Speaker 1: But it's still a fun game once kind of like this.
Speaker 1: so shadows ever Camelot if you don't know is one of those beat the game games where everybody cooperates to kind of beat this free setup or Semi random board.
Speaker 1: but like many of these games because most games have this element There's also the possibility of the traitor or the bad guy or one player saying fuck all y'all I win you all lose the board loses - yep That's good stuff.
Speaker 1: so yeah Lord of the Rings I think it was impossible, but I tried every single time I had the ring at the end of the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, but basically you know it's the game right.
Speaker 0: the board is in some sort of you know position.
Speaker 0: It's in some configuration and the goal of the game is to get the board into a different configuration Which is winning and you don't want the board to go into the bad configuration Which is losing.
Speaker 0: now all the players work together To get the board into the good configuration and the rules of the game.
Speaker 0: Sort of force the board to always fight against you on its own.
Speaker 0: You know you keep flipping over cards that do bad things you know and such.
Speaker 1: now We'll hold off until we're gonna review shadows over Camelot first because that's the important part.
Speaker 1: But we're gonna state we're not going to talk much about What it means to be a beat the game game or kind of?
Speaker 1: Exactly what that entails in the end for gaming as a whole.
Speaker 1: because I mean if you really break it down I'll be the game.
Speaker 1: games are just state machines.
Speaker 1: They end up being not fun unless you have a lot of kind of meta elements there right.
Speaker 0: so in shadows over Camelot You're you're all the kings of King Arthur's the Knights of King Arthur's court.
Speaker 1: Yes, you're not the king King Arthur.
Speaker 1: one King right Arthur?
Speaker 0: And there's a bunch of quests about to go on the quest for the Holy Grail the quest for Excalibur the quest for Lancelot's Armor the quest against the red dragon which appears after you get or don't get Lancelot's.
Speaker 1: I gotta go get Excalibur.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile the Picts and the Saxons.
Speaker 0: the Picts and the Saxons are constantly coming after Camelot.
Speaker 0: you have to constantly fight them off.
Speaker 0: the Black Knight always wants to joust.
Speaker 0: you have to keep jousting him.
Speaker 1: Guinevere is a total bitch.
Speaker 0: Guinevere is a total bitch.
Speaker 0: there are There's a siege engines piling up outside of Camelot.
Speaker 0: You have to once in a while someone has to go out and destroy a bunch of them.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile if too many of them appear Camelot be destroyed.
Speaker 1: There's a good chance that one of the Knights sitting at King Arthur's table is in fact a traitor and he'll turn on Camelot and he'll start making siege engines and other evil stuff like that.
Speaker 1: now the goal of the game is pretty cool Basically one there's.
Speaker 1: there's a couple of ways where the game can just fuck you.
Speaker 1: It's over you lose.
Speaker 1: But other than that pretty much There are white swords and black swords and as you complete quest you get certain arbitrary numbers of white swords to place around King Arthur's table, but if you lose a quest you get black swords to place around King Arthur's table.
Speaker 1: The majority wins in the end.
Speaker 1: black swords majority the traitor if there is a traitor wins or else the board wins White swords everybody, but the traitor wins.
Speaker 0: yep There might not be a traitor because there's actually the way the traitor works is that most there are seven players in the game and There are eight loyalty cards and one of them is the traitor.
Speaker 0: so no one might be the traitor.
Speaker 1: now of course my brilliant idea Sometime if I'm running this game for people or I I know some people are gonna play intentionally leave the traitor card out.
Speaker 1: No even better.
Speaker 0: put two traitor cards in.
Speaker 1: I want to replace all the loyalty cards with traders and watch how the game progresses because it's Basically gonna be a bunch of players all thinking they're clever and wondering why no one has figured them out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone's trying to do quests, but failing miserably at them on purpose.
Speaker 0: They're sort of not doing them very well, and then you know Everyone sort of not caring and then How long it would go on before people realize what was going on?
Speaker 1: I wonder if it would make it to the end.
Speaker 0: the traitor element is really the only thing that keeps this game viable.
Speaker 1: Yes, because I'll say this without the traitor Shadows over Camelot is worth playing at most.
Speaker 0: none twice nuns.
Speaker 0: It's worth playing once I say without the traitor nuns.
Speaker 1: I thought you have this weird thing against these sort of games.
Speaker 1: I think a lot of them are worth playing.
Speaker 1: once Me I guess I mean see the Lord of the Rings game was really fun the first time.
Speaker 0: game is bad.
Speaker 1: It was fun.
Speaker 0: The rules are written even more from the words.
Speaker 0: Yes, some of the worst rules I ever seen.
Speaker 1: the only problem with that worse than Hellas I'd even say was that I was determined to beat.
Speaker 1: I remember the day we beat that game.
Speaker 1: I ran around screaming Anyway, anyway, so basically all that happens every night has a different power, you know Like Galahad can do something and Palmaties could do something else and King Arthur can do something else.
Speaker 1: and like everyone has their special ability and their life bar.
Speaker 1: and you start in King Arthur's Court and every round you can either draw white cards or Go off to a quest.
Speaker 1: once you're at a quest You can't draw any more white cards till you go back to King Arthur's Court, right?
Speaker 0: And you sort of need white cards through the quest.
Speaker 0: So it's a game of go to the court draw a bunch of white cards take your white cards go out do a quest.
Speaker 0: Hope you have the white cards to beat the quest or that you can.
Speaker 0: other things might happen like King Arthur can trade cards with you and such to beat the quest and when you beat the quest you get white swords and you get other goodies return Back to the court get some more white cards go out and do another quest and at the beginning of every person's turn They have to progress the evil somehow which means either they put a siege engine out there Yep,
Speaker 1: they lose.
Speaker 1: a number of siege engines immediately ends the game, right?
Speaker 0: They lose health Can die you get a knight can die and sometimes a knight white might want to sacrifice Themselves.
Speaker 0: if it means that everyone wins the game because it is a cooperative beat the game game.
Speaker 0: so if somehow you can beat the game by every night killing themselves except for one night because you know Hopefully not the traitor is the last guy because that is a victory condition for the traitor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if everyone's dead, but the traitor but if there's you know If you can kill everyone off and still win you win even if you're dead as long as there's one non traitor left alive.
Speaker 0: Or you can draw a black card and a black card Pretty much makes evil happen and depending on the black card a different evil happens.
Speaker 0: it might be a general evil.
Speaker 0: that sort of fucks everyone.
Speaker 0: it might be a Quest specific evil.
Speaker 0: so, you know that you might draw a black knight card Which means you you one step closer to losing the black knight quest.
Speaker 0: and if you draw a lot of black knight cards someone better go over to the black knight quest and you know complete it or else we're gonna lose it and We're gonna get some black swords, which is bad.
Speaker 1: Now the strategy and the fun and everything in the game is pretty much that you have to juggle all of these quests among yourselves and Try to win the game.
Speaker 1: obviously, but the juggling is really important.
Speaker 1: I mean say some people are working on the Excalibur and some people are working on this and that and then it looks like Lancelot quest isn't going so well and no one's there.
Speaker 1: Oh crap We got to do something or Lancelot's armor is gone forever or oh crap.
Speaker 1: We're gonna lose the Holy Grail.
Speaker 1: that fucks us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there's some quest mostly the Lancelot quest in the Holy Grail quest the Excalibur quest.
Speaker 0: Yeah those three quests when if you succeed at those quests you get the Holy Grail or Excalibur or Lancelot's armor and if you get those they can help you out a lot.
Speaker 0: But if the trader gets those he can sort of fuck you over because he takes him out of the game and goes ha ha Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then all the other quests kind of repeat like the Saxons keep coming and keep coming and pretty much you let him build up.
Speaker 1: But then you got to go deal with them because if they build up fully before you deal with them.
Speaker 1: Well, they plopped out a bunch of siege engines and it's not good.
Speaker 0: Think of it as sort of like it.
Speaker 0: The game is sort of like you're in a boat that's taking on water and you have to keep bailing it out.
Speaker 0: And if you can bail it out enough so that you can get to shore you win.
Speaker 0: But if it sinks you lose and everyone's in this boat together Except there's one person on the boat who there might be a person on the boat who wants it to sink and they want everyone.
Speaker 1: The game is really really expertly balanced in that trader or no.
Speaker 1: You will always pretty much it seems and people reading reports of other people playing confirm this You'll get real close to losing and then you'll either Fight and fight and fight and eventually lose or come back on strong and win.
Speaker 1: But the game always kind of really like.
Speaker 1: you feel like you're always falling behind You're always falling down and you're losing and you're fucked.
Speaker 1: and oh my god.
Speaker 1: And like the the balance of the game in terms of drawing it out and the enjoyment is really really there.
Speaker 0: Yeah As opposed to something like Arkham horror or the Lord of the Rings game We just kick your ass and make you feel like all this sucks.
Speaker 0: This sucks.
Speaker 0: Shadows over Camelot really feels kind of even you're never like.
Speaker 0: yeah I'm kicking this game's ass cuz then it would be boring but you're never like.
Speaker 0: oh this sucks so bad.
Speaker 0: It's just wasting my time.
Speaker 1: The game does a good job of making you feel like you're completely fucked and you're about to lose and everything is falling down And yet you'll barely scrape by and then you'll win in the end with some big Everybody does something awesome and you win all of a sudden.
Speaker 0: I think it's really the way the game is abstracted is like you.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: The quest will look like, you know, you look at the Holy Grail quest You see a bunch of black grails lined up and like oh despair despair and desolation, you know.
Speaker 0: And then you'll see like a bunch of pigs coming in and you're like, oh the pigs is gonna be so bad.
Speaker 0: But then you know you sort of play it through and if you're sort of suffering and you're hungry for cards You don't have enough cards.
Speaker 0: Someone has to go back to Camelot to get more cards like.
Speaker 0: But in the end you get like a bunch of white swords, maybe a couple black ones.
Speaker 0: You're like, ah, I got it All right now.
Speaker 1: in terms I mean there's special cars and all this sort of stuff.
Speaker 1: but the quest themselves are pretty much like go there and discard cards until you win or Go there with a full house and put it down and hope your numbers be the hand that the Black Knight's gonna head.
Speaker 0: It's really a game of action management more and in addition to the card management In fact the action management more.
Speaker 0: so like I was playing the character who could move for free, right?
Speaker 0: So most people spend a turn moving to a quest.
Speaker 0: I could just move to a quest and then get going right away.
Speaker 0: So it saves me a whole turn which is huge or like me.
Speaker 1: I was the Saracen Knight Palamides.
Speaker 0: So my land is Palamides Palamides Palamides Palamides Palamides like calamity.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, there's nay there.
Speaker 1: All right, Palamides.
Speaker 1: Yes, you know what?
Speaker 1: He's a Saracen I feel conflicted about But my power was that I can get life back and it was totally lame.
Speaker 0: Yeah No, but you can.
Speaker 0: so let's say this the grail quest right and we need let's say many ten grail cards to beat.
Speaker 0: I've got ten grail cards.
Speaker 0: Well, it takes me an action to go there.
Speaker 0: then I can play one card per turn But we might also be drawing evil grail cards that may basically, you know set us back.
Speaker 0: So it's not.
Speaker 1: that's the thing that makes the game always feel on the edge of defeat that Like the way you draw these bad cards and kind of the allocation and the distribution in Short order a quest that you think you've got a handle on will suddenly spiral out of control and your moments from losing the grail And everyone's got to kind of pull together and buck up.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so the thing in this game is There's one major flaw and that is in the restrictions it puts on communication.
Speaker 0: Let me give you an example this this is the I mean.
Speaker 1: if nothing else I feel like this alone Takes an otherwise pretty serviceable game and a fun game and just ruins it for me, right?
Speaker 0: So let me let me try to explain that the flaw here.
Speaker 0: Let's say for example, it's my turn right on my turn I draw a black card.
Speaker 0: Let's say it's a. I pick it up.
Speaker 0: I look at I'm not supposed to show it to anyone.
Speaker 0: Right, but these are all my teammates, but I'm not supposed to show them this card.
Speaker 0: and the card says let's say it says black knight eight.
Speaker 0: that's pretty bad because that means there's.
Speaker 0: I have to put this on the black knight and it's really strong.
Speaker 0: and It means that if someone goes to fight the black knight say
Speaker 1: rims already at the black knight and I've got like two threes down And you don't know what the what the other three cards I have that I'm gonna be playing on the
Speaker 0: black knight only takes four Cards, whatever.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so it that means that if rim doesn't have really high numbered fight cards He's gonna lose to the black knight because this is a really big number.
Speaker 0: and if we're gonna lose to the black knight We're better off not wasting our turns fighting it.
Speaker 0: We're gonna lose it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, right but Scott, I mean one.
Speaker 1: I can't tell Scott What's in my hand?
Speaker 0: No, he can't tell me what kind of fight cards.
Speaker 1: So the care let's kind of have let's show you example of hope.
Speaker 1: these bullshit conversations are so.
Speaker 1: Scott draws the card.
Speaker 1: He looks at it.
Speaker 0: So I have to say it's a high one.
Speaker 0: I'm not allowed to say if it's an eight.
Speaker 0: I have to say it's high middle or low.
Speaker 0: That's all I'm allowed to say according to the rule book.
Speaker 1: Yes to which I can say.
Speaker 1: All right Do you think I can pull it off?
Speaker 1: I can't say That I've got three sixes in my hand left to go or two ones in my hand left to go are no sixes five.
Speaker 1: I'm totally just making up numbers to prove a point But I can't say anything.
Speaker 1: I pretty much have to say well you think I can do it and he can't really answer that question.
Speaker 1: He can pretty much say yeah, it's high Yeah, you can probably.
Speaker 1: maybe and here's the deal everyone I ever see play this game.
Speaker 1: they pretty much like people look at each other and signal and table talk and Basically break the rules with this Illusion or this nod to not breaking the rules.
Speaker 0: and here's the problem, right if you decide fuck the rules We're gonna say whatever we want because we're cooperating you.
Speaker 0: then the game becomes stupid because you just win.
Speaker 0: There's no way to lose unless you're morons because everyone will know exactly what's on all what you know.
Speaker 0: All the cards are.
Speaker 0: there's one person who has the secret ability.
Speaker 0: They get to look at the next black card and decide whether to draw it or not and they can basically say Oh, it's bad, or it's not so bad or whatever, but if we know exactly what it is Then we like oh we can deal with that.
Speaker 0: okay draw it or no we can't deal with that.
Speaker 0: don't draw it.
Speaker 0: I mean you basically what to do would be an obvious decision, and you'd win every time.
Speaker 1: and It's not that they.
Speaker 1: if they would have just banned a table talk and said you can't say shit Then the game would have been really good.
Speaker 1: I've been okay, but here's the thing.
Speaker 1: if they done that at least it wouldn't have been broken in this way where it's ambiguous As to what constitutes table talk ambiguous if you're breaking the rules or not and there's a lot of hinting and nodding and well Yeah, well don't play.
Speaker 0: someone who like needs grail cards would be like.
Speaker 0: I'm thirsty.
Speaker 1: That's bullshit.
Speaker 1: That's the same as saying give me a grail card, which you're not allowed to say.
Speaker 1: so why is saying I'm thirsty?
Speaker 1: Okay, either it is or it isn't.
Speaker 1: these ambiguous rules break the game They sure do, but if you don't let people table talk at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's say you made a rule where no one's allowed to talk No one's even allowed to communicate.
Speaker 0: you play the game online, and there's no chat room.
Speaker 0: You can't even look at each other.
Speaker 0: the odds of winning become very low if it becomes pretty much Impossible to win because how do you know who needs what you know?
Speaker 0: King Arthur's pretty much?
Speaker 0: Just got a guess.
Speaker 0: you know who to give what cards to the person who you know?
Speaker 0: Draws the black card doesn't look at looks at it and puts it back right.
Speaker 0: well Maybe the next person you know has no idea if it's kind of okay, or really bad or whatever.
Speaker 0: so they just draw it anyway.
Speaker 0: No sudden really bad happened, and there's nothing we could have done about it.
Speaker 0: We didn't have enough information.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like you know.
Speaker 0: everyone's playing blindfolded again And the game becomes really stupid because you basically winning comes down to end luck.
Speaker 1: the real problem.
Speaker 1: Is that the developers of this game?
Speaker 1: instead of coming up with an elegant solution to make the game balanced and fun and unambiguous and allow for the cooperative interaction That is so that makes the game fall so deliciously into acrimony every time it gets played.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's that's the strength of the game that everyone bickers and yells and argues and all that.
Speaker 0: but if they had been yeah That's the whole point of the traitor thing.
Speaker 0: I mean how can you tell who's the traitor if there's no tabletop?
Speaker 1: and even if there aren't traitors?
Speaker 1: There's the.
Speaker 1: you know a knight is in charge of his own destiny.
Speaker 1: So the whole table can say rim go do the grail quest before we lose it.
Speaker 1: I can say fuck you all.
Speaker 1: I'm totally gonna finish the Arthur quest for this quest.
Speaker 1: first the Lancelot quest because I think it's a better move.
Speaker 1: I can do it, and they can't stop me even if I'm not the traitor.
Speaker 1: I might just think I'm doing better.
Speaker 1: Yep, but because it's ambiguous I feel as though the developers were lazy and Decided not to bother coming up with some sort of elegant solution and just came up with this half-assed half-measure.
Speaker 0: What they should have done is they should have come up with a very specific list of things you may and may not say.
Speaker 0: Like, you know when you draw a black card, you can say either good bad or neutral.
Speaker 0: You're not allowed to say anything else.
Speaker 0: or when you draw, you know When you want a card from King Arthur you can you know, basically say I would like a card.
Speaker 1: Or maybe you have a hand of like six semi generic statements and you're allowed to reveal one on your turn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like on your turn, you know, they're.
Speaker 0: they're like say six communication cards.
Speaker 0: you can have any one of them face up at any time like you can give one to a player like like.
Speaker 1: maybe one Says you're proper fucked and one says oh shit's the grail And no one's allowed to talk or communicate in any way.
Speaker 0: otherwise no signaling no gesturing no winking no talking.
Speaker 0: And then that you know would sort of solve the problem because you wouldn't have the no communication making the game boring.
Speaker 0: You know not.
Speaker 0: you know less to go on to figure who's the traitor and you know stupidity and losing.
Speaker 0: But you wouldn't also have the open vague communication that makes the game easy and you just win.
Speaker 1: I feel as though the this Ambiguity of table talk alone takes this game and ruins it.
Speaker 0: It sure does completely otherwise an okay game because he's okay for a beat.
Speaker 1: the game game Despite the busted rule in that regard and all that other stuff.
Speaker 1: We talked about.
Speaker 1: I don't want to be unfair.
Speaker 1: The game is really fun for a couple of plays and this is a great party game.
Speaker 1: this is a great game if you if you were hardcore into games and you have a lot of friends who aren't if They're all over and you bust out this game and you teach it to a real quick and just run with it.
Speaker 1: It's a riot for people who aren't really really into board gaming and it's really fun for people who are into board gaming if you Only play it once or twice.
Speaker 0: the other problem with this game right is even if you you know play by all the communication rules you know really strictly and such if Everyone playing is like an expert and knows all the rules and knows how to play.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much Impossible to lose unless the traitor is super super.
Speaker 0: now this is your luck is really really bad.
Speaker 1: one thing That's very good about this game.
Speaker 1: I like this mechanic.
Speaker 1: I mean we see this mechanic in Verator.
Speaker 1: yeah, and we see this mechanic here the idea of a traitor and in this game The traitor is what saves it because if you play with expert players the traitor is the one thing that makes it possible for the game to be enjoyable among people who know the rules of the Game and are good at the game in the future.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if there was no traitor then expert players would win every time.
Speaker 0: even if it is a limited communication one It's a great party game.
Speaker 1: Just like at a casual party whip it out play it especially if people are drinking a little bit the game will get really fun.
Speaker 1: people really get into it.
Speaker 1: my role play a little bit or Find a group of seven people and play This game like once a month with the same group of seven people every time because then the traitor aspect it turns into a complex mafia and That could save the game But only if you like the game.
Speaker 1: if you don't like the game don't try that.
Speaker 1: But if if you think the game has potential and you're not put off by the table-talk aspects.
Speaker 1: We've brought up That's how to save this game and make it playable in the long run.
Speaker 0: The other thing is the game is a really high production quality.
Speaker 0: the boards are nice the cards are nice the box is nice The cards are real miniatures are nice.
Speaker 0: all the pieces are pretty good.
Speaker 1: though that thing that looks like an experience.
Speaker 0: Yes, I gotta tell you this there is an expansion for this game.
Speaker 0: It's not really an expansion.
Speaker 1: It's not what you think it is basically in the game.
Speaker 0: They're miniatures for each night right.
Speaker 0: there's one for King Arthur and one for everyone else, but they're not painted.
Speaker 0: They sell something that looks like an expansion to shadows over Camelot.
Speaker 0: That's actually just Replacements for all the night miniatures.
Speaker 0: They're exactly the same as the ones that come with the game only they're painted And they're not painted that well either and they charge money for this.
Speaker 1: It's pretty sad.
Speaker 0: don't buy it by accident unless you need like replacement pieces Which I highly doubt because they're kind of hard to lose.
Speaker 0: yes I think there might actually be other real expansions for the game, but I haven't looked into them.
Speaker 0: And I don't like additional quests, but I haven't looked into that and I don't really know so much.
Speaker 1: It's it's a good.
Speaker 1: I mean.
Speaker 1: This is a good game for one person in your circle of gaming friends to own yep.
Speaker 1: It's a good game to whip out of parties.
Speaker 1: It's a good game to go hardcore into with the trader.
Speaker 1: other than that It's kind of meh and most of the mehs from one Unless unless you like beat the game games.
Speaker 1: It is a beat the game game And if you don't like that sort of thing you won't like it and to The table talk thing really really hurts it a lot it does.
Speaker 0: It's pretty painful because you either feel like you're cheating or you feel like it's bullshit.
Speaker 1: Despite that the time we played it with the crew was really fun because one Pete was totally the traitor and did a good job right up until the end and - he didn't trade her enough.
Speaker 1: He could have done a lot more damage, but - Scott here It was probably the first time in my life that he's complimented me because basically what he said was Rim has to be the traitor because rim has been playing kind of poorly.
Speaker 1: therefore He's obviously the traitor.
Speaker 1: and when everyone said what the fuck Scott why he said it's rim.
Speaker 1: It's a board game.
Speaker 1: the fuck Do you think?
Speaker 0: Because I mean I was looking at what you had and I was like if I had that I would not be doing such shit Like that.
Speaker 0: you know and if you're doing shit moves that were obviously Shit moves.
Speaker 1: see the thing is see having seen my full hand and not cheating and table-talking I was doing the best moves I could be doing.
Speaker 1: yeah, yeah anyway But yeah, that's all we got to say about that.
Speaker 1: in general beat the game games are World of Warcraft without the leveling.
Speaker 1: yep I mean that's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: if you like doing raids You'll like beat the game games.
Speaker 1: But like raids once you've done a raid a couple of times And you know how to beat it beat the game games are no longer fun.
Speaker 0: and beat the game games are actually very similar to say jigsaw puzzles or cooperative games.
Speaker 0: yeah, well I mean they're cooperative.
Speaker 0: the thing is they're cooperative games such as Dracula.
Speaker 0: right but even though it's four against one It's actually not a beat the game game because it's actually a human being on the other end whereas in say Arkham horror There's no human being on the other end.
Speaker 0: thing is set by the cards and thus puzzle on a core level.
Speaker 1: that doesn't At least for the it for Dracula and a lot of these games that doesn't really mean anything.
Speaker 0: It means that there's actually a psychology to it and a different answer each time that is set by a human being rather than a set Answer.
Speaker 1: well the thing is the set answer is still randomized by cards and things and shadows of her camera.
Speaker 1: It Procedure it adds depth and complexity.
Speaker 1: yep now granted Dracula fails on a number of fronts I sure does.
Speaker 1: it does not fail on the front that I always feel like I want to play it even though I realize I Don't after I'm playing it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: It's mostly that the combat sucks, but the Dracula's hidden movement is awesome.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: It is all right.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: I think we're done are we done?
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at Frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.