Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, February 26th.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Sky.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we bring you the lost episode of Geek Nights as we review tickets to ride.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Well, tonight's episode is a little special.
Speaker 0: You might have remembered that right before Katsucon we did a show that was actually just hypnotoed for 20 minutes.
Speaker 0: So we pulled it down and I put it back up, but Libsyn decided to cache it for like a week straight.
Speaker 0: So there was no point at which I could upload and allow everyone to actually download the real episode.
Speaker 0: Now luckily it wasn't a full episode anyway.
Speaker 0: It was just a special.
Speaker 0: You know, we talked about ticket to ride a board game, but most of you didn't hear that episode because I eventually just pulled it down entirely and flushed out the Libsyn.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically we made an episode of Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: We tried to upload it.
Speaker 1: Rem screwed up.
Speaker 1: It failed epically.
Speaker 1: He just deleted the episode and took it off the internet.
Speaker 1: It's like it never happened.
Speaker 0: Because there was no other way to fix it.
Speaker 0: So some of you have listened to this, most of you have not.
Speaker 1: So now we're gonna put it back up.
Speaker 0: By the power of magic and gray skull, I bring to you our episode on ticket to ride.
Speaker 0: But because that episode, you know, getting ready for Katsucon was just a special anyway, we're gonna record some news and thing of the day right now.
Speaker 0: To kind of make up for that a little bit.
Speaker 1: And then I'll go back to playing Professor Layton.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go back to playing with my new laptop.
Speaker 1: Yeah, probably.
Speaker 1: Probably what I would be doing if I was you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but in the news Scott can't make chili worth a goddamn.
Speaker 1: Hey, alright, first of all.
Speaker 0: That was some of the worst chili.
Speaker 1: That chili wasn't that, first of all wasn't that bad.
Speaker 1: It wasn't good, but it wasn't that bad.
Speaker 0: I gotta say this.
Speaker 0: I really like I try to be polite and I don't I don't want to lie to you though and say like oh it was okay.
Speaker 0: That was the most unsatisf- you basically just made tomato paste with large chunks of chicken interspersed throughout.
Speaker 1: Okay, first of all, right?
Speaker 1: I tried to cut up the chicken.
Speaker 0: I knew I had to cut the chicken up into like two pieces.
Speaker 0: I knew I had two giant pieces of chicken sitting in a pot of hot tomato paste.
Speaker 1: First of all, I knew I had to cut it small, right?
Speaker 1: But I thought it would shrink so I cut it slightly too large, right?
Speaker 0: Then on the direction- there were like eight pieces of chicken in there.
Speaker 1: No, there were.
Speaker 1: there were a lot.
Speaker 1: But there weren't enough.
Speaker 1: I should, for a second of all, I should have put in more chicken.
Speaker 1: Like I cut up the chicken and I looked at it and I said that's enough but I should have cut up one more.
Speaker 0: I think more importantly you should have put something other than tomato paste and beans.
Speaker 1: Alright, hold on, hold on.
Speaker 1: So then I'm reading the directions right on the package and That's your first mistake.
Speaker 1: It said for more tomato-y chili, and I said that's what I like.
Speaker 1: It said do this.
Speaker 1: I shouldn't have done that.
Speaker 0: Well one, what you did is you took nice diced tomatoes, right?
Speaker 0: But because of the way you cooked them, you just turned them into tomato paste.
Speaker 0: You could have just used a can of tomato paste.
Speaker 1: Well, okay, here's the other thing, right?
Speaker 1: So I'm cooking it, right?
Speaker 1: And you know, it was it was going alright.
Speaker 1: And then it said hey, if you want thicker chili add this flour and then add some water and I'm like, okay I will do that.
Speaker 1: So all you did was take the already too thick tomato paste because it wasn't thick when I added that but it was too thick after it.
Speaker 0: That's because you reduced it too much.
Speaker 1: There was definitely too much reduction.
Speaker 0: And also because you're supposed to have, I don't know, peppers.
Speaker 1: Okay, first of all, right?
Speaker 1: First of all, I gotta tell you the directions didn't say to add that.
Speaker 0: But second of all, Don't follow the directions.
Speaker 1: Second of all, I realized after I already had the stuff going on that I should have done that.
Speaker 1: But then it was too late.
Speaker 1: You got to do that first when you're like, you know, browning the or cooking the meats.
Speaker 0: Actually, you can just toss it in at any time.
Speaker 0: It'll be fine.
Speaker 1: No, it's no good.
Speaker 0: Having made many successful chilies, it is not hard to make chili.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not hard.
Speaker 1: But anyway, Well, it doesn't make you the chili.
Speaker 0: First of all, you presented evidence to the contrary of it not being hard.
Speaker 1: I made good chili before.
Speaker 0: This was like, the chili in the can is better.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna say this is a great chili.
Speaker 1: I can't lie to you.
Speaker 1: It wasn't as bad as you're saying it is.
Speaker 1: And next time it'll be awesome because I have learned.
Speaker 0: Do you want me as a man to lie to you and say yes, Scott?
Speaker 0: That was an okay chili.
Speaker 0: I don't feel bad for having eaten it.
Speaker 0: It did not entirely unsatisfied me to the point that I feel like I should eat a different dinner.
Speaker 1: It wasn't that bad.
Speaker 1: It was just a little bad.
Speaker 1: Anyway, speaking next time, I'm gonna make the awesomest chili.
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: Plus, I think that the the shotgun really is superior to that the other bag.
Speaker 0: You just you just spice chili.
Speaker 0: You don't need a bag.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying.
Speaker 0: You just just make it.
Speaker 0: The bag of chili powder is just chili powder.
Speaker 1: No, there's more to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not much more.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 1: It's all about the number of alarms.
Speaker 0: And you can just kind of wing that.
Speaker 1: Don't worry about it.
Speaker 1: Next time, it's gonna be...
Speaker 0: Ah, judge it.
Speaker 0: After what happened today, I think I feel I think I feel justified in fact worrying about it.
Speaker 1: What the hell?
Speaker 1: You think because?
Speaker 1: Zomom, I made I made a great chili last time.
Speaker 0: When was that?
Speaker 1: Weeks ago.
Speaker 0: Weeks ago.
Speaker 0: Oh, was it?
Speaker 0: Was it really weeks ago?
Speaker 1: It was some number of weeks ago.
Speaker 0: Yes, a number of weeks ago.
Speaker 0: Probably a number greater than 50.
Speaker 1: No, not that many.
Speaker 0: Anyway, in other sad news, Gen Con.
Speaker 0: Now, there are two parts to this story.
Speaker 0: I'm sure a lot of you have heard rumors or seen some articles, but point the first.
Speaker 0: Gen Con.
Speaker 0: That venerable old...
Speaker 1: I feel like we talked about this already, but I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: That venerable old convention of people who like to play a role playing games and such at filed for bankruptcy for various reasons.
Speaker 0: Now, point the second.
Speaker 0: Actually, only one reason.
Speaker 0: The fact that Lucasfilm is suing them.
Speaker 0: Now, the details...
Speaker 1: It's hard to get sued by Lucasfilm.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, as all the bad things you can say about them, right?
Speaker 1: The only good thing.
Speaker 1: Well, there's some good things you can say about them, too.
Speaker 1: But for all the bad things you can say about Lucas and his empire is that he kind of lets people make Star Wars shit.
Speaker 1: So, you know, like he lets people make fan films and he lets people make fan arts and he, you know, he lets you go nuts with the Star Wars.
Speaker 0: Well, a lot of people are really kind of rallying to Gen Con side at all those bastards.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he lets those people do their costumes at the conventions with their...
Speaker 0: But, I'm curious as to what actually happened because like any sort of lawsuits like this don't just suddenly spring up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you got to do something serious to get them to sue you.
Speaker 0: It's more that a company like this wouldn't just out of the blue file a lawsuit.
Speaker 0: There is obviously been some sort of ongoing dialogue between Gen Con and Lucasfilm.
Speaker 0: They were unable to resolve their differences and Lucasfilm having no other recourse has filed this.
Speaker 0: Now, the four complaints are very interesting.
Speaker 0: Number one is that Gen Con has failed to uphold his legal obligations in terms of financial reporting, accounting and payments to Lucasfilm.
Speaker 0: Now, this is mostly in regard to Celebration 4, which was a Star Wars convention run by Gen Con or something like that.
Speaker 1: So, they ran a Star Wars convention.
Speaker 1: Apparently, Gen Con is a convention running company and they were supposed to pay Lucasfilm for the right to run the Star Wars convention.
Speaker 0: It's more complicated than that, that you could read the full complaint if you want.
Speaker 0: But I didn't even care about Celebration 4.
Speaker 0: I barely even care about Gen Con anymore.
Speaker 1: You care about Gen Con even a little?
Speaker 0: I used to really want to go and as time went on, I cared less and less.
Speaker 0: I never cared.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: It's a big gaming con.
Speaker 1: There's better gaming cons.
Speaker 0: When was the last time you went to a gaming con?
Speaker 1: Too long ago.
Speaker 0: Point the second.
Speaker 0: Now, this one's extra interesting.
Speaker 0: This is Lucasfilm.
Speaker 0: Going to PAX.
Speaker 1: PAX is all that matters.
Speaker 0: This is Lucasfilm twisting the dagger a little bit.
Speaker 0: Gen Con did not give auction proceeds to Make-A-Wish Foundation as they had agreed to.
Speaker 1: I'm not a fan of Make-A-Wish Foundation.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: Well, what do you have?
Speaker 0: What do you have against me?
Speaker 0: First, you make bad chili and now you malign the Make-A-Wish Foundation.
Speaker 1: Basically, Make-A-Wish Foundation, you know, I mean, you know, it's sort of hard and it's sort of it's very difficult to take a stand against a charitable organization that helps sick children.
Speaker 1: That's that's difficult.
Speaker 0: But Scott, I guess, is up to the challenge of harming sick children's dreams.
Speaker 1: No, but the Make-A-Wish Foundation gets a lot of money to pay.
Speaker 1: very like.
Speaker 1: most of what they do is like they.
Speaker 1: they'll very often, for example, get a famous person to visit a kid in the hospital.
Speaker 0: Now, do you know this just from the few news reports you see?
Speaker 0: Do you actually know about the Make-A-Wish organization and what they do on a day to day basis?
Speaker 1: No, I don't know what they do on a day to day basis.
Speaker 1: But I just think that, you know, if you're going to help sick children, you could spend the money on, you know, medicine instead of.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess we should get rid of Penny Arcade's charity because obviously it's just entertainment because that's because that actually helps.
Speaker 1: You're distracted from your pain when you play video games, this studies.
Speaker 0: And so getting to meet Michael Jackson doesn't distract you from your pain.
Speaker 1: No, it adds more pain.
Speaker 1: You just don't know it yet.
Speaker 0: OK, well, I guess Scott is entitled to his somewhat uninformed opinion on the Make-A-Wish Foundation.
Speaker 1: I'm not I'm not against them.
Speaker 1: It's not like Make-A-Wish Foundation is evil.
Speaker 1: I just think there are better charities.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Just you kind of went out of your way there to go after that.
Speaker 0: But the fact that that is an issue in this lawsuit, I find very interesting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, come on.
Speaker 1: Even if it's the Make-A-Wish Foundation, you know, it doesn't matter what charity is.
Speaker 1: It could be the Joe Bob charity.
Speaker 1: If you say you're going to have a charity auction and then you don't give the charity auction money to the charity, that is low.
Speaker 1: That is so low.
Speaker 0: Gen Con did not give Lucasfilm their share of the auction proceeds because apparently something must have happened.
Speaker 1: They probably were auctioning off goods donated by Lucasfilm, like sells or, you know, movie film or something.
Speaker 0: I like Adam IV.
Speaker 0: This is this is very much the lawyer part.
Speaker 0: Gen Con did all of this unjustly.
Speaker 1: OK, I don't know what that's supposed to mean.
Speaker 0: My guess, my take on this, because I've seen this happen with other conventions before, especially fan conventions are very often run by people who are not necessarily full of business acumen and may or may not actually just be banned.
Speaker 1: They're very unprofessional.
Speaker 0: I have this sneaking suspicion that what actually happened is that Jen, that the organization Gen Con that attempted to run Celebration for did not read fully the contract that they may have signed with Lucasfilm regarding whatever.
Speaker 0: And when confronted, were unable to cover their end of the bargain.
Speaker 1: That's a good guess as any.
Speaker 0: That is my guess.
Speaker 1: Makes sense to me.
Speaker 0: But regardless of all that, they claim that this is not like everyone who declares bankruptcy.
Speaker 0: This is not the end of Gen Con.
Speaker 0: This is simply a temporary measure to gain protection while they resort their finances, go with their more profitable venues and hopefully get out of bankruptcy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, actually, all their events are continuing to be scheduled and are planned to proceed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but even so, I mean, that is the way bankruptcy is supposed to work.
Speaker 0: You're supposed to be able to get out of bankruptcy.
Speaker 1: I would like to see statistics just like overall, like, you know, companies and people like separately, like the percentage of people in companies going into bankruptcy and then how many of them get out.
Speaker 1: That would be very interesting to see, like, because I mean, technically, shouldn't you try to like raise the percentage of people getting out of bankruptcy, like as high as possible?
Speaker 1: I mean, if everyone who goes into bankruptcy stays bankrupt, then is bankruptcy really working as a law?
Speaker 1: Not so much.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So anyway, what do you got the news?
Speaker 0: Because as much as I'd like to talk more in depth about this, I really don't care that much.
Speaker 1: No, I really don't care.
Speaker 1: OK, so by the commando, which we can talk about a whole lot, it's pretty much like the only non we.
Speaker 1: Well, actually, it's coming to the PC.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I guess it doesn't count, but it's one of the video games we can talk about.
Speaker 1: that's on the systems we don't have.
Speaker 1: Anyway, by the commando, rearmed, not the 3D by the commando remake, but the remake of the original.
Speaker 0: by the commando with newer graphics and more modern control, which I am much more looking forward to than the actual bionic commando that is coming out.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: By the commando, rearmed is coming out to the PS3, the 360 and the PC.
Speaker 1: However, it is going to use the PS3's remote play feature.
Speaker 1: If you are not familiar with this remote play feature, basically what this means is let's say you go and you buy bionic commando rearmed for the PS3.
Speaker 1: You sit down at your PS3 in front of your HDTV and you play bionic commando rearmed.
Speaker 1: But now you want to go lay in bed and play bionic commando rearmed.
Speaker 1: You get your PSP, you go lay in bed and you're playing bionic commando rearmed because your PS3 sends the game to the PSP.
Speaker 1: That's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Now, this is significant because number one, this is one of the first games and probably the first non Sony game to do this, to take take advantage of this feature.
Speaker 1: Two, this feature is actually being used and it works and it's useful and cool.
Speaker 1: And three, the DS, which is probably like a billion times more potential for a feature like this.
Speaker 1: that is definitely possible that it's technologically definitely possible.
Speaker 1: One hundred percent.
Speaker 1: Nintendo hasn't done shit, of course, again, because Nintendo doesn't have to like.
Speaker 0: Nintendo has always been able to do throughout almost the entirety of their existence.
Speaker 0: They can just laugh all the way to the bank because they're making so much money.
Speaker 0: They could just cease operations and have already made money off of all their products out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they have the high potential that is unfulfilled.
Speaker 1: But meanwhile, you know, they're high potential that is unfulfilled.
Speaker 1: OK, you know, it's it's still.
Speaker 1: they got good stuff going on.
Speaker 1: I mean, the Smash Brothers alone.
Speaker 1: I mean, come on.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But Sony, on the other hand, you know, even though they sort of got off to a really bad start, you know, and I still probably would never buy a PS3, the PSP is starting to look OK.
Speaker 1: You know, the pad upons not looking as good as it did when it was not because Tyco, if any arcade maligned it slightly and briefly after a a short encounter with it, his word me carries a lot of weight.
Speaker 1: What can you know?
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: As much as I like gave in Tyco and agree with most of what they say until Yahtzee weighs in, I got nothing.
Speaker 0: Man, if Yahtzee weighs in on Pat upon, that'd be awesome because I to this day, I've never found a single statement I can disagree with regarding video games that has come forth from that man's mouth.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying I'm not saying that I will agree 100 percent that Yahtzee, his word carries like 10 times the weight of Tyco's word.
Speaker 1: Yet Tyco's word, it is not an empty word.
Speaker 1: You know, that's you know, anyway, point is PS3, PSP is a little bit going on there.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, it is amazing.
Speaker 1: It's a little bit of command.
Speaker 0: It's the first time there's ever been a second place.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And the fact that it's continuing to be a strong second place hopefully will light a fire under Nintendo someday.
Speaker 1: to they actually seem to be fulfilling the potential that they have.
Speaker 1: Their potential is less.
Speaker 1: But the fact that they fulfill it, it's like Nintendo has a big like a gallon jug and Sony has a half gallon jug.
Speaker 1: But Nintendo's gallon jug only has a quart of liquid in it.
Speaker 1: But Sony's half gallon jug is overflowing.
Speaker 0: Man, I'd rather have a gallon of Sony's liquid than that chili.
Speaker 1: What the fuck?
Speaker 1: Leave my chili.
Speaker 0: Your chili wasn't that good.
Speaker 0: I got it.
Speaker 0: I can't.
Speaker 0: I can't let it slide.
Speaker 1: It definitely wasn't that good, but it wasn't like horrible poison.
Speaker 0: We'll get a neutral opinion later.
Speaker 1: It was a. it was an.
Speaker 1: actually next time it'll be a chili.
Speaker 1: I promise.
Speaker 0: A bunch of my coworkers are buying PS3 is a lot of people are buying them now just because it's the cheapest Blu-ray player on the market.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, the the PS2 run that won that slap fight.
Speaker 1: Well, the PS2 was incredibly popular and it exploded mostly because, you know, at the time DVD had already won.
Speaker 1: DVD was something people already were buying into and everyone wanted a player, but players are still expensive.
Speaker 1: And the PS2 came out and was the cheapest DVD player.
Speaker 1: So people said, hey, it's a DVD player and a PS2 can't beat that.
Speaker 1: And then the PS2 exploded.
Speaker 1: But now everyone has a DVD player.
Speaker 1: They're 40 bucks.
Speaker 1: So Sony said, hey, we can do the same thing with Blu-ray.
Speaker 1: And, you know, the problem was is it was a little different situation because first of all, there was a competitor to the Blu-ray and Blu-ray and HD DVD together are not commanding nearly the market share the DVD.
Speaker 1: And when the PS2 came out, DVD had already been a success.
Speaker 1: It was already poised to take over the market.
Speaker 1: You were already in a situation where people wanted DVDs.
Speaker 1: They were stuck with.
Speaker 1: there was still VHS is in the stores because people still had VCRs.
Speaker 1: But the stores were, you know, it was at like the perfect moment when DVDs were exploding onto the scene.
Speaker 1: This was like they tried to force the explosion instead of waiting, you know, for the bomb to go off and then sort of riding the explosion to get a double jump.
Speaker 1: They sort of like put the bomb down and hope that it would explode.
Speaker 1: And it still hasn't exploded yet.
Speaker 0: But anyway, we'll get some things the day out and then we'll air that last episode of Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day, this is real short, real sweet video of the guy who wrote the portal song is still alive, performing it in rock band with some other people who are moderately famous.
Speaker 0: And the performance is pretty ass.
Speaker 0: I got to say the video is not that great.
Speaker 0: All I want to point out is that it's amazing the kind of currency that the still alive song and portal pull, because you can have like you could go to a convention, a gaming con and just go up on stage and just start reciting random lyrics from that song.
Speaker 0: And the crowd would be cheering and screaming.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, this is such an example of that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a good song, you know, but people are going way crazier over it that I don't feel it that strongly.
Speaker 0: That's because portal was that way.
Speaker 0: People are still making cake jokes.
Speaker 1: It's a I know people just like at Kasukan.
Speaker 1: I was sick most of the time.
Speaker 1: Yet people were yelling, you know, cake is a lie.
Speaker 1: Cake is a lie.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, it's not funny.
Speaker 1: It doesn't.
Speaker 1: it's not a social currency.
Speaker 0: People are buying it and saying, look, I am a fan of that thing.
Speaker 0: Check it out.
Speaker 1: I wore a portal shirt one day because I am a fan of that thing.
Speaker 0: But I used to be that way.
Speaker 0: Don't pretend you're beyond that.
Speaker 0: There was a time when we would walk around.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, I'm not.
Speaker 1: I'm not beyond that.
Speaker 1: It's just this particular one.
Speaker 1: The yelling of how is this different than yelling Leroy?
Speaker 1: It's not any different.
Speaker 1: It's just this particular one doesn't do it for me.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: But Leroy still does.
Speaker 1: Oh, Leroy Jenkins.
Speaker 1: Even though I hate World of Warcraft portal, which I love, but the meme no good.
Speaker 1: World of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: I hate the meme.
Speaker 1: Two thumbs up.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So anyway, what do you got for me?
Speaker 1: So these guys, they're crazy Japanese people, of course.
Speaker 1: They took Final Fantasy 7 and they made pretty much the whole game, not on the SNES, not on, you know, I guess it was originally on the PlayStation, but on the Atari 7800.
Speaker 1: I wish.
Speaker 1: No, on the Nintendo Entertainment System, the Famicom, the original Famicom Final Fantasy 7, it basically make the whole game pretty much the whole game.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's some characters missing and some side stuff missing, but they've pretty much made all of the major plot, all of the major characters, you know, all the, you know, major scenes, all the major places, you know, the whole game, the bad guys from beginning to end, the most of the music, you know, it's as good as it could be done on the NES, you know, and it's, it's Final Fantasy 7 and it's on the final.
Speaker 0: I'll warn you, as cool as this is, the video is not very entertaining to watch because it's very slow and full of a lot of combat.
Speaker 1: Well, there's a lot of other videos and, you know, screenshots and all sorts of things.
Speaker 1: I'll use a ROM.
Speaker 1: You can download the ROM and play it yourself if you really want to.
Speaker 1: But, you know, this is on every gaming website.
Speaker 1: You know, I just had to talk about it just because it's so, you know, they took a game, you know, like a 3D game from, you know, one time period and they ported the game to an older engine.
Speaker 1: It's kind of a, it's quite a feat and it's definitely, even if it's not worth playing, you know, cause it isn't Japanese, I'm sure there'll be an English translation eventually.
Speaker 0: But hey, I played a good chunk of Final Fantasies 2 and 3, not in Japanese because I didn't have the right character.
Speaker 1: But with bad, bad translations.
Speaker 0: No, but, well, it was translated up until I walked into the first town and talked to some ninja and the ninja said gobbledy googity gobbledy sword sword gobbledy orb sword.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 0: And I said, fuck.
Speaker 0: And I kept playing for a while.
Speaker 0: I kept playing that game for a while before I gave up because not knowing what people say makes Final Fantasy hard.
Speaker 1: Real hard.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: What do I do?
Speaker 1: Where do I go next?
Speaker 0: Especially since that game had a talk to people to get the keywords to ask other people to learn other things.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But anyway, you should check this out.
Speaker 1: It's pretty amazing.
Speaker 1: It's everywhere on the internet, whatever.
Speaker 0: So thus, without further ado, I present to you the lost episode of Geek Nights, where we review Ticket to Ride.
Speaker 0: I don't remember what else we say.
Speaker 0: I don't remember anything from this episode.
Speaker 0: I hope you like it.
Speaker 0: For the uninitiated, you might wonder, how come there is no music right now?
Speaker 0: How come Rim's just talking?
Speaker 0: That means it's time.
Speaker 0: It's another Geek Nights special.
Speaker 1: I love how we use the word special and special is supposed to be a good thing.
Speaker 1: It's a positive word, special.
Speaker 1: But really, a special episode is where we're lazy and the episode sucks and doesn't have a news or thing of the day or anything.
Speaker 0: Special means for whatever reason, we're tired or busy or preparing for Katsu-kan.
Speaker 0: So as a result, we don't put together a whole show.
Speaker 0: We kind of just do something.
Speaker 0: If this is your first experience with Geek Nights, I highly recommend you listen to any other episode that does not include the word special in the title.
Speaker 1: Well, this isn't a bad episode.
Speaker 1: It's just that it's not going to familiarize you with the format.
Speaker 0: It is not representative of what Geek Nights is.
Speaker 0: Much like when I listened to another podcast a long time ago and I remember telling Scott who would recommend it to me, "Man, that thing
Speaker 0: sucked.".
Speaker 0: And we eventually discovered that I listened to the one random episode that happened to have had two guest hosts.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Is it sort of like, imagine if you meet someone for the first time, they make their first impression on you when they're completely plastered.
Speaker 1: That's what this is.
Speaker 0: That's kind of like when I met Daryl Surratt the first time.
Speaker 1: Something like that.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So Katsu-kan that we're preparing for is this weekend as in February what?
Speaker 0: In the Omnishorm Hotel in Washington, D.C.
Speaker 0: on the weekend of Friday, February 15th through Sunday, February 17th.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Not any other year.
Speaker 1: I don't know what you could be listening to this in like 2010.
Speaker 1: How far do I know, right?
Speaker 0: But yeah, we are going to be there doing crazy amounts of stuff.
Speaker 0: If you don't like anime, cause this isn't anime-con nominally, but one.
Speaker 0: Now, if you're a geek, Katsu-kan is absolutely awesome.
Speaker 1: Because, first of all, other anime-cons, the gaming room, not so good.
Speaker 1: Katsu-kan, go just for the video game room.
Speaker 1: It's worth it.
Speaker 0: Especially, remember, the video game room at Katsu-kan is actually two rooms.
Speaker 0: One room is like any other con's video game room, except that it's run awesomely.
Speaker 0: And the other room is our room.
Speaker 0: By our room, I mean at the front of the room is us playing music and chilling with our Atari 7800.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, he's busting out the kaboom.
Speaker 0: The rest.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna bust out the pitfall.
Speaker 0: The rest of the room is, let's see, these are arcade cabinets for games like, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Rampart.
Speaker 0: Rampart.
Speaker 0: Street Fighter 1.
Speaker 1: Root Beer Tapper.
Speaker 0: Oh, Root Beer Tapper.
Speaker 0: Dig Dug.
Speaker 0: Root Beer Tapper is the best fucking- Circus Tamer.
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 1: Rampart.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: Rampart again.
Speaker 0: Seriously, Katsu-kan is like the esteemed convention for esteemed gentlemen who happen to be geeks.
Speaker 0: And if you like video games, Katsu-kan is going to be up your alley.
Speaker 1: Rampart.
Speaker 0: But anyway.
Speaker 1: How many times do we have to say Rampart do you think before it's funny again?
Speaker 0: We've done a show on Rampart.
Speaker 1: Oh, did we?
Speaker 0: We did, didn't we?
Speaker 0: We better have.
Speaker 0: Surround castle to stay alive, Jinx.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: Good job, Blue Commander.
Speaker 0: Red Commander needs food badly.
Speaker 0: Wrong game.
Speaker 1: They might have the gauntlet working this year.
Speaker 0: Run, run, Red Commander, run.
Speaker 1: They had a gauntlet last year.
Speaker 1: Wasn't working too well.
Speaker 0: As in it wasn't working.
Speaker 0: You know what they should have?
Speaker 0: I want the old D&D game.
Speaker 1: Oh, the walk sideways one.
Speaker 1: And if that was on free play, oh my God, I'd be clericking it up using my- Sticks to snakes.
Speaker 1: Sticks to snakes.
Speaker 0: Nothing but.
Speaker 1: Oh, and also, of course, my aww, turn on dead.
Speaker 0: You know that aww I think is the same aww from Saab.
Speaker 1: Oh, they brought that or the Ninja Turtles or the Simpsons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I- All four of those games, the D&D one, the Simpsons, the X-Men, and the Ninja Turtles lined up with free play.
Speaker 1: I would not move from that spot.
Speaker 1: Like Scott, it's time to do this panel and beat the Ninja Turtles.
Speaker 0: Main event's the late show.
Speaker 0: You're interviewing- Eh, fuck it, whatever.
Speaker 1: Someone else- Ninja Turtles, man.
Speaker 1: Ninja Turtles.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Right, so Katsu-Kan.
Speaker 0: As a result, we totally copped out tonight.
Speaker 0: We're going to talk about a board game real quick.
Speaker 0: There's not a lot to say about it.
Speaker 0: Ticket to ride.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: It's fun.
Speaker 1: Ticket to ride is this game that sort of busted out and became really popular a year or so ago, maybe two years ago, and I can't even keep track anymore.
Speaker 1: The reason it busted out and so popular is because it has many game mechanics that basically they make the game really fun, and they could be used to make the game really good, and in some ways they are, but in some ways they aren't.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, think of it this way.
Speaker 0: The real secret behind this game's success is that it's so incredibly simple to learn, incredibly accessible, and it's a train game, but before you go, "Ah," and stop listening and shoot yourself, there are, in fact, three different kinds of train game in the world.
Speaker 1: Whoa, three now.
Speaker 0: Now, Ticket to Ride is the special last kind I'm going to talk about, but when most people think of train games, they think of games that involve wax paper, crease pencils, crayons, and crying.
Speaker 0: Those games require a special kind of person to play.
Speaker 1: They do, indeed.
Speaker 0: Then there's games like Railroad Tycoon or Age of Steam.
Speaker 0: I was about to say if you're a little-- The masochistic Railroad Tycoon.
Speaker 0: Probably the only game I've ever played in my life that has not a single catch-up mechanism whatsoever, and in fact, kicks you out if you're not doing well enough.
Speaker 1: We should learn how to play it.
Speaker 0: I did learn how to play it.
Speaker 1: I'm lost.
Speaker 1: Learn how to play it well.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So this is a special third kind of game, and we're starting to see more of these every now and then.
Speaker 0: They're starting to creep in.
Speaker 1: Third in Texas is very similar, mechanic-wise.
Speaker 0: Yes, but basically, it's not really a train game.
Speaker 0: It looks like a train game.
Speaker 0: It's themed like a train game.
Speaker 1: It smells like a train game.
Speaker 0: The board is trains.
Speaker 0: You take little plastic trains, and you make routes, and you think, "Hey, it's a train
Speaker 0: game.".
Speaker 0: No, this is actually a card game with a complex score-keeping mechanism built into the board.
Speaker 1: That is mostly true.
Speaker 0: It is a set-building card game, and there is not a lot else to it.
Speaker 0: There's a little bit of tactical stuff.
Speaker 1: That's quite similar to what was it?
Speaker 1: Was the Mario Nostrum?
Speaker 1: was the game?
Speaker 0: I think so.
Speaker 1: That was also the card game where the boats didn't really mean that much.
Speaker 0: But then there's, like, Moitre and Verator that just straight up only have cards.
Speaker 1: Yeah, these aren't too similar to those.
Speaker 0: I know, but I point out that those games didn't sell so well.
Speaker 1: Well, Moitre and Verator were never put out in English.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They sold well in Germany.
Speaker 0: Everything sells well in Germany.
Speaker 1: Right, anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the way Ticket to Ride works, basically, is -- and this is also the reason the game is so fun.
Speaker 1: I'll get to after -- you'll see, maybe, when I explain the rules, right?
Speaker 1: There's a board, and the board is a bunch of cities, right?
Speaker 1: And the cities are connected with tracks of different colors, some of them gray, some of, you know, colors, right?
Speaker 1: And there's some cards.
Speaker 1: And at the beginning of the game, everyone gets these routes, right?
Speaker 1: These route cards.
Speaker 1: And the route cards are special.
Speaker 1: The route card will say something like New York, Chicago, 10 points, or New York, LA, 25 points, right?
Speaker 1: Because that's a lot harder, right?
Speaker 1: And you're trying to fulfill those routes.
Speaker 1: You want to have your trains of your color going from one of the city to the other.
Speaker 1: And what I usually do to win the game is I'll have, like, a big route and then some small routes, and I will try to, you know, in getting the big route, also get the small route.
Speaker 1: So, for example, let's say I have two routes and one of them is New York, LA, and one of them is, I don't know, Oklahoma City to Chicago.
Speaker 0: Sault Ste.
Speaker 0: Marie.
Speaker 1: To Sault Ste.
Speaker 1: Marie, right?
Speaker 1: So I would go from New York to Sault Ste.
Speaker 1: Marie to Oklahoma City to LA.
Speaker 1: That way I can accomplish both with the minimal number of trains.
Speaker 1: It's the basic strategy of the game, right?
Speaker 0: Well, strategy.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's one of those games, right?
Speaker 0: Pretty much the strategy.
Speaker 1: It's kind of obvious.
Speaker 0: You look at your routes and you think, what is the most optimal way to get these?
Speaker 0: And then you think, all right, now, in addition to that, who is going to be trying to get in my way and whose way should I get in?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And you basically try to accomplish your routes in the least amount of time possible, the least number of resources.
Speaker 1: Right now, on your turn, you have four options.
Speaker 1: You can either draw train cards.
Speaker 1: You can put trains on the board by spending train cards.
Speaker 1: You can draw new routes.
Speaker 1: If you finish all your routes, you can draw new ones, which means you're probably going to win.
Speaker 1: Or you can, I guess that's a special option in the Europe one, because I'm looking at the Europe rules, the train stations.
Speaker 1: Is that an option in the other one?
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: I don't remember either.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll talk about the train stations later.
Speaker 0: We'll see how much of an impression this game made on us.
Speaker 1: The train stations are not that important.
Speaker 0: Yes, they are.
Speaker 0: But anyway.
Speaker 1: Well, they are, I guess.
Speaker 1: But anyway, when you draw train cards, this is the good mechanic number ones.
Speaker 1: He's a game of good mechanics that don't come together to create the greatest game.
Speaker 1: It's a good game.
Speaker 0: It's a fun game.
Speaker 0: It's a good like gateway game.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Anyway, drawing cards.
Speaker 1: There are a bunch of different colors of train card, right?
Speaker 1: And let's say this green train is a green track connecting New York and Rochester.
Speaker 1: I don't even know if Rochester is on the map, right?
Speaker 1: If there's green trains making that connection, then you need green cards to be able to build there or wild cards.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So you look in his five face up cards and one face down deck.
Speaker 1: So you can either draw two face up ones or two face down or a face up and a face down.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And the thing is, if there's a wild card face up, if you take that, you can't take anything else.
Speaker 1: So you can only take one.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Now, also, when you build a route with your little trains, you put the trains down pretty much like you see a route.
Speaker 0: It's blue and it's got three spaces.
Speaker 0: You got to play three blue cards or two blue in a wild.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Or three wilds.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Or a wild into blue.
Speaker 1: So you just you really try to get the, you know, the color that you need to make the connection you need to or the most urgent connection you need on your route.
Speaker 1: So, you know, if I have this big long route planned out and most of it, nobody's anywhere near, but there's a lot of action going on in Chicago and I need a specific route that's going to take four reds.
Speaker 1: I'm going to be drawn lots of reds whenever I can.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Now, you also get kind of increasing returns that the more trains you use, the more segments in each route.
Speaker 0: When you make a segment, you also get points for it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And like you get one point for a one segment, two for a two, six for a three.
Speaker 0: Or I may I don't know if that it's a scribble.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at an image.
Speaker 0: It's like depending, you know, there's ten for a five and fifteen for a six.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Since the map is such a big web of all these different routes, you can get from point A to point B like going three or four different ways.
Speaker 1: So you you the game sort of encourages you to go the ways where there are longer stretches of track between dots and you'll get more points that way.
Speaker 1: But then again, it'll be slower and you'll have a better chance of failing because in the places where there are shorter tracks, there's a lot more dots.
Speaker 1: There's a lot more alternate routes if someone comes in and screws you.
Speaker 0: Now, we we could talk about strategy or like how to be good at this game or whatever, but I mean, we did that with settlers.
Speaker 0: It was pretty easy with this game.
Speaker 0: It's kind of much.
Speaker 0: just do the most logical thing.
Speaker 0: There's very little strategy to think about, really.
Speaker 1: But the thing about this game that makes it great, especially for getting new people into more quality games, is this right on your turn.
Speaker 1: You only you can't like draw.
Speaker 1: It's not like, you know, you look at other games, right?
Speaker 1: And they say, what do you do on your turn?
Speaker 1: Well, in the first phase of your turn, you do this.
Speaker 1: And on the second phase, you do that.
Speaker 1: This game doesn't have that.
Speaker 1: This game has on your turn, you either draw cards or claim a route.
Speaker 1: That's most of what you're going to be doing most of the time.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And the options you have when doing that are also very limited.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's not that much on the board.
Speaker 0: There aren't that many colors.
Speaker 0: Not like, say, El Grande, where I can get any number between one and like 16.
Speaker 0: And each number has different values and different things.
Speaker 1: And on your turn, you're pretty much either drawing cards or spending cards to put trains on the board, one or the other.
Speaker 1: And it's very quick.
Speaker 1: You're doing a very small action.
Speaker 1: So you go around and everyone on their turn does a very small action.
Speaker 1: Small action, right?
Speaker 1: So you go around and I do something quick.
Speaker 1: The person left of me does something quick, quick, quick, quick, quick, quick, quick.
Speaker 1: Everyone does lots and lots of little things.
Speaker 1: And this keeps the game moving.
Speaker 1: You're constantly doing things.
Speaker 1: You're not spending a lot of time waiting for people to take their turns.
Speaker 1: Your turn doesn't have a whole lot to think about.
Speaker 1: You're thinking more as a collection of turns, but you're still constantly working your way towards that big thing.
Speaker 1: And then the thing about that is everyone's constantly playing.
Speaker 1: You're never out of the game.
Speaker 1: You're not really bored.
Speaker 1: The game keeps you engaged.
Speaker 0: And you don't need to worry about novice players needing to bevagon their ass.
Speaker 1: You don't have to think too hard at any particular juncture, you know, and it keeps the game at a good pace and it makes it a lot of fun for people who aren't super gamers.
Speaker 0: But if you're a hardcore gamer, still buy this game because it's a great game to get people into board gaming.
Speaker 0: And like other games we have that aren't the super best games, it's fun.
Speaker 0: I mean, Carcassonne is solved.
Speaker 0: Settlers is solved, but they can still be fun to play depending on the situation.
Speaker 1: And it can also handle a lot of players, like up to like five players.
Speaker 1: It's not bad for more than some other games.
Speaker 0: It's also a pretty quick play.
Speaker 0: It's something you can just whip out and play now.
Speaker 1: It's also really colorful and happy.
Speaker 0: We didn't own the game.
Speaker 0: Our friends James and Lisa had it, so they brought it and we played it with them and we never bought it.
Speaker 1: But we liked it the times we played it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So as a result, I was in the store, a Millennium in Rochester, and I saw Europe Edition.
Speaker 0: I thought, all right, well, I already played the normal one.
Speaker 0: I might as well just buy this edition and own that one instead.
Speaker 0: It can't be that different.
Speaker 1: Well, the Europe version adds two things that are kind of crappy.
Speaker 0: Randomness and more randomness.
Speaker 0: If you, sir, were tired of playing games where skill determines the victor, if you were bad at games and were frustrated at the fact that you lost due to your own lack of ability, have no fear.
Speaker 0: Ticket to Ride Europe is your game.
Speaker 1: So it has these tunnels, right?
Speaker 1: And the way the tunnels work is.
Speaker 1: it's just a normal route.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But if you want to build on the route, you like roll a dice.
Speaker 1: You roll one die, I think.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Is that right?
Speaker 0: No, it's pretty much you play out, like say you play out whatever many cards it is of the right color, and then you draw three more colors.
Speaker 0: Oh, right.
Speaker 0: And if you it's like you have you gamble and you can bet on the odds of finishing the tunnel or not.
Speaker 0: If you finish it, great.
Speaker 0: If you don't, well, you just wasted a turn.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like basically let's say a tunnel is three trains long.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So I try to build it and I have the three trains.
Speaker 1: Then we do this random thing and it might turn out that I need to.
Speaker 0: I'll read the actual rules.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 0: When attempting to claim a tunnel route, a player first lays down the number of cards required by the route's length.
Speaker 0: Then turn.
Speaker 0: the top three cards from the train deck for each card reveal that matches the color used to claim the route.
Speaker 0: An additional card of the same color must be played to successfully claim the route.
Speaker 0: If a player does not have enough cards, he takes all his cards back and the turn ends.
Speaker 1: Depending on luck, you might lose a turn, but you could sort of mitigate that by having extra cards in your hand.
Speaker 1: But then you might have to spend five cards to build a route that's only three long just to avoid losing a turn.
Speaker 1: So it's basically, you know, you can build this route, but you might get randomly fucked and it doesn't really add a lot to the game, but just sort of makes it annoying if you need one of those routes.
Speaker 1: The other thing the game as the ferries, which basically you need to have wild cards or some number of them to do.
Speaker 1: some of the ferry routes like this is one ferry route that goes from Smyrna to Palermo and it's six spaces long.
Speaker 1: And you could use any four cards you want that are the same color, but even wild cards.
Speaker 1: But you need two wild cards through those last two spots or else you can't do it.
Speaker 0: Now, we haven't played any of the other.
Speaker 0: well, the other expansion is the Marklin.
Speaker 1: It's they're not expansions.
Speaker 1: They're alternate versions of the game.
Speaker 1: You could buy Europe on its own.
Speaker 1: Marklin on its own.
Speaker 1: It's not an expansion.
Speaker 1: You don't need to own regular tickets to ride to get tickets to ride Europe.
Speaker 1: They're separate games entirely.
Speaker 0: But frankly, as far as I can see, the only thing you should buy is the original one is probably the best one, unless someone has played the third one and it's actually great.
Speaker 1: People say that people say the Marklin one has like these passengers that you have to deliver.
Speaker 1: And I don't remember what the mechanic is, but it could be good.
Speaker 1: It could be bad.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: But the most important thing is that it's pronounced Sue St.
Speaker 0: Marie, not salt.
Speaker 1: Also, green trains are the best.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Highly partial to the bright, searing blue.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the yeah.
Speaker 1: If you're the hardcore type of gamer person, you know, you this game, go back to playing El Grande in Puerto Rico.
Speaker 1: You're not going to play this game too much.
Speaker 1: But if you got a family, if you're trying to introduce people to maybe a world where there's, you know, cooler games in a world where games don't suck as much as Monopoly, you know, you can get someone to play tickets to ride.
Speaker 0: You know, it won't be that hard in a world where guess who isn't ruined by the fact that you're guys wearing glasses, right?
Speaker 1: And then they'll probably like it.
Speaker 1: And once you get them to play tickets to ride, you know, you'll be able to get them to play other games that look sort of similar that are much more complicated, like Puerto Rico or Settlers of Catan or Carcassonne or whatever.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, take it to ride.
Speaker 1: Not bad.
Speaker 0: And on that note, I got to finish preparing for Katsucon because we're doing a lot of stuff at this convention and we're leaving tomorrow, I guess Thursday morning tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: But I'm pretty much going to come home from work, look at my things that I'm going to be doing stuff with at the con, put them on a laptop and then go to bed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: And then the next day, me and Pete going to play some advanced wars for five hours while Scout drives.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, what else are you going to be doing?
Speaker 0: What are we going to be doing?
Speaker 1: Buying gas.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: It's not that far.
Speaker 0: It's like an hour past Otacon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 1: It's still, you can also pay for media at the Bob Evans.
Speaker 0: Oh, that Bob Evans.
Speaker 0: That Bob Evans saved my life and saved my life as well.
Speaker 0: But that's the story for another time.
Speaker 0: Stay tuned tomorrow night.
Speaker 0: The story of Bob Evans, where not only are we going to tomorrow night, talk about Katsucon and everything that's going on there, but we're going to review something important.
Speaker 0: It's one of those, you know, anime world order.
Speaker 0: They're a big anime podcast and then other podcasts that review things.
Speaker 0: There's always those big ones, the big names that they you're almost afraid to review.
Speaker 0: Like, I don't think I could do it justice.
Speaker 0: I got to wait.
Speaker 0: You never actually do it.
Speaker 0: Well, we're doing it, so we're not going to say what, but it should be pretty obvious that tomorrow night we're going to be reviewing the greatest animated television series ever created.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com, where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our crapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week, covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com, or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution, non-commercial, share-alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it, as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: [BLANK_AUDIO].