Speaker 1: It's Thursday, July 24th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm Rin.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, the demise of the dinner.
Speaker 0: Da da da da!
Speaker 0: The... Demise.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: What's a word that's synonym with demise?
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: The something of the supper.
Speaker 0: I created somewhat of a modern spectacle on the train home today.
Speaker 1: What could you possibly have done to make a spectacle?
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is, basically, everyone who walked by did a double take.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, because I got on the train, I took a slightly later train.
Speaker 1: I took a way later train.
Speaker 0: So I get on this train, you know, like 20 minutes before it's gonna leave.
Speaker 0: So as a result, a lot of people walk past me and almost every single one of them stop and did some sort of double take at me.
Speaker 1: What were you doing?
Speaker 0: So I had to bring my work laptop back to work to get some stuff done to it before I brought it home again.
Speaker 0: And, you know, I have my normal laptop.
Speaker 0: I do stuff on and the work laptop is bigger.
Speaker 0: It's a desktop replacement that I use, like, you know, for work.
Speaker 0: Got this encrypted hard drive.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like if I go on a trip, but it's a business trip or I'm working from home.
Speaker 0: I use this thing and, you know, VPNs into the work network.
Speaker 0: It's got all the work software.
Speaker 1: I guess that's all right.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you're not carrying it too often, then it won't be a physical burden.
Speaker 1: And that way you don't have to mess up any of your own computers and you can keep your work computing and home computing perfectly separate.
Speaker 0: Best part is it's got all the work software.
Speaker 0: I've got like the like the full on Adobe in the office and all those things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know the Oracle, all my server things, everything I could possibly need for work is on there.
Speaker 1: That's good, because, you know, like I know most of my work is Linux.
Speaker 1: All I really need to do is SSH to the work server.
Speaker 1: But if I had some sort of pre-configured separate work machine, that was, you know, a laptop be good, too, because then I could, you know, give it back more easily.
Speaker 0: Part of that's that, you know, I don't have admin access on it.
Speaker 0: I just have my normal work access.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Because you're only going to work with it.
Speaker 1: You're not going to do anything else.
Speaker 0: But if I need another laptop for whatever reason, I can just boot in Ubuntu CD and rock.
Speaker 1: Oh, definitely.
Speaker 0: I already tried that.
Speaker 0: It works just fine.
Speaker 1: Of course, it works just fine.
Speaker 1: It's a normal Dell laptop.
Speaker 0: I had to take it in and I don't have a bag that fits this thing.
Speaker 0: So basically I just carried it.
Speaker 0: And on the way in, that's fine.
Speaker 0: I just put it in my lap, went to sleep, you know, listening to some movies you should see.
Speaker 0: They actually did a good show.
Speaker 0: It was very simple.
Speaker 0: It's the kind of thing I'd like to do a week as Thursday about.
Speaker 1: Man, I like them and I like their show.
Speaker 1: And Rich, I am following him on Twitter.
Speaker 0: But, but, but.
Speaker 1: I just don't listen to it anymore.
Speaker 1: I don't know why.
Speaker 0: See, I started listening to it again.
Speaker 0: And as a result, I started watching a lot of movies again.
Speaker 1: I just sort of saturated with podcasts in general.
Speaker 1: I mean, there are podcasts I subscribe to where I just like every episode, like it appears in the thing and I just lead it.
Speaker 0: I actually listen to every single episode of every podcast to which I am subscribed, which is like four.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is, is like on the train, you know, it's like I've been I only I've been listening to less podcasts and doing more, you know, book reading and comic reading and video games.
Speaker 0: See, I'm doing 50/50 now.
Speaker 0: What I'll do is I'll either an anime watching.
Speaker 0: I'll either watch an anime or watch a movie or, you know, work on like a blog stuff.
Speaker 0: I got all these half written articles.
Speaker 0: I got to finish.
Speaker 0: But the other half the time I'll place it for or something and listen to podcasts at the same time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much all my activities are taken aback.
Speaker 1: My podcast listening is taking a backseat to the other thing.
Speaker 0: I really only listen to movies you should see.
Speaker 0: Dave and Joel and Anime World Order.
Speaker 1: I listen to a few.
Speaker 0: Oh, and NPR.
Speaker 0: It's all politics.
Speaker 0: I love that show.
Speaker 1: I listen to some more than that, but well, I guess I'm subscribed to more than that, but I'm not listening.
Speaker 1: And a lot of the ones I'm subscribed to are short.
Speaker 0: You know what else I'm subscribed to?
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: Twelve Byzantine emperors.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have listened to it all again.
Speaker 0: But other than that, great.
Speaker 0: There are going to be new ones.
Speaker 0: I hope I hope I hope he does a podcast on Venice.
Speaker 1: Venice is awesome anyway.
Speaker 0: So on the way home, you know, I'm awake, I'm not sleeping and I want to do stuff.
Speaker 0: So I don't have anywhere to put this laptop.
Speaker 0: So I've got this laptop on my lap and resting on top of it is my other laptop, which is open and I'm using.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So people are walking by and they see me with a laptop on my lap closed and another laptop open.
Speaker 0: And they'd stop and look at it like, what the fuck?
Speaker 1: Why is it?
Speaker 1: what the fuck?
Speaker 1: Just to have two laptops.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's kind of.
Speaker 0: it's kind of weird to have two laptops, I guess.
Speaker 1: I don't know what's so weird about it.
Speaker 1: I know people with a lot more than two laptops.
Speaker 0: Yes, but to have two on you.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: People looked at me like it was weird.
Speaker 0: Everyone who walked by looked like, what's he doing?
Speaker 1: I saw a guy sitting next to me on the train today.
Speaker 1: He had a Blackberry.
Speaker 1: And then from his pocket, he pulled out a cell phone.
Speaker 0: Not weird.
Speaker 0: See, that's not weird at all, though, because most people have like the work Blackberry.
Speaker 1: Two laptops is no weirder.
Speaker 0: I think two laptops is kind of weirder because there's no possible reason to have two laptops out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there is.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: To protect your lab from the other laptop.
Speaker 1: That's ludicrous because it's real warm.
Speaker 0: I mean, while I was doing this, I did actually have the Blackberry out because I was transferring stuff from the Blackberry to my laptop with the Bluetooth.
Speaker 0: I didn't pull my cell phone out because I'm not going to call anyone on the train.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no.
Speaker 1: But there was a meeting at work.
Speaker 1: But then like one that one of the bosses who was in on the meeting wasn't there when it was time for the meeting.
Speaker 1: The other one was on the phone and wouldn't get off the phone.
Speaker 1: And so the meeting was late.
Speaker 1: And then it was even later.
Speaker 1: So I took away later train and I got home like 10 minutes ago into my work.
Speaker 0: Made me late all the time.
Speaker 0: I quit.
Speaker 1: It's not all the time.
Speaker 1: It's one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is because you get home a lot later than you want to.
Speaker 1: And what can I do about it?
Speaker 0: Quit.
Speaker 0: Like you said, you always what are you?
Speaker 0: Are you a Barack?
Speaker 1: Where am I going?
Speaker 1: Who am I going to go?
Speaker 0: I thought it was easy to get another job.
Speaker 1: I thought your advice is easy to get another job.
Speaker 1: It's not easy to get another job with cool peoples.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I got a job with awesome people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I want your job.
Speaker 1: Your job has other problems.
Speaker 0: What problem could my job possibly have?
Speaker 1: I work in a company where, by and large, everyone is smarter than me because the actual work is not something I want to do, which is the most important thing.
Speaker 0: My work is awesome.
Speaker 0: I'm not doing.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't be doing I.T.
Speaker 1: work there.
Speaker 1: If I was doing I.T.
Speaker 1: work there, I would take your job.
Speaker 1: That would be just fine.
Speaker 1: I could do that.
Speaker 1: Be moving V.M.
Speaker 1: wares and you know, that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: I can do that.
Speaker 0: What kind of job do you want?
Speaker 1: I want the head.
Speaker 1: Well, my job is slowly becoming the job I want, which is why it's kind of cool.
Speaker 1: We're like we're switching from the PHP to the Jango's and like the things.
Speaker 1: it's like the things that we're suggesting are actually happening.
Speaker 1: Like we made a wiki for documentation.
Speaker 1: And it's like even though we got bought out, it's like now our opinions are somehow mattering more.
Speaker 1: And we're leaning more in the direction of what we the programmers want to do.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, you got to stay late.
Speaker 0: Take a later train.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe, you know, that won't be a problem in the future.
Speaker 0: We'll see demand more vacation days.
Speaker 1: Well, I already I got more vacation days and we got bought automatically to get more sell.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is now I can't just negotiate that with my boss because now he's an employee, too.
Speaker 1: We need to negotiate that with people in North Carolina.
Speaker 1: So it's more difficult.
Speaker 0: So you got we'll see.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to work at this place forever.
Speaker 1: I mean, come on.
Speaker 1: I've worked there for two years.
Speaker 0: I honestly it's weird, but I worked at IBM and that was really fun.
Speaker 0: But, you know, I had I couldn't just work at IBM my whole life.
Speaker 0: So now I work to the hospital and you all know my opinion of the hospital.
Speaker 0: There were there were a lot of reasons why I left the hospital and then it was sick.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was one of the reasons, you know, I can't complain too much about a job where at one point after my third boss quit and they didn't know like they knew they needed me to do work.
Speaker 0: There was a lot of work that needed doing.
Speaker 0: So they basically sent me off to do all the kind of weird work that required judgment on the spot, kind of like a ship's captain.
Speaker 0: How in the army, no one's really out on his own because there's supply lines all the way back.
Speaker 0: I'm talking Napoleonic days.
Speaker 0: So you could send orders pretty easily to most of the people doing all this stuff, but you could send a ship halfway around the world and you don't know if you're going to make peace or war.
Speaker 0: I mean, how often in Horatio is he out?
Speaker 0: They see a Spanish ship and they're like, shit, are we at war?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Let's see if they shoot at us.
Speaker 0: Crap, we're at war.
Speaker 1: Because if you're real close to Spain, then and you're from England or UK, whatever, I guess in those days.
Speaker 1: Yeah, England.
Speaker 1: Then, you know, you've been away from England for X days.
Speaker 1: They've been away from Spain for maybe a few hours, depending on how close to Spain you are.
Speaker 1: So there's a good chance they know the most current news, but you don't know the most current news.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, say you think you're at peace.
Speaker 0: They know you're at war.
Speaker 0: But what if you go the other way around?
Speaker 0: They know there's peace.
Speaker 0: You think it's still war.
Speaker 0: You're out there and the Spanish ship is coming up and they're yelling, no, no, peace.
Speaker 1: No, don't shoot.
Speaker 1: They could be faking it, you know, and then pull a surprise attack.
Speaker 1: You could do the same thing.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: So ship's captains were given incredible leeway to, you know, make judgment calls back then.
Speaker 1: Of course, if you fucked up, you know what happened.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: With great responsibility comes great risk.
Speaker 1: Comes great hanging.
Speaker 1: Hanging is frequent, pretty much.
Speaker 1: If you do this, you will be hanged.
Speaker 1: If you do this, you'll be hanged.
Speaker 0: My favorite part is that if you read the articles of war, it's like, if you are convicted of doing such and such, to be hanged or lesser such penalty as deemed appropriate, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 0: But then it hits a couple of them like mutiny and it's like to be hanged.
Speaker 1: It's not to be hanged.
Speaker 1: It's hanged.
Speaker 0: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: It's to be hanged, but there's none of that or lesser such punishment.
Speaker 0: There isn't even the option of doing less to you.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much like, I don't know how many times the ratio, the books and the movies there, they're just like, you know what the penalty is for that hanging.
Speaker 1: There's nothing we can do to save you, even though we know that you did it for a good reason.
Speaker 0: So Horatio does something awesome to get the guy off.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like, there's no way off the hook, man.
Speaker 1: It's hanging.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: In one of the books, he is obligated to hang someone for disobeying an order.
Speaker 0: The order was that he was in the Marine band and he refused to play a B flat because it was the wrong note because the music was written poorly.
Speaker 0: And the order was given by a technically superior officer.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Refusing to play a note, breaking an order, only option, hanging.
Speaker 0: And the funny part is Horatio's like, eh, I got to hang him.
Speaker 0: And his wife is like, what the fuck's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: Anyway, so, uh, so back at the hospital, I was kind of like a ship's captain at this point.
Speaker 0: So they'd send me off like whatever, there was something weird going on.
Speaker 0: They'd send me off like, all right, Brandon, you know, cause they didn't, I, that job didn't know my name was rim.
Speaker 0: Cause they, they didn't deserve to know my real life.
Speaker 1: But your real name is Brandon.
Speaker 1: Rim is the fake name.
Speaker 0: The thing is my, my, my quote unquote fake name is used by more people, both that I know and that know me than my quote unquote real name.
Speaker 1: Why don't you just then go to the judge and say, change my name?
Speaker 0: Actually, I looked into it and the only reason I haven't is that it's a giant pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: It's not that hard.
Speaker 1: You just have to go get a new ID at the DMV.
Speaker 0: No, it's a giant pain in the, I don't think you understand the pain in the ass it is to actually change your name.
Speaker 1: It can't be that hard.
Speaker 1: People do it all the time.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, they don't.
Speaker 0: And two, when you do, most people who do it are kind of poor.
Speaker 0: If you have a bunch of credit cards and a bunch of investments and all this kind of, you know, economic and all these things around you, they all have to be changed.
Speaker 0: Most people don't have straightforward policies.
Speaker 0: Your mail gets fucked up forever.
Speaker 0: Your credit rating gets fucked up until you deal with it at every agency.
Speaker 0: It's this gigantic snafu.
Speaker 1: You just call every single place and say I changed my name.
Speaker 1: I changed my name.
Speaker 0: I did the research and all the research indicates that it's such a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: And half the time people just, a lot of like people who suck just don't have the capability to deal with your name change.
Speaker 1: I can't imagine being, I mean, if it happened to me or if I want to change my name to Joe, I say go get a DMV.
Speaker 1: I got to call my credit card company and the bank and my job and the post office.
Speaker 0: Yes, I have to call all my credit card companies.
Speaker 0: I also have to deal with my health insurance.
Speaker 0: I have to deal with my investments.
Speaker 0: There's a lot to it.
Speaker 1: I would just tell my job and the HR person would take care of it.
Speaker 0: No, usually they won't.
Speaker 0: And there's a lot to it.
Speaker 1: Oh, they will.
Speaker 0: Also, you've got to make sure your medical records get transferred right.
Speaker 1: Old medical records might just disappear.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: If they don't do it, I could just quit, go get a new job and fill out all the new job paperwork with my new name.
Speaker 0: Regardless, I don't know why you're arguing.
Speaker 0: Apparently it's a giant pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: Plus, in most jurisdictions you actually have to go before a judge and prove a valid reason for changing your name.
Speaker 0: They can just say no.
Speaker 1: That'd be fun.
Speaker 0: Usually it's not.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: From what I read, it's not because the judges don't care.
Speaker 1: Judges are cool.
Speaker 0: Sometimes.
Speaker 1: I'm just going to be friendly with the judge.
Speaker 1: Be like, what's up judge?
Speaker 0: Anyway, so they'd send me off and they'd be like, all right, drive to this hospital.
Speaker 0: It's like 20 miles away or 30 miles away, like down somewhere weird.
Speaker 0: Oh, go to white planes.
Speaker 0: There's this hospital.
Speaker 0: With the wigs and the robes.
Speaker 0: We don't know what's going on.
Speaker 0: Go figure out where our switches went.
Speaker 0: So I'd go out there and they basically say, report back to us in a week.
Speaker 0: And that was the extent of my orders.
Speaker 0: So I'd go and I'd resolve the problem immediately or I'd find out what the problem was and I'd report back and I'd be like, here's the problem.
Speaker 0: What do you want me to do?
Speaker 0: And they'd say, hang on, we'll figure out what we want you to do.
Speaker 0: And then a week would go by and every day I'd doodlefully say, what do you want me to do?
Speaker 0: And they'd say, I don't know, go to the hospital and wait.
Speaker 0: And as I learned, they would never tell me what to do after I got to the hospital.
Speaker 0: And eventually if I kept asking, they'd say, oh, it's like five, go home.
Speaker 0: So I asked what to do.
Speaker 0: They'd say, wait.
Speaker 0: And then I would just go somewhere and hang out.
Speaker 0: I had my cell phone.
Speaker 0: If they actually wanted me to do work, they could call me.
Speaker 0: They'd never call me.
Speaker 0: And then I'd go home and then a week would go by without me doing any work.
Speaker 0: That job was awesome, but not in the awesome way.
Speaker 1: That was like my job.
Speaker 1: Middle of nowhere.
Speaker 0: I go to the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 0: You'd have to drive to that office where there was no one and do nothing and then drive home.
Speaker 1: Well, there was technically a work I was supposed to be doing.
Speaker 1: They were like, they wanted me to basically make a new version of this existing application.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, OK, what exactly do you want me to do differently?
Speaker 1: Like, what are the specifications for this remake of this project?
Speaker 1: You know, and they were like, all right, we'll have a meeting about that.
Speaker 1: I'm like, OK.
Speaker 1: Occasionally the project I had already completed needed a little bit of maintenance, but that was like once every couple of weeks, a tiny bit of work.
Speaker 1: So it was mostly just being like, hey, are we going to discuss?
Speaker 1: And someone's like, oh, well, you can at least do this part.
Speaker 1: We don't need to discuss that.
Speaker 1: I'm like, OK.
Speaker 1: I never did that part.
Speaker 1: No one noticed.
Speaker 1: No one talked to me.
Speaker 1: No one cared.
Speaker 1: No one said anything to me.
Speaker 1: No one checked to see what work I was doing.
Speaker 1: No one checked on the progress.
Speaker 1: No one noticed this meeting wasn't happening.
Speaker 1: Apparently they wanted it done, but they didn't want it done badly enough to actually pay attention to me.
Speaker 1: If I hadn't quit, I probably could have had that middle of nowhere job until now.
Speaker 1: Still just doing nothing.
Speaker 1: And I probably wouldn't have done any more work now than was completed then.
Speaker 0: Didn't you bring your DDR pad out there?
Speaker 0: Oh, I did.
Speaker 1: I had my DDR pad out there.
Speaker 1: And I would just play step mania while instead of working.
Speaker 0: Man, that's a good life.
Speaker 0: to a point.
Speaker 1: It was OK until I went insane for me in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 0: See, I don't know if I had a job like that.
Speaker 0: I would consider it a month or two worth of getting everything I needed to get done, done in my life.
Speaker 1: And that's the problem is that I, you know, while I was working in the middle of nowhere, I realized too late that I could have just not gone to the middle of nowhere and just stayed home.
Speaker 0: I kept saying every day, I was like, why don't you just get another job?
Speaker 1: Because it was just like, you know, it's sort of like that, eh.
Speaker 0: And you know what, even better, just get another job.
Speaker 0: Don't even say anything.
Speaker 0: Just see how long they keep paying you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then there could have been some legal problems later.
Speaker 0: There are ways around that.
Speaker 1: I don't know about that.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't have worried.
Speaker 1: That's the problem.
Speaker 1: is I worried just a little too much about, you know, cause I kept the CEO of the company lived like around the corner and sometimes he'd drop in like maybe once a month.
Speaker 0: And if he dropped in and you weren't there, he'd probably say, where were you?
Speaker 0: And he'd be like, eh, I was going out to lunch.
Speaker 0: I had a flat tire and I had to deal with it.
Speaker 0: There's no work to do.
Speaker 0: So I didn't bother calling anyone.
Speaker 0: And then I'd just show up for the next couple of weeks.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, well.
Speaker 0: Or you put a cardboard cutout of yourself in the distance.
Speaker 0: Like if there's a glass door in the entrance and break the door so it won't open, like his card won't work.
Speaker 1: And it was, it was a bad time.
Speaker 1: I should have, I really regret.
Speaker 1: I could have done a lot of things in that time that I didn't do, but I would have like gone on vacation.
Speaker 0: Seriously.
Speaker 1: I played a lot of video games and I would have made a blog.
Speaker 1: I listen to a lot of podcasts.
Speaker 0: You know what you do?
Speaker 0: It's like that comic, you damn kid where it's like, so is he going to work?
Speaker 0: He's got a new job.
Speaker 0: Like, yeah, the over under is five days before he gets fired.
Speaker 0: What you could have done is made a blog called my boss doesn't know I'm not working and doesn't seem to care.
Speaker 0: And have bets on when he finds the blog and what he does when he finds it.
Speaker 1: See, I'm a lot smarter now than I was then.
Speaker 1: So it's, you know, back then my best idea was I'll play step mania in the office and say I'm exercising.
Speaker 0: If they, you know, that's like the plan of I have found a soda machine that gives free soda.
Speaker 0: I'm going to get one free soda and then never come back and laugh about it for a week.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: As opposed to I'm going to make a blog about this soda machine.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I got one hell of a news here, so let's just get any news.
Speaker 1: Oh, he's not a feel like it because I got home late and at work I was actually working.
Speaker 0: It's Geek Nights Thursdays, the lounge.
Speaker 0: We can do whatever we want.
Speaker 0: There's no such thing as.
Speaker 1: Can we just end the show so I can, you know, go eat and go to bed.
Speaker 0: So I want to talk about this because this is one of those crazy things.
Speaker 0: Like what I heard in the news a while, you know, way back that riser as in the guy who made riser.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: He is charged with murdering his wife in this crazy elaborate scheme is just this crazy court case.
Speaker 0: And then the news much later found guilty much later told everyone what he did with the body.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It was like when he was just in the first part of that trial where he was just crazy and weird.
Speaker 1: It was like, well, there's a lot of circumstantial evidence and anecdotal evidence and character evidence that he probably did it.
Speaker 1: But there's all this weirdness going on and we can't.
Speaker 1: we don't really know he did it.
Speaker 1: There's no proof.
Speaker 1: And there was definitely reasonable doubt.
Speaker 1: But he was found guilty because he was crazy.
Speaker 1: And, you know, the jury convicted him because he was a nut job and he didn't know when to keep his mouth shut.
Speaker 1: And then he's like, oh, by the way, the body's here.
Speaker 1: So it's like, oh, you did do it.
Speaker 1: Genius.
Speaker 0: So this is that times a little bit.
Speaker 1: How could it be times a little bit?
Speaker 1: OK, I was like, how could it be more than that?
Speaker 0: It's on a similar level of just you read the news and go, what?
Speaker 0: Is that a joke?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Oh, I guess it isn't.
Speaker 0: So the spam king, Edward Eddy Davidson.
Speaker 1: I never heard him, but I've heard of many spam kings.
Speaker 1: Many people have been called this guy was the spam king.
Speaker 0: There were articles about him forever.
Speaker 0: He finally went to jail in April for spamming.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: I thought they just finally did jail for having them read the news.
Speaker 1: There's that can spam act, but it's so it's so weak.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: This guy was the spam king.
Speaker 0: He was known as the spam king, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 0: He was sent to jail.
Speaker 0: Now, when I say jail, basically he was sent to the most minimum security facility there is.
Speaker 1: So it was this like the lock up in the police station.
Speaker 1: or was this actually a county jail or prison, not jail?
Speaker 0: Oh, so he was sent to a federal prison camp, a federal prison, which, yes, it was a federal law.
Speaker 0: Federal prison camps are basically take cool hand Luke without the psychological torture, without the dying and without the hard labor.
Speaker 0: It's basically summer camp.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Man, I should become the spam king.
Speaker 0: They make you do menial work for nearby prisons that are more security.
Speaker 1: Like what kind of menial work do you do?
Speaker 0: Like, you know, I don't know.
Speaker 0: But basically it's like summer camp.
Speaker 0: There's almost no guards.
Speaker 0: And he was only supposed to be there for like twenty one months.
Speaker 1: Twenty one months is a long time, but it's not longer than I was in the middle of nowhere, which is basically the same thing.
Speaker 0: They also made him give up all the gold coins that he bought to hide his money.
Speaker 0: They didn't pay a seven hundred and fourteen thousand dollar restitution to the IRS.
Speaker 1: Here's a funny side story, right?
Speaker 1: I was talking with a coworker like a week or two ago.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And he mentioned, you know, I was talking about PayPal and some other stuff and a guy getting screwed on eBay and whatnot.
Speaker 1: And he's like, yeah, once I paid for something with e-gold and e-gold as a Web site, e-gold is a Web site that's sort of like PayPal.
Speaker 1: But the way it works is you give them money, then they give you you know, they that they have gold.
Speaker 1: They actually have gold that is represented by your money.
Speaker 0: Well, and then they give you a picture of your goal.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then they give you know, I guess they don't physically do it.
Speaker 1: But, you know, financially speaking, you're buying gold.
Speaker 1: Then there by giving them cash, then they transfer the ownership of that gold to someone else who then can turn it into cash if they want to.
Speaker 1: So you are basically buying something with gold, which is really good for the person on the other end of the line who wants to be paid in gold rather than paid in whatever currency you happen to use.
Speaker 1: Of course, recently, this is funny because he talked about using e-gold years and years ago and I'd never heard of it before.
Speaker 1: But just like a few days ago, there was a story on the Internet's e-gold mad money laundering going on.
Speaker 1: Ah, big surprise.
Speaker 1: Big surprise is money laundering with the with the gold transactions.
Speaker 0: I heard something else.
Speaker 0: So Penn Jillette was walking around and so he said something that offended someone.
Speaker 1: Guess I would never would have thought that these instant gold transfers a lot of PayPal type set up our money laundering heaven.
Speaker 0: So the spam king, his wife, visited him in prison.
Speaker 1: She's allowed to do and he didn't do the visiting with the wall on the phone.
Speaker 0: that much time left to go.
Speaker 0: Well, it's minimum security.
Speaker 1: So I got to access the park bench out in the grass, something like that.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: The fence around it.
Speaker 0: So he forces her to take him back to the car and he totally escapes.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 0: Thus turning his 21 month prison sentence into, well, you're fucked now.
Speaker 0: So he gets away.
Speaker 0: He escapes from the federal prison.
Speaker 0: He's at large.
Speaker 1: All he did was walk to a car, get in and drive real fast.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: They didn't chase him?
Speaker 0: He went home to his house, apparently got a change of clothes and then booked.
Speaker 1: How did they not go to?
Speaker 1: why did they go to his house and wait for him there?
Speaker 0: Because they did because he went right away.
Speaker 0: It's like he went straight to his house and got away.
Speaker 1: He must have lived really close.
Speaker 0: Well, they couldn't drive there faster and they didn't know.
Speaker 0: he broke out right away.
Speaker 0: But, quote, he jumped in the car with his wife.
Speaker 0: They when they were leaving, he forced her into the car, brought them home and left after a change of clothes.
Speaker 0: He is still at large.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Well, you see, now his options are pretty rough because it's like he's got to get a hide somewhere, which, you know, too many places to hide, considering he had gold coins and all this money.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there was more money hidden.
Speaker 0: I'm sure he retrieved that money, perhaps, perhaps.
Speaker 1: But I mean, it can't really cross a border to get away.
Speaker 0: Yes, it can.
Speaker 0: Depends if he makes it to the Mexican border, the Canadian border, you can totally just go over.
Speaker 1: Where is he going to go over where there aren't people guarding?
Speaker 0: You ever been to the Canadian border?
Speaker 0: There are a lot of places where you can just walk across.
Speaker 0: There's no roads, no nothing.
Speaker 1: Same with Mexico.
Speaker 1: All right, so now he's in Canada.
Speaker 1: What's he going to do in Canada?
Speaker 0: Use his money, find some mafia, get a fake name, live a life of luxury.
Speaker 0: Possible, possible, but it's still difficult.
Speaker 0: So, so, so, so, so.
Speaker 0: So what do you think happened?
Speaker 0: Because actually there was a fairly speedy update.
Speaker 0: In fact, it was a recent update.
Speaker 0: I read this immediately on FARC because I was home, I was working on stuff.
Speaker 0: Scott wasn't home, so we're not doing the show.
Speaker 0: I see news that I did not believe.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So, uh, what can possibly be?
Speaker 0: AK the spam king who reportedly forced his wife to help him escape from a Colorado prison on Sunday has killed himself, a woman and a toddler.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Earlier Tuesday, Colorado affiliate, nine blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 0: News reported that three people have been found dead at an apparent murder suicide in the area.
Speaker 0: He didn't live at this house apparently, but as far as they can tell, he shot himself and his wife and a toddler, but there was another child in the car who he did not shoot in his fine.
Speaker 0: He also shot a young girl who survived and was being questioned by police at the time of this press release.
Speaker 1: Wait, it's the same guy.
Speaker 1: So he escaped from prison to kill people.
Speaker 0: And then he disappeared for a while and they found him and a bunch of people dead and it looks like he shot them and himself.
Speaker 1: He was prob of my guess based on common sense.
Speaker 1: I have my own guess.
Speaker 1: My guess is that he was somehow, you know, trying to, you know, hide in these people's house or forcing them to help him hide or something like that.
Speaker 1: And of course it didn't turn out well and he gave up.
Speaker 0: Well, my belief is that the wife or someone is trying to talk him down with, look, you didn't have that long to go at summer camp.
Speaker 0: Now you're going to go to a real jail and it's going to suck and you're going to be there forever.
Speaker 1: If you get caught.
Speaker 1: I mean, if he was, he wasn't caught yet until he did the killing.
Speaker 0: But my imagination is you didn't think you clever plan through.
Speaker 0: You're going to get caught if you turn yourself in now and just let us go.
Speaker 0: This is probably going to be OK.
Speaker 1: Here's a here's a here's another guess.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: OK, so he's out.
Speaker 1: And they haven't.
Speaker 1: they're not on his tail at all.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They can't really find him because he had a good job of hiding.
Speaker 1: But he's real paranoid now.
Speaker 1: Super paranoid.
Speaker 1: So he's like, you know, forcing the people, his wife and the other people near to him, you know, to like not do anything and such and such.
Speaker 1: And making life generally miserable and the paranoia of, you know, be watching out and not doing anything because it might get you caught and not knowing what will get you caught.
Speaker 1: And such and such eventually drives him nuts over the days.
Speaker 1: And then he's nuts.
Speaker 1: And then, of course, killing people.
Speaker 0: There are reports that he was kind of paranoid and weird before all this.
Speaker 0: But I think that what the final straw was probably as his wife is saying and explaining all this, he realizes, oh, wait, I totally fucked up.
Speaker 0: And then he panics and just goes crazy and then possible quote when deputies arrived on the scene.
Speaker 0: It is kind of.
Speaker 0: it is actually really sad what happened.
Speaker 0: We thought we did find an adult male deceased by the driver's door of a silver SUV.
Speaker 0: We did find a female adult deceased by the passenger door of the SUV.
Speaker 0: And we did find a seven to eight month old little boy in the backseat who appeared to be uninjured, but was transported by rescue personnel as precaution.
Speaker 1: Where are these their kids?
Speaker 1: Where these kids come from?
Speaker 0: Unfortunately, inside the car was also found a little girl who we believe was about three years old and she was deceased.
Speaker 0: We did find another victim who was shot and who managed to run to a neighbor's house.
Speaker 0: She's a teenage girl transported with a gunshot wound, but she was coherent and talking to rescue personnel.
Speaker 0: Davidson had served less than two months of his 21 month prison sentence when he escaped.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: So whose children were these?
Speaker 0: No one knows.
Speaker 0: This is a developing story.
Speaker 1: No one knows who the children's parents were.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So the police show up.
Speaker 0: All these people are dead just a little while ago.
Speaker 0: What the shit?
Speaker 1: Hey, kid, who's your mom?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: And they don't tell reporters right away.
Speaker 0: So I'm not going to do the play by play or wait for updates.
Speaker 0: But this got this went kind of crazy out of control in a hurry.
Speaker 1: That is pretty crazy.
Speaker 1: I mean, if he escaped from prison, something is not easy to do.
Speaker 0: Even the minimum security prison, even cool hand Luke when they caught him.
Speaker 0: I mean, they caught him and they brought him back and they roughed him up a little bit.
Speaker 0: But that's all that happened.
Speaker 0: Even go crazy and kill anyone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 0: Cool.
Speaker 0: And Luke was awesome.
Speaker 1: He was cool.
Speaker 1: This guy.
Speaker 1: Not cool.
Speaker 1: This guy's this guy was not.
Speaker 1: is the guy was not cool hand.
Speaker 1: This guy was spam king.
Speaker 0: Gots to be cool.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you're the king of such bad tasting meat, I mean, that's a bad thing to be a king of.
Speaker 1: I'd rather I'd rather be a spam popper than a spam game.
Speaker 0: Spam.
Speaker 0: Don't dare conflate spam.
Speaker 0: The meat with spam.
Speaker 0: The spam.
Speaker 1: They both suck equally.
Speaker 0: Spam.
Speaker 0: The meat is mighty tasty.
Speaker 1: First of all, it's not meat.
Speaker 1: Second of all, it's not tasty.
Speaker 1: Basically, you were false on two counts.
Speaker 0: You realize spam is just cured ham.
Speaker 1: It's not ham.
Speaker 1: It's fake.
Speaker 0: It's just cured ham.
Speaker 1: No, it's artificial ham imitation.
Speaker 0: What is it, Scott?
Speaker 0: I suggest you go to Wikipedia and look up what spam is.
Speaker 1: Imitation ham.
Speaker 0: I'm going to read an excerpt here.
Speaker 0: Spam, spam, spam, spam, spam, spam, spam, spam, spam, spam, spam, spam.
Speaker 0: Wikipedia's, ah, God, there's a million articles.
Speaker 1: What about the spam king?
Speaker 0: I, Scott, quote, "Spam luncheon meat is a canned, pre-cooked meat product made by the Hormel Foods
Speaker 0: Corporation.".
Speaker 1: Yeah?
Speaker 0: It is meat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe technically it's meat, but it is not real meat.
Speaker 0: What do you define real?
Speaker 0: That's a no true Scotsman argument.
Speaker 1: No, I mean, it could be rats.
Speaker 1: That's meat.
Speaker 0: Yes, it is meat.
Speaker 0: But you can't say it's not meat.
Speaker 1: It is not.
Speaker 1: It is and it isn't.
Speaker 0: No, it is.
Speaker 0: What is the definition of meat, Scott?
Speaker 0: Don't pull this no true Scotsman bullshit with me.
Speaker 0: You call everyone on no true Scotsman.
Speaker 0: You're not going to get away with that bullshit now.
Speaker 1: Well, you see, the problem is there's multiple definitions of meat, you see.
Speaker 1: The one definition of meat is flesh of animal.
Speaker 1: That is the definition of meat.
Speaker 1: The other definition of meat is edible flesh of animal, you see.
Speaker 1: And it is definitely not edible.
Speaker 0: Spam is perfectly edible.
Speaker 1: You see, because there's two definitions of edible, you see.
Speaker 1: There's the definition of edible, which is able to be eaten without killing.
Speaker 1: And then there's the other definition of edible, which is good for eating.
Speaker 0: No, you see, what you're doing here, Scott, what you're doing is you're taking the no true Scotsman and you're hiding it behind pedantry.
Speaker 0: You're a pedantic.
Speaker 0: no true Scotsman.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: What's wrong with that?
Speaker 1: Alright, anyway.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's the same way that Checkers is a game.
Speaker 1: But on the other hand, it is not a game.
Speaker 0: Yes, it is.
Speaker 0: It's a good game, in fact.
Speaker 1: Not that good.
Speaker 1: Well, Checkers is maybe a bad example.
Speaker 1: Perhaps Final Fantasy is a game, but it is not a game.
Speaker 0: No, it's very clearly a game.
Speaker 1: Well, it is a game by the definition of a, you know, a thing that you do to entertain yourself.
Speaker 1: As though it's a good game, but it is not a, you know, test of skills.
Speaker 1: It is a test of patience.
Speaker 0: Anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: So check this out.
Speaker 1: Back in Rochester, you know, where we went to school, is the place of Kodak.
Speaker 1: And, you know, it's Eastman Kodak, so there's a place called the George Eastman House.
Speaker 1: And they have, of course, many old films and photos and things, and it's sort of a museum type of place.
Speaker 1: I could say more about it, but you can find out enough on the internets.
Speaker 1: But what they did is they took a bunch of their wicked old photos.
Speaker 1: Like we're talking 19 oh something like early 20th century photography and they've put it on the flicker.
Speaker 1: You can go check it out.
Speaker 1: And I'm looking through it and I'm like, wow, that's cool.
Speaker 1: Wow, that's cool.
Speaker 1: That's cool.
Speaker 1: But then like, hey, that's a famous photo.
Speaker 1: I've seen that before.
Speaker 1: And then now that's cool.
Speaker 1: That's cool.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's another famous photo I've seen before.
Speaker 1: And they're all on the flicker and really high quality.
Speaker 1: Looking at it in many ways, I realized that, you know, even though things nowadays are way better than things were in the early 20th century, there were a few things here and there they had better than we have now.
Speaker 1: Oh, for example, they had houses on trains.
Speaker 1: We didn't have.
Speaker 1: we don't have houses on trains anymore.
Speaker 0: Let's because trains don't go everywhere.
Speaker 0: Instead, Scott, we have Winnebagos.
Speaker 0: We have houses on roads.
Speaker 1: They had blimps.
Speaker 1: We don't know.
Speaker 0: We're coming back, actually, in a big way.
Speaker 1: We don't have blimps, though.
Speaker 1: We have.
Speaker 1: we have the MetLife blimp, which doesn't count.
Speaker 0: Actually, cargo blimps are coming back in a big way.
Speaker 1: We'll see about that.
Speaker 1: I still haven't seen one.
Speaker 1: I'll believe it when I see one flying over the house.
Speaker 1: You know, I've seen a picture on the Internet does not count.
Speaker 0: I got more than just that.
Speaker 0: But anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So it's it's pretty cool checking this shit out.
Speaker 1: And, you know, if you've got, you know, 20 minutes, click and look at old photos and you can see what the world looked like in, you know, the early 20th century, over 100 years ago.
Speaker 0: So in 1985, at the Grammy Awards, a confluence of awesome occurred.
Speaker 0: You know, every now and then, like a bunch of really awesome people get together and do something.
Speaker 0: And then that sort of thing is kind of rare.
Speaker 0: Like be like if I don't know, lead singer from the best band in the world and the best writer from the best band.
Speaker 0: It's like the all star game of music.
Speaker 1: The thing is, a lot of times they do that at the Grammy Awards.
Speaker 1: It's like, hey, we'll take two famous people, put them on stage at the same time.
Speaker 1: But then they'll be like a lip sync thing.
Speaker 1: And it's all sort of scripted and blend.
Speaker 1: It's not really as awesome as if they actually rocked out together.
Speaker 1: You know, the Grammys is sort of like it's got that the tone of an award show event.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have the tone of like the arena concert of all time.
Speaker 1: Let's get it on.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, it really depends.
Speaker 0: But this one is pretty cool.
Speaker 0: This is 1985, a musical act at the Grammy Awards.
Speaker 0: And the one thing I want to point out is that 1985 was the year when Cyndi Lauper was still pop.
Speaker 1: Well, I was three years old.
Speaker 0: I think she was just becoming popular.
Speaker 1: You know who I'm talking to, old man.
Speaker 0: The thing is, I actually was a big fan of Cyndi Lauper when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: I didn't know who it was.
Speaker 1: She sang the Goonies song.
Speaker 0: Good enough for you, good enough, it's good enough.
Speaker 1: I don't know who it is still.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: The Goonies song.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so they got Thomas Dolby.
Speaker 1: I don't know who that is.
Speaker 1: Is he the guy from Dolby Digital?
Speaker 0: No, in fact, he was sued by Dolby Digital for using the name Dolby.
Speaker 1: But is that his real name?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Oh, OK.
Speaker 1: So then they could sue him.
Speaker 0: Herbie Hancock.
Speaker 1: Howard Jones.
Speaker 1: I kind of know who that is.
Speaker 0: Get the hell off my show.
Speaker 0: Howard Jones.
Speaker 1: Don't know who that is.
Speaker 0: And Stevie Wonder.
Speaker 1: I know who that is.
Speaker 0: And in 1985, synthesizers were not like they are today.
Speaker 0: So this is a key, taran, vocal, whatever, boxing.
Speaker 1: Stevie Wonder is the master of all synthesizers.
Speaker 0: Beyond that, Stevie Wonder, I think my favorite thing about him is the way he smiles when a crowd is cheering for him.
Speaker 0: He always kind of like rears up and then kind of jives back and forth with this big grin.
Speaker 0: I love Stevie Wonder.
Speaker 1: He's pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this video is pretty cool.
Speaker 0: And let me tell you, I love the sound of old synthesizers, even though a lot of people, they sound cheesy.
Speaker 1: It depends on how they're being used and such.
Speaker 0: Well, 80s synthesizers sound cheesy partly because of the way they were used.
Speaker 0: And as a result, when you hear the sounds they can make, the sounds are automatically associated with cheesiness.
Speaker 0: But I think they're pretty cool and I think this is pretty cool.
Speaker 1: I think it really depends with the 80s synthesizers.
Speaker 1: They can be cool or uncool.
Speaker 0: So what do you eat for dinner?
Speaker 1: Two chocolate chip cookies and some apple juice.
Speaker 0: Well, I had a bowl of ice cream and four Jamaican beef patty bites.
Speaker 1: Sesame stick.
Speaker 0: Oh, and a handful of sunflower seeds.
Speaker 1: Sesame bread stick.
Speaker 1: Oh, some prunes.
Speaker 1: I finished off the bag of prunes.
Speaker 0: When I came home, I cut up some smoked Gouda and had it with some Malbatos.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: That's not much of a dinner, really.
Speaker 1: I mean, how many food groups did I cover?
Speaker 1: Fruit, fruit and cookie.
Speaker 1: You forgot yellow.
Speaker 1: Oh, and bread.
Speaker 1: So fruit, fruit, cookie, bread.
Speaker 1: I didn't get any vegetable or meat or dairy.
Speaker 0: You're missing yellow and grape drink.
Speaker 1: I really need that meat food group.
Speaker 1: Well, I did have two tiny tacos today.
Speaker 1: That covered my meat, kinda.
Speaker 0: See, at least I have these four Jamaican beef patties that I cooked and the two ought to eat.
Speaker 0: So they're sitting on the desk next to the microphone right now.
Speaker 1: I'm not a fan of the Jamaican beef patties.
Speaker 0: I don't know why.
Speaker 0: They're pure delicious.
Speaker 1: Not really, no.
Speaker 0: Delicious in a flaky golden crust.
Speaker 1: Well, we tried to make those frozen nachos yesterday.
Speaker 0: That was terrible.
Speaker 1: Well, it wasn't terrible.
Speaker 1: It didn't taste bad.
Speaker 1: But what it was is the nachi, like the frozen nachi, I boiled them and scooped them out like it said to.
Speaker 1: And they're basically just like tasteless.
Speaker 1: Like it was just tasteless mush ball things.
Speaker 0: Here's what I don't get, right?
Speaker 0: So it seems like a lot of Americans eat.
Speaker 0: Like I see so much frozen food and I see people buying so much of it.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, it's really, really convenient.
Speaker 1: Just, you know, take some food, heat it up, eat it.
Speaker 1: It doesn't take very long.
Speaker 1: You don't have to do a lot of work.
Speaker 1: You don't make a big mess.
Speaker 0: One, it takes longer than ramen.
Speaker 1: It does take longer.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, we should eat ramen instead.
Speaker 0: We ate it all.
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 0: All that's left is the... You should have bought more.
Speaker 0: I know, but I didn't.
Speaker 1: Just like I should have bought index cards for our panel.
Speaker 0: All that's left is the emergency ramen.
Speaker 1: Is it?
Speaker 1: What kind of emergency ramen is it?
Speaker 1: Well, which flavor?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Chicken?
Speaker 1: That's OK.
Speaker 1: Ish.
Speaker 0: At least it's not maruchan.
Speaker 1: It's not the ichiban, though, so it's...
Speaker 0: Yeah, or the fancy ones.
Speaker 0: But I lost my train of thought, which is kind of awesome.
Speaker 0: All right, so the frozen food, right?
Speaker 0: Every time I think, "Oh, let's try one of those frozen meals or frozen dinners,".
Speaker 0: they're so awful that they're not worth the convenience.
Speaker 0: I would rather eat nothing or eat garbage than eat those things.
Speaker 0: They're so tasteless.
Speaker 1: Not everything in the frozen aisle is bad.
Speaker 1: For example, you can get the frozen, like, ora-eyed potato things, especially, like, the onion tater tots.
Speaker 1: Those are good.
Speaker 1: You can also get -- what's the other brand?
Speaker 1: The Alexa potato wedges.
Speaker 1: Those are good, too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Jamaican beef patties.
Speaker 1: It's mostly frozen potato chip or French fry type things, tater tots, that sort of stuff.
Speaker 1: Those are good.
Speaker 1: Also, a few frozen pizzas are good.
Speaker 1: Most of them are bad, but some are good, like those two Leonard's ones.
Speaker 1: I like me an Eggo waffle, but Rym does not.
Speaker 1: But you could make a good frozen waffle.
Speaker 0: See, I guess what I don't get is that in the time it takes to deal with one of those frozen meals.
Speaker 0: that tastes like crap, you could make any kind of egg meal, like, any kind of combination of eggs and butter on a pan.
Speaker 1: Yep, you could definitely make an omelet.
Speaker 1: An omelet is just as easy as any, you know, frozen dinner.
Speaker 1: The thing is, Rym, is that we don't realize we don't have the microwave.
Speaker 1: If we had the microwave, then a lot more of those meals would be available to us.
Speaker 1: Have you eaten?
Speaker 1: And it would be a lot more convenient.
Speaker 1: But they're as disgusting, if not more disgusting.
Speaker 0: Usually more disgusting.
Speaker 1: Yes, but the convenience level would be there over the omelet that you currently don't have.
Speaker 0: The thing is, though, it's just as convenient.
Speaker 0: It takes you five minutes to make an omelet, from start to finish, unless you're incompetent.
Speaker 1: But it's like you gotta chop the stuff up, and you gotta...
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: A microwave dinner, you put it in the microwave, you push a button.
Speaker 0: Scrambled eggs require nothing.
Speaker 1: You gotta scramble, you gotta pour it into the thing, and you gotta move the spatula around.
Speaker 1: With the microwave dinner, you put it in the thing, you push a button, that's it, you're done.
Speaker 0: The thing is, the scrambled eggs taste a thousand times better.
Speaker 1: They sure do.
Speaker 1: The only problem with... No, they taste infinity.
Speaker 1: Well, they taste an imaginary number better, because what happens is the TV dinner has a negative taste.
Speaker 1: So if you were to divide the flavor rating, which is a very large positive number of the scrambled egg, by the negative number of the flavor of the TV dinner, you will get an imaginary number.
Speaker 0: I guess this is kind of, in our eyes, an indictment of the people who eat these frozen dinners on a regular basis, because they're so bad that I would rather not eat dinner than eat them.
Speaker 0: And the fact that there's so many of them, and I see people buying them all the time, we wonder why people are fat in this country if you're that lazy.
Speaker 1: Well, it's because they go for the fast food, not for the TV.
Speaker 1: The TV dinner helps, but it's mostly the McDonald's.
Speaker 1: But, I mean, there are dinners you can get in a can that are better than the ones that are frozen.
Speaker 1: I mean, even like Campbell's soup, it's all right.
Speaker 1: It's not, you know, great, but it's okay.
Speaker 1: Ramen, it's not great, but it's okay.
Speaker 1: And you can get good ramen, too, for like a few dollars instead of a ten-cent ramen.
Speaker 0: The thing is, I remember back to college thinking, you know, the quick meals.
Speaker 0: Pretty much, what did we eat?
Speaker 0: We made ramen?
Speaker 1: We didn't get a can of chili in it.
Speaker 1: Not too bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course, chili is also super easy to make.
Speaker 1: You can also get like a pre-prepared salad and then put salad dressing on it, and you're good to go.
Speaker 1: That's awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, our problem is we've been living our college lifestyle again where we basically don't cook a real dinner and then it's late and we're hungry.
Speaker 0: So we eat something convenient and go to sleep.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I really, see, this is why I'm really torn about this.
Speaker 1: Ideally, what I should be doing with my current, you know, life schedule is eating a humongous lunch and then not eating so much for dinner, but it won't matter because I got my nutrition at lunch.
Speaker 1: The thing is, I really don't want to spend money for a big awesome lunch because I save money by making my peanut butter and jelly.
Speaker 1: And I'm torn between.
Speaker 1: should I continue this trend of not getting proper nutrition and not eating a good enough dinner?
Speaker 1: or even if I do eat enough good, good enough dinner, it's right before I go to bed, which is really not so great.
Speaker 1: Eating a whole bunch of food, they go to bed immediately instead of using the food.
Speaker 1: Or should I break the bank and get proper nutrition and just go out and eat awesome lunches every day?
Speaker 0: Maybe it's just a factor of making a lot more money and the amount I care about money is getting really not cool because I'm spending money left and right.
Speaker 0: But I've got to the point where I will pretty much eat, at least on the days we do the show, a full dinner at lunch and then a light dinner when I get home.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's what I could do, is on the days when we're doing a show, I will go out and get an awesome lunch, but on the days when we're not doing a show, I'll just eat my peanut butter and jelly, still save some monies, and then we'll have to cook, though.
Speaker 0: Maybe because I'm running every day and all this stuff now, literally, I could eat a double cheeseburger, a real one.
Speaker 0: I'll go to Good Burger.
Speaker 0: I'll eat a double cheeseburger, onion rings, fries, and a root beer float.
Speaker 1: Even in high school, I could never eat a double cheeseburger.
Speaker 1: I would eat a single hamburger.
Speaker 0: The thing is, a double cheeseburger at the Good Burger isn't like a McDonald's with all the... It's basically two entire hamburgers, like real ones.
Speaker 1: That's the thing, for some reason I can eat two hamburgers separate, but the double hamburger, where it's two meats on the same bun, that's just inedible for some reason.
Speaker 0: A few days ago, I was like, "All right, I'm really hungry because I've been running and all this, and I'm going to run when I get home, so I'm going to eat a big
Speaker 0: lunch.".
Speaker 0: First, for breakfast, I had a sausage, egg, and cheese on a bagel, and an orange juice, and a Red Bull, and all that business.
Speaker 1: Actually, I was sort of helping out by eating breakfast again, but we ran out of English muffins, and that was my go-to breakfast.
Speaker 0: I buy my breakfast every day.
Speaker 0: Sausage, egg, and cheese, with a Red Bull and orange juice for breakfast.
Speaker 1: That's great.
Speaker 0: Then, for lunch, I went to the Good Burger, and I got a double cheeseburger, onion rings, and a root beer float.
Speaker 1: And a Red Bull.
Speaker 0: No, only one Red Bull.
Speaker 0: I figured I'd be good between the two, but then I was still hungry.
Speaker 0: Crazy hungry, all day, despite I was full when I ate that.
Speaker 0: Then a few hours later, I was hungry again.
Speaker 0: I went out, got some Beard Pappas, and I ate those.
Speaker 0: Then I was hungry again immediately after.
Speaker 0: So I came home, and I made a big dinner, and I ate it.
Speaker 0: And then I went out running, and I did all my stuff, and then Scott came home, and we watched something.
Speaker 0: And I was still hungry, so I made a fried egg before I went to bed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just that I'm getting home just an hour later, which is still enough time to do the show, and it's not too bad, really.
Speaker 1: But it's sort of that hour was the hour we used to cook dinner.
Speaker 1: And now it's like, get home, we do the show.
Speaker 1: By the time the show is over, it's nine o'clock.
Speaker 1: I'm going to eat dinner at nine o'clock.
Speaker 1: That's already crazy.
Speaker 1: I mean, I get home at like seven something.
Speaker 1: I'd like to eat dinner at five, six.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't want to eat dinner at seven.
Speaker 1: It's really, it's not good at all.
Speaker 1: It's like the time when dinner should be eaten is the time when I'm on the train.
Speaker 1: And it's unpleasant, to say the least.
Speaker 0: So at least, I mean, on the days we don't do the show.
Speaker 1: And that's the time I want to be eating dinner.
Speaker 1: So the time when I should be cooking dinner is like the last hour I'm at work.
Speaker 0: See, the way I do it, at least on the days we don't do the show, I usually come home and I make a dinner that'll be ready right around when Scott and Emily get home.
Speaker 0: And that works pretty well, but I can't make dinner all the time.
Speaker 1: Before I was coming home late and, you know, I was actually making dinner like once or twice a week.
Speaker 1: And, you know, I'd make chicken once or twice a week of different varieties and things.
Speaker 1: And I haven't cooked anything in like a couple months and I feel bad about it, but I can't really do anything about it either.
Speaker 0: Of course, part of this is we're starting to realize more and more that it almost seems like America, at least outside of like outside of the major cities, outside of major cities, outside of college towns, you know, normal suburban United States, the average town.
Speaker 0: It's like there is no way for someone, people like us who are not members of nuclear families and who have jobs to do most of the things that normal people in society are expected to do.
Speaker 1: I mean, the society is really structured in a way to where without a nuclear family kind of situation, things are very can be very inconvenient.
Speaker 1: For example, if you had a nuclear family, right, one person goes to work, one person stays home, or maybe one person, you know, even if they commute far away, the other person might work locally, you know, in town somewhere or if they work from home or something.
Speaker 1: So if a package comes, the person is home to get someone is home to get the package, or you make so much money, you have like, you know, a nanny or a house cleaner, someone to be home and get the package.
Speaker 1: If you want to go eat out, you're home early enough and you can just go somewhere nearby to eat out.
Speaker 1: If, you know, your whole house is full of commuters to get home at seven, everything closes.
Speaker 0: Well, no, no, that's the thing at least.
Speaker 0: All the restaurants are open.
Speaker 0: We can just go to a restaurant and eat out and it's great.
Speaker 0: The problem is that does get very expensive eating out at real restaurants every single night.
Speaker 1: It also makes you very fat very quickly.
Speaker 0: Not if you're active.
Speaker 1: No, but I mean, you got to, you know, eating out at restaurants too much is not so good.
Speaker 1: You definitely want to be eating in.
Speaker 1: the food you cook in your house is far better in terms of your health.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then go back to college where I cooked most of my meals, but most of my meals consisted of two to four eggs.
Speaker 1: Most of my meals were like a hot dog on a plate.
Speaker 0: I remember we'd have dinners where literally like both our plates would have like some scrambled eggs, some cooked hot dogs and like some bread to use as buns.
Speaker 1: That's the thing.
Speaker 1: It's like I had the best intentions.
Speaker 1: When we got to RIT, I brought my parents' old kitchen table.
Speaker 1: I cooked like a big spaghetti and meatball dinner for everyone.
Speaker 1: We all, you know, grouped up and, you know, then someone tried to cook a stir fry.
Speaker 1: And then that lasted maybe a couple of weeks.
Speaker 1: And before you knew it, we put the kitchen table out, you know, side saying, take this, it's free, because he was just taking up space and we weren't using it.
Speaker 1: And the communal cooking real dinners thing totally didn't happen anymore.
Speaker 1: And it was game over, you know, and Emily, when she got out of college and started living in Beacon, you know, I saw my past self in her because she was like, you know, let's cook dinner every night.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, yeah, that's what I thought.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, she was like, oh, this sucks.
Speaker 1: She was complaining because it wasn't happening.
Speaker 1: And then she was just like, yeah, I see why it doesn't happen.
Speaker 0: And it totally sucks.
Speaker 0: The thing is, though, she's been having a renaissance of cooking dinner lately.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, the key, the only problem here is that we were doing OK, actually, like before Scott started coming home late, we actually cooked dinner like most five, five nights a week.
Speaker 1: At least at least three nights a week, at least three, usually a good four or five nights a week.
Speaker 0: And we would cook a real.
Speaker 1: not all of those meals might have been awesome, but they were OK enough.
Speaker 1: They were better than hot dog on a plate.
Speaker 0: The thing is, Emily is a lot better than us at improvising with, you know, just whatever's laying around.
Speaker 0: She made like collard greens and rice and some eggs and some naan.
Speaker 0: It was super good last night.
Speaker 1: Of course, I don't like the collard greens, but I love collard greens.
Speaker 1: I'm not a fan.
Speaker 0: But it was great because she's like, I'm going to go dinner.
Speaker 0: It's like, awesome, because I was basically going to eat the emergency ramen and go to sleep otherwise.
Speaker 0: So she kind of saved me there.
Speaker 0: But yeah, basically, Scott, you know what it really boils down to is you get home late and that fucks everything up.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll do something about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: At least we can get through Con season first.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: If we see I realize, you know, it would solve everything if we formed a studio.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: And lived as a company.
Speaker 1: If we had a personal chef, we just pay them to come to the house around, you know, five, six o'clock every day, cook a dinner.
Speaker 1: And they didn't even have to stick around.
Speaker 1: They just could leave it in the fridge or something and, you know, or just keep it hot somewhere where we can just come home and eat it.
Speaker 0: Well, the other thing we could do is I could cook more because I was doing this for a while where I'd cook like Swiss steaks or like a little like a mini pot roast or like chili or a bean soup.
Speaker 0: Things that I can start like I get home from work, I put it all together or a casserole and I set it cooking and then around seven it's done and then we eat it.
Speaker 0: And then I save the other half of it and just reheat it the next day.
Speaker 1: There is one.
Speaker 1: There's a guy I work.
Speaker 0: The only reason I'm not doing that is Con season.
Speaker 0: We're busy doing stuff like every day now.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There's a guy I work with and he still lives with his parents in Jersey.
Speaker 1: But, you know, he's got they they they all work.
Speaker 1: You know, they're like he has a twin sister who's also working and his parents are working.
Speaker 1: So there's like there's no one in the house, but, you know, they got to eat dinner.
Speaker 1: So what they do is actually on the weekend, they cook like four or five dinners and then they set them all up in the refrigerator, you know, and then they reheat them throughout the week for dinner.
Speaker 1: So, you know, one person, someone comes home at eleven and someone else comes home at six and someone else comes home at one a.m.
Speaker 1: because they went out partying.
Speaker 1: There's something to eat.
Speaker 1: They can, you know, reheat their portion, a portion of one of the meals.
Speaker 1: And, you know, by the end of the week, all the meals are out.
Speaker 1: Then they go out to eat.
Speaker 1: And then on Sunday they cook, you know, five more meals.
Speaker 1: And we could do that, except we use our Sundays because we don't get enough time off work.
Speaker 1: We need that to do stuff like our geeky endeavors.
Speaker 1: They're not so much of the geeky endeavors while they're cooking their meals Sunday.
Speaker 1: You know, they're just watching a football or something.
Speaker 1: We can't do that while we're playing a video game or remember the days when we had this house.
Speaker 0: We were not podcasters.
Speaker 0: We were just geeks out of college.
Speaker 1: And we watched Netflix every single day.
Speaker 1: And every weekend we drove up the road to play DDR.
Speaker 0: Of course, the thing is, back then, not only were we not podcasting, no one else lived around, so there was no one else to hang out with.
Speaker 0: And, like, Scott got out of work earlier and I worked at IBM.
Speaker 1: I was working in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so he could leave whenever he wanted.
Speaker 1: Actually, for a while I was working in the city and then the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 0: I worked five minutes away from our house at IBM so I could leave whenever I wanted and go in whenever I wanted.
Speaker 0: So, I mean, I would come home for lunch half the time because it was right here.
Speaker 0: So we'd come home from work at, like, five.
Speaker 0: We'd be home.
Speaker 0: We'd watch, like, a Netflix and then a couple episodes of The Simpsons.
Speaker 0: And then we'd play a board game and then we'd play video games, like, until late.
Speaker 1: And then it'd be like, "What do we do
Speaker 1: now?"
Speaker 1: And he'd be sitting around going, "I don't know what to
Speaker 1: do.".
Speaker 1: And then we'd talk for an hour, which would have been a podcast if we had recorded it, but we just talked.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: And then we'd, like, cook a full dinner and then go to bed.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: Too bad we do a podcast.
Speaker 1: Too bad.
Speaker 1: Well, even if we didn't do the podcast, we'd still be screwed in the current situation.
Speaker 1: So at least we're making something, you know, and maybe one day someone will, you know, cook us dinner in exchange for podcasts.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should do that.
Speaker 1: Hey, guys, if you don't come, if someone doesn't come and cook us dinner five nights a week, podcast is over.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: So if you want this podcast to continue, you should come and move to Beacon and you will get paid ten dollars a day.
Speaker 1: So fifty bucks a week to cook dinners.
Speaker 0: Well, we could clear out the closet under the stairs, put a little bed in there.
Speaker 0: That could be it.
Speaker 0: If you cook us dinner five nights a week, you can live in that closet.
Speaker 1: I think that violates the rents.
Speaker 0: I'm fine with that.
Speaker 1: At least.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I think this Thursday is done.
Speaker 1: It's Thursday is indeed done, but the world sucks for single commuters.
Speaker 1: We were supposed to live in the city, but we don't.
Speaker 1: So it fucks us.
Speaker 0: But that's fine, because eventually we'll have our own front row crew studio and office space up here and the mansion on that land we're going to buy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you wish.
Speaker 0: It's coming.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 0: Actually called.
Speaker 0: It looks like that land has sewer.
Speaker 0: So I'm looking into buying it.
Speaker 1: We should go.
Speaker 1: We should walk over this weekend and, you know, poke it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll do all the poking.
Speaker 1: I got to take a look at the dirt.
Speaker 0: It's a good day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's how you know.
Speaker 1: If it's full of rocks, it's not good.
Speaker 0: All right, we're done.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com, where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week, covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com, or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says "Send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial Share-A-Like 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it, as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.