Speaker 1: It's Wednesday January night.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We review bone.
Speaker 0: Let's do this So this weekend if all goes according to plan and I have not put much planning into this yet.
Speaker 0: But but someone else has someone else names.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you have made the mistake of relying on others.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is sake we do not often.
Speaker 0: my really just didn't expect this day to come.
Speaker 1: But you see a lesson you should have learned.
Speaker 0: I have not skied in About a decade.
Speaker 1: I don't know if skied is a word.
Speaker 1: I think you're supposed to say guns have gone skiing.
Speaker 0: Well, no, I have not undertaken the.
Speaker 0: I've not gone skiing nor have I skied the verb ski.
Speaker 0: I have in fact not skied since I lived in Michigan.
Speaker 1: Have a water skiing.
Speaker 0: water skiing is not the same thing, but I'm saying it's still skiing.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I have not water skied either.
Speaker 1: Well, I ski do?
Speaker 0: I have not done that either.
Speaker 1: have a ski ball.
Speaker 0: I've played ski ball.
Speaker 1: Oh you skied.
Speaker 0: no because I would have ski balled.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I think those are all skiing.
Speaker 0: you need to be more specific as I have not skied in so long.
Speaker 0: but the other Scott when I said you know I'm Larry of suddenly going skiing again because I haven't skied in a been over a decade and He says as skis like riding a bike.
Speaker 0: He'll be fine Yeah, and I said, you know what you're right.
Speaker 0: and then I went and bought the stuff I needed to go skiing.
Speaker 0: and Then the funny thing is I went to buy the ski jacket and the guys like yeah, there's gonna be no snow in, Pennsylvania.
Speaker 0: What are you thinking?
Speaker 0: So, uh, I'm assured wherever we're going There's snow and we're gonna go skiing.
Speaker 0: and if I don't come back on Monday, you can assume that I'm in the hospital.
Speaker 1: Well, you know For having you know Even if you haven't gone skiing in a long time if there's gonna be just like shitty shitty crap snow Right and you go to some crap ass ski places.
Speaker 1: That's not so bad cuz it'll be cheaper.
Speaker 1: It'll be less crowded and You can get back into skiing and then save your money and your precious weekends for a high quality ski.
Speaker 1: Well the one sometime later after your skills have improved.
Speaker 0: Well, we had an alternate plan.
Speaker 0: if the skiing socks we can just sit in the lounge and drink all day.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: you can do that too, yeah But I think the one thing that might help me out is that I you know, I lived in Michigan.
Speaker 0: I skied on.
Speaker 0: almost all the skiing ever did was in Michigan and we don't get powder so much in Michigan.
Speaker 0: Not that the stuff you want to ski on.
Speaker 0: we basically get ice.
Speaker 0: So hopefully the fact that I've skied on nothing but the shittiest of snow my entire life Well, my entire skiing life will allow me to not die this weekend when I'm skiing on ice.
Speaker 1: See my 60-degree weather.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have the guaranteed not die plan.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it's called Scott's patented.
Speaker 0: I'm a wuss.
Speaker 1: It's called don't go skiing and instead do something else.
Speaker 1: like what skiing is sitting in front of the computer skiing Nice and safe when I comfortable Nice and warm - and I skied on a semi-regular basis.
Speaker 0: It was pretty much the best thing in the world.
Speaker 0: skiing is a fantastic sport.
Speaker 1: It's an okay sport.
Speaker 0: downhill skiing cross-country skiing is not as fun.
Speaker 1: It's not a bad sport, but at the same time it is far too dangerous for my taste.
Speaker 0: It's not dangerous unless you suck or don't learn how to do it right or are really weak.
Speaker 0: if you're really weak It's dangerous.
Speaker 1: more people have gotten hurt or killed skiing than racecar driving.
Speaker 0: So yeah But you got to look at the demographic.
Speaker 0: More people get hurt on the the black diamond who probably shouldn't be on the black diamond or falling off the ski lift because they Feel I'm not I have evidence of this, but I'm pretty sure like I've seen more Professional skiing people.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I guess it maybe it's kind of close have more professional skiing people gotten hurt or professional racecar driving people gotten hurt.
Speaker 0: You know, it's hard to say but I can say definitely that people a lot Recreationally get hurt a lot partly because a lot of them are really really stupid.
Speaker 0: I God, all right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's anime day and this this news kind of came out of nowhere Talking about any anime today.
Speaker 0: We're gonna talk about anime.
Speaker 0: All right, so a new type USA is a fairly venerable Publication in the u.s.
Speaker 0: It's I mean it began what when we went to Otacon the first or second time.
Speaker 1: second thing was 2002 I think late to the February.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's actually a relatively new anime publication.
Speaker 0: The thing is it is but I don't know maybe five years That's not that long.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's but it's no proto culture.
Speaker 0: But it was based on new type in Japan and I remember before new type USA was Released in the US in English.
Speaker 0: I was fascinated by new type.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Cuz I mean I didn't even you know the idea that there would be actually a magazine just about anime.
Speaker 1: something So obscure was.
Speaker 0: it was insane, you know, so no there were other magazines I was talking about more the point that if you don't understand Japanese and you open a new type I was gonna talk about that too.
Speaker 0: So it looks like it's the most fantastic thing ever.
Speaker 0: It's beautiful Just pictures and beautiful like yeah shots of every show into anime club.
Speaker 1: and they had new type magazines There's like what the hell is this and it's this huge magazine.
Speaker 1: Every page is printed with amazing quality with these amazing images of all these anime I've never seen or heard of and all this information about anime that I can't read.
Speaker 1: But I imagined that if I could read it it was giving me all this information I couldn't get anywhere else and it was amazing and I wanted to know.
Speaker 0: so new type was released in America in English as new type USA and it had.
Speaker 1: it had some articles by US people some articles that we just translated from the Japanese new type.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is I subscribed to it right away and I got the first one and it was great.
Speaker 0: and then I got okay I thought it was great.
Speaker 0: And then right about right before I got my first mailed one in the mail I I was reading it again and I realized that I hadn't actually read any words.
Speaker 0: I just flipped through it the same way I flipped through the Japanese one and I had this revelation of wait a minute.
Speaker 0: I can read all those words Oh, man.
Speaker 0: And I proceeded to discover that there was not a single word worth reading in new type USA.
Speaker 1: Well, the issues that I read which were like a handful of the earlier issues of new type USA some of the little tiny blurb kind of things in the back contains somewhat obscure kinds of information and Articles that you really wouldn't find anywhere else and that was somewhat interesting.
Speaker 0: But like those big shots of like a page with all the characters from an anime and then I'm like and four pages about this Anime that's coming out that text wasn't saying it.
Speaker 0: Yes the
Speaker 1: vast majority of it was completely useless and as soon as I you know Thanks to things like anime news network where I can find out about about all the upcoming shows New type USA really didn't have much of a use because I already knew most of the stuff that it was telling me.
Speaker 0: I unsubscribed Before the first issue.
Speaker 0: Unsubscribe Just didn't pay was gonna tell that story.
Speaker 0: I unsubscribed before the first one came because before the first one came the bill came.
Speaker 0: since being a college student I had checked bill me later and I decided well, I'm just now paying for new type.
Speaker 0: That's the end of this.
Speaker 0: and I stopped getting new type and I. there have been fewer more worthless publications.
Speaker 0: The new type USA.
Speaker 1: no, you know as you as bad as new type USA was as somewhat useless as it is.
Speaker 1: It is far from being the most useless magazine.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: soldier of fortune is wonderful.
Speaker 0: I mean, how else would I know how I can be a badass in like Zimbabwe?
Speaker 1: It's an okay magazine, but there are many worse magazines trust.
Speaker 0: Don't forget car and driver or a golf digest.
Speaker 1: Plenty of work anybody.
Speaker 0: this way new type USA Was was like the biggest for me scam ever because what like it's like it looked so great and then it turns out that those Words didn't say anything.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you're gonna tell the news about new type USA is fucking done.
Speaker 0: That's what the news is.
Speaker 0: It's done as of February now according to anime news network They're not sure if it's February or March because the details are scant.
Speaker 1: well Because what happens is every magazine in the United States is stupid and they ship like the March issue in February.
Speaker 1: And the you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: I never understood why the fuck they do that I'm printing the lead time for printing the lead time for distribution, but just change the month that's written on it.
Speaker 1: It's not hard.
Speaker 1: If you know, it's gonna ship in March right March on it, you know, which one is shipping in which month?
Speaker 0: Because the news in it is all from the previous month.
Speaker 0: That's to how publications work.
Speaker 1: So you just it.
Speaker 1: so instead of you know, pretending to act like you're actually having providing something useful and up-to-date You're just not even.
Speaker 1: you're just completely saying a fuck it.
Speaker 1: We know we're shit.
Speaker 1: We're super delayed news.
Speaker 1: That's a month late and completely useless.
Speaker 1: Let's just write the old month on there.
Speaker 0: I don't think that's a legitimate criticism.
Speaker 0: I think just a cranky weirdo Magazine that the month of the magazine comes up to new newsstands as opposed to when the stuff in the magazine is from.
Speaker 1: Actually, I think what most magazines write like the month after like.
Speaker 1: I think the March ships in February.
Speaker 1: I don't know it's it's stupid.
Speaker 0: It's stupid.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's stupid at all.
Speaker 1: I think it's stupid.
Speaker 1: So in February you want the March magazine to show up.
Speaker 0: I don't care I don't care what month it says.
Speaker 0: I read the magazine.
Speaker 1: I don't read any magazines cuz they're stupid.
Speaker 0: I don't care you're you hate everything.
Speaker 0: so but uh new type USA was worth hating and now it's gone and Theoretically, they're planning to replace it with something but they didn't say what see that that actually that's very telling.
Speaker 1: If ADV is getting rid of new type USA, right, but they plan on coming out with another magazine.
Speaker 1: Right that tells me that they actually Figured like, you know, their calculation is that they were making money off of it or they would make money off of it.
Speaker 1: But they were probably paying some license fee, you know for the new type name.
Speaker 1: And they are probably paying to get like a lot of new type content and images and stuff.
Speaker 1: and I think they're probably bargaining That if They get the same number of subscribers to their new magazine And they don't have to pay all those fees for the content and the licensing from new type Japan or whatever Getting any content from there.
Speaker 0: Anyway, they were they did not content.
Speaker 0: They were getting pictures.
Speaker 1: They were getting content.
Speaker 0: now I I would barely classify anything in new type is content.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, that's the question is that there was a lot of things in new type USA that were translated articles from new type Japan Articles in Japan either.
Speaker 0: what I don't get is why would anyone in Japan read new type?
Speaker 1: I don't know they're otaku.
Speaker 1: What do you want?
Speaker 0: but the really interesting thing and this is pointed out here on anime news network But no one knows what new type circulation was because like every stupid Industry thing in all of anime in the u.s.
Speaker 0: No one publishes any information.
Speaker 0: They keep everything secret.
Speaker 0: So people guess that new type had between 50,000 and 75,000 Subscribers, but no one knows and no anime magazine publishes Jack, so we can't really say anything beyond that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I really just don't understand these people keeping it a secret like oh people were know we're doing shidley or they'll know we're doing well, and it's like What do you care that if you're if you're doing shidley people knowing you're doing shidley isn't gonna hurt you.
Speaker 1: You're gonna do shidley no matter what.
Speaker 1: and if you're doing well You should brag about how well you're doing.
Speaker 1: is that you might do better.
Speaker 1: I Don't know.
Speaker 0: huh new type.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a picture of me in you and that's about all I can say about you.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right.
Speaker 1: So I know I was gonna do.
Speaker 1: I probably had a good news, but I didn't want to look for it.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna do a geek back.
Speaker 1: I've decided not geek bite big bite.
Speaker 0: Why do you keep saying geek bag?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's a better word.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I think you came up with geek bite.
Speaker 1: I came up with both of them.
Speaker 0: Well, you should have should have chosen better.
Speaker 1: Yes anyway I've decided that there usually aren't a lot of good news is on Wednesday and we usually just read anime news network because it's the Only website with anime news and there's a new type USA is going away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a good news, but there's only once and occasionally there's a you know an underwear pervert news from like newsarama.
Speaker 1: But that's it.
Speaker 1: So I'm doing more geek bites on Wednesdays because I read a lot of comics and things that you know Doesn't read.
Speaker 1: so I got.
Speaker 1: I got to get him out to you, right?
Speaker 1: So in my box of comics this month came this comic called wanton soup.
Speaker 1: You like wanton soup.
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 1: All right by James stoke away.
Speaker 1: I probably said his name wrong.
Speaker 1: st Okay, oh e it's an oni press which is the same people who publish Scott Pilgrim and the same format is Scott Pilgrim You know, it's a. it's a you know, little manga size digest deal, but it's printed left to right because it's you know American.
Speaker 1: It's not a manga.
Speaker 1: It's just a comic book like Scott Pilgrim.
Speaker 1: The artistic style it's pretty good arts.
Speaker 1: there's some you know, it's got manga style paneling and such.
Speaker 1: but the art style is sort of gorillas ish and like punk kids styling and It's not the greatest comic in the world.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna I'm not gonna lie, but it's just sort of fun and sort of happy.
Speaker 1: basically, the story is this guy named Johnny boyo, yeah great name and He's got a friend deacon vans and deacon vans loves the ladies and Johnny boyo loves cooking and they're truckers in space
Speaker 0: uh-huh,
Speaker 1: and basically, it turns into Johnny boyo goes back to his cooking school that he dropped out of to become a space trucker and It's all sort of like initial D but with cooking and but it's not you know that and alone I mean that's been done before.
Speaker 1: there's plenty of cooking animes and things, you know Ironwalk whatever and such like that, right?
Speaker 1: But because this is in space all of the things they cook are like completely made-up alien dishes and people are using like alien he like has to cook against aliens who have like, you know, two bodies and extra arms and legs and the.
Speaker 1: the tasting judge is a giant tongue and It's not really, you know amazing or anything, but it's just fun and I enjoyed it.
Speaker 1: so if you think you'd like that, this is a Cheap.
Speaker 1: it's 12 bucks From only press.
Speaker 1: it's probably in stores near you.
Speaker 1: wonton soup.
Speaker 0: Anyway things of the day now, uh, this was announced at CES and normally I talk about this on a Monday But I have to talk about this on a Wednesday because it does not bode Well for people who do not want to see certain things that anime conventions There has always been.
Speaker 0: kind of one of the holy grails of cell phones for people who are nuts about cell phones is What if my cell phone were also a projector and I just project video onto a surface?
Speaker 1: It's not something that's always been a holy grail But there have been many companies developing such technology and demonstrating it sort of like people have been making and demonstrating.
Speaker 1: You know flexible papers and things like that, you know It's one of those technologies that people are always showing off at trade shows and you know showing development versions of it and Stuff like that, but no one ever actually makes it happen for real.
Speaker 1: I'm real consumer products.
Speaker 1: It's just something always you see auditing on and gadget.
Speaker 1: you see pictures on the internet, but it never comes to life.
Speaker 0: now the situation here is that it exists and it pretty much works and Very rich people and people who really really care are gonna start having these things in the relatively near future.
Speaker 0: Now what is going to happen gonna give you a little look into the future is going to be the same thing that happened when?
Speaker 0: Laser pens came into existence.
Speaker 1: We're talking like two three years from now.
Speaker 0: I mean basically laser pens existed, but they were really really expensive and they were kind of useless.
Speaker 0: so fancy-pants professors and people who had way too much money and way too little sense own laser pens and They use them to impress people.
Speaker 0: when they gave you know presentations.
Speaker 1: They used them for science experiment.
Speaker 0: very few people because if you were doing a science experiment You probably just had a laser we used.
Speaker 1: well No, we used them in like middle school to do like, you know tests of like refraction and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Wow in middle school.
Speaker 0: We just had like argon lasers.
Speaker 1: Ah, we had laser pens.
Speaker 0: But anyway laser pens eventually got under $100 and once they were less than $100 and you could buy them in Radio Shack for like 70 80 bucks Every kid in the goddamn world had a laser pen.
Speaker 0: you would walk down the street and there'd be red dots everywhere.
Speaker 0: to be red Dots in people's living rooms because the kid across the street is shooting it from the roof.
Speaker 0: go to a movie theater There'd be 50 red dots on the face.
Speaker 0: It just it went nuts and if I like about a month or two eventually died down.
Speaker 1: the novelty ended but also the police Threats sort of made it die down.
Speaker 0: also I think the only reason it really ended was that people explored all of the things you could do with a laser pen not much.
Speaker 0: And that was the end of it.
Speaker 0: now Imagine if instead of projecting a little red dot you could project full motion 24 frame-per-second yaoi.
Speaker 1: Great, of course, you know if it's the lights are bright.
Speaker 1: It's probably not gonna be too visible.
Speaker 0: Oh, no But you're gonna be in a showing room and you're gonna be trying to watch a kuji bk Unbalanced and then suddenly there's gonna be penises all over all the walls Not to mention it won't work from too far away from the wall.
Speaker 1: So someone ought to be sitting right near the wall to make it work and to make it.
Speaker 1: You know
Speaker 0: the thing is I'm interested to see exactly what happens with all this because you know There's always that guy or that girl at the anime con who's sitting there in the hallway and a lot of times you'll see them Multiple days in the same spot and they'll have like their laptop and on their laptop.
Speaker 0: They've got all the anime music videos They downloaded from somewhere or they've got like DDR and they just sit there playing DDR with their fingers not even on a pad or Watching these music videos or watching these fan subs Attempting to gather crowds and eventually they will.
Speaker 0: I love these little pockets of people kind of surrounding these attention whores.
Speaker 1: try and I there's that one guy who does it.
Speaker 1: I think it katsu khan and a kinetic on.
Speaker 1: he just sets up his little computer and he plays stuff and people sit around Watching it and he's like gets all into it.
Speaker 1: He's a very strange man.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be a lot more of that once these things start getting more commonplace.
Speaker 0: So be Warned.
Speaker 1: yeah in two or three years anime conventions gonna get scary.
Speaker 1: You know that it's gonna be real scary when like the iPhone has a projector and you just aim the iPhone at the wall And then the video you bought on iTunes shows up.
Speaker 0: I mean at least luckily for now, we're not gonna have to worry too much because the people who buy these are gonna be You know attention.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, check out my thing.
Speaker 0: the same people have iPhones now But at the same time they'll be relatively rare and I'm not too worried, but give it a couple years and yeah.
Speaker 1: But yeah this year you should.
Speaker 1: this year You will see at least one phone become available somewhere in the world that has a projector in it to consumers.
Speaker 1: scary All right.
Speaker 1: That was your thing of the day not a news.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay, so check this out.
Speaker 1: Apparently this is this is as reported by Kotaku.
Speaker 1: So whatever but they got it from a Japanese site, which is linked.
Speaker 0: Oh, so some guy on the internet in Japan pictures just pictures.
Speaker 1: basically, they they have word that criminals are Hunting Japanese otaku, right because there have been like cases in Japan of like, you know otaku getting stabbed and otaku getting mugged and Otaku are being targeted by criminals, right?
Speaker 1: Apparently police in Shinjuku have been stopping people who look like otaku and subjecting them to like spot checks.
Speaker 1: So they'll be like the anyone who looks like an otaku.
Speaker 1: the police see them they stop them and then they search them for you Illegal stuffs, right?
Speaker 1: I guess you can do that in Japan.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't fly in the u.s.
Speaker 0: But wait a minute, but I thought the otaku were the victims.
Speaker 1: So that's why it makes no sense, but apparently a Supposed police list describes what types of individuals?
Speaker 1: Cops should check right?
Speaker 1: So here's the list of criteria.
Speaker 1: The police in Japan are looking forward to see who they should check you ready.
Speaker 0: aside from the fact that this is creepy police state Action, this ought to be hilarious.
Speaker 1: people wearing camouflage trousers or jackets People with chains or keys hanging off the trousers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people who look weak.
Speaker 1: Yeah people wearing a bandana people wearing leather leather so Basically, that's like.
Speaker 1: apparently that's a lot of otaku in Japan apparently meet those descriptions.
Speaker 0: Wow Should we give the list of what an American otaku is?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: kind of chubby kind of flabby kind of pale.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway a million shots keys hanging from their keychain.
Speaker 0: Yeah and a bus pass.
Speaker 1: so To see if those rumors right were true, right?
Speaker 1: This guy went to Shinjuku and he Drake.
Speaker 1: he followed all of those rules.
Speaker 1: He where he wore camouflage pants and Chad chains with keys and he had a bandana and like a leather jacket.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah the whole thing right to see if he got stopped and he did get stopped Right, but he put a note in his back He was wearing a backpack to that.
Speaker 1: the police would obviously want to search right and in that backpack He was only one thing.
Speaker 1: It was a note that said bummer failure.
Speaker 1: So, yeah check this out.
Speaker 1: is either a picture of him holding up the note and there's a picture of him with the police on The note and it's it's pretty funny.
Speaker 0: So if this is legitimate then the Japan - - cuz that's not cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I still don't it makes no sense that if otaku were being targets of crime.
Speaker 0: Why would they target otaku?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: it could be something that's lost in translation.
Speaker 0: Maybe they think that otaku or I don't know doing bad things and then the criminal elements are targeting them because of that.
Speaker 0: Maybe they think people are dressing up like otaku to do these things.
Speaker 1: I have no idea but that's that's what it says here and I have to.
Speaker 1: I can't read the Japanese site.
Speaker 1: Someone else can try to read it.
Speaker 1: See what it really says.
Speaker 1: But yeah great.
Speaker 0: So anyway tonight we're gonna talk about yet again a Comic book.
Speaker 0: Holy shit.
Speaker 1: Oh snap rims reading the comics.
Speaker 0: We'll see how long this lasts.
Speaker 1: Yeah So what comic are we gonna talk about?
Speaker 0: Oh, you want me to introduce it?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we could introduce it.
Speaker 0: Well this thing it's something that I think most people are aware exists.
Speaker 0: I mean even when I was a kid I remember seeing this you're like, oh, it's that thing.
Speaker 0: I know about that.
Speaker 1: you were a kid.
Speaker 0: Well when I was when I was a kid, I mean before college Uh-huh, and I think oh it's that thing.
Speaker 0: everyone like you'd see it in places and you'd hear about it.
Speaker 0: a lot of people who were into comics talked about it, but Never read it and I didn't know a lot of people who had read it.
Speaker 0: So I didn't really know much about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean when I saw this around, you know Like basically I saw images of it I could recognize it and I didn't know what it was called and later I did know what it was called.
Speaker 1: But I sort of I sort of like associated it with like, you know Johnny the homicidal maniac and and all those sort.
Speaker 1: I thought it was one of those kind of comics You know for like, you know the punk goth kids.
Speaker 1: It was that I thought it was one of their kind of things and I didn't really know about it.
Speaker 1: I think a lot of people in general Recognize if they see it, they recognize it.
Speaker 1: they go.
Speaker 1: I've seen that somewhere But you don't really know what it is or maybe you know what it's called except for people who've read it.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: my mice was different in that, you know I'd always go to comic shops because I was.
Speaker 0: I kind of wanted to get into comic books and I always see it there and I read.
Speaker 0: I think like one of the issues I didn't know it was this giant continuous story and I just didn't I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yep, so we're talking about today is bone by Jeff Smith and only Jeff Smith and no one else.
Speaker 0: Bone is the story of three bones from Bonville who leave Bonville and go on an epic journey and eventually Return to Bonville.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you should go and search on the internet and you'll see what these bone Characters look like and you'll go.
Speaker 1: Oh that's what you guys talking about.
Speaker 1: in case you don't know already cuz I'm sure if you're a geek you've seen this before somewhere and If you'd haven't realized this they're called bones because well They look like bones and they're from Bonville and their names are smiley bone phony bone and phone bone.
Speaker 0: Yep Now I finally read it and bone is really this kind of.
Speaker 0: it's not what I expected based on even what I'd read before And just on you know what you expect from those kind of characters.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you look at the cover of this comic and or any you have to you.
Speaker 1: really you cannot guess even what genre This thing is.
Speaker 1: but when you actually read it you go.
Speaker 1: Oh And it you it's a job.
Speaker 1: It's not like a surprise or anything.
Speaker 1: It's not like something new and original.
Speaker 1: It's you know, it's a. it's a type of story that has been told before.
Speaker 1: It's just not what you would expect from looking at it.
Speaker 0: it.
Speaker 0: to sum it up bone is basically just a straight-up Fantasy.
Speaker 1: it's an all-ages Epic adventure fantasy story, that's what it is.
Speaker 0: It just so happens that the three main characters are Extremely stylized and really don't fit in with the entire rest of the comic at all.
Speaker 0: Yep, but other than that, it's just a straight-up fantasy comic and that's the end of it.
Speaker 1: Well, it's a very long Straight up.
Speaker 0: It is very long.
Speaker 0: It was over 50 issues.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this thing it was a lot.
Speaker 1: it there was basically this came out a lot of issues like 50 something issues and it came Out over the course of a long number of years and there was no regular schedule wasn't like monthly.
Speaker 1: It was an issue came out.
Speaker 1: They waited a bunch.
Speaker 1: another issue came out.
Speaker 1: Can you imagine of trying to read this when it was coming out in issues?
Speaker 1: It would have been so painful.
Speaker 1: You know you would have been over 10 years.
Speaker 1: you'd be getting an issue and having no clue when the next issue was coming.
Speaker 1: Right, but now you can get all of bone in one volume one tremendous vine, which is what I have.
Speaker 1: Which is what we read which is the bone one volume edition and it's this gigantic fat paperback book.
Speaker 1: It's actually relatively cheap for what you get.
Speaker 1: It's black and white and it's every issue.
Speaker 0: I'd highly recommend if you want to read bone and you'll probably want to read bone because it's pretty enjoyable That you get that.
Speaker 1: Yeah Because you don't want 50 or so little issue that are gonna be hard to get now if you're wealthy.
Speaker 1: if you are wealthy you can get each Individual chapter of bone right and it's either separate volumes.
Speaker 1: I don't think all the volumes are out yet.
Speaker 1: You can get it in color because they're releasing these color volumes chapter by chapter, and they haven't done all the chapters.
Speaker 1: Maybe they have.
Speaker 1: you can buy color chapters instead of the one big black and white volume if you really want color And you're willing to pay for it.
Speaker 1: They have it.
Speaker 1: so What else are we gonna say about bone?
Speaker 0: well the story is actually.
Speaker 0: there's some.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of interesting I guess things to talk about related to bone.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to avoid talking about the plot in any great death because it goes so far from where it begins.
Speaker 1: Well, we could.
Speaker 1: we could talk about the beginning of the plot though The premise is you have this place called Boneville and there's these bones living there, right?
Speaker 0: But you don't even start with that.
Speaker 0: you start with three bones who have been run out of Boneville.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because one of them Epically failed to run for mayor.
Speaker 1: I was about to say that they were run out of Boneville.
Speaker 1: So these three bones got run out of town.
Speaker 1: So they're basically exiled and they're in this middle of nowhere and Eventually, they end up somewhere else where the story takes place.
Speaker 0: Yeah it's kind of like they get lost and they wander around and they end up in this kind of Normal fantasy world where everyone looks like a normal fantasy character.
Speaker 0: Yeah, three of them look like comic book characters.
Speaker 1: It's almost like an escaflowne a kind of transported to a fantasy world story except they're not Transported.
Speaker 0: they just walk to one and that they didn't know was there and then the snows fall and they can't get back and then They get separated and caught up in this kind of crazy Escalating story that it gets.
Speaker 0: it gets very epic toward the end.
Speaker 1: I think the two things I like most about bone, right?
Speaker 1: well, first of all, the art is Cart.
Speaker 1: it's like the.
Speaker 1: I can't really imagine art that takes fantasy But also like cartoonish art and combines it in such a way in which they can.
Speaker 1: you know at times the art will be like Whoa, and at other times it could be funny and it it totally works.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's just myth.
Speaker 0: I think that my favorite thing is that the boat like you'll get really into it and whenever something like one of the bones gets Punched or something or it's something frightening or horrible happens.
Speaker 0: They'll often make this face where their eyes go buggy with a dot in the middle and their mouth kind of goes open and it's Such a cartoony thing, but I cracked up out loud every time I saw it.
Speaker 0: It just fits so well.
Speaker 1: Also, one thing I like is that there are dragons in this story.
Speaker 1: Oh awesome drag.
Speaker 0: I think I have to point out that the way dragons are portrayed in bone is Exactly how I like dragons to be part.
Speaker 1: I think that's.
Speaker 1: everyone says that is pretty much that it's a fantasy story.
Speaker 1: There's dragons there's magic there's wizards and warlocks and whatnot, right?
Speaker 0: But the one dragon that you see the dragon that is involved in the story the most of all the other drag is the most Even-keeled thing you will ever see in anywhere the best character.
Speaker 1: Oh god, of course that that's you know.
Speaker 1: saying he's the best character is That's like say man, you know, you watch something like full metal alchemist or something.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of characters and some you like a lot and some not so much.
Speaker 1: in bone.
Speaker 1: Every character is super awesome Just some slightly more awesome than others and I think that's the biggest strength of bone is that every character is like your favorite.
Speaker 1: You can't except for the dragon.
Speaker 1: who's the most favorite?
Speaker 0: The dragon pretty much wins out.
Speaker 0: I just the look on his face and that look pretty much Never like it changes so many things.
Speaker 1: he says I did.
Speaker 1: Ah, but even the bad guys are awesome in this thing.
Speaker 0: I think my favorite bad guys, however are these stupid stupid fat rat creatures?
Speaker 1: Yeah, those those are also.
Speaker 1: those are right up there.
Speaker 1: But uh rock job John rock job.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: It's also an amazing job.
Speaker 0: Yeah And part of it's just the way they're drawn.
Speaker 0: I mean rock jaw rock jaw in particular.
Speaker 0: Just he's a cat, right?
Speaker 0: He's this giant mountain cat and he's drawn and portrayed so I guess as accurately cat-like as a being like that would be if it existed in the real world.
Speaker 0: just in terms of his facial expressions in the Way he reacts to things is just beautiful.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No wonder it took this guy so long to make this thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if it took him that long, at least he did a good job.
Speaker 0: Yeah, talk about characters staying on model.
Speaker 1: Good God Yeah, I mean it's one dude making this whole thing and that's not common in you know, u.s.
Speaker 1: Comics or anything like that.
Speaker 1: That's you know.
Speaker 1: in manga that's more common, but they have assistance.
Speaker 1: This guy did the whole thing on his own Tezuka style in.
Speaker 0: now The main characters are phone bone and phone civil P bone aka phony bone and they look the same except that Phony bone wears a shirt with a star on it and phone bones pretty much naked
Speaker 1: yep,
Speaker 0: and uh phone bones a pretty nice guy and phone civil is a complete jackass.
Speaker 1: and smiley bone is sort of like the Smiley bones an idiot savant.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's like the comic relief, you know tall kinda, you know funny guy who's like on this.
Speaker 1: that's sort of like a Marx Brothers set up in a way.
Speaker 1: and Smiley bones sort of like, you know, he hangs with.
Speaker 1: you know Phony bone, you know and sort of does the bad stuff with him.
Speaker 0: and you know, he's totally moral He doesn't care at all.
Speaker 0: He does a bad thing good thing whatever just does things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he just you know, he just he's just chillin hanging out doing what people want going along with the show seeing what happens.
Speaker 0: Now, of course, I can't forget cuz I love his name and I love every time I see him King Doc King that King Doc is this.
Speaker 0: the smiley is dude, but it's not a good kind of smiley.
Speaker 1: It's so great how that the way they draw the smiles on King Doc and his henchmen, you know It's.
Speaker 1: it's like a big toothy smile that is simultaneously like happy evil Hungry and scary and dangerous and all at the same time.
Speaker 1: It's it's pretty terrific.
Speaker 0: Now the one I guess the only criticism I have about bone and I guess I can get this out right away Is that I read the whole thing in one effective go over the course of about a week.
Speaker 1: I read it in a go in like a couple days.
Speaker 0: Well, I only read it on the train and I usually sleep in the morning so I read it on the way home, but The only thing I can say bad about bones that reading it in one go or one go ish at about the two-thirds point It starts to get a little bit cliche and you start to lose like you start to lose the drive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I definitely you know, it is all terrific.
Speaker 1: But this it definitely feels to me right.
Speaker 1: then when I read it There's a point at which Like the first part of the plot is like coming to a head like the first Climax in the story like big climax, right and there's a huge reveal and I really felt that.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'd have to ask Jeff Smith to see if this is true.
Speaker 1: But the impression I get I don't know how many times I'm gonna say that is that that first reveal was like planned from the beginning Right, and that was the plan.
Speaker 1: and then after that he sorta didn't have that planned out as well as he had points up.
Speaker 1: So it's like part a. we had a super plan written for it and it's executed beautifully And after that the plan is not so perfect.
Speaker 0: Well, I know there was at least a secondary plan.
Speaker 0: I've read in multiple places that he drew the last page of bone very early on Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: However, the last page is kind of predictable even from the beginning and it's it's kind of a standard ending that oh, okay That's what happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean it's an all it's a story for everybody It's all ages so you can't expect like some horrible terrible ending or anything like that.
Speaker 0: However, the the big reveal Scott is talking about I mean pretty much my favorite things in order are this reveal the dragon Rokja and then pretty much everything else.
Speaker 0: but the big reveal the the epic mo I mean there's basically you kind of wondering where this is going.
Speaker 0: and there's a lot of mysteries as to why all these dread the dragon and all these people care about these bones who had nothing to do with this world and what's Going on.
Speaker 0: and why does the hooded one await he who bears the star and?
Speaker 0: basically one thing leads to another and There's that that epic reveal happens where?
Speaker 0: Something comes over the horizon and something is revealed in epic glory.
Speaker 0: And I remember when I read that page I flipped to that page and it blindsided me and in retrospect I could have seen it in common, but yeah retrospect.
Speaker 0: No one sees this coming, right?
Speaker 1: I think that's the best thing.
Speaker 1: plot-wise about Bowen is how.
Speaker 0: that's the best thing.
Speaker 1: like any comic book ever He puts little bits into the story right that are sort of Off-handed or like he'll have like a like a chapter or a part of a chapter right like a file like a multiple page sequence.
Speaker 1: that's telling a joke because it's you know it's comedic.
Speaker 1: early on a lot of I think a lot of the best big adventure Stories start out sort of comedic and happy to let you introduce you to the characters and and grow to like them While just planting a seed of the big plot which is revealed later.
Speaker 1: that bone does that as well as anything has ever done.
Speaker 0: it Yeah, definitely ramps up these serious and ramps down the humor, but doesn't eliminate the humor.
Speaker 1: No, it doesn't eliminate the humor at all.
Speaker 1: there are many other things that do that though But this reveal.
Speaker 0: when I saw it I stared at it for about a second and I dropped the stupid book I was laughing out loud so hard it was.
Speaker 0: that was that that that alone makes bone worth reading.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh my even if you don't like bone get to that point You'll know it when it happens.
Speaker 1: that is that is the biggest reveal.
Speaker 1: But there are many other things in the book where they drop a small hint in like a joke or they bring something up Like in like a page or a panel, but they they make you notice it you won't forget it.
Speaker 1: Well, you'll forget it, but when they remind you of it ten chapters later You'll remember that you saw it and it.
Speaker 1: I love it.
Speaker 1: when that happens when they give you something You put it in the trunk right.
Speaker 1: I mean normally you get the sort of scooby-doo effect the what's it?
Speaker 1: What's his name?
Speaker 0: Chekhov's gun.
Speaker 1: Chekhov's gun, right?
Speaker 1: It's someone is trying to foreshadow something.
Speaker 1: It stands out like a sore thumb, you know, it means something later You've got your eye on it And then eventually when it reappears like it's going to you say I saw that coming a mile away.
Speaker 1: It was Chekhov's gun.
Speaker 1: It was scooby-doo, you know that that door in the background, you know was drawn.
Speaker 1: I'm obviously drawn in the cell and on the background so I knew it was gonna be animated.
Speaker 1: So I knew a zombie was gonna come out of it.
Speaker 1: You're not fooling anybody Right, but he basically does Chekhov's gun and you forget about the gun Which is so hard to do from a writing and art perspective and he pulls it off multiple times.
Speaker 1: Let's do it 100% of the time.
Speaker 1: there were eventually and I think that's part of why the sort of towards the end It gets a little bit cliche because he the Chekhov's gunning is not so accurate.
Speaker 0: Yeah pretty much a lot of the events that take place at the end kind of come out of nowhere and actually Later on in the story It seems like there's like you.
Speaker 0: when an issue ends and the next one begins or a volume ends The next one begins.
Speaker 0: in the book There's often a bit of a disconnect or the the the the action really gets interrupted and things kind of don't always Line up a hundred percent right around the transitions.
Speaker 0: Yep, but seriously that reveal I Cannot express to you.
Speaker 0: I people were looking at me at the train because I dropped the book was on the on the ground Gigantic book and I'm just laughing Uncontrollably, it was epic And the whole thing is epic.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's you know, there aren't too many epic adventure fantasy stories out there.
Speaker 1: This is one of the best ones top 10 probably It's also get.
Speaker 0: the end is kind of melancholy as I guess all epic things tend to be.
Speaker 0: I mean look at the end of Lord of the Rings how?
Speaker 0: Melancholy to use the word again it is.
Speaker 0: I mean it's over and just and everyone's Can't quite deal with what's happened to them.
Speaker 1: We went on a big adventure and you know everything happened and now it was gonna happen.
Speaker 0: now Now it's over and a lot of moving life and a lot of stories and at like the climax happens.
Speaker 0: And then our and happily ever after and bone does the thing that I loved so much.
Speaker 0: Escaflowne did this the Lord of the Rings did this where you did it?
Speaker 0: It's over and then you get what comes after and what comes after is always very Interesting and often kind of sad and kind of not necessarily anti-climactic but like the feeling you have when a journey's over and You have to continue living your life.
Speaker 0: You no longer have this goal in front of you that you've.
Speaker 0: this goal has been everything you've cared about It's.
Speaker 0: you know Frodo's got the ring and the ring is all that matters in the world.
Speaker 0: and now he's done it.
Speaker 0: the Rings gone.
Speaker 0: now what?
Speaker 1: Go to the Grey Havens and chill.
Speaker 0: Well, that's one answer.
Speaker 0: Sam wise was cool.
Speaker 0: He's like, alright, I'm gonna go back to Hobbiton and be a hobbit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but even then it was kind of like sitting around More an old Hobbiton.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep There's another interest.
Speaker 1: or like riding the big rollercoaster and riding a little rollercoaster.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean having a family like you did in Hobbiton is a little rollercoaster.
Speaker 1: But you go to Mordor and then you go back and you have to deal with more dog.
Speaker 1: You have to deal with your punk kids.
Speaker 1: you're like whatever my kids I can keep them in line.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not a you know, no, it's like doing cocaine and then doing less cocaine One that I don't know what that was like one thing One thing that I found really interesting and I I don't really want to.
Speaker 0: I guess it's not much of a spoiler in saying that This does not terribly come up but I was kind of surprised it didn't.
Speaker 0: but All throughout the first half of bone and even all the way through the end and they keep this checkoffs gun Keeps being showed you.
Speaker 0: they keep showing you this gun.
Speaker 0: But and even after some some things happen, they still show you the gun.
Speaker 0: It's like well the guns are even fired and I don't think there's any more bullets in it.
Speaker 0: Why do they keep showing it to me?
Speaker 0: But it is obvious that Bonville is basically the modern world Bonville.
Speaker 0: they keep referencing things in Bonville offhandedly and it's obvious that Bonville is a progressive modern Democratic society that has probably electricity and nuclear power plants and just a normal civilized world.
Speaker 0: and they put this fact in your face all the time with little asides even near the end where this one like in the very end like when these climaxes are happening and something comes up with food and this mystic suggests to smileybone that he tried this this stinky cheese and Fonsible makes a remark to the effect of you people with your like unprocessed food.
Speaker 0: What are you trying to kill us?
Speaker 0: Don't people know how to cook around here?
Speaker 0: And all these references and that fucking doesn't really come up at all in all of bone?
Speaker 0: No, not really except in one time.
Speaker 0: one time it comes up barely.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess grind it that one time.
Speaker 1: All right, is there anything else we got to say?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of the things I could say would kind of ruin.
Speaker 0: bone There's.
Speaker 1: I know it's it's.
Speaker 1: I don't want to root cuz it's it's not.
Speaker 1: there's not a lot of.
Speaker 1: I mean There's some messages in bone and some themes and whatnot, but for the most part it's a straight-up in-your-face open book adventure tale.
Speaker 1: so Anything you can say about it other than why it's good or that you should read it or you know What parts.
Speaker 1: what about it is what we like?
Speaker 1: We just be giving away the plot which is all that is there even though the plot is an amazing plot.
Speaker 1: That's epic.
Speaker 1: You can't really say anything about about spoiling it.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: All right, this is Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: So uh all grains of salt in place According to Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna read here in the 1990s an attempt to produce a film of bone through Nickelodeon Films was unsuccessful.
Speaker 0: according to Smith.
Speaker 0: Nickelodeon saw the story strictly as children's entertainment and insisted that bone characters be voiced by child actors and that the film had to include pop songs by Britney Spears and in sync.
Speaker 0: Smith's argument was that no one would even briefly consider putting pop songs in film adaptations the Lord of the Rings and Therefore they will not be placed in bone either.
Speaker 1: and so it was.
Speaker 0: I can say one thing though I think bone would translate Brilliantly to a film or a series of films or it would have to be something long.
Speaker 0: You could do it Lord of the Rings style or you could do it.
Speaker 0: You know, maybe in Japan where they the anime say they just animate a show for 13 or 26 episodes.
Speaker 0: We're great in that kind.
Speaker 1: Oh, it would work terrifically.
Speaker 1: there's also I think there's some adventure games of bone and I gotta say if you like like the kind of stories you get from Like LucasArts adventure games your bone is the same kind of story is now you will like that action.
Speaker 1: There's also a bone adventure game made by someone that you might be able to get.
Speaker 1: it's I don't know.
Speaker 1: Oh last year There's a Mac version of it came out.
Speaker 0: no great.
Speaker 1: so yeah, you can you might be able to get the adventure game if you search around the net and See what else do we got?
Speaker 0: but seriously, I think bone would be great as a film partly because there's no sort of inner monologue.
Speaker 0: It's done very cinematically and everything, you know, it's because characters say it or you see it Yep, and you could basically take the comic book and use that to do the storyboards and then just make bone.
Speaker 0: That why it kind of bothers me that no one's done something like this because I think it would go.
Speaker 0: Well, yes in the 1990s and it was Nickelodeon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only other thing I had to say about Jeff Smith the guy who made it he He went to work on Shazam and the Monster Society of Shazam Shazam and the Monster Society of Evil.
Speaker 1: So I'm waiting for that to be in a trade paperback and then I'll buy it.
Speaker 1: He's starting a new thing right called razzle r a s L and I think the first issue comes out in a month or two.
Speaker 1: I pre-ordered it obviously But I'll probably wait a few years for there to be one giant book of the whole thing before I actually you know Buy it, but yeah, he's starting a new comic.
Speaker 1: So if you wanna if you like bone, you should buy Jeff Smith's new comic and the other comics He's made cuz he really hasn't made too many comics.
Speaker 1: I mean he worked on bone for how many years, you know, and he didn't work on much else.
Speaker 1: I mean, maybe he did some covers and you know things like that.
Speaker 0: But yeah All right, I think we'll leave it at that because seriously Bone is a hundred percent worth reading.
Speaker 0: I can't think of anyone who wouldn't enjoy bone.
Speaker 1: I guess it is not a human.
Speaker 0: if you don't like reading then you probably won't like bone.
Speaker 0: that that's that's about all I can say.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.