Speaker 1: It's Monday April 28th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott And this is geek knives tonight the three major desktop operating systems, and why we both love and hate them.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well, we totally copped out last week.
Speaker 0: We did what two shows barely last week was pretty sad But I mean I got a new computer And I went out of town for the weekend like right after I sort of went out of town Far away.
Speaker 1: weekend before that we had that crazy thing in the city and The thing is it's funny because that weekend before last week We were thinking we were talking like man geek knives is really picking up like we're doing this radio things.
Speaker 1: We got all these like semi-professional things going on now.
Speaker 1: We're getting the big time.
Speaker 1: We're so professional now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, look how professional we are yeah, and then we totally cop out into a week of crap.
Speaker 0: That's all right because I think that after last week I'm sort of freshened, and I got some new ideas.
Speaker 0: I think we can you know tilt the show in a newer better direction because you know We've been doing the show pretty consistently, but I don't think we've improved it significantly in a while.
Speaker 1: But I think we hit a plateau where we got real good and to get beyond that we have to change something up and while I still want to put stuff in the experimental feed.
Speaker 1: That's like two steps beyond the kind of improvements I'm talking about right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got some ideas.
Speaker 0: I think it's gonna be pretty good Yeah,
Speaker 1: but actually I had a good refreshing weekend too because last week It was kind of like we'd been drilling and drilling and drilling and forcing ourselves not to miss episodes and go go go 180 Miles an hour and we kind of burned out, and we had this weekend where I actually went to Rochester.
Speaker 1: You know the old alma mater for Toricon.
Speaker 1: I'll talk about the overview.
Speaker 1: Toricon is my news on Wednesday because it was a good con, but it's one day.
Speaker 1: I realized something sad.
Speaker 1: Remember way back when you get to college And then you realize suddenly that all the stereotypes of college kids that you thought were fake and no one would really live that way You'd kind of become when you realize you're sitting in class in your pajamas Unshaven after having pulled an all-nighter and eating ramen for breakfast.
Speaker 0: That's college.
Speaker 1: Well before I went to college I always thought that was BS.
Speaker 1: I was like no one's really like that and I got to college And I saw people like that.
Speaker 1: I was like that's totally like hipster bullshit.
Speaker 1: That's all affected, and then one day.
Speaker 1: It was like look what you've become rim.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know what as much as those college stereotypes are real saved by the bell not real Not even close man.
Speaker 1: if saved by the bell you think is maybe that's it.
Speaker 1: I was burned by saved by the bell when I was in elementary.
Speaker 1: like middle school I saw saved by the bell.
Speaker 1: I was like man.
Speaker 1: That's what high school is like.
Speaker 1: High school I was like wow Zach Morris lied to me.
Speaker 0: do you think maybe like the Japanese people have a similar thing like they watch all these high school Animes when they're in middle and elementary school, and it's like man?
Speaker 1: I think high school is like all the high school anime that it's robot and then I'm gonna get punched by a girl that I like, but they will fall in love.
Speaker 1: and But then I get to college and it's like.
Speaker 1: no all the stereotypes were true.
Speaker 1: in fact the reality is far more Stereotypical than the media would even begin to portray it as yep, but I really I hit another one of those stereotypes, so We we go to cons a lot, and you know we see these people who are more famous than us but not super famous or people who are legitimately mainstream famous and They always kind of show up late like stroll into the ops office like five minutes before their event like yeah I'm here.
Speaker 1: Where's my badge?
Speaker 1: give me some booze blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: And then they go into their panel half-assily, and then they leave like skip their next four panels.
Speaker 1: You know that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: yeah, I know those types.
Speaker 1: I had a one panel to do a torque on and I Showed up at torque on like five minutes before it was supposed to go.
Speaker 1: I kind of walked in.
Speaker 1: someone's like you got a badge.
Speaker 1: I was like do you know who I am?
Speaker 1: Where's the con chair?
Speaker 1: and then I went.
Speaker 1: I was like do I need a bad?
Speaker 1: She's like nah probably not.
Speaker 1: and then I went over to my panel room.
Speaker 1: I walk in.
Speaker 1: people are sitting there waiting, and I opened with yeah, so I totally just got here And I didn't plan anything for this.
Speaker 1: Hi.
Speaker 1: I'm rim Dancing.
Speaker 1: actually the room was full alright, but it was the alumni room, but the thing is I know in 1829 room.
Speaker 1: Well the no I mean the alumni room.
Speaker 1: I don't know which one that is but I'm not gonna talk about all that on Wednesday.
Speaker 1: But I totally after I did my panel.
Speaker 1: I was like alright.
Speaker 1: That was great.
Speaker 1: See you guys.
Speaker 1: And then I kind of left the con.
Speaker 1: it didn't come back.
Speaker 0: So so hey how you supposed to review this con Wednesday if you didn't spend any time at it?
Speaker 1: I actually I asked them to send me kind of a synopsis press release And you know numbers and all that stuff, and I was there walking in walking out.
Speaker 1: I know how well the cotton you know you look at a con, and it's obvious this con succeeded.
Speaker 1: this con failed.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: torque on succeeded.
Speaker 0: well my new computer quite succeeded.
Speaker 0: with the awesome man.
Speaker 1: It's rare to see you excited about shit, but I got home from torque on.
Speaker 0: you know you want to touch my computer.
Speaker 1: I want to touch your computer like you wouldn't believe but you're not gonna cuz it's got password on it Physical passwords the most.
Speaker 1: I cannot think of something more trivial to break.
Speaker 1: but yet in all these years I don't think either one of us have ever even bothered thinking about hacking into each other's computers.
Speaker 0: No, it's like what we both use really good passwords.
Speaker 1: I mean I guess you don't need to know your password.
Speaker 1: I'm out your volume with a live CD.
Speaker 0: you could indeed do that, but you know what I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna turn on the bit locker encryption.
Speaker 1: bit locker encryption is pretty hot yeah, but you know what I'll do.
Speaker 1: I'll boot into Windows, and then I'm totally insecure, and you can just change my root password.
Speaker 1: Ellie I don't know if XP or Vista fix that but anyone out there you realize that with Windows anything XP or prior You can boot a floppy disk and just arbitrarily change anyone's password to anything.
Speaker 0: yep well Very soon.
Speaker 0: I have the powerful computer.
Speaker 0: It is running the windows, but I have the Linux going in the VMware And it's stupid.
Speaker 0: fast like I have a core to do at work, but it's a core to do a 64 6600. the cores are 1.8.
Speaker 0: Gigahertz and my one at work.
Speaker 0: right and it's pretty fast running Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: This one has two cores.
Speaker 0: there are three gigahertz.
Speaker 0: also It's 45 nanometer as opposed to 65 nanometer which means the transistors are 20 nanometers smaller than the transistors on the one I have at work man and 45 nanometer is Really small right?
Speaker 1: I remember when three digit and higher numbers were the hot shit, right?
Speaker 0: and In addition to that there's six megabytes of cache as opposed to like four.
Speaker 0: Um Yeah, it is stupid stupid fast.
Speaker 0: I think it's actually.
Speaker 0: I could have gotten a quad core for a similar price.
Speaker 0: I think it's actually faster than the quad core because the quad core would only be faster in situations where you were using multiple cores But actually most of the time your own.
Speaker 0: you know two is plenty yeah for the vast majority of shit.
Speaker 1: So fast I'll admit I just got a quad core at work a quad core Xeon like the quad core Xeon is is the cores are probably as fast.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much I got the best Computer that you can have on a desktop without spending like.
Speaker 1: like you know There's the amount of money you can spend to get something.
Speaker 1: and then beyond that it's like the I Commission a computer to be made for me by engineers.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much what I got but I don't need it like I don't even you.
Speaker 0: I use one of those cars like a little bit yep, so yeah, um There's gonna be some videos soon video action.
Speaker 0: there's gonna be a lot more PC gaming action going on.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be all kinds of action real soon.
Speaker 0: You better better watch out.
Speaker 0: also I got to say is the first computer I've ever had where it's actually as fast as me like I push.
Speaker 0: That's the number one thing I hate about all computers I've ever used is that I can push buttons faster than the computer can do what I'm telling it to do.
Speaker 1: not always I couldn't do that on my Pentium 200 at first, but then applications got more complex and more powerful And then I couldn't do that anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I started getting slowed down.
Speaker 0: I also I'm getting a lot faster than you know personally as you know like well because think about it It's real quick to type.
Speaker 1: You know the the command that would compile something.
Speaker 1: It's not real quick to get it compiled no,
Speaker 0: but I mean like just with Firefox on most computers I'm like ctrl L and I start typing URL and Like I'll like hat it'll go and then it'll sort of type half the URL because I typed it too fast before the ctrl L registered.
Speaker 0: well the place.
Speaker 0: I'll push ctrl W the ctrl T like close the tab open a new one and then start typing URL and like it'll Start typing the URL.
Speaker 0: half of it will be in the tab that didn't close yet and half It will be in the new tab.
Speaker 0: man.
Speaker 1: You had a slow computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah That even happens at work though on the course you do it really.
Speaker 1: yeah, that doesn't even happen on my computer here.
Speaker 1: It happens to me a lot because I'm that has once when I realized that opened like my 15th Firefox tab.
Speaker 1: yeah, I hadn't closed Firefox in like a week.
Speaker 0: I just you know all like.
Speaker 0: but I do a lot of stuff like I'll do it like a Command to open a terminal hat.
Speaker 0: that SSH is into a machine type of command like switch with the keyboard to another window That's already running a command cancel that command started a new one And I'm just.
Speaker 0: you know I do a lot of stuff like that the other day.
Speaker 1: This is just kind of an aside, but I was gonna reboot my computer.
Speaker 1: So I had one like I was closing all my windows like shutting everything down kind of gracefully making sure I wasn't like logged in anywhere doing anything.
Speaker 1: and I remember I pull open one terminal window in my ex windows thing and I'm like all right and I'm like root on some machine like some test box.
Speaker 1: so that exit and then obviously I'm not rude anymore.
Speaker 1: So I took exit again, but the terminal doesn't go away.
Speaker 1: now It's on some other computer, so I keep talking typing exit and over the course of like the previous two weeks I think I've been SSH into like eight computers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's nothing like that.
Speaker 1: I just I was like how deep did this go?
Speaker 0: just close nice You know.
Speaker 1: if you just close the terminal all the SSH connect I know, but because I was gonna type eggs a couple times and after it didn't close right away I was curious where I started and where I'd been.
Speaker 1: It was like what computer did I SSH into first and why?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have a computer that's as fast as me or faster than me.
Speaker 0: I'm able to like keep steam open all the time.
Speaker 0: I got iTunes in my room instead of having to VNC to the Mac and living room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was the main I'm.
Speaker 0: actually I tried to sort my music collection, right?
Speaker 0: I dragged a gigantic folder of music into the automatic sorting program and the limitation was the network speed of Contacting the.
Speaker 1: is this the same sorting application that would just crash on your old computer.
Speaker 1: Yes Wow Yes, isn't it great to have a fast computer?
Speaker 0: Oh, it's fantastic.
Speaker 0: Say let's let's make up some news here.
Speaker 0: So risers guilty That's my news.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Do you know do you want to do it?
Speaker 1: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: No, I got a news All right, then why are you announcing my news before I do it?
Speaker 1: I'd fine.
Speaker 1: I didn't say anything.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's right.
Speaker 0: So this is guy named Hans riser.
Speaker 0: I think guilty.
Speaker 0: I think we've talked about this on the show once before if maybe more than one long story short developer for riser FS Which is a damn good file system.
Speaker 0: Basically this guy the only reason we're talking about this The guy is an open source software developer.
Speaker 0: All right, he sort of single-handedly or mostly single-handedly invented this file system, which is really good.
Speaker 0: It's a good high quality file system That's really innovative.
Speaker 0: and the vert, you know, he's working on the fourth version of it.
Speaker 0: And if you look at some of the working on it forever the riser 4 has been like this dream of mine, right?
Speaker 0: But riser for you look at some of the things that it can do like on paper and it's like it's.
Speaker 0: it's like it would Be revolutionary if it actually came to be in the way that it's written on paper.
Speaker 0: But it didn't come to be because Hans riser, you know, there are other people working on.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's open source.
Speaker 0: I mean if someone really wanted to they could go and get the open the code and just can carry on the project and Some people might be doing that but I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: but anyway Basically You know, he's an open-source developer but separate from that he murdered his wife.
Speaker 0: well according to this court He murdered his wife.
Speaker 0: So I guess it's safe to say he did.
Speaker 0: I guess it's not Slander if a court found him guilty of murdering his wife, which they did.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we don't.
Speaker 1: it's not like the media.
Speaker 1: We don't know what we are the media, but we don't have to say allegedly anymore.
Speaker 1: We don't have to say Hans riser who allegedly murders his wife say Hans riser wife killer, right?
Speaker 0: But the thing is right if you look into the facts of this case Alright, it is incredibly strange.
Speaker 0: It is like one of the strangest murder cases I've ever seen right?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean like there's all sorts of stuff like they can't find the body, right?
Speaker 0: They're claiming that the wife ran back to Russia with the kids to run away from him.
Speaker 0: there was some guy who his wife was cheating with and They were doing like weird fetishy stuff and there was like a car that was found with Blood on it somewhere and it was.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of weird shit going on with this case Like this is one of those someone meticulously murdered or meticulously framed someone else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something is very strange.
Speaker 0: You know something illegal happened somewhere, right?
Speaker 0: It says you don't know what exactly and we still don't know what.
Speaker 0: but It's really, you know, this has been going on for a long time.
Speaker 0: And actually it was funny.
Speaker 0: a few weeks ago We were like, hey, did that ever?
Speaker 0: Conclude here.
Speaker 1: Actually, here's the Craig an example of the craziness.
Speaker 1: I'm pulling this from Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: I was just kind of looking cuz I remember some of the.
Speaker 1: I read that article months ago quotes Sean Sturgeon a one-time friend of riser and this is the guy who was supposedly Possibly sleeping with his wife and allegedly was an ex-lover of her Independently of all this confessed to killing eight other people.
Speaker 1: Yep, but claims that he didn't kill her.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So What Wow imagine that if this is to be believed Riser knew a guy who was had slept with his wife at some point who independently of all this murdered eight people But yet didn't murder her.
Speaker 1: and yet he murdered her.
Speaker 0: It's really a fucked up case and the only reason you have any interest in it is because why riser?
Speaker 0: for the software this guy happened to make and you know To it, you know his disadvantage as good as he is I guess in making file systems Hans Riser like many nerdy type people as some social issues.
Speaker 0: He's not really a likable He's kind of a weird guy and I think the reason that he was found guilty Despite they're basically not being much evidence in this case.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's no body.
Speaker 0: There's no there's no physical evidence There's no eyewitnesses.
Speaker 0: There's no nothing.
Speaker 0: All right, but he was found guilty From what I can tell because he didn't know when to shut up.
Speaker 1: I mean, I mean, I've heard a lot of rumors from a lot of people long before this.
Speaker 1: all You know murder trial happened that everyone said he was kind of an asshole to everyone.
Speaker 0: He's also sort of a you know, he's a weird guy and he Yeah, here it is a quote from the an article on wired which I'll link you to.
Speaker 0: this is this is Hans Riser's exact quote?
Speaker 0: Right, I have a compulsive tendency to say things that I know are true that people don't want to be true Huh?
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: This is just craziness.
Speaker 1: I imagine one thing though I am sure during the jury selection One of the questions was do you know who Hans Riser is and or do you use Linux?
Speaker 0: Perhaps they just didn't let anyone with a neckbeard into the jury room Perhaps but this is if you're like if you like watching like, you know Or any sort of police detective e-court shows right?
Speaker 0: This is the real deal.
Speaker 0: This really happened right and it's way more interesting.
Speaker 0: You mean you can't write a story like this, you know And so you should definitely definitely look into it.
Speaker 0: Definitely.
Speaker 1: So in some Definite tech news IBM is definitely starting to push Lotus Notes again.
Speaker 0: What the fuck isn't it dead was less something updated that shit.
Speaker 1: Yesterday oh god see I. my first real job outside of college and actually was while I was still in college was IBM Was for IBM.
Speaker 1: I work at the MLC, you know I was a. I was technically a software engineer, but really I was like a support engineer the milk of them.
Speaker 1: But even more I was at the MLC systems like the 200 millimeter fab.
Speaker 1: I worked at the place where they do hundred.
Speaker 0: I got a 45.
Speaker 1: Um It's 200 millimeters and it's a circle.
Speaker 1: Next to it the 300 millimeter fab and let me tell you the 200 millimeter fab.
Speaker 0: But I had a bunch of wafers because we know the other 300 millimeter fab and you're making 45 nanometer chips.
Speaker 0: How many transistors could fit all the way across the wafer?
Speaker 1: That is a calculation that I'm not going to try to make right now.
Speaker 1: Let me put it this way I like to make you do math 300 millimeters is bigger than you're thinking right?
Speaker 0: It's really big.
Speaker 1: Yeah and Like when we make these we'd cram like a hundred of them into this special kind of case and then they carry these cases around.
Speaker 0: And I remember one specific incident each wafer has got like a hundred More than a hundred chips on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like we're talking like PlayStation 3 cell chips right before they were announced.
Speaker 0: So these chips, you know one chip costs like hundreds of dollars at the store retail, right?
Speaker 0: You've got a wafer with hundreds of the chips on it And you got like a whole bunch of the wafers together in one spot.
Speaker 1: dude dropped one of these things.
Speaker 0: Oh, man That's like it's like you mean at least if you drop gold, it doesn't lose its value.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so at IBM we used Lotus Notes.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you Lotus Notes is pretty much functionally equivalent to you know, the exchange kind of Microsoft thing but the interface is Alien like if you've never used it.
Speaker 1: it is completely unlike any other program like that.
Speaker 0: So what does it do?
Speaker 0: Is it do like instant messaging?
Speaker 1: It does everything that exchange does.
Speaker 1: so Exchange integrated.
Speaker 0: so it's an email server.
Speaker 0: It's and it's a calendar.
Speaker 1: It's email calendar Messaging scheduling.
Speaker 1: you can build applications within it full database integration, whatever exchange.
Speaker 0: I don't think is that powerful.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the only thing exchange doesn't have is like a very robust mechanism for building applications within.
Speaker 0: yeah That's what I was saying that exchange didn't have.
Speaker 1: but the rest of that you can integrate exchange with all these database.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you can integrate his office communicator, which is actually really slick even though it doesn't support jabber at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you can always write all sorts like VB applications to make it do more things.
Speaker 1: But just the interface is alien and all the terminology is different.
Speaker 1: Like you don't synchronize your mailbox you synchronize your database because your mailbox is actually just a database and all this sorts of like.
Speaker 1: semantically, it's Unusable to someone who is familiar with any other email suite or office suite in the world Mm-hmm, but regard and you'd think oh, well, it's probably cheap or something.
Speaker 1: No, it was ludicrously expensive and Pretty much.
Speaker 1: No one used it.
Speaker 1: IBM and companies.
Speaker 1: you've used it a long time ago and were afraid to stop.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean before exchange existed.
Speaker 0: that was the thing.
Speaker 0: I mean.
Speaker 0: what else?
Speaker 0: what else could you do besides?
Speaker 0: just you know normal like send mail?
Speaker 1: Well, the Microsoft mail solutions have been around for a long time And so if the Lotus ones they were kind of like these two competing like their office suite.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everything exchange and Outlook have been around for a long time, but not they're relatively new compared to Lotus notes.
Speaker 0: Lotus notes is from like you could get that shit on like IBM ps1s, but you know Let me get into Domino like the server for Lotus notes because I dealt with.
Speaker 0: oh so Domino is the Lotus node server.
Speaker 0: pretty much the same way Exchange is the outlook server.
Speaker 0: But any notes is outlook.
Speaker 0: Is that you're saying pretty much?
Speaker 1: Okay Anyway, the deal is they're pushing it and they've dropped the licensing costs to be compared to other enterprise solutions practically free and I don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean, I I don't think I ever talked about this but one of the big things IBM was doing when I was there and I actually was a big part of this and I I Got us off of Windows and off of OS 2 but in some areas and a lot of people were working really hard to kind of move to Linux and move toward the future.
Speaker 1: but There is actually a Linux client native for Lotus And a native Linux server.
Speaker 1: those have been around for a while and IBM internally was using them for a long time as we were testing them or working out the kinks and all that.
Speaker 1: and there's also an OS 10 clients native and an OS 10 server if you're crazy Wow
Speaker 0: and
Speaker 1: What IBM is suddenly doing now is they're pushing this as a cheaper but still very functional Alternative to the Microsoft Outlook environment with the added benefit that you can
Speaker 0: write it in Linux.
Speaker 0: There definitely are You know some needed, you know competitors to exchange because I mean, you know for a business exchange is really where Scott and I are technical people.
Speaker 1: you think oh, we'll just run our own email.
Speaker 1: I don't think you understand how awful it is to run any email solution.
Speaker 0: I mean Google provides a pretty competitive product with the you know, the Google app.
Speaker 1: Oh, if I were a small business, I would use Google apps.
Speaker 0: But for a big business like IBM, you can't.
Speaker 0: Google apps sort of falls apart.
Speaker 0: It does not scale not at all.
Speaker 0: Maybe Google has their own like internal thing that they use that scales but they don't give that to other people.
Speaker 1: Plus small business you trust Google because you don't care large business or like where I work now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you're IBM your emails, you don't Google reading those emails.
Speaker 0: You can't have that shit.
Speaker 0: That can't happen.
Speaker 0: So you definitely need to run your own servers with your own software on them.
Speaker 1: But I'm going to look more into this and actually what I want to do.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna try to ask if anyone I know who works at IBM is still there.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna see if I can find that get some sort of press information about this because if the kind of promises are true and This works the way it's advertised and the licensing stays the way it is This is gonna be a big problem for Microsoft in the future.
Speaker 0: Maybe the thing is is that in that particular department is a lot of momentum.
Speaker 1: Yes, there is but at the same time There are a lot of relatively small companies that are up and coming and like kind of.
Speaker 1: now is the time to get our enterprise Shit together.
Speaker 1: What do we buy?
Speaker 1: and then IBM says well, look how cheap this is.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The other thing though, is that Even though you know, it might you know, if your whole business uses.
Speaker 0: it might be okay.
Speaker 0: for inter business stuff It might be a little tricky.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is for inner business stuff.
Speaker 1: The only problem is with the actual document writing and that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: But people have problems anyway, even if they're just using Microsoft stuff these days because of the incompatibilities.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, I mean, I don't I can't say much more about the details now.
Speaker 1: Well, I think this will go until I find out a lot more about it.
Speaker 1: We're it's gonna take some time, but I find this kind of interesting Things of the day.
Speaker 1: now typing of the dead is like the best typing thing ever.
Speaker 0: Ah Typing the dead is pretty good.
Speaker 0: But I actually I think Mario teaches typing.
Speaker 1: Where were you gonna play Mario?
Speaker 0: teachers typing on an old Mac l2c?
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, this was on bb spot, which is one of those sites that died a long time ago, but for some reason it's still there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, go bb spot.
Speaker 1: I don't know goes to bb.
Speaker 0: So maybe one guy I think one guy does the whole thing and I think he's living off the ad revenue.
Speaker 1: So well, the thing is mean pool pretty much just died, but it's still there.
Speaker 1: but bb spot Continues to update and well bb spot is a lot more.
Speaker 0: they actually generate content Whereas mean pool is just linking.
Speaker 1: before Even when it was the hot shit I never once read anything on bb spot ever all I would ever read things on there and look in the upper left corner Where they have their five like things of the day?
Speaker 0: That's what I mostly did but I would occasionally read there.
Speaker 0: They had some content there.
Speaker 0: Usually I didn't see it.
Speaker 0: weird It's like I wouldn't go to bb spot and read the content.
Speaker 0: if I went to bb spot I would look at their you know links in the top left like there are ten links of the day.
Speaker 0: But occasionally some other site like slashdot or something would link to bb spots content directly like a like a funny block.
Speaker 0: You know parody blog post they made and then I would read it.
Speaker 1: See, but anyway bb spot more and more lately kind of like College Humor is becoming this almost useful thing Especially to find things of the day because dig is dead.
Speaker 1: dig is just so useless now Like I haven't seen anything compelling on dig in weeks But right here from bb spot type racer.
Speaker 1: all it is you race against other people typing Live in real time and it tells you your words per minute and it's really really fun and I can say pretty I'm happy.
Speaker 1: I average about a hundred words a minute, which is a lot more than I expected.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got like 70 but I was on my laptop and I you know, I was still trying to figure it out.
Speaker 0: I'm sure when I go and see the other room on my wicked fast computer that I'll be dominating But of course it was weird.
Speaker 0: It's like I fucked up like a bunch of times on my laptop keyboard And I I was going really slow.
Speaker 0: I still won every race I raced.
Speaker 1: Well, I noticed though they have a recent high scores thing and like any web game I'm sure it's being gamed because the number 1 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15 16 17 places out of 20 are all occupied by the same guy who is cheetah, which could be cheater.
Speaker 1: Aha also 205 words a minute not bloody likely.
Speaker 0: He's probably wrote in a little script.
Speaker 0: They wouldn't be hard to write a script and read.
Speaker 0: that's reading the screen and then typing it or he's maybe he's copying and pasting Or something.
Speaker 0: Maybe he's hacked the JavaScript probably something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean theoretically.
Speaker 1: I guess that's possible but I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm happy with a hundred words a minute.
Speaker 0: a grease monkey script could Beat that game definitely.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'd recommend you all try this out.
Speaker 1: It's a fairly neutral way kind of objective to find out how well you type.
Speaker 1: do it a couple times They.
Speaker 1: the cool thing is they make you type something and they make everyone who's racing type the same thing.
Speaker 1: So if you saw if it's something with a bunch of semicolons, at least you're all being kind of hampered in the same way.
Speaker 1: but It tells you at the end what you were typing though.
Speaker 1: Most of the cases you should probably be able to tell.
Speaker 1: I mean I got the words to blow it in the wind by Bob Dylan at one point.
Speaker 1: I got someday lad.
Speaker 1: all this will be yours.
Speaker 1: What the cottons?
Speaker 1: No, not the cottons lad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got some Microsoft thing Aha.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So yeah, this is cool.
Speaker 1: And I want to hear your scores post them in the forum All right.
Speaker 0: So so in I think in Albion, right?
Speaker 0: they Basically the Office of Government Commerce, which I assume is is that like our FTC or something?
Speaker 0: What they do right, but the Office of Government Commerce in in the London's right.
Speaker 0: they hired a design firm To make a new logo for them because their logo is not so good Scott didn't?
Speaker 1: he told me about his news And he's like look at this logo and tell me what you see before.
Speaker 1: I saw it and I know what you're thinking right now.
Speaker 1: It's another unintentional goat see.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: it is so much better than that, right?
Speaker 0: So it cost them 14,000 pounds to have this logo designed and I guess they approved the design and they released the logo.
Speaker 0: and The logo is just the letters o G and C, but they're all like, you know, since those are circular kind of letters, right?
Speaker 0: They're all the same size.
Speaker 0: They're sort of touching each other.
Speaker 0: They're overlapping a bit.
Speaker 0: and You know there this is like this nice dark grayish color and it's you know, it's not too bad looking.
Speaker 0: Until you turn it on its side rotating it 90 degrees to the right then it is a laugh riot.
Speaker 1: So Scott, what does it resemble?
Speaker 0: Oh, I think people have to look at it to find out.
Speaker 0: if I tell them it won't be funny You you can kind of.
Speaker 1: it's almost a spatial kind of like a brain test.
Speaker 1: where.
Speaker 1: look at it without it being rotated for you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just think about the letter teacher.
Speaker 0: either.
Speaker 0: do this right.
Speaker 0: think of in your minds the letters o G and C But they're all exactly the same size, you know, perfect circles, right except o G and C, right?
Speaker 0: And I'll put them so like the O is a little bit touching the G and that C is a little bit touching the G right and now rotate it to the right in your mind and Think about what that looks like.
Speaker 0: and if you can figure it out without actually seeing it I don't think I would have figured it out I wouldn't have figured out without seeing it.
Speaker 0: but then you have some really good brain skills.
Speaker 1: use the form gyrus.
Speaker 1: Here we come.
Speaker 0: Yep, but I'm serious.
Speaker 1: I lolled.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I definitely I said the word low.
Speaker 0: I lulled and I sent it to all the co-workers who also lulled.
Speaker 1: So, uh tonight, all right You were like, oh, I'll introduce the show.
Speaker 1: I got this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I forgot.
Speaker 0: I thought we could like stop and have.
Speaker 0: I've done a show in a while out of the groove.
Speaker 1: All right Well, I'll groove it up.
Speaker 0: No, but anyway when I bought my new computer recently, you know, there's sort of this dilemma of What computer do I buy?
Speaker 0: All right, and The Mac Pro as I discussed previously was tempting and the reason it was tempting despite my dislike of the OS X, right?
Speaker 0: I don't like super hate it I'm just like.
Speaker 0: I don't like it as much as you know Fanboys, I just want to point out before you go any further think about this.
Speaker 1: We're at a point where if someone like Scott is going to buy a new computer effectively all Three major operating systems are viable choices.
Speaker 1: It's not like, you know, the OS 9 day.
Speaker 0: Well, there are other operating systems, but they're not desktop operating system.
Speaker 1: I said the major three nothing else is used for.
Speaker 1: worthwhile to you, but back in like the Mac OS 9 days It was obvious for anyone technologicals like duh You get a Linux PC or a Windows PC and you just discounted the Mac.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then before that you've obviously Discounted Linux because it was awful.
Speaker 0: I mean there was a time where it was just Windows.
Speaker 0: There is nothing else.
Speaker 1: Actually back then I think Mac was a valid competitor.
Speaker 0: because no no, no, we're talking like 1995 through like 2001.
Speaker 1: and remember there was pretty much 95 through 2001.
Speaker 0: it was pretty much just like wind held even before 95 I'd say 93 through oh one.
Speaker 0: it was pretty much windows all the way.
Speaker 0: and then oh 2001 is when Linux actually sort of became usable and then OS X came out when I don't know and that's whatever the Though SX came out is when the Mac started to get a little bit better but anyway.
Speaker 0: So it was kind of tough and to decide what I was gonna get mostly because you know I was like Linux would be the obvious answer.
Speaker 0: But the thing is I already had a Linux PC, right and I have a Linux laptop So I can already do all the stuff Linux does and if I was just gonna stick with Linux I would didn't need to buy a new computer.
Speaker 0: The reason I was buying a new computer is because I wanted to do some video editing which Linux didn't really have so much but it was Windows or Mac and it was a tough choice.
Speaker 0: and We sort of realized like what rim said there are three OS is now and it's a good and a bad thing and that each OS is really good at some things and really bad at some other things.
Speaker 0: and but none of them are perfect.
Speaker 0: and that is why the Mac Pro was so tempting despite its insane cost is because it was the Only computer capable of running all three OS is at once.
Speaker 0: plus.
Speaker 1: There is the side effect that if you buy a Mac product.
Speaker 1: What you do get is the industrial design.
Speaker 1: the fact that like our Mac mini downstairs to fight despite all its failings is In the end super great because it's completely silent and looks super good on our TV.
Speaker 0: It's really tiny But anyway, so yeah first I want to talk about like a little bit what a what an operating system actually
Speaker 1: real briefly Yeah,
Speaker 0: real briefly and then we'll just discuss what the how did I guess sort of how to pick which one is right for you?
Speaker 0: Okay, so an operating system right back in the olden days Right, like we're talking Apple 2 and previous days, you know You'd buy a computer and all the software for that computer ran Directly on the computer.
Speaker 0: so like Oregon Trail for the Apple 2 doesn't run on some Apple OS Right, it talks directly to the chips in the Apple - right it directly.
Speaker 0: So you put that floppy disk in there.
Speaker 0: the computer boots off of the Oregon Trail floppy.
Speaker 0: Now the thing is that means that when you want to write a game like Oregon Trail You have to understand the hardware in the machine And if you want to run that Oregon Trail on a different piece of hardware You have to completely rewrite the Oregon Trail a whole over again.
Speaker 0: Basically, the chip was the operating system really back in those days and it sucked.
Speaker 0: So they invented the operating system, right?
Speaker 0: Well, the operating system was actually invented a long time before that but you know It wasn't really big on the home PCs until you know like the DOS Windows Mac days which are a little bit later than the Apple - and Basically when operating system is it's just a piece of software.
Speaker 0: and that piece of software talks to the hardware.
Speaker 1: Right, and then I thought we were gonna be brief here.
Speaker 0: I am brief.
Speaker 0: all the other software talks to the operating system, so You put an operating system and the only people in the world who have to worry about Talking to hardware are people who make operating systems.
Speaker 0: and then when you write a piece of software like a game or word processor You only have to learn how to talk to the operating system thus Allowing software to run on a lot more different hardwares as opposed to okay only this one specific Machine can run Microsoft Word.
Speaker 0: No pretty much any machine can run Microsoft Word.
Speaker 0: So the question then becomes right since you have you know You have a machine and you need an operating system to go on it.
Speaker 0: How do you pick which one?
Speaker 0: You know what it.
Speaker 0: what is the difference?
Speaker 0: why even bother?
Speaker 0: why not just pick whichever one works?
Speaker 1: Well, the thing that kind of annoys me is that you know, I use all three op.
Speaker 1: In fact right now, I've got my Linux box in front of me and that's what I'm recording geek nights on.
Speaker 1: I'm currently typing up our post and going through my email and all this stuff while I'm talking and right next to me also is my laptop running Windows Vista and Both of them do their jobs and then right downstairs.
Speaker 1: I got the Mac with OS 10 and Every single one of them does something that the other two can't do and At the same time every single one of them annoys me in a different way to the point that I feel like they're all equally Useful and equally useless.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I agree entirely.
Speaker 1: basically I mean, well don't OS 10 annoys me because things are opaque and if it breaks I can't fix it because it doesn't tell me what's wrong.
Speaker 1: and when I right-click on things the context always change and the cut context changing bothers me more than anything, but When the OS does work, it's great.
Speaker 1: It's super pretty.
Speaker 1: It's super slick.
Speaker 1: The applications on it like adm are amazing.
Speaker 0: Well adm isn't a part of OS X But you can't run it on anything else.
Speaker 0: Actually, I like in Digsby now that that's my new thing.
Speaker 0: I don't need adm anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I'm leery about Digsby.
Speaker 1: Is that?
Speaker 1: why are they advertising with very very expensive advertisements all over New York City?
Speaker 0: Digsby yeah, really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, huh?
Speaker 0: I didn't see any.
Speaker 1: they're all over midtown.
Speaker 1: really I have to look for I wonder why I'm curious about where this project is going.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's just an.
Speaker 0: I am client and it works.
Speaker 0: So hey but anyway, see at the read that basically the difference between the OS is right is one.
Speaker 0: how do they talk to the hardware?
Speaker 0: All right, and what hardware can they talk to?
Speaker 0: and What software is for the OS is?
Speaker 0: that's really the big one, right?
Speaker 1: Well, there's also you know user interface.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is right is that user interface is really.
Speaker 0: I mean nowadays people sort of you know Identify the operating system by the user interface, but user interface really is a separate thing.
Speaker 0: It just so happens.
Speaker 1: Well that but that because of that it just so happens.
Speaker 1: you're about to say Effectively, they are intertwined at least with OS X and Windows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't readily change.
Speaker 0: Well, you can you can go and download different shells.
Speaker 0: No, switch it up.
Speaker 1: not for normal people.
Speaker 1: The average person doesn't know how doesn't even know they can.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't.
Speaker 1: I think we should really avoid the technical stuff and talk about just the reality of if you just boot Windows and use it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you just move windows and use you get the windows user interface and you can change it But you can't change it that much.
Speaker 1: The thing is Windows actually has a lot of intelligent defaults and for an average person if you just boot windows It'll do everything you want.
Speaker 0: I think for an average person Ubuntu Linux at least right or mo actually the major Linux desktop Distributions with any windows or Mac will all just work for an average normal person.
Speaker 1: Well redhead doesn't so much.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, actually.
Speaker 1: No, I just got a brand new redhead enterprise file.
Speaker 0: That's right at enterprise fedora will just kind of work.
Speaker 1: No fedora.
Speaker 0: Hey, when's the last time you used it?
Speaker 1: like a week ago?
Speaker 1: I have a fedora box.
Speaker 0: What was wrong with it?
Speaker 1: If you just boot a brand new fedora box and you start using it, it's fine.
Speaker 1: but then if you try to do some basic things like go and change your screen resolution a lot of times a lot of those Things just don't work Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so and right at enterprise right.
Speaker 1: five the newest newest thing.
Speaker 1: we install it all good.
Speaker 1: It's got a good Nvidia video card in the proprietary drivers come already installed because you know, it's this integrated.
Speaker 1: We bought a real Linux box tested and working.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So I go alright and I open the Nvidia settings thing and I go to change my screen resolution and it says, okay.
Speaker 1: And then it says do you want to save this your X config?
Speaker 1: if you say no then when you reboot everything gets?
Speaker 1: Reset to the defaults.
Speaker 1: if you say yes, it fails because you don't have the rights to the X configuration file.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you have to run.
Speaker 0: the Nvidia setting thing is root.
Speaker 1: Yes to announce to someone who sits down like alright This is my new computer and isn't super technical.
Speaker 1: That's already a deal breaker.
Speaker 0: I guess that is true.
Speaker 1: every other Configurator thing.
Speaker 1: if you're not root and you try to run it It prompts you for the root password or for your password or for whatever.
Speaker 1: but for the Nvidia thing No, it doesn't.
Speaker 0: Well buntu doesn't have that problem
Speaker 1: I know but right at enterprise and fedora do and even worse The only way to make it work is to add yourself to the wheel group and then use VI Sudu and edit the suit oars file to give yourself permission to do it and then run it as roots.
Speaker 0: Can't just use like gksu.
Speaker 1: that doesn't come with it by default It's not in there.
Speaker 0: I was like duh.
Speaker 0: Alright, gk sudha You know me Red Hat recently had a story that was all over the nets Like we're giving up on the desktop and people were like, uh, didn't you give up on the desktop when you split fedora off?
Speaker 0: Like years ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're marketing read at enterprise workstation as the enterprise desktop Linux and it's not A thousand times better and a lot more robust.
Speaker 0: How could they not be convinced as soon as they boot it up?
Speaker 1: Mostly it has to do with the fact that you know support and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Plus you can pay Canonical for support just like you pay Red Hat for support.
Speaker 1: It's not the same.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so what are the?
Speaker 0: what is the real decisions between the OS is here, right?
Speaker 0: Okay, OS X good things about OS X content creation content creation tools up the wazoo.
Speaker 0: Not only do you have the Adobe suite you have all the Apple stuff.
Speaker 0: You got the Pro Tools.
Speaker 0: You got everything all the content creation stuff works right and all the other content creation people use it.
Speaker 0: So it's all up in the business.
Speaker 0: You the heart it just it comes with the hardware so you don't have to worry about installing OS is or anything Tricky like that.
Speaker 0: It just works.
Speaker 0: and you know, the the hardware expects that one operating system.
Speaker 0: So, you know the the fact that everything's all integrated like that really all anything low-level that if you don't want to deal with it You're never gonna have to deal with it ever.
Speaker 0: and it looks really nice.
Speaker 0: and What else is so great about OS X?
Speaker 1: that's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: that's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: I mean, I mean, it's really pretty and slick and that actually does count for something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and also for develop, you know, it's not the greatest developers platform, but it's better than Windows.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know you do it is under the hood, right?
Speaker 0: there is.
Speaker 0: it was originally Unix down there somewhere deep inside.
Speaker 0: there is Unix there and you know you can.
Speaker 0: you can still get your Unix on in the OS X and Actually, you can install a lot of open source things like Fink and such.
Speaker 0: So you with OS X you can sort of get.
Speaker 0: you know, it's not as awesome as just running a Linux.
Speaker 0: But you can sort of get some of your Linux action and you can get all your nice-looking everything's easy action.
Speaker 1: and you get your multimedia creation and Action, if you're not a Mac person You're gonna be frustrated Anytime you want to deviate from what is already in front of you.
Speaker 1: if you want to change the behavior of something you're fucked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they're just.
Speaker 1: you're totally done.
Speaker 0: That's the one thing I don't.
Speaker 1: and if you're used to context menus and like right-click do something that all goes away Well, it doesn't all go away, but it's not.
Speaker 1: right-clicking on things will often bring up menus that don't do what you expect them to Be doing pretty much.
Speaker 1: but and also you're not gonna play any games.
Speaker 1: There's no more gaming for you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is all you can play Blizzard games.
Speaker 0: They're pretty much the only games on a Mac are like, you know, the game Blizzard World of Warcraft Starcraft Etc, etc, etc.
Speaker 1: Unless you boot camp and dual boot, but then that kind of defeats the purpose.
Speaker 1: now you're using Windows again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's sort of it's like.
Speaker 0: well, why did you buy?
Speaker 0: if you're gonna run Windows right why unless you're loaded with money Like loaded with money why buy the expensive Mac hardware, you know, the Mac hardware is overpriced.
Speaker 0: I got a computer that's almost as fast as the Mac Pro.
Speaker 0: In fact, my RAM is faster than the RAM and a Mac Pro.
Speaker 0: All right, it depends for your purpose.
Speaker 1: if I was buying another media PC for the downstairs I would still consider a Mac I'd get like the lowest 10 Mac mini.
Speaker 0: just because no I said why buy a Mac if you're gonna Run Windows.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, the thing is actually what I kind of want to do with our Mac mini as it as we have you know, it's older and older is run Windows on it downstairs instead of OS 10 because then we get the Awesomeness of that hardware.
Speaker 1: It's super silent and it's still pretty fast and reliable.
Speaker 1: it doesn't use a lot of power and we get the Bluetooth and all that this built-in but We can use the Netflix on demand in the living room.
Speaker 0: That would be okay.
Speaker 1: And the emulation.
Speaker 1: I think that's what we're gonna do with that Mac mini at some point.
Speaker 0: that's an okay plan.
Speaker 0: I see its merits but it has its.
Speaker 0: it has problems with that plan as well in That we wouldn't be able to use the handy-dandy remote that comes with the Mac mini.
Speaker 0: We never use it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I use it sometimes No Cuz I have to time when we use it.
Speaker 1: if you start the DVD player from the desktop Then that meant that remote is just gonna fuck everything up.
Speaker 0: Yeah also though It's like it's got like the slot loading DVD tray and you know stuff like that.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure exactly how well Windows would handle the Mac mini plus.
Speaker 0: the Mac mini is really slow and I think it would even be slower with Windows than it would be with Especially for what we do.
Speaker 0: we have to get an XP And we'd probably want to get the media center edition of XP that has that, you know, all that kind of stuff going on anyway.
Speaker 0: So the windows they move on to the windows.
Speaker 1: if you want to play games you got to use windows pretty much.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know you could.
Speaker 0: if you're if you need to use windows for something that's not a game You can run windows in VMware or something like that.
Speaker 0: But VMware is totally different.
Speaker 0: show.
Speaker 1: Do you know what actually do?
Speaker 0: a show on virtual?
Speaker 1: I think we did.
Speaker 1: but if you want to create content and you don't want to use OS 10 You have to use windows because the majority of the things for Linux for content creation, especially multimedia Are garbage.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean you can create content with Linux, but you're not gonna be able to create the highest quality content.
Speaker 0: You'll be okay, and it's not gonna be as easy.
Speaker 1: Oh Don't even say that with video you're hosed.
Speaker 0: Yeah video.
Speaker 0: You're pretty hosed.
Speaker 1: You're absolutely hosed.
Speaker 0: But at least you know windows right windows isn't really big on the content creation.
Speaker 0: It just so happens though that the Adobe software is for Windows and for Mac.
Speaker 0: So because of that windows is capable of decent content creation.
Speaker 0: if the Adobe suite dropped windows Windows would be like devoid of content creation.
Speaker 0: I mean that yeah, there's other programs like the Sony whatever and the avid something something.
Speaker 0: But really without the Adobe suite pretty much the Mac would be the only one in the content creation area.
Speaker 0: all right, but Windows has the gaming and Windows has the fact that it runs on just about every hardware without a lot of issues.
Speaker 0: Right like it just kind of works, and if something doesn't work you can get the driver for it And it supports you know every piece of hardware in the known universe.
Speaker 0: I mean a lot of people put down Linux saying oh, it doesn't support hardware blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: well It doesn't support as much hardware as Windows but actually all the hardware Linux supports or most of it anyway it supports automatically.
Speaker 0: a Clean Windows install really doesn't support that much hardware.
Speaker 0: you need to go out and get drivers from somewhere
Speaker 1: Install XP on a new computer a lot of times You can't see a lot of your SATA drives or all these sorts of hardware And you need special boot disks and special driver disks and all that just because the XP installer never gets updated.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there might be some hardware out there less and less every day But like there's some people they can't get their wireless card to work in Linux.
Speaker 0: right But if your wireless card does work in Linux it will just work in Windows.
Speaker 0: your wireless card might work But you might have to go out and you're probably gonna have to go out and get a driver and install and do a little Process thing.
Speaker 0: it might be easy to do it, but it's still something you have to do.
Speaker 0: OS X because it only runs and is only meant to run on Macs.
Speaker 0: It really supports almost no hardware.
Speaker 0: I mean it actually supports more hardware than you think it would.
Speaker 1: but at the same time we bought we had a wireless USB keyboard Yep, and OS X didn't support it.
Speaker 1: every time it booted every time it logged out every time anything happened It would say hey I can't figure out what kind of keyboard you've got and make you type all this crap so it could figure out what the keyboard Was and then it would work fine, but it would always forget those settings and make you do it again.
Speaker 1: But even worse if you like force-killed the thing that was saying.
Speaker 1: hey, I don't understand your keyboard.
Speaker 1: It just worked fine.
Speaker 1: Anyway, OS X just was a jerk about it Yep, so we eventually we just gave.
Speaker 1: we bought the stupid Mac wireless keyboard which by the way is a very hot little piece of hard.
Speaker 0: Well, and I don't really I won't like it for a desk, but for a living room.
Speaker 0: It's pretty awesome because it's really small It's wireless.
Speaker 0: It's Bluetooth So it doesn't take up USB slot and it works.
Speaker 0: and it works well with the Mac.
Speaker 0: You know it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like having a little control panel.
Speaker 0: You know eject Volume up volume down.
Speaker 0: you know it's.
Speaker 0: it's really great little media center controlling thing But on my desk it'd be terrible.
Speaker 0: So yeah windows the other advantage of windows right is that it runs Pretty much all the other soft all the proprietary software in the known universe, which is big for businesses.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know people don't think about it that much right, but let's say like my uncle.
Speaker 0: He's a dentist, right?
Speaker 0: He has lots of software that he needs to run as a dentist.
Speaker 0: He's got you know the Owns.
Speaker 0: the old is the dentistry.
Speaker 0: It's his dentistry, so he needs accounting software, right?
Speaker 0: He needs software to deal with people's insurance and dental records.
Speaker 0: He's in the software to talk to the x-ray machine and store all the x-rays in a big database.
Speaker 1: Actually, that's one way where if people really want to get Linux on the desktop and corporations that means open source developers have to get On all these kind of niche boring proprietary kind of things.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's called a vertical market is the correct term.
Speaker 0: I believe you know like What other operating system is gonna have the the dental x-ray software windows?
Speaker 0: You're not gonna get that on Linux or Mac.
Speaker 1: Software might just run in wine, but that's in my run it.
Speaker 0: there is a chance it might run in wine.
Speaker 1: Yes, but here's the way I look at it.
Speaker 0: If you're buying a computer to run that software running it and why it is probably not the best idea.
Speaker 1: But in the end, here's the way I really look at it to me By default it's bridge Linux because Linux if you don't need something that Linux cannot provide Then Linux is great.
Speaker 1: It's like the default and it's free.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then if you need something it's like you looks like I do this and this and this.
Speaker 1: I don't need anything or I want to play games suddenly.
Speaker 1: All right now I need Windows and Windows will do everything I need and play games or I need Adobe whatever.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Well, I can use Windows or Apple All right, which one of those two do I want?
Speaker 1: and then it's a matter of preference.
Speaker 1: But if you don't need one of those proprietary things I feel like it's at the point where you can go with Linux and it'll do everything you want and even your grandma can use It.
Speaker 0: yeah Well, it is the thing about Linux right?
Speaker 0: is that while Linux might not have the content creation and they don't have the gaming so Much though they actually have more gaming than Mac if you don't count the Blizzard stuff, right actually a lot more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Wesnoth is pretty hot and well, it's not this on all of us.
Speaker 1: It doesn't count but it's on Linux.
Speaker 0: I guess Yeah, but Linux actually has you know, lots of open-source gaming kind of action going on But what Linux does?
Speaker 0: the other thing that the other OS is don't is that it has all the basics covered, right?
Speaker 0: You're way browsing your instant messaging your office saying all your normal stuff.
Speaker 0: It's got your mp3 playing your video watching actually is the best video watching OS I say, right?
Speaker 0: And it's got all the other things.
Speaker 0: it might not do them Amazingly, but there's a piece of open soft soft sort of software out there.
Speaker 0: That'll do it like open sauce open sauce.
Speaker 0: Yes, now it, you know, for example audio recording, okay You're not gonna get your super Pro Tools, but you get your resounds in.
Speaker 0: your audacity Is which you're?
Speaker 0: you know, they're on.
Speaker 0: the audacity is on.
Speaker 0: the other OS is too, but you know And it does the job.
Speaker 0: it can do a lot of jobs.
Speaker 0: The thing about Linux though, is that on the other level the below-seeing level where it talks to the hardware You know the Linux kernel what what an operating system does talks to the hardware So the software doesn't have to talk to the hardware.
Speaker 0: The way Linux talks to the hardware, even though it can't talk to as much heart different hardware as Windows can The way it talks to the hardware is better in every way.
Speaker 0: I mean you go to a computer science class, right and they say blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: They'll talk about like memory management, which is something every operating system does is to manage the memory.
Speaker 0: Windows kind of Windows kind of waste your right, right, but it says Linux, you know, it'll be like.
Speaker 0: this is the best way to manage the memory.
Speaker 0: That's the way Linux does it.
Speaker 0: Windows doesn't do it that way Mac does it all sort of that way.
Speaker 0: Linux does it the correct?
Speaker 0: Computer science way and it does everything the correct computer science way.
Speaker 0: It is under the hood Superior and pretty much most fashions, you know.
Speaker 0: So if you don't need a piece of software that won't can't talk to Linux.
Speaker 0: Linux is the best because it talks to your hardware more properly than the other operating systems and you're gonna get less Crashing more security more stability and it's free.
Speaker 1: The thing is we keep saying Linux For the purposes of this discussion.
Speaker 0: We basically mean Ubuntu for a desktop user.
Speaker 0: Ubuntu is the way to go.
Speaker 1: We're talking about talking about servers.
Speaker 0: I didn't even come up But in terms of something that talks to your hardware links kernel is what talks to the hardware in the fantastic But no one cares about that.
Speaker 1: They think oh I use Linux.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's what they think.
Speaker 1: All right, I think that's it.
Speaker 1: I think we're back in the swing of things.
Speaker 1: There'll be shows all week.
Speaker 1: Don't worry
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's it's it's a it's a crazy world where simultaneously like, you know blessed and cursed in that, you know back in the day It's like Mac or PC blah
Speaker 1: blah blah blah,
Speaker 0: you know, and there'd be all these fights and there would be a clear winner here A clear winner there.
Speaker 1: It's at the point where you can't.
Speaker 1: anyone who says any one OS now of the big three is Absolutely superior unqualified is Bullshitting you because that's you can't say that anymore.
Speaker 1: They all do something better than the other two.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's sort of like the same department.
Speaker 0: We're getting to with the game consoles.
Speaker 1: Also, is that you know, I got like If you're a hardcore gamer, you kind of need to own all three consoles.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like we get your DS your PSPs Oh, yeah, DS.
Speaker 0: yet on all five console PS threes, you know your wheeze your x360s, right?
Speaker 0: You know these consoles.
Speaker 0: and back in the day You know people always argue as if there there's this sort of thinking.
Speaker 0: there has to be One is better and one is worse.
Speaker 0: period right something is better than the other thing.
Speaker 0: But really now everything is sort of equally good just in different ways and it's Good and bad and that it's not perfect.
Speaker 0: So you'll always be pissed off because it's never gonna be perfect But you're always gonna have something good no matter what you choose.
Speaker 0: So what are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: You know what I'm gonna do me into.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna eat some dinner.
Speaker 0: yeah dinner.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm.
Speaker 0: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: You can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives Visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution Non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.