Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, April 30th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm Rim.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, Eska, Blo, Nay, Dun, Dun, Dun, Dun.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So yesterday we talked a bit about how we had Mario Kart Wii and how we were worried about some things.
Speaker 1: And I would just like to point out in case anyone says anything that today, when I got home from work, we started it up and immediately discovered the menu that lets us change everything.
Speaker 1: So now we now race with no A.I.
Speaker 1: and pretty much no catch up items.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And even though the single player in Mario Kart Wii is pretty much just a practice to build up your skills combined with the unlocking bullshit.
Speaker 1: Everyone said it was annoying rubber band A.I.
Speaker 1: and I'd expected annoying rubber band A.I.
Speaker 1: I was unprepared for how annoying it was.
Speaker 0: It's pretty annoying, but basically the single player exists only to build your skills and to also unlock all the bullshit, which should be unlocked from the beginning.
Speaker 0: And the multiplayer is where the real game is at.
Speaker 0: And the multiplayer, I must say, is excellent day, as long as you change the rules to turn off the bullshit.
Speaker 0: Mighty fine.
Speaker 0: And I beat Rim.
Speaker 0: I was using the wheel and he was using the nunchuck.
Speaker 0: So that's like if I beat him in a foot race wearing a ball and chain.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe except for the fact that one, you couldn't beat me in one hundred and fifty CC.
Speaker 0: I don't think the wheel can do a hundred.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And do I have played the game maybe ten minutes total.
Speaker 0: See, beating you with the wheel at one hundred and fifty CC would be like beating you in a foot race wearing a ball and chain uphill.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll see.
Speaker 1: We'll see, because downhill actually might be an advantage.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: The analogy breaks down.
Speaker 0: So you got any other stuff to talk about?
Speaker 0: It's Wednesday.
Speaker 1: It's anime day.
Speaker 1: There's as usual.
Speaker 1: There's not like there's that much.
Speaker 0: Oh, I was gonna.
Speaker 0: I was gonna watch an anime today.
Speaker 1: Oh, because I've been kind of busting your balls about watching anime.
Speaker 1: So I was being the number one anime podcast in the English speaking world.
Speaker 1: We kind of got to got to get on this and talk about some anime.
Speaker 0: So I was going to watch the Kazu No Yojimbo DVD, even though I watched the first four episodes of the show a long time ago.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I thought that, too.
Speaker 1: And I was like, all right, I'll just skim through the first DVD and then send it back.
Speaker 1: And then the first episode started and I didn't remember any of that.
Speaker 0: I don't remember anything in the show whatsoever.
Speaker 0: I remember that it's a story about a stranger comes to town.
Speaker 0: It's that's all I remember.
Speaker 1: It's Fistful of Dollars.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's well, I know Fistful of Dollars in terms of throwing rock than paper twice.
Speaker 1: I still you know, that's really all you know.
Speaker 0: That's all I know.
Speaker 1: God Fistful of Dollars is kind of awesome.
Speaker 1: You should look it up.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the other thing is I got to look up.
Speaker 1: I keep forgetting.
Speaker 0: Finish it.
Speaker 1: I was saying I kind of suspect that the character designer is the same person from Gundam 00.
Speaker 0: Check it.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so I was going to watch Kazu no Yojimbo on the train on my laptop.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I even brought I remember to bring my optical drive.
Speaker 0: I brought the Netflix DVD.
Speaker 0: I was all set.
Speaker 0: I forgot.
Speaker 0: I had recently, though, upgraded to the new Hardy Heron Ubuntu and I had not installed the new DVD playing software.
Speaker 1: Ah, CSS.
Speaker 0: So I couldn't play the DVD and I didn't have an internet connection on the train.
Speaker 1: And well, I guess tomorrow, you know, you could have just written some sort of D.C.S.S Oh, yes.
Speaker 0: Because I remember the prime number.
Speaker 0: You know, it would have been funny.
Speaker 1: What if you'd been wearing the shirt?
Speaker 0: If I was wearing the shirt, then, yes, I could have done it.
Speaker 0: But even though, you know, even writing a D.C.S.S.
Speaker 0: right now, I would have to rip the DVD, run it through the D.C.S.S.
Speaker 0: and then just it would have taken my CPU and laptop not powerful enough to.
Speaker 0: you would have taken by the time it was done, I would have been off the train, basically.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But it's fun to think about.
Speaker 1: Plus what if the train got stuck, you know, 41 hours?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got to admit, I'm saddened by the fact that the Internet has made a million kind of parodies of that guy stuck in an elevator video and they're all awful.
Speaker 1: I had the pleasure of watching the first 10 seconds of stuck in an elevator for 41 hours with diarrhea.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But someone made that whole video.
Speaker 0: It's going to be next week.
Speaker 0: So between now and next week, I'm going to be watching some animes for a week.
Speaker 0: That should give us some anime shows to do.
Speaker 0: Oh, snap.
Speaker 1: Actually, after we watch some more Casa, no, you Jimbo, I think you've got to watch some Boca.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I did.
Speaker 0: I watched a bunch of.
Speaker 0: I just didn't finish it.
Speaker 1: Got to finish it.
Speaker 1: Can't talk about it.
Speaker 0: I was totally liking that show.
Speaker 0: That's my kind of show.
Speaker 1: Well, if you were liking it from what you'd seen, you'd like it a lot more.
Speaker 1: Pretty much right after you stop watching.
Speaker 0: My only problem with that show is that I have met knowledge that the man that it is that diverges from the manga that I've never read.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: I'll say this.
Speaker 1: The divergence that we'd heard about was that the person doing the anime wondered if they could get away with killing fewer children.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And I kind of want to read them.
Speaker 0: It makes me think, though, that, like, even if the show is great, it makes me really want the manga and think that the manga is better, even though it might not be.
Speaker 1: So apparently you're a you're pro children killing.
Speaker 0: I'm pro children dying.
Speaker 0: Children killing robot story.
Speaker 1: See, the thing is, if the anime was the kind of lightened, less sad, less hardcore version, I can't imagine what's in that manga.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Good God.
Speaker 1: I cried like four times throughout the last five episodes of Boca.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I started crying at the end of almost every episode because they kill a kid like every episode.
Speaker 1: Good God.
Speaker 0: OK, so I'm going to instead of a news because there is no news really.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there is.
Speaker 1: There's there's news that people are probably screaming about the fact that we haven't talked about.
Speaker 1: Maybe I can do my news quick.
Speaker 0: You want to do your news?
Speaker 1: I have a lot to say about it.
Speaker 1: But at the New York Comic Con, there was one kind of important announcement.
Speaker 1: A lot of people were lamenting the fact that in all the anime industry problems, Gurren Lagann, the TV was not.
Speaker 1: it just kind of fell off the license truck and no one had picked it back up.
Speaker 0: Well, well, ATV ran into that problem with that company or whatever.
Speaker 0: They lost a bunch of shows and everything was getting weird.
Speaker 1: Well, it just so happens that Gurren Lagann has been picked back up really by Bandai Entertainment.
Speaker 0: Oh, see, that's kind of surprising.
Speaker 0: So that definitely see anime companies.
Speaker 0: So hush hush.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But that basically confirms ATV lost the license completely and Bandai bought it.
Speaker 1: I'll admit, I'm sure Dave and Joel are going to cry about this and Daryl Surratt and all those people.
Speaker 1: But I have not seen even a second of this show.
Speaker 1: And while I've heard a lot about it until now, when I went to the anime news network and I see this picture.
Speaker 1: that's obviously from it, I didn't even know what it was about or what it looked like.
Speaker 0: I knew it was a robot show by Gainax, right?
Speaker 0: I just it is.
Speaker 0: It's a Gainax robot show, right?
Speaker 1: It's a robot show by Gainax.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Because there was that other like clamp robot show that was pretty recent and I was getting the two shows confused because this one's Tenga, Toppen, Gurren Lagann, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: What was the other one?
Speaker 0: I forget.
Speaker 1: It's weird how we watch so much anime because I didn't watch either one.
Speaker 1: So I don't know how this show slipped under my radar.
Speaker 1: I just kept having other things to watch and other things to do.
Speaker 1: And everyone's saying it's great.
Speaker 1: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: Well, probably watch it at some point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll definitely watch at some point.
Speaker 0: I just want to point out, though, that that what you lost your train of thought.
Speaker 1: It's gone.
Speaker 0: I got it.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: Bandai Entertainment.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, a lot.
Speaker 0: You know, Bandai Entertainment, first of all, is not Bandai Visual.
Speaker 0: Bandai Visual sucks.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But actually, I guess this sort of does hold for Bandai Visual, too, in that many things about Bandai Entertainment and Bandai Visual do not please me.
Speaker 0: But over the history of all anime production in the
Speaker 0: U.S.,
Speaker 0: well, not production, but anime distribution in the
Speaker 0: Bandai Entertainment and Bandai Visual.
Speaker 0: for all their failings, they consistently have the best selection of titles.
Speaker 0: If you were to pick, you know, if you were to tell me that I could get one free anime series.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But I had to pick the U.S.
Speaker 0: distributor and then one of their titles would be given to me for free.
Speaker 1: I would pick Bandai Entertainment every time because they're the greatest odds of getting a good show, especially because I remember back in like the late 90s, early 2000s, if you thought of a good anime, you always remember that Bandai logo right before it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That emotion thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All that business.
Speaker 1: But yeah, that's all I got.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen the show.
Speaker 1: I can't say anything about it.
Speaker 1: I guess you should listen to Dave and Joel if you want to hear about that show.
Speaker 0: Oh, why can't I find.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Code Geass was.
Speaker 0: that was the show that I always got.
Speaker 1: I've heard that was pretty bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Code Geass is the new clamp robot show.
Speaker 0: And tank of top and girl and Lagan is the guy next robot show.
Speaker 0: And I think I did watch the first episode of Code Geass, even though I completely forget it entirely.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: I don't know, because it was a new show.
Speaker 0: I watched, you know, the one episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess.
Speaker 0: But because I had the shows confused for so long, I think I put off the Lagan thinking it was the other one.
Speaker 0: And now now I've got it sorted out.
Speaker 0: Just now, as I recorded the show, I sorted it out.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: So you watch a show that you thought was Lagan, but wasn't.
Speaker 1: And then when you saw Lagan, you assumed that it was the show you'd already watched.
Speaker 0: No, that's not true.
Speaker 0: What had happened is I saw a show Code Geass, Lelouch de rebellion, right?
Speaker 0: Later, I saw that there was a new robot show called Tank of Top and Girl and Lagan.
Speaker 0: And I had thought that I'm like, oh, I seen that show when I hadn't seen it.
Speaker 0: I thought that, you know, because the names I got, even though the names aren't similar at all, at all, they're sort of complex, kind of crazy names for robot shows.
Speaker 0: There are too many robot shows.
Speaker 0: So I thought they were the same show.
Speaker 0: You know, I was confused.
Speaker 0: But now it's not like great as I'm recording this.
Speaker 0: My confusion has been cleared and now I will be swiftly corrected in possibly the in the coming weeks.
Speaker 0: watching of girl and Lagan, at least some episodes.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So obviously, because you were complaining about the lack of news, you don't have a news.
Speaker 0: I don't have news.
Speaker 1: What do you got?
Speaker 0: I got a geek back.
Speaker 0: Geek bite.
Speaker 0: God damn it.
Speaker 1: You're bad at this.
Speaker 0: I'm real bad.
Speaker 0: I got a geek bite.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So I go and I try to look at what comics I've read recently, you know, try to pick something out there.
Speaker 0: And I was looking and nothing really felt like a like a real strong geek bite candidate until I saw Orion.
Speaker 1: Now, did you read all of Orion?
Speaker 0: What is what do you?
Speaker 0: what do you?
Speaker 0: what's the definition of read?
Speaker 1: Because I'll admit there are certain moments where a shirotasm will kind of overcome me.
Speaker 1: Oh, and I'll realize that I've been flipping pages for like five pages, looking at pictures in the back, glossing over words in the back of the book.
Speaker 0: There's a dictionary and author's notes, which would probably be very helpful if I read it.
Speaker 0: But I did not read that.
Speaker 1: Wait.
Speaker 1: So he at least he made a dictionary and author's notes, not like the other Ghost in the Shell manga, where the ramblings were just kind of all over the pages.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So Masamune, Shiro, Shiro Masamune, the guy who did Ghost in the Shell.
Speaker 0: That guy, the guy sort of famous manga guy.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: This is one of his manga.
Speaker 0: It's all in one book from Dark Horse.
Speaker 0: It's eighteen dollars.
Speaker 0: I didn't pay eighteen dollars, thankfully.
Speaker 0: And I got to say this about Shiro.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: He is Shirotastic.
Speaker 0: Well, Ghost in the Shell is awesome.
Speaker 0: Super awesome.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And for some reason, I keep buying all of his other works.
Speaker 0: I buy the Appleseed.
Speaker 0: I buy the Tank Police.
Speaker 0: I buy the Orion.
Speaker 1: Tank Police is awesome.
Speaker 0: Tank Police is awesome.
Speaker 1: Appleseed pretty hot.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Appleseed is OK.
Speaker 1: Well, the Appleseed movie was really good.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And I buy all his manga.
Speaker 0: Thing is, most of his manga are kind of just crazy and don't make sense and aren't really that.
Speaker 1: No, no, we're not talking on the Trigun level.
Speaker 1: It's no Naito.
Speaker 0: No, it's definitely not on the Trigun level of not making.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's I guess there's two kinds of not making sense in a manga.
Speaker 1: There's the Naito Trigun of you flip pages and wonder if pages were missing and can't tell what characters are involved in a scene.
Speaker 1: And then there's the Shiro where there'll be a picture of a tank and this vomit of words around the tank on the page.
Speaker 1: And some of the words are talking about how we didn't draw the blah, blah, blah on the tank because he didn't think it would look good, but he knows they have to be there.
Speaker 1: And then the rest of it is complaining about, like some military political issue in Japan in the future, but not in the future of the manga you're reading, just at some other year.
Speaker 1: And it has nothing to do with the comic at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Orion, basically the deal with Orion is this.
Speaker 0: I'm going to, instead of, you know, Shiro usually likes to go off about science and technology and all that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or military stuff, right?
Speaker 0: Or something like that, right?
Speaker 0: In Orion, he basically makes up this universe where it's all like supernatural fantasy of gods and demons and snakes and monsters and...
Speaker 1: Wait, wait, wait.
Speaker 1: Gods, demons, monsters.
Speaker 0: Evil witches and magic and...
Speaker 1: Okay, gods, demons, monsters, evil witches, magic, snakes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, snakes.
Speaker 1: Snakes aren't that special in and of themselves.
Speaker 0: Well, no, I think they're big, magical sort of dragons.
Speaker 0: They keep talking about like nagas and things and, you know, this sort of crazy stuff.
Speaker 1: Not just, I picture like a wizard and a dragon and a Godzilla and then a snake.
Speaker 0: No, this is a semi-Watchmen spoiler, but there are scenes reminiscent of the ending of Watchmen in here.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's basically, it's just really fucked up and he can't tell what's going on.
Speaker 0: It's like he's just making up like this fantasy shit as he goes along.
Speaker 0: And there's a few cute parts, I guess, where like someone gets randomly, like this one scene where you see the girl talking to like these cute aliens, they're sort of octopus-ish, right?
Speaker 0: And the next scene, like she turns someone into one of the cute aliens and it's like hehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehe hehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehehe.
Speaker 0: and you know it's like a kingdom or something.
Speaker 0: and then like this demon guy comes out and there's gonna be some sort of apocalypse or something.
Speaker 0: maybe.
Speaker 0: and you know there people are trying to like set up these crazy magic spells.
Speaker 0: they're gonna make good or bad things happen or like all the evil in the world or all the good in the world is gonna come spilling in or out in some direction or something.
Speaker 0: and there's all kinds of made-up words all over the place.
Speaker 1: and now is this proper noun gobbledygook or just shirotasm.
Speaker 0: okay you ready I'm gonna read I'm gonna read some.
Speaker 0: some random speech bubbles you ready.
Speaker 0: okay naga system I'm ready.
Speaker 0: once you activate I'll fry you with an octo trigram.
Speaker 1: that makes perfect sense.
Speaker 0: it's an aqua loco type with a twisted hydro element an incredibly powerful Vajra naga force on this planet in 64 harmonics it'll reach threshold that everything will disintegrate.
Speaker 1: all right I I feel really bad.
Speaker 1: now you want to know why.
Speaker 1: when I read ghost in the shell he would say it's the same.
Speaker 1: it's like jabberwocky where you all the all the structure makes sense but the words don't mean anything.
Speaker 1: but in ghost in the shell when you read some of those words you think your brain says oh that was some sciency technical thing and I understand it and you know what.
Speaker 1: your brain just lying to you because it makes no more sense than what that just sounded like.
Speaker 1: that just used more fake words.
Speaker 0: okay I'm gonna read four bubbles.
Speaker 0: it's a dialogue between two characters character a then character B then character a then character B again right and that's all.
Speaker 0: that's how I'm gonna end this little geek bite.
Speaker 0: okay ready character a baby.
Speaker 0: he's a deep demon guy who was summoned.
Speaker 0: perhaps in another 200 Sykes or so we'll see a sorcerer's shell created that can truly discriminate between good and evil.
Speaker 0: character B. and when that time comes human spirits filled with good shall become deities ape spirits shall assume human form and human spirits tainted with bad karma shall remain human asterisk.
Speaker 0: there is a Buddha nature for each level of the soul.
Speaker 0: there are infinite levels of the soul and infinite numbers of corresponding Buddha natures.
Speaker 0: the spiritual hierarchy further subdivides the levels existing between apes men and gods.
Speaker 0: the physical body is only a manifestation of the spirit.
Speaker 0: character a again the human form is not the human soul.
Speaker 0: its eyes merely see what is transient.
Speaker 0: its ears do not hear the voice of the true spirit its words do not state the truth and its mind is ruled by karma.
Speaker 0: character B if psychoscience can weaken the barriers to the physical form words in mind it may become a legitimate method of reaching the truth.
Speaker 0: it's just a bunch of made-up talk that's really complicated.
Speaker 0: it makes no sense.
Speaker 0: and I'm picking random pages people random pages.
Speaker 0: I did not prepare this at all.
Speaker 0: I opened the book and flipped around looking for speech bubbles with lots of words and they were not hard to find.
Speaker 0: don't buy this unless you really hate yourself.
Speaker 1: you could have a contest and give it to someone.
Speaker 0: no I want to keep us.
Speaker 0: I have the whole shiro collection.
Speaker 1: what are you gonna do with that?
Speaker 0: give the whole thing to somebody.
Speaker 1: Wow on the condition it's kind of like those clauses in some sort of Don Knotts movie where you can have the mansion in the fortune if you spend the night in the haunted house.
Speaker 1: good one you can have Shiro's manga.
Speaker 1: if you read it it's getting down.
Speaker 1: oh god it's things of the day.
Speaker 1: I'm sure many of you have seen this but I'm also sure just judging from conversations I've had with our listeners in the past that many of you are not familiar with this.
Speaker 1: now you're an anime con today and there's always the kind of fan parodies.
Speaker 0: well actually a lot of anime cons don't have them.
Speaker 0: it's sort of you know it was.
Speaker 0: it was a lot more popular I think like a few years ago like one or two and it's sort of spayed it a little bit you know but it was pretty big for a time.
Speaker 1: well I guess the really big cons always have them in some capacity and even though actually a lot of the kinds of things that used to be fan parodies are now just in anime music videos straight up or kind of put into that realm.
Speaker 1: but yeah a long time ago I think it was called like otaku.
Speaker 1: this is otaku to them or something.
Speaker 0: yes that was it.
Speaker 0: I was gonna ask what the name of that thing was.
Speaker 0: we rented it from the anime club library and VHS and watch it as a group.
Speaker 1: yeah this was one of the earlier known to American fans fanfare is one of them more widely distributed early fan pair we were able to get our hands on because in like 2000 2001 times yeah but most people hadn't seen anything like that before.
Speaker 1: and then this kind of made the rounds.
Speaker 1: and then there was this surge for a couple years of everyone going.
Speaker 1: oh my god fan parody.
Speaker 0: I remember we watched this is otaku them.
Speaker 0: it's like a group and it would.
Speaker 0: for some reason it was hilarious.
Speaker 1: it was utterly hilarious but in reality look I watched it again a couple years ago lame.
Speaker 0: so so lame.
Speaker 1: I wanted to have because I've seen in my life a grand total of three fan parodies.
Speaker 0: I've seen one and a half.
Speaker 1: this is otaku them which is you know what it is.
Speaker 1: it kind of started it funny to watch in a group if you're not into anime enough to know a lot about it and you're not.
Speaker 0: because remember if you're sort of like a young naive punk kid with a bunch of naive punk kid friends like a high school anime club or freshman in a college anime club this will freaking knock your socks off.
Speaker 1: but remember this is from an era before YouTube back when anime hell and things like that worked a lot better.
Speaker 1: nowadays you've seen things like this already times a thousand yep.
Speaker 1: but the other two that I've seen and that made a big splash back in the day were Nescaflowne.
Speaker 0: I didn't see that one.
Speaker 1: it's not online I can't find it easily.
Speaker 1: I didn't look for a torrent or anything but they kind of screen it at.
Speaker 0: cons is anything like Nescafe.
Speaker 1: no Alan anyway I wanted to have a link to that because I wanted to make that my thing of the day since we're talking about tenku no escaflowne tonight but couldn't find it.
Speaker 1: so I went with the third the classic redeaf.
Speaker 0: ah redeaf now perhaps the most widely famed of the the fan parodies.
Speaker 1: now this is another one of those things where if you saw redeaf at a convention a long time ago and have fond memories of it don't watch my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: all you're gonna do is go.
Speaker 1: wow that was stupid.
Speaker 1: wow that wasn't funny at all except for the gendo part.
Speaker 0: yeah pretty much the only good part is the.
Speaker 1: it's getting down but I don't know there was something about watching this with a whole group of people at a convention and the fact that it was so poorly done.
Speaker 1: I mean the voice acting is super bad.
Speaker 1: half the time you can't even tell what people are saying.
Speaker 1: misato is called in.
Speaker 1: they phoned in the role as in literally the woman playing misato called them and they recorded it.
Speaker 1: yep it's it's just it's awful in every regard.
Speaker 1: but at the same time this is a piece of anime history and I think it's an anime.
Speaker 0: it's a US anime fandom history not not anime history.
Speaker 0: anime history would be like you know Miyazaki's notebook you know I think it's a piece of anime history.
Speaker 1: this is kind of.
Speaker 1: this is what was spawned in America.
Speaker 1: this is the result.
Speaker 1: Japan this is what you caused.
Speaker 1: okay it's it's actually kind of funny.
Speaker 1: there is the nice one bit at the end that I actually really like where they kind of point out the stupidity of the end of the show Escaflowne.
Speaker 1: but they're like.
Speaker 0: so you mean Evangelion.
Speaker 1: yeah yeah I said Escaflowne didn't I?
Speaker 1: yes he does.
Speaker 1: they're like.
Speaker 1: so you gave him the thing he's like.
Speaker 1: yeah you gave him the thing.
Speaker 1: oh shit and that's all I got.
Speaker 1: yeah you watch and see.
Speaker 0: if you've never seen this if you've never seen Evangelion though and you watch Redeaf.
Speaker 1: it does kind of spoil it yeah but in so far as you know what everybody dies in Escaflowne.
Speaker 0: everybody yeah everybody dies in both.
Speaker 1: Redeaf is an Evangelion fan parody yes as opposed to Nescaflowne which if anyone can find an online copy and send it my way I would be very happy.
Speaker 0: I'm sure some links to Nescaflowne are coming to us as soon as you push the upload.
Speaker 1: I'm sure Nescaflowne is as bad as Redeaf was remembered to be I'm sure but I remember.
Speaker 0: there was a time though where you I had already realized the fan parodies were lame and you were all like oh man I'm gonna go watch the fan parodies.
Speaker 1: it's so awesome.
Speaker 1: fan parodies can be awesome.
Speaker 1: there have been some super awesome ones since then.
Speaker 1: the thing is I just it's hard to find the good ones.
Speaker 0: I just remember that one OdaCon like you were super hyped to go to the fan parodies and I was like hell.
Speaker 1: no see I wasn't super hyped and the only reason I didn't go was I was gonna go and then I got hungry and I realized that if I didn't eat right then there was no way I would have eaten before the concert.
Speaker 1: so I totally didn't go to the fan parodies because food at that mall across the street is very important.
Speaker 0: it is indeed.
Speaker 0: oh I got to do a thing a day right?
Speaker 1: oh I guess you do okay.
Speaker 0: so check this out.
Speaker 0: here's the thing of the day that I cannot vouch for the quality of.
Speaker 1: oh great stellar things of the day tonight.
Speaker 0: yeah this is a webcomic right that I have not read.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's good.
Speaker 1: are you linking to it?
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's bad because I was really desperate for a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I got like four actually between Emily and I do.
Speaker 1: I've learned about three or four new comics some of them webcomics that I really got to read.
Speaker 0: but there is evidence once about Viking.
Speaker 0: yes there is evidence those to suggest that this webcomic is worth talking about.
Speaker 0: first of all the webcomic right.
Speaker 0: the art is by Paul Duffield who if you look at this art it's pretty high quality arts.
Speaker 0: he's sorry he's very good with the colors that I've recognized.
Speaker 0: that name no okay the name you should recognize is the writer of this weekly webcomic Warren Ellis.
Speaker 1: I don't know who that is.
Speaker 0: he is.
Speaker 0: he is the famous writer of non webcomics such as such as such as transmetropolitan.
Speaker 1: I didn't like that at all.
Speaker 0: I don't care if you liked it.
Speaker 1: the point is is that I gained no enjoyment from it.
Speaker 1: I remember when Steve had it we were at the shore and he brought all this transmetropolitan.
Speaker 1: he's like yeah this is like a great comic and I remember I read like all of it and it's oh my god I didn't like it at all.
Speaker 0: it was just awful.
Speaker 0: he also wrote that fell comic.
Speaker 0: did you read that one yet?
Speaker 0: nah no he also wrote planetary.
Speaker 0: he's written a lot of comics but the fell I think is my favorite comic by him is definitely the awesome.
Speaker 0: I mean we're gonna talk about that soon because I had the first volume and the second volume I think is pending pretty pretty quickly I'll try to read it.
Speaker 0: yeah it's it's an awesome detective thing.
Speaker 0: Emily liked it.
Speaker 0: she thought it was.
Speaker 1: I imagine I'll really like it.
Speaker 1: yes I've been watching a lot of anime.
Speaker 0: so Warren Ellis is a famous comic writer.
Speaker 0: right whether you like his stuff or not.
Speaker 0: I mean you don't have to like his stuff.
Speaker 0: it's not like say Alan Moore.
Speaker 0: we have to like his and he make it a webcomic.
Speaker 0: that's free and weekly and it's called freak angels freak angels calm.
Speaker 0: there's 11 episodes in each episode is six pages and you just go to the first episode and start reading and it shouldn't take you that long.
Speaker 0: I mean they're on episode 11. so what 66 pages to catch up at that?
Speaker 0: shouldn't take you that long to read 66 pages of comics?
Speaker 0: that's like three flimsy comic books worth right.
Speaker 0: so they've already got one trade.
Speaker 0: shouldn't take more than an hour to read through this even if you're slow.
Speaker 0: so you know free comic by a real.
Speaker 0: you know high quality you know professional comic writer you know that that's thing of the day worthy I say but you haven't read it.
Speaker 0: no I yeah.
Speaker 1: and then we talked about redead.
Speaker 1: yeah and now that yeah.
Speaker 1: well I think we gotta balance that out.
Speaker 0: so you know we don't know you're suing.
Speaker 0: this is bad.
Speaker 0: it could be good.
Speaker 1: I'm not assuming anything.
Speaker 1: I'm taking an agnostic and unknowing position.
Speaker 0: you you do but you associated it with Orion and redead.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying that there was a train and the trend might continue.
Speaker 1: it might be us.
Speaker 0: I don't see a trend.
Speaker 0: the trend is no it's bad.
Speaker 0: no it's bad.
Speaker 0: who knows?
Speaker 0: well that's not a pattern.
Speaker 0: unless we then talk about two more things that are bad and then one more thing that is questionable then it would be a pattern of bad bad questionable bad bad questionable.
Speaker 0: repeat.
Speaker 1: anyway tonight regardless we're gonna talk about one of those kind of big shows but luckily because it's a big show we can't really talk about it in any super deep detail.
Speaker 1: partly yes Scott hasn't watched it in a long time.
Speaker 0: I've only watched the entire show once.
Speaker 0: that was like more than five years ago.
Speaker 1: I'll say this this is a show that I was in 2002.
Speaker 1: I believe I have seen all the way through four times and then some.
Speaker 0: I've seen all the way through once.
Speaker 1: it's a show.
Speaker 0: I've seen the movie twice and I've seen the first four episodes twice.
Speaker 0: that's includes the time that I saw the whole thing.
Speaker 1: well it's a show where despite having seen it four and some times I cried at the end every time and you know when I say a cry because I tried a lot of anime but usually it's like Reaper.
Speaker 1: it's like Scott did just finish the Prince of Nothing trilogy.
Speaker 0: by the way I'm making all sorts of Prince of Nothing jokes now bitches.
Speaker 1: yeah you're a little late to that.
Speaker 1: you know what you're like.
Speaker 1: now though you're like those people who played portal like yesterday and they come to the party and they're like haha the cake is a lie and we're all like haha yeah yeah
Speaker 0: but you know what the difference is is that I'm much more clever and that's I'm making the jokes that no one else makes.
Speaker 1: we made the deeper joke.
Speaker 0: no you did.
Speaker 1: yes we did.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna have to go digging for some deeper jokes.
Speaker 0: then cuz they were the Prince of Nothing is a minefield of jokes.
Speaker 1: oh my god it is it is it is a no it is not a comedy.
Speaker 1: it is that there is so much in there.
Speaker 1: it's the kind of thing where you can reference it with other people in very clever way.
Speaker 0: it'd be Prince of.
Speaker 0: this is sort of a bad in poor taste but I'm gonna compare it to Cambodia in terms of its humor value it's kind of true and in terms of the you know minefields get it.
Speaker 0: yeah okay that's.
Speaker 0: I know that was in poor taste but I was.
Speaker 1: I was thinking more in terms of.
Speaker 1: it is not a pleasant fantasy world?
Speaker 0: no it is not.
Speaker 0: neither is Cambodia no but I think Cambodia is worse.
Speaker 1: well was at least bad anime.
Speaker 1: so tonight we're talking about this show which is nothing like Cambodia.
Speaker 1: tenku no escaflowne.
Speaker 1: vision of escaflowne is in my opinion.
Speaker 1: now we talk about must-see anime and we talk about good anime and bad anime.
Speaker 1: but if there are say three or four or five like greatest anime like TV series well yeah movies we can't really count.
Speaker 1: that's this whole separate.
Speaker 0: because then you see when you start movies you're like okay she movie every miyazaki movie every stodgy khan movie every you know you start going off and then you're in a mess.
Speaker 0: but when you're talking about TV shows at least the TV shows that aren't five zillion episodes and I know a lot of people hate you know making like a top ten or a top five list but escaflowne is in every one of those lists.
Speaker 1: it's gotta be what I would pretty much say.
Speaker 1: the way I would put it is that we kind of classify anime into a B and C anime.
Speaker 1: a anime is anime that leaves you with something.
Speaker 1: I mean examples of a anime or cowboy bebop Trigon like the big hitters the amazing shows Gundam seed not destiny clean up batters the star quarterbacks in the Super Bowl.
Speaker 1: and then there's be anime which are like I don't know scrap princess konkotsuo.
Speaker 1: they're good they're fun they're really worth watching but they're not like special they don't.
Speaker 1: they're not like the all-time amazing greats.
Speaker 1: you know yeah and see anime are like.
Speaker 1: you know initial D and all those things that we like anyway and then F anime are like girl in the gun.
Speaker 0: oh no I haven't watched it I can't.
Speaker 1: yeah we can't say.
Speaker 0: I just tried to say something that would incite people going.
Speaker 1: Oh Daryl Surratt for a second was about to call gogo 13.
Speaker 0: yeah I know like.
Speaker 1: he picked up the phone and then you said just kidding he hesitated for a minute much like speaking of gogo 13.
Speaker 1: Wow so much for escaflowne.
Speaker 0: okay so escaflowne right.
Speaker 0: the thing about escaflowne that makes it such an a anime right is that first of all you got a fantasy anime.
Speaker 0: pretty rare to have a fantasy anime.
Speaker 0: that's not just like a joke right?
Speaker 1: I mean what like serious fantasy anime do we have slayers edges into serious territory a little a couple of times right?
Speaker 1: there's twelve kingdoms.
Speaker 0: yeah I guess - it's a robot anime.
Speaker 0: they're mad robots in escaflowne but it's not a. it's not in the genre of robot show but it has the robots and they're cool.
Speaker 1: it's got pretty boys and cat girls.
Speaker 0: I guess that's it does like.
Speaker 0: that does yeah and the thing that's really like defines escaflowne.
Speaker 0: the way I sum it up in my mind is that somehow they take like stereotypes of anime like come on schoolgirl in high school transported to a fantasy world.
Speaker 0: there's a bunch of pretty boy bunch of pretty boys and cat and a magical war and she falls in love kind of.
Speaker 0: but is that not the most like by-the-book story you've ever heard?
Speaker 0: I don't know what is in terms of anime right but yet yet they pull it off and you don't even realize how cliche it is.
Speaker 0: because every cliche is like done with the finesse and the polish that makes it feel like original and new and amazing.
Speaker 1: it's one of those shows one of those rare shows where a lot of things try to be epic and there's different ways to look at epic.
Speaker 1: I mean you could look at kind of all the leiji Matsumoto works and say like those as a whole are this epic thing.
Speaker 1: but watching a show the the way like from where escaflowne starts until where it gets about halfway through and then to where it gets by the end it it is epic in every sense of the word.
Speaker 0: the plot is one of those like epic but not forced and I a lot of the plot you can see coming but a lot of it no way gonna see it coming?
Speaker 0: not at all not even close.
Speaker 1: so escaflowne before.
Speaker 1: I mean just if you'd stop listening to geek nights right now tonight because you got other things to do and you have not seen tenku.
Speaker 1: no escaflowne it is your duty to buy it and watch it.
Speaker 1: this is one of the greatest animated series ever.
Speaker 0: yeah it's really cheap too.
Speaker 0: I mean you can probably get.
Speaker 0: you can get every all 26 episodes of it in like one box right in the bricks and it shouldn't cost you more than $50.
Speaker 0: I paid $23 for it.
Speaker 1: Wow best Bob.
Speaker 0: Wow 26 episodes for $23 less than a dollar an episode for an entire anime series one of the best ever on DVD.
Speaker 0: I'm looking it up on Amazon right now.
Speaker 1: all right but there's actually there's a lot of interesting kind of side stuff about escaflowne.
Speaker 1: before we kind of get into what it's about and why it's so great.
Speaker 1: already talked about what it's about yeah but we can talk about that in a little more detail.
Speaker 1: well it's funny how whenever we do a show about a show we like which isn't that often we kind of gush.
Speaker 0: yeah you could walk up to rim like randomly and just say escaflowne I might just cry just like gush onto the floor me not so much all right on Amazon right I see escaflowne anime legends complete collection $45.
Speaker 0: that is worth everything that is totally worth it.
Speaker 1: I paid $28 for the first VHS tape of escaflowne.
Speaker 0: I see 43 used and new from $26.
Speaker 0: so you can get a used set 26 bucks.
Speaker 1: so escaflowne is actually kind of old.
Speaker 1: it's more than a decade old.
Speaker 1: this came out in 1996.
Speaker 0: oh god it looks like a late 90s early 2000 anime.
Speaker 1: yeah yeah but at the same time it was a very high budget.
Speaker 1: kind of we're putting all the right things together.
Speaker 1: it was one of those shows where you looked at and you knew wow all the right people are behind it.
Speaker 1: all the money's there.
Speaker 1: this is gonna be one of those gigantic shows.
Speaker 1: the same way you'd look at cowboy bebop when it was originally kind of being put out and and much like all these great shows back in that era it had a lot of trouble.
Speaker 1: it was almost not made like a bunch of times.
Speaker 1: it sat on the shelf for like four years.
Speaker 1: there they lost the first director which actually I'm not gonna tell the whole story but to sum it up briefly someone was going to direct escaflowne.
Speaker 1: that person was for various reasons not included in the project.
Speaker 1: by the end they it's actually kind of complicated but instead of the original director and the original concept someone by the name of Kazuki Akane became the director and made changes to escaflowne to the point that it went from a super run-of-the-mill garbage show into one of the greatest anime ever and I attribute that largely to the changes that were made.
Speaker 1: if you want to see what escaflowne would have likely been like otherwise there are two.
Speaker 1: well there are three but you probably haven't seen the third one.
Speaker 1: there are two manga.
Speaker 0: yeah that's the thing about escaflowne.
Speaker 0: it has two manga which is confusing.
Speaker 1: one is a shoujo manga and one is a shonen manga.
Speaker 1: they both suck.
Speaker 0: they're utter crap.
Speaker 0: the shoujo is a little better than the shonen but that's like saying it smells better than poop like.
Speaker 1: don't even be tempted to flip through the escaflowne manga.
Speaker 1: this is some bad bad manga.
Speaker 0: they're terrible not worth the penny.
Speaker 1: but this show just like Evangelion was originally going to be 39 episodes.
Speaker 1: this is back when shows were always 26 episodes and this show was gonna be you know three half seasons 39 episodes and unlike utenna instead of stretching out their budget with lots of stock footage and bad animation techniques which I think worked to utenna's benefit.
Speaker 0: yes well but that not for her.
Speaker 0: they wouldn't have worked escaflowne's benefit that's not sure.
Speaker 1: but escaflowne and Evangelion were both originally going to be 39 episodes and due to cuts they had to cut them short to 26 episodes.
Speaker 1: and escaflowne unlike Evangelion did this by not cutting out anything.
Speaker 0: you really can't tell that the show was supposed to be 39 episodes.
Speaker 0: if anything I mean like you watch say the original Matt cross TV series right where they tacked on extra episodes at the end and you can totally tell the point at which the original ends and then they begin the tacked on episodes and this.
Speaker 0: they cut episodes out but you can't tell.
Speaker 0: it's like it looks like they wrote the whole thing from the beginning knowing is gonna be setting plot out or changing things to make an end in 26.
Speaker 1: all they did was kind of tighten it up and save time wherever they could by kind of making the story progress faster and that was good.
Speaker 1: and as a result actually I think one of the greatest strengths of escaflowne one of those subtle things is that the show starts and it throws you into it and then it kind of progresses at a steady pace but the kind of.
Speaker 1: the rate of progression is accelerating throughout the show.
Speaker 1: so you get through say one plot unit in the first episode and one plot unit in the second episode and 1.1 plot units in the third episode and 1.4 plot units in the fourth episode.
Speaker 1: and the show kind of builds up the pace and builds up the pace.
Speaker 1: and epic like the epicness is going up and the pace is going up and filler scenes and atmospheric shots are cutting down.
Speaker 1: and the last like five or six episodes are this like bullet train to destiny like the show is just at this breakneck pace and things are happening.
Speaker 1: just it bam bam bam bam bam.
Speaker 1: and then it stops and it's over.
Speaker 1: and it's amazing.
Speaker 0: the worst part of escaflowne is there's so many cliffhangers often at the end of DVDs or VHS tapes and they're like the most grueling possible cliffhangers you can imagine like we're talking characters you love on the brink of death major major climaxes in the plot.
Speaker 0: just like left ambiguous.
Speaker 1: this show really strings you along.
Speaker 0: it strings you along so badly.
Speaker 1: it's kind of like in that regard.
Speaker 1: it's almost like those old Hardy Boys novels the kind of Hardy Boys the New Year's but unlike those it's not terrible like the worst example if you were watching escaflowne and you have you're watching the second to last DVD or tape or whatever you got and you see the fifth to last episode.
Speaker 1: make sure you've got the next episode handy cuz.
Speaker 1: there's.
Speaker 1: that's the worst cliffhanger at any show I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: it's really terrible.
Speaker 0: we're talking about the same one.
Speaker 0: I think we are the one where actually when we really where all you see is a robot and something's coming out of it.
Speaker 1: oh no no there's one worse.
Speaker 0: I think that's the worst one.
Speaker 0: well
Speaker 1: that while that one was like the second worst cliffhanger ever I think the one near the end where me and Ken got stuck in the elevator
Speaker 0: yeah coming
Speaker 1: back with the tape
Speaker 0: I think the one with the robot and the stuff coming out of it is the worst one.
Speaker 1: I don't even want to say anything about what either.
Speaker 0: these cliffhangers I find I found a clever way to say it without spoiling it.
Speaker 0: are you gonna say it robot with stuff coming out of it?
Speaker 1: oh I thought you had some other clever way.
Speaker 0: no that was my clever way.
Speaker 1: that kind of works.
Speaker 1: there's.
Speaker 1: there's no way to cleverly refer to mine other than other than to just blurt it out.
Speaker 0: man that and this is an easily spoiled show.
Speaker 0: that is a problem with it.
Speaker 0: well it's easily spoiled in one regard but at the same time a lot of things are kind of obvious to anyone who's actually seen the show.
Speaker 1: so it's it's one of those.
Speaker 1: yeah you could spoil it but spoilers don't mean much out of context like the journey is a lot more important than what happened.
Speaker 0: yeah yeah other thing about asking flown a is that the characters are pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: they're solid.
Speaker 1: there are a lot of main characters they're.
Speaker 0: all the thing is is like I do you know it doesn't have the simp the problem of a lot of other enemies or the main characters suck.
Speaker 0: the side characters are cool but I do think that the side characters are cooler than the main character.
Speaker 0: well it depends because it's all right thing is they're not really that far off to the side they're pretty close.
Speaker 0: they're just.
Speaker 0: you know they're not.
Speaker 0: domain to character.
Speaker 1: yeah well they're also all really three-dimensional and it starts out like the show looks a little stereotypical.
Speaker 1: I mean Alan she's are is the pretty boy and he's so cool and I'm gonna think he's so cool.
Speaker 0: but then do you think he's so cool?
Speaker 1: course I think he's so cool.
Speaker 1: he's the man.
Speaker 0: it's just your favorite anime character.
Speaker 1: but then as it goes I mean god that's what I. my aim name she's our 105. it wasn't named after Cliff she's our that's for sure.
Speaker 1: but then you know as the show progresses and no Alex is our is a sad emotionally broken man who's kind of messed up.
Speaker 0: yeah and then you've got like you know Dylan down.
Speaker 0: I mean people see you know crazy characters in anime like he's like the crazy psycho killers.
Speaker 0: right Dylan Dow is like the perfect execution of the crazy psycho killer.
Speaker 0: kind of care I think.
Speaker 1: the scene the scene I actually rerun when I was watching this the first time we actually rewind because it was a VHS tape.
Speaker 1: the scene where he got that scar on his face he's freaking out about it for like the rest of the show yeah and he's just sitting there with it like this flask in front of him and he's cutting like scratching this knife against the flask and the scene is just him sitting there kind of scratching this flask and then he suddenly freaks out and breaks it all over himself and screams
Speaker 0: yeah the show that that's really I said it before but escaflowne is all about taking the cliche but executing it in a way where it doesn't seem cliche it's like it makes it work every time
Speaker 1: and also right along those lines it takes the cliche.
Speaker 1: there's kind of this surface like you can enjoy escaflowne like the cliche of the cat girl.
Speaker 0: but the cat girl isn't bad you're not going all cat girl you're going huh cat girl.
Speaker 1: and then when there's the other cat girls yeah it's like cliche the crazy evil bad guy.
Speaker 0: but whoa he's so crazy.
Speaker 0: and wow that totally works as a character.
Speaker 0: and you know cliche schoolgirl brought to a fantasy world.
Speaker 0: but oh it's done so tastefully and not so shallowly.
Speaker 0: ah just like a like a truffle.
Speaker 1: but in addition to this ooh a truffle.
Speaker 1: but you look at it from that you can enjoy this show on this surface level this visceral.
Speaker 1: yay let's go fantasy epic adventure this crazy plot.
Speaker 1: but and a lot of people go whenever people say things like this well no I mean if you know the thing I'm about to say not the thing I just said.
Speaker 1: no escaflowne is one of those shows that's you know deep and stuff.
Speaker 0: it's kind of deep it's not super deep but it's got.
Speaker 1: it's got the depth it's got a lot more depth than you'd realize especially in the when you kind of find out what was going on.
Speaker 1: and you know a lot of shows have like cool.
Speaker 0: if it was a pool it would be deep enough for a high jump but not deep enough for an Olympic high.
Speaker 1: well I'll put it this way it's not deep in the big o2 way where they beat you over the head with.
Speaker 1: it's not deep in the existentialist philosophy.
Speaker 0: it's not deep in the Orion way.
Speaker 1: it's not deep in the ghost in the shell.
Speaker 1: you know social phenomenon and what is the nature?
Speaker 0: just the right depth where you stand on your tippy toes but and you keep your nose out of the water.
Speaker 0: well know what.
Speaker 1: what's great about the show is that it doesn't just have kind of one overarching moral.
Speaker 1: I mean you've been some evangelical despite all its existentialist.
Speaker 0: and try gun as well.
Speaker 1: yes try gun is just kind of considering the idea of pacifism and everything in the show is really just kind of around this one idea and as a or evangelical is kind of just around the idea of what our humans and how do we interact with each other and ourselves.
Speaker 1: eska flown a has like nine of those issues and yeah it wants them all equally well cuz each character like this side plots.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like.
Speaker 0: I really related a lot to Final Fantasy 6 where you have like a fantasy world a big epic kind of journey.
Speaker 0: you can actually match up a lot of the characters with Final Fantasy 6 characters being kind of similar you know.
Speaker 1: and oh man I just you said that I thought.
Speaker 1: but who would match up with lock?
Speaker 1: that was like or Edward and I was like duh Dryden.
Speaker 0: for both of them I think I think Edward.
Speaker 0: now she's our goal together.
Speaker 1: yeah they kind of do.
Speaker 1: yeah but I really like Dryden when he's got that mermaid.
Speaker 0: yeah all right but yeah you got Kefka for Dylan down.
Speaker 0: it's like you totally it totally works.
Speaker 1: well I think Dylan down out crazies Kefka though the only thing cats.
Speaker 1: a tough call that Dylan.
Speaker 1: tough call that Kefka murders a lot more people than Dylan.
Speaker 0: I can guarantee though if you like Final Fantasy 6 you like eska plonie and vice versa.
Speaker 1: in fact if you're one of those people who always wish the Final Fantasy 6 for an anime just watch eska plonie.
Speaker 1: pretty much it's better than that could ever be.
Speaker 0: yeah yeah I guess.
Speaker 0: cuz it doesn't have the random encounters it doesn't take as long.
Speaker 1: if you're gonna make a Final Fantasy movie I think the random encounter is the first thing to go.
Speaker 0: but yeah it's really.
Speaker 0: it's that kind of thing where even though there is a big major plot like all the characters have their plots and each of their plots is sort of separate.
Speaker 0: so it's like as you go through.
Speaker 0: it's like not only are you trying to figure out the big picture but there's the you know the thread of each of the main characters and what their deal is and all their deals come to a head and then the big thing comes to a head and then it's over
Speaker 1: and the show doesn't kind of take anything for granted.
Speaker 1: like there's the world.
Speaker 1: but the world is super super super fleshed out and all the politics and all the people and all the races and all those things are all there and all strong in the background the foreground wherever they matter and it's super consistent with itself.
Speaker 1: and as a result you know it's got the cliche of the girl who comes from the other world has some magical powers but they don't just leave it at that.
Speaker 1: like a lot of shows she's an esper she's an esper but seriously the show gets into some dark territory in regards to why does Hitomi have these powers?
Speaker 1: what are those powers doing?
Speaker 1: how are they affecting everything as we've been following this show?
Speaker 1: yeah how much can she really control them?
Speaker 1: the show really really really is good and that's all we can really say.
Speaker 1: we just keep saying that over and over again.
Speaker 0: now there is an escaflowne a movie.
Speaker 0: the movie has some of the same characters as the show a lot of the same characters but different character designs.
Speaker 0: actually the
Speaker 1: movie is basically take like every character from the show and pick like one element of their personality make that the entire character and then it's like everyone is a deep caricature of a character from the show and
Speaker 0: then take sort of the same universe but like a different world like so you know it's like it's the same but it's different and they just sort of tell a story with those characters in like you know 90 minutes or so.
Speaker 1: it's kind of like it takes one of the themes of escaflowne and just addresses that like it distills everything to one of its core essences.
Speaker 0: yeah you could watch the movie and it won't spoil shit about the real show and vice versa.
Speaker 0: they they really have not not much to do with each other.
Speaker 1: besides the characters the movie also was one of those super high-budget super pretty and you know what.
Speaker 0: it's pretty pretty.
Speaker 1: yeah it's a good movie it's not.
Speaker 0: it's okay.
Speaker 1: just if you if you don't go into it expecting you don't need to see it.
Speaker 1: but if you want to watch it just don't watch one and expect it to be the other one because they're both good.
Speaker 0: if you expect the movie to be like the TV show you're gonna be disappointed.
Speaker 1: plus don't forget the escaflowne movie was one of the first widely distributed digital fan subs.
Speaker 0: yep it sure was.
Speaker 1: Wow this was a long time ago.
Speaker 1: all of this yeah it was.
Speaker 1: but the story of escaflowne actually it's just that there's this girl.
Speaker 1: her name's Hitomi.
Speaker 1: she's a normal average girl but she's not an average boring girl.
Speaker 1: she's an average you know quirky kind of realistic girl.
Speaker 0: yeah and she's in high school and she does track and she has friends who were cool.
Speaker 1: yeah she actually has friends.
Speaker 1: it's not like the stereotypical.
Speaker 0: you know I don't have any friends blah and the friends are sort of normal and they sort of have these real high school problems.
Speaker 0: and she likes this boy and there's another boy.
Speaker 0: I think that doesn't really get talked about so much.
Speaker 1: and well there's Amano Senpai.
Speaker 0: right right right that's the guy that she likes.
Speaker 1: yes but one thing leads to another and she gets transported to this world.
Speaker 1: but it's not like it's out of the blue it's.
Speaker 1: I can't spoil anything.
Speaker 0: they slowly lean into it.
Speaker 0: like as a watcher as a viewer of the anime you kind of see that Sun's coming and you kind of know because it's a meta thing.
Speaker 0: right you know what.
Speaker 0: but they totally lean into it and it's it feels really natural and not just like poof.
Speaker 0: we're in another world like El Hazzard.
Speaker 0: this show kind of stand out like if El Hazzard is the wow we're just transported to a different world.
Speaker 0: suddenly this is the ah this is the right way to do that.
Speaker 1: even El Hazzard has a whole bunch of school build-up.
Speaker 1: it does.
Speaker 1: it has that one of my favorites comedy scenes in any show ever where Jedi is in the hallway freaking out as he looks at all the different bulletin board pictures.
Speaker 0: this is one thing that amazes me about Escaflowne is how the school the high school aspect of Escaflowne comes on so strong.
Speaker 0: yet the amount of screen time it gets is so small.
Speaker 0: but yeah like it's you barely see the school.
Speaker 0: but the school is so powerfully in the show.
Speaker 1: well the school also comes back.
Speaker 1: this isn't really a spoiler so much because it kind of illustrates an interesting the show.
Speaker 1: there's a point at which they're you know things are going on and they told me is trying to hide somewhere and her pager goes off.
Speaker 0: it's totally a Hoshi no koei thing.
Speaker 1: her pager goes off
Speaker 0: and in the fantasy world
Speaker 1: you know she's got her bag with her she's got CDs and all these things just with her but it goes off and it caused all this trouble and you forget about it going off because whatever it went off and all this action happens.
Speaker 1: and then at the end of the episode she's like they've relaxed and they're safe and she just kind of looks at the pager and then she sees the phone number on it and then it
Speaker 0: cuts to
Speaker 1: the real world again earth and there's a mono and he was just calling the pager.
Speaker 1: and is he there?
Speaker 1: he's in a phone booth and that's it.
Speaker 0: yeah and the thing is it told me is like for is wearing her school uniform.
Speaker 0: still everyone else is like you know knights and wizards and elves and shit.
Speaker 0: so it's like.
Speaker 0: you know that's like her character design.
Speaker 0: so it totally makes sense.
Speaker 0: but it's sort of it always ties.
Speaker 0: she's always carrying her bag of stuff from high school because it was transported to this world with her.
Speaker 0: she's wearing sneakers you know so it's like it's always tied back to this school.
Speaker 0: despite that the school gets almost no screen time and it's not.
Speaker 1: I mean it's not just a convenience or whatever.
Speaker 1: it actually kind of matters to the plot and it matters a lot.
Speaker 1: it is the plot now but what I was about to say before was that part of what makes this show stand out in terms of.
Speaker 1: you know you said the opening is kind of natural.
Speaker 1: like it it draws you into the world and a lot of modern shows seem to just like people have an idea like we're gonna make a show about blah and they introduce blah as quickly as possible and they wrap a little mystery around it to try to dangle you along.
Speaker 1: this show develops so much more naturally than a lot of these shows.
Speaker 1: I feel like modern anime seem to often forget that you have to have a strong come on in the beginning but they come on too strong in the beginning and in the end it makes a weaker come on
Speaker 0: or they come on too weak in the beginning because they don't want to reveal too much.
Speaker 1: I think the first episode of this show is one of the best not the best but definitely one of the better introductions to a complex world and a complex show.
Speaker 0: I think the reason it works so well is because they come on strong with the school.
Speaker 0: they bring you on everything about the school and then the fantasy world and you got nothing.
Speaker 0: so they got the mystery is all in the fantasy world but they were able to lure you in with the really strong school revealing everything.
Speaker 1: it really lets you identify with you.
Speaker 1: tell me a lot more because now you kind of got used to the school you're.
Speaker 1: you were grounded in this kind of.
Speaker 1: here's the world of the show and now you're transported along with her to this other world.
Speaker 1: and I also point out that in this other world earth is in the sky like a moon and you see it and they know it and they know she's from there and they call it the cursed world.
Speaker 1: do?
Speaker 1: they call it the curse world called the curse moon of the curse something.
Speaker 0: I call it something.
Speaker 0: I forget if it was cursed but they call it something and they're like it's like it's like it's like imagine if someone showed up like in front of your house and you knew that they were from the moon.
Speaker 0: you'd be like you're from the moon whoa but not just the moon the cursed moon.
Speaker 0: I don't remember if it was cursed.
Speaker 1: it is most definitely cursed.
Speaker 0: I forget I can't.
Speaker 0: I can't say either way.
Speaker 1: I mean I don't want to talk about the plot anymore because this is kind of the like.
Speaker 1: we're gonna talk about the show a couple more times in the far future because you know we got to do a final thoughts we got to do kind of the full review for people who have seen it all those sorts of things.
Speaker 1: but I don't feel like I need to talk more about the plot or anything because you need to see this show.
Speaker 1: this is one of the best anime ever.
Speaker 1: if you if you're an anime fan and you haven't seen this show it's like saying I haven't seen cowboy bebop I haven't seen trygun I haven't seen Star Wars.
Speaker 0: okay so if you didn't have enough reasons already to go watch this Cofloni I got two more reasons for you.
Speaker 0: number one yoko kano music and also number two no but teriyuki character designs.
Speaker 0: that's the pointy nose guy.
Speaker 1: I really like both of those people a lot and actually we're talking like a list anime you know.
Speaker 1: there's a third reason Maya Sakamoto.
Speaker 1: you realize this was like her premier role.
Speaker 1: ah I mean Maya Sakamoto who was famous.
Speaker 1: now this was her first real role she played.
Speaker 1: he told me the lead and she sang the opening song yaku soku wa erinai which is actually I really like that song.
Speaker 0: yeah you know the one thing is there is one song and it's not a bad song it's actually a really good song but it's like eska flow day.
Speaker 0: as you know it's a lot like.
Speaker 0: you know the Excalibur something.
Speaker 0: ah no what the the song from Excalibur what the hell's it called?
Speaker 1: well the thing is a lot of you do.
Speaker 1: the music in the yeah is absolutely fantastic.
Speaker 1: I mean it's yoko kano.
Speaker 1: duh but it's very symphonic.
Speaker 1: it's very.
Speaker 1: there are light motifs.
Speaker 0: I'd say it's yoko kano second best anime music scabula being her best enemy music.
Speaker 1: yeah I would have to agree because I think right up there at number three are the openings to the ghost in the shells.
Speaker 0: yeah that's was really good too all right.
Speaker 0: anything else we gotta say I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think that's it.
Speaker 0: I mean buy it Netflix it.
Speaker 0: if you're really poor maybe you can find it somewhere.
Speaker 1: if I had to you know I'd give a top 5 anime.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't rank them but it's easily cowboy bebop evangelical eska flown a try gun and something else.
Speaker 0: yeah probably not counting movies not counting movies die by TV shows.
Speaker 0: here.
Speaker 1: I cannot express to you how amazing the show is.
Speaker 0: pretty it's pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: it's it's must-see.
Speaker 1: this has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays we have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: you can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: if you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.