Speaker 1: It's Thursday March 20th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim and I'm Emily and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 1: We talk about what it's really like to be an animator and getting into animation.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well, this should be a somewhat different episode of geek nights from what you're used to because as Scott said last night He's off bowling with co-workers And so in place of Scott, you've got your own personal headphone.
Speaker 0: was me Emily.
Speaker 0: You might know me as go me dog from the forums but for all you new listeners I am like the one-person studio audience.
Speaker 0: I'm usually in the room when they're recording the show But you never hear my voice except for an occasional like fit of hilarity in the background.
Speaker 1: Well, we've actually talked about this.
Speaker 1: It's kind of weird.
Speaker 1: Oh when we it's hard to do like humor or anything even when there's like two people without kind of an audience to bounce off of We can always tell the show is usually funnier when Emily's in the room because we can kind of tell me.
Speaker 0: But the thing is it's so hard because when they get really funny I'm like terrified that I'm gonna ruin a take or something and that they're gonna have to like start editing the shot.
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh my god, I laughed.
Speaker 0: I'm so sorry.
Speaker 0: They're like, no, that's good.
Speaker 0: That means we're funny.
Speaker 1: Ah, but you see there's the magic of the noise gate.
Speaker 0: Well, actually the downward expander if you want to be fancy Yeah, but so anyway This actually been been on the forums a lot lately and you probably know me my handle go me dog.
Speaker 0: And actually it's funny because I was never a big forum person until recently and I've finally come to Understand why trolls become trolls, isn't it?
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: It's scary.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know cuz cuz.
Speaker 0: I found I'm not
Speaker 1: like
Speaker 0: playing devil's advocate or anything But I found that when there's a flame war and this this arguments coming I'll just go and I'll be a lot more Incendiary and radical than I usually am and be like, okay, let's take this match and just chuck it onto the lighter food.
Speaker 0: I know right and so it's kind of like this stuff.
Speaker 0: like like with cooking I would always be like why do we always eat boring food and then I move into my own apartment?
Speaker 0: I'm like damn I'm tired.
Speaker 0: I don't have time to cook and then it's like oh, I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: I ever complained about boring ham.
Speaker 0: Blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: Take it to the next level.
Speaker 1: I mean I was a semi-professional troll on farm.
Speaker 0: Well, no, no I don't think I'll ever go that far, you know, I at least have some sympathy for for the people I argue with Yeah, you have that except that one person, you know who you are.
Speaker 1: You haven't attained that level where you actually it's.
Speaker 1: it's like it's so impersonal that you don't even consider The issue.
Speaker 1: you don't even consider who the other person is or even what they said.
Speaker 1: Well, all you do is type something invective and then wait for the fireworks.
Speaker 0: That's it explode.
Speaker 0: Well, I I used to take stuff really personally on the forums that I remember.
Speaker 0: There was this one listener Killar knee and I actually I still listen I think felt really bad cuz a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I like yelled at him be like, why do you always get so argumentative?
Speaker 0: Leave Riven Scott's pronunciation alone, and I actually got like like, you know all uppity Adam Like.
Speaker 0: in retrospect I was like man, but that is not how things work on the internet.
Speaker 0: You know, of course very bad about that.
Speaker 1: Gomi dog is also somewhat famous on the forums for drawing certain Art shall we say?
Speaker 0: I drew those at work and and then like, you know It was it was just I I was animating and you know got around lunchtime and I was like, man I need to take a break from the 3d stuff.
Speaker 0: And so when that happens, I'll I'll get out the tablet and start sketching in Photoshop.
Speaker 0: and I was like, oh bands I know what would like make the fangirls flip out.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna do it.
Speaker 0: Well, we're having like a conversation about like moe girls or something.
Speaker 0: So no way.
Speaker 1: girls have been coming up a lot lately I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know In the world, there's just more moe girls left and right.
Speaker 0: I I don't know what put this Twisted idea to my little noggin here, but I was like, I'm going to do it's.
Speaker 0: probably I was thinking like, you know Our friend was talking about drawing Some video game characters and and you'll find out later which video game characters because it's pretty hilarious.
Speaker 0: but let's let's just say, you know, they're more of the PC gaming FPS end of things as as cute moe girls and like the Pokemon drawn as moe girls.
Speaker 0: and it seems like the the rage today is To draw.
Speaker 0: everything is cute boy girl.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, I'm going to take rim and Scott and mollify them terribly.
Speaker 1: All you need to do to complete this sort of circle of life is to take our moe girls and turn them into some sort Of Mecha Musume.
Speaker 1: Oh Tatsu will be the most conflicted person.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah You make you're gonna make.
Speaker 0: him will be like one of those Like Nakatsu from Hana Kimi where it's like oh, oh, okay.
Speaker 0: What's going on?
Speaker 0: If you haven't read or watched Hana Kimi, I actually really recommend it.
Speaker 1: it's it's a it's a very funny show but For all of you who are uninitiated I don't know how many new listeners will suddenly randomly stumble upon this episode.
Speaker 1: first of all episodes because Since Katsu khan we haven't really promoted and we're not going to until this summer and we go to every freaking convention in the world.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, we've got the the line up there.
Speaker 1: But this is a slightly special episode and that my our normal co-host Scott is as you know bowling with co-workers.
Speaker 1: I don't know when he's gonna be.
Speaker 0: you know, when you think about it, that's one of those old men kind of things like yeah I'm going bowling with the guys from work.
Speaker 0: It's like my god.
Speaker 0: We've gotten to that age haven't we?
Speaker 1: Up until my current job.
Speaker 1: I never would have even considered doing anything with most Michael.
Speaker 1: Well, I take that back because some of the people at IBM were cool, but I worked in a really small like cool department the hospital Yeah, but now we work at a cool company.
Speaker 1: your company kicks ass, you know, I'm curious.
Speaker 1: This is just a total aside, but I wonder do any of you out there?
Speaker 1: Did any of you work at that hospital?
Speaker 1: because I sent an email out to pretty much everyone who worked there like basically Yeah, screw you all thanks for the fish.
Speaker 1: Oh and by the way, I do this radio show.
Speaker 0: I knew you walked out with finger held high, but I did not know that you Promoted yourself at the same time.
Speaker 1: It's like fuck you and listen to kick nights.
Speaker 1: That was the proudest and highest finger that has ever been raised by ran you were.
Speaker 1: you were pretty pretty pumped about that like freedom Yonkers, you know, see I could yell freedom like Mel Gibson, but without the the bad stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah without the torture, but I do have a little bit of news because this is a rare moment.
Speaker 1: I can talk about politics without having Scott here to go.
Speaker 1: Nothing no, no, no, oh this Obama business.
Speaker 1: I just want people to be quiet.
Speaker 0: The thing is he gets really ticked at us when we don't know the absolute latest like up-to-date Stuff in tech news.
Speaker 0: He's like what you didn't know.
Speaker 0: such-and-such gadget came out.
Speaker 0: You're crazy and we're like, well, this is actually stuff that can affect your life Scott.
Speaker 0: He's like it won't affect me Nothing affects me.
Speaker 1: What he always says is it hasn't affected my life yet.
Speaker 0: Well, um Recession Bush etc.
Speaker 0: He hears me complain about Bush and then he's like, uh, well actually it has affected him.
Speaker 1: He has admitted this.
Speaker 1: he always says that it affects me because everyone around me is constantly yelling about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, he listens to me gripe about it.
Speaker 0: You know how like.
Speaker 0: he was sad because I always draw when I draw caricatures of rim and Scott I always draw rim happy and Scott is kind of like scally and and I think he felt kind of booed about that He's like I smile.
Speaker 0: Buddy caricatures Scott as Grouchy and I think it's partly like a balance thing cuz.
Speaker 0: on one hand you've got like it's kind of like the tragedy in comedy Mass for Greek theater and on one hand you've got like really smiley hyper rim and on the other hand You've got Scott who's kind of surly And he said, you know, I I smile.
Speaker 0: Why do you always draw me angry?
Speaker 1: And I was like, I don't know I look back like all the geek nights art We've had pretty much forever and even back to like our earliest earliest logos and banners.
Speaker 1: Scott is grouchy and usually full of stubble.
Speaker 0: My favorite one still was was art boy our friend Adam.
Speaker 0: he drew a Caricature of the whole crew and actually I liked mine too because I was like in the background Going wild and I had like these really round eyes like whee and I was like, yeah that pretty much captures it.
Speaker 0: but Scott was sitting in a corner typing on his laptop and thinking of a penis and I was like, yeah, that's got for ya.
Speaker 0: I Love Scott though.
Speaker 0: He's Sometimes we butt heads cuz.
Speaker 1: actually oh, yeah sometimes but you know It's not just you and Scott is it's pretty much everyone and Scott except to a large degree me.
Speaker 1: But that's partly because as far as I've been told I'm the most laid-back human being on earth.
Speaker 0: You have no idea.
Speaker 0: Okay rim is egotistical, but he's like the most patient.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you are you are but Much like confidence as he debates murdering his uncle to take control of the Empire.
Speaker 0: I I don't get it.
Speaker 1: I don't think I'm gonna commit patricide just yet though.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't.
Speaker 1: I'm all about the hubris anyway.
Speaker 0: What I was gonna say is he is the patient person like it's.
Speaker 1: it's like unless I'm hungry.
Speaker 0: Yes, when you're hungry, but even then you only get mildly like I don't know impatient.
Speaker 0: Well, not quite that bad but this guy he's great to deal with.
Speaker 1: but well I don't know.
Speaker 1: I've ever told the story on the show of how Scott and I came to be roommates because it was actually a very mundane.
Speaker 0: This is gonna be like the gripe about Scott show because I don't want in on that.
Speaker 0: I'm like happy at Scott lately.
Speaker 1: Oh, I am too.
Speaker 1: It's a funny story and Scott actually agrees.
Speaker 1: It's funny too and we might have told it before me Scott Alex and Probably the only person who's ever removed themselves from the front row crew.
Speaker 0: Oh, may he rest in peace.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he is dead to us or something.
Speaker 1: But no the four of us are gonna.
Speaker 1: you know We got we want an apartment together and there's this crazy lottery at RIT because there's no housing and we go in And we were walking up and we discover that the last four-person apartment other than the nasty ones at River Knoll We're gone.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, and we're like damn it.
Speaker 1: All right, we're gonna have to live in the crap Oh apartments and this is gonna and then someone yells Hey, I got two one-bedroom two-person colonies left.
Speaker 1: anyone want him?
Speaker 1: and we were at the front of the line.
Speaker 1: Oh, we all look at each other and we all go Oh, and then Alex says who's gonna live with Scott?
Speaker 1: and everyone looks at each other and there's this moment of silence.
Speaker 0: I can see Alex saying that and Scott's like what.
Speaker 1: and I said I'll live with him because I'm probably the only person who will Not murder him and and it's probably true.
Speaker 0: I have lived with Scott.
Speaker 0: I can attest to this I never actually tried to murder him.
Speaker 0: I tried to.
Speaker 0: Only one member of the front row crew has ever tried to murder Where I went for him and it might have gone into violence if I had actually got there.
Speaker 0: But I slipped on the kitchen floor and fell smack on my butt and I was like, oh my butt Kind of changed from like violence to comedy immediately and it was kind of like One person has actually tried to kill Scott and it wasn't you.
Speaker 0: so yeah, I'll leave that distinction for so.
Speaker 1: So Obama Obama So much to say but I don't want to do a whole episode on just me talking about politics because I can record that by Myself, I don't need anyone else here.
Speaker 1: I could just go and I feel of this way about this issue.
Speaker 1: John McCain is a giant twat.
Speaker 1: Not really.
Speaker 0: He's not that bad You know, that's like my parents though talking about politics to people who agree with you It's like you talk about priests into the choir.
Speaker 1: everyone agree Like.
Speaker 1: I know a lot of our listeners agree with me and like yeah Obama and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: But I don't think a lot of them agree with my political stances as opposed to my issue and politician stance.
Speaker 0: I don't always agree with your political stances, but Well, technically I'm an anti-federalist because I'm for federalism.
Speaker 1: That's America for you.
Speaker 1: But alright, here's the deal.
Speaker 1: Obama's up by enough pledge delegates and he's poached enough of Hillary's super delegates to where pretty much unless Hillary like Absolutely demolishes him in Pennsylvania.
Speaker 1: I don't see any chance of her getting the nomination.
Speaker 1: I think Obama is definitely going to be the next president of the United States and the cool thing is it kind of it's weird how it came down to Michigan and Florida because Michigan and Florida both went for Hillary partly because Obama took his name off the ballot in Michigan and actually didn't campaign in either state and Hillary kind of left her name on the ballot and campaign a little bit and then now she's even campaigning on the deal that she's going to reinstate their votes and How those votes for her should count even though in Michigan Obama wasn't even on the ballot.
Speaker 0: man What is up with Florida always messing stuff up?
Speaker 0: It seems like every time we have an election Florida is just like a major like clusterfuck.
Speaker 1: Well, see actually the real problem is Ohio.
Speaker 1: Ohio has more election problems than any other state.
Speaker 0: I know it's always and isn't it like kind of the swing vote thing where if Ohio goes one way.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: But it's weird.
Speaker 1: I actually had to.
Speaker 1: very seriously thing is I came to this conclusion right away.
Speaker 1: I kind of agree that those states should not get their votes because they totally broke the rules and it would ruin everything if they Voted now and it'd be a gigantic waste of money to do a reelection.
Speaker 1: and luckily Michigan doesn't have any money as they're not gonna do it and I don't know what the reason was.
Speaker 1: But Florida doesn't look like they're gonna do it.
Speaker 0: That's probably for the best.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but my old home state I give them points for trying hard and saying hey, we're gonna totally break the rules.
Speaker 1: But yeah, you lost that gamble and we'll see what happens in 2008 or two.
Speaker 1: both I get is 2008 2012 the next time you get a shot at this.
Speaker 0: didn't you like do a story about how Michigan had to like shut down for a day because it was like Michigan was closed because They had no money.
Speaker 1: The Michigan State Government had that happen a couple times.
Speaker 1: the Detroit city government has had that happened.
Speaker 1: Oh god, I could do a whole show on what's been going on in Detroit recently.
Speaker 0: And plus you've got your your ear to the wall.
Speaker 0: as far as Detroit politics is cuz your dad.
Speaker 1: yeah Actually, he's retiring in September.
Speaker 1: So I got a fly out to Michigan gonna do a fancy party.
Speaker 1: I get to fly out to a fancy party.
Speaker 1: Can I be your escort Scott?
Speaker 0: Scott.
Speaker 0: yesterday he was convinced.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh now we're gossiping about Scott again.
Speaker 0: This is terrible.
Speaker 0: You should never let me on the show.
Speaker 1: I think his argument was that there's a chance that there is an escort service out there that in fact provides escorts and nothing more.
Speaker 0: That's not what he said.
Speaker 0: He said escort services only take you to parties.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I was saying to Alex today.
Speaker 0: I was like that would be great if they had like tickets to every you know red carpet event in the city and you'd hire an escort service and they would take you to the party of your choice.
Speaker 0: even if You weren't invited you'd be like hello madam.
Speaker 0: Can you take me to?
Speaker 0: So and so's premiere party and they'd be like right away.
Speaker 0: No, no sex no sex.
Speaker 1: I'm just looking for an excuse to do that.
Speaker 1: I haven't done.
Speaker 0: I hate I hate quagmire.
Speaker 0: I I'm sorry I just hate that but I have a being a trumpet player.
Speaker 1: I have the rare gift of being able to do a gayety.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I mean that I don't have much more to say other unless I go into crazy depth.
Speaker 1: But the only chance Clinton has is Pennsylvania and I've actually donated a fair amount of money and our good friend the other Scott the stronger faster Scott.
Speaker 0: He's fighting the good fight for the Obama side.
Speaker 1: He lives in Pennsylvania and he's actually campaigning and working hard.
Speaker 1: So yeah, we've said this before but I'll say it again geek nights.
Speaker 1: the podcast officially endorses Barack Obama for president of the United States, but as Emily says Hillary is okay, but I like Obama better I. the thing is I have a lot of mixed feelings about Hillary.
Speaker 0: You you guys don't you hate on her more than she deserves.
Speaker 0: The thing is I liked Hillary a lot and and I I granted the ad Was was terrible and I thought that was a low blow and I was like Hillary.
Speaker 0: that is lame.
Speaker 0: Do not do such lame things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and also the the whole thing I mean granted Barack did a little politicking too because oh sure Well, they're politicians.
Speaker 1: doing politicking is kind of expected it Because Barack's actually in very little politicking like playing the political game and I think the biggest example of that was after his Former minister or whatever they call it in whatever church.
Speaker 1: He claims to be a member of yeah Why rich people blah black black blah and it was to turn his big media storm and he gave that speech and I think that Was a fantastic speech and that that was totally not the politicking speech.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because that was the speech that keeps that issue right in the limelight, you know Barack is the man.
Speaker 1: He's also pretty sexy.
Speaker 1: I got her.
Speaker 1: that smile is so just Okay.
Speaker 0: Now I've got two men.
Speaker 0: I've got to worry about Neil Gaiman and Barack Obama.
Speaker 1: Sorry, if Neil Gaiman and Barack Obama are the presidential ticket and they happen to show up at a fancy dinner party.
Speaker 1: That's the end
Speaker 0: So anyway, but
Speaker 1: my motive mostly my mixed feelings on Hillary come from a lot of the politicking she's been doing and Also the fact that I still can't get over that she actually voted for the war Because I I can't fathom anyone ever thinking that was a good idea.
Speaker 0: Yes ever.
Speaker 1: And all she had to do was say, you know what I voted for the war and that was a mistake.
Speaker 1: But no she stands by that vote.
Speaker 0: that that bothers me.
Speaker 0: that really does.
Speaker 0: You know, I I like it when people can admit their mistakes.
Speaker 0: It's Because it's better to admit your mistakes then to have everybody know you made a mistake and be like what mistake You know, it's obvious you did something bad.
Speaker 0: Just owed up to it and then we'll forgive you maybe.
Speaker 0: So anyway, um, there was another thing we wanted to talk about involving people in the streets with flags All that and I'm very angry too.
Speaker 0: It's a bit mad as hell.
Speaker 0: free Tibet.
Speaker 1: I'm I said it it's on the.
Speaker 1: What's China gonna do about it?
Speaker 0: Well, they probably don't let them listen to geek.
Speaker 1: So like they don't the Chinese government really doesn't understand when it is a good time to be oppressive and when it's the time To just let it slide Time to be oppressive.
Speaker 0: there are good PR times.
Speaker 1: There are ways to handle being a press.
Speaker 1: Well if it be quiet about it York whispers free to bet or something like that under her breath at a Chinese thing.
Speaker 1: If you just don't say anything about it It'll probably slip right under the radar and disappear.
Speaker 1: But the fact that China came out so lame not just like strongly but the statements they made it wasn't like they were those strong Like communist blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: It was like and Bjork hurt the feelings of the Chinese people And I almost laughed out loud when I read that.
Speaker 0: and it's like and you physically heard a lot of demonstrators.
Speaker 1: So I mean to their credit the violence has been in both directions.
Speaker 0: Anytime you get one of those, you know, the tensions come to a head.
Speaker 0: in any situation You're gonna have people throwing stones on both sides of the the fight.
Speaker 1: first We are totally back down and was like I just whispered it under my breath.
Speaker 1: I wasn't gonna make a big deal out of it.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile China's like.
Speaker 1: we're totally gonna ban you from China Bjork.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, she's crazy.
Speaker 1: Anyway, she's not the only I mean China has done a lot of Anything involving China and foreign entertainers lately because there's been some utter hilarity.
Speaker 1: I really feel bad for Chinese people who actually want to listen to music.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have issues with with China But anyway, so so about the the protests.
Speaker 0: I was when I was with Taguchi son taking him around.
Speaker 0: We we did the whole tour all around Manhattan and I was like but it's funny when you get me as a tour guide because you get all the big sights.
Speaker 0: Oh, this is the Woolworth building.
Speaker 0: This is the Chrysler building This is the Statue of Liberty, but you also get stuff like oh my god.
Speaker 0: This is my favorite manhole.
Speaker 0: and look at that.
Speaker 0: That's this place where I ate it one time and these people got into a fight, you know, so you get these really Exactly.
Speaker 0: I was just gonna bring that up.
Speaker 0: It's like I got my head stuck in there once when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: It's better than the early tours.
Speaker 1: I gave like hey Scott and Don.
Speaker 1: This is Brooklyn, I think In my mind crap express train totally didn't look.
Speaker 1: yeah, I wanted to show you That clock tower there.
Speaker 0: Well, that's so good.
Speaker 0: Actually that clock tower.
Speaker 0: It's it's a famous building Yeah, but I didn't know what it was.
Speaker 1: I made stuff.
Speaker 0: It's a bank and actually the reason why there are.
Speaker 0: I found this out on the tour bus.
Speaker 0: I actually went on a tour bus for the first time ever in New York City.
Speaker 0: It was it was actually kind of fun.
Speaker 0: If anybody else comes to visit I think we'll do that.
Speaker 0: So we took this tour all around.
Speaker 0: we went downtown we went through Brooklyn and and I found out that the only that that big bank building is Like the only skyscraper in that area because they were going to do a whole bunch of other ones.
Speaker 0: but the day the bank stores opened and that building was complete the stock market crashed like the day of And it was just like oh so much for that plan.
Speaker 1: No, thanks, man That's actually the.
Speaker 1: the only bad thing about my job is that in these troubled economic times I have a lot to say but I'm now federally barred from saying it Yeah,
Speaker 0: just just promise me now that we're you know Facing recession as many people are saying you won't be out on any window ledges like they were in the 20s.
Speaker 1: I'm not a stock trader.
Speaker 1: It's the.
Speaker 0: yeah, that's the.
Speaker 1: If the stock market goes up I can make a whole bunch of money But if the stock market goes down Equal opportunities to make money.
Speaker 1: as long as the stock market doesn't just sit there and not go anywhere As long as people are buying and selling stock I don't I don't have to worry about a stock is good or not and any trades I make or fake in the testing server.
Speaker 0: So yeah speaking of Brooklyn though, you know today today is a very special day for me.
Speaker 0: It's Japan day.
Speaker 0: Japan day because six years ago and then two years ago actually six years ago today I first set foot on Japanese soil and then two years ago.
Speaker 0: I had another plane flight over to Japan for college and I I think we should go to Brooklyn to the Botanical Gardens to check out the cherry blossoms in a few months.
Speaker 0: You know do a little hanami get some booze and sit out under the trees.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could be up for that.
Speaker 1: Things of the day.
Speaker 1: now Scott probably wanted to use this as a thing of the day, but you're gonna Be of course.
Speaker 1: I think I have a right because I actually saw it before he did.
Speaker 1: I can say that because Oh dibs for like hours Last night Scott's like rim.
Speaker 1: You got to see this hockey video.
Speaker 1: Yeah after the show.
Speaker 1: You got to watch this hockey video.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, we got you video hockey fight.
Speaker 1: It's not a hockey fight.
Speaker 1: so we go downstairs and I'm like Scott is this video where the guy shoots that short-handed goal from across the rink and he's like, ah But yeah, I saw it on College Humor.
Speaker 1: That's probably where you found it, isn't it?
Speaker 1: He's like, ah But I gotta tell you and I agree cuz he said the same thing This video did nothing but make my blood boil to see some hockey and I gotta go to a hockey game.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go crazy.
Speaker 0: I've been thinking about the Rangers so much lately.
Speaker 0: I don't know why but it's like I keep seeing people with jerseys and jackets and stuff And every time I see the Rangers thing, I'm like man, I kind of want to go watch some hockey.
Speaker 1: Well that night when we were stuck in Manhattan for a while because we were thinking about it because we're walking you know, we got to go to Penn Station we go past all the Rangers people and We passed a whole bunch of scalpers.
Speaker 1: I totally could have gotten a ticket if I really wanted Yeah, but then we wouldn't have gotten home.
Speaker 0: and the fact is I already paid for those goddamn Amtrak tickets.
Speaker 1: So yeah, but see that's that's the level of pony up the.
Speaker 1: can you take that extra level of screw it?
Speaker 1: Let's do it.
Speaker 1: Then I would have been paying for like the hotel room and everything at that point.
Speaker 0: Let's Rangers tickets are expensive enough.
Speaker 1: Let's just you know every year I debate getting season tickets.
Speaker 1: now that I use in tickets I don't know.
Speaker 0: We don't have time.
Speaker 1: man I would go to a lot of hockey games if I had season tickets, maybe especially because the only reason I Discounted it before was that I worked in the Bronx not in Manhattan.
Speaker 1: It would have totally sucked to go to a hockey game in Manhattan from the Bronx.
Speaker 1: But now I basically work at Grand Central.
Speaker 1: I can just go right there.
Speaker 0: It kind of rocks that we all work in the city now and and Alex and I work in the exact same place No less, you know, we're like in the same office.
Speaker 0: I'm like, aren't you sick of me yet?
Speaker 0: Are you sick of me yet?
Speaker 0: You know cuz we're like we.
Speaker 0: we live in the same apartment building.
Speaker 0: every in the morning He knocks on my door or I knock on his.
Speaker 0: we walked to the train station together.
Speaker 0: We ride the train.
Speaker 0: We don't talk a lot on the train, you know, we basically do our own thing.
Speaker 0: We walk from Grand Central to the office we sit and work on games all day Then we do the same thing only in reverse.
Speaker 0: and yeah When you're as talky as I am I'm like if I were me I would be sick of me.
Speaker 0: by now You're getting there All right.
Speaker 1: So what do you got for me?
Speaker 1: thing of the day?
Speaker 1: don't let our guest host do things at the day.
Speaker 0: You're special but I came prepared.
Speaker 0: Actually, I found two wonderful things today, but I've been deliciousing it up lately.
Speaker 1: Delicious is so excellent.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like I did.
Speaker 0: I signed up for it a long time ago cuz women's got were like use this use this.
Speaker 0: it was Like years ago.
Speaker 0: I remember Scott showing it to me the first time I saw it was on a train going to my internship and that was like More two and a half years ago or something.
Speaker 0: So I've had a delicious account for a long time, but I never really used it.
Speaker 0: and then now I started working.
Speaker 0: I don't want to have Bookmarks on my work computer because then I can't access them at home.
Speaker 0: So I delicious everything.
Speaker 0: but anyway, I found this thing and I thought it's very appropriate for Japan Day.
Speaker 0: and So when I was in Japan Especially in high school.
Speaker 0: There was this big thing Among the teenage girls called purikura, which is like a shortened version of print club.
Speaker 0: There's these little stickers that you get in the photo booth in in game centers in Japan.
Speaker 0: So you go to arcade.
Speaker 0: It's like four bucks wealth 400 yen and you put in the coins and everybody, you know does a pose and then you draw all over it and it prints out this page of stickers and then you cut them apart and paste them in your album.
Speaker 0: and And some of these girls had like these thick Binders full of purikura stickers and I'm like, let's see at a hundred yen a pop How much did they spend on these books?
Speaker 0: These must be like these binders filled with treasure, you know.
Speaker 0: And I thought wouldn't it be great if you can make purikura in America, but you know other than the occasional You know kind of lame Machine in an arcade.
Speaker 0: It's it's not the same.
Speaker 0: Trust me wasn't Wildwood.
Speaker 1: Those machines are like five bucks.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it's it's just it's.
Speaker 0: it's nothing to compare with the Japanese arcade purikura but I have found a website where you can take any photo and You can doctorate with all the little cute purikura doodles and you can make it look just like purikura.
Speaker 0: So if you want to do a purikura you and use it as like your icon picture or something go for it.
Speaker 0: It's called purikute and it is adorable.
Speaker 0: and for you guys out there because I know Just based on the the poll that more guys listen than girls There are a lot of hot pictures of Japanese girls on the site.
Speaker 0: so like if you want to look at like cute ace and women being like In and doing doing mugging for the camera go there and and you'll probably get a different kind of enjoyment out of it than I Did.
Speaker 0: but oh well So.
Speaker 1: but anyway now tonight we've got a bunch of shows like this lined up, but this is a good way to start it off.
Speaker 1: we've been really thinking about getting a lot of people who are in various professions that geeks might be interested in or Might not be interested in but also might not realize exactly what they're about just yet.
Speaker 0: Actually Alex asked me today.
Speaker 0: He brought up the the idea of you you posed a while back about working in the game industry.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because a lot of geeky jobs are not what you think they are like a video game tester.
Speaker 0: Oh, we were talking about that today - Jamie brought it up because we were testing a game.
Speaker 0: we were testing the sledding game and you know basically it just like we play it over and over and over again and look for bugs and we're like man the server lags and blah Blah blah and we have to note down everything.
Speaker 0: and we're like, you know You remember when you were a little kid and you wanted to be a video game tester.
Speaker 0: so bad Because it would be so awesome to get paid to sit around all day and do video games.
Speaker 1: Yep Let's see.
Speaker 1: hit the farthest left block.
Speaker 1: Nothing bad happened.
Speaker 1: hit the farthest left block while holding B. Nothing bad happened to became big.
Speaker 1: hit the farthest left block holding B. Nothing bad happens.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's about it.
Speaker 0: But with our games glitches always happen.
Speaker 0: I'm like, um, I'm falling down a waterfall.
Speaker 0: I think I went underground.
Speaker 0: what's going on?
Speaker 0: You know some of the glitch I should be talking about.
Speaker 1: it can't be any worse.
Speaker 1: This is quiet.
Speaker 1: quiet.
Speaker 1: It can't be any worse than baby Moses.
Speaker 0: It's it's.
Speaker 0: it's a lot better than baby Moses.
Speaker 1: We really want to do a whole series because we a lot of the people in the front row crew and a lot of different Fields and we want to talk about like from their perspective.
Speaker 1: What is actually?
Speaker 1: Really for serious like to be in that profession and what did you actually have to do if you want to enter that profession?
Speaker 0: And since Emily is in a profession that is interesting to a lot of you particularly probably Wednesday Haha, I'm an animator But do you wait wait until you hear the episode to decide whether or not you want to be jealous or not?
Speaker 1: Oh, so what exactly would you say that your title would be?
Speaker 0: Well, I am by my letter.
Speaker 0: when I got hired said I'm a virtual world character designer.
Speaker 0: But um, I which is like amazing.
Speaker 0: Like I love telling people what I do because they go Mmm.
Speaker 0: But basically I am the art department at this really small internet startup where we're designing games and doing some web applications and stuff.
Speaker 0: and Well real small-scale operation but really fun.
Speaker 0: and I am basically the art department.
Speaker 0: I am the jack-of-all-trades for the visual part of the 3d and so I do everything from modeling to texturing to the actual animation of the characters.
Speaker 0: and You know it started where I Drew a lot of sketches and said, you know, what what sort of characters do you want to go with?
Speaker 0: What what is the style we want to present here?
Speaker 0: And you know, I took a bunch of reference images from like everything from Wind Waker to triplets of Belleville, you know Just lots of different things to show to my boss and say so what are we going for here?
Speaker 0: And that's that's basically you know, the sketching out and deciding the look of the characters is what a character designer does.
Speaker 0: but You know, like I said, I I do basically everything Drawing and modeling and I can say oh, yes My name is Emily Compton and I model for a living and people go really with this look of disbelief on their face.
Speaker 0: I'm like not the modeling you're thinking of hehe.
Speaker 0: Anyway So about getting into animation which is the actual title of this show I Hear a lot of people who are into anime say they really want to be animators and I gotta tell you it's an awesome job but there are some things that I think you need to know about it before you actually become seriously interested in that as a career path and One of the things I want to bring up is Being an animator.
Speaker 0: really kind of isn't something you just one day you decide you want to do.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like oh, I like anime.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll be an animator.
Speaker 0: See, I think it's important to be drawing from a very young age and so like you have to be first interested in art and then become interested in animation I think and Then you'll kind of develop better as an animator.
Speaker 0: whereas if you were in something completely different like Programming and then one day you said I'm going to start drawing.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really work out.
Speaker 0: So well, it's very difficult.
Speaker 1: Well, I think you said before that you even there were people you were going to school with.
Speaker 1: who were you know?
Speaker 1: They're in animation programs.
Speaker 1: They wanted to animate but they couldn't actually draw.
Speaker 0: It's like there are people and and there are jobs available in the animation industry.
Speaker 0: If you don't even if you don't have the technical skills, and I mean, I'm not gonna lie to you I'm not even the greatest artist.
Speaker 0: I'm just you know, run-of-the-mill middle-of-the-pack kind of deal and You've got some people in art school that will just blow you away.
Speaker 0: Like I have this friend who works for Pixar and he's he's a great guy because he draws like you just insanely well But he's he's just like the most laid-back down-to-earth.
Speaker 0: He's such a good buddy.
Speaker 0: But anyway, um so when?
Speaker 0: When you're looking into animation schools and stuff you gotta understand that there's going to be a wide range of people attending and you're probably Got to get over any sort of artistic competition you have Because otherwise you're just gonna be like pissed off and miserable the whole time because there are going to be people who are better than you.
Speaker 0: But there there are people who are into art as a hobby and say they go to school for engineering.
Speaker 0: I remember rim.
Speaker 0: you wrote an article for imagine FX, right?
Speaker 1: I did but it was about Otakon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway, the there's this illustration magazine called imagine FX and they've got some really really good artists.
Speaker 1: It's actually a pretty cool magazine.
Speaker 0: It's expensive as all get out those those two magazines the CG world and imagine FX.
Speaker 0: every time I pass the newsstand I was like drool, but they're $15 but drool, but $15.
Speaker 0: and I was that way with Terrible, you know, it's like as soon as I. finally, you know, okay.
Speaker 0: I'm not buying new type, you know years ago I kind of you know Quit new type and then it was just like oh, but I found this new magazine and it's $15 Which is even more expensive than new type.
Speaker 0: But so anyway, imagine FX they had this article on this one creator and he went to school for engineering And then, you know, he finished his degree and he decided that he wanted to be a character designer.
Speaker 0: and He he had done art as a hobby and I think that's the important thing.
Speaker 0: You don't necessarily have to go to school for animation although it helps but you have to have this interest in art and you have to not just like anime and want to be Making anime to really like to draw and to draw all your life and to just look at the world and and think you know, what do I want to draw?
Speaker 0: all the time and My teacher described it as like a satellite dish you're always constantly looking around and trying to pick stuff up and An animator actually there's a step more than that because because a visual artist they're looking at Objects and thinking about drawing and just taking the world in through their eyes.
Speaker 0: But an animator also looks at how things move and so it's like I'll be sitting on the subway and being like man.
Speaker 0: That guy walks funny.
Speaker 0: I'll have to remember that.
Speaker 0: so it's like in my head.
Speaker 0: I'm always thinking.
Speaker 0: Oh that moves weird.
Speaker 0: I'll have to remember that.
Speaker 0: So anyway, you know you got any questions about Whether it's fun to animate.
Speaker 1: Well, actually I was curious too about in terms of what it's what's it like in school Like I want to like to be in school actually doing animation for grades and learning all this stuff freaking
Speaker 0: awesome Except for the times when you're up all night like Bags under your eyes and at one time actually I remember this very clearly staying up and pulling an all-nighter on an animation project because I remembered it thunderstormed and I saw lightning strike the Con Ed building and that was pretty cool and It was like 4 in the morning.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh if I hadn't been staying up doing homework I never would have seen this awesome sight, you know, so but I Loved art school.
Speaker 0: I went to NYU's Tisch School of the Arts so I I mean my impression of college life might be kind of changed by the fact that it was like Downtown Manhattan in Greenwich Village.
Speaker 0: So it was.
Speaker 0: it was actually quite a different experience from going to RIT and doing animation.
Speaker 0: but Really?
Speaker 0: I tell you this much if you decide to go into especially computer animation you will meet some of the most geeky laid-back people and Like a lot of my friends who are in animation.
Speaker 0: They're just really quirky really easy to talk to.
Speaker 0: it seems like animation.
Speaker 0: It attracts a certain kind of interesting personality and I remember just Animation floor had the best couch - that's that's a complete aside.
Speaker 0: but I remember after those all-nighters I used to go to the eighth floor and just lied on the couch like You are my friend But I'd open those doors to the eighth floor and it was just like I'm home.
Speaker 0: You know, I I loved the animation program at NYU.
Speaker 1: So it's great getting out of college.
Speaker 1: Oh, I mean, how do you get a job in animation?
Speaker 1: I mean, oh are they just in the major cities?
Speaker 0: or actually There are animation jobs outside the major cities But they're very limited and you'll probably find yourself doing a lot of motion graphics Which is like make stuff slide across the screen during commercials, you know Make exploding text during commercials.
Speaker 0: and so with the the main two two hubs There's also stuff in Canada.
Speaker 0: So if you're in Toronto is something and I can only speak about the United States because I'm not really sure about you know say Europe or But New York LA that's your choice.
Speaker 0: So I'm definitely.
Speaker 0: I was born and raised in New York, so I really prefer the East Coast.
Speaker 0: but I'm not Completely adverse to the idea of someday going out to LA to work for a bigger studio There.
Speaker 0: there is a big studio in New York blue sky studios.
Speaker 0: They just did Horton.
Speaker 0: here's a who and actually a lot of my teachers worked for them.
Speaker 0: I remember Dean my my senior thesis professor.
Speaker 0: He He did a lot of the animation for the sloth on Ice Age and he'd bring in clips all the time, but So New York's mostly independent.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of commercial work like a lot of music video work too in New York.
Speaker 0: But if you want to do something like Disney or Pixar or any of the the really big big names Those are all out on on the West Coast.
Speaker 0: So Actually my own story about how I got a job at my company so sauce doing the game animation that was completely random.
Speaker 0: So it was.
Speaker 1: you know, that's not so bad.
Speaker 0: Tell you the story.
Speaker 1: I kind of got my first job at IBM By accident and then from there everything was just the sea of accidents that got me where I am now.
Speaker 0: Yeah So I'll tell you the story because because it's kind of a funny story.
Speaker 0: But I remember there was a note pinned up on the bulletin board on the on the eighth floor.
Speaker 0: That was like a $1,000 character design contest and it had two stick figures on it.
Speaker 0: I was like who in their right mind with a flyer like this would give someone $1,000 for a character design contest.
Speaker 0: This is this is crazy.
Speaker 0: So I actually spent my birthday Designing like the evening of my birthday Designing characters for for the the contest deadline the next day.
Speaker 1: I think a lot of our and then I listeners will remember this because they were actually linked to in the forum by someone.
Speaker 0: Oh, I was I was so sad though it was like it's raining and I ate Mexican food by myself and I spent my birthday drawing in my room and it was.
Speaker 0: it Was a melancholy birthday and and then my friends called me.
Speaker 0: They're like, let's go out tomorrow.
Speaker 0: So that was all okay, but So anyway I submitted and they had a judging and I you might remember this if you've been on the forums a long time because I because I did kind of You know forum spam with the vote for me.
Speaker 1: You did it cleverly in the.
Speaker 1: I won't tell you which ones are mine.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, I thought I did.
Speaker 0: I thought I posted a picture.
Speaker 0: I think you might have late I did.
Speaker 0: I posted a picture.
Speaker 0: be like look at my characters check them out.
Speaker 0: if you like them vote for me.
Speaker 1: Maybe because I remember seeing them and not knowing which ones were yours ahead of time But being able to pick out easily which ones were yours.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz they looked kind of kind of Scott pilgrim II and my parents picked out these really anime.
Speaker 0: ask ones They're like, these are yours, right?
Speaker 0: But I really like these other ones.
Speaker 0: better I was like, no the ones you like are mine.
Speaker 0: the other ones those anime ones.
Speaker 0: Those aren't mine.
Speaker 0: So that was.
Speaker 0: that was fun, but I didn't win.
Speaker 0: Some guy got his.
Speaker 0: I found this out later because the guy who won was a friend of my coworker Brian who is awesome and He got his World of Warcraft guild to vote for his stuff.
Speaker 0: So he won even though his stuff was kind of me.
Speaker 1: Yes, learn a lesson out there.
Speaker 1: internet voting will never answer any question never never end.
Speaker 0: well, but but anyway, I didn't win.
Speaker 0: I didn't get the thousand dollars, but Eventually, I got an offer to be a software tester at social sauce and so I said hey why not?
Speaker 0: They'll give me a dollar and some free movie tickets.
Speaker 0: Why not test the software for him?
Speaker 0: so I did and I talked to them and I did this a few times kind of got to know the boss a little bit and you know gave gave lots of bossy advice in focus groups about their photo application and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: and then one day I See this post on the career board in in school.
Speaker 0: that was like Part-time character designer social sauce and immediately.
Speaker 0: I emailed them.
Speaker 0: I was like I can do it.
Speaker 0: I can do it.
Speaker 0: me me me I'm graduating soon and they're like, okay.
Speaker 0: and so they interviewed me and It was.
Speaker 0: it was kind of weird because we had known each other before and like they had seen a lot of my stuff before I was like, so what do you think?
Speaker 0: think you can do the job and they're like, yeah Yeah, you can do the job.
Speaker 0: and so it was.
Speaker 0: it was weird luck.
Speaker 0: and then I thought back to her.
Speaker 0: I was like man.
Speaker 0: if I hadn't spent that birthday Drawing those characters this chain of events wouldn't have happened.
Speaker 0: I wonder where I'd be now.
Speaker 0: and it was.
Speaker 0: it was kind of weird.
Speaker 0: So take that into account like never Discount any context you have like.
Speaker 0: sometimes things just work out very.
Speaker 1: that seems to go for like almost every profession I mean like IT and is the same way like everyone Who you know, everyone is connected.
Speaker 0: See I'm turning into Lane.
Speaker 1: be like everyone is connected or avatar when he goes to the swamp.
Speaker 0: I'm still mad that that Rims watching avatar and finally I have someone to geek out about it with around you had you had a caden Adam.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, your idol and I know.
Speaker 0: but the thing is they weren't around all the time.
Speaker 0: So when I was watching it, I was like, oh, oh and this happened and Zuko is sad, but I couldn't say anything.
Speaker 0: Zuko, he's so sad.
Speaker 1: I don't know more and more.
Speaker 1: I really like soccer though.
Speaker 0: That's kind of funny.
Speaker 0: I thought soccer would appeal to you because that that one quote.
Speaker 0: what was the quote?
Speaker 0: whim?
Speaker 1: Oh the well, can your science and logics tell us why the rain falls?
Speaker 1: Yes Yes, it can.
Speaker 0: that was an episode where they were debunking fortune-telling.
Speaker 0: Yes, exactly on woo woo and so it was so funny.
Speaker 0: cuz I'm like This is gonna be an episode that appeals to room and he talked about it immediately.
Speaker 1: I was like, yeah, that's your quote in there, you know, this is starting to give me an idea.
Speaker 1: actually This is a total non sequitur, but not completely.
Speaker 1: We've reviewed anime a lot on geek nights or movies or whatever, but it's always like me and Scott.
Speaker 1: we do a normal review.
Speaker 1: but I feel like we could do an interesting show if we got like Several front row crew people who had all seen the same show and just cut loose round table style.
Speaker 0: I'd go for a round especially with something epic.
Speaker 1: Like if we all talked about the old vampire 100 D movie or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually, I really want to watch.
Speaker 0: get Sankey or the girl who jumped through time.
Speaker 0: Toki Kake is really really Thinking about that today.
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: I love that movie, but get Sankey.
Speaker 0: I'm kind of and but none of you guys have seen it, right?
Speaker 1: I haven't.
Speaker 1: you haven't.
Speaker 1: no one has said anything good about God hasn't?
Speaker 0: Alex has it but it has dragons rim.
Speaker 0: Just watch it because it's Ghibli and dragon that comes from.
Speaker 1: you didn't listen to last night's show yet.
Speaker 0: Yes, I did and you were talking about rain of fire and how the movie blew.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but also how the only good thing in Twilight of dungeon is and the only good thing in Early years is the cute dragon girl.
Speaker 0: I like dungeon.
Speaker 0: actually though you you were catching flak on the forums cuz you don't read to Comics.
Speaker 1: I don't have time.
Speaker 1: What do you want?
Speaker 0: Hey, you have a train ride.
Speaker 1: Yes a train ride.
Speaker 1: That's already full of ever.
Speaker 1: avatar Cosino your Jimbo.
Speaker 1: and writing for my blog.
Speaker 1: I've got like eight articles.
Speaker 0: That's that's good.
Speaker 0: That's that's a valiant pursuit.
Speaker 1: studying the Napoleonic War so I could run my burning wheel game.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm still studying Greek history.
Speaker 0: No, you're very very good.
Speaker 1: and Roman history.
Speaker 0: But I just when you can started talking about writing on the blog it reminded me of something but Maybe I'll let you do it like in more depth as this thing of the day.
Speaker 0: But I found the most awesome open source software for screenwriting and storyboard organization and making your ideas.
Speaker 0: So all you writers out there take note.
Speaker 0: I have a present to show you and you probably already know about it.
Speaker 0: Well, you just behind the curvy surprise, but but this thing I was thinking man I need a screenwriting program, but they cost money, you know, it sucks and I'm making do with word and macro.
Speaker 0: And then I today I just stumbled across this.
Speaker 0: I was like this is awesome and perfect and it's actually cute for an open-source gooey, you know, and Anyway So, I don't know if if I just rambled and you actually learned anything about what it's like to animate.
Speaker 0: but one thing I wanted to say in closing about debunking myths of animation is one.
Speaker 0: It's not unless you're an independent filmmaker, it's not like I come up with an idea for an anime and I make it.
Speaker 0: It's like your boss gives you storyboards.
Speaker 0: They say draw a guy jumping and then getting angry and it should look like this.
Speaker 0: And then you make it with many many drawings and the thing with animation.
Speaker 0: as opposed to comics.
Speaker 0: I do comics to relax.
Speaker 0: I don't often animate in my spare time, but I I think it's very technical like Animation is is less artistic like the keyframes.
Speaker 0: You have to have a good grasp of art, but it's a different kind of Skill and it's a different kind of knowledge than what takes to draw still image because you're basically copying the same drawing with minor changes over and over for like tens of hundreds and dozens of times.
Speaker 0: and Yeah, so It's very time-consuming and can get really boring.
Speaker 0: but I tend to.
Speaker 0: I tend to get into the groove like I'll put some music on and I'll work and and then I fall into kind of a rhythm and you know, I turn out the drawings, but it's definitely not the same kind of Feeling you get when you draw a page of comic but there there is nothing like when you hit that playback or or shoot a pencil test and then you see This these drawings that were just drawings like come to life And that's that's the thing that gets me about animation is when you see a character that isn't real and yet You can give them life and it's also kind of like it's.
Speaker 0: it's great for a control freak like myself This is why I wasn't meant for live-action cuz I'm like it's raining.
Speaker 0: Why can't I control the weather?
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: and or why why isn't the light just right now?
Speaker 0: in animation you can you control everything.
Speaker 0: They are your puppets you make them dance.
Speaker 0: but so just just to let you know one the creative control you don't get as much and Unless unless you are say a script writer or a storyboard artist then you get a little bit more say over over what it actually looks like as opposed to the execution.
Speaker 0: and Let's See.
Speaker 0: so also You're not usually doing it by yourself.
Speaker 0: You've got to work with a lot of other people.
Speaker 0: and but that can be fun too because I remember working at the anime animation studio the animation collective which is doing speed racer and I crashed with these two while I was while I was working there and I remember that Every lunch hour we'd sit together and watch anime and it was great and and everybody was geeky.
Speaker 0: Everybody was cool.
Speaker 0: It was the most.
Speaker 0: like I said animators cool geeky laid-back people.
Speaker 0: for the most part you get the occasional like, you know Really tense Wow Angry Disney file, but then for the most part Yeah, animators are quirky and chill.
Speaker 0: So I I think you'll meet a lot of cool people if that's the career you choose and draw draw a lot.
Speaker 0: the end It's all this.
Speaker 1: so I guess.
Speaker 1: on that note if anyone has any actual specific questions I am sure Emily aka Gomi dog will be happy to answer them for you in the thread for this show And I'll make it into a flame war and then I'll draw Scott as a my waker.
Speaker 0: Good night to you all.
Speaker 1: bunwee This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 2: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 2: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 2: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: if you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 2: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 2: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 2: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 2: It's actually recorded at night.