Speaker 0: It's Tuesday January 29th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 0: We tell you not only how to not suck, but how to beat all your friends at Settlers of Catan.
Speaker 0: Let's do this If nothing else.
Speaker 0: the new Advance Wars is up hardcore.
Speaker 0: It is quite the hardest of course to the point that I think we're gonna hold off on reviewing it another week Or maybe two because I'm real close to beating it and I got a lot to say about it.
Speaker 0: Most of it is good.
Speaker 1: Yeah There's a lot of things to say about it cuz it's so different from the other advance Wars that if a I think Even if we had done like three Set a show for each and every Advance Wars in the past god.
Speaker 0: I could do a show.
Speaker 1: I don't think you're doing a show on this.
Speaker 1: new one would be red.
Speaker 0: I think I could do a show a whole show about every single map in the war room of every Advance Wars.
Speaker 1: today You had to do a whole show about every war room, man I don't think we should.
Speaker 0: I think that would get real old real quick, but I think I could.
Speaker 1: that's all you.
Speaker 1: I think it would just take about five minutes to talk about each man.
Speaker 0: Are you kidding span Island alone?
Speaker 0: They're like four different ways to beat it and they're five ways.
Speaker 0: if you use a certain CEO there The depth in those games is so great.
Speaker 1: I think you're just a little crazy with the advance orders.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe I am.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna pretend I'm not.
Speaker 0: at least I didn't Fail out of graduate school because of Advance Wars like someone else.
Speaker 1: we know fact you managed to play Advance Wars and pass.
Speaker 0: Yeah The fact that I s Frank the hard campaign on Advance Wars 1 & 2 and still graduated still amazes me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, I don't know there was a point at which I would play.
Speaker 0: I would get to school.
Speaker 0: I'd play while I was walking to class.
Speaker 0: I'd play in class.
Speaker 0: I'd leave class.
Speaker 0: They go to lunch.
Speaker 0: I'd play.
Speaker 0: batteries would die.
Speaker 0: I'd go buy more batteries continue to play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, GBA You know, in fact when I think about it, I really only played Advance Wars on my GBA.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well when that there's a blue and black DS light coming, I'm all about that.
Speaker 1: finally a somewhat decent color.
Speaker 1: I guess I can't afford to wait for a better color.
Speaker 0: So I'll take what I can get, you know, your regular DS works fine.
Speaker 1: Why don't you just keep using it because it's not as bright as a DS light.
Speaker 0: It's not as small Yeah, and how much does the DS light cost now compared to say six months ago?
Speaker 1: the same, huh?
Speaker 0: So if you bought it six months ago the cost of the same But you would have had six more months of the bright screen that the wrong color Plus.
Speaker 0: so so so so aesthetics matter.
Speaker 1: Well, no, it would also.
Speaker 1: the wear and tear on the system would have been six months worth.
Speaker 1: So now I'm getting a brand new one now which is you know.
Speaker 0: see the thing is what my regular DS got beat the hell out of partly because it was kind of big and bulky and also because I Carried on the DS.
Speaker 1: my the plain old DS was new and you turned it on.
Speaker 1: it was amazing.
Speaker 1: And now not so much.
Speaker 0: No, not so much.
Speaker 0: And the thing is I'll admit my DS seemed fine until it broke.
Speaker 0: it was like I can hold out.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna buy a DS light.
Speaker 0: I'll wait for the DS.
Speaker 1: I still pretty sure you broke it somewhat on purpose.
Speaker 1: Are you kidding even subconsciously on purpose playing Pokemon?
Speaker 0: I was in the middle of some Pokemons and I dropped it.
Speaker 0: I would you know how angry I was at the fact that I could not continue to play Pokemon and then I basically had a very large Somewhat suboptimal GBA for the next couple weeks before I bought a new DS but not.
Speaker 1: but you don't care about your Pokemons now.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, I could throw away my Pokemons and not even blink.
Speaker 0: I'm done with that game forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah Oh, well, so we gonna talk about newses or things of the day or any that kind of shit.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess I could start.
Speaker 0: I got a news.
Speaker 0: I'm sure the forum all knows what this is about and I'm sure they know my opinion but most of you Will see.
Speaker 0: we'll go with this.
Speaker 0: So there are some announcements.
Speaker 1: regarding Team Fortress 2 last week The game that we talked about way more on this podcast than it deserves.
Speaker 0: The game the game we waited for 10 years.
Speaker 1: I mean, I know it just seems that like if you take we probably talked about Team Fortress 2 on this podcast More than any other single game, but I don't think it really deserves that and I think there are a lot of other games.
Speaker 1: We never talked about that.
Speaker 1: We probably could talk about least a little bit like what I don't know a lot of the games You don't play like what game what game you talk about?
Speaker 0: So like Mario Galaxy talk about Mario Galaxy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we haven't played it yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I've been playing a Counter-Strike.
Speaker 1: Great, okay.
Speaker 1: Anyway, talk about your thing is Team Fortress 2.
Speaker 0: I've had a mixed love-hate relationship with it because on one hand it's Extremely well put together and well balanced and it's it's overall a really really solid game But at the same time it had a lot of in my opinion fundamental failings that Really really just bother me constantly when I play it and as a result, I haven't played it Nearly as much at all compared to pretty much any other FPS.
Speaker 0: I've liked in my entire life.
Speaker 1: Well, you've got an advanced source now, so just forget about it.
Speaker 0: I can't I just can't forget about it because I love FPS.
Speaker 0: I've been playing FPS is for as long as FPS is have existed.
Speaker 0: I played Doom like every other day from the day it came out But just play Counter-Strike then and forget I have then.
Speaker 0: but the thing is I like these teeny natural selection.
Speaker 0: Actually, I tried to play natural selection over the weekend.
Speaker 0: There were.
Speaker 0: there was one server with people on it.
Speaker 0: The rest were all bots Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I want to look into that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that one server it was running combat and everyone really sucked.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll look into that.
Speaker 1: We'll see what the story is.
Speaker 1: They are working on NS2.
Speaker 1: They have a little video.
Speaker 0: You know what Duke Nukem and Team Fortress 2 have both been being worked on in the past.
Speaker 1: Team Fortress 2 came out.
Speaker 1: Yeah after ten years and NS2 will come out in the next five years.
Speaker 1: I guarantee five years within the next five years.
Speaker 0: Okay, so in four point nine seven years I'm gonna get to be really disappointed by a game that won't live up to my unrealistic expectations.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling that NS2 will is not a game that will disappoint.
Speaker 0: I think you underestimate my my unrealistic expectations.
Speaker 1: Okay, maybe me if your if your expectations are too unrealistic then you can't be helped.
Speaker 1: All right I have faith in the people who make the NS2.
Speaker 0: so I Realized something and I kind of thought this but I didn't.
Speaker 0: I wasn't sure and now it's been proven to me because one Team Fortress 2 that you know, they realize that people aren't playing the game that much anymore.
Speaker 0: They're there aren't even like on eighth the number of people playing it now that we're playing it when it came out at least on the PC Servers have declined and the game is not nearly as popular as I guess they expected it to be.
Speaker 0: so they've been saying Oh, we're gonna change it We're gonna add stuff.
Speaker 0: part of that was adding new maps and the first of all these new maps came out Wasn't actually a new map.
Speaker 0: It was just that well map, but they changed it to be a capture the flag.
Speaker 1: Well, I think that's a good idea because they only had one capture the flag map.
Speaker 1: yet despite after the flag is the most popular Playstyle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean think back in like the weapons factory days.
Speaker 0: There were like 42 fort maps and all of them were popular.
Speaker 0: Yeah Team Fortress Team Fortress comes out Yep, and there was one.
Speaker 1: and well well was the second most popular map right after I guess, you know To fort.
Speaker 1: so the problem to forward it was too small.
Speaker 1: So they just made a CTF.
Speaker 1: well, and then it sounds good to me.
Speaker 0: now pretty much every Idea I had about what was wrong with Team Fortress 2 was crystallized by CTF.
Speaker 0: Well because CTF well made the game fun again.
Speaker 0: CTF well is like the best thing that could have ever have happened to Team Fortress 2 just by having open spaces and by having like Five or six different paths and even on a full-on like 16 versus 16 server You cannot cover every way of coming in and going out
Speaker 1: because on a normal well where it's captured the point, right?
Speaker 1: You're only ever really dealing with in a small area of the map at any one time.
Speaker 1: but in a CTF Well, you're dealing with the whole map at once and it really spreads everything out.
Speaker 0: now as a result the gameplay.
Speaker 0: I Noticed one thing people who weren't good at the game hate CTF.
Speaker 0: well because you can't do dick if you don't know how to play.
Speaker 0: FPS is.
Speaker 0: but The FPS skill that was so lacking in pretty much every other map in Team Fortress 2 is back and goddamn Is that like the best map ever?
Speaker 0: All right, and it proved everything I thought was wrong with Team Fortress 2.
Speaker 0: I mean I always complain like yeah Everything's slow and everything is like huddled together and aiming doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: and while aiming doesn't matter nearly to the degree that it did With the old-school possibly infeasible in the modern era FPS is at the same time just by having the bigger map Aiming matters a hell of a lot more than it did in any other tf2 map.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, so my interest in this game has been rekindled a thousandfold, but I will only play on CTF.
Speaker 1: Well, all right, but I might have to play some CTF.
Speaker 0: well you might you might your habits seriously.
Speaker 0: the game is fun again.
Speaker 0: I've been rocketed up.
Speaker 0: the spies can do shit.
Speaker 1: spot snipers matter But but I was waiting for the but I knew it was coming.
Speaker 0: see I wonder the good news first because CTF well is pretty.
Speaker 0: it's pretty much like valve said.
Speaker 0: alright rim.
Speaker 0: We heard that you were pissed off.
Speaker 0: Here's some candy.
Speaker 0: and then as soon as I eat the candy they say ah But that's the last of the candy and we're going to murder you tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Because it turns out that the other thing they're gonna add to the game is Every class is gonna get like a new weapon or something.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna get it all right.
Speaker 1: That's exactly what you wanted though.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh it is.
Speaker 0: yes Every class is gonna get a new weapon more because that's.
Speaker 0: the only other thing that was wrong with the game was that Every class needed one more main weapon, and it would have been like the perfect game.
Speaker 0: And they're adding one more weapon or one more ability to every class, but according to valve they're adding these weapons as Achievements I thought you were arguing for the achievements Against me now.
Speaker 1: Are you turning code?
Speaker 1: Are you joining the Scott anti-achievement brigade?
Speaker 0: I think Scott that you were.
Speaker 0: you're using a tactic that I've used very very often.
Speaker 1: Oh, are you saying my club my tactics are too clever?
Speaker 1: therefore I'm right, but a tactic that at the same time pointing out that my tactic is clever in fact proves me right not wrong.
Speaker 0: But clever it may be fallacious it is.
Speaker 0: no it is the fallacy you see of the false dichotomy.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's a false dichotomy because Achievements in and of themselves don't hurt games at all as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 0: They're there.
Speaker 0: whatever you can go after him.
Speaker 0: Don't go after him if you like him.
Speaker 0: That's great, but there is a problem in a game.
Speaker 0: That is nominally a stateless Skill-based versus team game where Achievements give you an advantage or change the options you have available to you within the game.
Speaker 0: basically team fortress 2 has become an MMO dun dun dun.
Speaker 0: now they haven't done this yet and I I was.
Speaker 0: everything I said about team fortress 2 being like the best fucking game ever and coming back and like this new map And they realized what they've done wrong, and they're fixing it.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much over.
Speaker 0: if they actually go forward with this if they decide that you have to arbitrarily level yourself up to get some Achievement in order to get the better healing gun or the different homing rocket launcher or whatever else they're gonna add.
Speaker 0: That reeks of bullshit to the level that I can't even begin to explain how.
Speaker 0: and not angry kind of Disappointed.
Speaker 1: yeah, I mean imagining counter-strike.
Speaker 1: right in counter-strike You have one game of counter-strike.
Speaker 1: it begins when the map loads and ends when the map changes, right?
Speaker 1: And the economics you know sort of go from round to round.
Speaker 1: But a set of rounds on one map is a game, and that's it.
Speaker 1: you don't carry your money from game to game.
Speaker 1: That's you know.
Speaker 1: in team fortress 2 one game is until the map ends until someone captures the flag three times or Captures all the points.
Speaker 1: It's one game alright, and what you do in a previous game should not affect the next game.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's that's how it get otherwise.
Speaker 1: It's just unfair.
Speaker 1: What if you went to go?
Speaker 1: you know play Scrabble with your friend right, but he won the last four games.
Speaker 1: He won the last four games of Scrabble that you were not involved in.
Speaker 1: so you go to play Scrabble But he starts with 400 points because he won the last four games that you were not involved in or he starts with all the Ease.
Speaker 1: yeah that does not make for a good game.
Speaker 1: and what they're gonna do to team fortress 2 is if someone got achievements in previous games Now that means they're gonna have more options.
Speaker 1: even if the options are no better or worse They're going to have more options available to them in the next game, and that's that does not make for a good game.
Speaker 1: It is not good.
Speaker 1: It takes away skill and encourages other things as bad.
Speaker 0: to clarify that sort of thing is Okay in a certain kind of game.
Speaker 0: if you don't want the game to be stateless or you don't want the game to be purely a Game of tactics skill or strategy, then that's fine.
Speaker 0: I think battlefield 2 is the example people brought up in the forums where yeah that game is not trying to be a stateless Versus game.
Speaker 0: it's trying to be a somewhat stateful semi simulation kind of game And it's this totally different thing and that that's all cool, but team fortress - I'm not a game.
Speaker 1: want to play them?
Speaker 0: well No, I respect a game like that.
Speaker 0: It's just that the kind of game I like is a game that is pretty much entirely a game of skill and a stateless game of skill at that.
Speaker 0: each round is Unique.
Speaker 0: that's why I play tennis.
Speaker 0: That's why I like games like that.
Speaker 0: I like to compete against people.
Speaker 0: German board games would totally suck if I could level up like in the Camarilla God.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh by the way in other news the cam sucks Because I'm curious if any man rim rim you better.
Speaker 1: you better take care of that news.
Speaker 1: it's an antique You know.
Speaker 0: you better watch that joke.
Speaker 0: Crap we're in a recursion loop.
Speaker 0: There's no way out.
Speaker 1: better watch that recursive loop.
Speaker 0: So uh I don't have a lot more to say about this other than that.
Speaker 0: You know what valve?
Speaker 0: fuck you this.
Speaker 0: I've waited for this game I for ten years and it came out and it was so close to being good.
Speaker 0: and then you're fixing the problems and you've realized there are problems and You're so close to perfection, and then you just take a big ol poop on it.
Speaker 1: well speaking of valve and the steam This better not be a steamy.
Speaker 1: Yeah How about how about the plumbing to go with your valve and your steam?
Speaker 0: all right?
Speaker 0: What's going on all right?
Speaker 1: So you know they have the steam thing right.
Speaker 1: let's you download the games now.
Speaker 1: We were by the game.
Speaker 0: we were talking about steam at work today, and I'm curious Why up in light of what happened to Vmware today?
Speaker 0: I'm I'm curious why steam doesn't try to work with Vmware to Get video stuff to work to the point that they could sell or give away for free.
Speaker 0: They steam appliance that runs on any any Computer that can run the M way because the problem there is.
Speaker 1: there's nothing steam could do to help them.
Speaker 1: They would need help from nVidi or Ati because they be oh yeah And if I need to write a piece of software that does everything that a video card.
Speaker 1: Oh,
Speaker 0: I'm well aware And I'm saying that if I were steam I would be doing everything I could I mean within the bounds of reality to Convince or lean on Ati or nVidia or Vmware all of them combined to try to get something like that because that would be pretty much the best thing in the world steam could Ever do to make themselves entrenched forever.
Speaker 1: It just seems like valve really never has and never will care about having steam running anything But windows pcs and it doesn't look like it's going to change even though it's something I want more than almost anything.
Speaker 0: It's something I'd be willing to pay a lot of money for.
Speaker 1: yeah I'd pay a lot of money for that.
Speaker 1: anyway What they have done right is there.
Speaker 1: they are now giving away something called steamworks, right?
Speaker 1: Let me.
Speaker 1: steamworks is for people who make games And it basically provides the.
Speaker 1: let me let me quote to gabe newell.
Speaker 1: You know Mr.. Steam Developers and publishers is spending more and more time and money cobbling together all the tools and back-end systems Needed to build and launch a successful title in today's market.
Speaker 1: Steamworks puts all those tools and systems together in one free package Liberating publishers and developers to concentrate on the game instead of the plumbing ha ha ha plumbing steam valve.
Speaker 1: all right Let me list everything.
Speaker 1: steamworks does you ready?
Speaker 0: This is either going to be a great list or a really really disappointing.
Speaker 1: It's a half great list and a half disappointing list all right.
Speaker 0: Let's hear it.
Speaker 1: So remember this is a tool to help people who are making games game publishers and game developers, right?
Speaker 1: First it gives you real-time stats on sales gameplay and product activation know exactly how well your game is selling etcetera, etcetera.
Speaker 1: alright State of the art encryption system.
Speaker 1: stop paying to have your game pirated.
Speaker 1: they have the.
Speaker 1: you know It's just.
Speaker 1: it'll be as hard to pirate.
Speaker 1: You know your games as it is to pirate.
Speaker 1: You know team fortress 2 or whatever.
Speaker 0: all right?
Speaker 1: Territory slash version control.
Speaker 1: basically you can release your game.
Speaker 1: You know different parts of the world and not worry about people in other parts of the world getting it.
Speaker 0: um so far.
Speaker 0: These all reek of like evil businessman DRM kind of things and not things to help me make a game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, is the bad ones all right now here.
Speaker 1: We go ready.
Speaker 1: Auto-updating ensures all customers are playing the latest and greatest version, okay, duh voice chat That's.
Speaker 1: you don't have to program voice chat.
Speaker 0: You just use the steam voice chat, man I think I haven't tried it yet, but I think you can voice chat in the new advanced horse Wi-Fi.
Speaker 1: yep Multiplayer matchmaking.
Speaker 1: so you don't have to make a matchmaking thing for your game.
Speaker 1: We just use the counter-strike team fortress matchmaking.
Speaker 0: That's actually really good because that's like the best system out there currently.
Speaker 1: yep Social networking with achievements leaderboards and avatars.
Speaker 1: fuck the achievements.
Speaker 1: But leaderboards and avatars without having you know there's nothing wrong with the achievements.
Speaker 0: They're chatting.
Speaker 1: as long as they don't give me the uber awp yep and Development tools so you can administer betas and things all right.
Speaker 1: So if you're making a game, and you guess you want your game to be on the steam You can just get the steamworks, and you can add all these features to your game.
Speaker 1: Especially you know if it's the sort of game where you know it's online Matchmaking you know servers and such without having to program all that shit.
Speaker 0: I don't get.
Speaker 1: I've already programmed it.
Speaker 0: so the game publisher you want to publish your game now.
Speaker 0: I can understand wanting to limit the markets in different places like release in the US and Japan and then in Britain or sorry Albion then in Australia or whatever because you know Distribution and all that is difficult.
Speaker 1: the main reason you want to do that I mean you think people would want to just release the game around the world to make the most money.
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: the main reasons I think that that I've got you know Re-importation from the cheap versions in the US.
Speaker 1: well no I think the reason that they don't want to release games worldwide just immediately is because Two reasons.
Speaker 1: number one right is you?
Speaker 1: they want to kind of translate the games You know and adapt them for different countries and stuff especially if there's laws about certain things like you know You can't have a let's say you make like Wolfenstein.
Speaker 1: well it's kind of hard to sell that in Germany you know with the Nazi whatnots and the laws there.
Speaker 1: so they want to avoid that kind of trouble.
Speaker 1: and Secondly they I guess Similarly you want to avoid you know if you do business in a one more country.
Speaker 1: now You're you know you're beholden to that country like Microsoft is getting sued in the EU even though They're you know country in Washington's your company, Washington State.
Speaker 0: well, so the thing is though.
Speaker 0: with digital distribution most of the barriers for worldwide release are eliminated and the only ones left are ones that come from you being afraid to stand up to some country that's afraid of Something that they shouldn't be.
Speaker 0: or if you're trying to be evil and make extra money Yeah, but I think that's why you still see different iTunes music stores for each country and do what I think we're gonna see as A result different.
Speaker 1: you know we shop channels for different countries.
Speaker 0: It just means that games released on Steam are going to for whatever reason Not appear in Australia until four months later for twice as much money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, but I really I just think that if anything you know well It's it's kind of crummy with the Steam DRM and all that other bullshit.
Speaker 1: You know you're gonna see a lot more games on Steam Which is just what Steam needs.
Speaker 0: and you know what I got to say.
Speaker 0: I see no problem with that.
Speaker 0: because Bioshock, right?
Speaker 0: I realize now that I know I don't need to go to stores at all anymore except for food and maybe very very Any video game any PC game?
Speaker 1: I can't buy on Steam or download from a website for free.
Speaker 0: I could buy an Amazon Yep, and I really really don't like going to stores anymore.
Speaker 0: going to stores is not pleasant and even then I don't want to a new like Bioshock comes out.
Speaker 0: I don't want to have to all right.
Speaker 0: go to Amazon pre-order it.
Speaker 0: then a physical box comes.
Speaker 0: What happens when I buy in a DS game?
Speaker 0: right a box comes?
Speaker 0: I open the box and throw the box away in.
Speaker 0: it is a smaller plastic box.
Speaker 0: I open the box.
Speaker 0: There's a bunch of papers in it.
Speaker 0: I pull them out I flip through one of them then I throw all of that away and all I have left is the game.
Speaker 0: yep and Computer games are even worse.
Speaker 0: they come with all this other stuff, but they don't come with anything useful.
Speaker 0: It's not like anyone ships manuals anymore
Speaker 1: and the only advantage of having the disc for a computer game is that if somehow your internet connection is dead and You need to install the game on a computer to play it because you don't have it installed already or broke or something Require
Speaker 0: online registration to work anyway
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: so if you have a net connection And you have steam you can download the game from steam and the only worry there Is that one day of steam dies you won't be able to get your games anymore, which is true.
Speaker 1: But I really just I don't see that happening.
Speaker 0: steams come a long way and steam has offline mode.
Speaker 1: So if you know that steam is gonna go away forever Get some drives and download and install all of your steam games And then put steam in offline mode and be done with it.
Speaker 0: plus if that really happened the one nice thing about steam and the Fact that gamers and nerds is that I?
Speaker 0: Imagine a lot of nerds would very quickly do everything they could to make steam work again Just so we can get with that.
Speaker 1: if it wasn't being constantly updated the DRM on the steam would be broken and all your games Would become unlocked or I imagine valve is really nice, and you know I you know the guys there even though They're.
Speaker 1: you know they're doing this stuff at it for the business reasons.
Speaker 1: They're not assholes.
Speaker 1: They make the good games.
Speaker 1: They care about the gamers.
Speaker 1: You know you could tell this the love and something like portal, right?
Speaker 1: So they're not gonna fuck us over.
Speaker 0: you could trust them unless we're fans of Skill based team FPS is yeah, well you know.
Speaker 1: like I said That's what we want.
Speaker 0: doesn't seem to be what most of the gamers want except the thing is Playership of Team Fortress has been dropping.
Speaker 1: so yeah because people don't know.
Speaker 1: people don't know what they want.
Speaker 0: I'll say this People may not want what I want because I'll admit that what I want is something from an older era But at the same time people don't want what's out there now.
Speaker 1: No people don't know what they want.
Speaker 0: That's the problem, and if a game could be made that was halfway between what I want and what they want It'd be a great game.
Speaker 0: the problem is that's up from the center of this triangle and valve is going to the exact opposite direction right now.
Speaker 1: full life consequences Consequences that will affect you for the rest of your life, so uh This was on FARC.
Speaker 0: I did not do any research into the veracity of the claims behind the origin of it.
Speaker 0: however I'm going to believe that the story is true because the The writing looks exactly like what a semi literate nine-year-old would spew forth from their hand or possibly onto a keyboard.
Speaker 0: alright, but uh Think about half-life and about John Freeman.
Speaker 0: Gordon Freeman's brother Must pretty creative for a nine-year-old kid live up to his family name and face full life consequences.
Speaker 0: now someone else being a genius took this and Narrated it while also acting it out in the half-life 2 engine.
Speaker 1: a little makinima actions.
Speaker 0: And let me tell you this is a little hilarious.
Speaker 1: No, I actually I didn't think it was so funny.
Speaker 0: I think you're a broken hearted cold-hearted horrible person for not liking this.
Speaker 1: yeah I don't not like it.
Speaker 1: I just didn't find it that exciting.
Speaker 1: I think it was just kind of.
Speaker 0: so what do you find exciting?
Speaker 1: Oh?
Speaker 1: You want to know the secret all right?
Speaker 0: What do you got?
Speaker 1: Alright, so this thing it is alright.
Speaker 1: I'm not exactly sure what the history of this is.
Speaker 1: that I think is why it is so appealing and Exactly what that why this video exists and what it's trying to do, but it's Ronald McDonald speaking Japanese To some song and he's doing DDR hottest party on three side-by-side DDR mats.
Speaker 0: oh man three mats.
Speaker 1: I wish I could play three mad DDR.
Speaker 0: That'll be something I know we both could.
Speaker 0: I wish I could set it up so where we could actually do it.
Speaker 1: You know what I'd like more than you know what I'd like more than that a DDR machine.
Speaker 1: No two by two mats to make a format square with screens on all sides.
Speaker 0: It was even better than that.
Speaker 0: what a dance floor Techno DJ.
Speaker 1: But yeah, this is uh it's pretty interesting, and I realized number one way to cheat at DDR clown shoes Especially with double mats.
Speaker 1: I know right there's double mats and clown shoes.
Speaker 1: you could hit two arrows at once with one foot with ease.
Speaker 1: It's diggity with the clown shoes, so You know if you want to if you want to win.
Speaker 1: It's some too mad DDR.
Speaker 1: Just get some clown shoes.
Speaker 1: It's real easy.
Speaker 1: You can you can stand up for you can say you could literally with clown shoes.
Speaker 1: You could just if you're doing single mat DDR Standard DDR.
Speaker 1: you could just put the clown shoes on and then just jump up and down really fast and pass the hardest on.
Speaker 1: So we've done a lot of shows You know Reviewing different board games or telling you about the rules or how they work and stuff and there's a lot of other Podcasts and things out there that do this, and you know we thought hey It hasn't really.
Speaker 1: no one's really done this yet at least not at a big scale of.
Speaker 1: you know actually telling you Strategy and how to win at games, and this is exactly what you do to play this game the best It can be played.
Speaker 1: and I guess for video games It's sort of hard to do that because we don't have the visuals necessary for a video game.
Speaker 1: You know and we don't have the.
Speaker 1: you know game facts sort of covers a lot of the the games that are just you know Sort of puzzle solution games, and maybe we could do like Street Fighter stuff But you really need to see pictures for that too, so but for board games We can pretty much just talk about strategy and how to win and you don't really need to see that much.
Speaker 1: You know maybe if it's a game like Tigris and Euphrates or go or chess you need to see the patterns, but for other games You don't really need to see any patterns or anything.
Speaker 1: we could just tell you how to win And that's what we're gonna try to do here.
Speaker 0: Yeah Now plus part of the reason we're doing this is that At some point in the near future Scott are gonna buy a camera and we want to start making just videos that show you how to be really good at board games like T&E in Puerto Rico and Gotta figure out how well this works.
Speaker 0: and settlers is such a simple game to basically beat that.
Speaker 0: What other game could we do first?
Speaker 0: maybe I guess Carcassonne, which is easily all right?
Speaker 1: Carcassonne you kind of need to see though.
Speaker 0: yeah, but in terms of simplicity of explaining how to win There's not so much to say.
Speaker 1: I think.
Speaker 1: guess who would be easier to explain?
Speaker 0: Ask if he's wearing glasses.
Speaker 1: Okay maybe maybe Yahtzee Actually battleship.
Speaker 0: We could just tell you what the search algorithm will work best.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna.
Speaker 1: we're gonna tell you how to win at settlers.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna see if that's interesting and we're gonna first of all we're gonna assume you already know how to play settlers of Catan.
Speaker 1: If you don't already know how to play settlers of Catan Then why you listen this show you got to learn how to play before you learn how to win.
Speaker 0: Well at the same time just log on to your Xbox and start playing some settlers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you'd you should.
Speaker 0: settlers is a fantastic game until you solve it and even then it's still not horribly unfun.
Speaker 1: No, all right, so First rule of settlers of Catan right is when you're starting the game The first thing you have to do is sort of put your initial settlements out there, right?
Speaker 1: Now when you're putting the initial settlements You know what where you go, you know Either are.
Speaker 1: you are there.
Speaker 1: you're gonna be the guy who puts out the first settlement ever and then the last one or you know the rules, right Basically on each of the numbers on the board because each resource spot has a number on it.
Speaker 1: There is some dots.
Speaker 1: More dots means that that space is more likely to be rolled.
Speaker 0: the six The dots are basically just if you don't know enough statistics to know the odds on 2d6 exactly.
Speaker 1: So six and eight have five dots and they're red because those are going to be the most frequently rolled statistically.
Speaker 1: after that comes you're like nine and five and then you know four and three.
Speaker 1: so you want to put your Settlement touching as many dots as possible.
Speaker 1: So this is a spot where you can put it where it's next to a six and a four and a ten.
Speaker 1: That's a pretty damn good spot.
Speaker 1: I mean the ten has what like three dots, right?
Speaker 1: The four has four dots.
Speaker 0: The thing is in terms of positioning in the early part of the game.
Speaker 0: now It doesn't matter when you go.
Speaker 0: other than that If you go last you have a special option of being able to know exactly where both of your settlements will go Mm-hmm, but generally you care about the dots more than anything.
Speaker 0: and if you're gonna win it settlers on average and in general When in doubt go for more dots.
Speaker 0: more dots can.
Speaker 0: you can never go wrong with more dots except an extremely specific and obvious situation.
Speaker 0: However, if the difference between a good loadout of Resources and a crappy loadout of resources is one or at most maybe two dots different You might want to edge toward picking the resource spot based on resource.
Speaker 0: They give you as opposed to number.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: I wouldn't sacrifice more than two dots But let's say I can choose to go here where there's you know, twelve dots or I can go there for ten dots But I'll have brick then that might be worth it Especially, you know depending on how late you're putting your settlement out if you can see where other people's settlements already are.
Speaker 1: Maybe not a lot of people are on brick.
Speaker 1: So it'll be much more valuable to go on a brick that's you know a little bit more likely.
Speaker 1: or Maybe you'll be a little closer to a very useful port.
Speaker 1: or maybe you know Your first settlement is really trapped by other people's settlements.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna be able to build any roads.
Speaker 1: So really you're not gonna be able to win if you don't put your second settlement somewhere that you can build a lot of roads Even though you get less dots, but I wouldn't sacrifice one more than one or two dots and it shouldn't be necessary too.
Speaker 0: If you're playing properly, yeah I mean there are crazy situations like let's say you go last and there's a spot that gets a ton of sheep and nothing else And a sheep port.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean in the weather one is taken exactly in the worst case scenario would be Basically, every other player puts their settlements in a way to fuck you horribly Sometimes which could happen.
Speaker 1: but in that case they'd pretty much have to detriment themselves Leaving a really great space wide open for you and you just take that.
Speaker 0: and so now before we get into I mean the exact specifics of placing that I think the the main discussion here is what are the strategies of settlers?
Speaker 0: because we can talk about the mechanics of like.
Speaker 0: there are certain things that are that are Universal to all strategies like how to deal with trading when to go after stiffy cards when to go after whatever.
Speaker 0: but the the fundamental thing about settlers that advanced players will think about and novice players don't.
Speaker 0: so much as What direction are you going to go?
Speaker 0: and there are effectively only three viable strategies in settlers of Catan and there are minor variations on these strategies.
Speaker 0: and Looking at the board and looking at where you can place You have to decide which of these you want and not let up and not change for the rest of the game.
Speaker 0: If you try to change strategies midstream, you're done.
Speaker 0: Now the strategies basically boil down to the.
Speaker 0: there's a little people call them different names, but there's a brick and wood grain and sheep and Tripod.
Speaker 1: well tripod is sort of a set.
Speaker 1: is it sort of goes along with either one of the two?
Speaker 0: The thing is they're kind of like tripod.
Speaker 0: tripod is special in that What it where you place and what you do is not dependent upon what resources you want.
Speaker 1: You know, you sort of need some brick and woods to do it But very little because you can trade.
Speaker 0: tripod is basically the strategy of go for dots and nothing else.
Speaker 0: get whatever resources you can No matter what they are because more resources always better.
Speaker 1: and with tripod you're gonna be building more settlements and fewer roads.
Speaker 1: So you're gonna want to try to get a more of a spread on the resources You're gonna need.
Speaker 1: you know, cuz a settlement requires a brick One of each one of four, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it doesn't need stone.
Speaker 1: Yeah It doesn't need stone but it needs one of everything else.
Speaker 0: and then the brick and wood strategy is Basically you want to start getting a lot of brick and wood and you don't really care about much else and you use the brick And wood to expand out all over the board as fast as you can and cut other players off from key areas that you're then Going to build it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: That also gets you the longest road Which is very.
Speaker 1: something is very important in the game is that you know You're playing on this in this game and the way to get points is to build settlements build cities longest road and Biggest army.
Speaker 1: if you're not going for either Longest road or biggest army, you're not gonna win.
Speaker 1: You need one of the two to win.
Speaker 1: I've never seen someone win without one of those two.
Speaker 0: I have but not when every player is experienced, right?
Speaker 0: You know, well think of it this way.
Speaker 0: Well, we're gonna give these strategies to you from the perspective of you're playing against suboptimal players.
Speaker 0: If you follow our advice, you're probably going to win every time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: if you follow what we say and you do it correctly then you will beat people who do not do this pretty much Statistically most of the time.
Speaker 1: if you're playing if everyone playing is following these strategies Then the game is gonna come down to chance.
Speaker 1: pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean the.
Speaker 0: the example is I entered a sanctioned official settlers of Catan tournament round one where everyone's in.
Speaker 0: I Won by like seven points.
Speaker 0: everyone just sucked like horribly and I didn't.
Speaker 0: and the next round I still won by a lot, but there were other players who were good.
Speaker 0: the third round It was literally every player was pretty much exactly equal in skill and it was totally random who won.
Speaker 0: and The fourth round it was perfectly random.
Speaker 0: It was literally without any exaggeration the player across from me one with ten points the player to their Around.
Speaker 0: the next player would have no matter what gotten their tenth point on that round.
Speaker 0: I would have gotten my tenth point on that round and the other player would have gotten the tenth point on that round.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess the odds were really nice and even out but you could have been paired with one of those people that you played The final game with in the first round.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I guess you just didn't.
Speaker 1: yeah luckily But yeah.
Speaker 0: So in that case because the thing is the way it was it was soft Elimination where the bottom two players were eliminated from the first round.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's not bad.
Speaker 0: So it wasn't that there's a pretty good way to do it.
Speaker 0: But that was when I realized that settlers is random among skilled players.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm All right, so but then the other strategy is the the stone and sheep strategies alternately known the city stiffy Strategy, yep You can either real.
Speaker 1: if you if you try to get lots of bricks and woods Then you're gonna build lots of roads and process a lot more settlements.
Speaker 1: If you try to get more rocks and grains and sheep You're gonna be able to build.
Speaker 1: upgrade to your cities getting more rocks and grains and sheep getting a lot of stiffy cards.
Speaker 1: Oh, but stiffy cards are development cards, but you're not cool unless you come stiffy guys.
Speaker 1: That's what they're called in German I guess but I think it's because the original German the development.
Speaker 1: They were really thick.
Speaker 1: They were printed on very heavy card stock.
Speaker 1: So people called them stiffy cards.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, yes.
Speaker 1: So if you get lots of stiffy cards, you can then use those, you know to get the largest army and also to win the Game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so basically the brick and wood lets you expand a lot But you're not gonna get a lot of cities and you just have to expand.
Speaker 0: block other players build as many settlements as you can The the and you'll get longest road.
Speaker 0: the sheep and stiffy strategy is you're gonna get the largest army and you're gonna have all these Cards, which are gonna help you with the fact that you don't have a lot of brick and wood like.
Speaker 0: hopefully I get road building or something, but even if you don't you'll be able to trade and get a board or something.
Speaker 0: and Tripod is the generic.
Speaker 0: this strategy will always work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, tripod means that you build a settlement right.
Speaker 1: you ignore resources.
Speaker 1: You're not allowed to build another settlement within one space.
Speaker 1: So what you do is you build two roads and then you build another settlement.
Speaker 0: and then well, no No, you build one road and then from that one road you branch out in both directions with a road.
Speaker 1: That's what I was about to say.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then you build a settlement on each of each of those.
Speaker 1: So basically you have three settlements.
Speaker 1: each settlement has one road pointing inwards and those three roads meet each other So that you can get the most settlements in the least amount of space, you know Normally, you'd have to build a settlement two roads a settlement two roads a settlement.
Speaker 1: here You can build three settlements with three roads pointing all pointing at each other.
Speaker 0: now the drawback obviously is one You're not gonna get longest road and two you're gonna be building settlements in suboptimal places.
Speaker 1: Yeah But because you have so many settlements and you're not really competing to fight for a lot of territory on the board You're saving a lot of territory and you're saving a lot of resources not having to build extra roads.
Speaker 1: All those extra settlements are a lot of extra points and you're gonna get you know, even though you won't get a quantity of resources you're gonna do above average because you're gonna be having you know, all these settlements over the place and just keep doing it and You know, it puts you in a really strong position in the game.
Speaker 1: You build a lot of stuff and then you just kind of win.
Speaker 0: now these three strategies.
Speaker 0: you might say Hey, I thought you said this game was kind of random, but look there's three strategies and they do well have pros and cons.
Speaker 0: I mean tripods kind of like the.
Speaker 0: I'm going to march slowly toward the end and no one can stop me and brick and wood is a really strong early game, but stiffy sheep has a really strong late game, but The problem is you really don't have any choice in which strategy you use.
Speaker 0: And the reason I say that is that You don't choose your strategy going into the game and then try to put your pieces where you can enact that strategy Based on when you go in the order of placing settlements.
Speaker 0: You have to look right now what your options are what the board looks like and from there decide Opportunistically which of those three strategies is the best tactically for you based on the current situation, right?
Speaker 1: So if I'm putting my initial settlements down and the spot there's a spot with a whole bunch of dots That's open like I'd like.
Speaker 1: maybe you know Like for kidding more than 14. that like a whole lot of dots not 14.
Speaker 1: I have a whole lot of dots like it's got a six in a five and a nine.
Speaker 1: It's huge it's a great spot right and It's got rock rock grain under it.
Speaker 1: Guess what my strategy is gonna be lots of cities and lots of stiffy cards.
Speaker 0: Yep, and beyond that I mean you really just have to look at the.
Speaker 0: I mean the only other real concern in terms of strategy and placement is simply Is there going to be a resource or a commodity that's going to be ultra rare?
Speaker 0: but again because of the way placement goes don't have a lot of choice.
Speaker 0: because Sir, if you get to play first Then you got to play your second settlement last.
Speaker 0: you can have one good spot and almost no control over your second spot.
Speaker 0: So you got to play a more conservative game.
Speaker 0: but you'll offset that by having one really good settlement and The old.
Speaker 0: and although you also have to look at in terms of dots This is a very much a secondary concern, but you do want to keep an eye on where other players have placed.
Speaker 0: I mean, oh if you're thinking well, I'm gonna go here and I'm gonna be brick and wood So right away, I'm gonna blitz a road out and get that sheet port over there.
Speaker 0: That's a really crappy idea.
Speaker 0: If anyone else is also gonna go after that sheet port and is also doing brick and wood You can't rely on it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you basically want to sort of avoid Competition.
Speaker 1: there's enough resources in the game for you to get ahead without having to fight anyone else for the things you need.
Speaker 1: and If you want if you think oh, well, I can expend resources to maybe fuck someone else.
Speaker 1: well maybe you can.
Speaker 1: but if you do that and It's the only way to do that really is if you're going for longest road and you can build roads to sort of block people.
Speaker 1: But other than that trying to screw people use the robber.
Speaker 1: Yeah No There's no other way to do it.
Speaker 1: Really that is not gonna hurt you in the long run.
Speaker 1: if you try to screw people a different way like taking something they need That you don't particularly need Then you're just gonna hurt yourself and someone else is gonna win besides the two of you Especially in the opening placement.
Speaker 0: never think.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'll go here because that denies him the blah Cuz one.
Speaker 0: if it's a good spot someone else would go there.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you don't have to worry about it.
Speaker 0: and number two only go the place that is best for you.
Speaker 0: Don't worry about hurting some other player because everyone's gonna place optimally or they're dumb.
Speaker 1: Yep Now that I mentioned the robber.
Speaker 1: Let's talk about the robber All right.
Speaker 0: Now if people have cute little rules about the robber like house rules like oh, well It's traditional for everyone to bribe whoever gets the robber.
Speaker 0: or you don't put the robber on the first round Or you put the robber somewhere where it won't hurt anyone and everyone plays nice.
Speaker 0: if you want to win at this game One there is no robber leeway.
Speaker 0: That's a house rule.
Speaker 0: Yep, you robbers in play right away.
Speaker 1: If you roll a seven if the seven is the first role of the entire game Robber goes that's it.
Speaker 1: That's how the game works.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: if you're playing with a house rule fine, you have to follow the house rule if everyone else agrees and Beyond that it doesn't matter because if you roll the robber you can accept bribes.
Speaker 0: You can do whatever you want.
Speaker 0: However Do not ever not fuck someone with the robber.
Speaker 0: Put the robber in the place that hurts the most the player who needs hurting the most every time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we have pity.
Speaker 0: don't think oh, I should be fair.
Speaker 0: Just if you keep rolling sevens keep putting them on the lead players like forest and now you have the only wood in the game.
Speaker 1: Yep put it where you can do the most damage.
Speaker 1: if someone is in second place right behind you and the other people have way less Points than you do like.
Speaker 1: if I have the longest road and rim has the largest army and I get the robber I gotta fuck rim.
Speaker 1: So I look on the board.
Speaker 1: Where can I fuck rim the hardest?
Speaker 1: Oh, look, he's got a wood factory and I've got a wood factory.
Speaker 1: That's the only wood in the game and he's got two settlements in that wood factory.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna rob and I'm gonna take a resource from rim, you know.
Speaker 1: also pay attention to what resources people have.
Speaker 1: You don't need to remember exactly.
Speaker 1: It's not really that useful But remember it's sort of what people have like if someone just rolled.
Speaker 1: if you just roll the six You know last turn that means that so-and-so has a lot of rock.
Speaker 1: if you need rock Maybe you should rob them to get rock.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the odds are pretty good.
Speaker 0: You can always play the bribe because inexperienced players will often do the bribe now first of all for experienced players.
Speaker 0: Never ever bribe anyone you'll never gain.
Speaker 0: It's not worth it.
Speaker 0: No I mean totally a waste of your resource.
Speaker 1: think about how stupid.
Speaker 1: if they robbed you they take one resource.
Speaker 1: if you bribe them You give them at least one resource.
Speaker 1: It's basically you're saying don't rob me I'll rob myself to prevent you from robbing me now.
Speaker 0: instead if someone other player is foolish and decides to bribe you Take the bribe and then screw someone else because now you've screwed two people.
Speaker 0: Yep And that's pretty much.
Speaker 0: it do as much damage with the robbers.
Speaker 0: you can Always, okay.
Speaker 1: And here's another strategy because the with the sniffy cards right the sniffy cards you can get our soldiers vast majority of them Right, if you get a soldier, you're gonna.
Speaker 1: if you're going for largest army You're gonna be using lots of soldiers every time you use one.
Speaker 1: Move the robbers somewhere and use them just like we said to fuck someone the hardest.
Speaker 0: now remember there is a rule a lot of People forget you can on your turn before you roll the dice.
Speaker 0: if you have a soldier card Play it to move the robber.
Speaker 0: So if the robbers on you don't play the soldier before you roll the dice to move them off your stuff Then roll the dice and if you roll a seven you get to rob twice in the same turn.
Speaker 1: That's pretty good.
Speaker 0: Also and in terms of the soldier cards if you were going for largest army Or you think you might go for largest army Pretty much as soon as you get a soldier play it immediately because remember you can only play one card per turn.
Speaker 0: Already having a soldier out before other players do gives you a huge advantage because when it comes the longest road in largest army Ties go to the defender.
Speaker 0: You want to be the first one out there the first one with stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if I have three soldiers and then rim plays his third soldier I keep the largest army until he plays a fourth one.
Speaker 0: But yeah, if you're not going for a largest army If you've decided you are not going to pursue that at all don't play the soldier until you need to.
Speaker 1: yeah Play the soldier pretty much on your turn before you roll when the robber is on you.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, you know that will.
Speaker 1: basically it's always good to hold on to one soldier.
Speaker 1: Anyway, even if you're going for largest army because then you can always if you get robbed You can move the soldier you robber off right away
Speaker 0: but
Speaker 1: only
Speaker 0: hold on to it if you already have one n plus one soldiers out there and Number of soldiers any other player has
Speaker 1: exactly.
Speaker 0: All right In terms of the other stiffy cards, I think it's pretty obvious when to use them it is.
Speaker 1: However, there's a trick with monopoly.
Speaker 1: now The monopoly trick only works against moron players who don't haven't played the game and have no experience.
Speaker 1: So it's not gonna work against us.
Speaker 1: but the monopoly card the way it works is you.
Speaker 1: basically you say Monopoly on rock or monopoly on wood and everyone in the game has to give you all of their rock or all of their wood.
Speaker 1: Right, so that's really good.
Speaker 1: If you need a specific resource and you don't have it and you know Other people have a lot of it then you can do that, right?
Speaker 1: Now the problem the thing is you have to make sure you don't use it on something No one else has like.
Speaker 1: don't say monopoly on rock when there's only one rock out there.
Speaker 1: wait And then a whole bunch of people rolled up a whole bunch of rock and they haven't used it yet.
Speaker 1: then monopoly on rock, right?
Speaker 0: Another thing the the the special strategy.
Speaker 1: I'm almost there.
Speaker 1: I want to take cuz.
Speaker 1: it's so awesome?
Speaker 1: Okay, because it fools noobs every time.
Speaker 0: Yes, it does.
Speaker 1: It does it fools noobs every time.
Speaker 1: The the real trick with monopoly is this Let's say I've got a lot of rock and I know that other people in the game need rock Right now.
Speaker 1: if they're dumbass players right who are noobs, they're gonna trade me their stuff for my rock.
Speaker 1: I'm the only one with rock or I have a you know, a lot of rock and no one else does right?
Speaker 1: So I trade away my rock and get all the stuff I really need the wood and the sheep and the grain right.
Speaker 1: then I say monopoly on rock and they have to give me all the rock back and The coup de gras.
Speaker 0: if you do this, yeah, I think it's pretty much a law of the universe.
Speaker 0: You must immediately after you've taken all the rock say well anybody need rock.
Speaker 1: Yep Now you don't have to do with the rock you could you know?
Speaker 1: If you have wood and everyone in the game needs wood badly You can trade away all your wood.
Speaker 0: then monopoly the wizard needs wood bad.
Speaker 0: Then monopoly all the wood back after you trade it all away now in terms of trading because this is very important When you see most people.
Speaker 0: the fun of settlers is you know trading and negotiating and whatever.
Speaker 0: but you'll find and especially like in tournament player among experienced players people don't trade a lot and The rule for trading.
Speaker 0: there are two rules of trading and if you're going to win at settlers follow these rules 100%.
Speaker 1: yes, if you trade see the thing is part of the fun of settlers.
Speaker 1: is all the trading action in the bargaining?
Speaker 1: Right, but the thing is in reality Bargaining is not a good idea.
Speaker 1: so much if you're a settler if you want a bargaining game play dude Oh, if you want a bargaining game play traders of Genoa Which is a game of bargaining where you can't win without bargaining.
Speaker 0: But unless one of the following two conditions is true do not ever trade with anyone under any circumstances ever.
Speaker 0: It will never ever ever be a good idea.
Speaker 1: Trading is always almost always a bad idea.
Speaker 1: in settlers.
Speaker 1: If you trade you will lose except in these conditions.
Speaker 1: now condition number one is if You rip someone off exactly if I'm trading someone like a wood for three sheep Yeah, that's gonna be a good trade for me and a bad trade for them.
Speaker 1: Hooray do that It.
Speaker 1: but if someone's ripping you off or if they're making an even trade don't do it now.
Speaker 0: ripping off pretty much means either Getting more resource cards than you gave the other person.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Oh and even then that's not always a good ripoff.
Speaker 0: Or if you know or you're pretty sure but you should know if you're keeping track of everything that the card you were giving To the other player will not help them nearly as much as the card They're giving you.
Speaker 0: Yes, in which case they made the mistake of trading with you.
Speaker 0: They shouldn't have.
Speaker 1: yeah, unless you are super confident that you are getting a way better deal than the other person Don't trade at all.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: The only other circumstance where an even trade would be acceptable is if You're trading with you're basically gonna be a kingmaker but the reverse kind of kingmaker.
Speaker 1: Yep trading with the last place player exactly if you're in first place Right and you make an even trade with the last place player or even a slightly disadvantaged a disadvantageous trade with the last place player You're helping out the guy in last place.
Speaker 1: He's not gonna come up and beat you even if you help him out as though as long as it helps you a little bit That's a good trade as long you know Of course if it's a trade you could have made with a with a port or you know.
Speaker 1: But with the four to one don't do that with a player.
Speaker 1: use a port or something, you know.
Speaker 1: No point in helping anyone else.
Speaker 0: Yep unless that you know a player is not going to win.
Speaker 0: if you're.
Speaker 0: if there is one person in your group who you know is Not going to win this game trade with them as much as you can but don't trade with anyone else Right and that way even though you help someone out they're not gonna win.
Speaker 1: and you got helped out a bunch and now you're gonna win.
Speaker 0: and And When in doubt always use a port instead of trading with the player if you think it's if if you can't find a way to Rip someone off.
Speaker 1: I mean if I have a port that lets me turn two sheep into anything I want right and someone else is gonna say hey, I'll trade you anything you want for two sheep.
Speaker 1: I could either give two sheep to another player to get a brick or give two sheep to the bank to get a brick.
Speaker 1: Yes What two sheep to the bank to get a brick is the same for me and it doesn't help someone else by giving them two.
Speaker 1: It's obviously a better move now.
Speaker 0: if every player is smart enough to follow these rules then basically there's gonna be no trading going on in the game pretty much or Everyone's going to be trading with the last place player.
Speaker 0: Yes
Speaker 1: I mean if you have three awesome players and one crappy player then what generally happens is everyone sort of fights to see who can take advantage of the crappy player the most and It's sort of a sad thing and this is why the game loses a lot of its fun But everyone's really good at it because there's not so much trading going on
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: That's largely all you need to know.
Speaker 0: to be a badass at settlers I mean beyond that Get resources buy what you can.
Speaker 0: in general you want to buy things and expand as quickly as possible.
Speaker 0: If you can build a settlement You probably want to build it.
Speaker 0: if you're racing someone else to get to the good spot Get there before them and get there before that like do whatever you can to ensure that you get there before them.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean always make sure that you have at least one spot that's you know has a road where you can build a new Settlement.
Speaker 1: you probably want to you know, if you can't it's like if you have enough to build a settlement But you don't have a road that will let you build one.
Speaker 1: build that road quickly You know, you don't want to hang around, you know with all this settlement, you know I guess if you have enough for a settlement you have enough for a road, you know Cuz you need the other brick in the wood, but you know always make sure that at any moment.
Speaker 1: What if you happen to roll up enough stuff for you to build a settlement?
Speaker 1: You don't want to have to spend a turn building a road and then the settlement next turn.
Speaker 1: you want to go settlement right away.
Speaker 1: You know make sure you have always a settlement.
Speaker 1: That's not a city.
Speaker 1: yet in case you get enough stuff to turn something into a city You can't if you have all cities.
Speaker 1: Well, you can't build another city.
Speaker 1: You need to build a settlement first.
Speaker 1: So, you know do stuff in the order to never leave yourself in a situation.
Speaker 1: We have the resources to buy something but you can't actually buy it because you're not set up to do it.
Speaker 0: Yep now once you've determined what strategy you're using and you're following all this other advice in terms of enacting them if You're doing the sticky sheep or you know, the rock.
Speaker 0: whatever the endgame strategy You pretty much you're you want to.
Speaker 0: if you can build a settlement.
Speaker 0: whenever you can build a settlement with that strategy do it No matter what.
Speaker 0: build the settlement, but other than that You pretty much want to get cities and stiffy cards in fairly.
Speaker 0: eat like get them whenever you can whenever it's advantageous Before other players.
Speaker 1: you want to start buying stiffy card.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Yes, you want to buy the first stiffy card in the game?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you want to have the first city in the game, which is very likely going to be a possibility.
Speaker 1: It's a good.
Speaker 0: it's a good deal And then from there you're not going to win.
Speaker 0: because remember there's hard and soft points.
Speaker 0: hard points are victory point cards Settlements and cities because those points cannot ever be taken away from you.
Speaker 1: and then there are soft points longest road largest army because you can Get largest army, but then someone could take it away from you.
Speaker 1: So it's a soft point.
Speaker 0: now you can win with the Stiffy sheep strategy without getting largest army.
Speaker 0: However, the way to do that is to buy more stiffy cards and and Basically buy stiffy cards as much as you can and if you get victory point cards instead of soldiers.
Speaker 0: Don't worry so much about largest army and just hold on to those victory point.
Speaker 1: Victory point cards are great because you don't have.
Speaker 1: you don't have to play them.
Speaker 1: You just hold them in your hand and then basically let's say I have six points on the board, right?
Speaker 1: And I'm holding some stiffy cards.
Speaker 1: Smart players will realize I probably have some victory points in there But they don't know how much because some of them are one some of them are two.
Speaker 1: I could be holding a soldier to bluff which is a good idea sometimes, you know, and So it looks like I have six and other people probably have like eight or something at this point.
Speaker 1: So they think I'm behind They might even make a trade with me or something if they're really dumb and then I just go Oh, look, I actually had like three points hiding up here.
Speaker 1: So I built one settlement and then I win.
Speaker 0: because remember The rule is you can only play one card per turn and you can't play the card that you bought that turn.
Speaker 0: Unless they're victory point cards that win you the game.
Speaker 1: Yep, then you can just play all of them at once.
Speaker 1: So just hold on to victory point cards don't play them and then at the end of the game When you as soon as you get ten points including those cards just flip them over and that that is no There's no point revealing information You don't have to reveal
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: in general don't Scrimp and save and dump things into ports in order to make a little road and put a settlement somewhere.
Speaker 0: if you're doing this strategy Because the stiffy cards will carry you and you want the stiffy cards to carry you you'll have the largest army.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you get.
Speaker 1: you get.
Speaker 1: you know, if you need something, you know.
Speaker 1: occasionally you'll get the stiffy cards.
Speaker 0: unless you build a few roads or you get the one that lets you you're a plenty or you can just keep using the Robber and get stuff and then you get so many resources with your cities.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just keep robbing the people that have the bricks in the woods as you don't need a lot of other stuff to win.
Speaker 0: now with the brick and road strategy the brick and wood just Expand as fast as you can.
Speaker 0: do not build cities.
Speaker 0: Don't even go for cities.
Speaker 0: Don't buy stiffy cards.
Speaker 0: Just you have to build roads out and then put settlements on them as fast as you can.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just pretty much build road road road road road road road.
Speaker 1: and every time you're able to build a settlement build one and then Build roads every other chance.
Speaker 0: So if you're sitting there with a brick and wood build a road now if you're doing the brick and road Strategy and you're not gonna tripod with it It is this is one of the few times where it's kind of advantageous to to advantageous to fuck another player.
Speaker 0: Let's say I can build road road settlement or I can build road road road settlement and That's if I put the settlement in the third place.
Speaker 0: It's equivalent in terms of what it gives me But it blocks another player.
Speaker 0: you probably want to do that because the brick and road strategy Involves being in everyone's way and preventing them from expanding.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean if you think about it, you cannot build a settlement within one space of another settlement.
Speaker 1: So put you since you're gonna be going around with a lot of roads and other people are gonna be moving kind of slowly You can really put your settlements in places that prevent people from being able to build settlements.
Speaker 1: You know you put your settlement one away, you know from the spot that some other guy wants.
Speaker 1: now He can't build anything there.
Speaker 1: You got him or build it right in the spot that he wants.
Speaker 1: now He can't build it there and you can get it there faster than he can.
Speaker 1: so,
Speaker 0: haha Now beyond that don't buy stiffy cards, really They're not gonna help you that much unless you really really really have a good reason to you Unless
Speaker 1: you just got like a bounty of resources from incredible luck
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you're probably gonna win and you're really only gonna need probably one city and then everything else can just be settlements
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now the thing is if you're following all these things we're doing and you're doing it correctly You know, you're not screwing up and you're not winning.
Speaker 1: That's because it's a game of luck.
Speaker 1: primarily most of the game, you know If everyone plays the way we just said it pretty much comes down to the roll of the dice.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know while sixes and eights are more likely to be rolled.
Speaker 1: It's not necessary.
Speaker 1: I mean Someone has their settlement on a five and ten and no one else does and fives and tens just happen to be rolled a bunch.
Speaker 1: That person's probably gonna win and it's not do any fault of you know, strategy or tactic.
Speaker 1: It's just the dice.
Speaker 1: Yep, that's how the game goes.
Speaker 1: It's it's a semi mostly random game when you get down to the bottom of it.
Speaker 1: So don't be upset if you lose even though you were playing the best you could.
Speaker 1: cuz that's just how it goes.
Speaker 1: Nothing you could do.
Speaker 1: but it's not your fault.
Speaker 1: only be upset if you lose.
Speaker 1: cuz your fault.
Speaker 1: Got any any other settler strategies?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think that's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: I mean, unless anyone has a specific question You can ask us in the forums and we'll go into laborious excruciating detail about exactly what to do in that situation.
Speaker 1: But other than that, yeah, I mean that's that's how settlers of Catan goes.
Speaker 1: I don't see It's not that complicated.
Speaker 1: There's not much else you can do to do better at it than just said.
Speaker 0: there's no other strategy.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's there's.
Speaker 0: the Poison is in the other cup strategies of going like say no one puts their things around for.
Speaker 0: so you have settlement on four and in the early game, so alright if Statistically fours aren't rolled very often.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna win.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna have any resources.
Speaker 0: But if I have fluke of the die as far as get rolled more often than statistically is expected You're probably going to win because every time that's rolled You're the only person getting reef resources But every time a six is rolled two people get resources or three people get resources, but that's not a strategy.
Speaker 0: That's just going for the like lower chance of happening, but the higher chance of winning if it does happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's sort of like, you know, it's it's like gambling.
Speaker 1: you can bet on.
Speaker 1: You know the the horse that's probably gonna win the Kentucky Derby and if you the odds are 50% of the time It's like you'll win, but you'll win very little or you can bet on that.
Speaker 1: You know long shot horse, then you might not win.
Speaker 1: But if the long shot horse gets ahead you win big and that's sort of like.
Speaker 1: that's sort of what he's talking about.
Speaker 0: But I mean beyond this strategy it's just.
Speaker 0: it's a game of tactics.
Speaker 0: and be as opportunistic as you can at every point you can and Because the game is simple enough.
Speaker 0: There is usually an exactly perfect or Arbitrarily equivalent move to make at any given point
Speaker 1: and then at this the thing you just have to remember is that don't play nice You got to be a bastard and fuck everyone as hard as you can and try to win as hard as you can and that's that's True for pretty much every game and that's why I think a lot of people Some people don't like playing with us because we play to win and when someone's playing for fun against someone who plays to win It's not gonna be very fun.
Speaker 0: Yep, like that.
Speaker 0: There was the game of end decker.
Speaker 0: I played with our friend Luke way back in the day and it was a good game.
Speaker 0: I eventually won that particular instance, but the way I won was basically by.
Speaker 0: I Did a tricky maneuver and I did all-out attacked Luke who was currently winning to the point because I realized and this is a General strategy for all board games if you're in second place and you do something that attacks the front runner Taking points away from the front runner is Perfectly equivalent to giving yourself points.
Speaker 0: Yep So if you can do something that gives you a lot of points or do something that gives you a few points But takes a lot of points away from the front runner.
Speaker 0: You're better off doing the ladder.
Speaker 1: So let's say I have two different moves I can choose from and move number a I get ten points and move number B I get five points, but the person first pace loses six points.
Speaker 1: B is effectively eleven points Which is better than a which is just ten points.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week Covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew.com or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.