Speaker 1: It's Thursday, June 12th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: Dodgeball Hit somebody.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: so a lot of people have been wondering what exactly is going to happen with the geek nights book club now that we've switched to the Temporary sabbatical schedule.
Speaker 0: Yeah shows a week in our.
Speaker 1: in our eagerness to change up the show We made one change followed by another change that disrupts the first change.
Speaker 0: now We're still debating exactly what to do because we've realized a couple of other Minor flaws in our clever plan.
Speaker 0: for one I don't want to make anyone feel bad, and I know people have lives and are busy and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: But man do you people read slow?
Speaker 1: I mean I have a big long commute and I work and I do this show even though I'm doing the show less and I can read faster than all these kids who are like in school with hours and hours of free time.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean I think the problem was I remember thinking like alright a month.
Speaker 0: well They'll definitely read the first book and I'll bet they can pretty much read the trilogy.
Speaker 1: So let's just do the whole trilogy and I read it in a couple weeks.
Speaker 0: God.
Speaker 0: I read the third book in like three days.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: That's cuz I went crazy.
Speaker 1: I met the whole trilogy in a couple weeks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah But no from from all the feedback We've gotten most of you have barely even gotten through the first book if you're even anywhere near finishing it.
Speaker 1: I mean on the one hand it's okay because you can not listen to the episode and then when you're ready listen to it.
Speaker 0: That would have been fine with the old schedule because whatever.
Speaker 0: but now Thursdays only come twice a month.
Speaker 1: Yes, you'll be missing like a whole month of Thursdays if you aren't ready yet.
Speaker 0: plus at the same time I realized that what as much as I want to talk about the whole trilogy I have more to say about the first book than will fit in one show as it is.
Speaker 1: Yeah and at least the books something that usually like when I read something or watch something that's a bunch of Episodes or sequels or something the whole thing blurs into one.
Speaker 1: but with these books There's a very clear separation of the three.
Speaker 1: that really it makes it easier.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about.
Speaker 0: just thing is I forget Exactly where each book ends and I remember exactly where the first book ends.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't.
Speaker 0: I guess I read it longer ago than you But like I don't remember like okay, I think back it's like alright When exactly did this specific event happen?
Speaker 0: and I know it's in like either, you know late first book early second book But I forget exactly.
Speaker 0: the thing is there are certain Demarcation points of knowledge whereby you can talk about a topic from the books But depending on how far other people have read in terms of which book they're on You certain there's a point in which you just can't talk about a topic anymore or a topic means something completely different.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like what are the non men?
Speaker 0: we can talk about what are the non men but we can only.
Speaker 0: but the context of that Is completely different by the third book?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's kind of difficult because even if we only talk about one book there might be spoilers for the second and thirds.
Speaker 0: It's very avoidable as long we just have to limit the number of people on the roundtable and Where I I can at least talk about the first book Can also talk about the first book without spoiling.
Speaker 0: their heads will probably just not include the rest of the crew in the discussion of the first book.
Speaker 0: There's no way to because they'll spoil.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, well regardless.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't know exactly what we're gonna do.
Speaker 0: We're probably going to continue and do the review roundtable.
Speaker 0: final thoughts Whatever of the first book of the Prince of Nothing trilogy the darkness that comes before Next Thursday's episode which is Thursday after next Thursday.
Speaker 1: You got two weeks.
Speaker 1: So the next Thursday episode we're gonna talk about this book.
Speaker 1: So at least finish the first book if you're interested, I mean if you're not interested, you don't have to.
Speaker 0: yeah I don't know if we'll start the next book yet because I kind of want everyone to read all three of these books then talk About them as a whole.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean we could do that sort of later.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to like if we're actually gonna have a book club.
Speaker 1: we should sort of he always have.
Speaker 1: there should always be at any point in time a Book that is the current book.
Speaker 0: but at the same time if we introduce a new book when half our listeners haven't even been Able to force their way through the first book then no one's ever gonna finish any of our books.
Speaker 0: They'll just ruin every like second or third Thursday.
Speaker 1: I know it's a tough choice I don't.
Speaker 1: I think we'll have to do it like every fourth Thursday, you know, we might just do it organically.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Read good God.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe we'll just have to say maybe what you know.
Speaker 1: If we just you know I mean Oprah doesn't slow down right and she does her book club thing and it sort of just forces people to read faster.
Speaker 0: Which how often does she do it though?
Speaker 1: I think it's every month isn't it?
Speaker 0: and how many episodes of Oprah are there?
Speaker 1: five a week?
Speaker 0: And also I'll bet a lot of people don't read the Oprah books.
Speaker 0: They just watch the next Oprah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have no idea what you know.
Speaker 1: But then again, maybe there's a lot of people out there aren't gonna read the book and they're just gonna listen to it.
Speaker 1: Take sort of you know, cuz they like listening to us talk about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same time well at least if we talk about just the first book, that's okay.
Speaker 0: But if we talk about the trilogy well pretty much ruin.
Speaker 1: I definitely think that you know for the whole book club thing.
Speaker 1: We have to keep everything to a single volume.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean if we want to do a whole series what we should do is we should do the first volume.
Speaker 1: Well, and then the problem is your volume should be sort of a special thing.
Speaker 1: later.
Speaker 0: I think the real problem is that a The majority of you seem to have.
Speaker 0: now you've been able to get through the first volume of this And maybe we should pick an easier book.
Speaker 0: All right next time one fish two fish.
Speaker 1: How's gonna do c-spot run?
Speaker 1: We gotta sit.
Speaker 1: mr.
Speaker 0: Happy might have to watch out though cuz there's spoilers.
Speaker 0: I mean I'm as much as I want to talk about the red fish.
Speaker 0: I think we have to wait cuz I don't know if you guys are gonna finish it in time.
Speaker 0: Okay Okay, enough insulting.
Speaker 0: What do we got in the news?
Speaker 1: Okay, so check this out.
Speaker 1: I'm.
Speaker 1: actually it was hard to find a news today But then I sort of I'll take the news from like the front page of the newspaper.
Speaker 0: Wait, wait, wait, so Supreme Court takes one step for further toward getting rid of this police state terrorism torture BS.
Speaker 0: Barack is gonna be the next president of the US.
Speaker 1: All right, so that's that's just fine.
Speaker 1: But what do I have to say about it other than yay for?
Speaker 0: Cub Scouts or Boy Scouts died in a tornado.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz they were in a tornado.
Speaker 0: There was.
Speaker 1: there was something on FARC now, but the CEO those are all well and good news But I don't really have much commentary to add to any of them.
Speaker 1: You know, there is one news where I do have a lot of commentary to add and that is the news about the basketball now Of the sports that there are professionally Entertaining in the United States.
Speaker 1: that was that came off really poorly.
Speaker 1: of the major professional sports the United States Basketball is perhaps my least favorite now.
Speaker 0: I would rather watch curling Now that is to be.
Speaker 1: I say they're about equal curling.
Speaker 1: Basketball is fun to play.
Speaker 0: at least curling isn't rigged.
Speaker 1: Curling is fun.
Speaker 1: curling is less fun to play the basket.
Speaker 0: Curling is pretty fun.
Speaker 1: Anyway, well, I guess it could be fun.
Speaker 0: for the novelty of it It's a matter of opinion.
Speaker 0: We can't I can't say basketball is objectively bad.
Speaker 0: I just I find I find it incredibly uninteresting except I don't know the last 40 seconds of a game and only if it's closed.
Speaker 1: Well, basically here's the news, right?
Speaker 1: So in basketball when you're playing the game of basketball You're not really allowed to touch people hit people bump into people at.
Speaker 1: you know Grab people or else it's a foul.
Speaker 1: and there is a you know A rule of what is a foul and what isn't.
Speaker 1: and depending on how you commit the foul, you know There's a penalty that is exact it.
Speaker 1: usually the other team gets a number of free throws You know to score points or whatnot, right?
Speaker 1: And the thing is if you get a lot of fouls against your team that could basically makes you know No matter how well you play you're gonna lose because they got you know, like a zillion free points, basically.
Speaker 1: so The calling of fouls by referees in the NBA the you know Which is the professional basketball league of men in the United States is sort of Inconsistent.
Speaker 1: I mean hockey had ice.
Speaker 1: hockey is very similar with the calling of penalties, you know tripping Slashing etc.
Speaker 1: But for some reason while there's many bullshit penalty calls and also many penalties that go on called It doesn't feel rigged so much even though it can actually turn the tide of a game a lot more than it can in basketball.
Speaker 0: Well, and at least it's a sport like hockey while there's a lot of arbitrariness There's kind of this Accepted sense of justice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like and you see this if you graph it out It's pretty clear that if the refs make a bad call one, they know they made a bad call immediately.
Speaker 0: Yep, and what they do in hockey at least is if there's a bad call against one team You can guarantee there will be an equally bad call against the other team at a similarly critical moment before the game is out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that's how they kind of regulate that.
Speaker 1: There's also you know the fans of hockey.
Speaker 1: You know while in an individual game you might call bullshit on this that or the other thing like you will at baseball saying Oh, no, he was safe There's a perception of objectivity in the penalty calling in Basketball.
Speaker 1: there is no perception of objectivity in the calling of fouls.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much completely subjective and It's real.
Speaker 1: I mean you're playing this game of basketball.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much impossible not to foul beat.
Speaker 1: mean I think they should just play basketball and I think they should just make it.
Speaker 1: you can't touch anyone period and just if you touch Anyone that's it foul even if you graze them.
Speaker 1: it would make it really, you know, they would.
Speaker 1: you know It's sort of.
Speaker 1: it's really the way the game is now.
Speaker 1: It's sort of broken and there's not much more I can say about that.
Speaker 1: But anyway the news the news is this guy Tim Donahue and he used to be a referee in the NBA.
Speaker 1: Then he turned out to be a felon.
Speaker 1: So he's going to jail.
Speaker 0: Wait, wait, he turned like it's kind of like he turned out To be a felon.
Speaker 0: All right, so he's a normal guy a normal guy and there's like wait a minute.
Speaker 0: You're a felon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: I forgot exactly what he did, but it was a big scandal and he got in big trouble and According to him right now that he's you know already feloned if that's a verb Felonized yes in validated.
Speaker 1: There was a very important playoff games.
Speaker 1: There was rigging of the games as in the referees were calling fouls You know aggressively against one team in order to get the results to turn out a certain way.
Speaker 1: That would benefit the NBA.
Speaker 1: because think about this right if you're the NBA the league you're a for-profit league You know, you're interested in fair competition, I guess, you know theoretically, but primarily you're interested in making money.
Speaker 1: So wouldn't it be in your interest as the league to have the incredibly popular team?
Speaker 1: against the incredibly popular team in the finals or And as opposed to the team for the middle of nowhere versus the team from the middle of nowhere Like the NHL was much happier with Detroit Pittsburgh, then they would be with Florida Nashville And the Stanley Cup Finals.
Speaker 0: luckily We don't have to worry about that so much because subtle rules changes and subtle strategy changes have made it to the point that Offensive old-school teams have a clear advantage in hockey once again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I should but the point is is that Basketball even if it is not rigged they give off this perception that it is indeed rigged.
Speaker 1: I mean there was a final and the NBA Finals are going on right now and it's the Lakers versus the Celtics Which is pretty much you couldn't ask for a better Combination of money-making for the NBA in terms of what teams are the finals.
Speaker 0: my whole life and to this day whenever someone says Celtics It bothers me a lot.
Speaker 1: That's what they are.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'm it's like alright, they just pretend it's someone with a Boston accent top pocket in the car.
Speaker 1: So the Celtics.
Speaker 0: So you pronounce your K's as C's.
Speaker 1: if your boss sees yeah, well, no, that's an X The Red Sox ease.
Speaker 1: Yeah anyway.
Speaker 1: so Basically, it's a huge deal now because everyone's like, ah, it's rigged.
Speaker 1: It's rigged.
Speaker 1: The guy says it's rigged and it's tough.
Speaker 1: Do you trust the guy who is the felon and got kicked out?
Speaker 1: It actually has a reason to sort of be vengeful and slander, you know his former employer?
Speaker 1: or Do you believe him because he's got the balls to?
Speaker 1: you know?
Speaker 1: Let out the truth that all the people who are still in the organization and it's really impossible to go either way without some more.
Speaker 1: But really all I say there needs to be some sort of independent investigation of some sort to figure out what the deal is.
Speaker 0: well because if it's rigged presents the fundamental problem in every possible whistleblowing event in the world where Anytime someone is a whistleblower a legitimate whistleblower.
Speaker 0: What what's like especially in the movies?
Speaker 0: You see this all the time, but also in the real world.
Speaker 0: What's the obvious thing you do to the whistleblower?
Speaker 0: you discredit them in some way in order to prevent people from believing them.
Speaker 0: We saw that in that this guy discredited himself, which is yeah, but we saw that in that liberal porn movie man of the year.
Speaker 0: It's like not the whistleblower.
Speaker 0: Let's fill her full of heroin.
Speaker 0: Yep, and that happens in the real world too.
Speaker 0: Anytime someone's a whistleblower Everyone tries to immediately discredit and you think oh, well, obviously they're just trying to discredit.
Speaker 0: but at the same time who has More to gain by discrediting than someone who is already in trouble with the organization and is only trying to get revenge.
Speaker 0: It's like it's.
Speaker 0: it's the least probable thing.
Speaker 0: That is also the most probable thing.
Speaker 1: So who you trust It's and that's why it's impossible to know without an independent investigation.
Speaker 1: and really for something like the NBA I mean normally I'd be like, you know, what do we care about?
Speaker 1: You know some sport who cares if it's rigged and I mean pro wrestling is you know, not a real sport.
Speaker 1: It's totally fake and no one cares.
Speaker 0: I'll say this I don't care if baseball is rigged.
Speaker 0: well
Speaker 1: The reason
Speaker 0: or basketball reason
Speaker 1: that it's important for the government's to check and see if these things is the US government to check and make sure that the major professional sports are rigged or not is because The stadiums for these sports are huge parts of the local economies and it's not government money that pays for these
Speaker 0: Disagree all.
Speaker 0: the only vested interest our government has is not whether or not the sport is fair But whether or not fans think it's fair and continue to attend.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's fine, too.
Speaker 0: But you know the point is their prerogative is not necessarily to prevent cheating.
Speaker 0: It is just to make sure that no one thinks they're cheating.
Speaker 0: to that I mean you can argue if you're gonna make the money.
Speaker 1: solution either way is an independent investigation Investigation.
Speaker 0: Well, yes because here's the problem.
Speaker 0: What if it appears to be rigged and it turns out that no, that's just the way it rolls Then you have to sack everybody anyway and say yeah, it was rigged now We fixed it and then rig it to make it look like it's not rigged.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a really tricky situation But regardless it's hard to enjoy a sport when you have the perception that it's just both rigged.
Speaker 0: It's hard to enjoy a sport where both teams score Every 20 seconds for the entire game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you basically have people trying to get.
Speaker 1: I mean seriously, you know in basketball you could just you have five guys Five guys can hold hands and make a wall around, you know around the nets You can't get close to it without touching them and you're not allowed to touch anybody.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not quite that I know because they can just shoot over your head or whatever.
Speaker 1: but even then touching is not quite that cut and dry I know but it's a very very Difficult thing to judge and I think basketball in general needs some fixing.
Speaker 1: I think really the way to make basketball better is to raise the net.
Speaker 0: Just put him another 10 feet up because they got these tall guys.
Speaker 1: But the net isn't really any higher that much higher than it used to be.
Speaker 1: They should make it like 20 feet in the air.
Speaker 1: It's like no one can possibly reach it and you have to shoot.
Speaker 0: So, you know what I would do.
Speaker 0: I would make three pointers worth four points.
Speaker 1: that well I would make.
Speaker 1: actually I would say if you shoot from half-court, it's worth five points.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, you get you get a percentage of points up to that would because then you'd actually the thing is right look at something like like Soccer or even better.
Speaker 0: Why don't I just have two nets the 10-foot net and the next to it the 20-foot net?
Speaker 0: That's worth twice as many.
Speaker 1: Then it gets kind of gimmicky.
Speaker 1: But yeah, the thing is you look at all these gimmicky sports Awesome.
Speaker 1: I know it's.
Speaker 1: it's really weird because you look at a gimmicky sport like watching slam ball.
Speaker 1: I know remember slam ball.
Speaker 1: It was so gimmicky with trampolines, right?
Speaker 1: The thing is the best sport the best team sport ever.
Speaker 1: ice hockey is the most gimmicky sport ever But it doesn't look gimmicky.
Speaker 1: But think of how gimmicky that is ice.
Speaker 1: It doesn't get gimmick here than ice.
Speaker 0: Why don't we just make basketball happen on ice?
Speaker 1: I'll play that shit.
Speaker 0: No, you wouldn't.
Speaker 0: you're afraid of skating.
Speaker 1: I'm not afraid of skating.
Speaker 1: I just have to learn skating.
Speaker 0: You want to learn skating.
Speaker 1: every time I've ever skated roller ice or otherwise, right?
Speaker 1: I do it and I get and I'll kind of wobble I wobble I wobble and after about an hour I'm kind of just whooshing around not super whooshing around but I can go in a circle without holding the railing and I can stop.
Speaker 1: It takes about an hour.
Speaker 0: It's hard to say because I've only ever seen you once.
Speaker 0: I remember you held on to the edge of the ice rink and you walked around it a one full Rotation around the entire thing and then you were done.
Speaker 1: No, it's not remember that.
Speaker 0: I was the one time we went with like half the crew we went.
Speaker 0: it was RIT.
Speaker 0: It was like free but free meant.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's no ice skates because everyone on campus is trying to ice skate.
Speaker 1: Anyway, no when I when I ice skate a roller skate Generally What happens is I have to learn again from the beginning because I forgot everything because I don't do it often enough to develop the muscle memory and then I kind of go around like holding on for a while and then eventually like after maybe an hour or so I can skate in a circle and Then stop and that's all I can do is skate forward and stop without holding on to anything and that's as far as I've ever Gotten.
Speaker 0: Why don't we imagine if I one-on-one hockey in the street?
Speaker 0: I imagine if I And I just want someone to play one-on-one hockey with all right.
Speaker 1: Well, then we need some goalie action.
Speaker 0: No, no, you don't one-on-one hockey Is a. maybe it's just cuz where I grew up and it was a common sport of kids two kids.
Speaker 0: We'll just play hockey against each other with sticks nets and a ball.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh two on two is a lot better but one-on-one works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well regardless.
Speaker 1: I'm sure if I skated every day.
Speaker 1: I eventually would be able to skate averagely.
Speaker 0: So this is a little out of the way.
Speaker 0: No None of you are gonna have seen this on Fark or slash dot or dig even though I don't think anyone Actually goes to dig anymore for news because dig is.
Speaker 0: you know, I've said dig is dead but I haven't been to dig in like two weeks and I went today and It was like there was nothing worthwhile.
Speaker 0: I only go to dig like once every couple weeks if there's not enough videos to watch another site On day that I had not already seen somewhere else better and more reliable with a higher or better signal-to-noise ratio.
Speaker 0: I just dig is done.
Speaker 1: It is definitely done.
Speaker 1: I said just cut it out of my RSS feed.
Speaker 1: then I cut out and I stopped doing RSS and then I stopped checking dig and I don't miss it at all.
Speaker 0: I used to have that policy of in my account on dig to make it bearable anyone who posted anything stupid.
Speaker 0: I just immediately put on the ignore list and never look back and I'd added like 600 people to my ignore list.
Speaker 0: so I logged in to dig actually today, right and I decided all right.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna look at comments and Ignore everyone to post something stupid.
Speaker 0: and as I began to click ignore on every single post I saw and I'm not kidding every single post I saw on the entire front page of two stories.
Speaker 0: Awesome, I'm done with dig.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, uh, here's some news you will find and you might wonder why I'm bringing it up Partly because I'm a rollercoaster.
Speaker 0: Well, I was when I was a kid a rollercoaster enthusiast.
Speaker 1: When's the last time you rode a rollercoaster?
Speaker 0: the last time I rode something that I would consider a legitimate rollercoaster.
Speaker 0: Was the summer after my freshman year at RIT?
Speaker 1: We rode that thing in Wildwood.
Speaker 0: that thing was barely a rollercoaster.
Speaker 1: Was it?
Speaker 1: was it a train?
Speaker 1: Did it go up and down hills?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah But it was a rollercoaster in the same sense that an Apple - could still be considered a computer.
Speaker 1: It is a computer technically.
Speaker 1: Yes, however, I was so fun.
Speaker 1: It's still fun to use an Apple - and play some Oregon Trail.
Speaker 0: No, it's not It's really not it is.
Speaker 0: it's much more fun to just play.
Speaker 1: It's not more fun to play Oregon trails.
Speaker 1: All right, but it's still fun to play the old Oregon Trail.
Speaker 0: It's not worth it.
Speaker 1: I would never the price we had to pay good God.
Speaker 1: It was like 10 bucks.
Speaker 0: I would never go out of my way to use an Apple - if anything I would use an Apple - emulator.
Speaker 1: I would.
Speaker 1: yeah All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's like playing man.
Speaker 1: We could we have a big roller coaster and We use it to emulate smaller roller coasters, but not if but the track modifies itself.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I was somewhat of a roller coaster enthusiast.
Speaker 0: now part of this was because I grew up in the Midwest and I'm not saying that every roller coaster park in the world or roller coaster in the world is bad because that's absolutely not true.
Speaker 0: and but the deal is that there's this place called Cedar Point and a lot of people outside of The Midwest who aren't roller coaster enthusiasts like as a geekery don't really know much about Cedar Point.
Speaker 0: But basically it is the never heard of it.
Speaker 1: so I met you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it is the roller coaster capital of the world and has been for as long as there have been.
Speaker 1: Thing in Japan no Tokyo spotland that do you know.
Speaker 0: how few roller coasters are there, but they're crazy.
Speaker 0: They're not that crazy.
Speaker 1: They're that one.
Speaker 1: That's great.
Speaker 1: They like two or three that are stupid crazy.
Speaker 0: Not so much I could.
Speaker 0: I could talk about that.
Speaker 0: But anyway, Cedar Point is the roller coaster capital of the world and the amusement ride capital of the world.
Speaker 0: They have like they have almost 80 real rides not counting like the kiddie rides and they have 17 Rollercoasters the weakest of which are better than the best roller coaster at the average amusement park.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean Six Flags.
Speaker 1: New England is pretty good But they've got let's see if I can cat last I checked.
Speaker 1: they had like one two three four five.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe six or seven roller coasters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Cedar Point has like.
Speaker 0: Most of the roller coasters are over 200 feet like all the good one.
Speaker 0: Oh my god I don't want even get into it.
Speaker 0: But anyway Cedar Point is like the roller coaster place.
Speaker 0: if you like roller coasters.
Speaker 0: That is the like the only place in the world.
Speaker 0: Like if you haven't been there.
Speaker 0: There's no point in going anywhere.
Speaker 1: It's also the amusement park with Snoopy.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It used to not be.
Speaker 0: that's a relatively recent change.
Speaker 0: It used to be Berenstain Bears.
Speaker 0: Yeah Berenstain bear country was there with all these learning science II exhibits.
Speaker 0: It was really cool and they tell you stories.
Speaker 0: and then one year I went and it was gone and in its place was Snoopy Land and Snoopy land was nothing but kiddie rides and food.
Speaker 1: Wasn't that better than Berenstain bear country.
Speaker 0: No Berenstain bear country was much better.
Speaker 1: Well, if you're a kid, wouldn't you rather ride rides?
Speaker 0: then look at that because learning she I would ride the roller coasters Yeah, and then I'd go to Berenstain bear country and learn stuff.
Speaker 1: What what would you want to learn?
Speaker 1: and ride roller coasters.
Speaker 1: and he could ride roller coasters and ride roller coasters.
Speaker 0: I'm a nerd.
Speaker 1: anyway.
Speaker 1: Snoopy is way better than Berenstain bears.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I agree.
Speaker 1: However, they gotta have Woodstock hockey rink.
Speaker 0: Let me put it this way Here's it looks like a giant bird bad.
Speaker 0: Here's why I had a problem with Snoopy Because Berenstain bear country and all that stuff is Cedar Point had this.
Speaker 0: it had this kind of old-school level of class like it was this kind of classy not Over-commercialized thing and there were no like gift shops or anything there.
Speaker 0: There weren't even that many gift shops in Cedar Point.
Speaker 0: But when they brought Snoopy you the the amount of Snoopy merchandise that was being sold at Every turn like they replaced every science exhibit left in the park with a Snoopy like gift store.
Speaker 1: and now you know the The trials of Bill Watterson.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 0: There's no Kelvin and Hobsland.
Speaker 0: Thank the gods, but Cedar Point Despite the I mean this is a place where you'd pay like 65 bucks to get in for one fucking day.
Speaker 1: That's about right for an amusement park.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was a major amusement park.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it was but for 17 roller coasters They gives it was only like a hundred bucks for a year pass.
Speaker 1: So that's the thing They always get you with the year passes where most people come there for a single day.
Speaker 1: most, you know I mean and this is Disney World we get like a three-day because you want to see everything.
Speaker 1: You know most most amusement parks.
Speaker 1: one day is enough to do everything once and very few people come back for a second day.
Speaker 1: So they always give you that they always have the year pass on offer because it's basically if you're gonna stay more than one day You should buy the year pass.
Speaker 1: and if you get a year pass and you actually come a lot You're gonna spend a lot of money on those overpriced foods and gifts.
Speaker 0: And if you are just staying for two days because when you want to eat you go out of the park to the marina I needed that diner.
Speaker 1: Yep, and that's the cheap year pass That's always cheaper than two single-day passes.
Speaker 1: really entices people to buy it and thus stay for two days And that's what they make like twice as much money off of you.
Speaker 0: Anyway, attendance at San revenue at Cedar Point itself is down this year despite the bag.
Speaker 1: It's down in every news.
Speaker 1: No, it's not in parks.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's not.
Speaker 0: no not at all In fact on average not just the amusement parks owned by the company that deals with Cedar Point See and all that but all Amusement parks.
Speaker 0: on average their attendance is pretty much static and on the aggregate.
Speaker 0: They're doing fine Really?
Speaker 1: I was hearing that amusement parks were down.
Speaker 0: They're not.
Speaker 0: what's down is individual parks are down but that's being made up for by other parks and The speculation is that basically people are going like they want to go to an amusement park But they're not willing to travel far or pay a lot of money to go to an amusement park Like they used to in the past because the economy's down and gas prices are up and all that.
Speaker 1: Mostly I think there's a lot of cheaper forms of entertainment than the music music part.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're a lot less difficult and have a lot less stress involved.
Speaker 0: What people are doing is they're going to.
Speaker 0: they're going to less good closer amusement parks like splashdown Park.
Speaker 0: Yes, good God that place is like 40 bucks.
Speaker 0: It has like three.
Speaker 1: if it wasn't if it was ten bucks I would have gone there.
Speaker 1: but 40 bucks ten bucks.
Speaker 0: Everyone within 40 miles would be there and you'd have to wait two hours to ride the 20-foot slide.
Speaker 1: I'm saying I would take a day off of work and you know, well, you know when no one was there and Scott I've driven past that place on work days even like hot days in the summer.
Speaker 0: The line is out the park Good God.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So anyway, but uh, yeah, that's pretty much it my that's my news.
Speaker 0: It's kind of excuse to point out that if you're a rollercoaster fan See your point is really the only place to go.
Speaker 0: but you know, I see your points down despite Despite being the rollercoaster capital of the world.
Speaker 0: It's in Ohio.
Speaker 0: Who's going to go to Ohio?
Speaker 0: except people are already in, Ohio?
Speaker 0: Michigan's Michigan, yeah, but they're right there.
Speaker 0: They're right next to it Indiana's and not so much because it's in the corner by the Great Lakes not the corner by Indiana by the other Great Lakes.
Speaker 0: Things of the day.
Speaker 0: now someone's gonna say but Ren this was on dig Yeah, it was also elsewhere.
Speaker 0: Anyway on YouTube someone put up a long excerpt from one of Carl Sagan's things and it's basically about the library of Alexandria and the history of that and what it meant for the world and What happened to it in case you didn't know.
Speaker 1: and now we have Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: Let's hope it doesn't also burn down.
Speaker 0: I Don't know what I can say.
Speaker 0: Carl Sagan is one of my personal heroes.
Speaker 0: I have so much respect for that man and the things that he did.
Speaker 0: I in a lot of ways Part of the rationale for doing geek nights and the reason we bring up certain topics so often is that in some small way?
Speaker 0: I want to spread his messages at least a tiny bit to the world.
Speaker 1: Well people's certain messages in general his messages being some of them.
Speaker 0: Well, it just so happens that his messages tend to very much coincide with my messages.
Speaker 0: Gee, I wonder how that could be partly because I remember reading cosmos as a kid and partly because he's right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I highly recommend.
Speaker 0: if you don't know a lot about Carl Sagan Or if you don't know a lot about the library of Alexandria Or if you have never seen Carl Sagan talk about the library of Alexandria.
Speaker 0: This video is incredibly depressing And I'll leave it.
Speaker 0: if it doesn't depress you fuck you if it doesn't depress you.
Speaker 1: Anyway All right, so check this out.
Speaker 1: I don't know what Forex is But I know it has something to do with trading of stocks and finance.
Speaker 0: I I cannot comment but continue.
Speaker 1: The point is is that trading stocks and things if you're not actually risking your monies is pretty fun.
Speaker 1: I mean I played the stock market game was out in seventh grade.
Speaker 1: I won.
Speaker 1: I went to the floor of the stock exchange.
Speaker 1: It wasn't that great.
Speaker 1: It's kind of boring down there a lot of paper on the floor.
Speaker 1: I think these like throwing paper on the floor for the aesthetic.
Speaker 1: Well, it's really not necessary.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is It depends on what kind of exchange.
Speaker 1: and the guy yeah, but the guys who sweep up the floor They just like to keep their jobs.
Speaker 1: It's like a union thing.
Speaker 1: You gotta drop paper on the floor.
Speaker 1: So we keep my jobs.
Speaker 0: But I gotta say cuz at work, you know Sometimes like we want to do a test or something and I can connect to the non-production Servers and I remember being one of my co-workers wanted to test something.
Speaker 0: So I bought 1 million shares of IBM And it was really fun anyway.
Speaker 1: And then when I was like high school When Yahoo Finance existed they had a stock market game on there and I played that I got crushed because I was versus the world Instead of versus the seventh graders in town.
Speaker 0: So well, here's the problem.
Speaker 0: If you look at the stock market in aggregate It pretty much looks like and emulates in a lot of ways white noise, yeah.
Speaker 1: So there's this program here.
Speaker 1: It's like a forex trading application right.
Speaker 1: and if you were actually interested in doing forex trading whatever that is Imagine it stands for finance.
Speaker 1: No something something now.
Speaker 1: Anyway, if you're interested in doing that these people have a program that lets you do that And it looks like a pretty good program at least judging from looking at it.
Speaker 1: What do I know about this, right?
Speaker 1: But if you just want to pretend to do some forex trading You can sign up get a free account and use their application as a game for free Forever.
Speaker 1: so you can just pretend to be a forex trader and play it as a game Which I imagine is mad fun and also mad educational.
Speaker 1: and it's free.
Speaker 1: So why the hell not?
Speaker 1: I think it's a pretty damn good thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I'll explain a little bit at least.
Speaker 0: forex means or stands for foreign exchange.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes It's pretty much just the currency market.
Speaker 0: Ah which is some buy ends sell euros is fun to think about.
Speaker 0: but Basically, all I can really say about this is that the margins on currency trading are very low and it's not A game you just pretend to have bajillion dollars.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I don't know if they let you.
Speaker 1: I think they I don't know if it's actually a game.
Speaker 1: Maybe they start everyone off with the same amount of money or something.
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: I don't know how it works either.
Speaker 1: I'd actually try it.
Speaker 1: It just looks cool.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna try it later.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's that sort of thing is really fun.
Speaker 1: I really can't comment too much Yeah, but it is fun to pretend to buy and sell stocks and things.
Speaker 1: I don't actually do this sort of thing unless it's your job because You're basically just risking a whole lot of money on nothing.
Speaker 0: see my guess is that this is basically a Marketing ploy to trick people into thinking that they can make a bunch of money and look how easy it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I based is just on going to the website and looking.
Speaker 1: I mean that's what they did in the 90s.
Speaker 1: Well, I was like etrade and Ameritrade and all those other like online day trading programs who would quit their jobs.
Speaker 1: They'd get these online day trading programs.
Speaker 1: They'd be like, ah, this is fun.
Speaker 1: They like watch little graphs Buttons and hope they could make money that way.
Speaker 0: I'm going to point out something that ruined the stock market.
Speaker 0: that is on Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at it right now because I like this page.
Speaker 0: I find it funny that it's here, but there's a page on Wikipedia entitled Forex underscore scam And I will leave it at that.
Speaker 1: But the game is free So it's not as big that's.
Speaker 1: that part is not a.
Speaker 0: I can tell you about a much better game.
Speaker 0: That's also free.
Speaker 0: It's called dodgeball.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 1: Oh, we're ready.
Speaker 1: We're getting into it Are we?
Speaker 0: dodgeball is a game of dodging balls in a non-homosexual way?
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is a dodgeball is that there's so many varieties of dodgeball and the exact rules But they all have one thing in common one person or one team throws balls at the other team until they are not Unconscious.
Speaker 1: Yes, and if you get hit with a ball, but you fail to also catch the ball.
Speaker 1: That is bad.
Speaker 0: What if it's a trap though?
Speaker 0: What if you trap it between you and the wall?
Speaker 0: Are you in the floor?
Speaker 1: I don't know, but then we're gonna get into that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and in Nowadays dodgeball is not allowed in many schools where safety Nazi parents have ruined fun for children.
Speaker 0: It's not for safety though, because dodgeball is super.
Speaker 0: you can't get hurt.
Speaker 0: playing for self-esteem.
Speaker 0: Yes, yes is for self-esteem is the same thing, but I don't understand.
Speaker 0: like I can understand the same overprotective bullshit I'm okay with not making kids throw medicine balls around anymore.
Speaker 0: I fucking hurt myself with a medicine medicine balls.
Speaker 1: Okay, but we're talking like foam balls here All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we play dodgeball with nerf balls.
Speaker 0: Well when the school made we played him with.
Speaker 1: they were nerf volleyballs, there are volleyballs, but they're made of foam.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing when we were forced to play in gym class.
Speaker 0: We played with this foam dodgeball crap.
Speaker 0: We played on our own case balls.
Speaker 1: No volleyballs Volleyballs are okay, too.
Speaker 0: That's cuz.
Speaker 0: we were hardcore.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Okay real men play with softballs.
Speaker 1: No, you know.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess softballs as in softball the game.
Speaker 1: No softballs and balls that are soft.
Speaker 0: Yes I know this is a cultural thing.
Speaker 0: like this happens in Japan.
Speaker 0: people play dodgeball in school and Jam and I know in America I don't know how much in the rest of the world.
Speaker 0: So I know we have a lot of foreign listeners.
Speaker 0: So basically dodgeball is a game that is played almost entirely by kids.
Speaker 0: We're forced to play it in gym class by gym instructors who are lazy Don't want to deal with teaching or anything at all
Speaker 1: And it's basically it's a special treat because usually they make the kids do something that is less fun like run laps
Speaker 0: Most as far as I've seen most gym classes in this country, especially in crappy schools You'll play dodgeball like every gym class now
Speaker 1: and when I was in school That's all was a special treat in
Speaker 0: good schools.
Speaker 0: But I went to a crappy elementary school for one grade in fifth grade and let me tell you We played dodgeball three out of five gym class.
Speaker 0: That'd be awesome Except no because basically the teacher would walk out and say dodgeball And he'd make it splits up into two teams and then he'd walk out of the room.
Speaker 1: awesome.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah, the teacher definitely needs to be there to be constantly refereeing which is what always happened when I played dodgeball.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I want to hear from people around the world Like how does the dodgeball you play if you played it work?
Speaker 1: because there are different rule sets all over the place with huge Variations and it's not really played outside of schools.
Speaker 1: There's no real.
Speaker 0: there's not a lot of professional dodgeballs except at our IT where we had the intramural dodgeball.
Speaker 1: I should have gotten into that but I didn't know.
Speaker 0: the only reason I didn't is because they always met or had their games During other things that I was more invested in.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah So you had no official responsibilities to the RIT anime club.
Speaker 0: no, but You were basically the vizier.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what was I gonna do that?
Speaker 1: Who was I gonna play dodgeball?
Speaker 0: Yeah There was that one time we challenged the gaming club to dodgeball.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and no one from the anime club showed up.
Speaker 0: So we just all played dodgeball together for like two hours.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was an okay time.
Speaker 1: so I played two different Varieties of dodgeball when I was in school and I'll share them with you because I really I really like explaining how these work because I We had some really good rule sets going on.
Speaker 1: The problem is these games only worked in a gymnasium with lots of with relatively lots of equipment, right?
Speaker 1: So the first kind of dodgeball we played was prisoner dodgeball.
Speaker 1: the way it worked is you had a gymnasium Preferably as big as possible depending how many people.
Speaker 1: you had two teams, right and you can go anywhere you want But you can only go between the half-court line and sort of the the backcourt out of bounds.
Speaker 0: Well, I think we can skip all those specific because pretty much everyone played in a gym and you couldn't go over the middle line.
Speaker 0: Right, they line up like five balls or so I guess line the center like you realize all those lines on the floor?
Speaker 0: He's no.
Speaker 0: like school gyms have like a million different lines and paying about sport you're playing use different lines.
Speaker 0: Yep, they all have names.
Speaker 1: I know I don't think our listeners know all the names So we won't use the center line as in if it was basketball the line that goes across the middle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right Anyway, so basically they go go and then the game starts and you go and you try to grab the balls off the front.
Speaker 1: But of course running up to grab the balls first you risk someone getting there before you and then nailing you really easily.
Speaker 0: god That's gonna be in that thread.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well you just said good god.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so run up and get the balls and then you pretty much just throw the balls back and forth and you try to hit People on the other team.
Speaker 1: and but if they catch it you're out.
Speaker 1: but if you hit them and they don't catch it, they're out.
Speaker 1: if you're out you raise your hand and You walk across.
Speaker 1: You know the other team zone and stand behind the enemy team.
Speaker 1: and when you're standing behind the enemy team You're in prison.
Speaker 1: and if you're in prison, you can't get out.
Speaker 1: you're basically stuck there But people on your team if they want to can attempt to throw the balls over the enemy team and if you in prison catch it, you're out of prison and you can bring the ball back to your team side.
Speaker 1: and That's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: the game doesn't really have an end Situation unless you get the entire other team into prison.
Speaker 0: and then here's here's the fundamental Problem with dodgeball as it is played by most people in schools.
Speaker 0: It is not designed to be a good game.
Speaker 1: It is designed to last a long time and it's designed to be fun throw balls people try to hit.
Speaker 0: It's also designed to be fun for everyone and as opposed because if you play I mean the web I always want to play dodgeball on our own because we'd always like pretty much they'd make us play dodgeball in gym.
Speaker 0: We hated it, but then we go to recess and we'd all play dodgeball.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we played it real and we all like we got really into it.
Speaker 0: Like we all formed our teams We'd be running around.
Speaker 0: we had strategies where like one guy yells candy bar candy bar.
Speaker 0: I forget what candy bar was but that's the only strategy I remember.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only other thing about prisoner dodgeballs that if you made a basket, you know Cuz they had the basketball nets down.
Speaker 1: you basically had to make a basket from half court with a foam volleyball.
Speaker 1: Quite a feat.
Speaker 1: the entire your entire team got out of prison, which is awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean what happened.
Speaker 0: it was like oh, man Shit gimmicky ways of playing and all that stuff and I don't want to get into all the different gimmicks cuz I'm up the mind that the best way to play dodgeball is just if you're out.
Speaker 0: you're out last team, whatever Yeah, and you probably want at least two balls.
Speaker 1: Yeah More balls, I actually think is better because he it's it turns.
Speaker 1: yet less of that action where a guy just stands there with the Ball, he sort of hides it behind his back.
Speaker 0: Well, no Here's the problem that I always ran into.
Speaker 0: if there was just one ball pretty much I let my entire team get eliminated because I just kind of I would just like ignore everyone and just duck behind people or push Him in front of the ball or something.
Speaker 0: And if I was the last one left, I just stand in the middle and there's only one ball and it's a big ball.
Speaker 0: No one can throw it so fast that I can't catch it or die.
Speaker 1: I see if you stand far away from the line, and I'm the only one left.
Speaker 0: So basically it's a standoff.
Speaker 0: I will stand there and if they throw it at me either catch it and they're out or it bounces doesn't do anything or They miss me.
Speaker 1: You have.
Speaker 1: the situation though is if you dodge it, then you pick it up You have to throw it at them without them catching.
Speaker 1: No, I would just roll it back over it back There you go.
Speaker 0: No, actually our gym had a good rule and we adapted this to the playground which was great because the playground wasn't even where.
Speaker 0: If the ball bounced as long as it was in the air when it hits you accounted.
Speaker 0: So if you bounced off the ground and that bounced up and hit someone in the nuts, that was totally okay.
Speaker 0: But by the same token if you trapped it against the wall or against the ground It was just a read like it didn't count for anything, huh?
Speaker 1: That's all right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you come with everyone.
Speaker 0: So as a result my strategy is usually to kick the ball and just kind of randomly bounce around and being someone in the face.
Speaker 1: See actually there was another variety of dodgeball We played and I remember I played it because I went to like They had like this summer program where you would go to the school Right if you go to one of the schools in the summer for a few weeks and like a little bus came to get you which is why my mom sent me there because then she didn't have to drive me and The.
Speaker 1: basically you chose two activities and did one in the morning and one of the afternoon.
Speaker 1: So I just chose gym and computers Every time.
Speaker 1: see.
Speaker 0: the funny thing is as athletic as I am and how much I like all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: I from from sixth grade.
Speaker 0: Until the one gym class I was required to take in order to graduate high school that I probably could have gotten out of If I pitched enough, I never took a gym class.
Speaker 1: We had to take gym class every single year.
Speaker 0: We see if you were in the marching band You didn't have to take gym class and in middle school if you're in the band, you didn't have to take gym class.
Speaker 1: No in our school.
Speaker 1: Everyone absolutely had to take physical education all the time.
Speaker 0: The worst thing was though you didn't have to shower in gym classes either.
Speaker 0: so no one shower.
Speaker 1: We need to shower but we had to change clothes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I often didn't just because I didn't care.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because the one gym class I took my senior basically your grade in gym was do you show up?
Speaker 1: Do you have?
Speaker 1: did you change your clothes?
Speaker 0: I decided to take Individual sports which was like a week of archery and a week of tennis.
Speaker 1: We had options like that.
Speaker 1: You could have taken net games, which is volleyball table tennis You know what?
Speaker 0: I totally did.
Speaker 0: I played through the ping-pong part Because I was awesome at ping-pong and I played through the archery part because I think archery is really cool and I convinced the teacher For the rest of it that I was gonna go do martial arts upstairs.
Speaker 0: I didn't know any martial arts and I'd pretty much just sleep up there or play my gameboy or my name gear Awesome, or do my or go home.
Speaker 1: Yep Anyway, so the other kind of vault dodgeball that I played which actually I like more was a really cool game.
Speaker 1: They had a name for it, but I forget what it was.
Speaker 1: I really like.
Speaker 1: remember they actually had three different kinds of balls Right, they had the foam volleyball They had the void kick balls, ah the void kick ball.
Speaker 1: and they had the nerve footballs right and they were sort of different distributions like there was only one or two nerve footballs and the rest were sort of half and Half the voids and the the foam balls, right?
Speaker 1: The foam balls were for nailing people and you would get a point if you nailed someone But no one got eliminated.
Speaker 1: if you caught one of those you also got a point, right?
Speaker 1: The void balls were actually dual purpose.
Speaker 1: You could either peg someone but you got less points for that because it was easier to peg someone with it.
Speaker 1: But with those you could try to score a basket and get three points and with the football you could drop kick it between.
Speaker 1: Like these the two things that the basketball net was hanging on, you know The two things that hang it from the ceiling and he scored a field goal.
Speaker 1: It was like five points.
Speaker 1: It was crazy and that was really fun because you were getting all these different kinds of balls and like the Drop-kick was such a rare event that anyone even attempted it.
Speaker 1: It was just sort of weird that way.
Speaker 1: So I would always try for the drop kick every time because it was like, oh man, someone's trying it.
Speaker 0: Oh my gosh, man.
Speaker 0: I just I like the much simpler course the one time we were playing dodgeball we had like four different balls out there and one single yellow nerf arrow from the bow and arrow because basically you could throw that thing and actually was really cool.
Speaker 0: if you held it by the front and Threw it like tail forward like a dagger It would go out and then straighten itself out and just make a b-line.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they throw it pretty high and hard though You did.
Speaker 1: it's a lot of wrist action to get that to go quickly.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but that arrow made that game.
Speaker 1: that arrow is good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the problem is it was really easy to catch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's good.
Speaker 1: You can't imagine going that.
Speaker 0: I'm a big fan of the really simple because like simple just one touch You're out catching the other person's out four or five balls.
Speaker 0: and like ten people on a team
Speaker 1: I like having some of the complicated things, you know Cuz it sort of it sort of mixes it up gives you something interesting to think about like add some sort of you know strategic element there supposed to just the raw physical Dodging and catching.
Speaker 0: and there's so much strategy even in the raw game like for example All right, five balls, right if you've got an organized team and we would often plan this stuff in advance.
Speaker 0: We'd be like, all right we'd wait until we had like four of the balls on our side and usually at that point the other team realizes what's up and go crap and they hold on to that last ball.
Speaker 0: like What are we gonna do?
Speaker 0: and what we do is we'd go we'd shoot a volley The organized volley.
Speaker 0: another great strategy We always had or we toss one up to get someone to go for a catch.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, someone else had the little ball behind their back and as soon as the person's looking up to catch it Whap him in the face with that ball.
Speaker 0: They missed the ball in the air and they're out.
Speaker 1: Yep Another good strategy we had is if you grab if you had a ball in your hands and someone threw a ball at you You could use it to bump that ball away.
Speaker 0: Yes, you could.
Speaker 1: so it's like.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna dodge throw that at me.
Speaker 1: I dare you bump ha ha ha ha I'm using the ball as a shield and it's basically what you do.
Speaker 1: is you'd bump throw real quick while they weren't ready for it.
Speaker 0: Well, no, don't bump throw Bump from the top down a little bit to bump it right back at him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that wouldn't really count.
Speaker 0: if you if they hit was he got to play with bounces.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, I know the thing about playing with bounces is it's good and bad in a way.
Speaker 0: I think it's nothing but good.
Speaker 0: I think it adds a lot to the game because then there's a lot more throws.
Speaker 0: you can do a lot of moves.
Speaker 0: I like the idea of moves.
Speaker 1: moves are okay.
Speaker 1: I like moves.
Speaker 0: But yes one one option.
Speaker 0: we played a lot was we basically demarcate a circle, right and it was just either teams shirts and skins or every man for himself and that's it.
Speaker 0: Then it gets crazy.
Speaker 0: Someone's got a ball suddenly.
Speaker 0: There's basically a circle of people around him going.
Speaker 0: don't throw it.
Speaker 1: We did.
Speaker 1: we did play circle dodgeball Which is where there's people standing around the circle and there's people in the circle and they the balls are coming at.
Speaker 1: you know There's balls two or three balls coming at you from all the people around the circle and they're throwing it at the people in the circle And if you get you're surrounded by people on all sides, so it's a game of.
Speaker 1: it's coming at you from all 360 direction, you know degrees, you know, you got to dodge that shit.
Speaker 1: and then if you get hit, you know You got to go into the circle and now join the people, you know Attack the rest of the people still in the circle the other fun and the last person in the circle wins four square dodgeball.
Speaker 0: We're basically we just divide the gym into four equal corners and it was four teams playing dodgeball.
Speaker 1: But the team diagonally from you would would sort of be like the last team sort of like warlords.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But at the same time if you were good enough You would eliminate the two teams either side.
Speaker 0: if it came down to just two angle teams that we switch it to the whole gym Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's obvious.
Speaker 1: Dodgeball such a. I mean.
Speaker 1: There's something fundamental about the game of throw something at someone and try to hit them with it.
Speaker 1: It just allows for such a wide variety of games Without actually making a broken or stupid game.
Speaker 1: because like the base concept is so good simple direct Competition between humans.
Speaker 0: I very much enjoy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Not indirect like two people running like a time trial but direct like two people Racing mountain bikes on the same single track.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like you have this sort of slight violent element to it which despite violence in general being abhorrent.
Speaker 1: is you know I mean violent cells right?
Speaker 0: possibly more so than say violence is abhorrent unless it's mutually consensual.
Speaker 0: sport violence.
Speaker 0: Yeah Hockey fires are so great because usually you want to fight.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and But at the same time no one's really getting hurt.
Speaker 1: and it's kind of fun.
Speaker 1: and you can be aggressive But you can also be defensive and it's not like I'm an offense now I'm a defense.
Speaker 1: now you can play it as you go, you know, you can.
Speaker 1: you can choose your own path you can.
Speaker 0: problem is the best part of every game was always the initial moment when There's three balls lined up in the front and everyone starts to the back of their court.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like it's blown cuz.
Speaker 0: Usually there's always those few people who run for it.
Speaker 0: But but and you always make the decision am I gonna run for it?
Speaker 1: What I would do is I would run for it right one time, right?
Speaker 1: I ran for it and I just ran as fast as I could because most people hesitate a little bit, right?
Speaker 1: I ran for it as fast as I could and when I got there, I just fucking kicked it really hard.
Speaker 0: Ha right.
Speaker 1: So everyone just just like got out of the way like whoa.
Speaker 1: Not because it would have counted because it kick doesn't count right slight kicks counted.
Speaker 0: So the way we actually that was one of these strategies.
Speaker 1: It didn't matter if a kick counted or not because either way they tried that they dodged it because they didn't want to get hit By that because I kicked it really hard.
Speaker 1: that would have hurt.
Speaker 0: but that was no.
Speaker 0: that was our strategy.
Speaker 0: We say there were five balls up, right?
Speaker 0: We plan ahead of time.
Speaker 0: five people will run Yeah And we'd pick which ball they're running to.
Speaker 1: we'd always designate One person as he will kick the ball as cover for everyone else is gonna grab Yeah, so the fact that now the second time we did it they knew they thought that I was gonna kick it really hard.
Speaker 1: So when I ran full-on, no one went over there They sort of sort of shied away and I just talk I got I got close I walked up and I picked it up and I'm like, ah You know.
Speaker 1: and then of course the next time, you know It's sort of like the psychology of multiple rounds the rock-paper-scissors.
Speaker 1: psychology sets in.
Speaker 1: so you got to stay one step ahead of the game.
Speaker 1: You know next time I don't run up really hard.
Speaker 1: I just sort of you know step a little bit and they go, huh, and then I run up and get it.
Speaker 0: Yep, the one strategy that was always key like my individual strategy was you know There's especially in gym dodgeball where everyone's kind of forced to play and there's always like half the people just don't want to be playing.
Speaker 1: That is one problem I always had in gym classes.
Speaker 1: you since it's a class which is pretty much a Sized cross-section of you know your class of kids in school, right?
Speaker 1: There you're gonna get people who are really into it and people aren't.
Speaker 1: and really it would only be fun if everyone was in.
Speaker 0: But the trick was a lot of people would pick off the low-hanging fruit.
Speaker 1: No Leave hanging fruit to the end a screen or you bounce balls off of them and then you always get the stereotypical Situation of the one nerdy person who hates sports being all alone and dodgeball with everyone else on the other team.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: It sounds stereotypical, but it's So often especially, you know What it really happens.
Speaker 1: the most is when you get the kind of dodgeball where when you hit someone they come to your team.
Speaker 1: So one team that's winning just gets larger and larger.
Speaker 0: There's not a good way to play.
Speaker 1: the losing team gets smaller.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not the best way to play but it's quite humorous because it's the only one team of losers and one team of winners And then they just have fun picking off all the losers.
Speaker 0: I remember this one game who's in fifth grade and we were using our attrition strategy Which is we'd get all the balls or as many as we could and we'd throw a volley an event.
Speaker 0: We only do this if we were up by it by at least like two people.
Speaker 0: What we do is we'd all walk up to the front with all the balls pick one person and all throw with that person.
Speaker 0: now They might catch the one of the balls and one of us would be out but not the other one.
Speaker 0: They're definitely going to be out too.
Speaker 0: So basically every throw we would eliminate one more person But they wouldn't catch it every time.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is there was this one kid who caught it every time.
Speaker 0: There are
Speaker 1: also those amazing moments in dodgeball where someone will catch more balls than it seems possible Like they catch a ball drop one and catch another one or they would catch one Put their arms out and catch another one between their
Speaker 0: arms Because most people they were afraid of getting out because they wanted to play.
Speaker 0: So they were so afraid of the ball because they didn't want to get eliminated that they wouldn't go for the catch.
Speaker 0: They'd be like, oh my god and try to dodge up.
Speaker 1: the worst Is it.
Speaker 1: occasionally you would catch it and it would bounce out of you because you would do the chest catch.
Speaker 1: You know like you cup your arms and you catch it deep in there because you think it's gonna be a lock and then it Bounces out.
Speaker 0: No I always tell the good dodgeball players because they would put their hands out With both hands and hold it out in front of them.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep That's the way to do it.
Speaker 0: or we had a couple of kids who were really good at volleyball And what they would do is when it came they'd bump it up and then someone else would catch it behind Every ball.
Speaker 0: the one guy would stand in the front whenever they threw it He'd bump it up and then his friend behind would catch it.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: It was so perfect.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of good machine long debate in class where the gym teacher stops and we had to argue whether or not that was legitimate.
Speaker 1: It's good stuff.
Speaker 0: of course that was only because we had a substitute gym teacher one day who was awesome.
Speaker 1: You know, maybe it's some anime convention or something.
Speaker 1: We could have a dodgeball event.
Speaker 0: Most cons would not let us do that.
Speaker 1: I know I know but I'm just if only we could do it at Otakon.
Speaker 0: You know, you know those kids are always fighting with the stupid sword.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they can play kendo out in that area.
Speaker 1: Why can't we play dodgeball?
Speaker 0: Let's bring a kickball to Otakon and just see what happens.
Speaker 0: I ordered a kickball.
Speaker 1: So one is not enough that we need at least three.
Speaker 0: We'll get some other people to bring.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also they might go off the edge up there.
Speaker 1: We might need to find a better place.
Speaker 0: I think that place is fine.
Speaker 1: You know, it might go over a pecs.
Speaker 0: Oh Man, I'll bring it to play to dodgeball.
Speaker 1: All right You got anything else to say about dodgeball then how awesome it is.
Speaker 1: now everyone should play and it's a travesty.
Speaker 1: It's not played as much anymore.
Speaker 0: I feel like in general.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't know I actually have a somewhat tangent, but I'll go on this real quick.
Speaker 0: I feel and I made a thread about this that a lot of geeks and a lot of nerds.
Speaker 0: It's like they shoot sport.
Speaker 0: They're like ah sports and they get this bug up their butt like I don't like sports and usually it seems It's because they conflate the idea of physical fitness or sporting With bullies and that sort of thing because there is some a little bit of a correlation Partly just because of physicality of it, but I feel like a lot of geeks do themselves a grave Disservice by letting themselves become physically unfit or avoiding sports or physical competition because of these kind of Unrelated or conflated issues.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not revenge of the nerds people.
Speaker 1: All right The Greeks had it right.
Speaker 0: a well-rounded classical education is critical to being a good person.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe not necessarily a good person because there were a lot of evil Greeks.
Speaker 1: revenge of the nerds is the stereotype.
Speaker 1: You're not supposed to be the stereotype.
Speaker 0: well-rounded education will do you nothing but good in the long run.
Speaker 1: I Mean look at all the things that you you know, look around.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, you might be a geek and dislike sports.
Speaker 1: But you probably think martial arts are cool and you probably think hockey is cool.
Speaker 1: And you probably.
Speaker 1: you probably think that Parkour is cool.
Speaker 0: do parkour.
Speaker 0: It's well, I was about to say it's easy.
Speaker 0: No, it's not easy.
Speaker 1: No, it's easy to get into it's easy to try.
Speaker 0: Well, you just got to start small yeah, and then we'll jump a little skateboarding.
Speaker 1: right nerd is nerd sport.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well the skateboard nerds are.
Speaker 0: the snowboarding is nervous for it of themselves.
Speaker 1: I know I know I don't know about snowboarding.
Speaker 0: I've never seen anyone actually do it.
Speaker 1: You never seen anyone snow?
Speaker 0: No, no see that's a joke right because any time in my whole life when I was a kid and I'd go skiing and then when I Finally started skiing in last year the one time I went skiing see if I could still do it Snowboarders were never snowboarding.
Speaker 0: They're always sitting halfway down like the bunny hill on their asses talking Yeah, never were they actually snowboard.
Speaker 1: I've seen him on TV in half.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just I don't know.
Speaker 0: I really don't think snowboarding is that fun compared to skiing cuz it's a lot slower and you can't do as much.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you can do the little tricks and stuff, which is cool.
Speaker 1: But I like that 1080 snowboarding video game for the n64.
Speaker 1: That was good.
Speaker 0: It was actually a pretty damn good.
Speaker 1: It's on the virtual console.
Speaker 1: I think it's one of the best snowboarding games even though I never played those SSX ones.
Speaker 1: Anyway, dodgeball Pretty awesome, which I think there should be a professional dodgeball league.
Speaker 0: I think there should be Olympic dodgeball.
Speaker 1: that I would agree should be like.
Speaker 0: I thought it really was.
Speaker 1: there was a movie About dodgeball, but I think it was one of those stupid wacky comedy movies and I didn't see it.
Speaker 0: I saw trailers to it.
Speaker 1: It didn't look funny at all No But that guess that was a missed opportunity.
Speaker 0: Guys from Firefly was in it and that's why everyone lost their shit over it.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: I didn't know that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that makes me want to see it less.
Speaker 0: Ah dodgeball.
Speaker 1: Ah Good times.
Speaker 1: Tell us your dodgeball stories.
Speaker 1: Tell us how dodgeball is played in your area.
Speaker 0: Yes We want all you will make us two small to be separate.
Speaker 1: You should make a dodgeball database all the different dodgeball rules in one place.
Speaker 0: Ooh, should we make that?
Speaker 0: that could be a money-making site the d-ball DB d-ball DB.
Speaker 0: Maybe we can start a d-ball League the Lig an international d-ball League international d-ball organized by nerds With a website with a ladder and a challenge system.
Speaker 1: Yeah something like that.
Speaker 0: Oh, man This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio.
Speaker 1: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.