Speaker 0: It's Thursday, February 7th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: Why sports spectating is not stupid football?
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So for the last several years Scott has often had I mean not often But he's had some crazy stories of things that have happened on the train in the morning.
Speaker 0: and son happened on your train this Morning for the first time.
Speaker 0: I had something crazy happen on my train But you had something crazy like the old guy who wouldn't get off.
Speaker 1: He wasn't crazy That was just.
Speaker 1: that was funny.
Speaker 1: and there was another equally funny one actually yesterday Where this guy was on the phone, right?
Speaker 1: You know normally when someone's loud on the phone on the train everyone's like shut up or the conductor says shut up.
Speaker 1: the guy was so funny and and just the way what he was saying that Basically the whole it was just a comedy routine for everyone on the car including the conductor.
Speaker 1: Basically his conversation was like this man.
Speaker 1: No ma listen to me ma ma ma ma.
Speaker 1: Just shut up.
Speaker 1: Shut the fuck up ma Just listen to me.
Speaker 1: All right, he had no business it ma ma ma Just just just be quiet now.
Speaker 1: I'm not don't say that ma.
Speaker 1: Come on mom ma ma in that exact voice for the for like took 20 minutes.
Speaker 1: it was When he stopped.
Speaker 1: everyone in the crowd like everyone sat there for a while and then one guy started clapping and The guy got really embarrassed and he kind of looked around like her and then he got on another car And I didn't see him for the rest of the ride.
Speaker 0: But today it wasn't.
Speaker 0: this is why they tell you when you're on the cell phone you should go in the vestibule.
Speaker 0: That's did Alex and vestibule.
Speaker 1: I do too, you know what a vestibule is very much like a Boy a how about a Macadamia Gazebo.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: All right, but no today I had something one of those kind of bad interesting things happen.
Speaker 1: So I get on the train and you know, there's a there's a girl.
Speaker 0: I just had two things in the same day.
Speaker 1: Well, this was today.
Speaker 1: The other thing was yesterday.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: So today I get on the train.
Speaker 1: I'm I walked and there's a girl kind of laying in one of the seats and I think all right the conductor who's going to Make her move?
Speaker 1: because this trains always crazy crowded.
Speaker 0: She was unconscious or something.
Speaker 1: No, she seems she was sitting there just Alright, so I put my earplugs in and I'm just kind of half asleep and then I hear moaning Uh-huh, and is she pregnant or something?
Speaker 1: Well, yes, but I'll get to that.
Speaker 1: Oh, so I'm thinking alright And I look around.
Speaker 1: I see other people kind of look into my direction.
Speaker 0: I already figured this one out.
Speaker 1: So I take the.
Speaker 1: now you didn't alright.
Speaker 1: so I take the earplugs out and I hear moans of pain and whimpering and all sorts of trouble from Behind me where that girl was.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So I turn around and I look and Ask her if she's okay, and she doesn't respond.
Speaker 1: She just keeps moaning.
Speaker 0: and then where did she get on Poughkeepsie?
Speaker 1: I guess so.
Speaker 1: then I'm thinking like alright I'm gonna get the conductor and do something and then the guy sitting across like in across the aisle in the same row looks at me and says you got a problem boss and I'm like, uh, this woman seems like she needs help.
Speaker 1: She's like he's.
Speaker 1: and then he says mind your business uh-huh, uh-huh, and That that is the moment when all the other people sitting on the train start saying Oh, this woman is clearly in pain and needs help.
Speaker 1: Who are you - and he's like mind your business you people.
Speaker 1: He's getting really agitated.
Speaker 0: Uh-oh Obviously, there's a daytime talk show situation happening here.
Speaker 1: It's a it gets far worse than this.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, I see a need for police and ambulance involvement already, so I've got my cell phone out.
Speaker 1: I'm ready to call the police just in case the situation escalates quick.
Speaker 0: I would have called 9-1-1 as soon as that guy said mind your business.
Speaker 1: Well the reason I didn't because we were in between Stops and the conductor was in the next car about to get there and the conductor can get police much more quickly.
Speaker 1: I would have I would have gone to get the conductor and you know immediately Yeah, but he was right there and it looked like someone else was already talking to him pointing in our direction.
Speaker 1: So things were things were going in the right direction All right, and pretty much this dude had the whole train car already ready to jump him if anything was going on You know.
Speaker 1: So, uh, the conductor gets there and he asked what's going on and everyone kind of starts to explain.
Speaker 1: and he asked the woman Are you okay, and she won't answer him.
Speaker 1: You need paramedics.
Speaker 1: You won't answer him.
Speaker 1: She just won't say a word to him.
Speaker 0: So you turn pregnant, right?
Speaker 1: I found that out later.
Speaker 0: So do I did she look pregnant?
Speaker 0: She wasn't very pregnant.
Speaker 1: she looked like a mid-20s woman, okay She wasn't going into labor.
Speaker 1: that I did the story is not.
Speaker 1: rim delivered a baby on the way to work.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, but I was saying, you know, I asked if she was pregnant.
Speaker 0: So I sort of assumed that you know, you said yes, so I assumed that oh, it's she must have been very, you know large
Speaker 1: well that I guess that that's just because you asked a question that had a somewhat unanticipated answer
Speaker 0: Because I that was you know, sort of an obvious guess there.
Speaker 0: what was going on?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the conductor is asking her and she really won't say anything.
Speaker 0: No, it's like it powers call Randy I got a million dollars.
Speaker 1: so then the conductor turns to the guy and says is she alright?
Speaker 1: and he says I don't know.
Speaker 1: uh-huh, so the conductor says Well, isn't she with you?
Speaker 1: and he says she ain't with me.
Speaker 0: Then why would you say in mind your business?
Speaker 1: So, uh, he said.
Speaker 1: so the conductor who obviously had already known about this situation and was just waiting for the opportunity to deal with Says well you gave me your ticket.
Speaker 1: and he says he says well She's apparently with all these other people because these all these other people care about my business And they should mind their business To which the conductor says Sir what's going on?
Speaker 1: And then he proceeds to balk and deny and refuse to answer anything.
Speaker 1: and then conductor is Obviously getting very close to calling the police.
Speaker 0: if he's not already I would have had the police already called.
Speaker 0: Plus the conductor is very see unlike, you know me right where you know, if I'm on a train I can sort of try to deal with a situation like that.
Speaker 0: But the conductor has special law protections that allow him to be an asshole.
Speaker 1: I'll say this if you don't know if you're in New York State And you'd do anything to a transit official if you a bus driver, I don't know if it applies to cab drivers.
Speaker 0: I think this is different laws for cab drivers like mass transit.
Speaker 0: anyone a subway Employee a bus driver any a train conductor They're protected.
Speaker 0: you even touch them you go to jail for like seven years.
Speaker 1: Basically touching one of them is the same as touching a police officer with the exact same penalties.
Speaker 0: It's almost as bad.
Speaker 0: It's pretty bad, yeah, but I mean it's it's.
Speaker 0: it's almost as bad not quite the same but there's a minimum sentences.
Speaker 0: Yes, there are very large ones I mean like if I if I'm walking down New York City Street, right and there's a cop standing there and I punch rim in The face right I would get like, you know assault battery something, you know night in jail something like that.
Speaker 0: Right if rim happened to be a train conductor I would be like a felony and seven years something ridiculous like that.
Speaker 0: Maybe I think there's like tens of thousands of dollars in fines.
Speaker 0: You don't fuck with those people.
Speaker 1: so anyway, the conductor eventually gets out the story and the work.
Speaker 1: the girl starts talking.
Speaker 1: finally and Basically, the two of them were at a hospital in Poughkeepsie and she is pregnant and there are complications.
Speaker 1: So they were told to go to a specialty hospital in Harlem Mm-hmm, so they had gotten on the train and they were told that you know just get on the train get to that hospital and they'll take care of you there and The situation like.
Speaker 1: they verified everything and it was totally normal.
Speaker 1: The only problem was that the dude was just a complete jackass for absolutely no reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: did he want to create suspicion into thinking that something was going on?
Speaker 1: I mean, it's one thing to you know, tell people to mind their own business.
Speaker 1: It's in even though I think it was a stupid thing to do.
Speaker 1: It's an entirely other thing to lie to the conductor.
Speaker 1: when he comes and asks you if everything's all right It is obviously trying to help.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean and why wouldn't the woman say anything?
Speaker 0: You know, I can understand not wanting to you know, share your situation with the world and have you know Some sort of privacy or something, but I mean, it's obvious that people didn't mean poorly.
Speaker 0: The people were concerned and if you you know, honestly did care you just you know, sort of say, you know You don't give all the details, but you would say, you know We're on our way to a hospital in Harlem the hospital in Poughkeepsie.
Speaker 0: He told us to go on the train and we'd be fine and that's what we're doing.
Speaker 1: if the guy had said it's okay She's with me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that would have been enough as long as she wasn't, you know, I don't know tied up or something I know right, but that And then you know, basically I just I was woken up by that.
Speaker 1: so I spent the rest of the train ride reading and playing advanced wars, but I got to overhear the conversations that went on throughout the train ride between the man and this woman and Neither one of them is the brightest Star in the sky the brightest bulb in the candelabra, shall we say?
Speaker 1: Yeah I Don't think their lives are going in a good direction.
Speaker 0: No, no, not really.
Speaker 0: Yeah now that is you'd like that.
Speaker 0: With an attitude like that, you know things that you might try to do you're going to fail at because people will you know?
Speaker 0: Your interactions with people will fail.
Speaker 1: Yeah I didn't get the end of the story because I moved out of the car to another car around Croton Harmon when she started vomiting All over the place.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's fantastic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the conductor took care of the rest of it.
Speaker 1: And yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: So that was my morning.
Speaker 0: Yeah on the way into work.
Speaker 0: I played some dwarf fortress, right?
Speaker 0: I was doing the best your fortress ever.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: Is this II?
Speaker 1: but then the story.
Speaker 0: but then a Giant cave swallow ate three of my doors.
Speaker 1: So you were in that chasm weren't you?
Speaker 0: it just flew out.
Speaker 1: I'm excited about that chasm.
Speaker 1: I remember you're like I got a chasm.
Speaker 0: it actually happened when I got to work and I upgraded to a newer version of dwarf.
Speaker 0: I think that newer version had more monsters coming out of the chasm.
Speaker 0: I would think that was a mistake.
Speaker 0: to upgrade.
Speaker 1: you can see you build the hallway to the chasm Right.
Speaker 1: put some door on the end of that shit.
Speaker 0: No It did it.
Speaker 0: the guy was going because the platinum was in like next to the chasm.
Speaker 0: like you couldn't get the platinum without Exposing yourself.
Speaker 1: I guess you got to put some Rangers.
Speaker 1: just stand.
Speaker 0: the Ranger got eaten by wolves.
Speaker 1: Maybe you shouldn't send him out to kill the wolves.
Speaker 0: Killed so many wolves by himself.
Speaker 0: like I have a refuse pile full of wolf carcasses.
Speaker 0: yet somehow one wolf got him.
Speaker 1: Are you sure he wasn't bleeding continuously from all the fights with?
Speaker 0: if he was it didn't say it anywhere.
Speaker 0: It didn't say watch out your Rangers bleeding.
Speaker 0: tell him to come home and it's not like.
Speaker 0: I could even tell him not to go hunt.
Speaker 0: Well, he did it on his own.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm just.
Speaker 1: I'm saying you got it.
Speaker 1: The dwarves aren't the brightest.
Speaker 1: No shit All right, no, but I mean I was reading a story on the wiki about a dwarf who basically locked himself in his room and Starved to death.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's happened And I tried to start a new game on the way home.
Speaker 0: But because I didn't have the wiki I couldn't get it the starting loadout, right?
Speaker 0: The game is very difficult to play or at least I can play it without the wiki But I can't start a new game without the wiki.
Speaker 0: That's very difficult.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've yet to actually play a game of this though I'm kind of thinking I'm not going to join this succession game because I'm awful but I could foresee a Parallel universe.
Speaker 1: What if rim the dwarf took over?
Speaker 1: Because I imagine rim the dwarfs responses to everything are what the fuck do these dwarves want?
Speaker 1: they're out of food.
Speaker 1: I don't know what's going on.
Speaker 1: And now one of them's dead.
Speaker 0: once things are set up They will largely sort of work on their own.
Speaker 0: if things are set up, right?
Speaker 0: But it's it.
Speaker 0: the part is getting it to that point and then not having any problems.
Speaker 1: I'll be honest I feel like I mean it was really cool interviewing the the lead developer for dwarf fortress But I feel like unless he open-sources this thing.
Speaker 0: It's never really gonna get much further than it is now I feel like it'll make progress But I think there are a lot that it basically won't achieve anywhere near its full potential.
Speaker 1: unless he does something different I think the game would be ten times better within a year pretty much from the day.
Speaker 1: It was open source pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah anyway On Amazon.
Speaker 0: I finally ordered a Leatherman cuz.
Speaker 0: I you know, I've always wanted one of those multi-tools.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I mean I had I had a wood man and an Iron Man and they didn't quite cut it now.
Speaker 0: And they had so many different choices, you know, and like I was I don't know which one I wanted.
Speaker 0: Right the Leatherman wave is the most popular but I mean that thing is a fucking saw in it.
Speaker 0: I don't need a saw.
Speaker 1: What if you're?
Speaker 1: what if you get a saw something, you know, watch watch we're gonna get to Katsu Kan, right?
Speaker 0: You'll have your brand new Leatherman and there'll be a tiny piece of wood and we will just need to cut it really bad.
Speaker 1: We'll be about to get the rampart cartridges into the room, right?
Speaker 1: but there's a little piece of wood stuck in the door and the door is just too small to get it in as a result and The con chair is gonna come in and say But no Katsu Kan is canceled go home right that might happen they could.
Speaker 1: then we'll play some tiny poker right now.
Speaker 0: So I finally figured I looked at all the options and I weighed them against each other and I figured out one that has Most of the tools I need and not so many tools I don't need.
Speaker 0: and I realize these things are real expensive like they're 50 bucks at the store 60/70 on Amazon 30 30 bucks, you know I noticed this today when I was thinking like I need all this stuff.
Speaker 1: I was thinking and I sat down it.
Speaker 1: All right, what's everything I need Other than you know?
Speaker 1: large capital purchases like houses and a new car?
Speaker 1: and I looked at everything I needed and I thought huh?
Speaker 1: I wonder how much of this I can get on Amazon right now.
Speaker 1: Went to Amazon everything.
Speaker 1: I got everything I even could.
Speaker 1: I was sitting there and I was like I was trying to think of anything else I could need cuz I could Just order it right then.
Speaker 1: I don't go to stores anymore Yep.
Speaker 0: So anyway, the one I ended up getting is the leatherman fuse.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it has a nice ruler and stuff and scissor and a what.
Speaker 0: now anyway I ordered it and it sort of didn't show up, but I checked the tracking information and it I basically said, you know Check that, you know Accepted for delivery.
Speaker 0: But that was it and it said that for a very long time and usually, you know They estimate a delivery date and things, you know show up way before that date.
Speaker 0: Well, it got to that date and it didn't show up.
Speaker 0: So the next day I emailed Amazon.
Speaker 0: I was like, what do I do?
Speaker 0: They're like wait until February 6th.
Speaker 0: There is six was yesterday.
Speaker 0: the tracking information hasn't changed.
Speaker 0: I said, I'm pretty confident.
Speaker 0: This is lost in the mail.
Speaker 0: So they said, okay, you want us to send you another one?
Speaker 0: I said yes No, so they just sent me another one for free with better shipping than before for free and we'll see if it shows up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's that's a Amazon lost in the mail.
Speaker 0: No worries.
Speaker 1: So, um in the news I have to talk about this a little bit.
Speaker 1: It's kind of it's related nominally to the important events of American politics that Scott doesn't care about but They do not call.
Speaker 1: a registry in the United States is not something I personally care about because I have a cell phone.
Speaker 1: they can't call me anyway, but Lot of people who haven't made the leap into the current century still have landlines.
Speaker 1: as a result They care about, you know being bothered every day by telemarketers And I would do if I had a landline.
Speaker 1: and we have the do not call registry Which basically is a list you can sign up for.
Speaker 1: that says all right telemarketers can't call you or they get fined out the ass.
Speaker 1: And it was a temporary bill.
Speaker 1: The news is that it has been made permanent by the Senate.
Speaker 1: So the do not call registry is here to stay.
Speaker 1: and even better they added something because a lot of people got calls from politicians, but they weren't actually the politicians.
Speaker 1: they were robots robots disguised as politicians.
Speaker 1: It is now against the law to call people with political message with robot Huh?
Speaker 0: Well, isn't that most of the calls you got there that was indeed.
Speaker 1: However, those calls were illegal anyway, because they went to my cell phone.
Speaker 1: But they were also from fairly untraceable numbers and there's a good chance that they weren't actually from the candidates They claim to be from.
Speaker 1: but uh, don't get me started on that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a Real still a big problem in this country in the fact that everyone has cell phones yet.
Speaker 0: They haven't really Updated the country to deal with the fact that people have cell phones only and it's like they got to work on that.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean other than when there's an election and I get a whole bunch of calls to my cell phone for like the two days before the election The country accommodates my cell phone usage a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, how are we not?
Speaker 1: what's missing?
Speaker 0: I know a lot.
Speaker 0: it like a lot of places you'll go and it'd be like home phone cell phone.
Speaker 0: It's like alright.
Speaker 0: Listen, I fill in just cell phone.
Speaker 0: It doesn't work.
Speaker 0: You know people gotta well, you know what I do.
Speaker 1: I just fill in the home phone because my cell phone is my own right but then they'll spam that one because you know No, and then when one I've never had anyone spam it cable vision keeps calling me.
Speaker 1: Well tell him not to call you.
Speaker 1: I know but have you actually told him not to call you?
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, have you sent send them a certified postal letter and in its state that you do not want them to ever call you Unless it's a direct matter pertaining to your continuation of service and or billing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what I mean.
Speaker 0: What that's what I want.
Speaker 1: well do that send them a certified letter and State in the letter that if they don't comply and they continue to call you after such and such period that you'll be forced to Bring legal action against them, but I don't want to bring legal action the pen.
Speaker 1: You know how fun that would be.
Speaker 0: I had to take a day off work to go to small claims court to get less money than I make in a day of work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz you can only get like a thousand bucks from small claims course, right?
Speaker 1: It's silly fun though They can imagine.
Speaker 1: it's kind of like paint.
Speaker 1: you pay some money right and you get to have fun.
Speaker 0: I would love to go to court if I had more if I had a bunch of vacation days.
Speaker 1: sure I have never been able to.
Speaker 1: every time I've been summoned to a court for something the charges have always been dismissed and I've never Gotten a chance to actually state a case.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So anyway You're gonna hear a lot of newses and things of the day from this blog which I was itself my thing of the day a while ago Science based medicine org.
Speaker 0: It's like the greatest blog.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, like every single thing they post here is awesome, and they post often like every day.
Speaker 0: There's something new here some amazing essay or something and the latest one is pretty interesting now.
Speaker 0: It's called the Iraqi civilian war dead scandal right now.
Speaker 0: Don't take this.
Speaker 0: Wait.
Speaker 1: Wait.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: I'm just curious is the direction of this a lot more people are dying than we think or is the direction of this not as Many people are dying as we think?
Speaker 0: the direction of this is a lot less people a lot less Iraqi civilians died than according To this one study.
Speaker 0: There's a study That was hard I'm not you know, of course a lot of people have died in Iraq on all sides and it's terrible and you know No, even if the statistic was 10, it's horrible, right?
Speaker 0: So I'm not downplaying the horribleness I don't want anyone to think that right but this article the reason it's so quality is because it shows you you know how someone can conduct a Scientific study not you know Randy or bullshit or anything and publish it in a somewhat trusted You know source and that you know published study will spread.
Speaker 0: and the idea You know the general idea of that published study will spread within.
Speaker 0: you know The the mindshare of the people and people will quote that study often and you know It'll basically create a fact.
Speaker 0: yet if the actual study was not Conducted according to strict scientific controls and and it just wasn't done properly I just I cut.
Speaker 1: I imagine I had a cut to you know, Family Guy style the statistician sitting at his computer and thinking how many people died in Iraq and Then he just pipes dev random into some sort of program.
Speaker 0: Well, you can read the story of actually how they got the numbers so incredibly wrong here, right But let me let me find this little part here that I can quote.
Speaker 0: Oh I lost it.
Speaker 1: Oh, well regardless.
Speaker 0: There was a one part.
Speaker 0: Oh, here it is.
Speaker 0: Uh, uh, uh Scrolling go go go go go.
Speaker 0: 100 animals an hour.
Speaker 1: I'm not editing.
Speaker 1: Nothing's coming out of this show.
Speaker 1: They're here in the dark side of geek nights that the continuity is broken.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Okay ears He talks about some of the different figures that people came up with.
Speaker 0: right and here's one of them.
Speaker 0: He says critics found yet another figure that I thought of also after deciding to write this the u.s Battlefield ratio of wounded individuals to deaths is eight.
Speaker 0: is that is somewhere between eight and ten to one right?
Speaker 0: Assuming a ten to one ratio, right?
Speaker 0: There would have been six million wounded Iraqi civilians seeking medical care over three years or ten thousand wounded per day.
Speaker 0: No hospital or other source of data could reasonably have confirmed such figures.
Speaker 0: you see so It's it's just a lot of people come up with these numbers and the numbers get published in some way and people believe the numbers And you got to really go and look and find out where the fuck those numbers came from.
Speaker 0: and you know Not I'm not commenting on the Iraq situation here I'm just.
Speaker 0: it's a really great example of how numbers can get just way out of control.
Speaker 0: and you know People are saying, you know 600,000 people died 600,000 civilians died in Iraq and that's probably a huge overestimation.
Speaker 0: It's probably much much less is is much closer to the truth.
Speaker 1: So since my news was kind of lame because the only commentary I have other than that it happened was basically Advertisers suck it.
Speaker 1: I don't care about you, but I got a bit of a geek bite here real quick.
Speaker 1: I almost said geek backs.
Speaker 0: I Scott says the main bits gonna be like long here.
Speaker 0: You got a won't be that long I don't know could be long.
Speaker 1: We didn't do a show yesterday.
Speaker 1: I thought that about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know but we couldn't come up with anything to do.
Speaker 0: actually that we did a news in a main bit And they sucked ass.
Speaker 1: the story of yesterday's show is thus Scott and I are sitting here tired.
Speaker 0: We're looking at me so tired.
Speaker 1: Well tired as in I want to get about my real business.
Speaker 1: You want to make the show and get done and eat some dinner and we're looking at anime news Network.
Speaker 1: Nothing happened.
Speaker 1: there was no news and we're like, alright Let's just do the show.
Speaker 1: and what we recorded was probably worse than even some of the beta episodes of geek nights.
Speaker 1: Halfway through my news.
Speaker 1: I was like, oh god fuck this.
Speaker 0: It was a pretty terrible on my news.
Speaker 0: and then rims news was even worse.
Speaker 1: My news was like the most epic fail I've ever had.
Speaker 1: I basically stated the news and then realized that I didn't have a single thing to say.
Speaker 1: Nothing.
Speaker 0: not even I was trying to sort of start something up on his news and all he was just.
Speaker 0: he was just going in.
Speaker 1: I was like and I was flailing.
Speaker 1: I was flailing Jerry But I want.
Speaker 1: I want because I'm reading this again and I think it's important and I talk about on Monday.
Speaker 1: But I'm pretty sure anyone who listens to Monday dedicatedly has already read this book.
Speaker 1: Cosmos by Carl Sagan is one of the most brilliant nonfiction works ever written.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's not.
Speaker 0: I thought it was a fiction.
Speaker 0: No, I don't know anything about.
Speaker 0: I just know who Carl Sagan is and that's a book He wrote.
Speaker 1: I was about to say you cannot be considered an erudite and well-read human being unless you have read Carl Sagan's cosmos.
Speaker 0: I haven't read any Carl Sagan ever in my whole life.
Speaker 0: I know who is though.
Speaker 1: Let me put it this way I read a large portions of.
Speaker 0: I know generally who he is.
Speaker 1: I know the about the author that cosmos When I was young on the recommendation of my family and teachers and all sorts of people.
Speaker 1: now when I say teachers I mean teachers after I got out of Catholic school.
Speaker 1: but Basically Carl Sagan's cosmos is a book that does nothing more than point out How absolutely amazing science is.
Speaker 1: now absolutely amazing it is the things we know about the universe and how staggering it is that we know these things.
Speaker 1: and even more staggering is the degree of certainty we can say we have about these things.
Speaker 1: and Unlike Richard Dawkins books.
Speaker 1: I mean, I really like Richard Dawkins But he's he is a little abrasive when he writes about religion and that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Carl Sagan this lives is pie.
Speaker 1: The way he writes is mellifluous.
Speaker 1: It's brilliant.
Speaker 1: He's such a good author.
Speaker 1: I cannot stress to you enough how great it is to read anything.
Speaker 1: He's ever read.
Speaker 1: I'm a Carl Sagan fanboy good God and I randomly started reading cosmos again.
Speaker 0: And I just want even when you have all these other things you to read here.
Speaker 1: see that's how you know Something's good like in the anime world.
Speaker 1: We know that cowboy bebop evangelicalian eska flown a try gun.
Speaker 1: these shows Utena are like the great shows because people will watch them Multiple times in lieu of watching new things.
Speaker 1: It's the same way with books.
Speaker 1: I'll read the prince of nothing again.
Speaker 1: I'll read Carl Sagan's cosmos again.
Speaker 1: Considering how many books I want to read that I haven't I can't think of a more glowing recommendation for me personally.
Speaker 1: If you have not read Carl Sagan's cosmos get it now.
Speaker 1: You can get it for like a dollar at every used bookstore in this country.
Speaker 1: It's been translated into every language.
Speaker 1: I can think of good.
Speaker 1: God should you read this book?
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: I don't know why I was reminded of this But I was looking at John's gonna be real happy.
Speaker 1: yes He is but I was.
Speaker 1: I was looking for a thing of the day yesterday in the show that we totally bailed on and I Was kind of I was coming up dry like I was with everything else.
Speaker 1: I kept beating that horse and pumping that well and no blood came out of that stone.
Speaker 1: So Suddenly I was looking around and I checked to see if my new episode of some anime was downloaded and I noticed in my incoming directory a Torrent I had downloaded and forgotten about.
Speaker 1: this torrent was every single song ever made including almost every remix I think exists from a band that I had forgotten.
Speaker 1: I really freaking liked a lot and Then I realized that a lot of people probably don't know this band exists Or you may have heard their music and not realized who they are or realize the extents of what they do.
Speaker 0: so uh Erotic E capital E hyphen capital R. O T I C erotic.
Speaker 1: do not Search for that on YouTube.
Speaker 1: YouTube does not handle the hyphen intelligently.
Speaker 1: you will not find erotic music videos.
Speaker 1: you will find erotic music videos yes, and Don't do it at work.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you this about.
Speaker 1: I was surprised at the number of music videos and Anime music videos set to horrible things.
Speaker 0: There is a big crossover between fans of Dance Dance Revolution and fans of anime.
Speaker 0: you see so Erotic was like the second most licensed music in If you take all the songs in DDR ever right.
Speaker 0: in any DDR mix and you group them by artist.
Speaker 0: Captain Jack is the number one most appearing far away.
Speaker 0: erotic is the number two most appearing yes?
Speaker 1: I learned about erotic from DDR.
Speaker 1: third mix yes, and Their songs?
Speaker 1: well here.
Speaker 1: I'll I'll play an example and see if you can.
Speaker 1: you can get the gist.
Speaker 1: see if this is an exercise From the following what is this song about?
Speaker 0: So ring my bell and just entice me.
Speaker 0: I need to love it much.
Speaker 1: Cuz he's wild and baby.
Speaker 1: when he aims he hits.
Speaker 1: Oh, please I Know Now how about this song.
Speaker 1: Come on.
Speaker 1: Please help me talk today.
Speaker 1: I need your love.
Speaker 0: Say I need a gig and you're so big.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: their songs are not just you know full of sexual innuendo.
Speaker 1: It's full of outright.
Speaker 1: It's a little bit of innuendo, but mostly just straight up like yeah, all right Yeah, and the best part is if you listen to all of their songs They pretty much actually tell a story.
Speaker 0: I mean all the songs that are on the same album in order.
Speaker 0: they tell this little story.
Speaker 1: I mean max shouldn't have sex with an egg with his eggs But he did so.
Speaker 1: then she wants Fred to come to bed and meanwhile dr.
Speaker 1: Dick is out saving people.
Speaker 1: It's Now my thing of the day is pretty much just erotic the band in case you didn't know about them.
Speaker 1: So I'm going to link to some of their music videos.
Speaker 1: The music videos are not great, though I think the dr.
Speaker 1: Dick one is hilarious.
Speaker 0: They're pretty funny.
Speaker 1: Don't watch them at work Yeah or don't watch them if you're offended by a multitude of boobs not attached to women bouncing around and being ridden by like beanbags.
Speaker 0: if you think You know Sir makes a lot times ten.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's kind of like the the music video in the Beavis and Butthead movie.
Speaker 1: It's it's the similar to that style of music video.
Speaker 1: All right, and pretty much every music video they ever did is almost the same.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day cuz we're main bit is sports related.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day is also sports related.
Speaker 0: Here is some hockey's right.
Speaker 0: This guy's taking a penalty shot.
Speaker 0: He's going in.
Speaker 0: He's gonna try to score right but He's not looking where he's supposed to be looking.
Speaker 0: usually, you know, if you think about when you're playing basketball, right?
Speaker 0: You dribble the ball.
Speaker 0: you have to but if you are always looking at the ball,
Speaker 1: which I do because I suck at basketball
Speaker 0: I don't have to look at the ball But if you can't dribble without looking at the ball while you're dribbling Someone's gonna take the ball away from you because you won't see them coming.
Speaker 0: Apply that to hockey you get the picture.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean imagine someone played soccer looking at their feet the whole time.
Speaker 1: Well, I've seen a lot of videos of football players who are looking at a ball and not looking at what's next to them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah No, but the greatest thing about this video is add the goalie does this little victory dance.
Speaker 0: I have seen a lot of hockey victory dances in my time.
Speaker 0: that is in the top three for sure No doubt.
Speaker 1: I think that is one of the.
Speaker 1: I think that's in the top ten of victory dances ever.
Speaker 1: Oh Like in that to the the premature victory dance the Hannibal took after he took over the Roman countryside.
Speaker 0: All right, I'll but I be in the lower half of the top ten Yeah, but somewhere between seven and ten, but it might it might make it.
Speaker 1: I'd have to actually compile So intense and it involves multiple stages of action.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: it's definitely a step up from the typical football spike the ball and run in midair.
Speaker 0: Whoo Yeah, it didn't.
Speaker 0: what it lacked though is the cleverness that many victory dances.
Speaker 1: I think it made up for the lack of cleverness almost entirely by the sheer guts that it
Speaker 0: yes, all right, so Basically, you know we do the geek nights here and I think we've said a thousand times that you can be a geek about anything Even though our show is about technology anime manga comics video games And everything.
Speaker 0: you can be a car you can be a geek about cars You meet geek about sports - yeah I mean, they're the traditional like geeky things like most of the things we talk about.
Speaker 1: but remember here at geek nights We decided and a lot of people use this definition though.
Speaker 1: I did hear that overseas in yonder Albion.
Speaker 1: They're kind of reversed in Australia.
Speaker 1: I heard it's that way too, but whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah a geek to us They speak a different language.
Speaker 1: They say lift instead of elevated and they when they say pants they don't mean pants.
Speaker 0: That's right It's a different different.
Speaker 1: They don't go on vacation they go on holiday and then they get their zeds anyway.
Speaker 0: So our vocabulary does not apply.
Speaker 1: the the American Heritage Dictionary and the Oxford English Dictionary do not refer to the same thing But to us a geek, you know, well, first of all, there's a normal and a person just a person default state.
Speaker 1: You know like nerds geeks dwarfs what all the different things you can call people.
Speaker 1: there's a person a little Venn diagram action And then all these things are subsets of person and one subset of person I would say is geek and another one is nerd.
Speaker 1: And I don't want to get into all the well.
Speaker 1: a dweeb is this but a dork is this but blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: but a geek is a normal person who just happens to have a a somewhat wider area of interest than an average person and independently of that has a couple or Maybe more.
Speaker 1: but I like if it's more than their Renaissance man, but a few extremely deep areas of interest.
Speaker 1: I mean look at us.
Speaker 1: we're super into podcasting and we're super into German board games.
Speaker 1: We're super into anime and we're kind of into sports and all these other things.
Speaker 1: We're geeks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you see a lot of people.
Speaker 0: They're not really super into anything.
Speaker 0: You know like you can always tell because like you see like a retired person right like rims retired grandpa Right made it was super carpenter man, right?
Speaker 0: Yep Is a carpenter geek and my grandpa he was a mechanic his whole life, but when he retired.
Speaker 1: he was super Carpenter not Mechanic-ing but also with the golfing and other things, you know, yep So like the normal person has the sphere of influence the geek has these slightly water sphere of influence with some spikes Just shooting out of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as long as you got a spike somewhere you're geek.
Speaker 1: now the nerd.
Speaker 0: No, we're done.
Speaker 1: But I just want to say a nerd is Instead of a sphere.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like a line going in one direction with nothing else.
Speaker 0: Alright, but anyway, so many geeky people who are usually interested in you know technology anime Board games and such.
Speaker 0: they often look down on sports, especially like spectating sports.
Speaker 0: Like you see people Spectating NASCAR and you go.
Speaker 0: I don't like those people.
Speaker 0: or you see people like, you know sitting on their couch going Watching footballs with some beer you go and I like those people.
Speaker 0: Yeah Sort of a a cultural conflict of sorts.
Speaker 1: like you see that I think a good real.
Speaker 1: the best example of it is in high School and even in a lot of workplaces.
Speaker 1: you see that there's three kinds of people when it comes to say the Super Bowl Giants won.
Speaker 1: it's a pretty good example here.
Speaker 1: So you've got the normal people who just don't care like they they like it or they don't.
Speaker 1: they don't care.
Speaker 1: What other people think Super Bowl happened great?
Speaker 1: There's the people who care about the Super Bowl the sports geeks and the sports nerds and they care about it.
Speaker 1: That's their thing.
Speaker 1: and they're like, yeah the Super Bowl and they talk about it.
Speaker 1: You talk about things you're interested in.
Speaker 1: and then there's those people who make a point of saying Super Bowl is stupid.
Speaker 1: I hate the Super Bowl.
Speaker 1: It's a You stupid woo solo cup wave and beer drinking jock bastards and your stupid Super Bowl.
Speaker 1: That affects my life in ways that you can't even understand because they're not real and I'm just lonely.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now see the thing is when it comes to the Super Bowl itself Like I'm not a big fan of like the you know beer and pretzels commercial watching Super Bowl culture.
Speaker 0: But the football itself, you know, it's a quality sport and it's worth paying attention to.
Speaker 0: you Might be.
Speaker 0: you know, a lot of people say Spectating sports is stupid.
Speaker 0: Just play them as if there's somehow, you know two Things.
Speaker 0: you can't both do both at once.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like saying watching movies is stupid.
Speaker 1: Just make them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you can make and watch.
Speaker 0: there's no reason you can't do both.
Speaker 0: You know, there there is merit to playing sports and there is merit to watching sports.
Speaker 0: They are not mutually exclusive in any way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, we're not saying you have to like it.
Speaker 1: It's not like you have to like everything in the world.
Speaker 1: I mean I Don't particularly like watching curling.
Speaker 1: Yeah me or do I like doing curling?
Speaker 0: However, if someone says I don't like particularly like watching certain TV shows that are not sports, you know It's like you.
Speaker 0: people like some things and don't like other things.
Speaker 1: Yeah now I have my opinions about things.
Speaker 1: I mean for example World of Warcraft, I think everyone knows my opinion on.
Speaker 1: But at the same time people are free to do whatever they want.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I think it's stupid, but I think it's stupid.
Speaker 1: I don't go.
Speaker 1: well I guess I do go around telling people it's stupid.
Speaker 1: So that shoots that out of the water.
Speaker 1: but I digress do as I say not as I do
Speaker 0: but it basically I want to Try to you know cuz I actually you know some sports I care about and sometimes I don't and my level of caring sort of goes up and Down and I want to sort of try to explain it to people who may be anti sport Why there is merit to sports spectating or
Speaker 1: at least what the appeal is to people who care about it.
Speaker 1: I mean You all you geeks and nerds out there.
Speaker 1: you've been in this situation before where you meet someone you're like Yeah, anime and they're like what anime is stupid.
Speaker 1: No one should like anime.
Speaker 1: and then you try to explain No, anime is not stupid.
Speaker 1: You just got to watch cowboy Viva and and they give you all the reasons you should like anime or you give them all the Reasons that they should like anime.
Speaker 1: we're gonna do the same thing to you from the sports perspective, right?
Speaker 1: No, it's a taste your own medicine.
Speaker 0: All right, so people they like to be entertained, right?
Speaker 0: And what is the oldest way of entertaining people?
Speaker 1: Sex.
Speaker 0: Okay, the second oldest way of entertaining masturbation.
Speaker 0: That's the same as number one For some people right.
Speaker 0: the old the oldest way of entertaining people right is Hearing or telling stories, right?
Speaker 0: It's all about a good story right now Stories you read, you know, like you read your novels, right?
Speaker 0: It's a fictional story and you know because of human feelings in the way You know brains work you when you hear a story or you experience a story through some medium You are entertained in some way it can.
Speaker 0: it can affect your emotions Depending on how attached you are to the story and the quality of the story and how you relate to the story, etc.
Speaker 0: etc, right so Sports themselves, you know from a playing perspective is a is a physical competition.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it's no different than like playing a game, right?
Speaker 0: You're trying to win a game But from a spectators perspective a sport or you know, especially like a professional sporting league is Sort of this space in which stories emerge almost like a role-playing game.
Speaker 0: in many ways you create this system and People work within that system trying to achieve various goals.
Speaker 0: But anyone looking at that system from the outside or even in the you know, if you are on the inside But you take a meta view These stories emerge and those stories can often be Epic and amazing in many many ways.
Speaker 0: and the thing is not only can it generate these amazing stories But the stories are real the real people doing real things.
Speaker 0: It's not like a role-playing game where you pretend to create a crazy story.
Speaker 0: It's a real story.
Speaker 0: and the story, you know It.
Speaker 0: it the way it turns out.
Speaker 0: you're watching these games Live and the story you don't know what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: No one knows what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: It's up to real people to do something real that'll actually happens before your eyes.
Speaker 1: Live now that there are a lot of other aspects to this.
Speaker 1: I mean we.
Speaker 1: there was a Ted that Scott talked about on Friday night party line a while ago about Synthesized happiness.
Speaker 1: now mention rivalries and the drama and you know the things unfolding.
Speaker 1: Here's a real examples because talking about it in the kind of academic terms of well people want stories and people To care about this and that is good.
Speaker 1: But the visceral examples I think are what really it's like.
Speaker 1: drive the point home.
Speaker 1: So the old r.i.t I'm the r.i.t.
Speaker 1: Hockey Now well one there's also.
Speaker 1: I want to point out that for all you geeks who don't live in the northern or north eastern But also northwestern United States or Canada or the Nordic lands or Russia Russia.
Speaker 1: Well, sorry, I'm a pockner I don't know what this Russia thing I was talking about.
Speaker 1: But uh hockey is Extremely popular in many many many tech schools I mean RIT MIT Caltech even if they didn't always have the best hockey teams RIT being the exception having an awesome hockey team.
Speaker 1: Nerds like hockey a lot and they always have in the north.
Speaker 1: so there are sports that nerds like.
Speaker 1: but aside from all that it's RIT.
Speaker 1: hockey is fun and we enjoy it, but there was a rivalry at RIT until recently when we basically Ascended and transcended the old ways and moved into the real like full-on division of the NCAA Division one.
Speaker 1: But we had a rivalry with the school Elmira.
Speaker 1: Elmira was some like crap.
Speaker 1: Oh school in the middle of nowhere like one of those little colleges as a backwater middle of the nowhere school Hicks, I Mean, I wouldn't malign it too much, but it's a school.
Speaker 0: I can malign it plenty.
Speaker 1: Well, well, all right I gotta put my hockey hat back on.
Speaker 1: Elmira was a hell basically where devil's incarnate rose Periodically to attempt to defeat the valiant tigers and epic copycock at combat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: So games against Elmira weren't really that special because all myrias hockey team was pretty good, but they weren't that great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess preview, you know before we got there It was sort of like RIT and Elmira.
Speaker 0: But Elmira sort of got worse as the years went on and RIT got better and some other teams got better and other teams Like Newman were always terrible.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so as a result Normally if I just gone to a hockey game against Elmira It would have been an average hockey name would have been anything special and it would have been the same for the Elmira people when RIT went to play there, but just through the years this Rivalry kind of sprung up where both schools would think about the other school to two entities that have nothing to do with each other.
Speaker 1: There was no reason anyone from Elmira would even know anyone from RIT.
Speaker 1: most likely they're just they're so far apart.
Speaker 1: No one cared.
Speaker 1: No, but because of this rivalry the two schools would really get into it and whenever there's a game at RIT pretty much everyone from Elmira would come to RIT fill the other half of the arena and all hell would break loose and Vice versa.
Speaker 1: every time the game was at Elmira and it became like this huge deal and it was super fun.
Speaker 1: It was like having a tiny little.
Speaker 1: Imagine if you had an anime convention where half the people love cowboy bebop and half the people hated cowboy bebop and everyone knew that.
Speaker 0: No, oh Yeah, it's just people attach these these feelings to something.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like You know you have.
Speaker 0: if you go to let's say you go to see The Roman Colosseum right and there's two gladiators right and they fight each other.
Speaker 0: Well, okay, you're seeing two guys fight each other's pretty barbaric.
Speaker 0: It could even be like, you know unpleasant right, but you know Let's say one of those gladiators was your gladiator.
Speaker 0: you you paid for them Or gladiator gladiator, you know, that was your guy, you know Like just like when you play World of Warcraft and it's your avatar in there except the gladiator is your guy.
Speaker 0: It's the same thing.
Speaker 0: So now suddenly you have a real investment in the results and you start to care about it.
Speaker 0: and when you care about something The what happens to that something now has the power to affect you in an emotional way.
Speaker 0: So the rivalry between RIT and Elmira isn't a physical thing.
Speaker 0: It's a law of the universe or anything.
Speaker 1: It's not like they're fighting over territory.
Speaker 1: It's not like there's a cat point in between RIT and Elmira.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we got some fat dude standing there, but because people attach this emotional, you know We don't like Elmira, but we do like RIT.
Speaker 0: Why is just the way it is?
Speaker 0: Because it makes it more fun and it creates this fun around watching what happens and when you score and you beat them With two seconds left on the clock You scream like crazy.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's very analogous to the soccer people or the football people in Europe where you could almost say that soccer has replaced warfare in Terms of like the expression of national pride and nationalism in Europe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much at least between the European countries, you know Yeah, and many other countries around the world as well.
Speaker 1: Just not the US and also beyond that It's I mean, you know go to an anime con right?
Speaker 1: I guess anime is easy example.
Speaker 1: But all right, you go to some sort of event.
Speaker 1: We've we've seen this a lot.
Speaker 1: we should do a show in the anime day on exactly how to do this, but you're you're.
Speaker 1: you see an event and The person up on the front will yell or say something and the whole like it's not anything special.
Speaker 1: they said Final Fantasy or was it?
Speaker 1: was it?
Speaker 1: or whatever thing it is that will trigger people.
Speaker 1: and if it was just one person there Like someone walked up to you and said hey Final Fantasy you'd probably go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what about it?
Speaker 1: but if you're in a crowd and there's meaning you like, you know You're in a crowd of people who love Final Fantasy and some guy on stage yells.
Speaker 1: So how about that Final Fantasy?
Speaker 1: You're gonna get the crowd screaming back and making a big deal about it and having fun.
Speaker 1: Well Sports are the same thing.
Speaker 1: you get a bunch of people who you know are all there for one purpose and they're of a like Mind or of the exact opposite mind and it creates this kind of group experience much like watching a movie with a group of people And making fun of it and almost getting kicked out of the theater.
Speaker 0: Now the other good the great thing about sports is that you know, it's a physical thing It's the feats of strength.
Speaker 0: It could be fast paced It could be slow paced right but in in as people on the field or they're trying to win a lot.
Speaker 0: You know they and you know Hopefully at least and in there trying to win they might do some crazy things or due to randomness crazy things can happen.
Speaker 0: I mean ice hockey is on ice.
Speaker 0: think about that, you know, you look at other sports like, you know They have the basketball with the trampolines and everyone looks at that like a gimmick.
Speaker 0: ice hockey is on ice People are on ice.
Speaker 1: It doesn't get more gimmicky than that, you know, I just keep imagining baseball on ice and I think I'd enjoy it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: It's like what's gimmicky?
Speaker 0: Everyone has to stand on something super slippery and they can fall down and hurt themselves with blades on their feet wielding spears.
Speaker 1: Yeah Most gimmicky sport there is yeah, and if you spare someone all that happens is you get two or four minutes in a little box Right.
Speaker 0: I Mean during the course of most sporting events, you know Crazy things might happen like just watch the Super Bowl and watch that Eli Manning play.
Speaker 0: Look at that.
Speaker 0: Look at look in slow motion.
Speaker 0: What happened there?
Speaker 0: They tried to grab a guy.
Speaker 0: he somehow crazily Inexplicably got away.
Speaker 0: He threw the ball.
Speaker 0: some guy caught it crazily in a crazy way, but he ended up with it.
Speaker 0: and It's just like wow, that's a physical thing that oh my god I'm not editing that out.
Speaker 1: We're live.
Speaker 1: Prepare for katsukan.
Speaker 0: Well, that's I fell on my face.
Speaker 0: That's great.
Speaker 0: You know crazy things happened and it's amazing.
Speaker 0: you watch these feats of strength that people achieve in while they are Striving towards a goal and you know you watch, you know, like owned videos on YouTube.
Speaker 0: or you watch You know videos on YouTube like rims thing of the day yesterday doing pull-ups off of a you know, a crane or or?
Speaker 1: Sasuke aka ninja warrior.
Speaker 0: ninja warrior.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 1: Actually one of my favorite things and the only reason I don't do it anymore is that I have in fact seen I think every Episode of it.
Speaker 1: but the old American gladiators, I love that show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wonder if the new one's any good, but I heard some are.
Speaker 0: I doubt I'm gonna be watching.
Speaker 1: I heard that some RIT alum was on it either.
Speaker 1: I think it's a contestant.
Speaker 1: I heard he won.
Speaker 0: I gotta look into that like to look into that.
Speaker 0: but yeah, it is fun You know in a sports context or not to watch other humans achieve physical greatness or even non-physical greatness, so In watching a live sport there is always that excitement of you know They're in a tough situation or something needs to happen and then something crazy happens and you go Holy shit.
Speaker 0: that just not only does that make a great story, right?
Speaker 0: But you see live the human achieving something.
Speaker 0: it oh, it's amazing.
Speaker 0: It can be amazing.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's not always amazing.
Speaker 1: and also I mean and a lot of the other hate is people.
Speaker 1: Oh people always look at.
Speaker 1: there's almost the stereotype that jocks are into sports and nerds are into dungeons and dragons, but Hi, you know, I think that a lot of geeks and nerds out there really kind of Overestimate the difference between the football watching football nerd and and the D&D playing D&D nerd.
Speaker 1: Because if you look if you talk to a person who's really into football, right?
Speaker 1: now first talk to someone's really into Dungeons and Dragons and they're gonna tell you about the character who has a 17 strength and they're gonna debate the did the like the different finer points of controlling an orb of annihilation and Whether or not stone skin is an unbalanced spell.
Speaker 1: and well like that goes something something.
Speaker 1: Talk to some football nerds and they're gonna talk about the statistics of last year's team versus this year And this guy got traded to this guy.
Speaker 1: So I think the offense is gonna turn on this.
Speaker 0: turn on your local sports radio AM station right and listen to the people calling in and talking to the radio hosts and what these people are saying.
Speaker 1: Those are where all the sports nerds are and then go listen to like Wow radio or one of those podcasts about World of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: They're talking the exact same way.
Speaker 1: They're just talking about Wow instead of football.
Speaker 1: Yep
Speaker 0: I mean another thing is that you know, a lot of people right they I really believe that there are a lot of people in the world who are sort of built to like certain things and But they don't end up actually liking all the things that they would like simply because they don't.
Speaker 0: you know, either the it's too hard for them to get the Information necessary to realize they like it or they have some sort of prejudice against it, right?
Speaker 1: I think a good example is we've had some friends who swore up and down robot shows.
Speaker 1: suck I don't want to watch some stupid robot show.
Speaker 1: They're all stupid and then eventually we were able to convince them that hey Eska flown a and Evangeline arguably two of the greatest anime ever made Involve robots.
Speaker 1: you might say they are robot shows.
Speaker 1: However, they're good.
Speaker 1: You will like them.
Speaker 1: I guarantee you will like them you're.
Speaker 1: the only reason you think you won't like them is because you have this preconceived notion that all robot shows are like Ghekhi Ganga Mazinger Nothing.
Speaker 1: Yep, granted.
Speaker 1: You're allowed to like those shows too, but for an entirely different reason.
Speaker 0: Yes, and you know a lot of people like they watch NASCAR right and they say oh, it's driving around a circle It sucks now.
Speaker 0: I'm not a big NASCAR fan.
Speaker 0: I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna defend it, you know.
Speaker 0: But what I will say is that net there is a lot more to NASCAR than people give it credit for.
Speaker 0: and the reason they just don't know is because they turn it on the TV and they see cars Driving around a circle and it really you have to be a geek about it or look into it to find out.
Speaker 0: Because the drama is not in.
Speaker 0: in many sports At least the drama is not in the obviously visible things.
Speaker 0: The drama is in the behind or slightly behind the scenes information.
Speaker 0: And if you don't follow the sport at least a little bit if you don't you know Listen to what the story is.
Speaker 0: You're just watching the physical events without the story behind it and you're not going to enjoy that no matter how great the sport is because the enjoyment is all about the story.
Speaker 0: and like if you don't know who the racers are or what the relationship between them is or You know who has more points than who or how this points work or how the sport works or the rules of the game The drama is lost on you.
Speaker 0: I mean if you're watching a football game and You know, it's it's fourth and goal, you know And is like two seconds left in the game, right?
Speaker 0: If you don't realize what that means you're not gonna be in a suspenseful, you're not gonna be in suspense.
Speaker 0: You have to know a lot about sports to understand the same way.
Speaker 0: people.
Speaker 0: if someone's you know Comes over to your D&D game or your game of Puerto Rico or any of your you know Your World of Warcraft and you're running some you know Crazy thing fighting some giant boss or something right.
Speaker 0: somebody comes up and knows nothing about it is just gonna see the barest Visual, you know obvious things about what are going on.
Speaker 0: Oh, so you're clicking repeatedly on a box and your guys swinging.
Speaker 0: you think back and forth and there's a dragon moving around and you're Like no, don't you get.
Speaker 0: but because they don't know the drama is lost and I think a lot of people who are looked out On sports don't you know bother because of maybe prejudice or other reasons to at least?
Speaker 0: Listen to the story or try to get information about the story So that the drama.
Speaker 0: this is no chance for them to like it because they don't even put the slightest effort into Discovering the story in the drama.
Speaker 1: now at the same time.
Speaker 1: We're not saying you have to like it.
Speaker 0: I don't like anything.
Speaker 1: baseball is a good example.
Speaker 1: I understand baseball.
Speaker 1: I know about a lot of the drama going on.
Speaker 1: I understand the rules fully.
Speaker 1: I can look at a baseball game and watch it and think all right Well this and this and this and I see where other people could get their drama from.
Speaker 1: I however find no drama in it and find it Incredibly boring.
Speaker 1: then I cannot enjoy baseball unless I'm playing it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I think another important thing It's not really related to mean like.
Speaker 0: I don't like basketball, you know because you know Even though I understand basketball used to play basketball, right?
Speaker 0: It's the fact they're scoring so often that I find, you know, very little, you know, incredibly exciting situations.
Speaker 0: That's why a lot of people say, you know, basketball is only exciting in the last few seconds.
Speaker 0: Well, even then it's only exciting last few seconds If the game is really close and I really think that basketball would be better served by being just a five-minute game.
Speaker 0: Just play for five minutes and that's it and you know because you're scoring so often.
Speaker 1: or just uh Make the court twice as long and put the baskets ten feet higher.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that would be cool, too.
Speaker 0: I have no problem with that.
Speaker 1: But at the same time I guess there's also the idea that if you're gonna really decide you don't like something you're gonna hate on It.
Speaker 1: you at least learn enough about it to explain your hate.
Speaker 1: I mean Scott and I don't like World of Warcraft at all.
Speaker 1: And if you ask us well, Raymond Scott What don't you like about World of Warcraft?
Speaker 1: I have a book.
Speaker 1: I have a book ready to go just sitting on my tongue to come out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but a lot of people they'll say oh, why do you hate NASCAR?
Speaker 0: They say it's cars driving around a circle or even Wow, and that's all they can say.
Speaker 1: There's been.
Speaker 1: there's been a lot of people in conversations I've had who have agreed with me that yeah World of Warcraft is crap But they agree, but they don't have anything.
Speaker 1: they can't back that up.
Speaker 0: They'll just say yeah people get addicted to it.
Speaker 0: It's not good.
Speaker 0: It's a waste of time and money.
Speaker 0: and I'm like, is that the best argument you've got?
Speaker 0: because if so I don't want you on my team, even though you agree with me It's kind of like getting the endorsement from the KKK when you're running for president.
Speaker 1: You're like, yeah.
Speaker 1: Thanks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's great.
Speaker 0: It's like great you.
Speaker 0: that means you agree with me about something, you know, and even if I got to figure out what that is Even if it's something like states rights, which I'll say, okay, you know, but I don't watch you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz your reasons for agreeing with me are not good.
Speaker 1: but there's another very important factor here and I see this a lot in.
Speaker 1: I actually saw many of our younger listeners and a lot of younger geeks and nerds out there.
Speaker 1: you're in school and The cool thing for smart kids to do is to be all down on gym class and to hate on sports.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna tell you right now as an uber geek.
Speaker 0: See and my high school is weird cuz Smart people were also letting.
Speaker 1: my high school was also weird.
Speaker 1: The band was much more popular than the football team and our band was popular But pretty much everyone on the football team and everyone in the band were all in the AP classes, too And like all the the so-called popular clique were all like that.
Speaker 1: honors valedictorian kids.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was no see in.
Speaker 0: my class is basically people who did shit and people who didn't do anything.
Speaker 0: It wasn't people doing this versus people doing something different.
Speaker 0: Is that the people who are doing things were usually smart and people were dumb usually didn't do anything?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it seemed like the same people were doing everything.
Speaker 1: the kid who was the valedictorian Was also in the football team and also in the band and also the head.
Speaker 0: So he played a bunch of football then got any unit switch uniform.
Speaker 0: Oh, you realize you're on the field and switch uniforms again when we marched at home games, right?
Speaker 1: We there would be like six people in the in the marching band lineup who marched in their football uniform and then as soon as we broke at the end of the show if Like the opening show and the the anthem and everything they ran over to the football team and then at halftime They ran back over to the band and marched in the show.
Speaker 0: Didn't they get a little tired?
Speaker 0: Yes Did your football team lose as a result?
Speaker 1: our football team lost because no one gave a shit about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there you go.
Speaker 1: I mean look at this way.
Speaker 1: We had a football games right the curve because we had a full like stadium in our high school and this crowd.
Speaker 1: the stands would be packed Halftime would come and after the band show pretty much everyone left and that no one was there to watch the rest of the game.
Speaker 0: That's one more thing about sports.
Speaker 0: Is that You know when you're an anime fan or a nerd right and you go to a convention or something and you go to the convention Because you know, it's it's a chance to be together with people of your same culture.
Speaker 0: It's like ah, I feel at home with these complete strangers who who I share something with.
Speaker 0: We have a common interest to come and bond.
Speaker 1: I mean as we've said geeks are kind of a global entity in that all of you listening to the show Probably have more in common with some geek in Norway and some geek in Japan and some geek in Hong Kong.
Speaker 1: Then you do with a lot of the people who live in very close proximity to you physically Right and sports are very similar.
Speaker 0: when I go to like giant Stadium right to go see a game You're like high-five and all the people near you and you're all cheering and you're striking up Conversations about whether they should trade this player that player.
Speaker 0: you're walking through the.
Speaker 0: you know The parking lot.
Speaker 0: people are you know all tailgating sharing?
Speaker 1: Here's another benefit of liking sports.
Speaker 1: if you got you like anime cons, right Basically, every sporting event is like an anime con for sports geeks and there's live me depending on the sport There's a lot of them mean.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you get season tickets to baseball.
Speaker 0: That's expensive But you're going to a lot of games a whole lot of games.
Speaker 1: But the point I was gonna make before about the kid the younger kids is that there's a lot of this hate on Sports and as a result a lot of kids don't like.
Speaker 1: they try to get out of gym classes They don't want to join sports teams and they say oh, well, I only care about the academics.
Speaker 1: I don't need sports.
Speaker 1: I'm of the mind very strongly that everyone who has the ability to should receive a well-rounded education.
Speaker 0: There is a lot of evidence a whole lot of evidence that suggests that you know kids who are there.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it's a strong correlation pot and most likely causation.
Speaker 0: people doing extra things like, you know Sports and or music and such do much better in the you know academic parts of the school.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: but I think it's many
Speaker 0: studies supporting that
Speaker 1: peep and not just for sports, but with everything I think early schooling I mean up right up until the point where you have to decide What direction you're going in your life and what you're gonna specialize in or at least right up to the level of your raw?
Speaker 1: Physical mental ability and physical physical ability.
Speaker 1: I think everyone should learn a lot of Shallow depth about as much as possible in order to give them a more well-rounded Life and a more well-rounded ability to exist in the world make intelligent decisions and live.
Speaker 1: people who specialize too much in any direction Too early.
Speaker 1: I think have a lot of problems in their lives later on.
Speaker 1: Exceptions to be made for savants and crazy geniuses.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if you're a normal dude, you're thinking I don't need to know any of that math or any of that that they're sports.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be a writer.
Speaker 1: You're probably not gonna be a good writer as a result unless you're some prodigy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the classic Stereotyped nerd jock war I think is something that only exists in the minds of people who perpetrated like a second-order simulacra.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly That's been on my mind lately with this whole anonymous thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so do you wanna join to say anything else about this?
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, one other thing if you uh, if you live anywhere near Rochester, New York, all right, you're a geek and You want to see what we're talking about?
Speaker 1: Go to figure out the schedule.
Speaker 1: good like RIT athletics calm look at these schedule for Yes, unless they changed it.
Speaker 1: All right, and you can check it while I'm talking and Go see when what these schedule is for our IT hockey games.
Speaker 1: Go to an RIT home hockey game and when you walk into the hockey arena You walk into the front doors.
Speaker 1: you paid your tickets.
Speaker 1: There's a press box in the luxury box above you.
Speaker 0: Go to your left go all the way above you as in on top of your heads Like you have to walk around to be able to see them and go back to the back left corner.
Speaker 1: There will be a bunch of people there many of them wearing orange shirts.
Speaker 1: some of them are loud and scary.
Speaker 1: sit near them, but not among them and Just see what happens throughout the course of this hockey game.
Speaker 1: You'll there's a good chance You'll become a hockey fan or at least an RIT hockey fan.
Speaker 0: Wow I see hockey plays a lot more games than he used to notice in d1.
Speaker 1: Yeah Oh, that's the other thing RIT hockey, but they're not doing that.
Speaker 0: Well this year.
Speaker 1: Well that that's the thing.
Speaker 1: RIT hockey was a little different when we were there because we've told the story before.
Speaker 1: but briefly There used to be three divisions of college hockey One two and three.
Speaker 1: the lower the number the higher the skill the higher the stakes and like closer to real sports Or professional sports or people who will go on to be sports players.
Speaker 1: RIT was in division two and they were near the top of division two.
Speaker 1: They're one of the best teams in division two.
Speaker 1: division two disappeared and Teams were a long time ago into either division one or division three based on certain criteria.
Speaker 1: The criteria did not involve how good they were necessarily but other things and the NCAA is crazy And you know what?
Speaker 1: there's a lot of stories and drama surrounding how the NCAA is crazy due to a fluke and The fact that RIT does not have a football team and probably never will again.
Speaker 1: after something that happened, I think in the late 60s RIT did not have enough sports teams to qualify for division one due to an obscure rule that is designed to prevent a school From putting all their money into one sport becoming the best in that and ignoring everything else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a lot of.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of sports NCAA craziness like that.
Speaker 1: So RIT was put in division three.
Speaker 1: now when one of the best teams in division two now basically has to play against people who I'm better at hockey than a lot of these people.
Speaker 1: All right Personally, and that's not much of an exaggeration.
Speaker 1: so as a result RIT kicked the ever-living crap out of people every game.
Speaker 1: They once beat a team a team known as Newman.
Speaker 1: Hello Newman to zero In hockey.
Speaker 0: that that's like a that's a crazy.
Speaker 0: that's like a football score.
Speaker 1: It's like that Bugs Bunny cartoon where someone hits the ball in the baseball game and they just keep like cha-cha up and hitting a home run and cha-cha.
Speaker 1: The game was like that.
Speaker 0: that was That was some game.
Speaker 1: So basically going to RIT hockey games was an exercise in well sadism counting And Elementary arithmetic and also just the ritual and the thing and like, you know Here's another good thing.
Speaker 1: a lot of geeks and nerds are into the Rocky Horror Picture Show.
Speaker 1: You know that ritualized thing where everyone goes and they watch the movie and people act out and yell things at certain times And there's like this this half performance half ritual event that people do it.
Speaker 1: It's super awesome.
Speaker 1: We should do a show about that sometime because I really dig that Rocky Horror action.
Speaker 1: Sorry, but we should have someone on for that though Yeah, we should have someone who's more into that cultures.
Speaker 0: I've only ever I like seen part of.
Speaker 0: you know, I know they do this thing But I really you know, it's not my thing and I don't know all the things about it.
Speaker 1: I've been to it a few times.
Speaker 1: I enjoy it.
Speaker 1: I do not know enough about the subculture to speak as an authority, but I enjoy what it is.
Speaker 1: I couldn't do a whole show on it, but The hockey games in colleges, especially at RIT, but MIT at a similar tradition are ritualized in that exact same way and It's it's incredibly fun.
Speaker 1: I cannot stress this enough.
Speaker 1: We have so many friends who hated loud things and hated sports and hockey and we convinced him to go to RIT hockey games And they became hockey fans within about 15 minutes.
Speaker 0: There's one more thing I got to say that I think we'll end it right is that you know the the primary Entertainment and sports spectating.
Speaker 0: is the story right?
Speaker 0: and you know You can get a lot of the story from the sports pages and whatever.
Speaker 0: but really a lot of the story Isn't something you can see.
Speaker 0: watching the game itself watching the game itself is sort of like watching only the combat in D&D.
Speaker 1: Oh god.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think it's quite that bad.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like watching only the fights in Naruto So watching Naruto.
Speaker 0: Yes, a lot of the story in sports is like it is semi fictional or Dramaticized and there are people who make a living as sports writers and they basically create this story.
Speaker 0: They make up new drama, you know on the sports pages in the paper and on.
Speaker 0: you know ESPN and other shows.
Speaker 0: and if you don't you know, at least slightly dip into you know, what sports writers are Creating their their art, you know, then you're gonna miss out on a lot of what's going on and then you know.
Speaker 0: So I recommend you check out, you know some sort of sports show regularly like, you know There's.
Speaker 0: there's all kinds of things.
Speaker 0: as ESPN is a zillion podcast personally I'll listen to one which is ESPN PTI.
Speaker 0: It's actually a TV show that's on at 530 Eastern every day But it's you can get the podcast audio for free from you know on iTunes or whatever and it's just two guys Talking about.
Speaker 0: you know, they sort of shallowly, you know Cover all the sports major sports news in in a hilarious Combative way and I think it's the the closest you're gonna get to a rim and Scott sports podcast.
Speaker 0: So, you know, but check something out and then you know if you're gonna be interested in a sport you have to check out the meta information in some way.
Speaker 0: find a podcast or a magazine or Sports page not a magazine or you know, even a sports history book, you know something you gotta You know.
Speaker 0: get into some sort of other media to get the deeper information To really fully comprehend and understand and appreciate the things that you're seeing.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.