Speaker 1: It's Wednesday May 28th on rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 1: We change it up a bit.
Speaker 1: We talk about whiteout the comic and animals that suck the anime.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So you know that watchman movie.
Speaker 0: They're making uh-huh yeah, yeah, I'm not.
Speaker 0: I haven't been like I don't know interested to see any movie especially not in the theater in forever but this movie They have done some things.
Speaker 0: two things that have actually raised my interest of seeing in the theater from negative a billion to negative 999 million all right.
Speaker 0: two things that that have given me confidence that this movie well actually three things But that have given me confidence.
Speaker 0: three three things that have given me confidence The Pope right That this movie might not be to suck and will.
Speaker 0: Number one Every picture from the movie that I see every photograph online Pretty much looks like the comic brought to life.
Speaker 0: I mean the latest picture I saw was a pit.
Speaker 0: you know how.
Speaker 0: I don't want to try to spoil anything.
Speaker 0: You know the.
Speaker 0: in between like chapters one and two there's like that sort of.
Speaker 0: I guess it's an illustration of a photograph of Like the original old superhero team with like the guy in the hood, and I know all the old old guys The whatever they were.
Speaker 0: yes There was a photograph released of like you know pretty much people in costumes You know you have making and it was looked exactly like the thing from the comic.
Speaker 0: only It was you know a picture of real people huh in costumes.
Speaker 0: I'll show it to you.
Speaker 0: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: - right I have received a. well.
Speaker 0: I have found I didn't receive it a Reliable word that this movie will be almost three hours long.
Speaker 1: Whoo that you know.
Speaker 1: it's weird you think.
Speaker 1: ah that just means if it's bad.
Speaker 1: It'll never end.
Speaker 1: That's true, but
Speaker 0: I know what it
Speaker 1: means to me Is that they're letting the people making it do what they think is right because it's very rare For the producers whoever is involved in the making of a movie to let someone say yeah I'm gonna make this movie longer than you know the short average movies everyone sees.
Speaker 1: hmm That's a big risk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it because that tells me you know in order to make this movie done Right you can't be leaving too much shit out, so if they're making it almost three hours We're reaching like the limit of what Hollywood's willing to deal with.
Speaker 0: that tells me that they're leaving all the important shit in now If you know if you've read Watchmen you know that there's some particular things that might be left out of the movie perhaps a Story about a black freighter, so
Speaker 1: I imagine you've discovered that they have incorporated it a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: No, not at all all right.
Speaker 0: It's in fact perhaps better than that.
Speaker 0: There's also You know the the pros parts in between the actual chapters of comic.
Speaker 0: right all right?
Speaker 1: How could it be better than that?
Speaker 0: Hi, all right, so There's three hours of movie and there are two obvious Parts of the graphic novel that would be cut out of any movie.
Speaker 1: are there intermissions?
Speaker 0: no that would be awesome.
Speaker 0: No, that would be wicked.
Speaker 0: They're just an intermission for every single chapter like a little tiny one anyway I know what they're gonna Do is they have filmed right the black freighter and they have.
Speaker 0: they have somehow filmed the the pros parts?
Speaker 0: right those parts are going to be released on a DVD that you'll watch and Then go to the movie or go to the movie and then watch the DVD.
Speaker 0: really yeah, so there's three hours of movie But that stuff is also there, but that's not part of those three hours man.
Speaker 1: We you know luckily living in New York I'm sure there's gonna be a theater where we can see the black freighter, and then the Watchmen Maybe maybe maybe but if not granted honestly easily get the DVD.
Speaker 1: I almost feel like if I were you'd probably better off seeing the freighter after the Watchmen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it doesn't really I mean for us.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: What order cuz you've read the book?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'm thinking in general after seems better than before.
Speaker 0: yeah the thing that still you know I'm gonna keep pushing people to read the Watchmen before this movie comes out.
Speaker 0: read it before the movie cut read it again.
Speaker 1: Yes, even though it's not in the book club.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: It will be read it and then you know.
Speaker 0: I'm still worried though that if I own the comic book store or even a bookstore I would team up with the local movie theater to fucking sell the book.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's gonna be enough book selling going on.
Speaker 0: I mean when V for Vendetta came out they were selling the book.
Speaker 0: you know more than usual.
Speaker 0: You know what I would but not nearly enough.
Speaker 1: You know what I would do.
Speaker 1: I would set up a promotion where if I were a movie theater I'd make a deal with a local bookseller even just do it myself with Amazon where I would sell the book at a slight Discount.
Speaker 1: if you brought a theos ticket like a stub to my place And I'd even sell the books in the theaters.
Speaker 0: people need they do need to sell the book in the theater.
Speaker 0: That's definite.
Speaker 0: I think they should do is if you buy the book Right you get like a pass that will like you know one of the big Maybe not.
Speaker 0: you know the local movie theater on the local level But like on the big level maybe like I don't know.
Speaker 0: pick a movie theater chain.
Speaker 0: crown crown is a movie theater chain.
Speaker 1: Right I don't even know anymore.
Speaker 1: AMC I guess.
Speaker 0: so AMC.
Speaker 0: AMC is definitely a theater chain.
Speaker 0: Lowe's Lowe's is a good one too.
Speaker 0: One of those big movie theater chain companies makes a deal with DC Comics and cuz you know they're gonna read Reprinting this as we speak right to put more on the shelves, right?
Speaker 0: It's never been out of print because as soon as it goes out of print Alan Moore gets the rights back.
Speaker 0: So and then DC's in deep shit, so it's definitely still in print.
Speaker 0: so what they should start doing is the next batch You know the next run.
Speaker 0: they should slip a coupon in there Maybe for free tickets or half off tickets at a specific theater chain.
Speaker 0: You know do a little D. You know big-time partnership action going on.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: They definitely need to do something to get people to buy the book buy the book read it Amazon Jeep Right.
Speaker 1: so I don't really have a news cuz we're gonna get right into this.
Speaker 1: We're doing a dual review tonight partly because we want to get through this stuff and partly cuz a lot more you are anime fans Than comic fans, so we're very pointedly putting the comic review first.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh plus.
Speaker 1: uh I think a lot of people who are into anime will probably like this comic.
Speaker 1: Maybe well at least if you're into good manga.
Speaker 1: But before we continue I just want to point out to everyone I know I mentioned it last week, but Friday this week as in Well, this is a Wednesday episode so Two days from now, but you're probably listening to this Thursday.
Speaker 1: So that means tomorrow May 30th at 6 p.m.. In 2008 in the Kinokuniya bookstore near Bryant Park in New York City We will be there with Tokyo FM and Brian Nishi to interview Hal Cali.
Speaker 1: They are they perform today, Sen They're pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: You might notice that you might know them from my thing of the day if you're a time traveler.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and If you want to learn about them you can learn about them the same way I learned about them and watch all their music videos on the YouTube.
Speaker 1: or just come to the Kinokuniya this Friday May 30th Despite the fact that anime news network knows nothing about it.
Speaker 0: They will soon.
Speaker 1: Seriously though it'll if you're a fan of these two You'll be able to get pretty close to him because the Kinokuni is not that big and TMR pretty much filled the upstairs.
Speaker 0: You'll also get to see us if you want to see us, and you haven't seen us.
Speaker 0: so yeah I guess some people might want to see us.
Speaker 0: Okay, so we went to the New York Comic Con and at the Oni table.
Speaker 0: There are some pretty awesome books going down.
Speaker 0: Rim bought a little.
Speaker 0: uh you buy the Scott Pilgrim poster there I might have.
Speaker 0: yeah, but the thing is I was gonna buy some of those awesome books But I had ordered them pre-ordered them online.
Speaker 0: so about a week later.
Speaker 0: They showed up.
Speaker 0: one of those awesome books is Whiteout by Gregor written by Greg Rucka art by Steve Lieber alright, and it's actually two volumes of it.
Speaker 0: But rim only read the first volume, so I'm also gonna talk about the first volume now Greg Rucka.
Speaker 0: This guy is lately.
Speaker 0: He's like my favorite new writing of comics guy favorite new comic star.
Speaker 0: He's not new, but he's like my new favorite comics writer as and I discovered him somewhat recently He wrote that Gotham Central, which is all about the police in Gotham City and not so much Batman But mostly the police who there.
Speaker 0: he wrote Queen and country which is a many multi-volume series of awesome British secret agent international CIA kind of action.
Speaker 0: and He wrote whiteout which is what we're gonna talk about here now before we go any further.
Speaker 1: if you just want the Soundbite review it's a comic that I liked.
Speaker 1: oh no I mean It's really always the best recommendation you can get about something Oftentimes is from someone who hates that thing.
Speaker 1: of course that doesn't always work because if someone really hates superhero comics And then they read a superhero comic that they like odds are it's not like superhero comics.
Speaker 1: So if you like normal superhero comics you probably won't like the things that they like mmm.
Speaker 0: Anyway whiteout To sum it up.
Speaker 0: It's basically a whodunit murder mystery kind of deal, right?
Speaker 0: So there's not.
Speaker 0: you know the the if you look at it.
Speaker 0: You know from such a zoomed out perspective It's not really exciting.
Speaker 0: what is exciting about it?
Speaker 0: And I think the the best part of this book is the fact that it's in Antarctica.
Speaker 0: now the setting of Antarctica You know and I guess it's a cool setting that's not used too often especially not for murder mysteries Like many people are there You know.
Speaker 0: but what gets me about this book and actually makes me really interested in, Antarctica And I kind of want to go there now is that since the setting of Antarctica It's such a dangerous barren place with no people the setting almost becomes a character in this book Basically a character that's out to fuck everyone all of the time.
Speaker 0: You
Speaker 1: know actually it's very interesting because I might have said it with somewhat more eloquence than that But much like if you read the terror that the book I think I talked about it a while ago It's about a bunch of Arctic explorers who eventually get trapped in the ice And I don't think it's a spoiler to say that they pretty much all died because it's based on a true story and in the true Story everyone pretty much all died.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, but there's a lot of similar stories that I've you know well stories that use the same mechanism like you read a submarine story and there's always that constant dread of the Dangers of what it's like on a submarine.
Speaker 0: or you read a like tank police.
Speaker 0: you read tank police and it's like the constant dangers of.
Speaker 0: you know the cloud of bacterial gas outside or So you know people are in space.
Speaker 0: Apollo 13 is a perfect example where you know space and and the shuttle are a character in themselves.
Speaker 0: you know providing all of the Conflict for the characters.
Speaker 0: you know taking the role of.
Speaker 0: you know the villain in what you will.
Speaker 0: But this book actually has you know a villain and that is you know the murderer and whatnot.
Speaker 0: But it also has the the sort of side villain of Antarctica itself.
Speaker 0: It's not so much a villain because it fucks the bad guys just as much as fucks the good guys.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so white out the story centers around this character the main character And she's sort of like this secret.
Speaker 0: She's not a secret agent.
Speaker 0: She's like It's hard to say.
Speaker 0: she's like a marshal from the US and she's sort of like the police of Antarctica where No guns are allowed now.
Speaker 1: There's an interesting story about why she's working in Antarctica.
Speaker 1: That's I guess that deal throughout the course of the plot.
Speaker 0: That's her.
Speaker 0: You know her her personal backstory deal, but It's kind of it's it the fact that no guns are allowed.
Speaker 0: yet She has to police Antarctica.
Speaker 0: at least you know police Antarctica as far as US interests are concerned.
Speaker 0: It's so funny because they you know they keep pointing out you know all the things that you know the treaties surrounding Antarctica say you have to do and then everyone breaks all the rules all the time.
Speaker 0: well not everyone not everyone pretty much just Just bad guys and some good guys.
Speaker 1: But it's interesting because you know there's a police officer And they don't say.
Speaker 1: I mean if you don't know about Antarctica you wouldn't think like yeah, duh no guns.
Speaker 1: But they don't really say it outright.
Speaker 1: so right away at least you're reading you think cop whatever And then suddenly it's like but you think all right.
Speaker 1: She's a cop.
Speaker 1: Here's the situation.
Speaker 1: She'll just pull a gun and everything.
Speaker 1: Oh wait a minute.
Speaker 1: Oh No guns right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that sort of still ties into the the Antarctica as a character.
Speaker 0: because not just you know the the weather and Physicalness of the continent are dangerous to the characters, but you know the laws and treaties Surrounding you know this international land see also in Almost a cop-out to say the setting is a character when really it's just a setting.
Speaker 0: it is But it's a very strong setting that plays heavily.
Speaker 1: you know it is But I guess it would what.
Speaker 1: it's a comic and it's mostly dialogue and poses and such and it's drawn black and white.
Speaker 1: so I Don't know that.
Speaker 1: while the setting is very strong I don't know if it has quite as much characterization or any of those things that I'd see and say the terror.
Speaker 0: no No, maybe not, but it's still pretty there.
Speaker 0: Another thing that I really really like I think I like more about this comic than anything else is Greg Raka obviously did a shit ton of research about Antarctica like holy crap.
Speaker 0: Just did he learn like everything there is to know like about.
Speaker 0: you know the weather where all the bases are you know how?
Speaker 0: people transport around You know what countries have you know positions where?
Speaker 1: At the same Token a lot of that you could get just from reading Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean he actually bothered to do the research.
Speaker 0: you know when he puts all this information And especially interesting tidbits of the information in the book.
Speaker 1: well That's one thing that's very good about it in that a lot of the Information is just part of the story And it just makes sense and it's presented in a kind of sensical sequitur way in the story.
Speaker 1: It's not just like well blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: Here's a map blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: It's just well.
Speaker 1: They're going to this base.
Speaker 1: How are they going to this base?
Speaker 1: and the distances and what's going on makes sense in that context yep?
Speaker 0: But I mean he's telling you a fictional story about fictional characters.
Speaker 0: but the information he gives you about the setting that they're in is Information that is true about the same setting in the real world.
Speaker 0: So you can be entertained by a fictional story and learn about Antarctica at the same time.
Speaker 0: And whenever you learn about something get interested in it, and now I'm interested about Antarctica.
Speaker 1: I don't think you actually want to go to Antarctica.
Speaker 0: I do on the one hand but on the other hand.
Speaker 0: I don't Know.
Speaker 1: I mean I think part of the reason I like this was that it was a self-contained story start to finish and while there's kind of background information all this it all kind Of plays in and comes full circle.
Speaker 1: There's no loose ends nothing's left hanging.
Speaker 1: It's just a solid police a little bit procedural kind of adventuring story.
Speaker 1: That's really all there is to it.
Speaker 1: Stylistically, I mean it's really simple.
Speaker 1: It's well it appears very simple.
Speaker 1: I mean just black and white and different textures and all that.
Speaker 1: but when you read the back and he explains you know how he drew it and put it together.
Speaker 1: a lot of work actually went into the composition in the drawing and he'd like put ink and different things and then scratch it away and Do different kinds of art and all the different scenes.
Speaker 0: well I mean think about it right Antarctica is like the perfect setting for a black and white comic book.
Speaker 0: because Instead of you know and say a color comic you know you might need to draw the snow or some such.
Speaker 0: here the pages are White.
Speaker 0: so drawing snow means not drawing.
Speaker 1: yes, cuz then those.
Speaker 1: usually when I print colored comics I print them on black paper.
Speaker 0: I know sometimes they do.
Speaker 0: actually You know you'll read like a comic and like all the pages like black around the edge.
Speaker 1: That's ink on paper I know.
Speaker 0: I mean sometimes you know the pages aren't perfectly white either.
Speaker 0: They're sort of yellowish anyway.
Speaker 1: There's no black paper.
Speaker 1: There's construction paper.
Speaker 0: construction paper is cool.
Speaker 0: I like construction paper.
Speaker 0: But Anyway, yeah, I like the art a lot.
Speaker 0: actually you know it might.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: It's not very cartoony.
Speaker 1: It's very sort of you know realistic, and I think one thing I noticed I was reading it about halfway through.
Speaker 1: I said wait a minute, so I went over.
Speaker 1: I pulled out sanctuary and I flipped over into a few pages, and I flipped through this and the way a lot of.
Speaker 1: I mean it definitely does not have the gecky gah face or The gecky gah pose or any of that, but or especially there's no gecky gah hero.
Speaker 1: No but one thing that it does have is if you look at the way characters stand and The way like all the different frames are kind of put together There they look very similar in terms of it's very Cinematic and very kind of dramatic eyes the way characters stand and the way they move Mm-hmm to where I guess the only.
Speaker 1: if you just took the faces of characters from sanctuary and put them on these characters It would work pretty well a day.
Speaker 0: I definitely think that We're pretty well.
Speaker 0: Also.
Speaker 0: I noticed a lot of the paneling.
Speaker 0: You know it's he definitely mixes it up.
Speaker 0: It's like somewhere between it.
Speaker 0: You know it's not quite the Typical like you know Marvel Comics kind of boring paneling you know But it's all.
Speaker 0: it's not quite the out-of-control manga paddling.
Speaker 0: It's like this nice in-between where some pages will just have like you know like an a box of nine.
Speaker 0: You know rectangles.
Speaker 0: But other pages will do sort of more of a like a Will Eisner sort of open panel on the bottom with like three Overlaying it.
Speaker 0: and you know he mixes it up.
Speaker 0: It's it's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: I like that action.
Speaker 1: I think the best part about it was that the story escalates Really quickly and it it's kind of it goes faster than you'd expect.
Speaker 1: I mean it starts, and you know you read a typical story, and it's all right here.
Speaker 1: We go.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be this up now There's gonna be the build-up to that and then there's gonna be the action later.
Speaker 1: But it steps it up right away, and then it steps it up again right away And you get right into the thick of it, and then it's done.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I sort of figured out.
Speaker 0: It's one of those ones where you can figure out.
Speaker 1: you know the who done it sort of like three corners obvious right away What's going on at least everything, but the the the twist how are they gonna get away with it at the end?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it's sort of like I figured most of it out about three-quarters of the way through But then like a couple pages before you know the real ending.
Speaker 0: I figured that out.
Speaker 0: So it was like ah there's a. there was a second thing that sort of you know catches you.
Speaker 1: There's really only one problem with this comic what?
Speaker 1: it's a very central plot element and It's not as bad as the newest.
Speaker 1: well not the newest, but the second newest Batman movie where Microwaves kill everybody in the city or wait.
Speaker 1: No they just make steam.
Speaker 1: but in this comic the McGuffin as it were is Ludicrously just dumb like it's the dumbest thing.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: I'm glad though that it doesn't play Like the McGuffin itself like even though it's there the McGuffin You know.
Speaker 0: it doesn't play that much of a role like you know It's.
Speaker 0: it's only discussed very a little bit and then a little bit at the end and mostly they could have made a better McGuffin.
Speaker 0: I they definitely could have made a better McGuffin, but it was.
Speaker 0: it was mostly about you know the characters And you know who was you know killed all these people in such as opposed to you know?
Speaker 0: Why the why was sort of just there?
Speaker 0: because they needed a reason for the killings to happen?
Speaker 1: But let's talk about the characters a little bit because there's really three kind of main primary characters.
Speaker 1: There's the domain character the cop and I like her because she's very non-stereotypical.
Speaker 0: Yeah, her name's Carrie right.
Speaker 1: She's a US marshal okay, and then there's the other girl who she works with.
Speaker 0: She's like the secret agent from the UK.
Speaker 1: What you I believe you mean Albion right right?
Speaker 1: And then there's the doctor who is one of those like.
Speaker 1: he's the salty sea dog of the South Arctic And he's just.
Speaker 1: he's like the best friend in the Arctic of the main character And he's just like this cool doctor guy.
Speaker 1: and the three of them are pretty much the characters.
Speaker 1: everyone else is either Villain or side character.
Speaker 0: yep pretty much, okay?
Speaker 0: So there is a second volume of whiteout and sort of what it is is Greg Rucka and Steve Lieber said hey We actually have an opportunity to work together again.
Speaker 0: Whiteout was awesome.
Speaker 0: Can we do it again?
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: We can do it again and Basically what they do is they don't tell you know a Murder mystery story.
Speaker 0: they tell a different kind of story much in the same fashion, but also in Antarctica.
Speaker 1: I know that you're not saying.
Speaker 1: what kind of story is that kind of a spoiler?
Speaker 1: is it something where you really have to Read it to see Cuz I forget.
Speaker 0: But yeah, and I'm not that good at remembering.
Speaker 0: You know things like that especially in two seconds.
Speaker 1: But didn't you just read it?
Speaker 1: How do you read a comic?
Speaker 1: and then I remember that's like saying yeah?
Speaker 1: I read this comic called Superman.
Speaker 1: What's it about?
Speaker 0: fuck if I know I read it like a couple weeks ago My brain started not doing so well.
Speaker 0: but anyway, it's It's basically it's just if you like to whiteout.
Speaker 0: you'll probably like whiteout - but it for some like when I read it It just felt like slightly less Enjoyable than whiteout one, but I don't really.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: I could really put my finger on exactly Why.
Speaker 0: maybe it's because I already you know knew the characters and sort of.
Speaker 0: you know I was comfortable in the setting more so.
Speaker 0: So it was less exciting and new and fresh and maybe it seems like I mean the first comic.
Speaker 1: whiteout was really good and I think part of the reason it was good is that it Ended and it was a solid story from start to finish and there was a lot there And especially with kind of the last few panels and the little like little subtle things.
Speaker 1: I really like the last two pages But it's it's felt like it's one of those things where it's a setup.
Speaker 1: It could keep going But I feel like it really would be better off if it just didn't keep going if it just was this one story because otherwise they'd either run out of stuff or They'd have to go in a completely different direction with it right away, or get old mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically what they do is they just tell another self-contained story in an arc.
Speaker 0: And now you could actually probably read the second volume before you read the first one.
Speaker 0: But it sort of makes some assumptions that you know about the characters a little bit.
Speaker 1: it assumes that you know it's cold.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well they all assume.
Speaker 0: You know it's cold.
Speaker 0: So yeah whiteout is definitely a high-quality comic.
Speaker 0: I'm definitely putting Greg Rucka on my automatic buying list for anything that has his name on it.
Speaker 0: It's from Oni.
Speaker 0: those are the people who published the Scott Pilgrim and this bill.
Speaker 0: this volume is $14, but I can't imagine it's gonna be $14 in Amazon.
Speaker 0: It's got to be less than that right.
Speaker 1: so things of the day.
Speaker 1: What I have here is you know it's it's one thing to say all right.
Speaker 1: here's something crazy.
Speaker 1: Here's something just wacky and out there because it's the days of the internet and YouTube or if you want to see something weird.
Speaker 1: There is enough weird stuff out there to keep you say - but every now and then Something kind of goes beyond just a little bit now.
Speaker 1: We're here We're talking to Hal Cali on Friday, but of all their music videos You should probably see this one because you think oh, it's just gonna be weird and zany.
Speaker 1: right It's really weird.
Speaker 0: is this a twinkle star one.
Speaker 1: Yes twinkle star Yeah.
Speaker 0: I watched a bunch of their music videos But this song of all their songs that I want that to listen to is like stuck in my head like doo doo doo Doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 1: I don't know I really like all gaku no sushi.
Speaker 0: Doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 0: I don't think I watch.
Speaker 0: I listen to that one.
Speaker 0: I like that one a lot Yeah, but the twinkle star song is totally in my head and the music video is totally wacky And Doesn't quite do it.
Speaker 1: I think the moment I lost is when that cow comes in the cow just the slow.
Speaker 0: So the fighting the Fox turning into a cat and the gorilla with the boombox.
Speaker 1: I just the fact that despite all the craziness you get honey get used to it And then there's the cow slow pan and it's one thing to just put a cow in a music video.
Speaker 1: It's another thing to put a slow pan of a cow in a music video.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 0: You should watch at least this and then Thank You Japan, maybe you'll decide if you like these people or not.
Speaker 1: I'll probably link to the other music video too because I actually like that one in a non-ironic way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like that like I actually do like the song with the.
Speaker 1: I like the song.
Speaker 0: the music videos is wacky.
Speaker 1: Of course, all the music videos are a little wacky at least.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I gotta ask them why their music videos?
Speaker 1: I think that's the first question.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna ask him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely.
Speaker 0: All right, so I Had a hard time finding a thing of the day, but check this out.
Speaker 0: I found this webcomic right and it seems like he's about to do like a whole bunch of strips that are related Right, and this is like the strip that's starting off this little storyline and the story is right.
Speaker 0: all of the public domain Characters that Disney is used over time such as Snow White the hunchback little mermaid etc, etc, right are all hanging out in like public domain forest or whatever and They're going to the Mickey's castle to get Mickey to join them because he his copyright is up.
Speaker 0: But it's.
Speaker 0: but it's not because you know the law extended it.
Speaker 0: It's pretty funny Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I want to see where he goes with this and I think I think it's gonna be good stuff because he's got the nice Copyright commentary, but he's also got the nice, you know jokes about all these characters.
Speaker 0: It's good stuff.
Speaker 0: All right, nice simple thing of the day.
Speaker 1: So it's rare that we find an anime that is new or not new.
Speaker 1: ish at least that we both immediately like.
Speaker 0: Well, it helps that you know, it's nice.
Speaker 0: It's one of those shows where all the episodes are like five minutes long.
Speaker 0: So our attention spans.
Speaker 0: we can actually watch it.
Speaker 0: how almost all of it.
Speaker 1: So basically our anime tastes are getting to the point to where we're basically children.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, there's a whole genre.
Speaker 0: I don't know if the US doesn't really have an equivalent for this, but there's a whole genre of anime.
Speaker 0: I don't even know if it's a genre but a whole set of anime shows where the episodes are really short like Risky safety.
Speaker 0: All the episodes are really short.
Speaker 0: He pots and he moves to me.
Speaker 0: all the episodes are like.
Speaker 1: I think we've talked about that show.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: but you know, I don't know when these things air in Japan But I imagine they must have some like television spot that like these things can go in You know whereas in America if you want to see like a short cartoon thing like that You'll find it maybe is like part of a Sesame Street or something like that.
Speaker 0: or you know I get think like what itchy and scratchy would be if it was, you know real, you know.
Speaker 0: Or if there was actually like a bows of the cloud.
Speaker 0: and he showed you like one Tom and Jerry cartoon But I bring up bows of the clown.
Speaker 0: He was a frightening human being it was but even like one Tom and Jerry cartoon is almost Longer than one of these, you know.
Speaker 1: Case in point.
Speaker 1: I remember a day back in the anime club at RIT where we chose to Marathon risky safety.
Speaker 1: and the thing is there was always this debate and if you've ever been in an anime club You always have these debates, you know, sob or dub Robots or shoujo, you know all the different but one of them was always do you show the opener and closer to an anime?
Speaker 1: Every episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you're gonna watch if you're gonna show the anime club right four episodes of Try gun, right?
Speaker 0: You get the opener and close.
Speaker 0: They're pretty cool.
Speaker 0: They're good openers and closes I'm not gonna deny and you should definitely show the opener at least once in the closer at least once.
Speaker 0: But should you skip them in between the episodes now?
Speaker 1: It's you might think this is just a simple argument.
Speaker 0: Or should you watch the order four times in the closer four times?
Speaker 1: fan subbers would cater to this.
Speaker 1: to where?
Speaker 1: if you're watching fan Subs like any good fan sub the first time you watch the opener you get the translation Subtitles.
Speaker 1: the second episode has the romaji subtitles.
Speaker 1: the third episode will have oftentimes either no subtitles No, the clean opener or they'll have just the Japanese subtitles.
Speaker 1: And then if they do that the fourth will have the clean opener.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of them will like alternate or you know between the two or three different You know kinds of subtitles.
Speaker 0: some of them will put like one at the top one at the bottom and karaoke it.
Speaker 0: But you know, it's this big debate and you know What we tended to do is for watching a four episodes of a new show We would you know show all the openers and closers
Speaker 1: Actually works really well because they gave you a three minute kind of Intermission between each episode where people would talk or run out and get a drink or go to the bath
Speaker 0: And also some shows, you know mixed it up.
Speaker 0: It actually had slight differences during the openers and closers.
Speaker 0: the opener and closer wouldn't be the same for every episode.
Speaker 1: That's always except for the try gun release in the US where they must have missed that when they were bringing it over.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they took the opener from the first episode and just used it on all the DVDs.
Speaker 0: But the actual try gun opener does change every episode in the Japanese release, but not in the US.
Speaker 1: Yeah lonely a little bit It's not a big deal Rocky one.
Speaker 1: You got to watch every opening Except they change like two seconds of.
Speaker 0: I know they're such assholes.
Speaker 0: Anyway, when you're watching a show where the actual show itself is like less than five minutes long.
Speaker 0: How do you justify?
Speaker 0: Watching like three minutes of opener and closer for each episode that there's more opener and closer than there is episode Now?
Speaker 1: that was the anime club policy to show the openers and closers.
Speaker 1: So we swear show in risky safety and after you know Five or so episodes people are getting a little antsy because there's almost more open or closer than there is show Especially with the previews.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're watching the preview for the next time on the five minutes of risky safety.
Speaker 0: You're gonna watch.
Speaker 1: but the thing is we asked the club like should we skip it?
Speaker 1: and some people yelled hell Yes, good God.
Speaker 1: and other people were like no No, we want to see it.
Speaker 1: and it turned into this thing where people started yelling stuff out during the opener.
Speaker 1: Okay, it was like this mini cult meme for one night and then it died.
Speaker 1: and that was the end of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, by the way the show we're talking about today.
Speaker 1: I'm echo dobutsu Dameko.
Speaker 0: dobutsu is a Trent.
Speaker 0: Emily taught me what it means.
Speaker 0: Dameko is like, you know, Dom a it's like.
Speaker 0: It's basically means useless like no no good.
Speaker 0: and then Dovitsu is animals.
Speaker 0: So the show is the useless animals.
Speaker 0: I like.
Speaker 0: I like to call it the animals that suck because this show.
Speaker 1: maybe I should read the Description that I've got in front of me here because it serves it best.
Speaker 1: All right, each of these animals does not live up to the expectations and standards of his or her species.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much have a wolf that is not ferocious.
Speaker 0: You have a unicorn that drinks sake and is womanizing.
Speaker 1: you have a cheetah who can't run and trips over.
Speaker 0: You got a near-sighted eagle.
Speaker 1: Who's an asshole?
Speaker 1: I love the rabbit cuz he's like the rabbit.
Speaker 1: don't you make fun of me?
Speaker 1: I have all the traits common to my species solitary and untrusted.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that rabbit really reminds me of that.
Speaker 0: that Cromartie High School.
Speaker 0: That's another short show Cromartie That Cromartie High School thing where it's like mmm if a rabbit is in a lion's den and it's not dead That's some fucking rabbit You know.
Speaker 0: and that this rabbit is totally that because it kicks all the other animals asses.
Speaker 1: But this is a show that was it's based on.
Speaker 1: there was a comic series from manga life back in like 2001 written by Noriko kawara and it's Basically just five minutes of these animals failing at life.
Speaker 1: now what makes it interesting?
Speaker 1: I mean, this is a kid a kid show.
Speaker 1: It's on kids station.
Speaker 1: It's a kids show.
Speaker 1: But the animals they're not just animals.
Speaker 1: it's not like a cute anime animal rabbit who fights with the wolf or whatever.
Speaker 1: they're basically adults in Like animal suits living in the woods.
Speaker 1: Yeah There's 21 year old guy in a wolf suit and the rabbit is this 26 year old dude wearing a rabbit suit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not it's it's sort of furry in that way.
Speaker 0: But really if you watch the show you'll realize it's not a furry.
Speaker 0: It's a cute comedy that just happens to have furry visuals.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: you seem to like what's-her-name the panther girl.
Speaker 0: Oh panther girls hot yo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I like her a lot, but I also like the.
Speaker 1: oh, you know what?
Speaker 1: I think all the members of the female feline club win.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, they're all they're all good But the panther girls the best.
Speaker 1: but the show opens with the panther girl reminds me a lot of the the nuts the the serious teacher from Azumanga dive Ah But I don't know is a wolf who sucks and he's traveling with a bindle and he's hungry.
Speaker 1: and he sees a rabbit and thinks Huh?
Speaker 1: Pray good God.
Speaker 1: and he goes to try to eat the rabbit and the rabbit kick his ass.
Speaker 1: Rabbit's name was Sahara rabbits a jerk.
Speaker 1: and then from there we meet the rest of these people And they just I don't think I can express to you how much they suck.
Speaker 0: They pretty much suck at everything and it's basically every.
Speaker 0: the wolf was looking for a new home.
Speaker 0: You know, he's got a bindle.
Speaker 0: he's on the road.
Speaker 0: he doesn't have a place to live and he wasn't gonna live in this forest with the shitty rabbit that he hated and then that the Cheetah girl came along.
Speaker 0: he go or leopard.
Speaker 0: Yeah cheetah.
Speaker 0: She's a cheater Yeah, she's.
Speaker 0: Then he falls in love with the clumsy cheetah at first sight.
Speaker 0: so he decides to live in this forest.
Speaker 0: But every animal in the forest is no good at what they're supposed to be good at.
Speaker 0: You got a whale who can't swim.
Speaker 1: the whale has floaties.
Speaker 0: the whale has a floaty and it can't swim.
Speaker 1: I think my bet the favorite name of all these people those Pegonoscale yeah The shy Pegasus shy emo super depressed Pegasus.
Speaker 1: Good God He's so great.
Speaker 0: I figured the unicorn would be your guy though.
Speaker 1: See, I'd really like the unicorn too because he there's really nothing wrong with him except that he's just an asshole.
Speaker 1: He lives in the woods, but like kind of by himself.
Speaker 0: I think the unicorn is the character closest to rim.
Speaker 1: Well, he is a woman.
Speaker 0: Is the woman?
Speaker 0: I think long-haired be shown in unicorns who drink sake all the time.
Speaker 1: But is he's mad lazy I think I mean what works is that you uni Hiko the unicorn and usa Hara the rabbit are both jerks But they're jerks in different ways.
Speaker 1: the rabbit beats people up and the unicorn just messes with people.
Speaker 1: Yeah And the two of them usually well like.
Speaker 1: there's one good episode where the two of them are kind of Hanging out watching the wolf just suck and they're basically just getting drunk and talking about how much he sucks while he's sucking.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my favorite part with the unicorn and the rabbit is the rabbit.
Speaker 0: You know the unicorn goes up to the wolf and he's like, you know, he's like, okay the unicorn just met the wolf Right.
Speaker 0: It was a horror.
Speaker 0: and he says, you know, tell me I will.
Speaker 0: he's like I will listen to your wish.
Speaker 0: and the wolf is like, oh man the you the magically unicorns gonna grant me my wish.
Speaker 0: So he's like, you know, I wish you know as he wishes for like Chico right or something like that.
Speaker 1: I forget what he wishes for.
Speaker 1: I don't want to be a coward.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he wants courage because that's what he sucks at.
Speaker 0: He's.
Speaker 0: he's not a courageous wolf he's a cowardly wolf.
Speaker 0: and The unicorn is like well try hard someday and you'll you'll get there.
Speaker 0: and the wolf is like Oh, you really were just listening and not granting you ass.
Speaker 0: So then he's done the unicorn as the rabbit what his wishes and the rabbits like her.
Speaker 0: and he's like I want your horn.
Speaker 0: He's like what do you want my horn for?
Speaker 0: and the rabbits like.
Speaker 0: my mom is sick in your horn.
Speaker 0: if I grind it up I can make medicine for my mom.
Speaker 1: now then the best part.
Speaker 1: He pulls out this other horn.
Speaker 1: He's like.
Speaker 0: he pulls out this horn and he tries to give it to the rabbit.
Speaker 0: He's like, oh here I have something for you.
Speaker 0: He's like really.
Speaker 0: he's like.
Speaker 1: this is the horn of my former lover who died blah blah blah tragedy.
Speaker 1: You can have it, but it's still a little cursed if you're okay with that.
Speaker 0: And the rabbits like no, I don't like a cursed horn, but then he's like, I thought this is a spare horn It's just my spare horn.
Speaker 1: the first one fell off asshole.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it shows funny like that.
Speaker 1: I think Scott's favorite character still Takaoka the eagle.
Speaker 0: the eagle who can't who has you know bad vision is the best is my.
Speaker 0: You know, I guess I don't like him in the way that I like the the panther girl But he provides me the most humor.
Speaker 0: cuz like, you know, he's.
Speaker 0: he's not stupid and he's just sort of normal But the only thing he sucks at is near-sightedness.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, he's just sort of hanging out being cool being an eagle, you know.
Speaker 0: but like he'll dive into the water like he's gonna get a fish and he'll be good at diving and He'll go into the water to come up with a straw man.
Speaker 1: We got to make an animated gif of that straw man for the forum.
Speaker 0: We do have to use that for the book.
Speaker 1: Let's don't forget the bear of sub siblings.
Speaker 0: Well, but they're from another town so they don't suck.
Speaker 1: I know but it's great cuz I come on a I love her.
Speaker 1: when she shows up cuz her and the rabbit bond through muscles and fighting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the eagle like whenever something's going on It's like he knows like a smart thing to do like he.
Speaker 0: so he's sort of like hey, you know wolf Let's team up on that rabbit and we can get him.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, you know, that's sort of like the smart good idea.
Speaker 0: It's just you know, he's near-sighted.
Speaker 0: So it does doesn't work.
Speaker 1: I Mean, I don't know what else we can say.
Speaker 1: if you like a light-hearted cute fairly clever really short show I've you got 26 episodes of five minutes each.
Speaker 0: you could watch this whole thing in a couple hours and you'll be done with it Forever.
Speaker 0: Well unless you want to watch it again because it's cute now You probably will be because we end up.
Speaker 1: I keep watching the episodes again and again as we show them to people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is on the crunchyroll so you can watch it there.
Speaker 0: There's also a torrent.
Speaker 0: if you can help me out with that I think it's still going on my computer and a lot of it's on the YouTube.
Speaker 1: so you can just get it there though Watch out because after a few episodes, the only thing left on YouTube are Russian subtitles or Spanish subtitles.
Speaker 0: Yeah Crunchyroll has the the, you know, fully English subtitles.
Speaker 1: as much as I dislike everything The crunchyroll is stands for and ever will be they do have the episodes available for watching.
Speaker 1: So yeah, but I mean I guess if you like Ozumaga Daioh You'd probably like this show.
Speaker 0: if you like risky safety apply like the show.
Speaker 1: if you're human I mean, it's.
Speaker 1: it's not like.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna pretend.
Speaker 1: I mean we might be talking like this is not?
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is not like high art.
Speaker 0: This is not like a Kira Miyazaki level anime.
Speaker 0: This is not the best anime in the world, but it's a cute funny show with good characters.
Speaker 1: It is really cute.
Speaker 1: And I think it's really funny.
Speaker 0: I think of another thing that really makes it funny and cute is in most shows Characters are drawn like seriously and then when something silly happens the characters will.
Speaker 1: That's the best thing.
Speaker 0: The characters will super deform, you know, it's like, you know, you're watching slayers and everyone looks normal.
Speaker 0: And then you know Leon inverse gets hit over the head.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the best scene in all the slaves.
Speaker 0: yeah, then she's all super deformed with the koala action.
Speaker 0: but in this show Everyone is super deformed or at least relatively super deformed all the time because it's cute animal show.
Speaker 0: But then what'll happen is they'll un-super deformed.
Speaker 1: They'll like be shownify.
Speaker 0: Yeah They're like they'll get all serious and be shown in or like all pretty and girly Suddenly like they'll zoom in and their faces won't just be circles.
Speaker 0: their faces will actually be like sort of serious anime faces and they'd be like, oh It's just it's a good change of pace is what I would say.
Speaker 1: I'd recommend anyone who's an anime fan.
Speaker 1: You have nothing to lose.
Speaker 1: It's five minutes long.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I was an anime club what I would do is I would sort of show these maybe like, you know One or two per you know, anime club meeting like maybe one at the beginning and then maybe one like oh
Speaker 1: I know what exactly what I do
Speaker 0: in the middle of the showing - it sort of cleanses the anime pallet
Speaker 1: Music videos, I'd probably show one episode of this every, you know every week or every whatever the anime club meets.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a good one.
Speaker 1: Just one episode It's.
Speaker 0: it's a good way to cleanse the anime pallet especially if you just watch something bad like say his eyes and Jotaro or something.
Speaker 0: then you can watch one of these and be like, ah, of course, we.
Speaker 1: we did that or we attempted to do something like that way back when Aruda came out and We showed everyone the first episode of that.
Speaker 1: they thought it was the hottest shit probably just cuz it was different.
Speaker 1: Whoa, did that go downhill?
Speaker 1: There have been shows that went downhill before but that show just not that it started very high to begin with but it went Like.
Speaker 1: you wouldn't think it could get worse.
Speaker 0: But I mean you did have crazy rocket launcher action But that wasn't enough to make up for the CG worse than a PlayStation video game.
Speaker 1: I Mean at least initial D had PlayStation 1 graphics early on.
Speaker 0: I know and think about that initial D had better Animation and graphics than urda.
Speaker 1: Ah Anyway, all right, don't forget Friday this week six o'clock, you know Cooney in New York City.
Speaker 1: Yep This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Speaker 0: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.