Speaker 0: It's Thursday, June 26th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim, and this is geek nights tonight the darkness that comes before.
Speaker 1: Let's do this Well here.
Speaker 1: We are it's Thursday and like we said way back.
Speaker 1: We're continuing with the the lounge.
Speaker 1: I guess Thursdays are different.
Speaker 1: Thursdays are special.
Speaker 1: Thursdays are not your typical episode of geek nights.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're in wanted a cop-out of doing the promised book.
Speaker 0: I did not want to come bring up many excuses about people not reading not wanting to talk about all three books there But I'm forcing it.
Speaker 0: We're gonna do the book club as planned.
Speaker 0: at the end of this episode We're gonna tell you what the next book is gonna be to clarify.
Speaker 1: I was not attempting to cop out.
Speaker 1: I was merely noting that our Original plan of having a roundtable and other plans we had to do this show kind of fell through because no one actually Wanted to do that.
Speaker 0: Oh you see I actually went back and I listened to the dodgeball episode last Thursday's episode where we talked where we said that we were going to do the book club the second book club episode right now and We said very specifically that we couldn't have that whole roundtable unless you were going to talk about all three books because people would Spoil it up.
Speaker 0: the would not yeah.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: We could have had it.
Speaker 1: We would had to pick very handcrafted people.
Speaker 0: Yes, so because they're only gonna talk about the one book the round table is not gonna happen.
Speaker 1: But regardless we're going to continue.
Speaker 0: the round table might happen in the future But not right now.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do it at some point because I have a lot to say about these books and I can people.
Speaker 0: I. just the main reason I want to have it is not because I feel like I want to say a lot, but just because All these people in the front row crew can't shut up about it.
Speaker 0: I want it that one everyone.
Speaker 0: just get it out of their system all at once.
Speaker 0: Well, you can shut up and maybe read some other books.
Speaker 1: What's been happening with the Prince of Nothing is that it's read by like a group a couple people And then it gets read by this other wave of people.
Speaker 1: There's other wave of people and like six waves of this have been rolling through the front row crew and as a result The books are always topical and every time the crew gets together Someone who has just started reading the book will always get the conversation with someone who read it before Along the lines of you have no idea.
Speaker 1: all man when so-and-so did such and such.
Speaker 1: Oh wait, oh so and so does the thing I can't tell you about.
Speaker 0: Why do you think it is here?
Speaker 0: let's let's start our book club discussion of the darkness that comes before by our Scott backer.
Speaker 0: Why do you think it is that these books?
Speaker 0: I mean, we've read a lot of books in common, right plenty of them.
Speaker 0: We've read plenty of books in our lives.
Speaker 0: I mean, why is it that these books?
Speaker 0: Get so much Conversation and so much desire to have conversation with others who have read it among our crew and other people.
Speaker 1: It's weird how unhesitant I am to say this.
Speaker 1: I mean people who know me more more closely than maybe through geek nights might know this.
Speaker 1: but the rest of you I'm very finicky about all my entertainment and I generally dislike almost every entertaining thing.
Speaker 1: I'm confronted.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people act like I'm the one who's all hating on.
Speaker 0: everything is actually the one who's hating but I don't hate on.
Speaker 1: I just Note that I do not find a lot of things terribly engaging.
Speaker 0: So I guess the difference is it's mo.
Speaker 0: I think that that actually is mostly in the expression like when you don't like something.
Speaker 0: you're like I don't like that.
Speaker 0: when I don't like something I say it sucks.
Speaker 1: You go one step further.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: I say I didn't particularly enjoy that.
Speaker 1: I think it was poorly written.
Speaker 1: you say it sucks and you're all stupid for liking it and I hate you.
Speaker 1: and I had sex With your mom.
Speaker 0: I think I stopped like two and a half steps shorter than that.
Speaker 1: But yeah Well, you skip to the big finish with the mom and whatnot.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I think for one I. but like I said, I'm Surprisingly unhesitant to say this.
Speaker 1: but these books are well written to a degree that was startling.
Speaker 0: yeah, I don't know exactly what it is, but it's like What I'm reading them.
Speaker 0: It's not just the choice of words.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess it is just the choice of words technically speaking but The way in which it is written right?
Speaker 0: It's sort of like when I read a Tezuka manga, right?
Speaker 0: It's like the combination of the words and the graphics creates this sort of, you know cinematic kind of experience, right?
Speaker 0: But there's something about the way he writes the words in these books where I can sort of almost get that same Cinematic experience during some scenes.
Speaker 0: Well this I wouldn't get it a lot of other books.
Speaker 0: Just don't give.
Speaker 1: that brings up pretty much the foremost reason.
Speaker 1: I think that these are so well written the thing that really stands out and you look at like other fantasy works like Tolkien and A lot, you know that things are very descriptive.
Speaker 1: It'll go on and on about how the detail token is.
Speaker 0: very tokens very sort of flowery and prosy and and poetry wise.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah But in general a lot of.
Speaker 1: he also is very exquisite he fills things with detail that I ended up skipping a lot of.
Speaker 1: I'll admit openly.
Speaker 0: I think there's the people who go a lot more into the intro.
Speaker 0: detail There are.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to keep this show express perhaps to some certain deceased people.
Speaker 1: possibly Yeah, but anyway with wheels The wheels I want a heron blade.
Speaker 1: so much so badly what at least I dare and fear good God.
Speaker 0: heron spear.
Speaker 1: I think the heron spear beats out the heron blade.
Speaker 0: Well Heron spears the wind.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but they're not.
Speaker 1: they're very very descriptive these books and this writing.
Speaker 1: but they're not descriptive in the kind of Expected way of you describe in stupid detail the color of this and the relief here and this and that.
Speaker 1: and there were five Leaves on this tree that was almost out of leaves.
Speaker 0: Well, I think I think that is one reason where you know, I'm usually sorry I mean, I like me a fantasy book.
Speaker 0: don't get me wrong but I think a lot of the fantasy books and a lot of fantasy fandom in general is Really heavy on this.
Speaker 0: on the idea of setting.
Speaker 0: they want detail in the setting, you know What kind of they like.
Speaker 0: they like, you know, I mean look at the Forgotten Realms type stuff.
Speaker 0: Where are all the how?
Speaker 0: what's the map of the town?
Speaker 0: You know, where are all the buildings?
Speaker 0: What are the people like?
Speaker 1: Fantasy authors tend to get really caught up in their own world.
Speaker 0: They do they do but it's all it's.
Speaker 0: it ends up being more about the world.
Speaker 1: Whereas which would be fun I mean, there's nothing wrong with the story about the world.
Speaker 1: I think it's just that they get caught up in the world and focused on the world.
Speaker 0: and a lot of Poorly written fantasy novels tend to focus on the details that no one else cares about whereas in the prince of nothing Series there is a world and it is as big a world as there are in.
Speaker 0: so in those other fantasy novels that are world-heavy you know, I mean look you have this holy war marching right and There are this this giant Empire release different kingdoms and each Kingdom has different people.
Speaker 0: This is the one Kingdom where the people that wear masks.
Speaker 0: There's the other Kingdom where the guys are sort of like Highlanders.
Speaker 1: almost well well, actually we don't really need to get into this but the the nations of the world are very Explicitly and directly based upon cultures from certain eras in history in that area.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's sort of obvious Scythians and such.
Speaker 0: Yes, but they don't.
Speaker 0: actually they don't.
Speaker 0: he doesn't spend a lot of words Describing to you like, you know These are the so-and-so's from the so-and-so.
Speaker 0: He sort of just throws the proper nouns out there, right?
Speaker 0: He just names the people and he's like.
Speaker 0: he's like yeah These are those people the so-and-so people and you just you see them and it's like the so-and-so people Walked into the room with their shrank heads hanging from ropes around their waist.
Speaker 0: So it's like ah, so those are sort of more, you know barbaric kind of guy.
Speaker 1: I think part of that is that as a result you end up.
Speaker 1: you learn a lot about the world Naturally as though you were there.
Speaker 1: It's like if you were in this world and you did not know these things.
Speaker 1: you would learn about them in this kind of natural way just from Speaking and talking.
Speaker 1: and the dialogue in these books is very natural with one great exception.
Speaker 1: But that exception is callous and it's actually very which makes it very unnatural I think.
Speaker 0: the other thing is that this book right I look at the books, you know And you take like say a literature class.
Speaker 0: How do you write a book?
Speaker 0: Well, you could write a book in the first person, you know, you could write a book from a narrator.
Speaker 0: It could have an unreliable narrator.
Speaker 0: You could have.
Speaker 0: you know all these different ways to write a novel.
Speaker 0: right the way this these books are written is You have an unreliable.
Speaker 0: Well, they're not really.
Speaker 0: it's not really an unreliable narrator.
Speaker 0: It is a reliable narrator, but the narrator changes.
Speaker 0: it's always in the first person but who that person is changes and whatever.
Speaker 0: you'll go through the book and you'll be reading and say it's From the point of view of a came in a commune.
Speaker 0: then you'll see like dot dot dot and then suddenly You're picking right up and it's from the point of view of Nair and then this dot dot dot and maybe or maybe the next Chapter and it's from the point of view of Esmina.
Speaker 1: now This is very important and there's a lot of subtlety in what happens as a result because one there is no objective narrator I mean the closest thing to an objective narrator you have is callous.
Speaker 1: the nominal protagonist Even though I would argue that a came in is the protagonist of these books.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what?
Speaker 1: I'll go one step further.
Speaker 1: the Prince of Nothing series the darkness that comes before and these other two books They break a lot of the tropes of literature and that it's difficult to say.
Speaker 1: if there even is a protagonist Yeah, it is.
Speaker 0: Definitely.
Speaker 0: I mean at least in the class.
Speaker 0: I mean, there are a lot of ways criteria you can use to determine, you know, who's the main character?
Speaker 0: It's like who says there has to be a main character.
Speaker 0: this main characters They're all sort of equal, you know.
Speaker 0: Which is why I think it actually gives me a really sort of Burning wheel kind of feel or like, you know any sort of good tabletop RPG where there is no main character.
Speaker 0: It's the people, you know, the actual PCs as opposed to the NPCs are the player characters.
Speaker 0: They're all equal protagonists and everyone else is a non player character.
Speaker 1: This is where the subtlety comes in and I don't think it could have been pulled off from any other perspective.
Speaker 1: But you only ever see this world through the perspectives of the characters.
Speaker 1: You're always inside their heads.
Speaker 1: So whenever a scene is described one you're getting it from this one character's perception.
Speaker 1: So everything is kind of filtered through them and you see their experiences and most of the narration is not objective.
Speaker 1: He did this.
Speaker 1: she did that it's.
Speaker 1: I saw him do this.
Speaker 1: I see him doing that.
Speaker 0: It's weird how one second you could be in a character's head, right?
Speaker 0: You know seeing everything they think seeing everything they see see hearing everything they hear The next second you'll be in another character's head in the same scene looking at the character you were just inside of and Not in and sort of questioning like, oh, what's that guy up to?
Speaker 0: It's like I was just in his head and now I'm questioning what he's up to Even though I just was in there and I saw what he was thinking.
Speaker 1: But I guess this the importance of this is that the whole idea of Kellis and what Kellis is I don't think could have been done eloquently or with any true justice if not for this switching of perspective because you kind of everyone's perspective is flawed.
Speaker 1: and then you hit Kellis and his perspective is Perfect which is frightening a lot of the time because the world is so completely and utterly different and alien from his perspective Compared to everyone else's.
Speaker 0: I think what's also amazing about the way calluses written is that he's written so As to be so transhumanist to be so.
Speaker 0: it's like he has superpowers beyond you know, what people have.
Speaker 0: It's not something that a human being in the real world can do.
Speaker 0: It's almost beyond comprehension.
Speaker 1: Transhuman is definitely the word out.
Speaker 1: the Hannibal Lecter is very close to Kellis.
Speaker 0: yet when you're in his mind Seeing what he sees thinking what he thinks hearing what he hears you can comprehend it, you know You sir, it's it's plain as day and it's plainly obvious of what's going on.
Speaker 0: And you know, but there's actually thinking what's he's doing.
Speaker 0: yet How can you comprehend it when it's so far above you?
Speaker 0: and it's it really traps your mind in a way because you're in his head There's a brilliant scene that actually it's almost as if he is, you know Fooling you inside of his own head like he knows you're there.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'll talk about that in a second But there's a brilliant scene.
Speaker 1: It's actually in one of the later books, so I won't Speak on it.
Speaker 1: But all I want to say is that Nayer the barbarian he is awesome, but also not awesome.
Speaker 1: He's awesome in the way that mr Tokai is awesome beside the point.
Speaker 1: But whenever you're in calluses head all of his planning and like his courses of action seem obvious.
Speaker 1: in fact, they seem almost predestined.
Speaker 1: like what other choice could he have made?
Speaker 1: but then later you're in Nayer's head and he is in a situation that you would expect Kellis to be in and Nayer trying to figure out what to do.
Speaker 1: I have the same Information that Kellis had when I was in Kellis had about about a similar situation.
Speaker 1: But now I'm in Nayer's head and not only can Nayer not figure out what to do But I can't figure out what to do.
Speaker 1: Yep It's pretty amazing but in terms of fooling because you're in from everyone's perspectives one You you get very intimated with all of the characters.
Speaker 1: I mean you by the end of the especially by the end of the trilogy.
Speaker 1: I I you feel as though you know these characters in a very visceral sense.
Speaker 1: I know what see it's like I know them really well, but I don't identify them with them.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't identify with them.
Speaker 0: But well, I identify with parts of each, you know.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like I'll listen to some podcasts out there.
Speaker 0: They have like a cast, you know They have a lot more than two hosts and it's like there's no one person on the cast Which I identify with but like one person.
Speaker 0: I'll really identify with them on one aspect But I'll disagree with them on some other aspect, you know, and the Princeton.
Speaker 0: nothing's the same way.
Speaker 0: it's like Nayer his his untrustingness of Kellis and His refusal to be fooled and he's in his skepticism and his seeing right through the bullshit.
Speaker 1: I totally identify with his Barbarism and other such not identify, but remember there's a difference between understanding a character Identifying with the character and feeling as though you know a character.
Speaker 1: Because by being in their heads by being in all the I mean if it was just the whole book was from one character's Perspective in one character's head then you would be intimate with this character But it wouldn't be apparent and it wouldn't mean anything.
Speaker 1: But the fact that you're in everyone's heads you start to.
Speaker 1: there's all.
Speaker 1: there's this beautiful tragedy to say something that a nonman would say in that you'll see a character and in there will be in their head and they want something desperately from another character or they love this character and then you're in this other character's head and they love the first character and yet when you're in a third character's head and you see these two Interacting you realize what's going on, but you're powerless to stop it.
Speaker 1: Mmm-hmm, like, you know You're more intimate with the characters than any of them ever could be with each other with the possible exception of again a Scene from the third book where someone is reading a book about the ancient histories of the world You know the original apocalypse and then this is a little nod of the people who've read all three books and then Realizes exactly who another character was and what he meant and what he what he was.
Speaker 0: but it was almost too late Too late, all right, so let's let's start getting some nitty-gritty so that first I got we got to talk about Alright, let's go to some big scenes and then talk about their meanings inside.
Speaker 1: Yes, let's skip over the ones We talked about right away in the world.
Speaker 0: Did we talk about we?
Speaker 0: did we talk about the whole issue all thing in the beginning the very very beginning?
Speaker 1: I believe we did but we could talk about that again.
Speaker 1: is that if nothing else.
Speaker 1: This is one of those books where the you know, call me Ishmael the opening sentence.
Speaker 0: I never read the color.
Speaker 0: Oh, I know nevermind.
Speaker 1: What were you gonna say?
Speaker 1: Call me Ishmael.
Speaker 0: I was like I was like at first.
Speaker 0: I was like I got confused.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh, yeah I never read that book called call me Ishmael.
Speaker 1: It's like no, wait a minute One cannot raise walls against what has been forgotten.
Speaker 1: Yeah that that line is very very important.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 0: So the book opens right and basically it's the end of the world.
Speaker 0: But it's it's they call it the end of the world.
Speaker 0: It's an apocalypse, right?
Speaker 0: But it's not the real end of the world where everyone dies.
Speaker 0: It's just lots of horrible shit going.
Speaker 1: It's almost like in a way this book begins where at the point where a lot of fantasy books would skip.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see that's one of those things where I'm always upset with pretty much every fantasy trilogy.
Speaker 0: I mean you read the Lord of the Rings but all the big Unpowered stuff with hundreds of dragons and hundreds of balrogs and tons of wizards and all that craziness happened way before.
Speaker 0: I Disagree with your idea that those books would be good because I don't think I'm not saying they would be good.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying I always want them.
Speaker 0: Yeah You want them because the good books you want that make you want those other books that aren't bad.
Speaker 1: You want that.
Speaker 1: you really do you want that?
Speaker 0: No, but I will give you a book.
Speaker 0: you want that.
Speaker 1: Yes, but I will give you a book that will make you realize that that is not price of dragon lands book.
Speaker 1: In fact, I was going to say the dragon lands books probably notice.
Speaker 0: I don't like those books.
Speaker 1: Those books are some of the worst Good god.
Speaker 0: Well, they're no.
Speaker 0: Ethan from Guy goes down a hill in a sled and hurts himself.
Speaker 0: No, it's not okay.
Speaker 0: Yes, so so check it out.
Speaker 0: It's like almost the end of the world.
Speaker 0: these people King from a giant awesome Kingdom has a castle hidden away and he runs away to that castle the citadel of Isha.
Speaker 1: I'll succumb during the height of the apocalypse.
Speaker 1: exactly no army of inhuman strength.
Speaker 1: It's scaled it's right and it's really.
Speaker 0: it's really subtle because they put the years in sort of like these headlines cuz 2147 year of the tusks the mountains of demerara right demo.
Speaker 0: Ah, yeah So but like at first I was like, you know, cuz it's not it's not a hue It's not an earth, you know year system.
Speaker 0: So I wasn't sure.
Speaker 0: I'm like, is that the year?
Speaker 0: does they measure it in days?
Speaker 0: What's there?
Speaker 0: What's their system for measuring these things?
Speaker 0: You know, I'm like, maybe it wasn't actually a thousand years later.
Speaker 0: Oh, no It was a thousand years later.
Speaker 1: because I think we said this when we're selling the book to you But the fact that the second chapter starts late autumn 4109 year of the tusks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and because I was thinking oh, maybe maybe it's sort of like a Chinese thing Where it's here at the tusk The next year is like, you know year of the horn and then the year after that is year of the tail.
Speaker 0: But I was like, you know exactly 2,000 years later it's not again and like.
Speaker 1: it wasn't necessarily confusing.
Speaker 1: but there was a moment of wait a minute when Mo you start to realize that mo Angus was Kellis's father Because mo Angus went out and he traveled and he you know He made nayer what he was.
Speaker 1: and then Kellis runs into nayer and there's again that brilliant scene where nayer sees Kellis he sees mo Angus.
Speaker 1: Yep And he's he's as confused as I am All right.
Speaker 1: So what I then went.
Speaker 1: but then at the same time then right along right there You see Kellis seeing nayer and realizing what right away that Mo Angus has trained him.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: He knows what I am Because he's they're talking about the trackless step and such right all the trackless steps.
Speaker 1: I think we need to talk a little bit about the track.
Speaker 0: And the thing is is when you know Kellis is walking down his trackless step, but then he sees that all of his tracks That this mayor has been put on his tracks by mo Angus That's like ah, he'd conquered the darkness that came before he believed.
Speaker 1: but then mo Angus came before and throughout the whole first book You always see this kind of conflict Possibly the only conflict at all within Kellis Which is I am following this path that my father laid out before me.
Speaker 1: Did my father come before?
Speaker 1: do I have any choice in the matter, but it's interesting because he's not questioning it.
Speaker 1: He's not thinking do I have a choice in the matter?
Speaker 1: He's thinking I am following this path.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's it's.
Speaker 1: it's very strange how he how he can note realize that he might have an option But yet he accepts that he has no options.
Speaker 0: Yep I was gonna say something awesome.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So yeah, so the title of the book the darkness that comes before so clever So clever, I mean at the first you think oh the darkness that comes before it's probably you know Some evil guys coming up doing some evil bad dark followed by the other things.
Speaker 1: you can even think it was something straight up.
Speaker 1: the darkness that comes before is the Apocalypse before the rebirth in all sorts of ways.
Speaker 0: Yep But no the the theme of Kellis and the Danie and the whole deal is you know that what comes before?
Speaker 0: Determines what comes after and not vice versa.
Speaker 0: Cause and effect.
Speaker 0: you don't have effects causing causes its cause followed by effect.
Speaker 0: You are come before the cause Control the causes are the causes know what the causes are then the effects.
Speaker 0: you own them you you know, so the darkness that comes before is a dark thing that Controls the causes.
Speaker 0: it comes before Everyone else's causes and therefore determines the effect.
Speaker 1: and it's the darkness merely because if you can't see what came before You cannot know what will come after.
Speaker 0: you can only guess it's not Really dark because it's evil.
Speaker 0: It's dark because you can't see it.
Speaker 1: You can't see it as I can.
Speaker 0: you see you're mastered by What do you see?
Speaker 1: What do you see?
Speaker 0: What do you see?
Speaker 0: But There any what do you sees in the first book?
Speaker 0: I forget.
Speaker 1: Yes but anyway Think about this for a minute before we even go any further.
Speaker 1: because what makes these books so appealing is they bring up Very difficult very complex issues and Like most of my favorite literature they give you get no answers you get no.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, the answer is this or this is the moral.
Speaker 1: the moral is well, that's what happened.
Speaker 0: Not only do you not get much answers on you know, the philosophical sense But you don't get a great deal of satisfaction in the literal sense either.
Speaker 0: I mean set you up with all this shit.
Speaker 0: You know a commune can cast wicked crazy spells of death dealing.
Speaker 0: Hey, you know, there's like, you know this consult.
Speaker 0: that's kind of evil and possibly scary Like look at a came in right?
Speaker 1: You don't even know that.
Speaker 1: the only indication you have that he is as powerful as he might really be is That there's a few scenes where someone puts forth some indignity upon him and He just thinks to himself that he could destroy this entire place and walk through the ashes of what remained.
Speaker 1: It's kind of.
Speaker 0: it's kind of weird because at first in the early part of the book, right?
Speaker 0: He's in that town and He's sort of he's spying around right in the in the town where the Scarlet Spires sort of own Ah with with what's his name that spy who gets?
Speaker 0: Shanked right gets poned right?
Speaker 0: So at that point I sort of felt like a Was sort of like a weaker, you know mage of sorts, you know that he didn't seem like he was such a powerful guy.
Speaker 0: It seemed like he was sort of spying staying hidden.
Speaker 0: He was scared of the Scarlet Spires coming down on him, you know.
Speaker 0: So I didn't really understand, you know, just what his power was You know any the nightmare thing sort of made him feel kind of weak like, you know, he has this big weakness.
Speaker 0: But you know as they're like, you know, you know, the gnosis is the serious business.
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh So it is Okay but seriously think about the idea of causality and that's what these books are in many ways about.
Speaker 1: if Everything is a product of the things that came before it then is there any possibility of free will or options?
Speaker 1: because I mean If one thing begets another thing and another thing begets another thing and you know I hit a ball and the ball rolls down hits another ball and the ball moved because I hit it.
Speaker 1: and I hit it because electrical impulses in my brain and that brain exists because of millions of years of evolution and all the way back is There free will and can there be free will?
Speaker 1: Mmm, and this is a book that addresses that straight up.
Speaker 0: Yep, and the thing is is whether there is free will or not, right?
Speaker 0: Some people are able to see what's going on and other people can't see what's going on.
Speaker 0: Well, they can.
Speaker 0: perhaps the people that can see, you know Perhaps they can actually.
Speaker 0: maybe they have free will and others do not and perhaps they control the wills of others or Maybe just appears that way because they can see what's going on.
Speaker 1: Well that definitely there is.
Speaker 1: the one thing I really wish we could talk about more is the Dunyane Themselves because it isn't until the second book where we learn in somewhat frightening detail Exactly how the Dunyane came to be the way they are.
Speaker 1: and very fries pretty frightening neuro puncture.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty scary.
Speaker 0: I mean This is I think I think that the training with the faces was even scarier.
Speaker 1: Yes, but this is the kind of thing where a typical fantasy book would just kind of gloss over that or just Oh wizard Did it.
Speaker 1: but no in here it is explained Scientifically to a degree that is frightening because it's so plausible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's it's pretty plausible.
Speaker 1: It's not super plausible.
Speaker 1: It's as plausible as Hannibal Lecter is not not not the Dunyane themselves But the experimentation and how they learn that.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that is plausible.
Speaker 1: I guess it is modern science and especially as time goes on could probably do things like that.
Speaker 0: Probably, you know, I wouldn't that might not be might not be able to have the same effect.
Speaker 0: But you know, it could still be there.
Speaker 1: but at the same time what if we could prove the inner?
Speaker 1: What causes the interactions of the brain to be the way they are or what the seat of seemingly freewill consciousness is?
Speaker 0: That's the thing that always that they keeps tearing me is that you know People, you know callous, right?
Speaker 0: He can see what's going on and most of what he does Right when he's.
Speaker 0: but it looks like he's controlling other people and you know, sort of owning them Really?
Speaker 0: All he's doing is just telling them what he sees He's like, you know, I see that, you know, these are all these causes and therefore this effect is gonna happen.
Speaker 0: So he just tells people the situation that they're in.
Speaker 0: Realize they're in.
Speaker 1: he only does that against very weak-minded people or like like in the beginning that trapper or people that he's already Weakened and he needs to finish do the critical.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, yeah but I mean he'd eat.
Speaker 1: most of the time.
Speaker 1: the way he tricks people is simply by appearing to them by seeing what they see and Appearing to be exactly what they want the most.
Speaker 0: Yeah that too or what a lot of time.
Speaker 0: He just you know Is that he just points out to people what they really are thinking that they won't admit to themselves that they're thinking.
Speaker 1: But no, he doesn't do that that often.
Speaker 0: He does it kind of often.
Speaker 1: Not really not as often as you think he does it but most of the scenes where he does that and it tells someone You know the truth that they refuse to admit to themselves or the truth that they desperately wanted someone else to confirm Those are his killing blows.
Speaker 1: Those aren't?
Speaker 1: he builds up to that by intubating himself by by answering the question What do you see to himself and then doing exactly what he needs to do?
Speaker 1: Because by seeing Kellis through all the other characters perspectives, I would like several times I forgot what he was.
Speaker 1: I was completely fooled by him Like I'd be reading from a cameos perspective resume as I was also fooled many times as well.
Speaker 1: I'd be like, ah Kellis Yeah, but wait a minute.
Speaker 1: It's Kellis.
Speaker 1: God damn it.
Speaker 1: Haha he got you and but the thing is I what I love so much is that that happens to nayer and His reaction is game theory.
Speaker 0: Perfect is exact.
Speaker 0: But I would you know, despite I wouldn't act like nayer 100% Obviously, you know with the the violence and the the Breaking of horses, but I'm there score earth or whatever Horses, I would not be doing that action But I would definitely be treating.
Speaker 0: I could see myself treating Kellis the same way.
Speaker 0: basically I'm why don't you believe anything?
Speaker 0: I say I'm always right because you know, he tells him what he sees and what he sees is Right.
Speaker 0: He's like because if I don't believe anything you say that even if you're right It'll be impossible for you to deceive me and that's the you know game theory.
Speaker 1: if you can't make an informed decision or a decision Is arbitrary then your only logical course of action is to make entirely random Decisions so that no one can second-guess you.
Speaker 1: Yep And as a result nayer starts trending more and more toward insanity and the brilliant thing.
Speaker 0: And I think this is hinted at because he just doesn't want Kellis to to own him.
Speaker 0: You know Kellis sees how it's gonna play out.
Speaker 0: nayer says I can't let it play out that way.
Speaker 0: I don't want it to be right this One.
Speaker 1: he doesn't care about the holy war or any of these people there.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well, he cares about himself.
Speaker 1: He cares about one thing.
Speaker 0: is that spoiled in the first book If we say what it is that he wants to murder Mo Angus, is that in the first book?
Speaker 0: I think it is in the first book.
Speaker 1: Yes, that is definitely in the first book.
Speaker 0: Okay, definitely is.
Speaker 1: Despite his dislike of Kellis He doesn't care about these people because the skill then D are one of my kind of like how the orcs are Luke Crane's favorite race in burning wheel.
Speaker 1: I love how Intricate and I guess it the way the non men would describe it beautiful.
Speaker 1: Well, this is Andy are.
Speaker 0: this is why the prologue is so important.
Speaker 0: in the prologue, right?
Speaker 0: He treats that woodsman like shit, basically, right?
Speaker 0: He just bowls him over and then it gets owned by the non man, right?
Speaker 0: Does the non man own him before or after the woodsman?
Speaker 0: It doesn't really matter.
Speaker 1: It's after the woodsman.
Speaker 0: Okay?
Speaker 0: He's treating you and then you see him.
Speaker 0: go through all these other people, you know, the main characters Akame in there as minute everybody right and he's treating them like the woodsman.
Speaker 0: It's just taking a lot longer.
Speaker 0: He's just like ah, it's not job And you saw the woodsman before.
Speaker 0: but then You think of the non man and you're like is one of these people gonna get him like the non man got him?
Speaker 0: Maybe Nair is gonna be like the non man not just Nair.
Speaker 1: What about confess?
Speaker 1: Yeah Because confess is also it.
Speaker 1: well all the characters are fascinating because they're they're three-dimensional to the to a ludicrous extents and Conf.
Speaker 1: I love the scene.
Speaker 1: confess is a product of some sort of defect of birth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that might be from the second book.
Speaker 1: I don't remember off-hand I don't really remember anything but there that I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: I couldn't even say who my favorite character is.
Speaker 1: I mean I identify the most with the K mean because he's the one person who is earnest and forthright.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't identify.
Speaker 0: Identify with you know, as I've said like probably for the third time Nayers, you know skepticism such.
Speaker 0: I identify with a communes You know, but when he's not even he's not going crazy and having nightmares, you know He's sort of.
Speaker 0: he's actually sort of level-headed and sort of you know, cool with it.
Speaker 1: But is not Nair a product of what moe Angus did to him coupled with his upbringing?
Speaker 0: yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: if the skill then D culture came before then the Fact that Nair is does the things he does can almost be excused by the fact that.
Speaker 1: did he have any choice?
Speaker 1: Yep Well, I mean, but then again moe Angus showed him that he had a choice and that's the fact.
Speaker 0: it is a commune.
Speaker 0: Just uh, you know the what the night.
Speaker 1: That's.
Speaker 1: the fascinating thing about Nayer is that he didn't realize that he had a choice and all moe Angus did was show him that the step is trackless that he could that he had a choice that He did not have to be what he was and as a result, I mean before that he was not a good skill Vandy He was a mediocre skill Vandy at best and his father didn't seem to have a lot of respect for him.
Speaker 1: After moe Angus showed him what you know that the truck step was trackless that he had options he went with those options and then he saw the result of that and he was so overcome with shame and Fear and all these emotions that he kind of his only possible Reaction was to be the best skill Vandy he could be.
Speaker 1: and he does these things to overcome his internal shame fear and doubt.
Speaker 1: So it's like he's smart enough to not be a skill Vandy But he's trapped by what the skill Vandy are and the promise of if you do these things You'll be respected by these people.
Speaker 1: I want to be respected by these people again.
Speaker 1: I must do these things and as a result, he does them he becomes skill Vandy more So than any other skill Vandy ever was or is I think in the first book.
Speaker 0: that is the trackless step message is the one Translate translates most into the real world.
Speaker 0: You know the modern real world today because I see people all over the place, right?
Speaker 0: you have problems or just want things and There are many other many things they can do.
Speaker 0: the step is trackless yet They block out certain options for you know, not any real reason.
Speaker 0: it is for psychological reasons.
Speaker 0: They they limit themselves to.
Speaker 0: you know, I can't.
Speaker 0: that's not something I can do.
Speaker 0: That's not something I can do and usually the things that they just refuse to do for who knows why are probably the best ways for them to get what they want and have things go nicely.
Speaker 0: and You know you see Nayer is in that same sort of situation that you know at when he's before Moangis comes that a lot of people I meet in everyday life are in where you know, they want certain things But they don't realize that there are other ways they could be going about it and just something about their minds Sort of like, you know just cancels out those options.
Speaker 0: then Moangis says, you know, you can do these options and suddenly he's like, oh Shit, I could do these other things.
Speaker 1: All right Let's go off on.
Speaker 1: let's talk about a cup because there's a lot of big scenes that I can talk about Talk about what someone we haven't talked about at all The Emperor xerius.
Speaker 1: Okay, so xerius and all the people surrounding the Empire.
Speaker 1: It's fascinating and wonderful and I love these characters Even though I despise everything they do and everything I say is something I'm actually sort of Unclear about right?
Speaker 0: So is it like the Empress is his mom, right?
Speaker 0: He doesn't have a wife.
Speaker 0: There's no wife Empress.
Speaker 0: No, there's no Emperor cuz he was sort of okay cuz it was sort of like unclear at times.
Speaker 0: cuz like, you know His mom is old.
Speaker 0: His mom is younger.
Speaker 0: He's got the house.
Speaker 1: Now that I think back.
Speaker 1: I don't really remember.
Speaker 0: He's got the hots for his mom.
Speaker 1: That family is full of incest.
Speaker 0: it is full of incest But it's totally I'm.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like the way that the characters interact throughout in the different like scenes throughout the books.
Speaker 0: I can't really exactly tell.
Speaker 0: the relationship seems to sort of change almost randomly which I guess fits because those people are insane.
Speaker 1: Yes They are But they're a product of lots of inbreeding and not the good kind.
Speaker 0: lots of inbreeding and lots of power results in no good.
Speaker 1: But at the same time like the see I hinted at this when we were selling this book.
Speaker 1: Confess came out of that somehow, but he at the same time confesses fucked up.
Speaker 0: He is but he's not as fucked up as serious.
Speaker 0: He's.
Speaker 0: at least he's smarter than serious.
Speaker 1: No, no, he's not.
Speaker 1: That's the problem.
Speaker 1: in
Speaker 0: some ways he is because
Speaker 1: the thing that's so wonderful about the scene I hinted at would when confess returns victorious from the war with the skill Vendi and He is standing before his uncle the Emperor of the Empire of the Nansarian and he's you see in his head and he's thinking I Should kill my uncle right now.
Speaker 1: My troops are all lined up.
Speaker 1: They'll support me and the whole time he's thinking so should I stab him in the neck and Or and then just rush forward?
Speaker 1: should I stab him in the gut?
Speaker 1: Well, how exactly should I go about this?
Speaker 1: and you see and then the Emperor's perspective and he's doing all these things and you see that scales Knows what's going on.
Speaker 1: scale see?
Speaker 1: I say scales.
Speaker 0: Anyway, what it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: That sounds right in my head.
Speaker 1: I never looked up how it's like.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think like scales better what it doesn't matter they that there's so many proper nouns in this book and only some of them have pronunciation guides and On a sword and bore is one of the best words.
Speaker 0: I think it's on a suit in board on a certain bore.
Speaker 0: I think it's on a certain bore.
Speaker 1: on a certain bore sounds on a stupid.
Speaker 0: I think it sounds more Kingly.
Speaker 1: I think on a certain bore sounds more kingly now.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway that I like that word though.
Speaker 1: I do like I love these books.
Speaker 0: That's another thing is that he's really got the kiki booboo going on with his proper nouns.
Speaker 0: You know, if you know what I'm saying, he's totally got the synesthesia going on.
Speaker 0: I'm like on a certain bore is is the ancient king right?
Speaker 0: and that sounds like the name of an ancient king.
Speaker 0: it really gives you an ancient king feeling, you know, and and Nayer Erskyothas is a very Barbarian sounding kind of name and it gives you the synesthesia of sort of, you know, grrr and the kah of barbarianism.
Speaker 0: So it's like even though he seems to have chosen like, you know a base almost seemingly random proper nouns Completely made up.
Speaker 0: They really have a strong, you know sounding even though they're not based in Latin roots or anything Consistent within the cultures.
Speaker 1: that yeah brought them out within the books themselves.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's another thing.
Speaker 0: like all the Nansurium proper nouns are sort of you know Similar like you've got zinnimis and xerius and khanfass.
Speaker 1: those, you know Those all those words sort of feel like they're from the same culture the same language especially because you know that a lot of these languages were related to each other and the nations all came out of a very natural history.
Speaker 0: yet in the north this place is named like, you know, Ishuall and Golgotharoth.
Speaker 1: Golgotharoth.
Speaker 1: I'll have to get to that in a minute.
Speaker 0: I don't know how much Golgotharoth is in the first book.
Speaker 1: Not enough.
Speaker 1: Not enough Never you mind the arc of the skies.
Speaker 0: There is not enough Golgotharoth.
Speaker 0: This might be a spoiler.
Speaker 0: There is not enough Golgotharoth in the three books They taught you with that shit.
Speaker 1: Well I'll say this the first book.
Speaker 1: I remember I started reading it and it hints at the Apocalypse is going to happen again.
Speaker 1: All right, I'm fine with that.
Speaker 1: I'm reading Oh a holy war starting.
Speaker 1: that's gonna be on the way to the apocalypse.
Speaker 1: And then I remember Alex says just keep reading.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna tell you where the first book ends.
Speaker 1: You won't be happy but you know, the first book ends with all right.
Speaker 1: The holy war is About to begin.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean think about halfway through the book They show you.
Speaker 0: they show that the reader at least.
Speaker 0: yes, the consult is real.
Speaker 0: Here's the crow demon.
Speaker 0: and then at the end of the book It's like Akavian knows the consult is real.
Speaker 0: and then they end the book and you're like, ah fuck you Fuck you.
Speaker 1: It's like it's like when you're climbing breakneck Ridge where you see the peak, you know, like, all right I'm almost there.
Speaker 0: Because our listeners know breakneck Ridge.
Speaker 1: Yes, but I'm going to explain it.
Speaker 1: So you get to the peak but then you look up and there was another peak set back that you couldn't see from the ground.
Speaker 1: And there it is.
Speaker 1: I'll climb that peak and when you climb that peak There are two more peaks.
Speaker 0: But yeah, they totally.
Speaker 0: it's like the consult is obvious it's.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: they're basically Obviously bad.
Speaker 0: that the obvious bad evil guy.
Speaker 1: but at the same time what they are What they want and what they are compared to what?
Speaker 1: The no god is.
Speaker 1: and what you mean mug for our log father.
Speaker 0: Talk about an evil name.
Speaker 0: Look at that synesthesia going on at the same time.
Speaker 1: I don't I don't know what to think about the no god.
Speaker 1: But again, that's something we can't.
Speaker 0: I know what to think about the no god.
Speaker 0: At least I think I do.
Speaker 1: I think I know what I saw.
Speaker 0: I think I know what I saw too.
Speaker 0: Perhaps some like sarcophagus the tornado around it.
Speaker 1: so here's the problem the.
Speaker 1: I guess the a lot of the Academic points that I would really like to discuss about these books require that you have read all three books.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not going to say.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, we could just talk about it spoilers whatever because it's not one Comprehension impossible without having read.
Speaker 1: Yeah, indeed and beyond that the this is like cowboy bebop.
Speaker 1: I could not spoil some of the things that happened.
Speaker 1: I would not feel right in doing so.
Speaker 1: No, I wouldn't feel right because I assume you've read the first book.
Speaker 1: That's scene that I was talking about where confesses.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna murder the at my uncle.
Speaker 1: I'm going to become Emperor and how Elegantly.
Speaker 1: What the I mean?
Speaker 1: up until this point I'd pictured serious and looking a lot like Aladdin the king in Aladdin.
Speaker 0: I Didn't picture serious like.
Speaker 1: I just picture him looking that way.
Speaker 1: I don't know why this Bumbling crazy.
Speaker 0: I think I pictured him more like Xerxes from Civ 2 But anyway, I don't know why.
Speaker 0: maybe it's the exes.
Speaker 1: the exes doesn't look anything like Xerxes.
Speaker 0: Yeah I picture you know I picture con fast as like one of those Roman guys with sort of like the close curly fro and like you sort of like at the white and gold going on.
Speaker 1: and he's Is a man who exemplify.
Speaker 1: if you had it if he was a burning wheel character his trait would be able to sneer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the other thing is that if you actually read the descriptions of these characters, like I sort of always messed up reading them I do that in a lot of books.
Speaker 0: actually It's sort of my fault is I don't the Descriptions of what characters look like.
Speaker 0: I sort of come up with what the characters look like based on like.
Speaker 0: I sort of apply a look to their attitudes Rather than actually reading the descriptions of what they look like at the same time.
Speaker 1: They're looks exactly like his attitude.
Speaker 0: Well, that's true.
Speaker 0: But I don't think anyone's there's not gonna be too much dispute about what nair looks like.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know conference is a beard.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize that till the third book.
Speaker 0: Good God Yeah, it's like, you know, cuz I just sort of pictured him is like, you know in the way I sort of thought he acted.
Speaker 1: actually that's an important point.
Speaker 0: I keep me giving off and crazy tangent.
Speaker 0: That's how this book is.
Speaker 1: but when we were talking about how you see things from different people's perspectives and all that the reason that these books are so descriptive and if they don't fall into that trap of Describing exactly the intricate design of the language on the sword than the blah blah blah blah that no one cares about except fantasy book like super fans is that the descriptions are often very vague very subjective very Transient.
Speaker 1: they jump around a lot and the reason for this is because again, we see everything through other characters heads.
Speaker 1: So You when you experience a scene Despite the fact that you get less objective information than you might expect In fact, like when you describe a battle or a fight in these books So you're reading about a scene where two characters meet or when two characters sitting around a fire.
Speaker 1: There is very little actual descriptive text saying what colors things are what things look like where people are.
Speaker 1: All the descriptive text is The impressions.
Speaker 1: it's as though you were there.
Speaker 1: You are the character that currently has the point of view and you were experiencing things the way a real person experiences things this kind of Train of thought stream of consciousness like you don't.
Speaker 1: the description when you meet someone is not.
Speaker 1: He was this tall and he had a beard.
Speaker 1: if you walk into a room.
Speaker 1: He was a man who scared me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you walk into a room and you say hi to someone you don't suddenly You know measure them weigh them, you know, you know calculate like how how hairy they are Like it colors their eyes Realistic and that you see what a real person would see.
Speaker 1: a lot like a lot of times a character.
Speaker 1: You'll miss a whole bunch of what's going on because the character in whose head you were was not paying attention.
Speaker 1: and you weren't paying attention because you were following them and they were Thinking about something or like.
Speaker 1: they see something and they fixate on it.
Speaker 1: Then they miss what the person just said or they miss something.
Speaker 0: that happened Actually a lot in the first book a lot more than in the second and third books.
Speaker 0: I found myself reading going back and reading again and finding I didn't actually miss anything.
Speaker 0: It just wasn't told to me and that's that alone.
Speaker 1: If nothing else.
Speaker 1: that is the brilliance of this writing.
Speaker 1: That is what makes our Scott backer I a writer among writers.
Speaker 1: for me is that he can write a book that is so Exquisitely immersive and so wonderfully.
Speaker 1: you feel as though you see everything like it's again.
Speaker 1: it's an example from the second book, but there's a gigantic battle in the course of the Holy War and The battle is described and you feel as though you are standing right there Next to the general in charge of the entire army watching
Speaker 0: it from on top of him.
Speaker 1: You feel as though you see every detail.
Speaker 1: you're there You were actually there and yet if you actually read it like paragraph by paragraph or backwards Almost nothing is described.
Speaker 1: It's all flashes and impressions and it's.
Speaker 1: it's perfect.
Speaker 1: It's hard to describe it with it.
Speaker 1: Just you have to read it.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't think I would even do it justice by reading an excerpt.
Speaker 0: No No reading any Excerpt.
Speaker 0: the only things you can really read from this book to impress people like the quotes the beginning the chapters which are all awesome.
Speaker 1: That is another brilliant part of these books.
Speaker 0: Well, how a lot of books do the shtick of putting quotes at the beginning of the chapter.
Speaker 0: some books use quotes from other real Books.
Speaker 0: some books use, you know Quotes that are sort of relevant to the chapter at hand and this does that somewhat.
Speaker 0: but they you this book does quotes and most of them are either from Fictional books of the past of the world.
Speaker 0: They're books that exist within the book.
Speaker 0: So it's like, you know, there'll be a quote from the tusk which is the Bible of the prince of nothing world.
Speaker 0: there'll be quotes from you know, some book a Commie and writes years from now, you know at so, you know, he lives because those quotes are there, you know It's not a spoiler and it's like and all of them are awesome.
Speaker 1: I mean right away Not men's rank and men.
Speaker 1: the first forgets the third regrets and the second has all the fun an ancient Coonerick nursery rhyme, I think it's Cooney Eric, whatever.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter There's a symbol over one you a different symbol over the other you yeah Coonerick, whatever.
Speaker 0: It's a good.
Speaker 0: my favorite one was I think I forget what it was.
Speaker 0: It was so relevant.
Speaker 0: It was like the.
Speaker 0: I Can't remember now.
Speaker 0: Oh, it was basically one that said faith dumb science.
Speaker 0: good.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of those.
Speaker 0: there are I mean, there's an essay online.
Speaker 0: I've talked about it I think at least mentioned it before.
Speaker 0: he talks about, you know, the sort of a hypocrisy that goes on being a a Skeptical science reason minded person and a fantasy world with magic and God knows what.
Speaker 0: and he is an essay that R Scott backer wrote talking about how you can sort of you know Put these two things together and these books clearly go right along with that essay.
Speaker 0: You know You got to read the essay to sort of it help you a lot understand what's going on the books.
Speaker 0: if it wasn't obvious already I mean, I basically read the books then saw the essay and went oh duh that makes sense.
Speaker 1: So the.
Speaker 1: I guess we should probably wrap this up.
Speaker 1: We again we barely scratched the surface.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, the surface not even scratch.
Speaker 0: I mean, there are characters within time.
Speaker 0: We didn't talk about Esma at all.
Speaker 0: We didn't talk about the crow demon.
Speaker 0: All right, mostly a character driven things.
Speaker 0: That's really how it has to be talked about.
Speaker 1: I want to address at least one.
Speaker 0: We didn't talk about the campfires.
Speaker 0: don't come to the second.
Speaker 0: No, they don't.
Speaker 1: I think I want to address one actual serious literary issue because it's one.
Speaker 1: well there's two but I'll address the first one first and see we have time for the second one because we've mostly again been talking about The show is basically been all man.
Speaker 1: These books are awesome.
Speaker 0: How awesome are they?
Speaker 0: So that's what people want.
Speaker 0: I mean, we've sort of realized that people don't need you know.
Speaker 0: There's reviews to decide if you're gonna buy something or not Right, and then there's reviews to entertain.
Speaker 0: people have already experienced the work and I really think that Podcasts in general are definitely seem to be leaning towards the ladder and there's actually a demand for the ladder except We didn't talk a lot about specific awesome scenes and go.
Speaker 1: Oh my god We mostly just kind of went.
Speaker 0: but I mean if you had read the book and you're listening to what you know If you've been listening to us, I imagine that you were probably just sitting there going.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Alright, I hope so.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well in speaking of all yeah We do have to note how the first book ends that scene in when.
Speaker 1: basically I love that all the complex interplay where?
Speaker 1: Kellis Notices that something is wrong with scales and the fact that he's.
Speaker 1: it's like his face is Composed and it's like you got the fingers stretched across something.
Speaker 0: the way they actually described the skin spy is actually You.
Speaker 0: everyone totally has the same idea of how it works.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like oh, it's just like a bunch of little fingers all crossing each other.
Speaker 0: So it's like, you know, like a venus flytrap only with a lot more teeth.
Speaker 0: It is the technique.
Speaker 0: the word technique used in the first.
Speaker 1: no, it's used in the second bow.
Speaker 0: so forget the word technique.
Speaker 1: Yes, there is no check.
Speaker 0: There is no technique.
Speaker 0: We made up the technique.
Speaker 0: ignore it.
Speaker 0: It's not like you.
Speaker 0: learn any shit about the technique.
Speaker 0: Anyway fuckers Tell me about the fucking technique.
Speaker 0: I want to know but that's it.
Speaker 1: The way the first book ends is not only brilliant, I think and I really like what happened and the way but soul Crushingly depressing.
Speaker 0: Oh god.
Speaker 0: I mean it's.
Speaker 0: they hit you really hard in one direction with the whole.
Speaker 0: Yeah, skin spies consult is real.
Speaker 0: a commune knows what you're gonna do what you can do and then two seconds later It's like, you know, uh, Esma shows up and he totally just doesn't even notice her.
Speaker 1: That was one of the saddest scenes in any book I've ever read and I was like no way no way assholes.
Speaker 1: but at the same time The the see.
Speaker 1: this is the brilliance of these books.
Speaker 1: the parallel scene again can't talk about it.
Speaker 1: later book spoilers when someone's Reading a book and you get the same scene reversed Total burn just all of that.
Speaker 1: and then the second book picks right back up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the second book picks up pretty much the page after the first book The same book but but I think we all are distinct.
Speaker 1: I came in was being a complete moron by not phoning home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much call home a came in.
Speaker 0: It's weird how Usually when there's what like I watch movies and other things like that, right and I'll always say, you know Why didn't they just do this?
Speaker 0: The character was stupid and I sort of lose my suspension of disbelief, right?
Speaker 0: We're all.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to think of an example I Tried.
Speaker 0: see I can't think of one right now.
Speaker 0: No here and bring up baby.
Speaker 0: Why didn't he just leave?
Speaker 0: why he could have just left.
Speaker 1: see when we were watching it You didn't say why did you just leave?
Speaker 1: you said why doesn't he punch her and then leave?
Speaker 0: that too that did.
Speaker 0: It's like when the character has an easy out when there's just a do this and everything will be cool.
Speaker 0: And they don't do it.
Speaker 0: and at least here We know why.
Speaker 0: Akami and doesn't do it because Kellis is messing with him exactly.
Speaker 0: So there's my suspension of disbelief is not destroyed.
Speaker 0: There's that.
Speaker 1: however, I keep saying billions where a came in resolves to do it.
Speaker 0: I remember reading I'm like, yeah, and then he failed.
Speaker 1: No, he's gonna.
Speaker 1: it's like alright, he's gonna do it.
Speaker 1: It's about time Let's go.
Speaker 1: and then you see like Kellis sees what he's gonna do and Kellis is oh, man And Kellis tricks him and forces him not to do it.
Speaker 1: and I wanted to stab Kellis right then and there so badly.
Speaker 1: It's like but I only wanted to stab him because I was in his head.
Speaker 1: once I'm out of his head again I couldn't know and then I stopped wanting to stab him and I liked him again, but when It's like a commune.
Speaker 0: I can believe that he doesn't do it.
Speaker 0: So it's okay I'm not going crazy, but I'm rooting for him to do it almost the whole time and it's crazy How in these books I'll be rooting for either things I want to see happen for entertainment purposes usually involving more consult appearances, right?
Speaker 0: I know God references.
Speaker 1: No, I wanted you know what I wanted from the beginning.
Speaker 1: as soon as the word gnosis appeared I wanted to know what the fuck the gnosis wasn't why it was.
Speaker 1: I really wanted to know.
Speaker 1: I wanted to came in to tell me Yeah, and I'll.
Speaker 0: there also be things I'll be rooting for characters to do because it's best for them.
Speaker 0: Of course I'm usually whoever's head I'm in right now is the person I'm rooting for them to do something Right, and I'm even if it hurts one of the other characters that I was rooting for a minute ago.
Speaker 0: But throughout the book and unlike any other book or movie or anything I've ever read or watched or listened to or anything What I root for actually Changes.
Speaker 0: I'll root for a commune to call home and then later on I root for him not to call home.
Speaker 0: It's crazy I can't believe.
Speaker 0: I couldn't like I couldn't imagine myself doing that.
Speaker 0: but I was doing.
Speaker 0: I was like don't call home Don't go home, but I was like, wait a minute.
Speaker 0: I wanted it to call home so badly Just a few chapters ago and there's now.
Speaker 1: I'm saying don't go home Especially later because the holy war is marching and a lot, you know, you're rooting for the holy war a lot of the time.
Speaker 1: But then you step back and realize wait a minute The holy war is terrible.
Speaker 1: The holy war is only going to make the apocalypse more likely.
Speaker 1: What is kill is doing?
Speaker 1: What is that?
Speaker 1: What are these people doing?
Speaker 1: It's all careless.
Speaker 0: Oh my god Right, but I can't root against the holy war because of all I know of you know The guys down in Shema first time.
Speaker 0: we've said she may.
Speaker 0: I can't believe it, right?
Speaker 1: I don't like them either.
Speaker 0: I don't want them to kick all the asses of all these people because even though I might you know Not have any you know loyalty to the the men of the tusk Right the characters that I've grown on are in with this side.
Speaker 0: So I that's the side that I'm sort of on even though from an objective sort of pie-in-the-sky Perspective the holy war is terrible and I hate it.
Speaker 0: It sucks It's.
Speaker 0: it's a giant crusade of evil.
Speaker 1: the brilliance of these books And again, it all comes back to the fact that we keep word.
Speaker 1: We're so intimately inside of characters heads and we only see things through the eyes of people in the books.
Speaker 1: There's a brilliant scene later where a character says to him or herself.
Speaker 1: Am I crazy?
Speaker 1: No, I'm not.
Speaker 1: But this I keep saying brilliant I have to stop saying it but that I'm always rooting for whoever I am at the moment.
Speaker 1: I'm always on the side of whoever I am and the fact that my loyalties as the and occasionally You're something bad.
Speaker 1: Yes, but at the same time I Feel bad for whoever I am with even if they are a bad person.
Speaker 1: Yep, the only person I don't feel bad for is Kellis because I don't know what to think about Kellis.
Speaker 1: Well, I know what to think about Kellis, but that's because I've read two more books.
Speaker 0: But because he's callous, you don't know if what you think is what you should think or not.
Speaker 0: Sometimes but for everyone else the picture is clear and the doubt is a race.
Speaker 1: But the fact that my loyalties as an external objective reader are so fickle Yep, and it's it's really surprising to me and sometimes I'd I'd stop reading at the end of a character's perspective thing and go Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: I hate nayer.
Speaker 1: Why was I rooting for him?
Speaker 1: I hate him so much?
Speaker 0: Well, I only root for him because he is foiling Kellis.
Speaker 1: So I hate.
Speaker 1: but I think you root for him because when you're in his head to a degree You're him because you see identify with his frustration.
Speaker 1: You see what he sees and that's all these books are about is what do you see?
Speaker 0: What do you say?
Speaker 1: because what you see is all yet be?
Speaker 1: What you see is what you are because everything that you see is the darkness that came before and Kellis is the only person in the world except for mo Angus that we know of yes And I guess the rest of the dunyane who are hiding who can see?
Speaker 0: Well that we know of and think of all the subtlety you look.
Speaker 1: no because remember Early on and a lot of people when they read these they miss this very important point that the dunyane were woken up by Visions of mo Angus who had left at some point.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that's that's something that needs some clarification.
Speaker 0: It's not super obvious.
Speaker 0: The reason Kellis Kellis is living with the dunyane being dunyane being basically hermit monks.
Speaker 0: Well, they're not really hermits there because they're not alone.
Speaker 0: But you know that Collective hermit right there.
Speaker 0: They're collectively they're a hermit.
Speaker 0: They're like monks living on the mountain never communicating with anyone staying hidden at the same time Castle.
Speaker 1: actually some people have the gift they can see the onta and some people cannot.
Speaker 1: people who can see it have the Capability to work magic even if they don't yep, and so obviously some of the dunyane have this capability, right?
Speaker 0: But anyway, the dunyane their monks living cut off from the world Kellis is with them.
Speaker 0: Mo Angus left them at some point in the past.
Speaker 0: We don't know why we don't know much about it.
Speaker 0: All we know is that mo Angus sent dreams back to them via magical powers and the the dunyane that saw these dreams Decided they could Brooke it no more.
Speaker 1: So they send Kellis out.
Speaker 1: It's funny out It's all.
Speaker 1: you get the impression that they did not bother telling Kellis what he had to do Because naturally they knew that he would do it because they came before him.
Speaker 0: Yep They're just like, you know Kellis go out and deal with these dreams that were sent to us by.
Speaker 1: that is that scene where he walks out into the world Forgets that he was a man and then remembers.
Speaker 1: Yep is so beautifully written.
Speaker 0: and then the dunyane that had the dreams go down into the labyrinths and They're done with themselves.
Speaker 1: Yes It is so subtly implied that all the dunyane that received these dreams killed themselves because they were tainted.
Speaker 0: somehow Perhaps they were someone came before them.
Speaker 0: So rather than let you know someone get the best of them or or you know No longer, you know coming before they off themselves that they would end.
Speaker 1: so to ponder And this is the funny thing again.
Speaker 1: This is the only question in the first book that Kellis is ever grappling with Did Bo Angus come before me or do I come before him?
Speaker 0: Yep, and then all right Come before me.
Speaker 0: Can I get ahead of him?
Speaker 1: But if when guess left did he come before the rest of the dunyane?
Speaker 1: Well, he definitely came before the ones that often because that is something that is very interesting.
Speaker 1: Maybe what makes mo Angus and Kellis what made mo Angus leave and what makes Kellis be the one to go out to get him Is their blood because the dunyane don't seem to believe in that magic or all these things should exist because they can't understand or control It or whatever other reason we don't really know.
Speaker 0: but yet even if mo Angus came before the dunyane But the dunyane made him what he is So did they come before themselves.
Speaker 1: but this hints at the fact that there is something to The blood of the Anna syramore that makes it different independent of the dunyane.
Speaker 0: But that can't be because that would be something after coming before.
Speaker 0: that's reverse causality.
Speaker 0: It is because a lot of it basically that's one thing that you it's not Super explicit, but whenever someone talks about prophecy, right as in you know This is a sign of something to come.
Speaker 0: Kellis says no, that's impossible.
Speaker 0: Something that comes after cannot come before, you know cannot affect which comes before.
Speaker 0: and you think wait, how is that prophecy?
Speaker 0: Well think about it.
Speaker 0: Let's say there's an apocalypse that's gonna happen 50 years from now.
Speaker 0: and I know that's gonna happen because just now like this second There was an eclipse.
Speaker 0: Let's I'm just making this up right and eclipse now is a sign of an apocalypse in the future.
Speaker 0: Okay So the one way of looking at it is that Apocalypse that that eclipse is the cause of the apocalypse.
Speaker 0: that would make sense But that's not what you're saying when you say that it's a prophecy.
Speaker 0: when you're saying it's a prophecy You're saying the apocalypse is a foregone conclusion.
Speaker 0: It happened and it has caused the apocalypse of the future Caused the Eclipse now and that is not something that can be.
Speaker 0: if you're with the dunyane mindset Or the logos, you know something that comes later cannot cause something to happen.
Speaker 0: now It hasn't happened yet.
Speaker 0: How could it cause anything?
Speaker 0: It's way out there.
Speaker 1: Ah But anyway well there will address at least one academic issue because one.
Speaker 1: well first one thing that gets brought up a lot and I'll admit I saw this in the beginning - it is very easy to Feel as though a came Ian's relationship with his students was homosexual And there is some of that going on there.
Speaker 1: what I see in that is mostly a use of One.
Speaker 1: as someone else other than me pointed out so eloquently this goodness book does not beat around the sexuality at all.
Speaker 1: people Like men only refer to other men in these tender terms, but at the same time how many women are in these books?
Speaker 0: Two that we really get to know.
Speaker 1: Yes, exactly.
Speaker 1: But in regardless, I think it's just because a came Ian uses very very no, no.
Speaker 1: three There's that the zero the Empress lady a lot of a came Ian and Proyas in particular and all the all the people surrounding them price.
Speaker 1: you use very Praysha price shit.
Speaker 1: P. R. P. R. O.
Speaker 0: Y. His nickname is.
Speaker 0: they call him price Yeah, which always sort of struck me is sort of like a Yiddish name like, you know The price yeah, you do in there.
Speaker 0: It just sort of felt like that.
Speaker 1: That makes sense.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the fact moisture Motion.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: I almost lost my train of thought.
Speaker 0: That's all right.
Speaker 0: But here we go.
Speaker 0: My Yiddish can do that.
Speaker 1: Yes, it can.
Speaker 1: Yiddish often has this.
Speaker 0: Yiddish often comes before.
Speaker 1: but the language that a came Ian uses both in his head and when speaking When referring to his students, there's a lot they've been.
Speaker 1: it's referred to as love.
Speaker 1: There's some people described it as a feminine language.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't go that far but I would say that it's definitely the language that is used is a kind of phrasing that would imply in a modern setting Homosexuality to a lot of people on the one hand like when it when they start.
Speaker 0: when that stuff was coming in I was sort of like cuz he trying to make this out to be gay, but I sort of just took it at Ophelia or fraternal Definitely impression that I get.
Speaker 1: that's corroborated by other things I've read since then but yeah, I get the impression that that that is there is nothing more than tenderness and filial peaty.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people got to learn that word filial.
Speaker 0: That's an important word.
Speaker 1: Yes, especially in these books.
Speaker 0: Yes filial love learn it, but then you have it.
Speaker 1: probably that leads right into the accusations that these books are sexist and These are accusations that are very easy to make and very difficult to deny.
Speaker 0: well, you know, but the Name of fantasy book does not sexy The ones that involve matriarchal societies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but even those are that some of those are reversed Usually most of those.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, come on like you could have like, you know Battle of the Amazons what it's just sexist still.
Speaker 1: well, I guess the point I would make is I mean Wonder Woman still sexist.
Speaker 1: We've gone on for over an hour So I'm not gonna belabor the point but the way I would approach this is that it is set in a very realistic world and human society in these eras was generally women did not have a lot of opportunities to for advancement and the books are following a war a foreign war.
Speaker 1: it is very unlikely that there would be many women involved in this at all.
Speaker 1: and I guess by Putting that by making it just a completely gender neutral world one would have removed a lot of the reflections that the book casts upon Our modern world and the things that us as humans actually do and did.
Speaker 0: it's strange how I was often noticing in this book Right how it is a fantasy world.
Speaker 0: right and you look at a fantasy world like say No, look at look at say Middle Earth.
Speaker 0: right Middle Earth doesn't really have.
Speaker 0: you know a lot of things the in it I mean besides trees, right?
Speaker 0: I mean you don't have the same animals that you have in the normal world so much.
Speaker 0: You know, it's it's different, you know fantasy animals in Middle Earth and such right.
Speaker 0: but in this book is You know half the things would be fantasy things and half the things we real-world things like you just be like.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, a guy had camels and horses and it's like this camels and horses and we just.
Speaker 0: he just says horse It doesn't even bother, you know, it's just normal horses like in the real world.
Speaker 0: yet.
Speaker 0: There's magic That's not in the real world and it's just this total mixture right going on right there.
Speaker 0: So he's obviously kept the sort of societal structures of you know The Middle Ages and the Crusades when women were not so hot?
Speaker 0: Well, they were.
Speaker 0: probably they were hot in one way, but you know They were not doing too well with the civil liberties and such.
Speaker 0: But he changes a whole bunch of other things and seeing which things are just taken directly from the real world Honestly, I would say is most of these books right and which things are the fantasy world right?
Speaker 0: that is that is mixed in is a huge part of what's going on, but in terms of There are two I guess female main characters among one.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 0: It wasn't as bad.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is sir way was a product of her upbringing.
Speaker 1: her upbringing came before her.
Speaker 0: Hey quite so and I do pointed many blue babies.
Speaker 1: I feels I can't.
Speaker 1: I can't dislike her But I can't dis I can't.
Speaker 0: truly just I can.
Speaker 0: There's a point at which you can.
Speaker 1: but at the same time what made her that way?
Speaker 1: and did she ever have a choice?
Speaker 0: I don't think she had much.
Speaker 1: well She had a choice, but did she didn't know she had a choice, but I would put basically I don't want to talk about all these other ancillary issues because I don't really want to.
Speaker 1: we've already gone on long enough and we Got to talk about the book we're doing next time anyway, yes So what I would say is that how many main characters are there?
Speaker 1: and out of them two are women?
Speaker 1: So it's not as Overbalanced as it would be easy to believe because of the main characters.
Speaker 1: There are two substantially important female characters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Think about it those female characters whatever, you know negative, you know things.
Speaker 0: they're portrayed as having betrayed.
Speaker 1: No worse than the male characters ever callous except for callous.
Speaker 0: But you know everyone else gets owned just as much as they get owned Right there.
Speaker 0: own the everything's equal owning all around.
Speaker 0: In fact, there are many men that get owned quite a lot more than the women get owned.
Speaker 1: And you know as people bring up that there's a lot of rape in these books again There is equal raping among all genders sad and species.
Speaker 1: It is quite unpleasant But at the same time the whole the rape thing and this comes up a lot more in the second third books not raping all the time but what that is.
Speaker 1: because if Darkness comes before and people are the products of what came before What is the best way to control a person but to control their biology if nothing else?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the skin spies.
Speaker 1: this is kind of hinted at and it is pretty much explained explicitly later in the books.
Speaker 1: I don't feel badly and spoiling it but the skin spies are controlled primarily by the fact that as biological beings Controlling their brains and their hormones and their lust controls them better than any technology ever could.
Speaker 1: Yep, and That is kind of what all of that rape is.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's it's technology taken to the amoral immoral extreme.
Speaker 1: Oh Crow demons, okay so Okay, I guess I just I don't feel that these books are unduly sexist because any aspersions that are cast upon the female characters are No worse than the aspersions cast upon the male characters.
Speaker 1: and I think a came Ian probably comes out the least Aspersed to make up some cromulent words of all.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So the next book we're gonna do.
Speaker 0: if you've looked at the website you probably you know to get this episode.
Speaker 0: You probably already know what the next book is.
Speaker 0: But if not, we saved to be decided not to tell you till the end of the episode.
Speaker 0: so it could be a surprise.
Speaker 0: We're gonna do the episode about this book.
Speaker 0: Let's do it eight weeks from now.
Speaker 0: So there's gonna be three Thursday episodes that are not book of the month or book of the whatever book episodes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's gonna be a book episode.
Speaker 1: realize that not everyone reads quite as quickly as we do.
Speaker 0: So you're gonna have three non book Thursday episodes.
Speaker 0: Then the fourth one from now is gonna be about the book that we're gonna do next.
Speaker 1: well keep this short because I don't think you shouldn't need to be sold on this.
Speaker 1: this if the prince of nothing and the darkness that comes before and the warrior prophet and the thousandfold thought and all these are Scott backer books are Revolutionary or amazing words of literature that are coming out now or that are recent snow crash by Neal Stephenson is a Revolutionary work that is old and we now are we
Speaker 0: actually from the early 90s
Speaker 1: old?
Speaker 1: But we've gotten to the point where Technology has shown us that Neal Stephenson was very very Very ahead of his time and brought the ideas that he talks about have been brought to reality to a frightening degree.
Speaker 0: They're pretty much really three modern writers.
Speaker 0: We're probably do books by all of them at some point, you know over who knows how long right.
Speaker 0: that is sort of like the geek Right.
Speaker 0: Well, there's maybe four if you throw Terry Pratchett in there.
Speaker 0: There's Neil Gaiman Neal Stephenson, William Gibson and Terry Pratchett are like the geek Novelist gods of the present time.
Speaker 0: sort of it.
Speaker 0: get any I don't know.
Speaker 0: maybe you could throw someone else in there.
Speaker 0: yes, yeah, but those are pretty much the four and Neal Stephenson snow crash is pretty much The baby couldn't really think of a better starting place if we're gonna go down that road.
Speaker 1: No, the one thing I want to bring it cuz if this should be the five-minute, you know With a book just to get you know.
Speaker 1: This is what the book is.
Speaker 0: But I imagine most people listening to geek nights have read it or should have.
Speaker 1: but if you read this book now Not knowing when it was written.
Speaker 1: It's easy.
Speaker 1: I mean with one exception one idea This is a reason.
Speaker 1: No listening to reason is just awesome.
Speaker 1: But the the thing with the languages.
Speaker 0: Oh, right, right, right.
Speaker 1: The rest of it the cyberspace the technology all these things is very pedestrian very done-it-done-before old.
Speaker 0: it seems like You know the stuff about cyberspace really seems like a bad sci-fi channel original.
Speaker 1: And I remember I was reading this book for the first time and I'm reading his description of cyberspace and I'm thinking yeah It's kind of like that, but he really kind of missed it on a few things.
Speaker 1: But in you know, the spirit is pretty much spot-on is in the early 90s.
Speaker 1: Yes, like the first one I flip back and I looked at this book was written in freaking.
Speaker 1: This book describes a thing Cyberspace that did not yet exist.
Speaker 1: Muds were around and that was all you had.
Speaker 0: the well pretty much a new idea with this realm.
Speaker 1: The first MMO did not appear until late 1996.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah this book Was so prescient.
Speaker 1: it came.
Speaker 0: it came before it sure did.
Speaker 0: Not only that but this is a book.
Speaker 0: it is humorous.
Speaker 0: It has a lot of humor going on.
Speaker 0: It has Pretty cool characters.
Speaker 0: It has cool Sci-fi action.
Speaker 0: It's got all sorts of cool ideas going on.
Speaker 1: The whole thing with the burb claves and the kind of balkanization of society.
Speaker 0: Yeah, really really really full-on libertarian privatization of absolutely everything but including roads and land and Themselves.
Speaker 1: a lot of that really reminded me just for it for a number of reasons because I guess I recently read hocus-pocus Again, but and by Kurt Vonnegut and I was reminded of it in many occurrences Mmm, I gotta read some hocus-pocus.
Speaker 1: That's it's one of my favorite Kurt Vonnegut's.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a good one.
Speaker 0: so Snow crash by Neal Stephenson.
Speaker 0: I imagine many of you have read it at least.
Speaker 0: I hope more of you have read this than have read Prince of Nothing.
Speaker 0: You know because I can understand if you didn't know about Prince of Nothing if you didn't know about snow crash a little less Understandable.
Speaker 0: So if you haven't read this, this is like required geek reading material for all right I so Snow crash good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the way I would deal to say it is that snow crash is not necessarily the best written book I cannot look at.
Speaker 1: I would not put Neal Stephenson on the pedestal that I've put our Scott backer or a lot of other authors Because for one I'll say this I think Neal Stephenson as good of an author as he is writes shit.
Speaker 1: action scenes Yeah, I think his action scenes are crap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the the skateboarding scene at the beginning of snow crash is okay.
Speaker 0: so the other action scenes not so good like with It's the raven action scenes not so great.
Speaker 1: But at the same time the way raven it described reminds me a little bit of nair.
Speaker 0: Do we have to read the most famous quote from this book?
Speaker 1: Do I think we might have to?
Speaker 0: All right, let it said it on the show before I know but I have to find it.
Speaker 1: But this is one of those things like if you're if you consider yourself an anime fan Even if you do not like neon Genesis Evangelion, you should have seen it because it is a revolutionary work of animation.
Speaker 1: By the same token if you like science fiction or you were a technology geek Even if you do not like Neal Stephenson or you do not like snow crash You should have read it because it is a revolutionary work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like even.
Speaker 0: you know I do that I do this with comics all the time is even if I don't like a comic if it's significant or important You know, I read it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's like if you don't like Citizen Kane fine, you should still have seen it Until a man is 25.
Speaker 0: He still thinks every so often that under the right circumstances He could be the baddest motherfucker in the world.
Speaker 0: If I moved to a martial arts monastery in China and studied real hard for 10 years if my family was wiped out by Colombian drug dealers and I swore myself to revenge if I got a fatal disease had one year to live Devoted it to wiping out street crime if I just dropped out and devoted my life to being bad Hero used to feel that way too, but then he ran into Raven in a way.
Speaker 0: This is liberating.
Speaker 0: He no longer has to worry about trying to be the baddest motherfucker in the world.
Speaker 0: The position is taken the crowning touch.
Speaker 0: the one thing that really puts true world-class bad motherfucker them totally out of reach of course is the hydrogen bomb.
Speaker 0: if It wasn't for the hydrogen bomb a man could still aspire.
Speaker 0: maybe find Ravens Achilles heel.
Speaker 0: Sneak up get a drop slip a Mickey pull a fast one.
Speaker 0: But Ravens nuclear umbrella kind of puts the world title out of reach Which is okay.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it's all right to just be a little bad to know your limitations make do with what you got.
Speaker 1: And of course if that doesn't work, he might listen to reason.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.