Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, March 11th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim, and this is geek nights tonight the side-scrolling beat-em-up games.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: You know surprisingly we haven't played brawl at all yet today.
Speaker 0: I played it yesterday for a bit and that like subspace emissary thing like.
Speaker 0: I'm not.
Speaker 0: I don't think I'm even 20% done with it according to the number in the top right.
Speaker 0: how long does it take to beat goddamn?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna let Scott go through all that and I'm just gonna play normal Smash Brothers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, rim can't be trusted to play co-op mode.
Speaker 1: I believe the lack of trust here is very simple.
Speaker 1: You see Scott can't be trusted to not suck at the co-op mode.
Speaker 0: I'm sure.
Speaker 1: I'm sure every time we try to play River City Ransom or something We'll be playing and I'll be doing well and Scott will.
Speaker 1: just it's not like he does it on purpose.
Speaker 1: He just lacks.
Speaker 1: I guess I don't know skill, but he'll constantly.
Speaker 0: just yeah, I like so much skill.
Speaker 1: That's why I beat the game on hit me and it'll hurt me and he'll knock me over River City Ransom.
Speaker 1: He'll constantly just like hit me with a pipe or knock me with a brass knuckle or something.
Speaker 1: He'll throw a tire at a wall and hits me in the back and kick me.
Speaker 1: You'll punch me Punishing you for sucking.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, I'm doing just fine.
Speaker 1: So, uh, you see Scott misses and hits me.
Speaker 1: I never miss but Sometimes I hit Scott and that is in retaliation for him not pulling up his end of the bargain.
Speaker 1: Boss fights are much easier if I throw Scott off the cliff then beat the boss by myself.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm sure because you know, I can beat River City Ransom just fine on my own, but we're there And gauntlet I can beat just fine on my own except when you're there.
Speaker 0: shooting all the food.
Speaker 1: Gauntlet one for one is actually a pretty shitty game and that we're not arguing that right now.
Speaker 0: But do you or do you not shoot all the food in gauntlet does preventing anyone from having a good chance of doing?
Speaker 1: Well, I think a much more apt example in gauntlet is when as a warrior I push you into every single slime and death We run across.
Speaker 0: see this is exactly what I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: That's different.
Speaker 1: No, that's gauntlet.
Speaker 0: No, it's all the same.
Speaker 0: gauntlet cannot be trusted as a partner in co-op games.
Speaker 1: Just gauntlet.
Speaker 0: We really want to play co-op games But rim can't seem to play and actually try to win tries to kill all the other players in grief.
Speaker 1: Yet how come whenever we play four swords who gets voted all the way?
Speaker 0: the fuck down because you grieve.
Speaker 0: That's all you do.
Speaker 0: is you shoot me with the fire rod.
Speaker 1: So then you vote against me, but there's two other people and they're also voting against you.
Speaker 0: So something because you're just all laughing together voting against me, even though I helped the most.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got the most jimmies.
Speaker 1: Everyone is out to get you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: Well, they're not out to get me.
Speaker 0: You're just.
Speaker 0: you know, it's not like evil.
Speaker 0: It's like haha funny, but it that's not.
Speaker 0: no like haha funny.
Speaker 0: Let's vote against Scott every time low.
Speaker 1: Oh, we don't do that.
Speaker 1: We vote against you because you're a cock.
Speaker 1: Throw us into the water.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: You know how I'm a cock because the whole time I'm going you morons Why aren't you trying to win?
Speaker 0: Why are you shooting each other with the fire rod?
Speaker 0: Goddamn it.
Speaker 0: Let's try to win.
Speaker 1: See that's the thing.
Speaker 1: There's a Bike.
Speaker 1: whenever I do grief, it is very much intentional.
Speaker 1: However, in that one mission.
Speaker 1: We have to avoid the searchlights.
Speaker 1: I And yelled and yelled at Pete for making a mistake.
Speaker 1: It happens to go back to the beginning and while he was yelling at him Scott just fucking stood there and the searchlight got him.
Speaker 0: Hey, I knew what I think.
Speaker 0: basically what the issue was there is that we had got caught by the searchlights, right?
Speaker 0: But then I was.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize right away that the reason the searchlights caught us was not because I thought it was just cuz someone Else is stupid and walked into them.
Speaker 0: But I didn't realize it was because the smashing of the pots attracts them.
Speaker 0: and then so yeah Once I learned that lesson, I did not mess up again.
Speaker 1: Anyway, this isn't really news, but I'll talk about it briefly.
Speaker 1: as you may know Scott and I are going to be at PAX.
Speaker 0: We have guaranteed it's a lock barring death or catastrophe.
Speaker 0: We will be in Seattle near the end of August for an event of penny arcade Expositioning now exhibitioning.
Speaker 1: there is a small chance But not a zero chance that we will be engaged in some sort of events at PAX.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we we can.
Speaker 0: we have no idea.
Speaker 0: basically we said please and we're waiting for them to say maybe yeah Pax is kind of different from other cons.
Speaker 0: I mean I look at my Congress a little bit a little bit bigger Yeah, a little bit video game a little bit other side of the country.
Speaker 1: Also not quite formatted.
Speaker 1: the way anime cons are Can't just run the same kind of panels you're on at these little anime cons as you can.
Speaker 1: is something like packs?
Speaker 0: No, not really.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we're working on it.
Speaker 1: We're gonna try to do some awesome stuff for you guys there and there'll be much more details to come.
Speaker 1: as time goes on We'll find out.
Speaker 1: So, uh, what do you got in the news for me?
Speaker 0: since I have nothing else today I'm not sure if I did this news on the show before.
Speaker 1: I don't remember you were gonna do it the night.
Speaker 1: We got fucked and stuck in the city and then Emily saved us with the Amtrak.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't remember but this is from February 12th.
Speaker 0: And if I did this news before oh, well tough shit You'll have to hear it again.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter because this is a news that everyone should read and it's sort of very.
Speaker 0: I think it's really important.
Speaker 0: So it's worth even if I talk about it twice.
Speaker 0: Basically, the story is here.
Speaker 0: There's a sort of a casual in quotes, you know I'm not sure how much I'm liking that term now gaming company.
Speaker 0: They make video games, right and basically, they realized that like 92% of the people playing the full version of their game online Right because they it was an online game they knew how many people were playing it 92% of the people playing the full version online Had pirated it.
Speaker 1: think about that the that's not even like the majority.
Speaker 1: That's not even a lot.
Speaker 1: the vast Unmitigated majority of people playing that game had pirated it for free.
Speaker 0: That's an Overwhelming amount.
Speaker 1: like you could basically say pretty much everyone playing that game was pirating and you would not be exaggerating that much.
Speaker 0: So, what did they do, of course they tried some DRMs, right.
Speaker 0: so they Pumped up the DRM and then they looked how many people were playing and they pumped up the DRM.
Speaker 0: They looked how many people were playing right and they sort of kept track the whole time.
Speaker 0: now This isn't a very good scientific study You know and it for a real science or whatever because it's only a sample size of one game, you know not too many controls that sort of thing, but Basically if you look at these numbers It's it's pretty obvious that at least for this one game that one about one.
Speaker 0: Okay, let me try to say this properly for every 1000 pirated copies they sort of blocked with DRM.
Speaker 0: They got one sale.
Speaker 0: So Anyone who's like, oh no you pirated a thousand copies of my thing.
Speaker 0: I lost a thousand times the ticket for the sale price.
Speaker 0: no, you lost like one times the sale price for every thousand.
Speaker 1: because this brings up a very Interesting issue because in the anime world in the technology world This is becoming a debate and an issue to the point that we could talk about it validly on all four nights of geek night.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pervading every possible kind of media.
Speaker 0: I think that what this shows is something that I had suspected for quite a while.
Speaker 0: All right, picture this you're at a carnival right and you're walking down the street Okay, and a guy says hey come in and see the bearded lady one dollar, right?
Speaker 0: Well at the price of one dollar, right?
Speaker 0: You know Some people will see the bearded lady and some people will not see the bearded lady at the price of two dollars.
Speaker 0: even fewer People's here to see the bearded lady.
Speaker 0: This is basic economics here.
Speaker 0: Right the higher the price the few people who will pay to see the bearded lady.
Speaker 0: Right now the thing is is that there is so much media and so much stuff Right that it's gotten to the point where there are some things in fact most things where you know for free For zero dollars.
Speaker 0: just about anyone will at least take a peek at the bearded lady, right?
Speaker 0: But once you raise the price to a dollar Like it's like well, I'd like to see the bearded lady, but I don't want to see it that bad that I'll pay money.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like if you give something away for free even if it's not that good even if it's kind of a Tons and tons of people check it out because it doesn't cost them any money.
Speaker 0: But as soon as there's a price on it, no one wants it.
Speaker 0: so the assumption that Someone pirating it would have bought it if it wasn't free if they couldn't pirate it is complete horseshit.
Speaker 0: The only if they give the game wasn't piratable.
Speaker 0: if they couldn't pirate the anime if they couldn't get the fan sub They just wouldn't watch they wouldn't play they wouldn't.
Speaker 0: It's like they.
Speaker 0: they like it enough to do it for free, but they don't like it enough to pay anything for it.
Speaker 1: now again We're not.
Speaker 1: I mean don't read into this in terms of thinking like oh so piracy is okay blah blah blah Cuz.
Speaker 1: it's not what we're saying.
Speaker 1: That's not even close to what we're getting it that the point here is just that there's so much media of every possible kind so much Entertainment available in the world today in the modern industrialized world that the cost of a obtaining any given form of entertainment or the I guess the value people are willing to give up the opportunity cause people are willing to expend is Approaching zero.
Speaker 1: like look at YouTube.
Speaker 1: how many people would even consider?
Speaker 1: Going to YouTube if it cost anything to see a video on YouTube?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like I'll watch a video of a cat bouncing around for free.
Speaker 0: if it was a dollar known watch it It was a penny.
Speaker 1: No one would watch it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much So we're.
Speaker 1: this is an interesting problem because even further you can't compete with the past.
Speaker 1: I mean consider.
Speaker 1: people always say and I again You know not condoning piracy and this is kind of a sad example, but seriously if you think about this consider Every book every single book that has ever been written in the that's in the English language today.
Speaker 1: Now let's say that due to piracy and used book sales No one from this day forward ever Buys a new book again or in any way contributes to the livelihood of an author.
Speaker 1: ever ever ever again There are still more good books in existence than any human being could read in their entire life.
Speaker 1: Yep Now that's not to say oh, well, therefore we should stop making books.
Speaker 1: That's ludicrous.
Speaker 0: That is ludicrous because they're new who?
Speaker 0: this is definitely room for more good.
Speaker 1: but what it's saying is that because of the retention of data in society today and Because of the availability of access to information and across all medium media mediums We're getting to the point where you don't just compete with like.
Speaker 1: if I write a novel or I make a video game I'm not just competing with about Scott who wrote a novel or Scott who wrote a video game.
Speaker 1: I'm competing directly with every video game maker or every author who has ever existed and That competition gets to them.
Speaker 1: I mean think about that.
Speaker 1: Think about trying to keep.
Speaker 1: there are already Hundreds of thousands of things that are better than anything.
Speaker 1: I will ever do already out there already done.
Speaker 1: A lot of them are already available for free.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you try to charge money for your new thing It's better be fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: or basically people are gonna walk by and you're standing there saying bearded lady five bucks They're just like fuck you man.
Speaker 0: I'd go in there for free, but not for five bucks.
Speaker 1: besides There's a stubbly lady over there for nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if you if you if they walk by and you say holy shit Something fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: I can't think of anything right now.
Speaker 0: I don't know vampire cars right vampire car five bucks.
Speaker 0: people go vampire car.
Speaker 0: No fucking way.
Speaker 0: and they pay five bucks.
Speaker 0: cuz it's so awesome.
Speaker 0: So vampire car.
Speaker 0: I just tried to think of something awesome.
Speaker 0: Vampires are okay.
Speaker 0: Cool cars are cool.
Speaker 0: vampire car.
Speaker 1: That's not bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean that's up there with a naked car.
Speaker 0: No, it's better than naked car.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is I've already seen a naked car So I'm not gonna pay to see another day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't want to see.
Speaker 1: you paid a Nazi name Naked car, you know if the naked if I hadn't seen the naked car would have been a happier person.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: But yeah, you know you.
Speaker 0: basically It's getting to the point where if you don't make something, holy shit.
Speaker 0: Awesome It's not worth the money of a whole lot of people especially people who are internet connected because it's this isn't just like Oh rimmons got saying this or oh people saying this.
Speaker 1: we have evidence.
Speaker 0: now We have a little bit evidence.
Speaker 0: Someone should really do a study along these lines to figure out like, you know Like.
Speaker 0: sit people down in front of a like, you know choice.
Speaker 0: This thing is zero dollars.
Speaker 0: This thing is five dollars pick one.
Speaker 1: I remember when Napster first got wiped out because Napster kind of suddenly disappeared.
Speaker 1: There was a gap between when Napster went down and when non techie normal people could once again get access to peer-to-peer stuff.
Speaker 1: Hmm and I'm reasonably certain that CD sales did not increase at all in that time.
Speaker 1: Hmm, maybe and Again, I don't know what to do about this that I mean it's one thing to tell the anime industry Look you say piracy is ruining you But if you eliminate it all piracy, you probably wouldn't see a single additional sale than you see now.
Speaker 0: They see a handful of additional maybe five or six maybe seven.
Speaker 1: how many people I mean?
Speaker 1: how many punk kids are?
Speaker 1: Honestly going to pay $20 per DVD for one piece?
Speaker 1: if they can't get it free?
Speaker 1: instead They'll just watch cat jumping on a trampoline on YouTube or they'll go play the video game.
Speaker 1: They already own.
Speaker 1: Yes, they'll go buy them.
Speaker 0: I mean think about this if they couldn't watch it for free.
Speaker 0: They just wouldn't watch.
Speaker 0: If it wasn't zero dollars to see the bearded lady They would just walk right by the bearded lady tent and never see the bearded lady.
Speaker 1: I could spend the next five years of my life playing all the amazing Gameboy advance Gameboy PlayStation 1 and PlayStation 2 games that cost a couple dollars each to get But I just never played because I never had time.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So that really reduces the incentive to buy a new game.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Anyway in other news this is Related to gaming partly in that I know a lot of gamers are fans of this and that that's kind of the demographic they go After and also because it is in and of itself a game Battle BOTS, I'll talk about battle BOTS
Speaker 0: talking about the real battle BOTS like that was on TV way back.
Speaker 1: Yeah battle BOTS that show that everyone was really excited about.
Speaker 1: then once it came on Everyone realized how absolutely lame it was.
Speaker 0: That's really old.
Speaker 0: That was that when I was like in high school, right?
Speaker 1: the long story short is that they struck a deal with ESPN and It looks like it's going to be on ESPN 2 again.
Speaker 0: Well, ESPN 2 is you know full of like trick pool and other stuff like that.
Speaker 1: So trick pool is so much cooler than battle BOTS.
Speaker 0: Oh, it definitely is but it's you know, it's not out of the realm for Battle BOTS to also be on the same channel as the trick shot pool, but a lot of people are excited about billiards.
Speaker 1: Sorry, but I'm gonna say this This is kind of a sneaky way of getting a review in because this is something that was really big when I was in high school.
Speaker 1: battle BOTS is Really dumb and I've never found it entertaining.
Speaker 0: battle BOTS Trademark is really dumb.
Speaker 1: Yes robots fighting is amazing.
Speaker 0: robots fighting is awesome.
Speaker 0: The idea of robots fighting is awesome.
Speaker 1: You get all the fun of making bugs fight without the horror of making living beings fight.
Speaker 1: You make mechanical beings fight with rockets easy.
Speaker 0: the on paper battle BOTS like the greatest thing ever But in reality the actual show battle BOTS the actual rules the actual game Sport of battle BOTS not cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, did anyone out there actually actually enjoy watching battle BOTS?
Speaker 0: I'm sure someone did especially the later seasons.
Speaker 1: I'm really curious to hear why.
Speaker 1: because it was so unentertaining and so slow and so pathetic.
Speaker 1: now What I want to whatever I really want to talk about here is how to make battle BOTS.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 1: This is real.
Speaker 0: We need a lot fewer rules because they've been way too many limits on the robots.
Speaker 0: They should have let you go hog wild.
Speaker 0: I'm talking like Chainsaws guns Pissed.
Speaker 1: no, I understand no projectiles that make sense.
Speaker 0: Oh, come on projectiles for the win.
Speaker 1: No, you'll Yeah, but no cuz I don't like that cuz then you got to make all these rules about ammo and all that I don't have.
Speaker 0: like like like sort of a helicopter thing with big weights on the end We're just Ram like wham right in the side of you like a big spinning thing I don't know.
Speaker 1: I always like the idea of you know, like a like a cattle stunner a captive bolts Mmm, I really like the idea.
Speaker 0: That's a good one.
Speaker 1: I never saw a battle bot that was cool and battle bots were so lame.
Speaker 0: now There are a few.
Speaker 0: the best ones are the ones that would scoop.
Speaker 0: they were so low to the ground.
Speaker 0: They would scoop up under the opposing robot and then they had buzz saws on their top.
Speaker 0: So when the opposing robot was on top of them, it would get all cut up.
Speaker 0: Those are the best ones.
Speaker 1: I think the real problem with battle bots aside from the restrictive rules was the fact that it was really kind of amateur Backyard whatever now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those robots controlled so imprecisely like they would hobble around.
Speaker 0: They weren't like, you know, the controls weren't dead-on They.
Speaker 0: if I was making a robot I would have the controls be so tight That would be.
Speaker 0: I would concentrate on that more than they make.
Speaker 0: how many times you'll make robots that had like Swinging attack arms and the arms like miss every time it's like?
Speaker 0: or they'd like try to rotate it into position And it wouldn't quite work.
Speaker 1: Also the so-called damage zones or whatever.
Speaker 1: We're totally lame and weak.
Speaker 1: My idea of a damage zone is a plate and above that plate is a hundred pound weight that is smashing down Repeatedly and continuously as hard as it can.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you might that might be hard to maintain that weight But even so it's still pretty.
Speaker 0: that's that would be much better.
Speaker 1: Just something cool.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: pits fire Acid so definitely needs to be fire involved.
Speaker 1: The battle bots didn't show enough damage or weren't able to be constructed in such a way as to cause enough damage to be interesting.
Speaker 1: Now here is the simplest most obvious solution kick out the kids and the backyard bullshit.
Speaker 1: Why don't they have the board engineers at IBM and the free engineers at Lockheed Martin and military contractors?
Speaker 1: I'm talking make battle bots f-fucking-1.
Speaker 1: I want to see board engineers from IBM making death machines that fight against equally awesome death machines from Lockheed.
Speaker 0: I want them to have to do this shit in the middle of like the desert where no one will get killed because it's so Fucking dangerous.
Speaker 0: I see like honestly like six foot tall like freaking.
Speaker 0: Holy shit.
Speaker 0: It's a tank on legs I want to see like EMPs.
Speaker 1: I want oh, man.
Speaker 1: I want this to be awesome and battle bots is not awesome.
Speaker 0: I want to see like a robot that like walks over really quickly like has a Prehensile hands rips the head off the other robot like connects to its internal circuitry Jams the remote control signal makes the other robot turn around and kill.
Speaker 0: It's the person controlling it.
Speaker 0: Scratch that last part yeah, but that'd be good in the cartoon though.
Speaker 1: I think you see where I'm going with this.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Anyway, it is time for things of the day.
Speaker 0: Oh that wasn't your thing today.
Speaker 1: No that wasn't my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Okay, let me do my thing a day.
Speaker 1: Are you wanna go first?
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay?
Speaker 0: You know the choose your own adventure books right?
Speaker 1: ah those books.
Speaker 1: the best part about those books was dying.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's actually an interview with the guy who created the choose your own adventure books.
Speaker 0: on the comic geek speak podcast.
Speaker 0: They did it a long time ago, but it's a. it's a great interview.
Speaker 1: I was glad that everyone read those books the way I did.
Speaker 1: you have like four fingers and four different pages.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, oh, yeah, but anyway some guy made a little graph.
Speaker 0: You know like like in the computer science sense of the.
Speaker 0: choose your own adventure book.
Speaker 0: it starts at page one And it's sort of you know it's like okay, then you go to page two.
Speaker 0: It's the only place you can go.
Speaker 0: then three is the only place you can go.
Speaker 0: then you go to four or six and he Has every ending labeled.
Speaker 0: so it's like there are 121 pages 36 endings 12 full page illustrations one start page 44 choices 33 continuing pages, which are just pages that say turn.
Speaker 0: you know go to the next page.
Speaker 0: And some of these endings you can look and they're.
Speaker 0: they're pretty funny And they're really good.
Speaker 0: endings are really far away from the start and the thing that really gets Makes me laugh.
Speaker 0: the most is on page 113. you have a choice.
Speaker 0: It will either send you to page 120 or 121. page 120 Cousins rich.
Speaker 0: that's the ending.
Speaker 0: page 121 rich.
Speaker 0: It's like on the final page.
Speaker 0: you choose between your rich and your cousins are rich.
Speaker 0: I Think Man, I have so many.
Speaker 0: this is the same book where the ending could be free ghost or which dies I remember one Or die in tomb Where you get captured.
Speaker 1: it's like at this one end.
Speaker 1: if it would choose your own adventure It was and it's pretty much.
Speaker 1: you spend the rest of your life in the prison planet, and then it's like the end.
Speaker 1: or If you want to try and escape go to page whatever and on page whatever you fucking get shot to death.
Speaker 0: Here's another funny one from this book.
Speaker 0: at.
Speaker 0: the book is oh by the way the book He made a graph of is the mystery of chimney rock On page one.
Speaker 1: I remember that one is page one.
Speaker 0: oh something I can't tell.
Speaker 0: right and a page one.
Speaker 0: oh something.
Speaker 0: you have a choice you can either look back or don't look back.
Speaker 1: You don't want to look back.
Speaker 0: if you don't look back it sends you to the page You're currently on and you just repeat the page.
Speaker 0: Look back you die.
Speaker 0: so basically don't look back.
Speaker 0: Don't look back.
Speaker 0: eventually you look back you die.
Speaker 1: ah Man someone needs to revitalize and bring back.
Speaker 1: choose your own adventure.
Speaker 0: But they are the guy who may originally made them is doing it.
Speaker 1: where I never see this?
Speaker 0: They're in the store.
Speaker 0: go to borders.
Speaker 0: They want to go to Amazon search.
Speaker 0: choose your own adventure.
Speaker 1: You're all man.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, you're gonna buy some kitty books.
Speaker 1: I think we're gonna do a Thursday or yeah All right, well you know get on that anyway, so uh you might have seen this video.
Speaker 1: this video is on college humor.
Speaker 1: It's on YouTube.
Speaker 1: It's on dig.
Speaker 1: It's all over the place, but It's all set the scene for you.
Speaker 1: You know when you're a kid in elementary school or preschool you play the parachute game Where everyone stands around a parachute you wave it up and down with balls in the middle and then at the end like the big Finale y'all go up, and then you get inside and you pull it down, and then you're all inside the parachute And it's super cool.
Speaker 0: Oh the big giant parachute in elementary school is way awesome.
Speaker 1: I remember I'd always like leave a crack behind me and try to make it collapse on everyone before we got out.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but anyway all right That's awesome for little kids, and I could even enjoy doing that once or twice now.
Speaker 1: So the scene is.
Speaker 1: we're at a college campus.
Speaker 1: in the distance to the right is a group of parents and prospective Students getting a tour of the campus.
Speaker 1: our our protagonists in the window are narrating They're obviously high.
Speaker 1: They're way high here.
Speaker 1: I'm coughing.
Speaker 0: They are test owned.
Speaker 1: however They're that cool college kind of stone not that dammit Duane kind of stone, and it's still stone now.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying that stone is awesome But there's a difference between the cool stone guy who you just kind of go hey to and walk away and dammit Duane.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there is and now fast move forward a bit and in the center of the screen There's a parachute, and they're obviously a bunch of people playing the parachute game.
Speaker 0: inside the parachute This is a bunch of people sitting in it And it's sort of full of air and it's kind of moving around like a little colorful mushroom on the ground.
Speaker 1: Standing outside of the parachute is a police officer or perhaps a campus security guy?
Speaker 0: We can't tell.
Speaker 1: it looks like an actual police officer.
Speaker 1: again.
Speaker 1: RIT's campus safety looked like actual police officers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they sure did.
Speaker 1: of course up when they got hit with that bottle They left and then the real police officers came followed by the riot police.
Speaker 1: They sure did told that story didn't we?
Speaker 0: I'm sure we must have.
Speaker 1: ah if we didn't we were involved in a riot once And we got no riot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not not much of a riot.
Speaker 1: I got pepper-balled.
Speaker 1: It wasn't cool.
Speaker 1: Well indirectly yes It wasn't cool.
Speaker 0: No it wasn't cool.
Speaker 1: I imagine directly is that times a million, and I imagine it's sucking.
Speaker 1: yeah Yeah, something like that, but uh so in that parachute there are 20 Maybe 25 people.
Speaker 1: now What are they doing?
Speaker 1: their hotboxing?
Speaker 1: hotboxing is a term for smoking weed in a group in an enclosed space?
Speaker 0: I was not aware of this until just now.
Speaker 1: Now that is probably the most efficient way to smoke your drug of choice And I imagine so because you're all the secondary smoke here.
Speaker 0: You're saving it up.
Speaker 0: You know you you can keep inhaling it even when you're not.
Speaker 0: you know smoking directly.
Speaker 0: if you're passing something around you know You're always getting some.
Speaker 0: it's not bad.
Speaker 1: and also imagine the atmosphere if you even if you think marijuana like you're against drugs And that sort of thing and you know whatever.
Speaker 1: imagine the people in that balloon.
Speaker 1: They're probably have you yeah parachute Yeah, in a balloon.
Speaker 1: not such a good idea.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: They're probably having it a freaking good time.
Speaker 1: I imagine that being a chaotic and wonderful environment in there.
Speaker 1: if you're into that sort of thing I mean think about that.
Speaker 1: you got the thrill of doing it in public out in the open with a whole bunch of people.
Speaker 1: You're also playing the parachute game, which is finding it up itself, and you're stoned which makes everything.
Speaker 1: That's fun a Thousand times more fun even if it's not fun to begin with.
Speaker 0: yeah pretty much so.
Speaker 0: supposedly so.
Speaker 1: the campus the campus safety or police officer obviously knows what's going on and Benny hilarity ensues.
Speaker 1: I got something to say about that because someone put the Benny Hill aka Yakety-sacks over the end of this.
Speaker 0: yeah people call this song like the Benny Hill song.
Speaker 0: No, the song is called yakety-sacks.
Speaker 1: get it right Benny Hill is just someone up and to use the realize that there are probably three tiers of people out there And I think that the tier that Scott and I are in or the minority by far I don't know I don't.
Speaker 0: I think the first group is the minority the people who actually saw Benny Hill back in the day.
Speaker 1: That's well.
Speaker 1: I've saw Benny Hill every day as a kid.
Speaker 1: No I didn't it was.
Speaker 1: I'd come home from school right in middle school and every day on TV as I came home was Monty Python's Flying Circus two episodes of it and then Benny Hill.
Speaker 0: we did not have the luxury of that.
Speaker 1: yeah Well I had Canadian TV, and let me tell you what Canadian TV is.
Speaker 1: American TV times a thousand.
Speaker 0: Yeah But not that.
Speaker 0: so there's people who actually know the fuck.
Speaker 0: Benny Hill is right.
Speaker 0: then there's people like me.
Speaker 0: We're come home from school, and I watch cartoons, but in the middle of those cartoons They'd be commercials from local cable television trying to sell like CD Compilations like you know pure funk and whatnot?
Speaker 0: actually pure funks not bad, but I have it.
Speaker 0: But they also tried to sell like Benny Hill VHS tapes and DVDs.
Speaker 0: They would always play that song and a lot of people you know all they know of Benny Hill is that commercial.
Speaker 0: that but everyone must have seen.
Speaker 1: but then I realized that there's probably a third tier.
Speaker 1: And these are the people who only know of this through parody.
Speaker 1: they've seen Family Guy's and Simpsons and YouTube videos making fun of this and Parodying it and they've seen
Speaker 0: everyone using this song in all sorts of videos and other places and saying Benny Hill in Association with the song
Speaker 1: and they probably don't even know who Benny Hill is granted.
Speaker 1: I'll admit I didn't find Benny Hill bad funny.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: He's not that funny.
Speaker 1: He's no Monty pythons flying.
Speaker 1: some Monty pythons fly.
Speaker 0: He's just sort of a classic generic slapstick kind of ha ha funny guy, but he's not super funny.
Speaker 0: But he's worthy of respect.
Speaker 0: And you shouldn't be going around saying Benny Hill if you don't know who the hell it is.
Speaker 1: Let me say this the sheer number of stoners who escaped from that parachute is epic.
Speaker 0: The cops should have gotten some backup to surround the parachute.
Speaker 0: then it would have been even more hilarious.
Speaker 1: He should have just opened fire.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't think he can do that.
Speaker 1: He could have just said we've got you surrounded.
Speaker 1: Nobody move.
Speaker 0: He could have tased them, bro Don't tase them bro.
Speaker 0: Hey, just taste the whole balloons.
Speaker 1: All right, so what do you got for me?
Speaker 0: What do I have?
Speaker 1: Oh, oh no thing of the day Did you forget?
Speaker 1: No, I sent the link to you and then I sort of did you get so caught up in my thing of the day That you forgot your own thing of the day.
Speaker 0: No, I already used my thing.
Speaker 0: There's choose your own adventure graph.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, it was nevermind.
Speaker 0: Dumbass.
Speaker 0: I'm dumb.
Speaker 0: That's why you're confusing me.
Speaker 1: So, uh, I have a memory.
Speaker 1: this memory is of being at Cedar Point when I was a kid a very young kid and Cedar Point, I don't know if it's still there but for much of my childhood, I think Cedar Point is still there.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 1: this thing at Cedar Point All right Because in Cedar Point was an arcade a massive arcade and half of this arcade had new games.
Speaker 1: But half of the arcade had basically Katsu Kans video gaming room times a thousand.
Speaker 1: They had every old arcade cabinet ever man.
Speaker 0: I remember when there were big arcades like that.
Speaker 1: Those are the days like as much as I love roller coasters I would spend like half a day in this arcade at Cedar Point.
Speaker 1: every year You want to go to New Hampshire and go to the the fun spot we should but honestly if it's still there the arcade at Cedar Point with the classic arcade games was like the best fucking arcade I've ever been into.
Speaker 0: my sesame street also has a very impressive arcade but fun spot is by far the number one arcade.
Speaker 0: There is no question.
Speaker 1: But uh, anyway, I remember a time in my life I was young and you know when you're out with your parents on a vacation you often don't get to Slip away and hang out with nerdy geeks or people are into the things you're into.
Speaker 1: Well at one point I remember I saw these like four punk kids play and they were about my age a little older.
Speaker 1: you know hip and cool kids and they were playing the Simpsons arcade game and They had been playing it for a while and I remember two of them left.
Speaker 1: so I walked over with my mom and we started playing with them and I learned at that moment that Anyone can be friends with anyone if standing in front of and playing a walk sideways beat-em-up in an arcade.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you the level of camaraderie in that game was was to the point that it has rarely been duplicated in my life.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you it was.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's my birthday party or someone else's but it was at the you know Somewhat relatively local arcade type place.
Speaker 0: and you know If you're at someone's birthday party you get a cup full of fucking tokens and they had you know The six-seat x-men machine with the two monitors.
Speaker 1: Oh man, and nothing moves the blob.
Speaker 1: Nothing moves the blob.
Speaker 0: That thing we rocked it.
Speaker 0: I brought it from the start and you know other kids switched in and out but I was Cyclops from beginning to end, baby That was some good time.
Speaker 1: There's something about those walk sideways co-op beat-em-up games where especially in the arcade Even though really it was just an exercise in pumping quarters in until you win and skill would basically Reduce the number of quarters somewhat but not as much as you'd think.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's pretty well.
Speaker 0: I mean cuz you could only get like your power so many times which you clear out the screen, right?
Speaker 0: So you could sort of work together all about Colossus and it would be like, okay on this screen We can beat up the guys with our normal powers or death screen.
Speaker 0: We can beat up our guys our own powers.
Speaker 0: Okay, we're not gonna beat this screen.
Speaker 0: unless someone uses a power you use the power.
Speaker 1: Okay, you know people just know in common sense like how to fight the boss jump strike jump away jump strike jump away stand back.
Speaker 1: Well, he does well.
Speaker 0: Ninja Turtles was all about that.
Speaker 0: we would think cuz you had the jump kick the jump slash and the regular slashes and you had to mix them up just Properly and you could actually Ninja Turtles had some I guess Minor amounts of skill to it.
Speaker 0: if you knew how to fight each kind of guy without getting hit You could get really far without putting in too many quarters.
Speaker 0: But
Speaker 1: there is definitely something about the formula of those arcade beat-em-ups where even though the skill didn't matter so much it was just a matter of basically pumping in cool in order to be cool and still be there with everyone, but the for some reason these games Fostered this sense of friendship and you get really into it and it would always become like this epic quest like hey guys Wanna fucking beat the Simpsons?
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's go want to beat Dungeons & Dragons.
Speaker 0: Dungeons & Dragons one.
Speaker 0: I forgot about that.
Speaker 0: Golden Axe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but now yeah, basically the beat the side-scrolling beat-em-up.
Speaker 0: I mean there were co-op games before but the side-scrolling beat-em-up is the original co-op Genre as far as I'm concerned, you know, I mean you look those are the first games where people are like, okay We're in this together, you know, you take the right you take the left you do this you do that you use your power I'll use mine, etc.
Speaker 0: Etc.
Speaker 1: Now, of course arcade non arcade Regardless far and away.
Speaker 1: I think the best one of these ever is River City Ransom But that deserves a show in and of itself.
Speaker 1: So we're not even gonna talk about it.
Speaker 0: Well, we can talk about a little bit.
Speaker 1: I just fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: River City Ransom was great was better than other Games.
Speaker 0: even it was way ahead of its time because unlike other side-scrolling beat-em-ups River City Ransom The items actually worked properly.
Speaker 1: It was somewhat nonlinear.
Speaker 0: It had RPG elements of getting money and buying shit.
Speaker 1: It was really funny.
Speaker 0: You could actually go anywhere you wanted instead of just continually going right beating up the bad guys.
Speaker 0: go right beat up the bad guys.
Speaker 0: it was actually really complex for the NES.
Speaker 1: and Yeah, if ever a game the music is awesome.
Speaker 1: ever a game has been in such dire need of a proper Perfectly making the dodgeball in the DS.
Speaker 0: They gotta bring back the River City Ransom.
Speaker 1: Oh god, super dodgeball.
Speaker 0: It's not a beat-em-up.
Speaker 0: You can't talk about it.
Speaker 1: It's one of my favorite games in any medium ever.
Speaker 0: Okay, oh that game You know the Ninja Turtles one.
Speaker 0: I'll go talk about that because this turtles game in the arcade it was pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: It's one of those arcade games that you know, it works so well.
Speaker 0: cuz you know for turtles No, it makes sense for joysticks.
Speaker 0: Hey, you know it was.
Speaker 1: you fight the bebop you spider you fight the rock steady.
Speaker 0: for a large portion of my childhood That was in.
Speaker 0: that was pretty much the game that was in every arcade and it was just like the cartoon.
Speaker 0: and this is Of time where the arcade was superior to the home console.
Speaker 1: people would always talk like man.
Speaker 1: Imagine if you could have arcade graphics at home and that was why the Neo Geo was so legendary among kids.
Speaker 1: But no one actually had it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the thing was is I had the Ninja Turtles to Arcade edition for the NES and it was almost as good.
Speaker 0: It was almost as good as the original.
Speaker 0: you had all the same moves.
Speaker 0: There are actually two additional levels in the game.
Speaker 0: The only things that were different was that it was you could actually sort of get to the end of the game with.
Speaker 0: you know The number, you know lives they gave you.
Speaker 0: you could beat the game and without spending any money.
Speaker 0: well, except for the $50 to buy it and This the music was a little worse.
Speaker 0: The graphics were a little worse.
Speaker 0: But and and the one part that I think was the most Disappointing was that they took out the part of the game where you fight bebop and rock steady at the same time.
Speaker 0: That was a good part of the game Yeah, but they added in other parts like riding the skateboards and fighting the wolf guy and the level with the Tigers.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was a good one.
Speaker 1: I think my favorite of the arcade ones.
Speaker 1: However, I mean X-Men has a special place in my heart.
Speaker 1: I was always colossus.
Speaker 0: Well, it's unlike Simpsons Ninja Turtles.
Speaker 0: I think those games are all in the same engine Although I don't want to look it up right now.
Speaker 1: They feel like they were.
Speaker 0: they feel like they were the same engine with different graphics on them But the X-Men had the six players which really and it was at the height of the popularity of X-Men that helped it a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was like cartoon X-Men.
Speaker 1: That's my.
Speaker 1: that's the only X-Men.
Speaker 1: I really really like.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Ah But those were good games, but I think my favorite arcade walk sideways beat him up will always be Final Fight.
Speaker 0: Final Fight was in the arcade.
Speaker 0: Final Fight was like an NES SNES game.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure there's an arcade version.
Speaker 0: I've never played an arcade Final Fight.
Speaker 1: Anyway, what's your favorite game?
Speaker 1: and I'll look that shit up.
Speaker 0: Let's see streets of see streets of rage.
Speaker 0: There's like a whole series of streets of rage and you know, I think streets of rage 2 might be the best Or at least my most favorite.
Speaker 0: But all the streets of rages are kind of good because it.
Speaker 0: the thing about those is that you had this choice of characters.
Speaker 0: I liked all the characters but blaze was actually pretty hot One of the first characters.
Speaker 0: when you're like, you know a 13 year old.
Speaker 0: in those days You try to be like doing a jump kick so you can see more leg action Released in the arcade in January of 1990.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 0: I have never seen a final fight.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: I have seen that we we'd be sinful not to mention the double dragons Because I will talk about double dragon in a second.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I gotta say there was nothing in my childhood more satisfying than as Hagar Taking a guy shoving his face into my butt and crushing him.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean in streets of rage you would you know grab on to someone's head flip over them flip back over them Just infinitely because it was fun then push another button and throw them across the screen at other guys who would then get hit.
Speaker 0: That was good times.
Speaker 0: And also the streets of rage had the good weapons as well.
Speaker 0: See it like a. Nintendo had all the final fights and Genesis had all the streets of rages and it was there.
Speaker 0: basically, you know Technically mostly the same kind of game.
Speaker 0: neither one was technically superior to the other.
Speaker 0: they just had different characters different settings.
Speaker 0: You know, I guess streets of rage.
Speaker 0: you had to sort of push the button in the cop car shoots a missile at the screen action, but Final fight had the push a button and you sort of throw a fireball which kills all the guys.
Speaker 1: action I remember in.
Speaker 1: uh, I think there was a. I think it was streets of rage on the Sega Game Gear.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there probably was not a great game.
Speaker 0: I had it No, but you know that the thing is these beat-em-up games are largely dead With kind of good reason, I mean I remember I played some sort of 3d beat-em-up ish game on the ps1.
Speaker 0: we're like you'd walk around these like Small 3d areas beating guys up.
Speaker 0: It was kind of a you know, and I don't you know.
Speaker 0: since then I think there's like been games like God hand and whatever but not too many.
Speaker 0: beat-em-up is sort of a.
Speaker 1: well They I think it's more that they're not super popular.
Speaker 0: No, not really Even though I think if they were brought back properly they would be super popular like River City Ransom could still do really well if you just You know like streets of rage probably wouldn't do that.
Speaker 0: Well today because it's pretty much walk sideways push B occasionally push a right but River City Ransom where you got weapons that actually work Smartly and such I think that that would be really popular.
Speaker 1: now You know, it also would probably work really really well, but it would take some doing.
Speaker 1: this is one of those you know pie in the sky ideas and this is also when I say MMO.
Speaker 1: Ignore everything bullshit, you know about MMOs.
Speaker 1: MMO does not mean Wow It does not mean MMO RPG, but imagine a massively multiplayer online River City Ransom or equivalent.
Speaker 0: Isn't that basically with that city of heroes is supposed to be?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it could have been done so much better and I Have a lot to say about that.
Speaker 0: I've never played it.
Speaker 0: So I don't know but that's what I've you know.
Speaker 0: That's what people basically said.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I think superhero 3d beat-em-up MMO.
Speaker 1: I think it could have been executed a lot better and with a lot less of the I don't know bad Trappings of most MMO games today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see the thing is after you know The super early beat-em-ups right you being rigid double dragon was like, you know the game That's.
Speaker 0: I don't know if that was the first one but I was the first one.
Speaker 0: that sort of got was all about the elbow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the problem with double dragon right is double dragon - great game.
Speaker 1: double dragon 3 one of the worst fucking games ever.
Speaker 0: Not just not that but it's that double dragon as a whole.
Speaker 0: the controls really were not good.
Speaker 0: You'd like push one button to attack to the right and another button to attack to the left and that was sort of like.
Speaker 0: It just didn't work out very well at all.
Speaker 1: a lot of game.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is there's a lot of these games came out in the early days when controls weren't fully standardized yet and people I mean Renegade I remember like depending which direction you were facing different buttons did different things and it was just so Confusing.
Speaker 0: yeah, but double dragon, you know, it's a classic and double dragon - is probably the best of the bunch.
Speaker 0: But the controls can be quite annoying.
Speaker 0: I mean It's not obvious how to do the jump spinning kick But it's pretty much necessary to be able to do it on command in order to win.
Speaker 1: Well double dragon 3.
Speaker 1: I think we can watch the angry video game nerd about that bullshit.
Speaker 0: You sure can.
Speaker 0: but you know when double dragon sort of later.
Speaker 0: You know later double dragon games like they made it into a fight a stupid fighting game and then a stupid cartoon based on The stupid fighting game.
Speaker 0: and you know That's when it stopped being a beat-em-up and that's when the final fights in the streets of rages came in.
Speaker 1: Pretty much though I mean if you've never played one of these games before don't like go out and play them by yourself because they're not fun.
Speaker 1: You really need to play these games with someone.
Speaker 1: so if you're ever at an arcade with your friends some sort of classic arcade somewhere and You see a Simpsons arcade machine Grab three friends and just decide you're going to beat it and you will probably have a good time Even though the game itself from a technical level is not that good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Simpsons one actually is a very good choice, you know Because I imagine two people who have never played a beat-em-up like trying to play streets of rage.
Speaker 0: It might get kind of boring.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much like okay.
Speaker 0: We're beating up different guys.
Speaker 0: Here's the guys with different hair color.
Speaker 0: Okay, now we're beating up a fat guy.
Speaker 0: Okay, now we're beating up a bartender.
Speaker 0: It's like alright, come on And then at the end of the game you beat up a businessman with a gun.
Speaker 0: Oh my god a gun, right?
Speaker 0: But the Simpsons actually has all sorts of Simpsons shit going on all over the place and it's actually you know The stuff that's on screen while the game itself is just a beat-em-up.
Speaker 0: The stuff on screen can be very entertaining if you're a Simpsons fan at all.
Speaker 1: I played that game with my parents more than once and they enjoyed it.
Speaker 0: Yeah just like the Ninja Turtles one is only really entertaining if you're a ninja.
Speaker 0: if you know something about Ninja Turtles at least the Cartoon and you're a fan then that game will really really work for you because you'll see all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 0: Be like, oh man, look at that.
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: Look at that.
Speaker 1: Is that all we have to say?
Speaker 0: I don't know you got any thing to say about beat-em-ups not terribly I mean.
Speaker 1: it seems like it's kind of like when we played Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles.
Speaker 1: beat-em-ups as they have pretty much always been implemented with the possible exception of River City Ransom are Primarily games of the experience and by the experience, I mean the experience of playing them with someone else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's not much I mean.
Speaker 0: some of them can be really hard and some of them can have sort of complex Near fighting game level, but you know, you're not gonna have fun playing the x-men arcade game all the way through by yourself.
Speaker 0: No, not too much.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much Walk.
Speaker 0: hold to the right whenever a bad guy gets near you tap the button repeatedly and remember that nothing moves the blob.
Speaker 0: Pretty much anyone moves the blob very easily just by hitting it.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.