Speaker 1: It's Wednesday January 23rd, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We review the for immigrants manga.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well, we were almost gonna go to a con this weekend almost.
Speaker 0: maybe this is tiny tiny chance.
Speaker 0: We'll go.
Speaker 1: I think the chance is zero.
Speaker 1: I'm already planning on going skiing this weekend.
Speaker 0: I'm also planning on working on stuff instead of going.
Speaker 0: but yeah this we still a tiny chance as we don't go.
Speaker 1: I mean we haven't been to gaming cons a lot ever since uber con moved an hour further south and didn't have Luke crane and it's like wow, there's no reason to go now.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so oh, there's this gaming con dreamation this weekend.
Speaker 1: Hey screw it.
Speaker 1: Let's go.
Speaker 1: Luke.
Speaker 0: Crane's gonna be there.
Speaker 1: and Yeah, then we realized Oh Luke cranes events according to I think the con chair whoever was who emailed us back filled up within quote minutes of the schedule going online.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess he's a hit right and he'd be such a hit Making more money.
Speaker 0: think about this.
Speaker 1: We were about to go to a con and sign up to do multiple events run by one guy With whom we have gone to multiple events in the past.
Speaker 1: I can imagine us getting there him saying you guys again What the fuck?
Speaker 1: Let me choke burning wheel to someone else.
Speaker 0: I mean in a hit.
Speaker 0: already know it exists in the history of role-playing.
Speaker 0: have there ever been like rock star dungeon masters?
Speaker 0: And like he is?
Speaker 1: I mean, I think the closest thing is Theoretical.
Speaker 1: I mean in terms of famousness or awesomeness you could look at like Gary guy guy.
Speaker 1: But I mean when Gary guy gags when was the last time he ran a campaign for anyone?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean seriously I guess I guess if he ran a thing at a convention like ran a game for people that people would sign up like crazy But mostly for his name, you know people Luke crane isn't a famous name.
Speaker 0: people are signing up because his games are actually awesome.
Speaker 1: Luke crane should be a famous name.
Speaker 0: However, god damn it's like, you know, I don't know I'm not really.
Speaker 0: I'm saying we're people who aren't deep into that circle.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm sure people who are deeper into the gaming cons recognize other names of people running games and sign up.
Speaker 0: You know based on that.
Speaker 0: but to think that someone you know Has a name and you just you sign up for a game based on the name alone and you're not a gaming con person That's pretty big.
Speaker 1: It's funny.
Speaker 1: Otherwise and other people seem to do the same thing.
Speaker 1: They look and if there's a burning wheel event does not excite them.
Speaker 1: It only excites them if they see run by Luke crane.
Speaker 0: Well, actually, I think some of the other burning wheel events did fill up also.
Speaker 1: Oh, of course they did but I wonder how many of those people didn't realize that while it's probably gonna be awesome It's not Luke himself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or maybe it is, you know that guy.
Speaker 1: he'd probably run two burning wheels simultaneously Just in two different rooms, but also There was some other either.
Speaker 0: they said they were they were gonna talk to him about.
Speaker 0: you know Dexcon Which is the con I was planning on going to which is run by the same people in July That they're gonna try to get Luke to bring more DMS to run more burning wheels.
Speaker 1: I'd say we could do it, but I'm not ready for that.
Speaker 0: No, no, not at all.
Speaker 0: I would be people who signed up for my game would be quite disappointed.
Speaker 1: But speaking of cons, I'm not gonna go and talk about this forever.
Speaker 1: But I have to point out that in February There's a convention called Katsucon pretty much one of my favorite guns everywhere.
Speaker 1: What if everywhere the point is we are running a whole crazy ton of events there?
Speaker 1: We're gonna be in the video game room though.
Speaker 1: Every time we're not running crazy events.
Speaker 1: I highly recommend if you're a fan of geek nights and a fan of anime that you go to Katsucon.
Speaker 0: It's February 15 16 17.
Speaker 0: So not this weekend not the weekend after that not the weekend after that But the weekend after that.
Speaker 1: Now there has been a schedule change.
Speaker 1: We're only running six events instead of seven.
Speaker 0: Oh, no six events.
Speaker 1: I think they highlighting event is going to be the Late show Katsu late night Katsucon Friday night from 1030 to 1 a.m Why oh, so so wait, let me see what the description of that event is in the con book.
Speaker 0: It says right here Oh, um watch Scott sleep.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, that's a wonderful event.
Speaker 1: I thought you said you had a monologue written.
Speaker 1: Shit great good game.
Speaker 0: I got like four weeks, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see how that goes.
Speaker 1: yeah anyway in actual anime news up a while ago we talked about a show that we were really excited about because of the trailer and then we watched the show and it was an okay show but It was not quite what I expected.
Speaker 1: well that show was picked up and now it is going to be available and in fact on February 19th the first DVD of Moonlight Mile is going to be coming out in the US for you to see in English.
Speaker 0: Didn't we do a geek nice about?
Speaker 0: we did a geek nights about Moonlight Mile.
Speaker 1: we did but I think we have a lot of new listeners since then.
Speaker 1: and also I want to remind you it's out if you think a show about men striving to become astronauts and beef and friendship and camaraderie and all that business in space.
Speaker 1: and Independently of that you really want to see a bunch of Sherpas have an orgy.
Speaker 1: The show is for you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess two female Sherpas.
Speaker 1: Well, then there was the guys there and then there's that other random sex scene in episode 2 and then I think there's a random Sex scene in at least one per episode for the rest of the show.
Speaker 0: I've seen the manga for it in various Japanese bookstores.
Speaker 0: I'm wondering how close the manga is to the a nine.
Speaker 1: well, it is gonna be on a Anime networks video on demand and the end of the end of this month.
Speaker 0: So, huh?
Speaker 0: Oh, I guess they gotta put something on that anime network, right?
Speaker 0: They pretty much put every a TV show on there.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so yeah and a TV.
Speaker 1: pick this up.
Speaker 0: So Is that I got?
Speaker 1: that's all I got.
Speaker 0: Okay, so there's no anime news.
Speaker 1: There's nothing to talk about.
Speaker 0: There's no anime news.
Speaker 0: That's why you fight geek bite is you're gonna have her a lot of geek bites on Wednesday because a lot of Comics and things that I read.
Speaker 0: and why an anime that I watch that rim doesn't.
Speaker 0: and this is a way to sort of get Them out to you without waiting until we can do a full show on them.
Speaker 0: So I'm actually gonna tell you about something mad old gonna talk to you about Galaxy Express 3 9 TV show.
Speaker 0: now Way back in the high school days like 98 99 right before I was big into the a-nines.
Speaker 0: I gotta stop saying a-nines.
Speaker 0: I was watching the sci-fi channel and there was like a week of anime and that's.
Speaker 0: that was like sort of like the tipping point In the anime fandom of myself.
Speaker 1: Wow for me.
Speaker 1: It was in fourth grade.
Speaker 1: Yeah on the sci-fi network fan Ain't mad.
Speaker 0: after project a okay It's like a little slope.
Speaker 0: and then that we get that week of anime was like the the peak and then it just sort of Was downhill like whoosh from there into the anime club, right?
Speaker 0: But one of the things they showed was the Galaxy Express 3 9 movie and then the second Galaxy Express 3 9 movie and More than any other other movies that I saw that week.
Speaker 0: Those were the ones that were like, oh man is There's.
Speaker 0: there's not much get that gets better for me in anime than watching some outer space Opera, Leiji Matsumoto late at night in the dark.
Speaker 1: Hello, I recall I think I watched like earth say Otsu or two and then I fell asleep before three nines.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that one works though for late night dark aloneness.
Speaker 0: That's a good sort.
Speaker 0: semi space opera ish kind of anime is it?
Speaker 0: is that kind of late night mood, you know?
Speaker 0: but anyway, so I had watched the movies.
Speaker 0: and You know If you don't realize the first Galaxy Express 3 9 movie is a compilation movie that sort of summarizes the TV show And you know what more than any compilation movie I've ever seen it Summarizes the TV show up damn Well, like it is a substitute for the TV show if you do not want to watch a hundred and thirteen TV episodes.
Speaker 0: but the hundred and thirteen TV TV episodes Surprisingly are not like, you know bad.
Speaker 0: It's not like they cut out bad stuff It's just that the TV show is not monster of the week.
Speaker 0: It's more like planet of the week.
Speaker 0: you know every every week the train stops at a different planet and they get out and they do something and then they get back on the train, you know.
Speaker 0: and Thing is slowly over time throughout the series.
Speaker 0: They reveal more and more things about the main plot, you know, like oh my tell is all mysterious.
Speaker 0: and oh Where did they?
Speaker 0: you know that gun belong to someone who to belong to or there's a train in space.
Speaker 0: Where is it gonna go?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is from watching the TV show.
Speaker 0: I think even though the compilation movie is still fantastic and that's something everyone should see the TV show is also fantastic.
Speaker 0: I mean a lot of these.
Speaker 0: some of the planets of the week are kind of weird like there's one where they get off a Planet where these amorphous blobs live.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that that episode was not so good.
Speaker 1: But hey nothing wrong with a movie.
Speaker 1: How dare you discriminate?
Speaker 0: They weren't movies.
Speaker 0: They were not good.
Speaker 1: No movie games.
Speaker 0: No, no movie games Right now.
Speaker 0: but something that what I like about the show is that first of all You get to see a lot more of the universe like you're seeing these like non 3-9 trains and all this other stuff going on that you don't get to see so much in the movie.
Speaker 0: and Also each episode sometimes is a multi-part story.
Speaker 0: but you know each I guess story within the TV show has a really good like sci-fi kind of message to it and it's like Granted the message of all.
Speaker 1: pretty much every one of these works always seems to come down to something along the lines of ah Gave up my humanity, but for what I sure hope I don't give up your humanity.
Speaker 0: Actually, a lot of them aren't about humanity.
Speaker 0: There's some about environment stuff and some about family and some about you know Being poverty.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but you cannot deny that a lot of them involve Man.
Speaker 1: someone gave up their humanity.
Speaker 0: the main workout for the main theme of the show is you know good Turning yourself into changing your regular body for a machine body.
Speaker 0: Do you see some people regretting it and some people enjoying it and some people liking it?
Speaker 0: but then being assholes and you know They show it they pretty much show you all sides.
Speaker 0: and unlike the movie which is sort of just like machine bodies bad The TV show sort of really mixes it up over time and any one of these episodes make would make a real pretty decent Short sci-fi story on its own.
Speaker 1: I can give you all the one warning.
Speaker 1: It's not really a warning because I love this stuff.
Speaker 1: I eat it up, but I will say Be prepared anytime you watch any leji Matsumoto work for not drama, but melodrama.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: uh, there's people fan subbing it right now.
Speaker 0: They just put out episode 24 today, and I'm gonna watch all this fair.
Speaker 0: Watch out I'm watching every single episode and I Really like that closing song - it reminds me a lot of those old show closing songs like the Macross closing.
Speaker 1: So I like all that old kind of anime opener closer music.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the opening song is like, you know a Japanese guy going You know one of those.
Speaker 0: I Like this action.
Speaker 0: It's good action.
Speaker 0: If you're if you're not downloading the fan subs, maybe you should you're not gonna ever.
Speaker 0: It's never gonna be on DVD.
Speaker 0: Well, who's gonna be able to sell a hundred and thirteen episodes of a show from like 1979?
Speaker 1: Well, I was older than I am someday.
Speaker 1: It'll be in the public domain.
Speaker 1: Yeah after I die Things of the day So everyone gets one.
Speaker 1: I mean Scott and I have our initial D and Some one of our friends watches bleach, you know, everyone has their one like shonen fighting kind of.
Speaker 1: oh my god is he gonna do the thing for episode long battle between two people kind of show.
Speaker 1: everyone gets one that they really like and Emily has recently found hers.
Speaker 1: It's this baseball show and it's just crazy the pitcher catcher.
Speaker 1: Something's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Oh my god drama, but I just wanted to watch a baseball anime, but it's hard to get them because they're not in English.
Speaker 1: Well, this one's being fansubbed.
Speaker 0: no really, I believe it's a cold I don't even remember.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can partly because I'm in Windows.
Speaker 1: now I'm using my fancy cool edit Pro instead of any sort of crap program in Linux.
Speaker 1: but the problem is Windows not so great and Windows not used so often.
Speaker 1: so Japanese no worky.
Speaker 1: a lot of question marks here.
Speaker 1: All right, but uh, you know in America We have fan art and fan works, but they always take that kind of to the next level.
Speaker 0: in Japan Yeah, the cosplay is way better than ours Daikon animation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we lose they rule.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but one one thing that is done in Japan and this is being done more and more partly just because technology is making it Easier, but at the same time this is the kind of thing where you look and say wow I think I'll just draw fan art.
Speaker 1: people take you might have seen these before the opener to a show and Then they take characters from another show and they fully Reanimate the opener to the first show with the characters and the inside jokes from the second show.
Speaker 1: Now granted this is not.
Speaker 1: I was very very impressed by this until Emily pointed out that most of these people either Rotoscope or trace or just like over right overdo it with keyframes and just figure and just reanimate exactly change the heads.
Speaker 1: Yeah, flash helps a lot But at the same time that's still quite a bit of work.
Speaker 0: It is a lot more work than making an AMV where you just copying cutting and pasting.
Speaker 1: But of all of these this part of the high one of the highest quality ones and it is to that baseball show.
Speaker 1: It is the opener to asa manga.
Speaker 1: daioh, but it is that show.
Speaker 1: It's pretty high quality is pretty high.
Speaker 0: But the entertainment value for me was not so high.
Speaker 1: You didn't even watch it.
Speaker 0: I watched part of it.
Speaker 1: You watch two seconds of it before I opened up another window to look something up.
Speaker 0: No, I watched it before Emily sent it to me the other day.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, you're just a cold-hearted bass I was like 10 15 seconds of.
Speaker 0: Then I said I basically said oh I get the joke, okay, I'm done.
Speaker 1: I think it's really funny.
Speaker 1: and also if you're looking for a crazy initial d-style baseball show Whatever the show is called question mark question mark question mark plus question mark.
Speaker 0: Ooh, it sounds like good show to me All right.
Speaker 0: So check this out.
Speaker 0: You know Totoro, right?
Speaker 1: I do.
Speaker 0: we should do a show on Totoro probably.
Speaker 0: Maybe you have to watch Totoro again.
Speaker 0: Okay a long time.
Speaker 0: you know that.
Speaker 0: the Picture that always you always see if Totoro at the bus stop with the umbrella and the girl hiding under it whatever, right?
Speaker 0: Some guy who lives in?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I guess this is Nagasaki because it says on the top of the web page web news the Nagasaki shimbun HP.
Speaker 0: I can't read anything else on the side obviously because it's in moon language but there's a picture of a guy of not the guy.
Speaker 0: but apparently a Guy made a Totoro statue with an umbrella and put it at the bus stop in his town and it looks just like The bus stop in Totoro, so if it's raining you can go to the bus stop and stand under the Totoro's umbrella.
Speaker 1: Did he do this with permission?
Speaker 1: Was it a commission?
Speaker 1: Did he just do it?
Speaker 0: I think he just did it like because he wanted to out of like niceness like a bored old retired man or something?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's not enough details in English for me to tell you but it's cool nonetheless.
Speaker 0: And there's a picture which is enough to make a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: So tonight To get right along with the main bit here.
Speaker 1: We're gonna talk about something.
Speaker 1: I guess you should all put on your erudite hat your highbrow hats.
Speaker 0: Yes Yes, we're not gonna talk with fake British accent, I mean we should put in our beanies cuz we're so such intellectual artistes.
Speaker 1: I believe you mean berets.
Speaker 1: All right beanies.
Speaker 1: the exact opposite.
Speaker 0: In my brain was a picture of a beret but out of my mouth came the word beanie.
Speaker 1: In fact, I would say if ever there were two hats that were diametrically opposed in the most extreme way possible It would be the beret and the beanie.
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: I would think we could have a three-way of The beret on the top and then down at the bottom left of the triangle is the beanie and the bottom right is the German Spike helmet.
Speaker 0: Well, I was thinking the spike helmet would definitely be in one part of the triangle and the beanie and the other.
Speaker 0: But I think that the beret would actually be somewhere between on the line between the beanie and the top hat.
Speaker 1: No, because the top hat is class without pretension I don't know.
Speaker 1: the beret you can't get away with unless you are a percussionist or you are in France.
Speaker 0: Well, then where do you place the bowler hat?
Speaker 1: The bowler hat is classy classier than the top hat.
Speaker 0: I say Anyway, let's talk about the the intellectual business.
Speaker 1: It's no puppy helmet.
Speaker 1: No, so we're gonna talk about tonight something kind of amazing something kind of interesting.
Speaker 1: It's not the.
Speaker 1: It's not like this great entertaining thing to read.
Speaker 1: it's more of a historical document It's the kind of thing you would read for a class.
Speaker 0: Yes, it's.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like that.
Speaker 0: It's a book where the the contents of the book itself, right are only fascinating from a meta perspective Sort of like, you know The the fact of what it is is more important than the actuality of what it is when you read it the content.
Speaker 1: So tonight we're going to talk about the the for immigrants manga which was written by a man named Henry kiyama in San Francisco and it chronicles the experience of Japanese immigrants.
Speaker 1: the United States from give or take 1904 to 1924 so turn of the century, you know late Industrial Revolution Like this is World Fair Times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and basically Way back in the early 20th century this Japanese guy comes to the u.s.
Speaker 0: He immigrates here to San Francisco and While he's here He sort of draws manga of his experiences.
Speaker 0: and the manga isn't sort of part English part Japanese that you know no one could really understand except for people who are in his situation.
Speaker 0: and You know, what happened was Frederick Schott who's like he's one of those epic kind of anime manga guy.
Speaker 0: He's pretty much like the the foremost Academic authority on animes and mangas at least the foremost English academic authority on animes and mangas and Tezuka and all that kind of Stuff.
Speaker 0: that's like what he does.
Speaker 0: He's like a professor of that.
Speaker 0: basically I'm sure the Wikipedia page about the guy he spoke to the RIT anime club once before we got there long before he got there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in fact in the anime club library unless the club stupidly got rid of him to this day There are several VHS tapes of his lectures.
Speaker 1: Yep Oh, wow, Fred Schoen has like the tiniest little Wikipedia page ever that needs some beefing up right there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's written a bunch of books.
Speaker 0: so if you're really interested in you know learning a lot about the history of anime and manga and all sorts of Intellectualisms around it that his books are the ones to read pretty much right away.
Speaker 0: But anyway, he was you know digging around doing his research and in some library He found like like a card like a card in the in the index, you know in the card catalog.
Speaker 1: Right that thing that we don't use anymore, you know, I'm not Physically touched a card catalog since I was in elementary school.
Speaker 0: I touched one In high school and even then in elementary school.
Speaker 1: There was a computer.
Speaker 0: Yep I used one in high school because the town library had gotten you know some like, you know VT 100s hooked up to some kind of system that had a thing right.
Speaker 0: you could also dial into it from home Which is cool.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, I realized something sadder.
Speaker 1: I haven't been inside of a library since I was a college student Yeah, me either.
Speaker 1: and even then the only time I ever went to that library was to take a nap or once to get a Book that I couldn't find online
Speaker 0: If I wasn't buying the comics on the cheap from the the discount place I would be going to the library to like, you know, take them out and then bring them back for free.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so he was digging around once doing research.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna go into too much detail on this because it's in the introduction to the book Which I suggest you read because it's the.
Speaker 0: I think it's the most, you know, three.
Speaker 1: I know a lot of people skip that sort of thing when they were, you know That's really the most important part of this book.
Speaker 1: I like the people who read Watchmen and then they skip all those words in between the pictures.
Speaker 0: You mean the most important parts?
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or at least, you know, just as important as the rest of the parts.
Speaker 0: There's some people who read Watchmen to skip the pirate parts, but the pirate.
Speaker 1: Ah, yeah, we've talked about that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so it talks about how Frederic show discovered this manga written by Henry kiyama You know when he was, you know, chronicling his his life as a Japanese immigrant in the US in the early 20th century Industrial Revolution Roaring to early roaring 20s kind of times and
Speaker 1: also during the kind of Ascendance of Japan to the world stage.
Speaker 1: I mean, this is right around the the The Russian Japanese war which was basically two Semi-western powers fighting to show who was more Western and apparently Western men have a big ol wall.
Speaker 0: Whoa, but basically It's the story of this guy and he's a pretty smart Intellectual guy.
Speaker 0: but because he's you know, Japanese in America, you know, he's ends up working, you know Like normal kind of the same kind of jobs that would I guess Stereotypically be given to like, you know illegal sort of immigrants from Mexico nowadays, you know working in a kitchen Cleaning up someone's house.
Speaker 0: that that's the sort of thing he was doing in those days.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the comic itself is is semi-autobiographical.
Speaker 1: It basically follows these four different Japanese immigrants to the US and they both take four somewhat different paths.
Speaker 1: one of them ends up gambling a lot and one of them's an art student and One of them's kind of the main guy and it just it follows them through these short kind of sketches.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's not really any one overarching story.
Speaker 1: There's just a whole bunch of short bits about different aspects of life in the in the 19 aughts and the 1920s as a Japanese immigrant in San Francisco.
Speaker 0: Yep, the first part of it I think is is sort of funnier but also really sad and that it mostly shows them trying to get Jobs, you know struggling to get a job in someone's house and then screwing up at the job and being told to go home.
Speaker 0: And they keep you know, it's funny cuz it's like don't get told go home go home.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got told go home Not again, I think what's most fascinating though is and Scott mentioned this at the beginning that this is written bilingually and and showed even talks about how.
Speaker 1: that's probably why this Comic basically failed when it was first published.
Speaker 0: was really it was published really?
Speaker 0: I mean, what did he say about how it was published?
Speaker 0: It could have been that many copies of it, right?
Speaker 1: Well, there was that.
Speaker 1: the real trouble was that there was no market for something like this because it was written bilingually.
Speaker 1: It was written in English and in Japanese and it kind of mixes between the two and if a character would say something In English, they said it in English.
Speaker 1: Yeah something Japanese.
Speaker 1: They said it in Japanese and it's interesting looking at how.
Speaker 1: he'd obviously be new enough English to get by but he wasn't Super well versed in English and as you definitely see that in his English writing and at the same time He actually makes according to Fred a lot of mistakes in the Japanese writing -
Speaker 0: yeah Well, I mean, you know, he's not like, you know, I mean we make mistakes and you write in English And that's our first language.
Speaker 0: So, of course a Japanese speaker who's not doesn't have an editor and a proofreader is gonna make mistakes.
Speaker 0: You may make mistakes Okay You know without an editing and a proofreading there's gonna be mistakes even in your first language, but you know, I think that I Think show it made a really good decision when he was translating.
Speaker 0: it is anything that was originally written in English.
Speaker 0: He left it as is.
Speaker 0: you can see the original lettering.
Speaker 0: that was done by hand But all the Japanese.
Speaker 0: he sort of erased it and then typed in the English.
Speaker 0: But he tried not to like, you know, like ruin the bubbles or anything.
Speaker 0: So a lot of times like it's hard to read it because you know He's more about preserving the history than preserving the content.
Speaker 0: I think that's the right way to go with this book.
Speaker 1: Don't think of this as a comic You're just gonna read.
Speaker 1: think of it as kind of a a primary historical source.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much Yeah, it's exactly what it is.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so what were your favorite parts in this thing here?
Speaker 1: Oh, you want to get right to that because he ran out of anything intellectual or insightful to say.
Speaker 0: I think a lot of the things intellectual to say about it are You know sort of like said in the introduction, you know, and it's like what I don't know.
Speaker 1: one thing I can say I just I love reading.
Speaker 1: any sort of piece written can fight to contemporaries to the air.
Speaker 1: I mean That's why I'm reading a lot of Roman and Greek histories now and I was reading this old Japanese poet who wrote about how he used to do the same thing.
Speaker 1: I love that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: It gives her really Interesting if somewhat biased perspective, but
Speaker 0: one thing that I remember is actually really interesting about this is that it's done Every page is like six panels right one two three four five six So like two across and three down and they're all the same size.
Speaker 0: So he wasn't really experimenting with the paneling that much, you know, it wasn't really that kind of thing but it's left to right and it was originally left to right and According to show it apparently, you know, cuz the the mangas of the time, you know People are copying the American comics and whatnot.
Speaker 0: they did it left to right even though their language rent from right to left.
Speaker 0: and You can see a lot of the panels are they're numbered.
Speaker 0: he writes, you know He puts it in the bottom right corner the number one two three four five six so that people know which order to read them in.
Speaker 0: and I thought that was pretty interesting right there because you know, of course now we have all these mangas that are right to left and we're like, no, don't flip them don't flip them.
Speaker 0: and Originally, you know the the the manga people weren't even flipping American comics to read right to left They were writing their own comics left to right to match us.
Speaker 1: I think actually the.
Speaker 1: but it was said best in terms of what you'll get out of this by will Eisner of all people Kiyamas the for immigrants manga is a treasure like the yellow click kid and jigs and Maggie.
Speaker 1: I actually don't know what jigs and Maggie is.
Speaker 0: I don't know one of those old come.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know the yellow kid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know what it is.
Speaker 1: I read one of them in a social studies book once in middle school Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It is a splendid and authentic example of the immigrant literature of the period more candid and outspoken than any of its Contemporaries is a classic that demonstrates the true literary role of the comics to reflect ordinary life.
Speaker 1: Moreover is a fun read Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's pretty much nails it.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: the thing is it it does especially later deals with very serious very depressing very just kind of Bad issues, but it it deals with them in such light like when he one of the characters decides All right I'm gonna go fight in the war and come back and get my citizenship and he goes.
Speaker 1: he fights in the war and it's a very kind of comic couple.
Speaker 1: a panel of I fought in the war and he gets back and now he tries to get his citizenship and they're like No, and he's like, ah all that work for nothing.
Speaker 0: But if you think about what actually happened there It's sort of disturbing in a way that the whole thing feels kind of light-hearted because of the way the comic is done.
Speaker 0: But some of the subject matter is really heavy.
Speaker 1: It's like oh god You know like like the one guy who was up his face was deformed in an accident while he was working on the farm And now he's trying to get a bride.
Speaker 1: so he takes a picture to hide his deformity and then he gets a picture ride from Japan and then he puts a plaster over half his face to try to hide it until the wedding happens and then the plaster falls off and and And all hell breaks loose and that that's one of the stories and it kind of ends on that note.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's but it's the way that he treats that, you know serious material is very Light and it's sort of like uh, I guess it's sort of it helps though because if he dealt with it Seriously, it would be sort of difficult to read this thing without getting really depressed Really quickly.
Speaker 0: You'd be like, oh god life was so terrible.
Speaker 0: God damn But maybe that's just.
Speaker 0: you know, the way the guy was, you know, he sort of.
Speaker 0: you know He lived in a horrible kind of situation at least it from our perspective.
Speaker 0: But maybe you know, that was his attitude is that he was sort of a light-hearted kind of guy And he's well.
Speaker 1: actually from what I remember reading in the intro He talked about how he wasn't a light-hearted guy now other people were and how he wanted to reflect that in some of the characters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 0: That sounds good to me But yeah, it's I think the most thing the most important thing out of this manga is not the manga itself You know, which isn't you know, it's not like the greatest manga of all time or anything but it's historical significance and the context of it.
Speaker 0: and You know you get to see an account of the history of the time, you know from someone who was living it Uncensored and full-on, you know, I mean he talks about the San Francisco earthquake and all sorts of the world's fair when it comes to town.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean imagine, you know, I mean you read history books.
Speaker 0: It's just someone writing about something or writing about something or I've had something right?
Speaker 0: This is a guy who was alive during the time Writing during the time in comic form about what he and his friends were living at the time.
Speaker 0: and you know at that time.
Speaker 0: I guess this is a topical work, you know.
Speaker 0: And now it's a historical work and I guess that's the.
Speaker 0: the thing about all topical works is they become historical works eventually Honestly, I think that's all I have to say about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not much to say it's not very long It's just one book.
Speaker 0: I bought it on Amazon So you should be able to buy it on Amazon also if you go on Google Books actually be searched for it for Immigrants manga on Google.
Speaker 0: There's a Google Books entry that shows up right away.
Speaker 0: That has like the introduction and the table of contents and a few of the pages and both cut.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of the pages from it.
Speaker 0: Not the whole thing It mostly.
Speaker 0: you're only gonna get like two pages of comic but you get almost all the other non comic pages.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: it's not nothing else.
Speaker 1: even if you don't want to buy this at least read that opening introduction because there's even like pictures of the guy and Pictures from the era because there were a lot of Japanese immigrants in San Francisco.
Speaker 1: Yeah at that time.
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: mean the thing really feels a lot like sort of an exhibit in a museum You know where you read a little card and all the good stuff is on a little card and then you look through the glass At the actual artifacts and that's just sort of like, you know You apply what you got from the card to the artifact and now suddenly this meaning to it If you just look at the artifact in the glass right away, it's just like okay There's a little statue in the glass.
Speaker 0: very nice, you know, it looks cool.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, I know it's kind of a short episode.
Speaker 1: But what do you want from us?
Speaker 1: We've actually been going along a lot lately.
Speaker 1: So this will give the lips in a little bit of a rest until we upgrade it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe we can upgrade that lips in sooner rather than later then make some extra shit or something.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't think we're gonna get anything extra done until after katsu khan probably not but that's pretty much the only from katsu khan.
Speaker 0: until like July is the only time we're gonna have because then It's on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, especially if we do what we might be talking about tomorrow, but we'll talk about that.
Speaker 0: What are we talking about tomorrow?
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: Don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.