Speaker 0: It's Monday, May 19th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 0: We don't mince any words and we talk about tech issues the way we talk about tech issues in our real lives.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I'm driving to work this morning, and I'm driving to work.
Speaker 1: Why are you driving to work?
Speaker 0: Well, I'm driving to the train station.
Speaker 1: Okay where and then oh oh you told me this already.
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 1: How could this not be the opening bit?
Speaker 0: so I'm driving to the train station.
Speaker 0: I'm running a little late Which doesn't really say much because I'm always running about two minutes late whenever I go for the train.
Speaker 0: So I always make it, but I think I've been late to work Once for missing a train ever and that's cuz.
Speaker 0: this really slow van got in my way.
Speaker 0: There's nothing I could do about it Mm-hmm, but as I'm driving you know I don't really pay attention.
Speaker 0: It's like it's 4 455 o'clock in the morning.
Speaker 0: I'm barely awake In the morning.
Speaker 0: I'm driving so I'm in my car.
Speaker 0: I noticed that all the transmission fluid I'd added to my car yesterday leaked out, so I got a deal with that.
Speaker 1: awesome Not all of it.
Speaker 1: where didn't you add the Sealy stuff?
Speaker 0: No?
Speaker 0: I just added transmission fluid way to go.
Speaker 1: Why did you just pour it right on the ground?
Speaker 0: because I wanted to see how fast the leak was.
Speaker 0: now that I know that?
Speaker 0: It leaks quickly I'm gonna use the leak sealer and that's gonna keep it long enough until I buy a new goddamn car.
Speaker 1: Hey, I think you need to start looking at cars now.
Speaker 1: Of course what you should do if I were you is You could start biking to the train station about now right?
Speaker 1: no.
Speaker 0: You know freaking cold.
Speaker 1: It is in the morning.
Speaker 1: I don't know how cold it is that early in the morning.
Speaker 1: How cold it I when I walked out of the door it was nice.
Speaker 0: Yes, you walk out.
Speaker 0: You know what when you walked out the door.
Speaker 0: I was already at work.
Speaker 0: I'd been at work for a while.
Speaker 1: if I were you I would sell the car while it goes Soon.
Speaker 1: it's not gonna go and the price will drop in half.
Speaker 0: No because the the real trick there is you trade it in because Trading in is good too, but trade it in while it still goes.
Speaker 0: The thing is I know it's gonna keep going for a while because the one thing I know is the transmission is bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's not so bad that it's gonna explode on me anytime soon.
Speaker 0: I know how much time I got left with this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've never.
Speaker 1: I've.
Speaker 1: actually I got a sir.
Speaker 1: I think it's time to service the transmission in my car.
Speaker 1: I've never done that I should take.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna take it to the dealer though because I don't trust the other places.
Speaker 0: Transmission service isn't that hard to do yeah, but you know who knows my car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah If I if I own a new car I'd probably Go to a lot more reputable mechanics than I tend to go to.
Speaker 1: yeah Yeah, if I had a piece of shit car I would go to the most unreputable mechanics that I could find.
Speaker 1: cuz I when I had to get my car fixed before I drove around some shady looking because like When your car is brand new you're like make this like it was you know a month ago when it was really brand new.
Speaker 1: You're like put duct tape on it your life's make it keep going another month.
Speaker 0: Yes, so it's like how many more days will a hundred bucks get me?
Speaker 0: but Anyway, so I'm driving to work, and I'm just totally zoned out.
Speaker 0: I'm just.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty much thinking Get on the train and then I can sleep.
Speaker 0: get on the train and then I can sleep.
Speaker 0: get on this is that a butt?
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: so I'm driving and on the right in front of it's not a school anymore But it was a school now.
Speaker 0: It's like I don't know exactly it's for sale still.
Speaker 0: well currently people are leasing it And I found that out because I read the school budget and they make $150,000 a year from leasing that building to someone.
Speaker 0: uh-huh, but and there's a community garden in front of it.
Speaker 0: But I look up and I see yeah, how does a community garden work?
Speaker 1: Can we just take stuff out of it?
Speaker 0: Probably not.
Speaker 1: oh can we put things into it?
Speaker 0: possibly we should ask I wonder how it works Over there.
Speaker 1: well, I mean this herbs there.
Speaker 1: So it's like can I put some herbs in and take some herbs out like stuff in taking stuff I'll go I'll go drop off like a little cup of tomatoes if I can get some Red Oaks Mill where we were mountain biking that one time.
Speaker 0: you went mountain biking.
Speaker 0: There's a farm collective there And you can get pretty much for free as long as you ask and you actually do stuff a little like Five foot by five foot plot in a nice farm.
Speaker 0: You can grow whatever you want.
Speaker 0: They don't slow far away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, but I don't need a plot.
Speaker 0: I have a bucket Anyway, but there was a but we held him in suspense on the bus stared at it And as I'm driving, I only saw it for about 25 seconds, and I probably would have stopped Because maybe this person was in distress.
Speaker 0: But they were obviously moving and if they had somehow died or passed out in that position I don't know if I was equipped to help them wait.
Speaker 1: They were on the ground.
Speaker 0: Oh, they were standing.
Speaker 0: Okay, but they were kind of leaning.
Speaker 1: That's what you do when you're mooning.
Speaker 0: Yes, but they were wiggling it around and their hands were back there spreading it And it was a little.
Speaker 0: I hate to be crude so I'm hoping that the humor of the situation will outweigh the crudeness.
Speaker 1: But it was a poopy, but uh Maybe they were just asked for someone to help him wipe.
Speaker 0: all I could think as I'm driving by is all right, dude You might be in trouble right now, but there's very little I am equipped with to help you and I'm cute.
Speaker 0: I'm not I don't have time to deal with it.
Speaker 1: You know wipes in the car.
Speaker 0: No, I don't.
Speaker 0: I Think what was happening.
Speaker 0: my 25-second assessment because remember I was the only person on the road.
Speaker 0: This is like a half hour before the morning rush hour starts.
Speaker 0: I think I was pretty animated too.
Speaker 0: I think it was crazy bum poopy, but Drunken.
Speaker 1: crazy bum poopy, but I don't know.
Speaker 0: drunken but definitely crazy bum poopy, but alrighty.
Speaker 0: But the scary thing is in the 25 seconds I had to stare at that thing it took me a half that time to figure out that it was a butt.
Speaker 1: Why what do you think?
Speaker 1: it was cuz?
Speaker 0: you know when you wake up and you're not quite awake.
Speaker 0: So, you know your alarms going off or your phones ringing But you think it's the other thing and you're banging on your alarm clock.
Speaker 0: Why won't it stop?
Speaker 0: I like that when I'm driving I am cuz it's four o'clock in the morning.
Speaker 0: All right Boobie, but okay crazy bum poopy, but that was my morning.
Speaker 1: Okay, you want to do this news?
Speaker 1: We have to not need to avoid talking about this news for hours have to avoid talking all the ancillary issues to it.
Speaker 1: Yes, you ready for this.
Speaker 1: I'm right.
Speaker 1: You really you don't know what this is yet.
Speaker 0: Do you know I'd cuz?
Speaker 0: I didn't Actually, I worked on stuff all day.
Speaker 0: I didn't even take a lunch.
Speaker 0: So I didn't get to read the internet.
Speaker 1: so today Google launched a new Google thing called Google Health and It's not a competitor with WebMD or any of those type of sites.
Speaker 1: what Google Health is?
Speaker 1: as you get an account right and then any of the Medical institutions doctors pharmacies hospitals that are partnered up with Google Health You can Digitally request your medical records and Google Health will aggregate them for you now.
Speaker 0: I Am so ambivalent on this issue.
Speaker 0: on one hand One that puts the company I used to work for out of fucking business.
Speaker 1: good Well, I mean is the other problems right is all right.
Speaker 1: Let's just go through the list of problems here.
Speaker 1: ready Privacy issues.
Speaker 1: Google has your health record.
Speaker 0: Yes, but at the same time from the rim perspective looking at myself My metal my personal medical records mean nothing to anyone with me.
Speaker 1: And yeah, I really don't care if you know when I got a tetanus shot, but at the same time I understand Why many out like.
Speaker 0: I understand the concerns people have about medical records and I can see many situations Where I might not want my medical records to be out there.
Speaker 0: Google knows I have of the AIDS another one hire me, but at the same time my personal medical records, frankly I wouldn't care if even the listeners had him because you don't have any weird medical issues that my medical records say.
Speaker 0: great Wow, he's in good health.
Speaker 0: His cholesterol is practically zero.
Speaker 0: is my blood pressure is 120 over 60 Exactly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if you had some problems that you know were Delicate issue.
Speaker 0: Well, I have one.
Speaker 0: his his member is just so so gigantic.
Speaker 1: I know staggers the mind.
Speaker 0: Journal articles have been written about it Right Anyway, so anyway it I'm sorta isn't that right Simba?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm having some some problems.
Speaker 0: Well, here's here's the thing.
Speaker 0: I can sum all the issues up very simply.
Speaker 0: Google a hitherto up until now Google has been expanding and kind of everything Google is added.
Speaker 0: It's like alright, I Trust Google with X and in return I get Y. first I trusted them with my searching and the searches I do and in return I get the best search results in the world.
Speaker 0: And then I trusted them with the ability to read every email I ever send or receive and in return I don't have to deal with stupid squirrel mail anymore.
Speaker 0: And then I trusted them with every document I write and in return I can access my documents anywhere.
Speaker 0: But now I have to trust them with my medical records and I think this is the line where if Google was going to be Evil, this is it.
Speaker 0: This is where it's gonna be.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think they're gonna go one step further credit card Google credit.
Speaker 1: once they get the Google like accounting software where they have all your financial information About everything you buy and all the money in your bank account and everything.
Speaker 1: When they get that information then they own you and it's only After they get everything that they're gonna fuck you over because then you'll have no recourse whatsoever because you won't have money for the Lawyer, you won't have.
Speaker 0: I don't know exactly how to kill you on June 1st 2011.
Speaker 0: I don't know everything that gained awareness.
Speaker 1: They'll know everything you think and say so that they can control you What they know already.
Speaker 0: think about the aggregate information they have on rim.
Speaker 0: They know everything I've searched for for the past several years and every email I've sent and received and all the documents I've written.
Speaker 0: and you know what.
Speaker 0: if you look at the Google ads in my gmail, they're pretty spot-on in terms of my interests.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't look at the ads in the gmail.
Speaker 0: Well, the other thing is they they know exactly where I live.
Speaker 0: They know where I work.
Speaker 0: They know where I go because I type all the addresses I go to into Google Maps all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, get an Android phone now.
Speaker 1: They know where you are.
Speaker 0: Blackberry has the GPS.
Speaker 0: Google Maps always knows where I am.
Speaker 0: In fact, I tell it to know where I am because I always ask it.
Speaker 0: Where's the nearest Starbucks?
Speaker 0: Where's the nearest bank?
Speaker 0: Where's the nearest whatever?
Speaker 1: So yeah, it's a. do we trust Google?
Speaker 1: the other thing that bothers me about this is they used some words I don't like such as Holistic or
Speaker 0: poopy, but well
Speaker 1: holistic literally means, you know Like you know, if I say we can get a holistic look at your medical situation That means I can look at all your medical records and look at the whole thing.
Speaker 1: No, that is good.
Speaker 0: However, the word holistic has been co-opted by Randy bullshit.
Speaker 1: exactly when someone says oh We'll get a holistic will give you a holistic treatment.
Speaker 1: That means Instead of giving you medicine for your problem We're gonna give you a whole bunch of Randy bullshit.
Speaker 1: that way you're getting the whole treatment as in Missing treatment and the Randy, you know fake medicine fills in that hole.
Speaker 0: You're definitely getting the whole treatment as in that's what they'll bear you in after it stops working.
Speaker 1: Poopy asshole treatment.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, no No poopy, but is funny saying poopy asshole is not funny?
Speaker 0: that that evokes a whole new set of imagery.
Speaker 1: I know here's something else right?
Speaker 0: Okay, go to Google Health, right?
Speaker 1: Let's say you have I don't know Allergies, right?
Speaker 1: Do you want allergy medicine ads on your Google Health?
Speaker 0: I don't care about that.
Speaker 1: But then you're getting into issues there.
Speaker 1: now You're talking like Pharmaceutical companies paying big money to Google.
Speaker 1: so that cuz you know, that's what Google's thinking It's got.
Speaker 0: they do that.
Speaker 0: Anyway with the doctors directly Yeah, yeah, but when I would go to the allergist as a kid and it'd be like well I need a new allergy medicine because of whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah allergist.
Speaker 0: Luckily.
Speaker 0: She was smart about it.
Speaker 0: She would be like you want to take whatever like back when lorata Dean was kind of new.
Speaker 0: and they're like here you can take Lorata Dean and I was like, what's that?
Speaker 0: And she's like, well here is enough free samples to make it for the next three months.
Speaker 0: And it was like three different brands of drugs, but it didn't matter because they're all the same thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah So here's is what they have to say.
Speaker 1: They say there are no Current blueprints to open the site to advertising and right now we will never sell user data.
Speaker 0: All right I can translate that.
Speaker 0: we have built in all the capability we need to sell Advertising and we plan to shortly Just not right away cuz that you won't sign up.
Speaker 1: we get you to sign up when there's no ads.
Speaker 0: then we put the ads I might sign up anyway.
Speaker 0: Because here's there's one saving grace to all.
Speaker 1: I think the only problem with it is, you know They don't have you have to get your records in from all the medical places You've been.
Speaker 1: that's tough because I that's tough Especially if they haven't if there's a place that hasn't signed in with the with the probe.
Speaker 0: Well, no, it's tougher for me.
Speaker 0: I haven't had a primary care practitioner since I was in high school.
Speaker 1: I Didn't?
Speaker 1: I?
Speaker 1: you know I haven't had one since I was in high school and I didn't know which one to pick cuz it's like you moved to a New place.
Speaker 1: you don't know the doctors.
Speaker 1: So I just sort of picked the doctor down the street, right?
Speaker 1: You know and I went to see him once and he was a little.
Speaker 1: he was okay.
Speaker 0: See, I've just I'm pretty much in good health.
Speaker 0: So I actually didn't get physicals or anything at RIT.
Speaker 0: just cuz I was kind of poor and while I had health insurance I didn't have like it was.
Speaker 0: it was down to the point of well if I drive to a doctor That's like three dollars worth of gas.
Speaker 0: I could buy a lunch with that.
Speaker 0: Yep But you know, I finally when I worked at the hospital They're like you got to get tested for tuberculosis.
Speaker 0: Cuz they were you know, the hospital in the inner city and then they gave me a full physical.
Speaker 0: That was the first physical I'd had in forever.
Speaker 0: Yep But I just I don't go to the doctor like ever.
Speaker 0: the last time I went to a doctor is when I cut my finger Halfway off.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually go right you went to the doctor after yeah I went to a doctor and then I gave up and went home.
Speaker 0: and then the next day I went to a doctor and He's like good God Here's some iodine Soap that Seriously, did you go to the emergency room?
Speaker 0: Iodine so soap - he was like, why didn't you go to the emergency room?
Speaker 0: I was like I did.
Speaker 0: then I left.
Speaker 0: He was like, ah, well, that is a really bad hospital.
Speaker 0: Of course when I asked well, what hospital should I go to?
Speaker 0: he said and this area?
Speaker 1: Yeah Great Google Health can make the Google Hospital.
Speaker 0: Alright, I think we can't talk any more about this.
Speaker 1: I think now we can.
Speaker 1: we got to stop.
Speaker 0: next Monday.
Speaker 0: Our show will be is Google evil?
Speaker 1: yet now you want to do a whole Google evil show.
Speaker 0: I think we need to.
Speaker 1: I think you should a general more privacy show.
Speaker 0: I don't know privacy is even.
Speaker 0: oh god I have a. I have so many things in my delicious about privacy.
Speaker 0: I've been saving for a privacy show News.
Speaker 0: All right listeners.
Speaker 0: Do you want privacy or Google next week?
Speaker 0: Well, I'll make it.
Speaker 0: I'll even make.
Speaker 0: we'll make a stupid up there similar.
Speaker 0: You can just vote privacy Google or you don't care Alright, so in other news this this this has been making the rounds.
Speaker 0: It's very.
Speaker 0: this is one of those things where a lot of people will look at it And I guess not understanding the issues make a much bigger deal out of it than it probably is.
Speaker 0: but at the same time It's one of those.
Speaker 0: it's both very Unsurprising and very surprising at the same time.
Speaker 0: Apparently a full 20% of US citizens have never used email in their entire lives and a majority of them don't plan to ever.
Speaker 1: Well, there's a probably, you know about 20% of people are old people.
Speaker 1: That's that makes sense.
Speaker 1: or you know people who live in the middle of nowhere like, you know What.
Speaker 1: so what are the people who live in those arcs?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's just that the article actually doesn't say a lot.
Speaker 0: it links to a bunch of other articles.
Speaker 0: But the the gist of this is that there are two Demographics of people who are not connected.
Speaker 0: The first one obviously is old people and people who live in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 0: Well, no, no old people in general just don't use new technology, even though it might be better for them in many ways.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of reasons and you can't say oh, well, they're bad or anything.
Speaker 0: It's just that's the way it is, but there's a much more Interesting a quote age and education are factors in the divide.
Speaker 0: one half of those who have never used email or over 65 but 56% of the people who don't use email have never had any schooling beyond high school if they even graduated high school uh-huh, and The scary part of these findings is now I'm super generalizing these results like times a billion.
Speaker 0: So take this with a big ol grain of salt.
Speaker 0: But it seems like half the people who don't use email or who are generally disconnected from the modern Technological society are old people and that's to be expected.
Speaker 0: The other half are not old.
Speaker 0: In fact, many of them are young.
Speaker 0: They're just so Disconnected from society either due to poverty or due to geography or due to language barriers.
Speaker 0: I mean illegal immigrants definitely play a big part of that.
Speaker 1: I think well the counting Immigrants here the only counting US citizens.
Speaker 0: See I'm not a hundred percent sure.
Speaker 1: This is the problem.
Speaker 1: See this would be a lot more useful if they correlated the data with some other data For example, but yeah, how many people I worked for the census in 2000?
Speaker 0: I worked for the US federal census.
Speaker 0: My first job I ever had was for the federal government and The problem we had was that the people we sense to very poor areas like to the ghettos and to the slums met pretty much the people who need to be counted the most.
Speaker 0: the people who need the most help and the government needs to know About so we can figure out where to put the money in.
Speaker 0: the social programs are the ones who hide from the census because they're afraid of being deported or they don't understand what the census is.
Speaker 0: or even if They are legal citizens They don't understand the census and they're afraid when someone with a federal badge shows up that they're knocking.
Speaker 0: They don't even know the US has a census.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and It's very difficult to get useful statistics from the people in America who need the most help as a result.
Speaker 1: No, you know at that.
Speaker 1: see if you don't have an education It's very.
Speaker 1: you need the most help and you make it as hard as possible for anyone to help you and you only hurt yourself.
Speaker 0: But at the same time because there's such a hostile I mean look at illegal immigrants in particular Because the environment in the US in the places where they tend to live are so hostile toward them.
Speaker 0: Anyway, and the political climate.
Speaker 0: there is a lot of pressure on them to the point that they won't go to the doctor even when they need treatment because they're afraid of being deported when I Don't think anyone could make the argument that we got citizen or no if you need medical treatment You should get medical treatment.
Speaker 0: We might we might get a deal with the problem of why you're in illegal or why you have like why you're in this situation In the first place, but getting someone the medical treatment is probably better for society than not giving it to them Regardless of who pays the
Speaker 1: emergency room.
Speaker 1: Well, if they're actually not gonna just make you wait all night You know if they're actually going to fix you, you know If you're having a heart attack, they save you first to then ask questions later.
Speaker 1: Trust me They're not looking for your ID until you know, you're sure you're not dead.
Speaker 0: But this is this is another complicated issue that probably deserves and I'll show entirely but Ponder the fact that one out of five Americans has never used an email ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I still I'm.
Speaker 1: I think that the people who aren't the old people I think a lot of those people also you would find that they have no TV.
Speaker 1: No telephone, you know, they're very well.
Speaker 1: There is an interesting quote, you know people like Amish people.
Speaker 1: You know that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah I don't know if they got the Amish people because the way they surveyed I don't know if Amish people would have been gotten.
Speaker 1: well pause who knows.
Speaker 0: but Many people just don't see a reason to use computers and do not associate Technology with the needs and demands of their daily lives and I think this really because again old people You know the half of these people.
Speaker 0: that kind of makes sense, but on the other spectrum, I think there's a lot of people who?
Speaker 0: Because their lives are so disconnected from the modern technological world they don't need computers in their daily lives.
Speaker 0: and I Feel I don't think this situation is going to get better.
Speaker 0: I think it's going.
Speaker 0: I feel like this Divide is just going to get worse over time, but I don't know what to do.
Speaker 1: I'd I think will be a month There'll be a much bigger gap But I think most people are gonna be on this side of the gap and not on the other side At first I don't know.
Speaker 0: in the long run.
Speaker 0: I mean worldwide it's much more difficult issue.
Speaker 0: But even in the US there are a lot of people who are completely off the radar.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah a lot of them put themselves there.
Speaker 1: it's it's tough call.
Speaker 1: yeah I'll be more interesting and say 20 years when you know old people, you know, the old people will be people who like us.
Speaker 0: Anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: So if you want to go first check this shit out, right?
Speaker 0: I'm checking.
Speaker 1: so a guy took a Whole bunch of programs and he stuck them together right to check out these programs that he stuck together.
Speaker 1: He took the MySQL and he took the integrated taxonomic information system.
Speaker 1: combine those two, right?
Speaker 1: He took some PHP and some pearl.
Speaker 1: He took the HMM toolkit from Cambridge, which is a mathematical engine that generates acoustic models.
Speaker 1: He took Julius a voice recognition engine audacity or a quarter an audio recorder, right a Lexicon guide for phenom structure.
Speaker 1: I think he used the British English example pronunciations Vox forge utilities, right which allowed it to build the acoustic model that the the mathematical engine would you know go at.
Speaker 1: and Then festival which is a thing that you know takes text and then you know Reads it out.
Speaker 1: Like if you I've used festive festivals the only one festival in my sequel the audacity fun fungus festival, right?
Speaker 1: Festival audacity in my sequel, I guess PHP are the only ones of these I've used before and Festival is sort of like a text-to-speech program for it's open source and it works really well.
Speaker 1: Like you could type in like hi, how are you doing?
Speaker 1: And then I think like this British dude will say hi How are you doing?
Speaker 0: I guess that now is the worst British accent I've ever heard.
Speaker 1: I didn't say I did I didn't use a British accent in the voice I Britain.
Speaker 0: sorry, sorry Albion, but I believe what you meant is.
Speaker 1: Oh So It's pretty amazing.
Speaker 1: so he combined all these things and what he did is He basically made a thing where you can talk To my sequel and then the results will be read back to you.
Speaker 0: So wait select star fraud.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: Huh pretty crazy stuff here and it's it's people wanted you know us to do a show that was technologically complex.
Speaker 1: Well, I didn't explain this particular thing in a technologically complex way But if you go to this page and read it, you will need technological knowledges to understand what is being said on this page.
Speaker 0: So it's been a while since we've used a TED talk as a thing of the day But this one bears mention this one.
Speaker 0: This is very interesting because it's a confluence of many things.
Speaker 0: I like particularly crows.
Speaker 0: I Really really like.
Speaker 0: I mean I like birds in general.
Speaker 0: I grew up and I had a from when I was very young my parents.
Speaker 0: we had an african-grade parrot dusty who is smarter now than a lot of people I knew in high school, but I crows for people who aren't familiar with crows or haven't dealt with them in their daily lives are Super super intelligent like they are.
Speaker 0: People think like oh parrots are really smart, but crows are equally smart in many ways.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean Crows are you know, they're not like human smart, but you know.
Speaker 1: or dolphin smart I mean
Speaker 0: if you if you doubted look at all the videos of crows spontaneously making tools and using those tools to do things Yeah,
Speaker 1: but crows are no slouches and I you know There is you know, maybe it's crows can't talk only because they don't have the the bits to talk, you know Who knows
Speaker 0: but anyway?
Speaker 0: Joshua Klein did a TED presentation and I'm gonna summarize a lot because really you gotta watch this video and the video says it All and the video is again like every TED video eloquent and perfect and amazing.
Speaker 1: We're gonna start watching some more TED videos again.
Speaker 0: I haven't watched him a while But the idea here though that the shallow idea is that he made a crow vending machine and crows used it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he said when rim told me this story, but first I thought it was bending machine and I was like crow bending like crow bar.
Speaker 1: Well crow vending machine as in you know, put money in.
Speaker 0: chips come out but potato chips I mean well peanuts actually in this yummy, but the way and he explains how the whole thing worked.
Speaker 0: But the idea is much deeper than that that the crow vending machine for peanuts was just the proof of concept.
Speaker 0: It was the simplest most basic.
Speaker 0: like look this idea is possible.
Speaker 0: Here's the simplest proof I could do in a hurry.
Speaker 0: We should look into this.
Speaker 1: crows actually vend.
Speaker 1: Yes, where they get quarters from.
Speaker 0: they found them.
Speaker 1: It was actually a money collection machine for him.
Speaker 1: He's basically selling peanuts for a quarter ripping off the crows.
Speaker 1: Well, it is a bad deal.
Speaker 1: How smart are they?
Speaker 1: They don't know the words of a quarter.
Speaker 0: to get it to go and make sure they did it He spread quarters around the area.
Speaker 0: but anyway, the idea here that the gist of it is that Just a lot.
Speaker 0: today there are a lot of species in the world that aren't Adapting so well to the fact that humans exist or the world is changing and climate and all that and we spend a lot of time Trying to protect these species.
Speaker 0: But at the same time the species that have adapted really well or the ones that are living Kind of side by side with humans and are just they're dealing with it We we tend to look at them as pests and try to destroy them and get away.
Speaker 0: We don't care about you.
Speaker 0: Everyone hates The ones.
Speaker 1: yeah pigeons crows and rats.
Speaker 1: I think part of the reason that we tend to get rid of them is because they're ugly and people like the cutest crows aren't Ugly and rats are really cute.
Speaker 0: Even city rats are pretty cute.
Speaker 1: No, not really.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they are.
Speaker 1: They're all like ratata.
Speaker 0: They're like But or where even worse radicated all right, okay does not a good Pokemon?
Speaker 0: no, it's not it's ugly Vg cats the rat morning star anyway.
Speaker 0: So but his idea is that Crow.
Speaker 0: look at crows in particular.
Speaker 0: crows have adapted to dealing with humans to a degree that is almost frightening.
Speaker 0: they and Despite the fact that we keep trying to eliminate them and keep them away they don't go away and almost all the crows in the world live within five miles of a human settlement and all this sort of stuff and They're doing pretty well because they're super smart.
Speaker 0: So his idea is Instead of trying to destroy the species that have actually despite us trying to get rid of them Coexisted and not gone away as opposed to the species that we're trying to protect that are going away anyway What if we use this or train them or come up with a way to have an actual mutually beneficial?
Speaker 0: Arrangement and his ideas are far-fetched.
Speaker 0: like we can train crows to bring us money in exchange for food.
Speaker 1: Well, I can get mad rich if I had some train crow.
Speaker 1: remember coin bad angry fuck.
Speaker 0: I promise to protect children.
Speaker 1: You can make that you think of the day.
Speaker 1: god.
Speaker 0: No That's like the.
Speaker 0: that's one of the.
Speaker 0: that was like After all your base that tried to be the next all your base and it failed to a degree.
Speaker 0: That is epic.
Speaker 1: Yeah It was the thing of the day.
Speaker 1: once it was yours I did lobster magnet on the same day.
Speaker 0: Because if you've got a lobster and you've got a magnet did it it it it it it.
Speaker 0: it lobster has antenna But don't you grab it?
Speaker 0: Okay so You could train crows and basically pay them to do things and they're smart enough.
Speaker 0: So and their work for peanuts Ha but seriously like his ideas and he just threw him out there.
Speaker 0: Like what if after like you train crows in the city to after a parade or in a stadium after a game?
Speaker 1: To pick up all the garbage, I don't think they like ticker tape.
Speaker 1: It doesn't taste good.
Speaker 0: No, no, you train them to bring the garbage to a place in exchange for food.
Speaker 1: I could just I'm just getting visions of like, you know Movie where the evil guy has like the army of crows.
Speaker 0: I'm getting visions of hey, they're following the School getting attacked by murders of crows for their change.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 1: But seriously at the bigger crow army, it'll be really Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Everyone.
Speaker 1: I'd like these crow armies.
Speaker 0: my crows are power powerful or just like that Simpsons where Homer has the flock of crows.
Speaker 0: No, you go.
Speaker 1: Oh my flag of seagulls.
Speaker 1: I win.
Speaker 0: But Martin, he's like no honey a flock of crows is called a murder.
Speaker 0: But this videos because it's a cool idea that It's possible to have an you can.
Speaker 0: we can have a relationship with smart animals where we pay them for goods and services directly.
Speaker 0: I mean we kind of have it with like horses.
Speaker 0: They pull us around in return oat bag.
Speaker 0: I get my oat bag Salt Lake, but the video is fascinating and very well done.
Speaker 0: and that's all I have to say about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only thing I have to say about that that I didn't say already is that I'll agree I'll go with him on the on the mammals and bird type, you know creatures that have you know lived with the humans.
Speaker 0: Hey, we could see cucumbers and need some more love.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about You know There are other creatures that have lived very close to humans and done very well that we do not want to have working for us.
Speaker 1: May I point out the mosquito?
Speaker 0: Ah, but the mosquito we've dealt with where we live.
Speaker 1: you are You train the mosquitoes and I will spray you with mosquitoes, right?
Speaker 0: Well mosquitoes aren't so smart.
Speaker 1: no, not really well, they're really smart.
Speaker 1: They're smarter than vampires.
Speaker 0: No, I think vampires have the edge anyway.
Speaker 1: So today we've gotten mad Requests to do like high-tech talk.
Speaker 1: that was not dumbed down in any way And I don't know how well this is gonna go.
Speaker 1: I can already hear people turning off their iPods up there goes But some of our listeners want it and we've never really done it.
Speaker 1: We've always hesitated to do it and For me I have like a natural tendency to always like explain things if I don't think someone is understanding what I'm saying
Speaker 0: Especially because like we're at the point now where Scott is very specialized in what he does I'm very specialized in what I do.
Speaker 0: So my depth of knowledge in IT is well beyond Scott's but Scott's depth of knowledge in programming is well beyond mine So we even have to like I have to pull back a little bit and he has to pull back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I the only person I explained what I'm gonna explain today too was Alex because I didn't think rim would get it.
Speaker 1: So Yeah, we both decided.
Speaker 1: Well, what are we gonna talk about?
Speaker 1: That's really really in-depth technology.
Speaker 1: That's not dumbed down in any way and I you know, all I could think of that was recent was this Ubuntu bug I submitted and Rim was gonna talk about the NTP problems.
Speaker 1: He was having with VMware at work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm basically we both just picked something we can talk about.
Speaker 0: This is not really a throwaway episode but more of a Word.
Speaker 0: we're not gonna mince words.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna hold back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's sort of like let's just talk about some technology issue.
Speaker 1: that's cool, you know fresh on our minds and Personal to us so that we can you know, because then we know all the details of it, you know it's not something we read about something we did and Explain it and you know not dumbed down terms in any way whatsoever just on someone, you know Explain it to someone who has the same technical knowledge, you know that on our level and see what the listener reaction to that is
Speaker 0: Well, the tricky thing is though if I was talking to another enterprise IT expert I would say the VMware timekeeping problem and they would go.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that's the end of it.
Speaker 1: I know that that is the problem, but I figure I'll try to explain it to rim Basically, and I'll try to explain my thing to Scott and I already know about your thing.
Speaker 0: Oh, do you?
Speaker 0: But because basically the idea here is If this works or anyone out there if you feel that this is the proper level we can do Actual shows just at this level.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it all that We're is mostly even if you don't like this episode just listen to it to help us out to you know Tell us if you understood it or not or if you enjoyed it whether regardless of whether you understood it completely it'll
Speaker 0: also give you a tiny idea of if you're if you're Into computers you want to go into IT or CS because you'll hear
Speaker 1: about some - mine isn't really a program No, it's a Linux issue.
Speaker 0: Well, if you want to if you want to grow a neck beard, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is mine is serious neck beard action, let me tell you All right.
Speaker 1: So do you want me to go first?
Speaker 1: Go right because you keep pausing like you want me to go first.
Speaker 0: That's cuz.
Speaker 0: I really got a burp and I was waiting for you to get going so I can burp burp away Alright, so check out this problem.
Speaker 1: I'm having it work.
Speaker 1: See Why don't my development development server connect to it via SSH, right?
Speaker 1: But to make things easier, I'd rather use G VIM on the local machine then use VIM in the terminal.
Speaker 1: You know when I'm SSH to the remote machine because then G VIM has a much better interface.
Speaker 1: I can make the window bigger better fonts, right?
Speaker 0: Well, I even have the problem where I work on a lot of different servers and some of them aren't set up.
Speaker 1: So well, yeah Now the dev server is a BSD is a free BSD and there's no X on it because it doesn't need X. You know installed on there right not installed at all.
Speaker 0: No, there's no X is no X lives It's not like are super important like trading like whatever servers We don't like.
Speaker 0: no one runs an X terminal but X is installed.
Speaker 0: So if I'm SSH 10 and I got to do something like I can run an X program even though I just have a shell Yeah, so I got no X forwarding right.
Speaker 1: so I have to use the G VIM on my local box.
Speaker 1: I can't you know X forward G VIM from the server.
Speaker 1: So my only option is I can.
Speaker 1: I can either Check out the code repositories to my local machine work there and then push the files back to the dev server Where I would you know could look at them in a web browser or whatever.
Speaker 1: That's a huge pain in the ass right.
Speaker 1: copying all these files back and forth screw that shit, right?
Speaker 1: So how am I supposed to get G VIM to open up the remote files in the dev server?
Speaker 1: The answer is I have to use some sort of intermediary.
Speaker 1: the intermediary But I was using was Nautilus in gnome.
Speaker 1: You know the file manager because it using it used to use this gnome VFS system to basically turn the SSH SFTP connection into a virtual file system Right.
Speaker 1: so I could open up Nautilus and be browsing the files on the remote machine and I could right-click on the files.
Speaker 0: I feel like I would have set up a Samba share, but then again Samba Samba.
Speaker 1: Even if I did a Samba share, I would have to do the same thing with gnome VFS I right through Nautilus.
Speaker 1: so I go through there right click on the file and I would say open in.
Speaker 1: you know Like G edit which is the gnome text editor.
Speaker 1: And then what it actually does using gnome VFS is it just launches G edit and passes on.
Speaker 1: you know the command-line argument of.
Speaker 1: You know the the whole as cuz G edit knows how to take SSH Command line arguments so we could open something over the connection on its own Right, but G VIM doesn't know what the hell to do with that, right?
Speaker 1: So I actually in the old version of Ubuntu prior to Hardy Heron I had a script that I was a special open with G VIM script.
Speaker 1: the thing is that was very annoying because saving and loading were extremely slow.
Speaker 1: in The new Ubuntu they replaced gnome VFS with G VFS.
Speaker 1: that combines with fuse Right and the thing about fuse because Linux only a root user can mount a file system and run mount a file system Right.
Speaker 1: So how are you supposed to get a real mount of a remote file of any kind of file system?
Speaker 1: If you're not root and you don't want to become root and you don't want to share it with anyone?
Speaker 1: So they've got this fuse system now, that's really hot.
Speaker 1: So what you can do now because they're using G VFS and fuse instead of gnome VFS.
Speaker 1: when you mount something in Nautilus with the with the virtual file system It actually does a what is a saying effectively a real mount in your dot G VFS folder in your home directory.
Speaker 1: Thus when I go into Nautilus and I right-click on the file and I say open in G VIM It actually opens up as far as it's concerned a local file and the fuse and G VFS take care of all the SSH stuff.
Speaker 1: So I can actually work on remote files on the local machine in G VIM without exporting and without bullshit.
Speaker 1: now What is the bug here?
Speaker 1: And why did I submit this bug to the Ubuntu bug reporting?
Speaker 1: So if I go to the other machine right on it in the terminal and I check the permissions on one of the code files I'm working on right the permissions are 644, which is what they should be, right?
Speaker 1: If I open the file up right through the Nautilus G VFS fuse with G edit which is the gnome text editor and I save them the permissions don't change whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Now if I do an LSL on the remote server They're 644, but if I do the permission if I check the permissions in the local, you know, virtual file system every directory is 700 and Every single file is 600.
Speaker 1: There is no changing that.
Speaker 1: you can't change it.
Speaker 1: You can't do anything about it.
Speaker 1: That's the way it is Which makes sense because you don't want other people on the same machine as you.
Speaker 1: looking at the files that you virtually mounted Right, you know you only want the person who actually mounted it and root to be able to get in there.
Speaker 1: Otherwise like I would SSH into a server Mount it with fuse and then you know you SSH into my computer and then boot.
Speaker 1: you're in my SSH on this other computer.
Speaker 1: You don't have the credentials for that, but you're in.
Speaker 1: that's no good.
Speaker 1: So it's actually correct.
Speaker 1: The problem is is that vim and also g vim when they save they modify the permissions.
Speaker 1: Now for some reason if you try to own One of the files in the virtual file system.
Speaker 1: It just says hey Jones not supported.
Speaker 1: But if you chmod what actually happens is it schmods the file.
Speaker 1: not in the virtual file system Which I already said it goes unchanged.
Speaker 1: it schmods the file in the real file system on the remote machine.
Speaker 1: So when I save a file in vim in g vim that I'm going through this.
Speaker 1: You know g VFS fuse system.
Speaker 1: on the remote machine the permissions get changed to 600 because as far as g vim is concerned the permissions Are 600 so it saves them and schmods to 600. so now it's no longer 644. in the real file system It's 600 and the web server can't read it because it doesn't have permission to read it.
Speaker 1: And I have to go and SSH on the command line anyway to change permissions back.
Speaker 1: and now it's more of a pain in the ass To edit with g vim than to just SSH in the terminal and edit normally score one Yes.
Speaker 1: So it's a huge huge pain in the ass and I submitted the bug to Ubuntu because who knows where this bug is, right?
Speaker 1: How do you fix this bug?
Speaker 1: Do you change fuse and g VFS that the permissions are different locally?
Speaker 1: I don't think that's a good idea.
Speaker 1: that raises all sorts security issues.
Speaker 1: Like I just talked about do you change g vim?
Speaker 1: Or vim so that they don't schmod when you save?
Speaker 1: well, that's not a bad idea because I mean no other text editor I know of does that.
Speaker 1: but the problem is maybe someone out there has some other application that expects g vim and vim to change Permissions on save and thus that will cause a bug somewhere else and you fix this bug.
Speaker 1: It could be an expected permission somewhere else and I had to submit that bug to g vim not to Ubuntu.
Speaker 1: Or maybe it's a Nautilus problem.
Speaker 1: but good but I did actually try it without going through Nautilus.
Speaker 1: I just you know changed directory to dot g VFS and went direct and the things still happen.
Speaker 1: So I have no idea what the appropriate fix for this bug is.
Speaker 1: I could think of a few.
Speaker 1: Some guys started to help me out and then he sort of realized what the problem was and he's just like oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: And then some other guy is like for what it's worth.
Speaker 1: I am also experiencing this behavior.
Speaker 1: This has already caused a few problems for deploying fixes to clients.
Speaker 1: So he must have clients where he SSH is into their servers and fixes things for them and he's going through the same system I'm going through.
Speaker 1: and but when he saves now all of a sudden he breaks his clients web pages because he changed the permissions on all the files.
Speaker 1: so Yeah, did anyone understand that?
Speaker 0: Oh, I don't know.
Speaker 0: At least you get the comfort of nothing is more.
Speaker 1: Did you understand that rim?
Speaker 0: Yeah All right.
Speaker 0: Nothing is scarier though.
Speaker 0: Then when you run into a problem like that and you go online and there's no reference to that problem anywhere else in the world Yeah, I've had that happen a couple times.
Speaker 1: That's when you make the bug reports.
Speaker 1: It's funny though, because if I do like if I do gedit like, you know Cuz g edit.
Speaker 1: g vim now actually supports like, you know, like SFTP.
Speaker 1: So if I on the command line if I do g vim SFTP Scott at remote machine slash home slash code slash file dot text Alright, if I do it that way g vim itself is going.
Speaker 1: g vim All right is handling the SSH and SFTP and it doesn't fuck up the permissions because it's direct to the remote file system.
Speaker 1: But if I do g vim space dot g VFS slash, you know You know server slash code whatever then it screws everything up because you know It.
Speaker 1: it says what are the permissions on this file?
Speaker 1: The answer is 600. it's chamad 600 and then the fuse passes it on to the real file system and changes the 644 to 600.
Speaker 1: Very annoying very very annoying.
Speaker 0: Well what I've been dealing with lately and so far I've gotten no answer from VMware has pretty much gotten dark on me and I've talked to some high-up engineers Even though I kind of already know the answer.
Speaker 0: I'm just waiting for someone official to just admit it.
Speaker 0: but a lot of you use VMware and People don't really seem to realize that Time in VMS is pretty much completely screwed up.
Speaker 1: Well, the reason for that is you have the.
Speaker 1: the only place you can get real-time on a computer is the operating system That is running directly on the CPU.
Speaker 1: every other pro every other piece of software on the computer, right?
Speaker 1: Basically begs the operating system for CPU cycles and it's up to the operating system itself to decide which CPU cycles to give to which other applications and when.
Speaker 0: but when you're running in a virtualized environment especially if you're using like a VM server where you've got this server that has I don't know 10 or 20 virtual machines running on it.
Speaker 0: Because then you have the problem where everything is ticking along but say for the machines are using a ton of CPU.
Speaker 0: So other machines that aren't so heavily loaded right now get d scheduled temporarily so they're not getting CPU cycles at all.
Speaker 0: and The problem here is that those machines effectively kind of slow down or stop like there's no amount.
Speaker 0: The time is not accounted for.
Speaker 0: that was missing.
Speaker 0: So when they schedule up again now their clock is falling behind.
Speaker 1: Yeah See it's not a problem for the software running on those machines because obviously the software doesn't need any cycles But the clock on the machine the time the time will get slow.
Speaker 1: That's not good.
Speaker 0: And that's really not good for any system where time matters I mean logging and that it's an awful awful situation and luckily the worst thing that can ever happen.
Speaker 0: It's okay Theoretically if time gets ahead because you'll never have a log entry appear After an entry where it shouldn't have appeared or should have appeared before it because that can screw things up royally Like that can bark your file systems in some cases.
Speaker 0: that can just ruin.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't want to go open up your log file and it says yes something it happened five o'clock.
Speaker 1: Then something else happened at five oh one.
Speaker 1: then something else happened at 459.
Speaker 1: Whoa, that's bad.
Speaker 0: But so but before that I mean before virtual machines what I set up a fairly sophisticated NTP which you know network time protocol Environment to get because we need super super accurate time and I looked into those radio receivers.
Speaker 0: They actually give you pretty.
Speaker 0: they're not that good overall.
Speaker 0: You're better off just using NTP and syncing to miss.
Speaker 1: NTP is pretty is pretty good.
Speaker 0: NTP is amazing despite the fact that the dude who wrote it is kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: Well, he's just an easy crazy old Linux and Unix Santa Claus guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like he predates the neckbeard He has the Unix Santa beard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean that's that.
Speaker 1: that's why Linux guys have the neckbeard.
Speaker 1: They're true.
Speaker 1: They're working their way up to.
Speaker 1: you know, Unix was the full-on Santa Claus.
Speaker 1: Linux is the neckbeard.
Speaker 1: So I guess whatever comes next, you know, it's good.
Speaker 1: Well Apple is like little goatee, you know and Microsoft is clean-shaven.
Speaker 0: And then but don't forget there's the suspenders.
Speaker 0: you're not allowed to wear suspenders unless you're over the age of 60 or Use Unix.
Speaker 1: No, this is the suspenders are not the Unix Santa Claus.
Speaker 1: Is there like the mainframe Santa Clauses?
Speaker 0: Ah, I guess some of the old old Unix guys who used to be mainframe guys, maybe Bafa You can't wear suspended.
Speaker 0: Bafa can wear suspenders.
Speaker 0: All right, of course, you only use them to kill someone.
Speaker 0: Yeah but Actually setting up that environment because it was the first time I'd worked somewhere where they cared about time and when I said I know NTP there.
Speaker 0: They were all excited.
Speaker 0: So I set up this super sophisticated environment and Basically, we need.
Speaker 0: it's not just that I need accurate time.
Speaker 0: I need really accurate time.
Speaker 1: I mean with that stock market closes the computers have to say done right now it's not even just that.
Speaker 0: but there's regulatory things where like Did not get into the specifics of this because economic knowledge is is somewhat separate from technical knowledge.
Speaker 0: But if a true like a trade happens like a stock trade It has to be reported to the relevant agencies within a set amount of time.
Speaker 0: or you're basically just fucked like you've got a report when things happen.
Speaker 0: and I think right now the rule is you have 90 seconds.
Speaker 0: now we report within like a tenth of a second.
Speaker 0: But you have 90 seconds.
Speaker 1: But there's a good chance that's gonna be a computer messes up and saw and like the reporting computer goes.
Speaker 1: Uh-oh Well, you see like let's say the reporting computer goes.
Speaker 1: Oh for like two minutes.
Speaker 0: Well, that's why we have a very sophisticated system with lots of redundancies where that never happened I know but that's that's a big worry right there.
Speaker 0: That's why I'm paid what I am because I remember I'm a production support engineer.
Speaker 0: I work for the revenue generating side of my company.
Speaker 0: My primary mission objective is that there are a set of servers that generate money for the company.
Speaker 0: those servers must never Stop working ever and if they do I have to bring them back up and then I have to explain to people who might not Be so technical why they went down and whose fault it was Mm-hmm, and it might be my fault.
Speaker 0: So, I mean I got to admit some of the scariest things I do are they say there's a minor problem on the production server or even a little thing Like I gotta do like do something with the firewall on the production server.
Speaker 0: I need to look at the firewall or something.
Speaker 0: Anytime I type su - and type in that password that password That.
Speaker 0: that's some scary times.
Speaker 0: cuz like suddenly I actually have a separate window.
Speaker 0: I have this whole environment of like 10 different X windows with different background colors.
Speaker 0: One of them is red and if I'm in the production server I'm in there and I types I'm like type type a type type type type.
Speaker 0: Sometimes I get like hey, I'm about to type this on the production server.
Speaker 0: I want you to note that I'm typing this right now.
Speaker 0: or do you do you have any problems with the update statement?
Speaker 0: I'm typing right now in the SQL database.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a good one of course.
Speaker 0: actually usually if I typed an update statement between the hours of 9 a.m.
Speaker 0: And 4 p.m I'd probably fired on the spot probably but that's that's an aside.
Speaker 0: So I actually to get a good time environment I actually had to get three separate NTP servers and I made all of them peer to each other.
Speaker 0: So they kind of as a group will decide what the best source of time is and then each one of them I actually made a matrix where it there's a pool of five NTP servers from NIST that they all share.
Speaker 0: But then each one of them has four additional NIST sources that are all geographically dispersed.
Speaker 0: And actually these three servers tour in New York and one's often like Virginia and I have like this crazy.
Speaker 0: So it's a pretty sophisticated environment.
Speaker 0: and on top of that I had to set up Reporting because I have to verify to the back office and to all the auditors that we have accurate time Not just on these servers, but on all the important servers that connect to them.
Speaker 0: So that was a project in and of itself because I had to actually set up a way to monitor Externally whether or not these servers are synchronized and then how good their sync is.
Speaker 1: She's got like what you got your turn on your computer is a list of all the servers and then little clocks next to all.
Speaker 0: Actually, no, I'm on.
Speaker 0: basically I'm on it I can't.
Speaker 0: there's a bunch of ways to do it and I could just grab traps from the NTP services.
Speaker 0: But that's not super reliable.
Speaker 0: because what if the NTP server goes down exactly?
Speaker 0: It's not gonna send me a trap.
Speaker 0: And also I don't want to trust that at all because track SNMP traps are not.
Speaker 0: you can't verify At least with SNMP version 1 which is what the majority people still use that a trap got there.
Speaker 0: There's no like.
Speaker 0: yes.
Speaker 0: I got your trap or huh?
Speaker 0: He didn't Respond to my trap.
Speaker 0: Maybe I should send it again.
Speaker 0: And again, what if your server crashes then or hangs?
Speaker 0: You're not gonna get a trap.
Speaker 0: so I've.
Speaker 0: I monitored the root dispersion which is not the amount that the time is off by but the Theoretical maximum possible error that I could have.
Speaker 0: so if I take the root dispersion and add the Differential or the time difference the like the absolute difference I get mathematically the absolute Maximum error that I could have in my time from the quote unquote true time Even though nothing ever actually converges to true time.
Speaker 0: But that's all well and good.
Speaker 0: and I set this crazy thing up and I'm not even get into how I set up the monitoring Cuz I had.
Speaker 0: I had to extend the NTP stat and the NTP queue commands Through SNMP in order to be able to pull it for like MRTG and all these things.
Speaker 0: But alright, that's all well and good.
Speaker 0: now we want to run virtual machines.
Speaker 0: But virtual machines you can't just run NTP because NTP if it runs into trouble will just crash.
Speaker 0: Like it'll synchronize the clock.
Speaker 0: It'll say whoa, that was off by way too much and it'll silently fail.
Speaker 0: Yep, and that's it.
Speaker 0: You're done.
Speaker 0: NTP is not running anymore.
Speaker 0: So I go into all these virtual machines.
Speaker 0: I go into one and it is literally Gaining about one to three seconds per second.
Speaker 0: It was like four years into the future when I logged into it.
Speaker 1: Whoa That's great.
Speaker 1: I mean I have VMware's at work, you know, I use them just.
Speaker 1: you know It's like look at things in different web browsers.
Speaker 1: This is on an ESX server I know and but they they only get off, you know, they're there they get off a little bit.
Speaker 1: But I mean if I suspend one and then bring it back the time will be way way.
Speaker 0: Well, you realize are you running VMware workstation or what?
Speaker 1: I'm where you see VMware play ever.
Speaker 0: Ah, oh god Your screen can't even run like VMware tools or anything.
Speaker 1: Well, actually it can run VMware tools.
Speaker 1: You just can't install VMware tools.
Speaker 1: So if you get an image that has the tools in it, they work, but if you don't have the tool Wait, wait, wait, so how do you know they work?
Speaker 1: because I've downloaded images that have the tools in them.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but how do you know they're doing what?
Speaker 0: because you know what they do?
Speaker 1: Well, it can.
Speaker 1: it can sort of do a shitty time synchronization.
Speaker 0: Actually see here's the problem.
Speaker 0: I had to know Exactly how that worked and the documentation didn't say crap.
Speaker 1: as from what I can tell it seems that basically all it does is When you turn the virtual machine back on and synchronize the time.
Speaker 0: actually if you edit the config file Especially with like an ESX server We have a lot more options.
Speaker 0: You can specify a lot of options and each of these options has varying levels of documentation Related to them.
Speaker 0: So what I tried to do is like alright, so I look and I said oh, there's a list of Things I can set to true and on those things those events.
Speaker 0: It'll hard sync the clock to whatever the time is which is actually pretty bad because the way NTFE works.
Speaker 0: the important thing is that it's lose the time like if the times off it'll slowly converge on the real time unless it's way off and then it'll jump it once and then slowly converge because you'd rather have a very off but very consistent clock than a Generally very on but very erratic on a low level like a clock That's always accurate to a minute.
Speaker 0: But within that minute the second edge is jumping around left and right which is actually what happens in virtual machines a lot Like if you run.
Speaker 0: if you run a clock that has a second hand in a VMware You'll see it jumping around a lot of the time.
Speaker 0: so I Set these options and I told it.
Speaker 0: All right, I want you to synchronize the clock Every five seconds, so I know it'll never be off by more than five seconds in the worst case scenario.
Speaker 0: And I want you to sync it anytime the the disk or defrag in the virtual machine or anytime suspended or resumed and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: and It totally didn't do jack Didn't do anything.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: So I do more reading and it turns out that and this is the tricky part.
Speaker 0: so there are different ways in the kernel to specify how you deal with time and you set the kernel clock and Modern kernels actually are very clever where if the kernel misses a clock tick and I'm not even gonna get into how the clocks work but what it'll do is it'll intelligently figure out how many ticks had missed and Compensate by adding ticks downstream so that the clock will always be kind of accurate.
Speaker 0: But in a virtual machine Those ticks were supposed to be lost.
Speaker 0: So as a result, it synchronizes the clock forward, but then the clock itself knew that it missed some ticks.
Speaker 0: So it adds ticks downstream the VMware soft sync thing, which I couldn't find documentation forever.
Speaker 0: I got the VMware engineers to send me Documentation.
Speaker 0: it says hey lost ticks blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna make the time speed up a little bit so it catches up.
Speaker 0: but then The lost ticks happen again and the clock which is getting faster and faster and faster and faster and faster and faster.
Speaker 0: So I asked the VMware people.
Speaker 0: Hey, what's the deal?
Speaker 0: And they said oh, it doesn't sink the clock backwards only forwards To which I say alright wise guys.
Speaker 0: So how should I synchronize the time?
Speaker 0: They said.
Speaker 0: So what I ended up doing is I set the clock to pit in the kernel Which basically is the dumbest clock you can set.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it ignores if it misses takes.
Speaker 0: it doesn't care.
Speaker 0: It never tries to catch up.
Speaker 0: It just assumes that the clock takes.
Speaker 0: it's getting from the pit timer are perfect Mmm, and then I ran the NTP demon, but I used the tinker settings Which never ever ever mess with.
Speaker 1: the tinker said that's the one the Unix guy hates.
Speaker 0: No one wants you to use those settings and you can do some crazy stuff with NTP.
Speaker 0: I I had never set those settings before because they're interesting But I was of the mind that there is nothing I could ever do in there that would have a good effect.
Speaker 0: But I said this the tinker panic setting to zero Which the end result of that?
Speaker 0: it does a lot of things, but basically it turns off all error checking and all Sanity checking in NTP.
Speaker 0: so NTP will not crash now when the time is bad.
Speaker 0: It'll just keep plugging It'll just set the clock.
Speaker 0: It doesn't care.
Speaker 1: It's so bad that Unix and if he finds you just slit your throat at night, but at the same time The VMware seemed accurate.
Speaker 0: now, they're not getting ahead.
Speaker 0: They're not getting behind because I got the clocks at the pit.
Speaker 0: I turned off the VMware tools bullshit time saying and I'm running NTP with this tinker panic to my good.
Speaker 0: I know the time is good But now I have this very difficult problem and I'm being asked by people who want to.
Speaker 0: they want to be able to say to non-technical like auditors that the time is accurate to verify it.
Speaker 0: and The time is pretty accurate.
Speaker 0: But how do I verify?
Speaker 0: because what can I compare the time on an unreliable time server to?
Speaker 0: Within it's the context of itself.
Speaker 0: So now I wrote this script that is basically Sorting through VAR log messages for NTP DS.
Speaker 0: I change the clock statements and then I'm using MRTG to graph the jumps in time to try to figure out when these big jumps are because the NTV loop stats were worthless because NTV is basically acting as though it's just on a server that has an unreliable hardware clock Which the real solution to that is.
Speaker 0: well get a different server because their hardware clock is broken Yeah, but the VMware hardware clock is broken.
Speaker 0: Yes So I'm having this problem where now I have accurate time But I do not have precise time.
Speaker 0: because that?
Speaker 0: because while the time will be accurate.
Speaker 0: anytime you look at it I can't guarantee that while the clock ticks are going along that the clock remains accurate all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not ticking at one second per second.
Speaker 1: But anytime you look at the time it'll it'll look right.
Speaker 0: so I'm running the NTP loop stats and Those didn't tell me shit Those are.
Speaker 0: those were not very helpful, especially because with the tinker panic off NTP never realizes when it's having a problem Because it doesn't realize having a problem.
Speaker 1: I can't tell you.
Speaker 0: what it'll do is it'll assume that the problem is the hardware clock and it'll just kind of put the time Back to where it was.
Speaker 0: So now I'm just I'm looking for any time.
Speaker 0: the clock moved by more than a second within a second.
Speaker 0: But even then I've got all this data now and I'm trying to figure out a way to mine through the data to get something Useful, so I started running it on a Linux box.
Speaker 0: I've got a physical Linux box to try to see if I get because you know, I get this data.
Speaker 0: It's like alright.
Speaker 0: What does this data mean?
Speaker 0: I'm trying to compare it to the data I'm getting from a physical hardware box But I can't find any trends that are useful.
Speaker 0: and I'm getting to the point where I might just have to say Yeah, the time is accurate and kind of base my professional reputation on it because I can't prove the time is accurate.
Speaker 0: I think There there are two good ideas that I've you know, what one idea is we're thinking about using Zen for all the servers.
Speaker 0: We're time matters.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the thing I'd like to see what you get if you use Zen or User user mode Linux just sort of worse than Zen across the board.
Speaker 0: But well, it seems like Zen.
Speaker 0: from what I gather Zen is doing the same thing as user mode Linux in terms of hardware clock Yeah.
Speaker 1: And I'm also wondering how it'll perform on say like bots or any of those like x86 like, you know machine emulator type.
Speaker 0: well, I Found another way to make this work to guarantee that I will have accurate time Mmm, but it I had like.
Speaker 0: I was at a meeting where this was explained to me by a VMware engineer.
Speaker 0: It made sense, but it's really kind of complicated to deal with and then I remember having to explain What I had just heard back to the VMware engineer to make sure that it because it was kind of ambiguous.
Speaker 0: But basically let's say I have four core or let's have eight cores in my VMware cluster.
Speaker 0: if I want Accurate time and I want to guarantee that the virtual machine that I want to have accurate time on never gets descheduled I have to set a reservation a CPU reservation that is exactly equal to the frequency of the fastest core in the cluster.
Speaker 0: And that made sense but not like it makes sense on a top like a superficial perspective.
Speaker 0: but I was thinking but why specifically is that what I must do?
Speaker 0: and Then I learned a whole bunch about how VMware allocates cycles between cores and how all that business.
Speaker 1: well Yeah, because if using the ESX server, right the underlying operating system Linux or Windows or whatever Allocating cycles to the ESX server and then the ESX server allocates cycles to all the machines within it.
Speaker 0: Well It's basically the way it handles Reservations and the way it handles cores.
Speaker 0: if I set it in this specific way and there's a little bit more to it.
Speaker 0: But and if I do all these things then I will never get Descheduled because it will never try to allocate those cycles to anyone else because the reservation Forces it to be on one of those big cores and forces it to always have that much core available.
Speaker 0: but so it's basically all the solutions I've gotten are these kind of Half-assed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they pretty much work, but I can't verify that they work other than by trusting what the VMware engineers say or Looking at my loop stats that are of dubious quality.
Speaker 1: See, I think that one solution and I know why VMware doesn't do this because they could do it easily and they'd actually Make a lot of money doing this is Right now VMware even the most expensive VMware runs on top of Linux or Windows or Mac or some sort of underlying operating system.
Speaker 1: They should just make the ESX server an operating system that runs directly on the hardware.
Speaker 0: It actually is that like we run the ESX server, but it's actually a very specialized Linux and it is it is.
Speaker 1: But I'm talking like if they remove that one layer This is the VMware kernel ran on your hardware.
Speaker 1: Then they could develop a protocol where that would know the time and have a special way of time To tell them how much time since it last gave them a cycle.
Speaker 0: because I've been a thorn in the VMware people's side for so Long they sent me the experimental solution.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's this Descheduling process that's part of this new VMware tools And if you run it supposedly whenever your VM gets descheduled when it comes back online, like when it gets his cycles back This process will basically allocate all the missed cycle Like all the time and cycles that were missed to this process as though that process had just used the whole processor for all that time.
Speaker 1: and in Theory won't that make the clock just like jump up a whole bunch real quick?
Speaker 0: No, because basically the in terms of the clock slewing in the way the clock is handled because when the VMware is Descheduled it can't do anything.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so it would be the same.
Speaker 0: it would in theory behave the same way as if When I had our physical server and a process temporarily used up 100% of the CPU.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: The problem is I just can't get it to work Experimental and I can't get any support from VMware cuz even all this Has a watermark that says experimental no support.
Speaker 0: So I called VMware and I was like, hey I can't get this to work and they're like what.
Speaker 1: no support.
Speaker 1: Yeah, did you not read what it said, but support the guy that gave it to me.
Speaker 0: He didn't even give me any documentation.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to run this thing on my own and I got to do this kernel update but the kernel update just crash and didn't work and He's probably just sent you like a virus.
Speaker 1: yeah said this is yeah, this is an update.
Speaker 1: I'll do it.
Speaker 0: That's the issue I'm dealing with right now because all the other issues I'm dealing with are more business process Enterprise stuff than technical stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could talk about.
Speaker 1: you know People probably wanted me to talk about something complicated.
Speaker 1: that was programming.
Speaker 1: but to be honest with you the programming I do at work is is not is not interesting or complicated.
Speaker 1: So it's kind of lame.
Speaker 0: yeah, like if you wanted a more like Practical or IT thing like I guess something I really could have talked about is I had to guide this application.
Speaker 0: I don't want to get into it, but I had to run this thing on a server as a service.
Speaker 0: But it's an X only application that needs that going to be open.
Speaker 1: I hate that shit.
Speaker 0: Ah The bullshit I had to go through to make this thing work and I eventually came up with the way to run it in this fully headless mode, but it's not interactive and I Servicified it like I made a Python wrapper to where like, you know You start it like a service and it'll check just like it'll check a PID file to make sure it isn't already running.
Speaker 0: but that was extra complicated because someone could run it independently of this headless mode as a GUI with a separate PID and If you run it as a GUI, it's not.
Speaker 0: actually it doesn't run the process itself.
Speaker 0: It spawned some Java process so I gotta figure out what PID is like.
Speaker 0: all the possible page that could be it and they all have different names.
Speaker 0: kill them All gracefully and then run it and then generate it.
Speaker 0: is all this bullshit I had to go through and I finally got it working.
Speaker 0: I made a cron job to start it and stop it and everything was good and Then it still just stopped working one day.
Speaker 1: That's bullshit.
Speaker 0: This program is like the worst thing ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there's no competitor.
Speaker 0: Ah Hate that I feel like with all the time I spent doing that I probably could have written something that did what it does in Python.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it depends what I have what it I mean.
Speaker 1: if there's no competitor There's a good thing to make because then you'd be the competitor.
Speaker 1: just step to do one step up and you win.
Speaker 0: I don't want to though.
Speaker 0: I The more I learn about the fixed protocol the less I want to deal with it.
Speaker 0: But this program.
Speaker 0: but yeah that I mean I could talk about that in detail.
Speaker 0: That's a much more Practical thing like what do you do when you have a program that isn't a demon or isn't a service?
Speaker 0: But you want to treat it like it's a demon or like it's a service?
Speaker 1: I give it its own computer So nothing else fucks with it and I just I make a custom machine.
Speaker 1: So it works and then I try to find a way to get rid of it.
Speaker 0: All right, let's do that.
Speaker 0: We'll run into VMware, but then we had the time issue which totally screwed up.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, I'd run it on it.
Speaker 1: So I'll get a box and put it on the box.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we think if I had an old DOS program I needed to run I would just go out get a DOS box put it on there and that box would do that one thing.
Speaker 1: That way I can make the software on that computer custom-configured for that one thing.
Speaker 1: It would work perfectly and nothing else would fuck with it.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much the only thing you can do in a situation like that.
Speaker 1: well
Speaker 0: the worst thing was when we first started running this like I would basically X-forward the stupid GUI because I had to keep the GUI open because once you started running if you need to change anything if The GUI isn't running you have to just kill it and then start the GUI.
Speaker 0: Yep, so I'm for exporting the GUI and then alright, but now now that is running I Can't like save the configuration then run it headless.
Speaker 0: I have to leave it running.
Speaker 0: So if I log out of the X session or I turn off my computer it crashes.
Speaker 0: It's done.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, cuz you're doing exporting you shouldn't do X forwarding for that.
Speaker 0: Yes, but what am I gonna do?
Speaker 0: I don't have physical access to the machine.
Speaker 1: You could use a remote desktop situation.
Speaker 0: No, cuz the one we're not gonna run VNC on these servers.
Speaker 0: no for various reasons.
Speaker 0: So basically what I did is we have this rack card, which is like this, but you can use in an XDM CP.
Speaker 0: Well, actually what we did is we had an IP console like a rack card where I can get Console access to the physical box via like a sideband are using the serial cable.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: that That sideband interaction has come a long way since the last time you used it.
Speaker 1: serial cables the way to go.
Speaker 1: man You want the security little no modem action?
Speaker 1: No, why not now nowadays?
Speaker 0: What you do is you have a separate subnet or a separate vlan actually and you connect all these rack cards to it or They're called different things but side the sideband is the way to go.
Speaker 0: it's a card in the box that gives you console physical access or and even actually we have them where they give you a Web access to the console itself.
Speaker 0: The security is pretty good actually like it's hard to break into it, but So I write basically I logged in there Ran X then I ran the program there and if anyone else needed to mess with it It was running there.
Speaker 0: and that was the safest way to do it except for the fact that the console because of Another unrelated issue the mouse cursor was always one inch to the left and one inch up Where it really was.
Speaker 0: And we have an open issue with the IP console people and they were like, well, yeah, we're not gonna fix that ever Assholes not fixing shit like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those are the issues I deal with.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: You can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives Visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution Non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.