Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, March 26th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and this is geek nights tonight night wizard and legendary gambler Tetsuya.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: You know today I thought I'd be nice and I went and I got a melon pond as part of my lunch along with the curry pond and I got an extra melon pond that I was gonna bring home and he ate it.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, you lost it.
Speaker 1: No I was just going to leave it in Emily's apartment and then drive home and then she would get home and say what's this?
Speaker 1: Oh a melon pond, but she got out of work early.
Speaker 1: She had an appointment somewhere and she called me and said hey, let's all say hi before you catch your train.
Speaker 1: I go down and of all I had bought her a melon pond.
Speaker 1: She had independently bought me something to eat.
Speaker 1: So we traded things to eat and then went along our way.
Speaker 0: Alrighty Okay.
Speaker 0: No speaking of things to eat though You know this morning I had that I bought some high-quality peanut butters his two letters over the weekend.
Speaker 1: Oh that you did.
Speaker 0: I also ran out of jellies at work.
Speaker 0: So I put some jellies three jellies Unopened jellies and the peanut butter in a bag and I brought it to work.
Speaker 1: that bag gone.
Speaker 0: I left that bag on the train Outstanding.
Speaker 0: It's like all the train lost and found.
Speaker 0: and I'm like, yeah, I left this two letters bag on the train.
Speaker 0: Did anyone find it?
Speaker 0: They're like if it was food, they threw it out.
Speaker 0: Ah Even though it wasn't very perishable You know, I mean it would have lasted a day or two.
Speaker 0: it's peanut butter and jelly.
Speaker 0: jelly wasn't gonna go bad at all I don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean I can see why they would have laws about that or You know, but at least you know for an hour or so.
Speaker 0: I mean if someone calls right back, but I basically got to work and I was just like fuck.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling what actually happened is the person you called was probably eating a delicious peanut butter and jelly sandwich.
Speaker 0: If I get to go now, right and I had to continue eating my not as good peanut butter until I can get some more.
Speaker 1: That's harsh because you know that you had the potential to have better peanut.
Speaker 0: I know I only ate it once and now I got to go buy all new jellies.
Speaker 0: It's like three jellies a lot of money.
Speaker 0: It's like almost ten dollars.
Speaker 1: I spent more than that on lunch today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I went out for like sushi lunch today, but I got it.
Speaker 0: I got a don.
Speaker 1: I also went out and got sushi lunch and I got sushi and a melon pan and a curry pie.
Speaker 0: It was a weird don because it this place.
Speaker 0: I got it at right.
Speaker 0: they put a lot more stuff in there, right?
Speaker 0: So it was kind of more interesting than the Don's I'm used to but they also put some stuff in there.
Speaker 0: That was sort of tasting like, you know, that's sort of fishy not the best sushi place in the world.
Speaker 0: flavor Like it got in my egg and I was kind of like Some bites were yummy and some bites at this.
Speaker 1: I actually really prefer the Don's from the yaga yaga remark as opposed to the ones from the cafe Right next door and they're also cheaper.
Speaker 1: So it's like alright the better one is cheaper.
Speaker 0: Yeah Workers though.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, they're at the level where they're outrageous enough that they'll get sushi But they all just get like normal rolls.
Speaker 0: Just like the nose normal ones.
Speaker 0: They have.
Speaker 0: they're like, yeah give me like a California roll and a Philly roll and Spicy tuna man.
Speaker 1: We go to the neck over like that's a new roll.
Speaker 1: What's in it?
Speaker 1: Who cares?
Speaker 0: Give me the double garlic roll and that's like the second best roll ever.
Speaker 1: It's just whole cloves of fried garlic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm like, why don't you guys get like beef Don or something?
Speaker 0: They're like, what's that?
Speaker 0: Well, I remember when I was living the other guy was like the other guy.
Speaker 0: I was you know I started talking about the sushi train.
Speaker 0: They're like, yeah, he's like, yeah, it's great.
Speaker 0: You just get all this stuff You don't even know what it is.
Speaker 0: Just eat it.
Speaker 0: and I'm like, you don't know what it is by looking at it Like I know what it is.
Speaker 1: Well, I remember let me assume Out this way and I was I had a landlady and her boyfriend and well that we're.
Speaker 1: they wanted to go to the grocery store.
Speaker 1: So I went with him and we went uptown and we passed by the osho Japanese steakhouse Mm-hmm, and I was like, ah, hey Japanese place I like Japanese food.
Speaker 1: and he was like what like sushi.
Speaker 1: and I was like no pretty much all of it.
Speaker 1: and he was like Well, what else is there?
Speaker 1: and I was like, ah And I start naming things.
Speaker 1: He's like, ah, oh, huh?
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 1: He apparently as far as he knew Japanese food consisted of steak or sushi.
Speaker 1: Really when I explained the concept of such.
Speaker 0: yes in Italy all they eat is pizza meatballs and spaghetti, but that's absolutely true.
Speaker 0: I did you shut up.
Speaker 1: So are we gonna talk about the the really big anime news or you want to go first, uh, I Think you can go first.
Speaker 0: I had some other opening bits Like I was thinking not you know, like that out.
Speaker 0: I had three openings.
Speaker 0: I can hold off But I forgot what they were.
Speaker 1: so they're They're gone cuz the elephants in the room.
Speaker 0: His name is anime Boston, but All right, so I got to do a geek bite.
Speaker 0: cuz there's no news and I'm gonna continue my plenty
Speaker 1: of news but go
Speaker 0: on anyway, so in the in the sort of comics community, right the The latest hubbub is sort of been about the Green Lantern and people are like, oh man
Speaker 1: The Green Lantern is probably one of the dumbest ideas for a superhero ever.
Speaker 0: Superhero ideas are dumb.
Speaker 0: No, not all.
Speaker 0: even even the Batman idea is dumb.
Speaker 1: How the Batman idea is not that tall.
Speaker 0: think about this.
Speaker 0: It's kind of a dumb idea.
Speaker 0: guy who's really rich lives in a cave and buys fancy things and as a butler It's not really.
Speaker 0: it's a pretty car.
Speaker 0: You know, it's not dumb at all as a sidekick wearing green underwear kick ass That's not dumb.
Speaker 0: That's not dumb.
Speaker 1: Well, it's dumb but in a different.
Speaker 0: but anyway anyway, but you know the new Green Lantern stuff Apparently, I don't know the deal with it.
Speaker 0: But if people were just raving about it non-stop non-stop raving So I'm like, alright, I stand by.
Speaker 0: So I stand by my don't knock it till I try it policy and I say alright, you know you bitches You know hyping up your Green Lantern that I don't have a lot of confidence in right which in which Green Lantern should I read?
Speaker 1: Ah That's how I read comics is I?
Speaker 1: pretty much every time Scott's like you should read a comic I'm like, alright What's the best one?
Speaker 1: I haven't read.
Speaker 0: well I said, alright So this current story that you're raving about right?
Speaker 0: Where does it begin?
Speaker 0: What trade should I buy?
Speaker 0: Give me the ISBN number.
Speaker 0: So they gave me the ISBN number right and it's Green Lantern rebirth by Jeff Johns and the art is by Ethan Van Schuyver and Someone named Prentice Rollins.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the E does.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Oh, here's the credits penciler Ethan Van Schuyver Anchors letter colorist, whatever.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I read this the whole thing even though I'm gonna be honest I didn't want to finish it.
Speaker 0: This is terrible.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Well, could you enumerate?
Speaker 1: I mean, what was bad about it?
Speaker 0: Okay Well, basically his is the deal, right?
Speaker 0: At first I was thinking, you know as I my only premise, you know sort of prejudice against these sort of comics especially the DC ones is that they require a lot of Prerequisite knowledge to understand.
Speaker 0: I'm like because I know nothing about the Green Lantern other than that He has a ring and he doesn't like yellow.
Speaker 0: That's all I really know that It's gonna be.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna understand the story and that actually was not true You see because in the in the front page here There's a who's who and it tells me who all six Green Lanterns are.
Speaker 1: there's six.
Speaker 1: Yes, I knew there was one and I think there was one that I knew was different because he was black.
Speaker 0: There's what.
Speaker 0: one of them is black.
Speaker 1: Yeah, are they all green?
Speaker 1: Is there like a red lantern?
Speaker 0: Well the original original original Green Lantern because if the Green Lantern and the Yellow Lantern teamed up don't can be them the super Original Green Lantern from the ancient olden days, right?
Speaker 0: He's actually like not the same as the other ones.
Speaker 0: He's like a you know, sort of magic based and the other Green Lanterns are sort of space, you know with the Rings and such.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway So that actually wasn't a problem.
Speaker 0: I understood the plot of this comic 100%.
Speaker 0: There was nothing.
Speaker 0: So I congratulate them on.
Speaker 0: you know, having a comic that sort of continues this incredible ongoing never-ending story.
Speaker 0: But someone who doesn't know that story could understand the plot that that was good.
Speaker 0: The art is also great.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess it's not you know, the art that I'm gonna hang on my wall, but for comic book art It's like hey, this is pretty good arts here.
Speaker 0: I could look at this.
Speaker 0: It's not painful.
Speaker 0: It's pretty appealing.
Speaker 1: Does it have that that charm and class that was reminiscent of the days when I like the x-men a little bit a little bit The way the x-men looked that was epitomized in the Fox cartoon.
Speaker 1: like that is that's the only kind of superhero I like other than I guess cool Batman.
Speaker 0: I can say that I would happily have mr Van Skyver draw some pirates in my sketchbook.
Speaker 0: Right What is wrong with this comic?
Speaker 0: Well, first of all while I understood everything that was going on, right?
Speaker 0: It seemed like When I was reading it that there were lots of references to things and I sort of got the references Like I understood them because I read the little who's who in the front like I understood what they were referencing.
Speaker 0: But it felt like it was sort of like there was a pointer You know that was supposed to like.
Speaker 0: I could tell that huh?
Speaker 0: That's supposed to make me go Like sort of like when you watch a remix of our mashup of things you like and you go Oh, man, look at that mashup and they make a reference to something, you know that, you know.
Speaker 0: But you know other people might not know and you sort of get that feeling, you know, like Like it's.
Speaker 0: I know I know, you know, I guess.
Speaker 0: so it makes like a clever Death Note joke, you know, and it's like You know.
Speaker 1: anytime someone ever says the words if this is a diplomatic mission, then where is the ambassador?
Speaker 0: Yes stuff like that, right and they it seemed like they did that a lot and not being someone who had a pre-existing Emotional attachment to any of these characters or to the story and just a knowledgeable, you know I guess knowledgeable is in terms of one page of text, right?
Speaker 0: It seemed like a lot of the emotions I was supposed to have all reading it?
Speaker 0: I didn't have.
Speaker 0: it was sort of like saying Hey you there Green Lantern fan who loves Green Lantern You should feel who right now because they're referencing something else.
Speaker 0: Ooh, and I'm like, no, I'm not feeling that right now But I can tell you're trying to evoke that emotion.
Speaker 0: It's so obvious.
Speaker 1: It's okay when a work does that because and there are works that had this extra level like they have stuff there for people who?
Speaker 1: Know.
Speaker 1: but yet you can enjoy it not even knowing any of that like watching the V for Vendetta movie.
Speaker 1: There were a ton of references to the comic but they didn't in any way get in the way of enjoying the movie.
Speaker 1: You can enjoy the movie and never even know there was a comic.
Speaker 0: The thing is is that while I you know, I was worried that without knowledge I wouldn't understand but I understood.
Speaker 0: wait a minute.
Speaker 0: There was no enjoyment to be had because all the enjoyment was in the form of references.
Speaker 1: Ah, so I was gonna say there is the problem simply that oh you understood it you understood it all too.
Speaker 0: Now the other problem I have with this right is that much like other DC comics I have read that instead of just sort of being a really close personal kind of story about the characters.
Speaker 0: it ends up being like this cavalcade story where this just Superman's here Batman's here Wonder Woman flash all these people just showing up green arrow.
Speaker 1: I think that comes out of the fact that Pretty much, they know like I mean
Speaker 0: you already have like five or six Green Lanterns to deal with
Speaker 1: All right, you know, I here's why I think they do that All right, so they know I'm gonna make up numbers to make it easy.
Speaker 1: They know that there's like eight people who like Superman and two people who like the flash.
Speaker 1: So if they've got a comic that has Superman in it They're gonna get eight people to buy it.
Speaker 1: if they put the flash in a little bit Then they're gonna get two more people to buy it and they put in the Green Lantern.
Speaker 1: One more dude's gonna buy it.
Speaker 1: and if they put in Wonder Woman then like five other people are gonna buy it.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: I don't know if that's what they're thinking or not But it really it turns everything.
Speaker 0: every single story becomes sort of like this giant world spanning thing with everyone in it and it's really all about this like Unemotional plot where you don't actually have characterization you sort of have these Character templates and the plot just sort of acts on them and the characters don't act.
Speaker 0: They're not like burning wheel characters that you know, like live in life for what you believe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're just sort of like the instead of five.
Speaker 1: for you to believe your instincts are things like I hit you you little guy.
Speaker 0: They're like the characters are the costumes really they're so two-dimensional and then they just this plot just sort of stirs them all up and then you see what happens and I Don't know why people are going crazy for this.
Speaker 0: Like this is like their favorite comic right now, but It's not my favorite comic right now.
Speaker 0: I'll read it.
Speaker 0: You want to read it?
Speaker 1: I'll read it.
Speaker 0: All right, you can read it I'll read it.
Speaker 1: I'll give any comic a fair shake.
Speaker 1: I'll shake it as I'm throwing it now.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna make a joke like that.
Speaker 0: But the actually there was one aspect of the plot, which I enjoyed and Basically what the part of the thing and it's is that one of the Green Lanterns right is basically Unafraid and they keep it's.
Speaker 0: the thing is they're not subtle with it at all.
Speaker 1: They're like, he's not afraid and That could be done so much better.
Speaker 0: But anyway, well, it's it's actually.
Speaker 0: it's a really good Plot mechanism that I liked.
Speaker 0: but the only thing I didn't like about it is it wasn't subtle right.
Speaker 0: and here's is the deal Right, so he's not afraid.
Speaker 0: but Batman is all about, you know controlling people with fear so him and Batman don't get along.
Speaker 1: and it's sort of like The thing is I think that man can't control with fear.
Speaker 1: He controls with violence, right?
Speaker 0: Well, you can't because the dudes like a Green Lantern and Batman is just some guy and they Demonstrate that at one point because he just freaking punches Batman in the face, but I thought Batman kicked Superman's ass.
Speaker 0: This is uh, yeah, that's what people say.
Speaker 0: But yeah, anyway, there's a great like whole page where he's just punching Batman right in the face.
Speaker 0: what repeatedly now just once Batman survive?
Speaker 0: Well, cuz wait a minute.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 0: The Green Lantern doesn't have super strength He has a super ring So he punches you is just like a normal puzzle.
Speaker 1: Batman have that big stupid yellow plate With the passion in the face, so I did Batman just like poking with the yellow thing.
Speaker 0: What yellow thing?
Speaker 1: I don't know like the yellow plate with a bat on it.
Speaker 1: I've seen pictures of Batman with that stupid.
Speaker 1: Yeah Carry around yellow spray paint whenever that dudes.
Speaker 1: They'll actually this grill.
Speaker 0: They talk they talk about you know, there's that's that's part of the stupid plot is like Oh, why yellow this and why it doesn't do any more and blah blah blah blah blah and all that.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of trying to explain away.
Speaker 0: You know things, you know by you know, and they sort of try to incorporate the plot into the explanation.
Speaker 1: I just make a tank that's painted yellow and made out of kryptonite and I don't let any radio signals get in.
Speaker 1: So Batman can't mess with me.
Speaker 1: and then I robbed banks with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway, it was like that was one aspect of the story That was almost enjoyable, but they were so unsubtle and obvious with it.
Speaker 0: It's like if you had a great symbol symbolism and sort of message or like a little theme.
Speaker 0: But then you just came out and just and that yelled it really loud, you know like Yeah, so I cannot recommend These green lanterns by the Geoff Johns that everyone is touting so much as being fantastic.
Speaker 0: They are not mighty.
Speaker 1: I'll read it.
Speaker 1: You might get a geek bite of my own about this in the near future.
Speaker 0: No, I think I'll just have to hear you going.
Speaker 1: God God It'll keep you up all night.
Speaker 0: Plus if you're really if you're gonna read comics, you should read something good and not something bad.
Speaker 1: All right, what should I read next?
Speaker 1: I've already read Watchmen V for Vendetta and Batman the Dark Knight Returns.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'll go get something and bone.
Speaker 0: All right Well, I'll get something.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna talk about this in great detail because I kind of want to wait until this happens and keeps happening and how would people react to it?
Speaker 1: and then I'll talk about it because half of this is it's about time and But the other half is is it too late?
Speaker 1: Gonzo their their new shows are going to be streamed on the internet zero day simultaneously with English subtitles in Japanese in America and the u.s.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and this is with a crunchy roll in YouTube and some other thing and I don't want to go into all the details But for the love of God, it's about time.
Speaker 1: I wish Gonzo the best of luck with this because this is what the anime industry needs.
Speaker 1: None of this.
Speaker 1: Well, we're afraid of Re-importation so we're gonna make the Americans wait a year and by then everyone's pirated it and then we're not gonna market the show at All's.
Speaker 1: no one's gonna buy it.
Speaker 1: But yet we made all these DVDs now are fucked and then rim buys the DVDs for a dollar at an anime con two years later.
Speaker 0: No, you know what's gonna happen now?
Speaker 0: is they're gonna realize huh?
Speaker 0: We're giving it away for free.
Speaker 0: Look how many people are watching way.
Speaker 0: now we can actually tell that this show sucks and that show doesn't suck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but think about this.
Speaker 1: Gonzo could make a good show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they could they could they could.
Speaker 0: maybe they try plus give it away for free online.
Speaker 0: A lot of people watch the early episodes then they'll never get to the end and be disappointed.
Speaker 1: But at the same time they're free.
Speaker 1: You're gonna looks like they'll have like you can pay to get higher quality versions and all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 1: But this this in general is really really really good news, and I hope it goes well.
Speaker 1: But I don't want to talk about that because I have something much more important to talk about Something that could have affected us.
Speaker 1: But I guess luckily.
Speaker 1: But I say this kind of too facedly because at the same time I've wanted to go to anime Boston for like the last six Years, well,
Speaker 0: I don't I didn't really want to go to it like oh, man I really want to go to anime Boston, but it was sort of like hey, there's an anime convention right there.
Speaker 0: Why not go?
Speaker 0: it's also one of the like a couple hours away, and it's pretty significantly large.
Speaker 0: It's like katsu khan-sized.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's bigger than katsu khan.
Speaker 0: by far really.
Speaker 1: they had 15,000 people this year.
Speaker 0: how many katsu?
Speaker 0: kind of 6,000 something.
Speaker 0: oh really okay, I thought I always thought I'm a Boston.
Speaker 0: katsu khan was sort of similarly sized like not as big as Oda khan, but way bigger than like kinetic on, but I guess anime Boston is bigger than I thought.
Speaker 0: well thing is I didn't know a lot about anime Boston because I knew it was an anime convention in Boston.
Speaker 0: That was pretty big every year.
Speaker 1: It would come up and like you know we have our khan schedule.
Speaker 1: We go to a lot of khan's and actually The next khan we're going through.
Speaker 1: just for I'll talk about this more, but we're gonna be pressed at the New York comic-con.
Speaker 1: We're not doing any panels no table nothing.
Speaker 1: If you're gonna be there come say hi to us.
Speaker 1: well, we'll figure out a way to find you.
Speaker 0: well Well there will be times of meeting up.
Speaker 0: Probably look at what like comic podcast people are doing and stuff and also that thing ninja consultants have a table there Yeah, so we can go and bother them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, so every time I thought like I'd be reminded of anime Boston in this kind of conversation.
Speaker 1: Hey, Ram.
Speaker 1: You go to anime Boston tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Oh, I guess not.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yes, oh it was this weekend wasn't it?
Speaker 0: yeah, it's just.
Speaker 0: it's like I don't Track the convention, so I don't know when to reg and it doesn't happen.
Speaker 1: It's not like Otakon where I like have the RSS feed and and or like katsu khan where we sit there and read the staff Email.
Speaker 1: by the way I got to point out again katsu khan is awesome because we're already planning out the layout for the video game Room for next year.
Speaker 1: yeah, that's how it's gotta be but anime Boston did not Exhibit this level of foresight that katsu khan is so wonderfully brought to us.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't know was there video yet at all if their video game room was good or bad or any Boston in general.
Speaker 1: I don't know how many of you have heard it was on anime news network.
Speaker 1: We had a couple of friends there I think Mookie was there, but Basically they fucked up.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh and an anime Boston 2008 was full of epic lose and fail.
Speaker 0: well I'm glad we didn't go then.
Speaker 1: the thing is I Kinda wish we had gone because we weren't what the thing that happened would not have affected us.
Speaker 1: We would have been inside going wow where is everybody?
Speaker 1: and then we would have walked outside and gone.
Speaker 1: oh But basically they Completely boot the registration at anime Boston.
Speaker 1: this year people were reporting Nine and ten plus our weights for badges.
Speaker 0: I mean Otakon has like more people.
Speaker 0: yet the reg so fast.
Speaker 1: Otakon has the best registration of any convention professional or otherwise I've ever been to in my entire life.
Speaker 0: Well, no, there is one better registration and that is where they mail you your non-counterfeitable badge in the mail And then you just walk in.
Speaker 1: well alright alright, but I've never been to a convention that did that.
Speaker 1: okay I'm just saying of all the things I have gone to all the professional conferences all the anime things all the video game everything Otakon's weight is pretty much zero unless you were dumb and choose to wait in line.
Speaker 1: But we don't have to talk about that.
Speaker 1: anyway.
Speaker 1: the deal here is that anime Boston There's a lot of claims as to what happened something like they're saying oh well the convention center Yeah, all everything we're gonna say about anime Boston.
Speaker 0: remember.
Speaker 0: We weren't there.
Speaker 0: We didn't talk to anyone directly who was there.
Speaker 0: We didn't talk to anyone who ran it.
Speaker 0: We're going completely by text on the internet in forums and websites that are reporting.
Speaker 0: so that's you know.
Speaker 0: It's just so.
Speaker 0: in case you say anything wrong We're like tertiary sources here, so don't blame us.
Speaker 0: so apparently we can get we can do.
Speaker 1: there were long long waits on Thursday for pre-registration, but apparently very few people use the Thursday compared to other cons.
Speaker 1: I mean I guess Otakon is kind of the exception where almost half of Otakon's attendees seem to show up like Midday on Thursday and stay until like five o'clock on Sunday, but that might just be the way Otakon is.
Speaker 1: but so Friday Basically the line was just crazy and a lot of people could not get in Friday period and Saturday the lines were still super super super bad.
Speaker 0: was anime Boston?
Speaker 0: was there red?
Speaker 0: how much?
Speaker 0: how much did they grow?
Speaker 1: Well apparently they had about 4,000 more people this year than last.
Speaker 0: that is a pretty significant jump.
Speaker 0: But their reg wasn't so terrible last year right?
Speaker 0: and a 4,000 people wall a significant jump.
Speaker 0: 4,000 people does not a nine-hour line mate right even if their reg last year was like You know a two-hour wait.
Speaker 0: right a 4,000 extra people would most double.
Speaker 0: It's like a three or four hour wait.
Speaker 0: And that would be if they really sucked.
Speaker 0: so even if they didn't modify their registration system at all They would have been just fine this year, and I guess well It would have been just fine, but they wouldn't have been as this bad, so what did they fuck up?
Speaker 1: Well here is the official statement from Jackie Elion.
Speaker 1: we love Archie anime Boston 2008 director of registration.
Speaker 1: also the Providence anime conference 2008 registration manager.
Speaker 1: oh see We Have a lot to say about the Providence anime conference.
Speaker 0: I have to wait.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're only going to go if we're press.
Speaker 1: if we're if I have to pay to go I'm not gonna go especially after this because I don't trust Jackie Elion way Love Archie or lavash.
Speaker 1: I don't know how to pronounce it.
Speaker 1: I don't know this person don't even know what this person looks like.
Speaker 1: But this is the person could be some hot person to whom the buck has been passed quotes to address your points.
Speaker 1: one Gone are the days that the reg division is overlooked.
Speaker 1: I plan to restructure and double the amount of staff we have in the very least now.
Speaker 1: I would like to point out that according to what I heard Even if you quadrupled the number of staff it would not have helped.
Speaker 1: you had so few.
Speaker 1: Anyway moving on point two Unfortunately security suffered a real blow.
Speaker 1: 30% of their staff did not show up.
Speaker 1: They hired 60 and only 40 showed up.
Speaker 1: this forced us to use volunteers for a lot of line wrangling and Unfortunately people you pull from a crowd are never going to be as good as those hired to do a specific job like securities.
Speaker 1: now If this was all line regulation and security these people had almost no impact as far as I could imagine On how long it took to register people.
Speaker 1: so that doesn't really have anything to do with this.
Speaker 1: and uh three Unfortunately, no I'll get to what that's for.
Speaker 1: We did what we could but if we offered any type of refund the con would cease to exist.
Speaker 1: The majority of the cons bills come after the convention and are paid by the at-con funds.
Speaker 1: We cannot possibly do this.
Speaker 1: I hope you understand and wish for anime boston to fix the problems rather than cease to exist now.
Speaker 1: I don't want to sound like a jerk here but if I showed up to any convention that I had paid to to attend And I show up on the first day of the convention and discover that nine hours later will be the earliest I can have my badge.
Speaker 1: I'm going home and i'm demanding a refund and I probably paid with a credit card.
Speaker 1: So in the very least i'm charging back.
Speaker 0: Yeah at the very least charging back.
Speaker 1: No, well pretty much I would have.
Speaker 0: I mean there is a case to be made like, you know, there is.
Speaker 0: you know You're going to have to expect to wait but then there's a reasonable expectation of waiting and nine hours For a con, you know, basically yes, there are events going all day.
Speaker 0: No, it is not possible to get your badge until the you know The day for which you have purchased to go to those events is over.
Speaker 0: That is an unreasonable expectation.
Speaker 1: So yeah now I don't know what's going to come.
Speaker 0: that's like if I bought baseball tickets And they weren't I wasn't going to be able to get to my seat until the ninth inning.
Speaker 0: Unreasonable.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now especially I mean with fan conventions.
Speaker 1: There is a certain extra amount of leeway.
Speaker 0: I give a convention a lot more leeway than I would give a professional for-profit organization Like if you show up at odicon on friday And you pre-reged and you get in by like one.
Speaker 0: that's okay.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's the best but that's expected.
Speaker 0: but seriously nine hours or more more than my entire working day as in If you have to stay in line so long All right that if you a reasonable here's my.
Speaker 0: you know what I just came up with scott's rules for a reasonable line weight.
Speaker 0: A reasonable line weight is a weight in line in which you will never have to take a break for peeing or food.
Speaker 0: If you have to wait in line so long that you need to leave the line to pee Or poop or leave the line to eat a meal and come back to the line.
Speaker 0: That's an unreasonable line.
Speaker 1: But uh, it gets better.
Speaker 1: You want to know what caused this line.
Speaker 0: This is my uh, putting together I've read all the computers that the reg people are using crash.
Speaker 0: They didn't have some sort of a backup system.
Speaker 1: So apparently this year they decided to go with a self-service registration system.
Speaker 1: Oh god now, okay I've read claims that the delays were due to the fact that people took longer to use this system than was expected.
Speaker 0: Well, well Now from being someone who used rides many trains that
Speaker 1: is that's a possibility
Speaker 0: and the tickets for said trains Are sold by automatic machines and the level of incompetence I see people who are not used to those machines using them like if someone knows how to use a metro card machine.
Speaker 0: They're like doot doot doot doot doot and in like 15 to 30 seconds They've done their business.
Speaker 0: someone who doesn't know how to use one could be standing there for up to a minute or more Not knowing what to do And or going very slowly and reading everything very carefully.
Speaker 0: So for an automatic system at a convention registration where there's going to be a line You know each and every person comes up learns it does it.
Speaker 0: that's going to take forever.
Speaker 1: There's now there are ways to mitigate that and I could understand if they'd been a little bit off into how long it would Take for people to do it.
Speaker 1: But how many of these do you think they had?
Speaker 1: how many?
Speaker 1: well how many?
Speaker 0: how many people are waiting in line and one day?
Speaker 1: They quote estimates run as high as 15,000 paid attendees.
Speaker 0: Okay, so 15,000 paid tenants, but they'd all didn't show up Friday.
Speaker 0: So let's give them some slack.
Speaker 0: Let's say like 10,000. so 10,000 people we're gonna say if it takes one minute to To do the do the machine, right?
Speaker 0: It takes 10,000 machine minutes 10,000 machine minutes.
Speaker 0: So if you had one machine it would take 166 hours with 10,000 people to do the whole thing, right?
Speaker 0: Is that right?
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna do the math.
Speaker 0: I think that's about right.
Speaker 1: The thing is someone else did the math in a forum.
Speaker 0: I don't even have to bring it down to a reasonable two or three hours.
Speaker 0: You would need like 50 more than 50 machines.
Speaker 1: now how many machines Scott do you think they had?
Speaker 1: Well judging by his reports differ.
Speaker 0: judging by the resources of a fan-run Anime convention and and because I already know that there were severe nine-hour waits a nine-hour wait I would peg it around 15 something machine for four machines Possibly five.
Speaker 1: I have heard both of those two numbers.
Speaker 0: now they even take into account like machine breakdown because I have no idea.
Speaker 1: but I Could not if that if it is true that they only had five machines Even if they only had ten machines double the numbers that I've seen reported.
Speaker 1: Like there's no way anyone could have thought that would have been adequate.
Speaker 1: There is no possible way.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: It could have been a situation in which you know They contracted out the machines to some company and the company showed up with like four machines when they ordered like a whole bunch We don't know.
Speaker 0: but even if that's the case you basically when you run a convention You need to you know have a plan.
Speaker 0: for what if everyone we're paying to do stuff just doesn't show up and they did not Have such a plan.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean God the content the contingency plans we had it like katsu kon for if things went bad or if any trouble happened and Contingency plans that I am sure Otacon has and that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: It was I Have so much to say but here's what I would have done.
Speaker 1: now again I don't know the full situation But if it was true that there is a very very long nine plus hour line and registration is a problem I would have gotten staffers together even had whoever I need.
Speaker 1: I would have gotten some people I would have gone to the line and I would have designated groups of people by color or something and I would have had a badge amnesty on Friday.
Speaker 1: Anyone can come in and I just have people at the doors making sure we don't violate the fire code.
Speaker 1: Yep Now again this sort of thing might have been not possible due to the contract they signed But it sounds like they had a lot of problems with the contract They signed anyway in terms of using space in the Convention Center, which seems to be a common problem.
Speaker 1: I think Connecticut had a problem with their contract a few years.
Speaker 0: a lot of the fan-run Conventions have a problem and they don't fully read the Convention Center contract or they don't get a lawyer to look at it and they End up breaking some of the rules or violating something somewhere that they didn't realize.
Speaker 1: now I really don't want.
Speaker 0: it is why hotel cons are much easier because you don't have that you don't have as much bull You have bullshit, but hotels are a little more lax than the convention centers.
Speaker 1: No, this is tricky for me because on one hand I don't want to be super down on anime Boston aside from not being there.
Speaker 1: It is a fat, you know fan-run conventions get a lot of slack.
Speaker 1: But at the same time I have to look at this from the perspective of an anime fan and had I gone and not been press or staff or anything I
Speaker 0: Would
Speaker 1: have Basically gone to the front of the line after I discovered that there was basically no way I was gonna get in a reasonable amount Of time I would have demanded a refund for Friday and had they said no I would have charged back my credit card and gone home.
Speaker 1: Yep, or in the very least just not gone to the convention.
Speaker 1: Yep, or I might have even gone to the convention charge back my credit card.
Speaker 1: anyway.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of things I would have done.
Speaker 1: I don't know how many people out there Know that you can charge back on a credit card.
Speaker 0: You can also do stop payment on a check.
Speaker 0: you write.
Speaker 0: of course that cost money though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it does which That's probably good.
Speaker 0: Stop payment stop payment and charging back your credit card are very effective methods for when you are dissatisfied With service usually expensive service.
Speaker 0: for example If you hire like a DJ or something and then for a party and then they suck You should charge them back and then they'll be like what the fuck.
Speaker 0: and then you can be like, you know, you really sucked.
Speaker 0: We're gonna negotiate a lower price because you sucked and then you can really you know, push people around.
Speaker 0: It's it's a good idea sometimes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just don't you know don't get in trouble for stealing because that can happen to like, you know you buy HDTV and then charge it back and keep the TV.
Speaker 0: Yeah not gonna fly now.
Speaker 1: the fact that anime Boston is unable or unwilling to give refunds means one of two things either they're just unwilling to because it would be a substantial burden and but the thing is because they say that it would basically prevent anime Boston from continuing.
Speaker 1: either they're lying which I doubt or they do not have enough operating capital or contingency budget or even Credit to deal with that situation.
Speaker 1: Yeah that also more importantly that means that regardless of like How many people are reported to have been caught up in this mess if the number of people?
Speaker 1: Caught up in this mess to the point that all of them demanding refunds would bankrupt anime Boston That means a lot of people were caught up in this mess and that is inexcusable.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean think about this right if That I mean a lot of fan-run conventions.
Speaker 0: if you don't have just a pile of money like, you know Enough to run the convention already Then you're basically taking all the reg money then using all the reg money to pay for the con and you're breaking.
Speaker 0: You know, you're sort of breaking even and always have an empty bank.
Speaker 0: what
Speaker 1: you've got to do in that case is have in some sort of insurance policy be it and in a negotiated insurance policy that'll cover a contingency like that or Like guaranteed credit based on future revenues some sort of backup plan
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if you're just doing it that way and refunds will kill the con well, I mean think about this right you can either give refunds and kill the con or There'll be some sort of class-action lawsuit and kill the con.
Speaker 0: It's basically they killed their own con and the thing that's sad about it Right is the part that makes me, you know, because on the one hand is like fuck anime Boston They suck.
Speaker 0: but on the other hand to think about this, right?
Speaker 0: The reg people are really the ones who suck and of course I guess the responsibility for that goes all the way to the con chair.
Speaker 0: But think about say the person running panels in anime Boston.
Speaker 0: They might have been running the best damn panels You have no idea.
Speaker 0: but that now their cons gonna die because someone else, you know that something they're not responsible for was the suck.
Speaker 0: And that's you know, what if the video rooms are great and such?
Speaker 0: it's like oh, oh you got it.
Speaker 0: You know that part is kind of sad Yeah.
Speaker 1: But I still and I think you would do the same thing and if I were in the situation Charged-backs are coming.
Speaker 1: Yeah but I got to address something too because While a lot of people are complaining about this legitimately some people You know these people I saw one woman complaining that her son had an asthma attack in line And oh, that's not the kind.
Speaker 0: you can't blame the con for that.
Speaker 1: and more importantly I'm not.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna paraphrase here, but I was looking at the quote a little while ago.
Speaker 1: What they should have done is kept the pillows concert secret.
Speaker 1: people shouldn't have come to this con Just to see that stupid rock band.
Speaker 1: They should have come to the con for the love of anime.
Speaker 1: Pillows is the reason we had these problems.
Speaker 0: Yeah, great.
Speaker 0: Thank you.
Speaker 0: Daryl Surratt's friend.
Speaker 1: I believe it's Daryl Surratt.
Speaker 0: It could be but yeah, that guy needs to shut up.
Speaker 0: It's like yes, there was.
Speaker 0: there are valid things to complain about.
Speaker 0: Yes That doesn't mean that every complaint you have is valid.
Speaker 1: I just in the end.
Speaker 1: I if nothing else.
Speaker 1: if What I'm looking at now from the anime news network is the extent of the formal statement from the con about this I'm not impressed at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, glad I didn't go to anime Boston and I mean, I don't see myself going to it in the near future?
Speaker 1: Definitely not.
Speaker 0: does it mean, you know?
Speaker 0: Well, I had a pillows concert which is something to see but it doesn't really seem like anime Boston has something to offer that.
Speaker 1: oh, I was going through this quickly.
Speaker 1: I'm now looking at the full statement, which is actually much longer.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Do you got any good bits in there?
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 1: My name is Jacquelyn Lavache.
Speaker 1: I'm the director.
Speaker 1: blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: I would like to address the issue of registration wait times this year.
Speaker 1: first and foremost I sincerely apologize for the five plus wait times experience.
Speaker 0: Apologies doesn't fill my wallet and give me my nine hours back.
Speaker 1: There are many factors that caused this to problem this problem.
Speaker 1: These included the lack of sufficient staff which was more than last year, but still not enough.
Speaker 1: We also wrote an entire new database that was created to make it more functional and user-friendly Allowing people options like changing their badge name and seeing the status of the registration for the convention.
Speaker 1: yet There's still kinks that worked out.
Speaker 1: main issue with the self-service kiosk.
Speaker 1: after taking feedback from the previous year We tried a new process of registration that we thought would help spade blah blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: This was not the case.
Speaker 1: We became aware of the problem.
Speaker 1: We immediately began to rearrange the room as best we could to process registrations.
Speaker 1: with permission of the Hines We opened the back door redirected the line.
Speaker 1: blah blah blah blah blah wasn't enough.
Speaker 1: We did our best didn't work.
Speaker 1: after we closed We did an immediate Reconfiguration again did helped but not enough.
Speaker 1: I promise you will fix it next year and we learned a lot.
Speaker 1: I'd like to thank all the staffers who made this possible.
Speaker 1: I was like to thank the Convention Center for making helping us out.
Speaker 1: last like they encourage anyone who has feedback to contact me Send him links to this episode.
Speaker 1: People yeah, also if anyone was there I want to hear some first-hand accounts.
Speaker 0: I definitely want to hear the first time.
Speaker 0: I want to hear exactly what went down from people who are more reliable than Pillows hating guy in the forum.
Speaker 1: Yes, and also written Scott who are reading the forum where pillows hating guy posted.
Speaker 0: All right before we do things of the day.
Speaker 0: I was reminded of one thing.
Speaker 0: I wanted to say We've gotten.
Speaker 0: you might recall we're doing a contest for some books.
Speaker 1: Oh, yes.
Speaker 0: I forgot to mention last week and So far we've gotten two entries one of which was fail and one of which I have to double-check just to make sure it's not Fail.
Speaker 1: however, even if it fails due to some technicality it is definitely win in terms of content.
Speaker 0: I think it is so if you want the entire Guin saga manga published by vertical which I've talked about on the show before.
Speaker 0: it's a good manga.
Speaker 0: It's not the greatest manga ever, but it's it's high quality.
Speaker 0: It's worth owning.
Speaker 0: It's a fantasy manga, which is rare to come by.
Speaker 0: I mean a good fantasy manga is worth something if you like fantasy because there's not a lot of them.
Speaker 0: All you have to do is write an essay about why we should give it to you for free.
Speaker 0: You need to you know, have be grammatically and spellingly correct.
Speaker 0: You need to email it to geeknightsofrontrecruit.com put something in the subject line about the contest Guin saga manga and You need to write at least five paragraphs.
Speaker 1: I think we said and it has to be an essay We want a thesis statement some sort of conclusion paragraph, you know body paragraph number one reason number one Why you should give it to me.
Speaker 1: I'm awesome body paragraph number two.
Speaker 0: Also, I'm awesome Number three, I'm poor number four.
Speaker 0: I like manga.
Speaker 0: It's you know, something like that in conclusion.
Speaker 1: Give it to me.
Speaker 0: Yes, so If you do this The odds are that if you follow the rules of the contest and actually succeed in sending us a proper essay in the proper format With proper grammar and spelling and all that you're probably going to win.
Speaker 0: It's your free manga in exchange for typing.
Speaker 0: This is probably if I not get if I don't get any more entries because so far they've been two entries.
Speaker 0: So I don't get any entries soon.
Speaker 0: I think by next week.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna mail it out cuz.
Speaker 1: yeah Why didn't anime Boston just go halfway down the line and tell those people to come back later?
Speaker 0: because they're dumb They're well cuz.
Speaker 0: think about it.
Speaker 0: if they did that it would have been like a New York Comic Con situation of you know People are standing outside then someone comes out and says go home.
Speaker 0: You're not getting in.
Speaker 1: Well, you know what?
Speaker 1: you know what else you could have done.
Speaker 1: could have gotten a bunch of people and printed out a bunch of numbers and given people Numbers and said come back and then we'll get back in line with these numbers after we sort this business out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, good.
Speaker 0: Uh, there's a they could have done something they didn't, you know improvise with the wellness.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right enough ragging on anime Boston.
Speaker 1: After 40 minutes of that it's time for things of the day.
Speaker 0: really 40 minutes almost.
Speaker 0: Okay things that a real quick All right.
Speaker 1: So what do you got?
Speaker 0: So this is website that's actually been getting pretty popular lately called bit strips calm.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty good website.
Speaker 0: Basically what you do is if you have no artistic skills whatsoever like me you make comics but you don't have to draw.
Speaker 0: you just have to type and make characters and drag them around.
Speaker 0: and People are making a lot of funny comics on here including me.
Speaker 0: It's everyone come and make comics.
Speaker 1: We'll make some sort of forum thread dedicated.
Speaker 0: There is a forum thread dedicated to it.
Speaker 1: Well, I'll link to that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So I'm catching up on a lot of animes suddenly on the train and right now I'm watching bokurano, which is fantastic.
Speaker 1: We reviewed it briefly a while ago.
Speaker 1: Once I finish it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna give it to Scott.
Speaker 1: He's gonna watch it all and then we're gonna do some sort of full-on review.
Speaker 1: It's a really good show.
Speaker 1: But my thing of the day is very simple.
Speaker 1: It's a YouTube video that includes a piano rendition of the opening theme.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: No, the opening theme is a really really really good song.
Speaker 0: That's that uninstall song.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty good song.
Speaker 0: I like it.
Speaker 1: Well, it's the nice thing the thing about bokurano and what.
Speaker 1: the reason I picked this thing today is that it seems like you can Almost always tell if a show is worth watching by the opener and a lot of the times you can it is for anime.
Speaker 1: Like there's certain things that are common in openers for good shows.
Speaker 0: Well, let's see Japanese j-rock or j-pop Opener.
Speaker 0: this show cost a lot of money and will probably be very popular.
Speaker 1: an opener that was written for the show.
Speaker 1: This show has the backing of people who care.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can pretty much.
Speaker 0: you know opener that has a dance, you know You can really tell a whole lot about an anime show from the opener once you know anime.
Speaker 1: generic j-rock opener generic show Yep, but anyway, that's all I got.
Speaker 1: So moving on tonight last night We were trying.
Speaker 1: we tried to watch ghetto Sankey, but we ran into some trouble and it was late.
Speaker 1: So in the said we watched some anime.
Speaker 0: So instead of the studio Ghibli we watched two completely random episodes of some animes.
Speaker 0: We're random.
Speaker 1: luckily, I will probably go short on this because this turned into the oh my god.
Speaker 1: anime Boston episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's fun.
Speaker 0: So you want which one you want to do first?
Speaker 1: I think we should talk about Nightwizard the animation.
Speaker 0: All right, so we watched episode 1 of Nightwizard the animation.
Speaker 0: This is actually a show an episode that we had watched a long time ago But where you rewatched it to sort of refresh the memory.
Speaker 0: as to what was the deal with this show?
Speaker 0: Basically, it's one of those Feel good Scream and shout anime club shows.
Speaker 0: That's not so great to watch on your own But with friends it can be a good good old time.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: It's nothing spectacular If you run an anime club show the first episode of this to your club.
Speaker 0: Good God, I cannot stress that enough But if you're looking for some highbrow kind of you know anime for the ages you want to wait for the next show.
Speaker 1: We're gonna talk.
Speaker 0: This is not your department.
Speaker 1: what frightens me is the absolutely high ratings the show has gotten on the anime news network Really?
Speaker 0: Oh, wow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those are those are a pretty above average ratings.
Speaker 1: Yeah The thing is I would actually have rated the show kind of highly because I know it's the kind of thing that Dave Riley hates.
Speaker 1: It's one of those wacky anime comedies.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'd give this like Seven out of ten this show if it didn't have six and a half.
Speaker 1: It's got this problem where it's one of those zany crazy funny because it's just so stupid.
Speaker 1: but yet You know well-constructed shows but tacked on to that is an actual takes itself seriously plot that Totally just doesn't fit.
Speaker 0: Basically, the story is it seems like there's a normal world and some sort of monster world, right?
Speaker 0: And they sort of interact and they don't really tell you much about it except there There are some kids who have to fight the monsters of course.
Speaker 1: and the main character is I'm pretty easy.
Speaker 0: in the main character Cuz he gets about equal screen time with some other characters.
Speaker 1: I think he's the character who's supposed to identify with I guess.
Speaker 1: But Renji is a kid and all he wants is to get to goddamn school.
Speaker 1: But instead no this woman comes up and says woman.
Speaker 0: She's like 12 years old find this, but she looks love She's a wizard or something.
Speaker 1: She's probably.
Speaker 0: she's in charge.
Speaker 0: She's sort of.
Speaker 0: there's one girl who's in charge of like the good Wizard types and there's another girl who seems to be in charge of the evil.
Speaker 0: yeah, basically It seems sort of like a harem show because this is the one guy who wants to get to school and all the other characters are Like the childhood friend who's a girl the the shy new girl who's you know friends with the childhood friend girl?
Speaker 0: the quiet girl with the gun who helps fight the monsters the evil in charge of the monsters girl and The kind of bitchy Annoying in charge of the good guys girl, so it's a bunch of girls in a guy.
Speaker 1: now The show has a lot of very kind of cliche, but cliche within the context of the show like tropes.
Speaker 1: I mean There's this basically the head girl of his night.
Speaker 1: wizards will grab the guy Usually while he's on his way to school or while he's on his way back from the last mission on Trying to get to school again and say pretty much alright.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna send you to probably die in this horrible fight.
Speaker 1: Are you gonna respond with okay, or?
Speaker 0: Yes, she's like.
Speaker 0: she's like you guys.
Speaker 0: I'm offering you this mission.
Speaker 0: You can replace ply with okay, or yes.
Speaker 1: now This is obviously one of those really really forced jokes, but I found myself cracking up at it the third time.
Speaker 1: I don't know why.
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: don't know I laughed at it the first time because I remembered it you know cuz I remember like oh, yeah This is the okay, or yes show ha ha ha ha, but then every other time they tell the okay, or yes joke It's like yeah,
Speaker 1: so what are these missions?
Speaker 1: This is when it goes from a kid in the modern world walk into school He's pulled into space onto Mars, and now he's fighting skeletons that are dressed up like clowns with a sword.
Speaker 1: and This is when we see the absolute best part of this entire series not this episode the whole series.
Speaker 0: He's even though you've only ever seen the first episode.
Speaker 1: He's thrown onto Mars right and He lands on top of all the a bunch of these skeletons and the one skeleton directly behind the skeleton he fell on.
Speaker 1: Does the skeleton equivalent of raising an eyebrow?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that alone.
Speaker 1: What makes this show worth it?
Speaker 1: that one second of screen time Partly cuz it reminds me of a character Scott played in an old D&D game a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I thought the best part was the second mission.
Speaker 0: They send him on.
Speaker 0: he has to fight like these midget No-mo, and he goes to eat lunch right.
Speaker 0: so then he finally beats up all the no monsters And they're only like nine of them, and he so he sits down He breaks out this bento, and he's eating it, and he's like ah finally I can't get to school But I can eat my lunch.
Speaker 0: and he's sitting on Mars Around with all these dead monsters and he breaks out his lunch and a monster You know sort of gets up and sort of creeps up behind him, and he just sort of backfists it And he's like fuck you.
Speaker 0: I'm eating lunch.
Speaker 1: God damn it.
Speaker 1: I love the backfist.
Speaker 1: It's so used in anime I mean hokudono can.
Speaker 1: there's like one backfist per episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I don't know what it is about the backfist.
Speaker 0: I don't know There's something about that not Looking.
Speaker 0: someone comes up behind you and you just sort of hit him with the back of your fist and right in the face and They go down.
Speaker 0: That's that's so cool.
Speaker 0: It feels like it works every time even though.
Speaker 0: It's cliche.
Speaker 1: You know how I know I know how that really works though You know we learn this in kung kung fu.
Speaker 1: So this is what you do.
Speaker 1: If ever you're like if you know in your life that at some point people are gonna sneak up on you What you do is you train the kung fu so you can do all those different kinds of punches Especially that back fist punch and every five minutes you just back fist punch Whether or not there's anything there and hopefully whenever someone's sneaking up on you one day.
Speaker 1: You'll get him.
Speaker 1: No, no, but that's what I imagine.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: You might notice that I didn't pay attention.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and like if you back fist punch if no one's there.
Speaker 0: You just sort of raise your hand and y'all And then you hit you break someone's face by accident you run away.
Speaker 1: actually I think an honorable mention for good scenes in this episode is when they play the crane game with the kid.
Speaker 1: I Don't remember that they pull him up with that hook from the sky.
Speaker 1: All right, right, right Yeah, but then the whole second half of this episode has some sort of serious crap plot about a girl.
Speaker 1: It's totally the girls dead in that thing.
Speaker 1: I don't even want to bother talking about it.
Speaker 1: The tree comes back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that one of the shy girl discovers that she's like a night wizard too and then fighting a tree.
Speaker 0: I can't get over the title.
Speaker 0: That has a generic multi-beast in it.
Speaker 0: Ah the multi-beast Yeah, we're arguing like is it really a chimera?
Speaker 0: Is it really lion lizard and the correct combination?
Speaker 1: It's some kind of multi-beast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was like, it's some generic multi-beast.
Speaker 0: I'm like, I really like the word multi-beast.
Speaker 0: I'm glad I came up with it.
Speaker 1: What I really like though is that they're like, oh, it's the tree.
Speaker 1: blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: You should confess your love to the person you're like under this tree and then good things will happen.
Speaker 0: Like and it's like this horrible ugly tree with nothing growing on it.
Speaker 1: that's been like gnarled in there for centuries Like it's the.
Speaker 1: it looks exactly like the evil tree that tries to eat the kid in poltergeist.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then suddenly as they go to the evil world and the multi-beast comes out suddenly It's a beautiful cherry blossom tree like the biggest one in the ever seen.
Speaker 0: it's like, okay So in the evil world things are nicer.
Speaker 0: Okay, and then it kills the multi-beast and the tree gets ugly again.
Speaker 0: It's like wait, aren't you supposed to kill the multi-beast?
Speaker 0: and then the tree gets pretty.
Speaker 0: it's totally backwards.
Speaker 1: Maybe these are the bad guys But just the title I don't know.
Speaker 1: night wizard does not sound like a good show.
Speaker 1: all.
Speaker 1: if anything whenever I hear Night wizard all I can think is I put on my robe and wizard hat.
Speaker 0: Yeah So if you're looking for 15 minutes of you know Laughing it up with your and already your friends who are already anime fans and already know anime cliches.
Speaker 0: Or you have an anime club.
Speaker 0: you can watch this first episode and get some yucks.
Speaker 0: I would not recommend.
Speaker 0: Like watching this whole show for as like a serious Yes is the best show ever kind of deal because I think there's gonna be some harem elements and some Elements really lean a little bit toward lesbians a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's hard to tell without more episodes.
Speaker 1: It's not nearly as sexually charged as Bocorano though.
Speaker 0: It's only a 13 episode show apparently.
Speaker 0: So if you're bored, hey You know what.
Speaker 1: though if you're that bored I can name a hundred shows you should watch before that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the animation in the show is average.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's that standard Computery.
Speaker 1: well done Chris modern bad standard modern anime.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: What's the other show we're talking about?
Speaker 1: Well the other show we debated Watching the show almost as long as it took to actually watch the show based on the name alone.
Speaker 1: Yes, because we knew this was gonna be bad going into it.
Speaker 0: It's a show from 2000.
Speaker 0: Well night wizard is from 2007 the end of last year.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh, yeah Almost forgot.
Speaker 1: night wizard was directed by the eminent Yusuke Yamamoto who is famous for fuck all.
Speaker 1: anyway.
Speaker 0: Okay This show we're about to talk about is from like the end of 2000 and early 2001 and it's a 20 episode show.
Speaker 0: I guess I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: that's what anime news network says and The setting of this show is actually really awesome.
Speaker 0: It takes place in 1947 Shinjuku and it's actually pretty cool because you know it really takes the historical Context into account and I like that.
Speaker 0: It's the rest of the show.
Speaker 0: That's the problem.
Speaker 1: Well, you know to be fair.
Speaker 1: I just got to go back.
Speaker 1: He did do welcome to the NHK and sergeant frog, okay But anyway, I just that's my thing.
Speaker 1: I like to say famous for fuck all whenever I don't recognize a director All right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yes the show we're also we're about to talk about now is Directed by Nobutaka Nishizawa who I'm pretty sure is not the niche because I remember there was I I discussed this with you know Gerald and people in the know.
Speaker 0: there's the niche.
Speaker 0: who's actually some other niches our and This niche is actually a different niche and this is not a bad niche.
Speaker 0: I mean Nobutaka Nishizawa was the chief director of the Galaxy Express TV show.
Speaker 0: Was the series director of a Dragon Quest show?
Speaker 0: Was did the Patiliro remember this?
Speaker 0: last time they came up is when we did the Patiliro.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah that show.
Speaker 0: yeah, so that's that's this director that we're talking about here and The show that we're gonna talk about.
Speaker 0: All right based on the name alone.
Speaker 0: It's gonna tell you everything you need to know.
Speaker 0: The name of this show is legendary gambler Tetsuya.
Speaker 1: Now you might remember our review of Akagi.
Speaker 1: I Orders of magnitude worse than the show.
Speaker 1: the show has a tiny bit of entertainment value.
Speaker 1: Akagi had one good moment ever and that moment was very simply.
Speaker 1: How's he gonna do it?
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Well, I think Akagi also concentrated mostly on the mahjong whereas legendary gambler Tetsuya while there's it's it does concentrate quite a bit on the mahjong.
Speaker 0: there is Also, mostly the gam the gambling and the you know characters and the setting does take some Effect.
Speaker 1: but in Akagi, it's like how's he gonna do it?
Speaker 1: mahjong is a game of almost complete chance.
Speaker 1: It's it's not a test of skill or anything.
Speaker 1: Oh my god How are they gonna make this dramatic and then he just fucking cheats?
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least that made sense.
Speaker 0: It's like well, there's no way to add.
Speaker 0: How's he gonna win without eating?
Speaker 1: This show is also about mahjong and How do you think they handle the tense situation?
Speaker 1: How do you think they they do it?
Speaker 0: Well, they pretty much use all of these cinematic and animation techniques that were perfected in initial D and they multiply them by a thousand.
Speaker 1: the music starts playing.
Speaker 1: the guy across the table has the Aura, I mean he throws down the piece like for BAM ladies.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah You can really say about the show other than it's.
Speaker 1: I got crack five five crack.
Speaker 1: I've crack.
Speaker 1: I don't know I'm not an old Jewish lady now.
Speaker 0: Yeah for people who don't know mahjong is an ancient Chinese tile game.
Speaker 0: That's very similar to gin rummy In the way it is played played
Speaker 1: by three groups of people,
Speaker 0: but it's also played by old Jewish ladies in the United States and they sort of play a different version of the game in a way and It's you know, it's played with the same set of tiles, but it's a very different game But it's still.
Speaker 0: it's not a very it's a somewhat different game.
Speaker 0: just to give you some you know knowledge background.
Speaker 1: So what happens in this show?
Speaker 0: someone cheats, oh, okay Well, I think it was just really experts late of hand and still cheating.
Speaker 0: The other thing is that in Akagi they were showing you the like the cheating technique and this one is like No way.
Speaker 0: that tile was like under the table.
Speaker 0: how the hell that happened.
Speaker 1: But there was one really good scene and you know The show does remind me a lot of initial D Like.
Speaker 1: there's.
Speaker 1: there's a character who's kind of like bunta and there's a character who's got like they kind of.
Speaker 1: they set up the same Thing and there's the old differences that the main character loses right away.
Speaker 1: But the old master like this is set by the way at the end of World War two.
Speaker 0: I told him that already.
Speaker 1: Yes, so well This is important because there's a scene where they're all playing their illegal mahjong and then that was.
Speaker 0: that was the good scene.
Speaker 1: You're right, and then American bombers come so everyone's running away.
Speaker 0: Now this is a flashback to when the main character is like learning mahjong from the master back in the day and the master is Like.
Speaker 1: I know what I must do.
Speaker 1: luck luck luck blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: and he walks back.
Speaker 0: At least they got it right.
Speaker 0: mahjong is all about luck and nothing else.
Speaker 0: and he walks back into the building instead of evacuating Like I'm just gonna die today and he goes like up on the roof of the building and all the students are like no What are you going in the roof of the building?
Speaker 0: You're gonna die.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, and it's set up like one of those.
Speaker 1: All right This is how the like mentor with the main character died.
Speaker 1: and then we're gonna have flashbacks to this all the time and you know Not quite to the gundam sea level of yelling out the people's names but I expected that yep.
Speaker 1: And then this is really a spoiler cuz you're probably not gonna watch this show and even if you do whatever.
Speaker 1: So they come back out and he goes to like see if he's okay and the guys just taking a nap on the roof didn't Care at all.
Speaker 0: He's like, hey luck, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah My god.
Speaker 0: Oh my they totally took the whole flashback to.
Speaker 1: you know, my mentor bit and turned it on and say and What we thought was a 50 yen coin Emily informed was that was actually a 50 zany coin and as any is We're nothing nothing.
Speaker 1: It's like what a hundredth of a yen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's our zany God who gets his name from the zany which is like a worthless coin.
Speaker 1: Yeah we knew that but we didn't know that that was any and we're like 50 yen's a lot back then because they're talking about 500 yen, like it's this crazy amount of money.
Speaker 0: and then I'm like, but wait that coin you just had said 50 on it.
Speaker 0: He just let it sit on the floor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, it was there 50 nothing.
Speaker 0: Oh the up.
Speaker 1: The other thing is that the the awesome Boonta like guy is Peter Laurie.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he kind of.
Speaker 1: yes You might not recognize that name, but you recognize that guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's that guy from all those old mafia movies Yep, and a lot of he was in M and he was in.
Speaker 1: You'll know the guy when you see him.
Speaker 1: maybe I'll link to a picture of him if I think too He's on Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: But anyway, that's pretty much all this shows.
Speaker 1: God There's not much to it.
Speaker 1: It's better than Akagi if you really are into initial D kind of shows and you know about mahjong.
Speaker 1: But you got to know about mahjong and you got to know about it from a Japanese perspective.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's one thing that really got me is like I know how to play mahjong the Chinese way and I know how to play it The old Jewish lady way, right and I know the old Jewish lady terminology and I know the Chinese terminology.
Speaker 0: They're playing mahjong as far as I can tell the Chinese way, right, but they're using Japanese terminology.
Speaker 0: So I can't understand what's going on.
Speaker 1: Oh also this show exhibits a frightening Misunderstanding of the applications of statistics.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's quite frightening.
Speaker 0: good.
Speaker 0: At least I think he didn't do that.
Speaker 1: Yes, I think he was like, oh he just cheated.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Okay, but this show is like you change the order of the draw.
Speaker 1: now the game's different.
Speaker 0: Oh my god It's also like the guy's on a roll.
Speaker 0: He won the last game.
Speaker 0: He's gonna.
Speaker 0: he's on a streak.
Speaker 0: I gotta break his streak.
Speaker 1: He's got momentum in this completely separate game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like oh my god He rolled a six.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: He rolled another six.
Speaker 0: He's gonna roll a six again.
Speaker 0: No, it's a one out of six chance of him rolling his eggs.
Speaker 0: It's it's not changing.
Speaker 1: All right I think that's all we got.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.