Speaker 0: It's Monday March 31st.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: more on programming languages.
Speaker 0: Let's do this This weekend.
Speaker 1: well this past weekend was the night of iron.
Speaker 0: It's really more like the nothing weekend.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it was the weekend that also included the night of iron.
Speaker 1: well Saturday night We had nothing better to do and we had free time and all our work was done.
Speaker 1: So uh we had the night of iron And it was indeed a night of much metal, and it was a very good kind of metal notice.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying what it was.
Speaker 1: that's because I kind of want to keep you all in suspense Because nothing called night of iron could not be awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we sort of just we didn't plan the night of iron and just sort of we were like hey Why don't we do this and like hey?
Speaker 0: That's that would be the night of iron wouldn't it?
Speaker 1: and the of course then we had no choice.
Speaker 1: the path before us had been Prepared.
Speaker 1: yeah, yeah That's all I got.
Speaker 1: the weekend was relaxing.
Speaker 1: I went to work today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh, I remember.
Speaker 0: I have an opening bit.
Speaker 1: I remember what it was like five minutes before the show going on.
Speaker 1: man I wanted to say something, but I forgot it as screw it and now you remember it.
Speaker 0: now I remember it.
Speaker 0: I knew I would remember it real soon that I did all right.
Speaker 0: So what do you got so when I worked in the city the last time which is the first job?
Speaker 0: I got out of college.
Speaker 0: that wasn't a co-op right.
Speaker 0: I worked over near where Emily and Alex work now right and that building Had a scaffold on it.
Speaker 1: is that scaffold finally gone?
Speaker 0: well No, that's scaffold while I was still working there.
Speaker 0: They removed it right at some point.
Speaker 1: is it back?
Speaker 1: no Did it fall on someone now?
Speaker 0: then I that same company moved me to the middle of nowhere And then I quit that company and I came to work for the company I'm working at now.
Speaker 0: the building that I'm working at now had a scaffold on it.
Speaker 0: Until today they removed the scaffold.
Speaker 1: I think that means that you're gonna get a new job.
Speaker 0: I know I think it means that I I will only be hired by companies in New York that have scaffolds around the building.
Speaker 0: Well, you know eventually that scaffold to be removed for the building.
Speaker 1: by that logic because I have a similar logic every time I get a job.
Speaker 1: I walk from Yonkers station up to Well from Yonkers station up to kind of the northern part of Yonkers Uh-huh, and then I take the number six bus.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So yeah call Randy, okay.
Speaker 1: So yeah, that's all we got.
Speaker 0: That's it Scaffolds on buildings.
Speaker 0: It's pretty freaky when they take them off cuz that scaffold must have been there so long Cuz all the stores they don't have big signs saying what they are.
Speaker 0: This is this big flat area.
Speaker 0: So all those stores are probably gonna be calling up the sign makers.
Speaker 1: Well, actually funnily enough.
Speaker 1: I went to dinner a ramen joint with Emily on Friday just kind of out of the blue.
Speaker 1: Okay, I want to go to dinner.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we went out and I did.
Speaker 1: we just we're walking through asked like near Astor place because there's an awesome video game store there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then she says hey, look where we are Remember this and I'm like I look around and I don't recognize anything like I look and it's like wow I probably never been on the street before and it turns out no It was that she used to live on that street.
Speaker 1: The scaffold was just gone.
Speaker 1: It looked like a different Street.
Speaker 1: Yep, but that reminded me of something that happened Before I met her.
Speaker 1: I got out of work I got killed by a scaffold.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I'm in fact dead.
Speaker 0: This is a computer-generated Rim and scaffold.
Speaker 1: ate your mom much like how they finished that John Candy movie without John.
Speaker 0: and I even seek you miss eek scaffold revenge.
Speaker 1: Actually that that leads to even God talk about the non sequitur train going off to nowhere.
Speaker 1: Well, actually no, it's the sequitur train.
Speaker 1: It's not a non sequitur at all.
Speaker 1: when John Candy died that When John came back
Speaker 0: I was killed by a scaffold
Speaker 1: and when princess died when both of them died were two instances Where I was able to prove to my parents Astoundingly that the internet was powerful because they never believed me and they always kind of scoffed at like whatever.
Speaker 1: and then I remember one day I was like, hey John Candy's dead and they were like what.
Speaker 1: that's BS.
Speaker 1: There's no way.
Speaker 0: and then the next day the new there's no way that a big fat unhealthy guy died.
Speaker 1: Okay It was there's no way.
Speaker 1: how would you found out about that?
Speaker 1: I was like.
Speaker 1: the internet said so.
Speaker 1: And then when princess died, I was in the realm playing and then someone named princess die was said out of the blue man I'm gonna get a lot of shit for this name.
Speaker 1: He'd even called that for like two years.
Speaker 1: Uh, and he I'm like what.
Speaker 1: and he's like, uh, Well, and he says what happened.
Speaker 1: and then we're all like, oh Yeah, that sucks.
Speaker 0: change your name dude, no, he was like level 80 you couldn't change your name, uh Yeah, what can you change your name in the World of Warcraft?
Speaker 1: It's just make an alt and power level it.
Speaker 0: I know but I mean like if I level up to like the highest level in World of Warcraft But my name suddenly becomes taboo.
Speaker 0: Can I change it?
Speaker 1: Yes by making an alt and power leveling it.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's the thing all you kids now.
Speaker 1: You're so lucky.
Speaker 1: There was no such thing as power leveling in the realm.
Speaker 0: Well, there was there every I think, you know back in the day there was power leveling But you know what they did.
Speaker 0: they would fucking notice you doing it and kick your ass.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 1: back in the day Once you got a high enough level you get like one experience point for killing the biggest baddest thing in the land.
Speaker 1: You'd have to go and kill it a thousand times to level up.
Speaker 1: There was no way around that.
Speaker 1: a higher level character couldn't get you more experience.
Speaker 0: All right anyway.
Speaker 1: Good move on to news and things of the day, but I didn't tell my story Because I don't worry I don't know I have a lot to say about my news.
Speaker 1: so aside from John Candy dying I was waiting in the Starbucks duster place not the scary hobo Starbucks the other Starbucks the nice one.
Speaker 0: Oh this story.
Speaker 1: Okay, and this is just weird and funny and it's probably bad because I'm sure it stroked my ego just a little bit.
Speaker 1: But at the same time it's kind of weird.
Speaker 1: It's funny.
Speaker 0: I think your ego It's kind of hard for anyone to stroke it because basically you have these auto Strokers that are covering every inch of it.
Speaker 0: You know what and the surface area is.
Speaker 0: even though the surface area is constantly increasing He does the auto strokers sort of spawn new strokers.
Speaker 1: I think the real the real issue with my ego is that.
Speaker 1: well actually it's much related to tomorrow's thing of the day anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I'm sitting in the Starbucks and Emily calls me.
Speaker 1: She says she's gonna be a little bit late, and that's fine.
Speaker 1: I got my laptop I'm working on stuff, and I'm just chilling there and a few minutes later this cool this guy.
Speaker 1: He's pretty cool-looking you know 20-something guy, and he he walks up behind me, and he says excuse me, sir.
Speaker 1: And I'm like yes, I turn around are you a?
Speaker 1: Long pregnant pause are you rim from geek nights, and I'm like yes Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I can't believe it's you.
Speaker 1: I heard your voice But I wasn't sure where.
Speaker 1: I had to look a picture of you up online and make sure it was you.
Speaker 1: oh my god My girlfriend's gonna be so jealous cuz she's not here, but oh my god.
Speaker 1: And that the fact that I have been recognized by a fan Randomly in New York City as opposed to randomly at say an anime convention.
Speaker 1: I've been to for the last five years is Somewhat startling and bad for my ego not getting any smaller.
Speaker 0: well I mean on the one hand it's sort of likely I mean in a crowded city with a lot of people.
Speaker 0: you know if you have a few thousand fans around the world You know and we Limit to the English-speaking world odds of fans being in New York City pretty good Odds of fans being in a part in New York City where people our age tend to be a little bit about.
Speaker 0: you know It's really.
Speaker 0: you met a fan in public in the one of the most likely places Most likely places that'd be like a GameStop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, but you know what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: It's like it's pretty close.
Speaker 0: It's pretty high on the charts of likely place to meet a geek nights fan in public.
Speaker 0: yeah But even then I think it's not like you met a geek nights fan on a cornfield in Kansas.
Speaker 1: You know that might be more likely because odds are if I was going to a cornfield in Kansas on the show I'd be like I'm gonna be in this stupid cornfield next week if anyone lives there.
Speaker 1: Please come say hi.
Speaker 0: Please give me some gosh Much of glory.
Speaker 0: I need more of everything else.
Speaker 1: But no I think it illustrates something much more important.
Speaker 1: People recognize us not by sight, but by sound.
Speaker 1: now think of that sitting there doing your thing and Sony redo our website.
Speaker 0: We'll have we'll go get pictures taken of us, and we'll have pictures there.
Speaker 0: So people will recognize us by sight and we'll also start doing videos or something.
Speaker 1: the fact that you could be sitting somewhere And then you hear my voice, and it's like I don't know where that voice came from but I know what it was.
Speaker 1: Yep, so yeah, dude.
Speaker 1: I forget your name, but I think I saw that you emailed me.
Speaker 1: You're totally cool.
Speaker 0: I think his girlfriend emailed.
Speaker 1: Oh he also emailed us like a little while ago.
Speaker 1: I haven't read it yet.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay, whatever cuz I'm doing this podcast thing instead.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I'm speaking of podcast.
Speaker 1: What are you on the news?
Speaker 0: okay, so Motorola.
Speaker 0: Motorola is a company.
Speaker 0: Motorola makes a lot more things than you realize they make.
Speaker 0: I mean Before the max had like IBM power PCs in them.
Speaker 0: now all the max had Motorola CPUs in them.
Speaker 0: Motorola makes a lot of chips that make a lot of things.
Speaker 0: in general you probably have Motorola products in your house.
Speaker 0: You don't even know about The Motorola products in your house.
Speaker 0: that you do know about though are usually probably cell phones and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: and you know for a long time Motorola actually was a pretty badass cell phone maker.
Speaker 0: I mean that's star tech.
Speaker 0: I had one that was one of the best phones.
Speaker 0: It's like the first phone that was kind of thin you know.
Speaker 0: and then they made the razor Which is like y'all.
Speaker 0: it's a huge hit.
Speaker 0: right crazy huge but You don't really realize it these days, but Motorola is kinda in the shitter not doing so.
Speaker 0: well yeah, they they've had a lot of trouble lately in the stocks and such and and and One of the things I realized you know from reading this and reading other things is that business wise?
Speaker 0: Part of the reason they're doing bad is not only because they haven't come up with anything new But I'll get to that but because the razor right.
Speaker 0: when the razor first came out.
Speaker 0: It was like it was sort of like Apple's products.
Speaker 0: It was a super sexy high-profile device that people desired because it was so ludicrously thin right.
Speaker 0: But unlike Apple where Apple will up the marketing up the price and make it you know like oh, it is so great.
Speaker 0: Motorola started out that way.
Speaker 0: the razor was like 200 bucks and like this ultra fancy thing.
Speaker 0: only for a minute.
Speaker 0: You know cool people.
Speaker 1: But then now long later him Captain gets the cheapest crap cell phone that he can get free from.
Speaker 1: whoever gets cell phones from Goes to get a cell phone, and they're like here's a razor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now.
Speaker 0: I have it like every freaking color.
Speaker 0: It's the free phone that you get it's like.
Speaker 0: so it's really you know doing that.
Speaker 0: on the one hand You know it's sort of like.
Speaker 0: well You make a lot of money because now you sell a bajillion razors But on the other hand you don't make so much money and keep your company afloat because you don't have you're not the having the cool Awesome products, but now as for not coming up with anything else Some guy he's not just some guy.
Speaker 0: actually he's new mayor for Oz.
Speaker 0: I probably pronounced his name wrong.
Speaker 0: Sorry new mayor for Oz He was the personal advisor To Jeffrey Frost.
Speaker 0: Jeffrey Frost was Motorola's former CMO.
Speaker 0: That's the guy who in pretty much invented the razor right and then worked on the rocker And he was pretty much the guy at Motorola who may and pretty much came up with all their shit.
Speaker 0: That was worth a damn.
Speaker 0: and without that guy.
Speaker 0: They're fucked.
Speaker 0: and well that guy died in 2005 and it's pretty sad Because I mean there's no evidence of this.
Speaker 0: But if you read the story like if this was like a play on Broadway You it.
Speaker 0: basically the guy was worked to death.
Speaker 0: the company and all the executives pretty much work this guy To death having him come up with all the new stuff, but regardless that's a separate.
Speaker 1: It's a separate issue though granted this obviously this guy had a high truck factor.
Speaker 0: He had the highest truck factor because now without him Motorola's in the shitter and his personal advisor new mayor for Oz Wrote a letter to engage.
Speaker 0: well He wrote a letter to Greg Brown and the rest of the executive team of Motorola pretty much Calling them out like well you guys suck.
Speaker 0: You've ruined Motorola, which is a great company blah blah blah and This is really a fascinating read.
Speaker 0: because he sent the letter to Engadget to be posted on Engadget, which There's a guy Jason Calacanis who used to be in charge of weblogs incorporated which is a division of AOL which is which Engadget's a division of that and He's now doing something else, but on Twitter He talked about how the way Engadget is so awesome.
Speaker 0: Is that all these people who work at these big tech companies are like friends with the Engadget guys?
Speaker 0: And they'll use Engadget as a bludgeon against their own companies like so some guy working at a company Like say Apple right if Apple does something They don't like they'll leak it to Engadget and Engadget will say it and then force Apple You know to change its ways or whatever.
Speaker 1: granted if I were Apple what I would do is internal to the company.
Speaker 0: I'd Periodically I'll just block Engadget.com.
Speaker 1: I'd make it appear that things were gonna happen to select groups of employees that weren't gonna happen But that were bad and see what got leaked and then and then of course I can look good by being no That's totally untrue and made up and discredit all these people.
Speaker 1: But then I could slowly figure out who's leaking and either get rid of them or get rid of them.
Speaker 0: the side effect of that Though is that all these really bad stories about your company will get out.
Speaker 1: See, but then all those really bad stories immediately get refuted and never come to pass.
Speaker 0: It doesn't help it doesn't you know that?
Speaker 0: might you know, that's true But the mind share is still.
Speaker 1: you're putting negative mind share even when if the reputation Short term if you do it once yes view it twice.
Speaker 1: Yes, if you do it 40 times Then suddenly no one trusts any bad news about your company.
Speaker 1: and then when it finds out that you're actually dumping radioactive waste inside of baby seals for fun No one cares cuz that's just fake like all those other fake stories.
Speaker 0: anyway The point is is a really fascinating news story and it's it's kind of sad cuz like wow Motorola was you know They made good phones.
Speaker 0: and now What's going on?
Speaker 0: The company is splitting in half one half of the cut the phone part of the company is going one way and all the other Stuff that's actually profitable and still, you know business as usual chips and stuff is going to the other part of the company.
Speaker 1: now I'm not allowed to really talk about my opinions on the future of Motorola But I think I can say it pretty obliquely by saying that I will probably never see in my hands a new Motorola cell phone.
Speaker 0: No, it's pretty.
Speaker 0: it's really fascinating reading all this stuff.
Speaker 0: This guy says because he talks about how like why does Motorola Have like this fleet of private jets where other companies the same size maybe have one or two, you know?
Speaker 0: And it's like why you know are the executives like don't even know how to use a computer?
Speaker 0: he has you know emails printed out and put on his desk and He basically just bashes all the CEOs and boards and all the high-up executives in the company for being completely incompetent and not knowing anything.
Speaker 0: and He talks about how there's the one the guy who died is pretty much the only reason that their phones ever successful.
Speaker 0: and wow, it's a pretty sad story that it is general and It's really worth reading if you care about the insides of tech companies and how the tech industry works and whatnot.
Speaker 1: So speaking of one person who's awesome I want to talk about this a little bit because it the story itself is not super important.
Speaker 1: This is like news from nowhere that no one will really care about.
Speaker 1: but the lessons learned from this are pretty Impressive and important to damage irreversible.
Speaker 1: Man, that comic hasn't updated in like ever.
Speaker 0: but those guys you still do stuff.
Speaker 0: They did something for penny arcade recently, but they don't do anything for me now that out.
Speaker 0: In fact, I imagine if you paid them they do something.
Speaker 1: No, they didn't remember.
Speaker 1: I ordered from them A big poster and for like five months it never came.
Speaker 1: So finally I went to mocha and they were there and I was like I ordered a poster.
Speaker 1: Where is it?
Speaker 1: And they were like, ah, would you like one now?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was like, yes.
Speaker 1: Yes I do.
Speaker 0: if they're at mocha again, you can get on their case.
Speaker 1: Ah Oh, well anyway, so, uh, basically the story here is that some school that had a computer network Was so Incompetently managed like pretty much every school I've ever seen is in terms of pretty
Speaker 0: much every public school in the u.s And most of the private schools and pretty much most schools.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but well, there's a town somewhere where the town has I like a team of like three IT guys who were super Linux.
Speaker 0: Ease of the whole town is perfect.
Speaker 0: But anyway anywhere else is probably terrible anyway.
Speaker 1: So basically what happened is this 11 year old kid who knew a little bit more about computers than everyone else at this school Including the teachers.
Speaker 1: everyone Basically said I'll fix it and now he's the network admin.
Speaker 0: Well days after the IT guy just left, you know, basically was just like screw this school and he was a terrible IT guy.
Speaker 0: Apparently, you know the the librarian who sort of you know, because the librarian has to deal with you know Like library computers and whatnots they.
Speaker 0: I remember in elementary school our librarian was sort of more You know the computers than anyone else because he sort of forced to learn that sort of thing a little bit.
Speaker 0: So his mom was librarian which is why you know, he sort of got into that You know gig there
Speaker 1: now the kid didn't get
Speaker 0: an inside the kid
Speaker 1: didn't do a perfect job but he proved something very important because Basically, all he did was the smart thing that anyone with even basic like technological computer literacy not straight-up computer literacy But like kind of power user computer literacy would do.
Speaker 1: he support scan the network.
Speaker 1: You know ping scan figured out what all the devices were Got rid of all the spyware and malware Put some antivirus and some you know gateways and things and basically just cleaned everything up and upgraded everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it just you know went around doing Windows Update and all that He didn't.
Speaker 0: actually he's not actually doing the good amazing job that someone like us would do But he's still what he's doing with basic knowledge of things that he's basically doing to every computer in the school What you should do to your computer in your house and it's making the school a thousand times better than every other school Even though it's still not good on the absolute Scott scale.
Speaker 1: now this Speaks both of hope and of fear.
Speaker 1: it speaks of hope because it is proving to me that yes the generations that are coming up Despite the fact that things are a lot easier for them than they were for us And then things are a lot easier for us than they were for the people before us There are still punk kids out there who know what they're doing.
Speaker 0: Yep They're still learning the technology because I mean we you know, there are some people who have said that hey You know we because you weren't forced to use computers when computers were hard to use.
Speaker 0: You don't actually learn anything.
Speaker 0: and it sort of seemed that way.
Speaker 0: it seemed like, you know people who were younger than us.
Speaker 0: They knew how to use a computer for Facebook or whatever But they didn't really know because they didn't have to deal with installing PC games and DOS.
Speaker 0: But then at the same time, you know writing in basic on it.
Speaker 1: Yes a lot of people from that generation They only know how to use Facebook, but the similar percentage of people from the previous generation Couldn't have used a computer at all Even if they were like.
Speaker 1: and this I think the same percentage of kids are awesome and techie regardless of how easy it is.
Speaker 0: It's beginning to seem that way.
Speaker 1: They have the benefit that they can stand on the shoulders of giants and skip all the.
Speaker 1: they don't have to learn about IRQs.
Speaker 1: They can jump straight into writing a Python program.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But it also speaks of fear because the fact that this school did not have any competent technological person at all Not a single person knew enough about computers to let to be able to do a better job than an 11 year old.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I would do it hire me, but they cry can't afford me.
Speaker 0: So it's not gonna.
Speaker 1: they're not gonna pay me six figures?
Speaker 0: No, they're not which which is what it would take for me to be.
Speaker 0: I would be the IT guy and the computer teacher at the high school for an entire school district.
Speaker 0: You'd have to pay me $100,000 a year because I would be like, you know I'd probably be willing to do it for a lot less.
Speaker 0: That'd be a great job But even then it would still be like 80,000 like they wouldn't pay me that I'd be getting more than any teacher.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's really the sad thing is really I'd be doing two jobs teacher job and IT guy job.
Speaker 0: That's gonna take a lot of monies.
Speaker 1: I think the real problem is just that there's.
Speaker 1: there's no the way IT and CS and computer things work.
Speaker 1: If you're competent at all You can always make a ton of money out in the real world and not working for schools.
Speaker 1: Not just schools, but other things do I mean?
Speaker 1: most hospitals have awful IT.
Speaker 1: Part of the reason why I live a part of the reason why I left my previous company.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, IT is so bad that 11 year old kids can do a better job.
Speaker 0: Even when the job they do is terrible It's still a better job than real people thing is those J.
Speaker 1: He didn't do a terrible job.
Speaker 1: He did probably the same job.
Speaker 1: I would have done when I was 11.
Speaker 0: I mean God when I was 11.
Speaker 1: Well, you were 11 Scott when I was 11 They didn't have any windows.
Speaker 1: but but even if they did when you think about what think about in middle school What you knew about computers you would you could do a middle school job, probably.
Speaker 0: Yeah Realistically my school didn't really do such a bad job there They're only there.
Speaker 0: the bad job they did was and you know There were a few sick obvious security problems, which I could have patched up that they didn't.
Speaker 0: but other than that The main problem was their bad policy rather than their bad systems.
Speaker 1: I remember when they caught me in hacking the computer.
Speaker 0: hacking the computer was installing shockwave flash.
Speaker 1: Not even that hacking the computer was.
Speaker 1: I rebooted and then I held f5 So I was in DOS and then I was writing a program in cube basic to make sounds Bored and they accused me of hacking and I was like, can you even explain what I'm doing?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and they really couldn't.
Speaker 1: and they were like if you weren't an honor student you would have been suspended.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 1: yeah, okay But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: I'll warn you.
Speaker 1: I think this thing of the day is awesome.
Speaker 1: However, some of you might think that is boring.
Speaker 1: what I have to say to you who think it is boring That is that I don't know I could make fun of you.
Speaker 1: I don't know what I would say.
Speaker 1: I'll just warn you that you might not find this terribly interesting But at the same time you might find this fascinating.
Speaker 1: This is a 20-minute explanation of how to manipulate three-dimensional and two-dimensional shapes in terms of inversion and That might sound weird but trust me if nothing else watch the first five minutes because they'll explain what they're talking about and Then they'll ask a question.
Speaker 1: You'll get a couple of.
Speaker 1: you'll think oh, I'll just do it this way and they'll say oh well Here's why that doesn't work.
Speaker 1: and they show you with this little diagram and then they'll show you the answer and the answer is crazy.
Speaker 1: Now if after seeing the answer
Speaker 0: and someone's like Nobel Prize or not Nobel Prize level But that's like masters doctor thesis math answer there in terms
Speaker 1: of
Speaker 0: some guy figure
Speaker 1: that out and describing kind of like Three-dimensional geometry and and math like just I'm trying to use words that will make this make sense.
Speaker 0: It's the kind of stuff, but we don't even really understand.
Speaker 0: so it's not easy to talk about it.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean it.
Speaker 0: I remember doing a lot of stuff with three-dimensional service and calculate I mean, I sort of I understand it on a surface level I could not reproduce.
Speaker 1: was that it was that a joke or did?
Speaker 1: was that just a mistake?
Speaker 0: It was sort of a joke.
Speaker 0: I could not.
Speaker 0: I could not reproduce it nor could I explain it very well.
Speaker 1: I mean the furthest I got was like alright calculate the The charge distribution on a three-dimensional surface.
Speaker 1: and if that sounds scary It's even scarier when you find out that the answer is double integrals.
Speaker 1: Yep, double integrals suck my balls.
Speaker 0: Single integral sometimes like my balls.
Speaker 0: So - she has more ball sucking.
Speaker 1: The thing is a double integral sucks the whole set isn't even so simple as two integrals.
Speaker 1: It's something far worse.
Speaker 1: I know I know but anyway, this video is Amazing because this is this is the way to teach things like this because it's kind of a question and answer.
Speaker 1: You've got the instructor who knows the answer asking the leading questions and the person who doesn't know the answer asking Questions and they're kind of being guided toward discovering the answer on their own without being given the.
Speaker 0: yeah it's sort of like the very beginning of the video, which is all I've seen is Basically, anyone can understand what's going on.
Speaker 0: It's very visual It's very obvious and it really if you're the kind of person who is a problem-solving thinking person You're gonna look at this.
Speaker 0: you give like, huh?
Speaker 0: Huh, and the guy is thinking the same thing.
Speaker 0: You're thinking so, huh?
Speaker 1: I showed Scott a little bit and he's like duh, I do this and then the video is like duh, I'll do this.
Speaker 1: Oh, it didn't work shit.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, no, it's bullshit.
Speaker 0: It would have worked.
Speaker 0: But I was wrong.
Speaker 1: They're like, no, here's why I wouldn't work.
Speaker 0: And then eventually like here's the right answer and the right answer is so crazy that you want to watch the rest Which is probably would have been boring on its own except it's explaining the thing.
Speaker 0: That was so crazy that blew you away.
Speaker 1: Yes, and seriously, it's worth watching just to see the crazy thing.
Speaker 1: You'll know it when you see it.
Speaker 1: It's crazy the answer It's like the answer is probably gonna imagine if there's like a simple math problem, right?
Speaker 0: But you couldn't really figure out the answer, but it didn't seem too complicated.
Speaker 1: It's like adding like they ask you questions like add a bunch of single-digit numbers together Like and you're like, huh?
Speaker 0: And it's a little tricky maybe but you're sort of getting at it.
Speaker 1: And then you're like what.
Speaker 0: you have the ability to think about the problem But you can't arrive at the answer because every answer you come with is wrong.
Speaker 0: and then you're just like, oh, yeah The answer is absolutely insane.
Speaker 1: It's like add a bunch of single-digit numbers and then multiply it by like 1.1 and blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: You're like, alright Alright, what's?
Speaker 1: the answer is like 10 billion?
Speaker 1: Like what 10 million?
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway This is super cool.
Speaker 0: All right, so check out.
Speaker 0: This is way cool, dude.
Speaker 0: And he's doing some raps now usually raps about things that are you know, it's so often corny.
Speaker 0: This one is a little bit corny, but this is terribly corny.
Speaker 0: It's not terribly good.
Speaker 1: It is terribly corny.
Speaker 0: It's kind of corny, but it's terribly corny.
Speaker 0: It's kind of corny.
Speaker 0: This dude does a rap.
Speaker 0: He's pretty good at the rapping I would say slightly above-average rapping skills but his rap is about web design and This guy really knows about web design.
Speaker 0: and if you know about web design This rap will entertain you greatly because it's pretty much just inside Basically.
Speaker 1: guide to web design don't get turned off by the very beginning.
Speaker 1: It might be like, oh, this is gonna be lame.
Speaker 1: He goes into some depth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like we're talking minutia.
Speaker 0: We're you know, usually you hear one of these raps and it's like they sort of talk about something.
Speaker 0: They'll discuss a topic, but obviously they only have some sort of surface layman's knowledge of the topic.
Speaker 1: You know a lot of those like people who are.
Speaker 1: they say they're nerdcore and they try to make some nerdcore But all they really do is say Dungeons & Dragons twice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: This guy really knows his shit.
Speaker 0: I imagine he's a web designer and a rapper and If you are a web designer, you will find this very amusing.
Speaker 1: and if you are a rapper I hope you find this amusing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you're a rapper, you could probably find a better rap, but this rap is not bad You know, it's much better rap than expected.
Speaker 0: You expect like a really bad rap for this kind of thing.
Speaker 0: But no, it's an okay rap.
Speaker 0: This guy gets mad points.
Speaker 1: So moving right along, you know, we've been doing this Alternating ITCS thing for a while.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do one more set of them and then we're gonna go back to kind of our normal Monday shows for a while.
Speaker 0: Oh, wait, it's yesterday.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh wait, I guess I could talk about it.
Speaker 1: Just kidding cuz I just dropped 50 grand on a stupid ticketing system and I got a flyaway for like a week to learn How to use it.
Speaker 0: No, I'm just kidding.
Speaker 0: I'm messing with you.
Speaker 0: I was trying to be all like oh shit wait to make people, you know, I'd ruined it anyway Talk about some CSS today, I guess right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No last week.
Speaker 1: I think you talked about pro.
Speaker 0: last week I did a terrible job.
Speaker 1: Well last time not last week.
Speaker 1: last time We realized that Scott and I are alternating.
Speaker 1: the Mac is.
Speaker 1: Scott did an awesome intro to IT And I was like CS CS.
Speaker 1: Yes, and then it was like my turn to intro IT But I was hungry and we had bra.
Speaker 1: so I was kind of like yeah It is everything and I was the end and then I did a really good one is in we're alternating here.
Speaker 1: So it's Scott's turn to do an awesome one.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right, so I'm gonna try to do an awesome one.
Speaker 0: I realized that it's sort of like trying to do these episodes.
Speaker 0: I have to find a balance because on the one hand it's like I want to give all the information Like.
Speaker 0: I want to give the whole thing from beginning to end not jumping over any steps.
Speaker 0: So in the beginning there were only zeros.
Speaker 0: I want to step on every single stone to get across the river But I realized some of those stones like the stone I did last time not so interesting and not so useful to the people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean think about it most of you even though it is an important thing to learn most of you out there.
Speaker 1: a lot of the questions we're getting people are Like so what programming language does what?
Speaker 1: which programming language that I weren't is Python?
Speaker 1: cool.
Speaker 1: What about Ruby?
Speaker 1: and To answer that question Scott really had to talk about what is programming?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but all those people were going.
Speaker 1: Okay, but what about Ruby?
Speaker 0: Yeah so I'm gonna have to find a way to strike a balance between the things you need to know and Also the things you want to know and being entertaining and I think I can do this, right?
Speaker 0: So last time I talked about you know, what a language is.
Speaker 0: now it's a set of rules for arranging an alphabet, you know in a way and You Know.
Speaker 0: the thing is is you can make up any language you want, right?
Speaker 0: so why do we have a whole bunch of different programming languages?
Speaker 0: because Each language the set of rules you come up with is made in such a way So that you can match.
Speaker 0: the goal is to match human thinking with the assembly language in the computer.
Speaker 1: So the glad you didn't say computer thinking computer thinking.
Speaker 0: you want to find a language because a programming language can't be a human Language because a digital non fuzzy logic computer cannot understand it.
Speaker 0: Right if it could be a human language.
Speaker 1: when we develop some amazing fuzzy when AI computer There will be a pearl compiler and then write me a pearl program and compile it in its exactly We won't need programmers anymore.
Speaker 0: All you'll do is you'll tell your computer what you want to do and it since your computer is an AI that just happens To also be connected to some you know, really powerful processing
Speaker 1: The same time connected to some sort of schoolgirl prosthetic, all right, you know what's gonna happen in the future.
Speaker 0: Yep Then you won't need a programming language anymore.
Speaker 0: But because we still need a programming language what we do is we come up with rules for arranging alphabets some grammars to design languages in such a way that a human can think in those languages and work with them the same way.
Speaker 0: you think in English you can think in C or think in pearl or think in Python.
Speaker 0: But also the computer can read those languages and actually do something based on those languages can divert them into computer instructions.
Speaker 0: so the reason we have different languages and not just one language that's perfect is because What you're doing with a language is you're trying to solve a problem.
Speaker 0: All right You might be trying to solve the problem of when people visit my website send them a page.
Speaker 0: You might be trying to solve the problem of do complex math on a supercomputer.
Speaker 0: You might be trying to solve the problem of make my calculator do normal math, you know, there's all these different problems.
Speaker 0: And when there's different problems, it's easier to think about certain problems in certain ways.
Speaker 0: And since you can't sort of write one language to rule them all Which I guess would be sort of crazy, right?
Speaker 0: We create languages that are structured in different ways so that they are suited to solving certain kinds of problems.
Speaker 0: For example list lisp as in.
Speaker 0: I got lisp now not.
Speaker 1: I would like to preface what Scott's about to say by saying that I Discovered that lisp is used a lot in terms of writing audio processing things.
Speaker 1: Yes, so I started looking into lisp because it that I don't program much if ever.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Good God Right, but lisp the word lisp the reason it's called lisp is because the list processing language you see and Basically I call them the parentheses languages because it's all parentheses all over the place Like you do a parentheses something comma something comma something.
Speaker 0: you got a list, you know.
Speaker 0: Then you'll put like some name of a function, you know Like pop push I forget what the words are because I haven't used.
Speaker 0: I use lisp once a long time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: I know about it on paper But I don't really know it because I don't use it.
Speaker 0: for like.
Speaker 1: audio is an example.
Speaker 1: you because I was you know looking into This you want to say you want to process some audio?
Speaker 1: So it's like.
Speaker 1: you've got a list of different kind like different transformations.
Speaker 0: It's like the sugar and the cutter.
Speaker 0: there's something like that.
Speaker 1: Well, you've got like a list of different attributes of audio and then you've got a list of different functions You want to apply based on different parameters?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway, the point is that lisp is a Language that is built around lists, right?
Speaker 0: So if you're thinking of solving a problem that involves lots of lists of things, right?
Speaker 0: Lisp if you think about that problem in the lisp language or try to you know Solve that problem with the list programming language it that was sort of a ATM machine right there lisp programming language It'll probably be really easy and it probably won't take as many lines of code to do that to solve that problem.
Speaker 0: You know, for example, well at least when I used AutoCAD way back in the day and like high school, right?
Speaker 0: Like it must have been AutoCAD 2000 or I would think it was AutoCAD release 14 The.
Speaker 0: you know AutoCAD.
Speaker 0: you control it with the GUI clicking on buttons and then clicking on the screen to give the print.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: But you can also do all of AutoCAD from this little command line and all the commands were very lisp-like.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it might have been lisp powering the AutoCAD in those days.
Speaker 0: because think about what is AutoCAD when it's.
Speaker 0: it's your you're creating.
Speaker 0: You know architectural diagrams mechanical diagrams, you know blueprints that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: It's lists of points lists of coordinates lists of vectors and that's all it is.
Speaker 0: So lisp is the perfect language to do that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: So people often ask you like, oh, what's what's the best language?
Speaker 0: You know for learning?
Speaker 0: or what's the best language for this?
Speaker 0: and what's the you know?
Speaker 0: Is this language better than that language?
Speaker 1: And the answer is I want to use an analogy real quick Is a hammer better than a screwdriver?
Speaker 1: Yeah, see each language, you know answers, of course.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Well, actually There are some program, you know lisp is not the only Language of its kind.
Speaker 0: there are other languages that are similar to lisp.
Speaker 0: For example scheme is very similar to lisp right and so many people will argue that you know Scheme is better for learning than lisp.
Speaker 0: and you know, there's different variations on the same theme.
Speaker 0: and you know many times It won't matter which one you choose.
Speaker 0: or maybe one has a few Disadvantages and one has other advantages sort of like you go to the Home Depot, right?
Speaker 0: It's a whole bunch of hammers, but this one's a ball peen hammer.
Speaker 1: and this you just wanted to say ball peen.
Speaker 1: You've been wanting to say it since I said the word hammer.
Speaker 1: You've been obsessed with that word.
Speaker 0: for the last or like you'll go and there'll be a Phillips screwdriver and a flathead screw.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 0: They're both screwdrivers, but they're a little bit different.
Speaker 1: What about tech hammers.
Speaker 0: tech hammers are the best anyway.
Speaker 0: So a programming language is much like that, but sometimes there is one that is just better than the other for example.
Speaker 1: Actually, I can't think of a terrible language right now In terms of like doing something useful Q basic not so useful.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know that there are languages that are.
Speaker 0: sometimes they're the same kind of language.
Speaker 0: They're suited to solving the same kind of problem But one is just better than the other.
Speaker 0: for example a plastic toy hammer a big metal hammer.
Speaker 0: You know one is just better than the other.
Speaker 0: boner.
Speaker 0: yeah You can suck that.
Speaker 0: he both solved the same kind of problem.
Speaker 0: You know that one doesn't really do anything.
Speaker 0: the other one doesn't do but one is just better at that.
Speaker 0: So one of them is kind of useless, but you know when it comes to comparing something like C and something like Java They're not really Comparable.
Speaker 0: I mean if you have a problem in mind like this is my problem Which language is best for solving this problem?
Speaker 0: then then I can give you an answer because I can say well The this language the advantages of this language will mean you can solve that problem much easier or get these Advantages and such and such I can.
Speaker 1: I can give one opinion though I think and for people who don't know more about this topic or kind of are listening to Scott to learn about CS But don't really code or just like you're new to all this I think I would in the end recommend Python.
Speaker 0: well that see here's the thing right here.
Speaker 0: I'll start talking about what certain languages are good for right.
Speaker 0: We'll start with Python because it's a very popular recent choice, right?
Speaker 0: Python is a language that is really.
Speaker 0: it's an object-oriented language.
Speaker 0: I don't know I'm not going to talk about.
Speaker 0: maybe I'll talk about what that means.
Speaker 0: It's an object-oriented language and pretty much for most modern programming for the web and for desktop applications Object-oriented, you know.
Speaker 0: when it first came out, they thought it was a fad but no it's the real deal.
Speaker 0: Object-oriented is pretty much is is the way a lot of programming is done these days.
Speaker 0: Because thinking in an object-oriented manner seems to be very good for solving a great many common computer problems And even if it's not the optimal way of solving your particular, you know problem.
Speaker 0: It's usually a very good way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the example I was given by a professor early on at RIT was he showed quake and He talked a little bit about programming languages while quake just played in the background.
Speaker 0: I think I was there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you might have been.
Speaker 1: and then he basically said all right now because you know We were all techie people a little bit like we were punk kids and most of us knew some procedural programming like basic or something.
Speaker 1: and it was like how would you make quake in a procedural language?
Speaker 1: and We were like, ah and he's like it's not impossible, but it's effectively impossible.
Speaker 0: Yep, because a procedure.
Speaker 0: I'll start talking about this then write a procedural language, right and in many ways all languages are sort of procedural or a procedural aspects of the better.
Speaker 0: procedural language is Pretty much sort of just easier assembly, you know assembly Says do this then do this then do this then go over here and do something different Then go back over here and do what you were doing again.
Speaker 0: You know, it's here the order to do things and sometimes it can repeat things It does which it will often do if I go and do something else that it can go and do a bunch of times.
Speaker 1: Go sub.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It'll do also it.
Speaker 0: basically it's programming by procedure.
Speaker 0: It's like here are the things to do in order, you know.
Speaker 0: If you want to build a house first pour the foundation then set up the frame then, you know put on the roof.
Speaker 0: I don't know how to build a house obviously But then I mean there's some problems there.
Speaker 1: and what if you want to build ten houses?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, it's not just do you want to build ten houses because building ten houses easy It's follow the instructions of building a house ten times.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but what if you want to you know to have you know, red houses blue houses and green houses?
Speaker 0: Well, we can still do that with the procedural language.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it gets more and more complicated on townhouses.
Speaker 0: And then you want to build houses on different streets and you want to people in the houses furniture in the houses.
Speaker 0: You're gonna build a lot of different a lot of people walking around the houses and you also want to program the construction workers.
Speaker 1: different houses have Different attributes.
Speaker 1: or you want the prices of the houses and like all the houses are different But they're all based on like a same basic house.
Speaker 1: Just everyone wants some custom stuff.
Speaker 0: This is where you get object oriented programming in which the the thinking behind object oriented programming is you define a bunch of classes Right in a class, you know an instance of a class is an object.
Speaker 0: So I'll have the class house and one instance of the class house is an actual house and I can write the class House to sort of describe it sort of writing the class house is sort of like saying houses are like this
Speaker 1: I have to interrupt you by people who live in class houses shouldn't throw it.
Speaker 0: That's bad.
Speaker 0: That's bad I'm sorry, so I write.
Speaker 0: I could also write a class car, you know.
Speaker 0: And I basically when I write the class car in code I'm saying cars are like this.
Speaker 0: They have these properties and cars can do these things.
Speaker 0: a car has a color.
Speaker 0: It has a horsepower It has a size and has a weight.
Speaker 0: it can drive it can stop it can honk its horn, you know, I Define sort of what a car is like.
Speaker 0: then I define specific cars.
Speaker 0: I say new car Ferrari.
Speaker 0: it's red it can as 400 horsepower.
Speaker 0: It goes really fast It's horn sounds like this.
Speaker 0: and then I say Ferrari go drive and then the Ferrari will drive and then I can be like new car new car new car drive drive drive stop You know and I can make all these cars start doing all these things.
Speaker 0: They're just defining what a car is like then making cars and then make it, you know looking changing the properties of the cars and Invoking the things that the cars can do.
Speaker 0: and it's a much, you know thinking about solving problems in that way.
Speaker 0: You can solve a lot of problems that way.
Speaker 0: I mean, let's try to think of a Real problem you would solve that way like a video game, right?
Speaker 0: Enemy, I make the enemy class.
Speaker 0: The enemy has these many hit points and he can.
Speaker 0: these are his attacks, right?
Speaker 0: The good guy he has these many hit points.
Speaker 0: He does these many attacks.
Speaker 0: the map The map is this long it has this many things in it.
Speaker 0: Then I after I make all these classes I describe what enemies and good guys and maps are like.
Speaker 0: I then just say new map put in the map ten enemies put in the map one instance of the good guy and Map go and then you have a game and like you just loop through and have them all like.
Speaker 1: things will call thing.
Speaker 0: You don't even need to loop through you just you know, say everything start and then the things will go.
Speaker 0: Ah, yeah, but if you program properly with threads and in such odd I I'm not likely never be at the point.
Speaker 1: Well, I will program with three.
Speaker 0: It's not that hard.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I make a bunch of objects and then I loop through them calling some sort of timing thing that tells them all to do Their shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see you take See, that's that's.
Speaker 0: that's a very common way to program things is to use an object-oriented data model But to use an actual, you know procedure wrapped around that as opposed to just using you know, some sort of functional Non-object-oriented, you know data structures just like some list linked linked lists and some arrays
Speaker 1: That the main reason like I do things like that and a lot of people do is because the object orientedness of setting it Up makes it very easy to put everything together and then coding the other part is very easy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so between the two it takes a lot less good programming practices.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So a programming language.
Speaker 0: the reason we have so many of them is because each of them allows you to think in a different way to help you solve different kinds of problems and you really want to pick the language and Lets you think in a way that is conducive to solving the problem at hand.
Speaker 0: Should I keep talking?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I keep talking some.
Speaker 0: so let's just go over.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be real brief and talk about like the most popular languages.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's a good thing.
Speaker 1: Not talking about some specific languages would be pretty sad and people would not be happy.
Speaker 1: I think so.
Speaker 0: see see is a pretty popular language.
Speaker 0: It's not object oriented.
Speaker 0: It's it's a functional procedural language And it's mostly good for doing things like device drivers and You know programs that might have to like run on your microwave or stuff like that cuz.
Speaker 0: but C is really good at is.
Speaker 0: It's very close to assembly, you know, it does a compiler for C for pretty much any piece of hardware out there.
Speaker 0: So you can do really low-level stuff, but you don't have to write assembly.
Speaker 0: You can write C which is a little bit easier a lot easier, you know You can mix C and assembly together a lot, too.
Speaker 0: So it really it makes writing that sort of close to the hardware program a lot easier now.
Speaker 0: before a long time ago C used to be it and for a lot of things C is still it because You know, even though it might be harder to write something big You know like a game like a big 3d game.
Speaker 0: and see if you do write it and see because you're so close to the hardware You can do lots of optimizations and get a really high performance.
Speaker 0: So if you need high performance C is also a good way to go.
Speaker 0: But there's also C plus plus.
Speaker 0: C plus plus is pretty much a lot like C But it's got object-oriented action going on.
Speaker 0: objective C is also similar to that.
Speaker 0: The thing about C plus plus is that I really don't like the syntax.
Speaker 0: It's pretty painful.
Speaker 0: It's it's.
Speaker 0: you know writing in C plus plus is not a joy But it has advantages in that like C you can compile it for anything.
Speaker 0: You can actually still get really close to the hardware like in C, but it's object-oriented.
Speaker 0: So you can actually think about a lot of problems in a more modern way, but also get high performance.
Speaker 0: And that's why a lot of games are written in C plus plus because they get the high performance But they can still think about the game in an object-oriented way And it won't be so hard to make a game as it would be to make the game in straight C Like they did in the olden days.
Speaker 0: Let's see what else we got here here.
Speaker 0: Visual basic right.
Speaker 0: visual basic is a programming language But it comes with sort of like this GUI making thing for Microsoft.
Speaker 0: You know the Visual Studio whatnots and pretty much what is good for is if you need a Windows only program Or want to run it in wine or something.
Speaker 0: That's pretty simple, but it's mostly just a GUI.
Speaker 0: You know a Windows GUI with buttons and labels and images and you know nothing nothing fancy.
Speaker 0: You can whip it up in visual basic really quickly.
Speaker 0: It's it's a visual basic.
Speaker 0: You know it's.
Speaker 0: you make a visual thing.
Speaker 0: That's very basic and you can make it mostly by clicking on things without very little code at all.
Speaker 0: That's the visual basic is all about.
Speaker 1: but at the same time don't underestimate it.
Speaker 1: visual basic and the related.
Speaker 1: You know Microsoft II things are very powerful for doing certain things.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean if you want to make like a little GUI that helps people generate like spreadsheets in Excel in a little format Visual basic is where it's at.
Speaker 0: yeah Let's see what else I can think of.
Speaker 0: all right Java right Java is very object oriented like super object oriented.
Speaker 0: Right, but the advantage of Java is that first of all there is Java libraries for pretty much everything in the universe.
Speaker 0: So if you want to you know do like encryption you don't have to write a whole new encryption thing.
Speaker 0: There's a Java encryption thing that you just use.
Speaker 0: it's already there for you.
Speaker 0: You can actually you know you can add some features to it if you need to.
Speaker 0: if you want to do graphics There's already a Java graphics thing.
Speaker 0: you just take it and use it.
Speaker 0: You know they already wrote the classes.
Speaker 0: You just got to use them in your program.
Speaker 0: It's beautiful.
Speaker 0: the thing about Java Is that you're not gonna get the highest performance.
Speaker 0: Java's a lot better with performance than it used to be but it's not the highest Performance.
Speaker 0: the advantage of Java is that Java runs in a virtual machine sort of like VMware, but not quite.
Speaker 0: So you write a program in Java.
Speaker 0: now that program runs on any machine that can run a Java virtual machine.
Speaker 0: You write the program once.
Speaker 0: you can put it on any machine that has Java from a cell phone to a supercomputer.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: see you have to sort of rewrite your program for every different chip because you're writing so close to the hardware.
Speaker 0: You know that you've got to recompile the program for different machines and sometimes you might have to change the code in addition to recompiling.
Speaker 0: So that's the advantage of Java.
Speaker 0: Java is actually you know a lot of you put down Java applets You know and they should put down Java applets because that's really where flash is the winner.
Speaker 0: But Java really is the way they go.
Speaker 0: look at puzzle pirates.
Speaker 0: puzzle pirates is written in Java.
Speaker 0: a lot of cell phone games are Written in Java yahoo games a lot of those are written in Java, and that's you know.
Speaker 0: Java's really good at that.
Speaker 0: It's also really good a lot of other things that you may not realize.
Speaker 0: Java is being used Because a lot of people just sort of associated Java with Java applet, but you know a lot of web servers run Java.
Speaker 0: You don't even realize.
Speaker 0: it's also good for like enterprise database stuff because it's so you know robust You can just also, but just bump up new virtual machines all over the place You know you get the advantages of like a VMware without actually having to do a VMware.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean a lot of like big e-commerce website thing.
Speaker 1: solutions are using Java stuff integrated with some sort of crazy web sphere.
Speaker 0: Yep, yeah, let's see what are the major languages all right?
Speaker 0: I'll talk about PHP PHP.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I try to think of something to call it like piece of shit something but PHP started out way back in the day when people had like Geo cities right and they could only make HTML And that was it static HTML, but they wanted to put stuff on their websites like little counters and other dynamic things.
Speaker 0: you know things on a web page that weren't static and Basically PHP started out is like hey put this little bit of code on your website And I'll put a counter there or but it's a little bit of code on your website and an animated thing will appear.
Speaker 0: and People did that and it was like all men's and then PHP somehow expanded into being a full-on.
Speaker 0: programming like PHP is kind of useful and that you can use it as like.
Speaker 0: you know a Scripting language you know just like for doing normal like operating system stuff.
Speaker 0: You can use it to sort of make really easy.
Speaker 0: You know websites that are dynamic because you can mix it in with the HTML.
Speaker 0: you can like write some HTML Then a bit of PHP then a bit HTML then a bit of PHP.
Speaker 0: So you can sort of put dynamic things in the middle of the web page, so if you're good at HTML It's not that hard to do.
Speaker 0: PHP also You know and there's.
Speaker 0: it's a. it's really.
Speaker 0: you don't have to really program it even though if you want to You can take PHP and go full-on object oriented awesomeness all the way.
Speaker 0: It's it's it's totally crazy like that But it's not so Advanced and it actually leaves you with a lot of trouble where if you actually try to make something big and crazy You'll often fall short with PHP You know run into a lot of problems and such and it's actually pretty tied to like the web server in many ways and it Can cause a lot of trouble there.
Speaker 1: right talk a little bit about pearl.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you a pearl pearl the philosophy.
Speaker 0: The other thing is that a lot of languages will be similar to each other But the philosophies will be different and pearl is the great example of you know a language where what it does is just fine But the philosophy is one that is basically the opposite of the Python philosophy, right?
Speaker 0: Pearl and Python in terms of what you can do with them are pretty similar.
Speaker 0: I mean you know you can both.
Speaker 0: you know they they're both for web pages.
Speaker 0: They can both You know make actual applications in them.
Speaker 0: They're both sort of higher level Languages.
Speaker 0: there's quite a bit of similarity going on.
Speaker 0: My thing is the philosophy of pearl is that there's a million ways to do everything and there's all these sort of syntactical Shortcuts and things.
Speaker 0: so it's like you can write a verbal program, and I could write one.
Speaker 0: They do the same exact thing, but yours looks nothing like mine You know.
Speaker 1: yeah pearl is also the language where a lot of people learn what regular expressions are.
Speaker 0: yep?
Speaker 0: That does it.
Speaker 0: pearl is very good at processing text.
Speaker 0: you have some text and you want to do something with it.
Speaker 0: You know you want to read it or you want to turn it into some other text.
Speaker 0: pearl is awesome at that right because it's Very closely tied with the regular expressions.
Speaker 0: Python is sort of does all the same stuff as pearl except Python.
Speaker 0: Philosophy is.
Speaker 0: there should only be one way to do it.
Speaker 0: You know if I write a Python program to do X and you write a Python program to do X They should look exactly the same.
Speaker 0: there shouldn't be another way to do it.
Speaker 0: You know there's sort of a right answer or the.
Speaker 0: you know a theoretical right answer like This is the way that this program should be written.
Speaker 1: I thought I've just also.
Speaker 1: I found Python to be very intuitive.
Speaker 0: It is a lot of like.
Speaker 0: the thing is you probably haven't used a lot of the other also intuitive.
Speaker 0: No, I haven't, but I've used pearl and Python and I pearl isn't that intuitive But Ruby Ruby is just as intuitive as Python is.
Speaker 1: I never actually tried to use Ruby.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of the things will look very similar to to Python.
Speaker 0: You know just sort of variable equals this you know.
Speaker 0: if this then that sort of you know the typical very easy to understand Sort of stuff.
Speaker 1: yeah There's this brain fuck.
Speaker 0: know about brain fuck.
Speaker 0: Yeah See brain flick is just sort of a joke language.
Speaker 1: It's not really useful for anything except teaching But at the same time you can learn a lot from it because if you are able to write something moderately complex in it You've learned a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's really you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah There's a lot of languages out there that are sort of toy languages like.
Speaker 0: they make them not for the purpose of actually doing Anything really useful for the real world even though you might be able to.
Speaker 0: but sort of you know as Sort of like exercises like you look at the language And you think about it, and then you know your mind sort of expands thinking about that and now you're better at dealing with other Languages and such and brain fuck in white space, and
Speaker 1: I was about to bring up white space.
Speaker 1: They're all good examples of that because I just realized that the Wikipedia page on white space is fantastic.
Speaker 0: Here's the language.
Speaker 0: you probably may not have heard of that.
Speaker 0: I sort of learned once called prologue right in prologue as the name sort of implies is a very logical language.
Speaker 0: you ever do those problems in the in the puzzle books that Are like you know.
Speaker 0: there are five people and five items.
Speaker 0: Joe doesn't have the red item.
Speaker 0: Mary has the blue item.
Speaker 0: You know he has the item that's darker than that one But lighter than the other one.
Speaker 0: You know that sort of thing and you sort of put X's in the boxes to figure out who doesn't match and who doesn't match With what.
Speaker 0: and see you figure out who has what item and who lives in what house and you know which item is in which house.
Speaker 0: and all that business.
Speaker 0: Prologue is a lot like that.
Speaker 0: you sort of say okay There's this thing This thing.
Speaker 0: you sort of set up these these rules like you said at the circumstance like okay this can equal either this this or this.
Speaker 0: this can never be equal to that.
Speaker 0: and This is one of these three and then prologue just sort of sorts it out and arrives at an answer.
Speaker 0: So it's very good at solving logic type problems where you have associations of things and some sort of set of logical rules and you want to see like this sort of the the set of all The possible answers like if you're doing some discrete maths Prologue is the way to go because it'll just be like oh, that's your situation.
Speaker 0: These are all the possible true things that will fit that.
Speaker 0: you know I'm gonna wrap.
Speaker 0: try to wrap it up here.
Speaker 0: We probably should yeah You guys pick a language that haven't talked about this probably pretty big I don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean all I write it is pearl Python and bash.
Speaker 0: I didn't actually talk about Python even though I've mentioned it a hundred times.
Speaker 0: Python is basically the thing about Python.
Speaker 1: talk about Python.
Speaker 0: I sort of talked about it.
Speaker 0: What else you gonna say the thing about Python the answer to know about is that first of all?
Speaker 0: unlike a lot of other languages where indentation, you know Indentation is really sort of a thing to help you read like you can write and see and not indent and it won't care.
Speaker 0: But you know you you're supposed to indent because it makes it easier to read and makes it easy to be able to understand.
Speaker 1: by Indenting we mean like say I have a for loop or a while loop or something.
Speaker 1: I indent everything underneath that in the loop.
Speaker 1: So it kind of stands out as being grouped together under the loop.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're easier to read.
Speaker 0: It makes it easier to read the program and figure out how it works.
Speaker 0: Python Forces you to indent like it actually looks at when the Python interpreter runs and looks at your code.
Speaker 0: It looks at the indentations and it's like hey that indentation doesn't make sense.
Speaker 0: or okay That's indented one down from this.
Speaker 0: Therefore I should do this.
Speaker 0: You know, it's indentation actually matters in Python.
Speaker 0: But Python is a really useful language because on the one hand, right?
Speaker 0: it's it's a very high level object oriented language with a lot of power and a lot of Shortcuts to make you know everyday, you know programs and scripts very easy.
Speaker 0: It has an interpreter so you can just sort of type in Python code and it will happen Immediately to sort of test things out.
Speaker 0: like you if you have a class you wrote you don't actually have to write some You know script to test the class out.
Speaker 0: You just type Python you import the class and then you sort of make objects in the class and you can just sort of you Know you can be like I'll make a car and the car is made immediately and you'd be like, okay Drive car and you can watch the car drive and you can see if things are working and how they work.
Speaker 0: and that's why It's very useful for learning and testing.
Speaker 0: but Python also In is very strange in that you it sort of compiles into C sort of.
Speaker 0: So if you a lot of people nowadays like when they're writing games Like a big game that has to be like, you know, very high performance 3d game need a lot of frame rates, right?
Speaker 0: They'll write it in Python because very easy easy to think about doesn't take very long.
Speaker 0: But then they'll convert the parts that are low performance like oh this part's really slow here The part where renders the the bad guy.
Speaker 0: so they'll convert it to C. They'll rewrite all that code to make it fast.
Speaker 0: But the rest of the code is still Python, but it's all good because just import the C library into the Python It doesn't care.
Speaker 0: There's a little Python wrapper around it or wherever you need to do and You can make really high-performance Applications without having to write everything in C. You can think about things in the Python way and only write that rewrite the slow parts in C. You think hey Python has a whole lot of other advantages besides that like, you know, a lot of frameworks.
Speaker 0: There's modules for pretty much everything you could want, you know, like if you want to you know, do this.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a Python, you know, it's sort of like Java.
Speaker 0: Python also has a module for everything.
Speaker 0: You just have to find that module and import it and read the documentation for how it works.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's it's generally pretty useful for a whole lot of things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll probably talk about more languages again later.
Speaker 0: I gotta I gotta figure out what I'm gonna talk about next.
Speaker 1: well pretty much I mean, I'm gonna do one more and then we're gonna go back for a little while Maybe a week or two a couple of weeks probably to normal Monday night show.
Speaker 0: So I got like a month to figure out what I could talk about in the next one thing.
Speaker 1: I'd like to end on those.
Speaker 1: I think I was poking around the list on Esoteric or so Lang.
Speaker 1: it's a wiki of esoteric programming languages.
Speaker 1: That's the word And I think I discovered my favorite programming language ever.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: What is it rim?
Speaker 1: It is called IRP.
Speaker 1: All right internet relay programming.
Speaker 1: I will leave it to you to read how IRP works.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew.com Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.