Speaker 0: It's Thursday September 25th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm sky and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: Finally we review with spoilers snow crash by Neal Stephenson.
Speaker 1: Oh snaps Let's do this.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I love about living in New York.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's a lot of reasons to like it.
Speaker 0: I mean I went to a place called milk and honey and got a really good bagel this morning.
Speaker 1: But if it was called milk and honey, why did they have bagel?
Speaker 1: shouldn't they have had milk and honey?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: there was neither milk nor honey there what but they had bagels But you couldn't buy milk to wash down your bag.
Speaker 1: No Well, the thing is that or did you get your bagel flavored by honey?
Speaker 0: They're super kosher and there's even a sign like they won't let you bring in any other food in there.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 1: It's one of those you places.
Speaker 0: All right, and it was a really good bagels, but I couldn't get any milk.
Speaker 1: Oh They probably had some meats there.
Speaker 0: Yes, they had locks and locks doesn't count.
Speaker 1: It's fish.
Speaker 0: They also had kosher sushi and they had much other stuff.
Speaker 1: Anyway, fish doesn't count.
Speaker 0: What about mermaid?
Speaker 0: What what about mermaid?
Speaker 1: I Think because mermaid doesn't exist.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter But if mermaid did exist I'm sure you could go to a rabbi and ask him and I'm pretty sure he might tell you that the bottom half is Okay, and the top half is not okay to eat.
Speaker 0: But uh, what I really like is that you know, I lived in Michigan and my commute I guess to high school would be interrupted by occasionally a car accident.
Speaker 0: Maybe a deer Maybe a prayer for pretty much a lot of people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but living here, my commute is being interrupted by the UN General Assembly and motorcades and armed guards and diplomats and bodyguards and Funny people wearing funny outfits from funny countries talking to each other in funny languages.
Speaker 1: I love those.
Speaker 0: those are the best and they always look so happy like every diplomat I've seen For the entire week has looked really really happy.
Speaker 0: and then just I don't know Here's a notice to all you kids out there you ready be a diplomat when you grow up?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's great diplomats unless you get shot.
Speaker 1: diplomat is the best job in the world.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends I mean depends on why you don't want to be the dwell.
Speaker 0: It depends on where you're the dip like I'm saying do you want to be the diplomat to say the internet?
Speaker 1: No, see what you want to do.
Speaker 1: is you want to study a language.
Speaker 1: that is a language not many people study yet.
Speaker 1: You want it to be a language that is spoken in safe places?
Speaker 1: For example learn Romanian and then you can be the diplomat to Romania.
Speaker 0: Oh, that'd be great.
Speaker 1: And it's a pretty sweet job because you can do as you please Travel a lot live in luxury not do much else.
Speaker 0: Well, you know theoretically deal with foreign policy at a very direct and real and meaningful scale, right?
Speaker 1: If anything that happens between the US and Romania, guess what?
Speaker 1: not much You never know never know I mean, but what was the diplomat to Romania's job?
Speaker 1: Hey, can you guys help us out in Iraq?
Speaker 1: But anyway, thanks.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Bye Basically the United Nations General Assembly provided a boon to me a boon a boon.
Speaker 0: You see I'm walking toward this training class.
Speaker 0: I'm in training all week So I'm actually going to the city and walk into this other building up at like 45th Street by Times Square Mm-hmm, and I'm trying to walk back home from work today From the training and there's a big motorcade and it's going up 6th Avenue and I pretty much I can't like easily cross it.
Speaker 0: Like it just there's trouble.
Speaker 0: So I start divert myself a bit, you know anytime there's traffic in the way.
Speaker 0: You just walk in the other direction in parallel and then walk and that's the way New York is.
Speaker 0: so I'm walking down the street that I haven't walked down in a long time and I Found another good burger and it's closer to my work than the other good burger that I eat at all the time.
Speaker 1: Why didn't you you could use Google Maps?
Speaker 0: I never thought to.
Speaker 0: I didn't even know there's more than one good burger.
Speaker 1: You know what.
Speaker 1: there might be non good burger burger place.
Speaker 1: You should go to Google Maps.
Speaker 1: type in burger.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 0: It told me about burger heaven, which is not so great more of a diner Like burger heaven, but they I found a good burger randomly.
Speaker 1: and here's something I don't understand.
Speaker 1: right UN headquarters It's pretty much on the east side of the city on the water.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right near the FDR Drive or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why doesn't those people?
Speaker 1: why do they have motorcades?
Speaker 1: Why don't they boat in?
Speaker 0: Because it's all diplomats who are an Boats.
Speaker 0: no, it's got its attaches and diplomats.
Speaker 0: So what they're doing is they're all staying in those luxury hotels like the Algonquin and the.
Speaker 0: you know All the fancy famous old hotels.
Speaker 0: I personally am a fan of the Mandarin and the mandarins nice place But they're all the circle the Iroquois the Algonquin, you know right next to the New York Yacht Club.
Speaker 1: Yeah that area I know the Mandarin or Oriental hotel in Columbus circles the best hotel in the city as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway, oh That's all I gotta say, okay, so I don't know.
Speaker 1: Pete I don't talk about the specifics of my job too much on the show but You know, our company was somewhat recently acquired by another company, but it wasn't like haha.
Speaker 1: We're buying you.
Speaker 1: It was like, you know, it was an arranged deal.
Speaker 1: My company was owned by four partners.
Speaker 1: I assume they were equal partners.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know business details.
Speaker 1: I just code there and they sold the company to this other company.
Speaker 1: So now they're just managers and now the new company is the bosses, right?
Speaker 1: Okay, big deal didn't really change my job that much except for Something that happened today.
Speaker 1: You see we used to just you know, and he wanted to buy things specifically in tech, right?
Speaker 1: We had a tech budget and we spent the tech budget, right?
Speaker 1: We would buy a server when he wanted.
Speaker 1: you'd buy something else you want, right?
Speaker 1: And we would always get exactly what we asked for one of the new dev server.
Speaker 1: We got this Dell like one you rack mount Dealey with like, you know, two CPUs in there.
Speaker 1: Very nice.
Speaker 1: We picked it out.
Speaker 1: We customized it at dell.com.
Speaker 1: We ordered it.
Speaker 1: get a little company discount.
Speaker 1: all good.
Speaker 1: So now we have a new company that owns us.
Speaker 1: They didn't really give us a tech budget.
Speaker 1: They just said when you want to buy something tell us and we'll get it for you.
Speaker 1: Okay, so my boss, right?
Speaker 1: Go it.
Speaker 1: He went down to you know, the North Carolina where the where the new companies are and Well, there are new owners are anyway.
Speaker 1: And he saw that all the people there all the tech people had tons of monitors.
Speaker 1: one guy had three monitors stacked vertically on Each other.
Speaker 1: other people had like, you know big stretches out right and he's sitting there in his office, right?
Speaker 1: Basically, he's now head of tech in New York.
Speaker 1: He's got a 24 inch Dell ultra sharp.
Speaker 1: Not bad.
Speaker 1: Not bad, right.
Speaker 1: and also In addition to that I have this really I don't like it 22 inch Samsung Which is the same resolution as my 20 inch Dell and I would much rather either have you know B20 injured the same resolution or a 24 inch of the bigger resolution.
Speaker 0: Actually, I would just prefer not a Samsung.
Speaker 0: I don't like their screens.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is Samsung looks like I like their HDTVs a lot But I don't like their monitors.
Speaker 0: the monitors their new monitors.
Speaker 1: Their monitors used to be awesome when I bought those 17 inch Samsung's back in the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah hot but nowadays poop I just.
Speaker 0: basically they're too glossy and like they look they look cheap.
Speaker 0: One of the more noisy really now It's all the ones we have at work like they're glossy and they have this really cheap glossy plastic rim around him, right?
Speaker 1: So my boss has this plan, right?
Speaker 1: I wanted a new monitor because the color on the Samsung's fucked up anyway, and it was actually hindering some web work.
Speaker 1: you know, I was seeing the wrong colors and whatnot and He wanted you know to sort of get you know Felt like he was getting played out because the people in North Carolina had better displays than needed.
Speaker 1: So and for other reasons, you know, he needs the way he works.
Speaker 1: He has windows He just opens his taskbar is basically loaded with way too much shit.
Speaker 1: He just leaves everything open all the time and a million windows.
Speaker 1: So he really needed another monitor anyway for the way he works.
Speaker 1: I don't cuz I have virtual desktops.
Speaker 1: So He ordered two 24 inch Dells, right and then he was gonna give his current 24 inch Dell Which is the previous model to me, right and then everything will be all cool.
Speaker 1: Someone else who didn't care could take my 22 inch Samsung who wasn't a tech person.
Speaker 1: They would be more than happy with it.
Speaker 1: So he orders the 220 inch 22 inch Dells.
Speaker 1: and You know the I the one system in guy in New York sends a letter to North Carolina.
Speaker 1: So they can order it and have it sent here and today to Dell.
Speaker 1: boxes arrived obviously containing 24 inch monitors.
Speaker 1: Right, he opens one up He sets it up You know and he had a problem because they were all.
Speaker 1: he was dumb and he didn't.
Speaker 1: his computer didn't support didn't have two DVI outs and he bought the wrong video card and whatever and I could have done better job with that.
Speaker 1: but you know, I sorted that out, but we noticed that this Dell monitor that showed up didn't have that the memory card slots on the side and Wait a minute, and that sounds like it's not an ultra sharp and the screen.
Speaker 1: you couldn't move it up and down.
Speaker 1: All you could do is tilt it.
Speaker 0: I'm moving my screen up and down to right and it didn't swivel left and right.
Speaker 1: you had to just move it to the left Into the right.
Speaker 0: you didn't get an ultra sharp.
Speaker 1: Well, we go and we're like, wait a minute, right?
Speaker 1: So after a few minutes of confusion and whatever, you know first we're just like, I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe you know That's that's it I don't know.
Speaker 1: after some look I go to the Dell website and I see and I realize aha That is not the ultra sharp.
Speaker 1: That is the non ultra sharp.
Speaker 1: That is what has happened here and he's like Shit, I you know and I look the price of the ultra sharp is like 600 something dollars to the 24 inch.
Speaker 1: But the non ultra sharp is like 300 something and that's the retail price.
Speaker 1: So we paid less than that.
Speaker 1: So we go and we're like did we order the wrong one?
Speaker 1: Let's check and we go and we look at the email that was sent to North Carolina and it says ultra sharp very specifically Which means North Carolina changed the order on us.
Speaker 0: Did that did you?
Speaker 0: did you call him on it?
Speaker 1: Did you say hey, they're calling him on it.
Speaker 1: That's not my job.
Speaker 1: I didn't order the monitors.
Speaker 1: The point is let this be a lesson to everyone out there.
Speaker 1: You might think that selling your company is great because you get a pile of money But don't do it cuz they'll stiff you on the monitors And that's totally not worth it.
Speaker 1: He was really pissed cuz.
Speaker 1: a minute, you know, I think of it.
Speaker 1: you'd be pissed too if you were like You know, you're in charge of this company Basically, then you sell it to someone and then and now they stiff you on the monitor.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is, you know at what my argument if I were North Carolina would be Can you articulate to me why you need the much more expensive ultra sharp?
Speaker 0: For any reason other than personal comfort and enjoyment?
Speaker 0: it would be easier, right if swivel it you can.
Speaker 1: Developers and the other tech people in North Carolina didn't have amazing monitor setups to you know Which we could point at but they had normal monitors down there.
Speaker 1: We could point we couldn't point at them, but now we can.
Speaker 0: but why do you?
Speaker 0: why should you have the same thing?
Speaker 0: There's no business reason if you know.
Speaker 1: if you see how my boss works, you know that he needs that Plus, you know, he refused, you know, we're like that.
Speaker 1: we're tech people.
Speaker 1: We're very particular For the normal people.
Speaker 1: they got no reason for the tech people.
Speaker 0: So anyway, you know, it's Thursday and we'd said a long time ago we'd slowly start changing up the format of Thursday because What I'm gonna talk about might seem like it's the thing today, but I'll get to why.
Speaker 0: it's news now.
Speaker 0: I've talked about this man.
Speaker 0: There's legend.
Speaker 0: I thought you did this thing in there this legend among men Boring news first.
Speaker 0: I've talked about him kind of often on the show a long time ago But I hadn't talked about him in a long time.
Speaker 0: I kind of forgot.
Speaker 0: We forgot it.
Speaker 1: I never forgot the guy.
Speaker 1: I forgot his name.
Speaker 0: I just didn't.
Speaker 0: I stopped thinking about him because he wasn't on FARC all the time anymore.
Speaker 0: And you know, he kind of faded from the limelight, but just recently, you know Scott asked me Hey, what was that guy's name?
Speaker 0: And sure enough acid every once in a while, but he asked recently and then sure enough Henry Earl appeared in the news again.
Speaker 1: now Henry Earl my here one of my heroes not my top hero But he's on the hero list.
Speaker 0: I can say that I know the story of Henry Earl to heart.
Speaker 0: I know this man's ins and outs Familiar with Henry Earl.
Speaker 0: I am in fact because you see I've been really got intimate with Henry Earl for a long time.
Speaker 0: However I'm just going to read to you the Wikipedia about Henry Earl because the whole thing it's not that long But the way it is phrased I find it somewhat hilarious.
Speaker 0: Henry Earl born October 24th, 1949 is a homeless man from Lexington, Kentucky.
Speaker 1: I thought he had a home famous for his extensive police record.
Speaker 0: Nearly all of his arrests have been for public intoxication With a few charges of disorderly conduct third-degree trespassing Second-degree trespassing and at least one count of begging.
Speaker 0: the fire Website showing Earl's arrest record from 1992 to present indicates that he's not been arrested for any theft or violent offenses.
Speaker 0: So he pretty much is only ever arrested for public intoxication.
Speaker 1: You don't have to be afraid of Henry Earl.
Speaker 1: if you meet this guy You should totally hang out with him be like whoo get him drunk And then he'll spend a night in jail.
Speaker 0: and there's in fact a problem in the area where he is Frequent to be frequently attends where college kids will spend their spring break.
Speaker 0: They will actually go to Lexington, Kentucky and find him.
Speaker 0: He's not difficult to find and take him around drinking.
Speaker 0: That is a common spring break trip, in fact, there have been stories on multiple groups of students from multiple schools Simultaneously each trying to bribe him to follow them around instead of the other group with increasing amounts of alcohol Times.
Speaker 0: Henry's rise to fame was in large part because of the Fayette County Jail at a public website Which listed a person's arrest record and mug shots?
Speaker 0: Henry had an extensive record and a wide range of emotions expressed in the mug shots from despondent to happy.
Speaker 0: The page was linked to regularly by internet news blog FARC calm.
Speaker 0: The new website eventually had to be shut down due to the strain that was being placed upon it.
Speaker 0: Henry's made numerous talk show appearances has been featured in national and international media venues.
Speaker 0: Really I want to see that on November 16th 2005 it was reported that a 55 year old black man had died in police custody in Fayette County prompting speculation the Henry Earl had in fact died.
Speaker 0: The man turned out to be Donald Ross another man.
Speaker 0: It was not Henry Earl.
Speaker 0: people, you know, breathe breathe the sigh of relief In 2006.
Speaker 1: sigh of relief because someone died.
Speaker 0: Well, because it wasn't Henry Earl who does.
Speaker 1: I loved Henry Earl Moore?
Speaker 0: Yes, because Donald Ross you see it also been arrested for third-degree assault Has never hurt anyone but himself.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's okay.
Speaker 1: I guess kinda.
Speaker 0: in 2006 Henry Earl sobered up with his number of offenses a number of days spent in jail overwhelmingly lower than previous years.
Speaker 0: Fortunately, he returned to his old ways in 2007.
Speaker 1: No, that's that's simultaneously sad and awesome.
Speaker 0: now the thing is Henry Earl is kind of a folk hero and He got enough folk heroes.
Speaker 0: He exemplifies a A Idiom of life that I agree with in one regard.
Speaker 1: He's a modern Johnny Appleseed.
Speaker 0: If you're gonna do something be the best damn doer of that thing that they can possibly be.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean think about it.
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: if you're like a meth addict, that's pretty sad But if you're an epic mecha meth addict, at least there's in the horribleness of your existence.
Speaker 1: There is some like silver lining on your cloud.
Speaker 0: It could be a cautionary tale.
Speaker 0: It's hard.
Speaker 1: because of being a meth addict that cloud is real dark.
Speaker 1: But if you're being a drunken hobo The cloud is a lot less dark than meth addict.
Speaker 0: basically If you can make the best of a bad situation or in the very least if your life can serve as a warning to others Then you have in some small way mitigated the misery that otherwise was your life.
Speaker 1: And I mean that guy.
Speaker 1: I mean think about all the hobos who just get drunk in a dark alley Wasting their lives away with no recognition, right?
Speaker 1: They're just sad and no one learns from them and they don't learn from anyone and their existences are just terrible.
Speaker 0: Henry Earl is internationally famous and people fly to his hometown to find him and buy him drinks.
Speaker 0: Now the reason Henry Earl comes up is he was in the news recently.
Speaker 0: Basically a bunch of news media had reported that Henry Earl had achieved a milestone in his life.
Speaker 0: He had been arrested for his 1,000th public intoxication incidents.
Speaker 1: That's is that more arrest than anyone ever I Don't know.
Speaker 0: what I do know is that this was patently untrue Because the people reporting were digging up a story and they basically didn't do all their research.
Speaker 0: In fact, Henry Earl had reached that milestone long ago Has been arrested 1,333 times to date.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, he should stop at 1,337.
Speaker 0: I'm going to say this this is another quote from that Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: Let's get arrested four more times and then go sober for real.
Speaker 0: I point out that in Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: This is the first citation.
Speaker 0: in 2008 Earl was arrested for the 1,000th time since 1992. the judge sentenced him to 1,000 days in jail saying that the sentence was quote only fair.
Speaker 1: That judge is an awesome judge at that time.
Speaker 0: yet In fact when arrested one thousand three hundred and thirty three times since his first arrest in July of 1970, man They should send some just one night in jail for every friggin thing.
Speaker 1: Why why?
Speaker 1: why this thousand days keeping them off the liquor?
Speaker 0: maybe trying to help him?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: So I would like to point out that if you wish to follow Henry Earl, there's in fact an RSS feed and The page you want to go to is called.
Speaker 1: Is there a Firefox extension?
Speaker 1: Yes you.
Speaker 0: whether he's in or out of jail It's much like the a pagoda Firefox extension that tells you whether or not a pagoda is alive.
Speaker 0: There is the Henry Earl Firefox extension.
Speaker 0: At least there was.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it still exists or if it works in Firefox 3.
Speaker 0: That tells you if he is in jail or not in jail.
Speaker 0: But if you go to what's up with Henry Earl, which I will link to Every time you go there's a random mugshot of Henry Earl and let me tell you he's smiling in the vast majority of them.
Speaker 1: Even though he's a sad story there's something to like about Henry.
Speaker 1: You in a way you should be Henry Earl, you know, whatever your lot in life is You should you should go full out.
Speaker 1: But in a way you shouldn't be Henry or you should not be Henry Earl homeless and drunken.
Speaker 0: I Can say one thing though Henry Earl has not harmed anyone but himself and that's more than you can say for a lot of other People out there.
Speaker 1: that is true.
Speaker 1: In fact, Henry Earl has helped many other than himself mostly front behind.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so that was my exciting and interesting Thursday bit.
Speaker 1: Why you gotta be using cool things of the day like Henry Earl right before my completely boring and everyday news?
Speaker 0: Well, you see what.
Speaker 0: there are things I could have talked about.
Speaker 0: I really want to talk about the business with Obama calling McCain and being like yo, let's do something about this economic disaster and McCain saying, okay I'll call you back and then immediately hosting a press conference asking Obama to do something Great and then, you know trying to cancel the debate or I could talk about the fact You know that there was a general collapse in the stock market.
Speaker 0: I could talk about all sorts of things but that all had to go on.
Speaker 0: Oh, wait a minute.
Speaker 0: There's an animated gif of Henry Earl right here.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's all those mugshots.
Speaker 0: Great Wow.
Speaker 0: Okay Anyway, Scott, what do you have?
Speaker 0: What's new and exciting in the world of Scott?
Speaker 1: Alright, so check this out, right?
Speaker 1: You know, I always hate the fake medicines.
Speaker 1: I'm well aware of your vitriol Yes, and recently the government has actually been cracking down and the fake medicines have been very nice.
Speaker 1: They they're going after a fake cancer cure websites, you know that are in the US that they can actually go after.
Speaker 1: They're you know, sort of crack it down and some false claims on various things, you know making them stop.
Speaker 1: there's there's some pretty good action going on in terms of fight against fake medicine and the FTC the Federal Trade Commission which you know sort of regulates commerce and makes sure you don't falsely advertise is You know doing its job and they have said that they're not gonna stop.
Speaker 1: this isn't like a one-time deal.
Speaker 1: They're keeping an eye out.
Speaker 1: They actually made a website.
Speaker 1: I think it's ftc.com Slash.
Speaker 1: is it curious?
Speaker 0: I think No, yeah, no you complain that I have a good news and yet you don't.
Speaker 1: you're not even ready.
Speaker 1: I'm ready.
Speaker 1: I just forgot about the sub.
Speaker 1: say until - here it is.
Speaker 1: Yes, ftc.gov Slash curious you see my mess up there.
Speaker 1: Anyway, and it's a website that basically tells you how to spot fake cancer cures and tells you to be skeptical.
Speaker 1: and it's it's Curious get it.
Speaker 1: See you are e - oh You're curious about the cure.
Speaker 0: Oh, wait, perhaps I should use hey.
Speaker 1: Oh Instead it's a good website.
Speaker 1: if you're you know, if you have cancer and you're really uninformed, it's that's a good place to go.
Speaker 1: but anyway so the government's doing a good job there, but there's a study recently and People have known for a long time many of the reasons that people go to fake medicine.
Speaker 1: Right, and one of the reasons people go to fake medicine is because when you go to the doctor, right?
Speaker 1: the doctor a real doctor is usually not that nice or Attentive.
Speaker 1: they don't make you feel good.
Speaker 1: They're actually kind of scared even even as much as I know that the real doctor is where it's at.
Speaker 1: It's not comfortable going to a hospital or a doctor's office or anything like that.
Speaker 1: I mean you're in a hospital.
Speaker 1: the doctor maybe shows up once a day.
Speaker 1: It doesn't say much to you You know, it's it's not really pleasant.
Speaker 1: The doctors don't do a lot to make you feel good.
Speaker 1: But if you go to fake medicine, right some like bullshit, you know, homeopathy Chiropractors something something Acupuncture, you know meditation BS, right?
Speaker 1: They're not actually gonna help you with any actual medicine But they'll be real nice to you and they'll sit down and talk to you for a long time and make you feel really good In terms of you know, mentally speaking they'll be very reassuring with lies But it's reassuring and this is something we've sort of known.
Speaker 1: but it was something you knew in sort of a common sense sort of way.
Speaker 1: and well the There was a study.
Speaker 1: the study author was dr.
Speaker 1: Diane Morse an assistant professor of medicine and psych Psychiatry at University to Rochester.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Despite RIT being the super geek school U of R had a far better arcade Yeah, and U of R was a big school for medicines.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they had.
Speaker 1: they ran the hospital that you know RIT students went to if they had a problem.
Speaker 1: anyway They did a little study there and they found that.
Speaker 1: Well, I'll read from the little article here.
Speaker 1: while doctors are able to address such concerns as medication issues missed appointments or pain They tended to skirt existential issues such as questions dealing with life and death Which are of paramount importance to most patients.
Speaker 1: the study author said Physicians only responded to 10% of empathic opportunities and when patients raised existential concerns Physicians tended to shift more to biomedical responses.
Speaker 1: Physicians had trouble addressing the bulk of concerns that were about patient fears Concerns about death or dying or worsening conditions and they go on and on and pretty much they studied and they found out Doctors really won't say anything to make you feel better now.
Speaker 1: They didn't go in to ask why doctors aren't saying these things, you know.
Speaker 1: But I can come up with some ideas such as doctors are very concerned about being ethical and if they start You know getting too friendly and and you know close to you It might sort of break that.
Speaker 1: you know, what's appropriate for the patient doctor relationship, you know It's.
Speaker 1: it's real hard for you know, you know There's a lot of doctors who have to you know Sort of unpleasant things to your body and if they sort of know you too Well, it could.
Speaker 1: I could imagine it being more difficult, you know than doing it in a cold and calculated matter of doctoring.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's.
Speaker 1: uh, it's pretty interesting and I've had an idea for a while.
Speaker 1: Let rim Let me tell you I might have I told you this idea before that.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: All right, you can shoot.
Speaker 1: I think that when you go to a doctor or a hospital or something, right?
Speaker 1: It's obvious that there needs to be.
Speaker 1: you know, the doctors need to talk to you more.
Speaker 1: But the problem is not only do the doctors not want to you know, have ethical problems or you know Patient-doctor relations problems, but they also don't have a lot of time especially hospital doctors.
Speaker 1: They got to treat so many people.
Speaker 1: they're running around from hospital to hospital You know, they can't spend too much time with any one person, you know They can't afford to sit there and talk to you because they actually had to be doing procedures.
Speaker 1: Do you know?
Speaker 1: checking people running tests, etc, etc.
Speaker 1: I really think that there's a space to have a new job of Person who you can talk to at the doctor or at the hospital.
Speaker 1: just a person whose job it is to Talk to the patients and tell them what's up, you know who can know have enough medical knowledge to you know.
Speaker 1: Read the charts see what your condition is, you know tell you about your condition and things.
Speaker 1: maybe not actually perform procedures or tests or make medical biomedical recommendations or you know prescribe anything or anything like that, but just You know to discuss your problems with you and make you feel better and such and we don't.
Speaker 1: I don't think we have people like That.
Speaker 1: I think we need them and maybe if we did people wouldn't go get fake medicine so much.
Speaker 0: Anyway things of the day now.
Speaker 0: if geek nights means one thing to you.
Speaker 0: It should mean Dedication.
Speaker 0: you see I feel as though I have found a kindred spirit out there in the world of radio.
Speaker 1: I don't think I have.
Speaker 0: I have at least I mean to still be doing this after what five three years?
Speaker 1: 500 plus crazy episodes 500 plus crazy episodes is not equal to what is in this video.
Speaker 0: This video is fantastic.
Speaker 0: It is pretty good video.
Speaker 0: I mean, I just I don't really want to describe it but suffice to say a radio DJ is talking You know doing much like I'm doing now.
Speaker 0: He's leaned into his microphone.
Speaker 0: He's talking increase something starts to happen behind him something Possibly dangerous and it's not like he doesn't notice it.
Speaker 0: He basically turns around while still talking has this look of oh shit.
Speaker 0: But he keeps talking without skipping a beat and meanwhile like you read like he turns his back on the thing that is happening Continues to do his radio thing.
Speaker 0: Obviously, he's live I guess waiting for someone to help him and eventually someone comes in to help him.
Speaker 0: They do not help.
Speaker 0: the situation escalates and I will leave it as a surprise to you what happens in the end.
Speaker 0: This man is a tiny hero, he's a little bit more of a hero than Henry Earl.
Speaker 1: No, he's not.
Speaker 1: He's just crazy and stupid I think.
Speaker 1: but at the same time crazy and stupid makes for incredible video entertainment.
Speaker 0: crazy and stupid awesome All right, however, I think the coup de grace today will be well.
Speaker 0: tonight is Scott's thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Yes, I I have trouble not cracking up.
Speaker 0: Just thinking about it.
Speaker 1: This video is one of the best videos I've seen in quite a long while.
Speaker 1: Many people, you know have trouble when listening to the hip-hop music's Comprehending what is being said and the same can be said for you know, metal music's or rock music's.
Speaker 1: but in this particular case talking about the hip-hop music's and they listen to hip-hop music's and either because they are not familiar with the vocabulary or Because the way the words are enunciated they can't actually, you know, make them out with their ear, you know Perhaps because of slurring or or you know the rhythmic, you know movements of the words make it hard to decipher them Or many reasons why someone who is untrained in the in the arts is not used to listening to it would not be able to Comprehend exactly what is being said in the lyrics of hip-hop song if those lyrics were not written down and maybe even partially or fully translated.
Speaker 1: So what we have here is a video.
Speaker 1: It seems like there's.
Speaker 1: it looks like a school gymnasium or equivalent Community center room pretty big actually a packed house and on stage There are a couple of hip-hop artists having a freestyle battle.
Speaker 1: a freestyle You know battle is where you know, they they hip-hop and they rap without any preparation.
Speaker 1: They don't write the lyrics up beforehand.
Speaker 1: They come up with them as They wrap them now.
Speaker 0: granted we could do a whole show about that.
Speaker 0: It's a cool thing, but there's a lot of a lot of tricks and filler words and like things you do like freestyle.
Speaker 0: Rap is difficult, but you can do a lot of preparation to be good at it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah, it's it's but to do it.
Speaker 1: Well, really, you know, that's why they have competitions.
Speaker 1: It's if someone, you know keeps falling back on say, you know a repeated phrase or theme, you know Well, they think of the next thing to say.
Speaker 1: that's not as good as someone who keeps coming up with newer and more indefinitely.
Speaker 1: It's like a verbal fencing and someone who you know keeps the rhythm better without going uh, I mean you go.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's like you lose.
Speaker 1: but you know Someone who keeps a better rhythm or has you know better rhyming words or clever rhymes is definitely getting ahead in the freestyle rap battle.
Speaker 1: Anyway, here's a video of a freestyle rap battle between a man named hydrogen and a man named boost.
Speaker 1: The man named hydrogen, right?
Speaker 1: He does his rap followed by you know, the man named boost.
Speaker 1: then, you know, they decide who's the winner.
Speaker 1: This video.
Speaker 1: however The audio is completely dubbed over.
Speaker 1: there is none of the original audio is left.
Speaker 1: The original video is but not the original audio.
Speaker 1: instead what we have are some white guys.
Speaker 1: they have translated the lyrics to the freestyle hip-hop battle and They speak them at.
Speaker 1: you know As they be hip-hopping is going on so that if you aren't someone who does not understand hip-hop lyrics You can watch this video and you will understand what these people are saying.
Speaker 0: now, I want to say one thing.
Speaker 0: I got to say this pretty clearly.
Speaker 0: This is Hilarious beyond belief.
Speaker 1: not only is the translation of the lyrics itself hilarious, right The end of the video has a special treat.
Speaker 1: That is the payoff.
Speaker 0: basically I will not reveal because you're going to watch it wait for it because it's one of those things where like it's funny and you're really digging it and then Something happens and music starts playing and It is it is.
Speaker 0: it is somewhat hilarious.
Speaker 1: You could say yeah Do not do yourself a disservice by skipping around in this video or anything like that because you need the build-up or else it is.
Speaker 0: The payoff is not worth it.
Speaker 1: Just play the video and watch it from beginning to end and then if you are not laughing I don't know what's wrong with you.
Speaker 0: It's such a I have a joke, but I can't make it without spoiling.
Speaker 0: Don't don't make it anyway tonight How you made the joke, that's right.
Speaker 0: so tonight Finally after a long long time of it being put off by various things We're to talk about Neal Stephenson's snow crash in a spoiler if ik.
Speaker 0: final thoughts the geek nights book club manner.
Speaker 1: So if you haven't read snow crash, like we told you to and it seems like actually looking at a poll I put up maybe like half the people read it then 25% plan to or kind of sorta but then 25% No, so actually that's a lot better than we were thinking.
Speaker 1: I think it's just the people who read it, you know weren't speaking out enough.
Speaker 1: So I think we're just gonna force the book club because you know, it's sort of like in the library We have the signs that say read and a famous person with a book, you know, we're sort of like that.
Speaker 1: I think that's good.
Speaker 0: I think we can avoid talking about a lot of the things we talked about when we Introduced this book in terms of you know, why like why we read it and why it's important.
Speaker 0: I forgot what we said when we introduced this book, but we'll have to touch on a lot of that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, because it's kind of central.
Speaker 0: I mean the book itself is important Primarily because it kind of catapulted Stephenson into this I guess.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: He's a real author.
Speaker 0: Look at what he wrote.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Neal Stephenson was pretty much just like a nerd author and then snow crash You know sort of brought him into being a real author who is respected although nerdy.
Speaker 1: So because of that we have two Neil's the Neil Stephenson and the Neil Guyman.
Speaker 1: do not confuse the two.
Speaker 1: It is very important that you have a clear separation in your mind.
Speaker 1: Neil Stephenson is NEAL Neil Guyman is NEIL.
Speaker 1: All right, very different people.
Speaker 1: No confusion.
Speaker 0: Well, the one thing we really have to just bring up again because it bears repeating is that this book was published in 1992.
Speaker 1: oh that just that freaks me out.
Speaker 1: cuz I read it.
Speaker 1: Well, not more than two years ago.
Speaker 0: Basically you read it now and you think like it reeks of the 90s But it was written before the 90s really happened.
Speaker 0: Like you read it.
Speaker 0: You're like, wow, it's the 90s.
Speaker 0: This is what the internet was like in the mid late 90s.
Speaker 0: This is what this is a 90s book, but it was basically written in the late 80s.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you wrote this book or a similar book now Everyone would say that's derivative crap derivative crap.
Speaker 1: and you know a part of the things some of the things in this book Right warrant completely original at the time of its writing.
Speaker 1: But a lot of it was a whole lot of it.
Speaker 0: It was it was it was ahead of its time and that it it talks about the internet as it would be in the late 90s well before it happened with a scary degree of accuracy.
Speaker 0: Granted I say with the degree of accuracy because it takes a lot of liberties.
Speaker 0: I mean the actual reality of what's going on in this book.
Speaker 0: I mean the metaverse VR all those things which are really big in the 90s.
Speaker 0: But VR never really came to pass.
Speaker 0: like VR is almost entirely faded from the limelight.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like any science fiction book.
Speaker 1: right when you write about the future you write about not the actual future usually But you write you know what that the vision of the future was in that time.
Speaker 1: like, you know, you read some 50s sci-fi.
Speaker 1: It's all like moon men and shit.
Speaker 0: or you watch like a strange days Which is still one of my favorite sci-fi movies ever.
Speaker 0: But you look at you're like wow.
Speaker 0: That doesn't like you feel like the culture of the movie feels off like it doesn't feel like a future culture.
Speaker 0: but it was made in like 1991 and it's set in 1991 and 99. if you go back to 91 and you look at what the world was like and what?
Speaker 0: America was like.
Speaker 0: you think wow back then I could see this as being the 1999 future.
Speaker 1: and then inevitably, you know After something, oh, you know science fiction book comes out and the future does happen.
Speaker 1: We look back and we always find you know Some facets in some science fiction book somewhere that match the future we have created and we always wonder Did we just take the fiction and make it reality or was there just so much fiction that no matter what reality happened?
Speaker 1: Something would match it?
Speaker 1: and it's it's a tough question, but science fiction inevitably become science fact somehow eventually.
Speaker 1: It's just always been that way.
Speaker 0: I don't know why But we just talk about the book spoiler.
Speaker 0: I mean the thing is it's not like other works like we talk about Ava.
Speaker 0: You know a lot of anime a lot of other books and there's just oh you can spoil it blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: But this is not really a spoilable book.
Speaker 1: That's kind of what I like about it.
Speaker 1: Is it you know, really spoiling?
Speaker 1: I don't want to go into my spoiling rant But if something can be spoiled that means to me at least that it relies heavily or somewhat on surprise Right or twists of some kind.
Speaker 1: and if knowing the twist beforehand makes the work No longer enjoyable or as enjoyable then perhaps it was relying too heavily on the surprises and the twists Whereas a work that is continued to be enjoyed in successive rereadings, you know.
Speaker 1: Or maybe you find new things each time you look at it.
Speaker 1: That is a long-lasting enjoyable work.
Speaker 1: You know, the Sistine Chapel or the Mona Lisa, you know, you can't really spoil them, right?
Speaker 0: She's marking.
Speaker 1: in fact, the more you look at them the more you enjoy them.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: and snow crash is Sort of like that in which the more you think about it The more you can see what was so important about it what it was saying the more things you can find in there to be.
Speaker 1: But in other ways if you reread it there are certain things you notice that are maybe not so it's not perfect in any way.
Speaker 0: But yeah, well, you know speaking of not perfect the one real criticism I have and I have this with all any Stevenson work I've ever read but I guess it stands out more in this one because I think it's one of his earlier works.
Speaker 0: But he while he can write very iconic action scenes Like you think to you know Listen to reason that whole business with reasons the kind of thing where a nerd reads it and go.
Speaker 1: Oh my god Moments.
Speaker 1: I really think that the whole reason thing in there while we love that listen to reason scene Right and while it's so awesome and this great joke and it's it's pretty fucking awesome and in a movie It would be so badass even in your mind when you're reading.
Speaker 1: It's badass.
Speaker 1: I Think that he really just put that in there because it was awesome.
Speaker 0: But a lot of the scenes in this book and a lot of his works are like that and I mean it seems like it's Tamed as his works have gone on.
Speaker 0: but like you see it here There are a lot of scenes or moments that he was probably thinking man It'd be really cool if this happened and I kind of puts it in.
Speaker 0: but yeah at the same time in the story if they Didn't have reason a lot like a lot of the plodges couldn't have had but it didn't have to be reason.
Speaker 1: It could have been something else, you know calling it reason and making it specifically like that is sort of what the you know Is the it didn't.
Speaker 1: really there's no reason it had to be called reason other than to make a joke and to be double Awesome, but I'm going to make but pretty much the most scathing criticism I have about Neal Stephenson.
Speaker 0: the dude can't write action scenes for crap.
Speaker 0: His action scenes are by and large awful.
Speaker 0: They're confused.
Speaker 0: They're they're cloudy.
Speaker 0: It's like he didn't plot out and he sort of like if you tried to film it based on what he wrote.
Speaker 0: It would basically be impossible and everyone who tried to film it would be completely different.
Speaker 0: It's muddled.
Speaker 0: then the narrative kind of shifts in and out of all these different voices like Neal cannot write action scenes.
Speaker 1: Good God Well, I didn't notice that.
Speaker 1: the one thing that really stands out in my mind in that sense It's like.
Speaker 1: well the the two big action scenes that I can remember at least right are.
Speaker 1: In the early part is the car chasey bit right and where he's trying to deliver the pizza Well, he's not really a chase But he's trying to get the pizza there on time.
Speaker 1: Right and I could sort of follow that.
Speaker 1: but really more in that scene was less about the actual Action happening and more about introducing you to the world, you know, the the crazy libertarian Corporate world or everything is privately owned and everything and how he gets on the highway owned by one company and pays a toll And all that stuff.
Speaker 1: but toward the you know, the climactic action scene of the what is a bicycle race in cyberspace, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that scene was basically.
Speaker 1: it's a rhyme.
Speaker 0: Yes There wasn't much to that scene to be honest.
Speaker 1: No, I couldn't follow that scene at all.
Speaker 1: All I sort of got out of the scene was they're chasing, you know.
Speaker 1: And it didn't have the suspense of one person's winning.
Speaker 1: now the other person's winning now the other person's winning.
Speaker 1: You know who's ahead or who's behind.
Speaker 1: it was just sort of like this crazy race going on.
Speaker 1: It's whoever wins.
Speaker 1: Oh my god I don't know what's going on.
Speaker 1: and then suddenly weird shits happening and then someone wins.
Speaker 0: Okay the end but also in general, I mean Obviously his later works are much better, but the writing in snow crash I'll be honest in a lot of points is a little amateurish like it.
Speaker 0: just then like the voice or the like the passive nature will come in and out and this it is disjointed and Chapters really don't flow into each other at all.
Speaker 0: And it's kind of just all over the place.
Speaker 0: But at the same time I Don't know if it was intentional or not But the result of that the disjointed narrative almost kind of mirrors the world that he is presented to us this fractured Balkanized world that in the physical real world makes almost zero sense like it did.
Speaker 0: it couldn't really be.
Speaker 0: but at the same time if you look at Internet culture as it grew and what it became which I point out was far after he wrote this book.
Speaker 0: It's almost a perfect like metaphor or a perfect representation of what internet culture is like.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean in the book, right the one of the things I really love about snow crashes the world of snow crash Which is sort of like this libertarian paradise where?
Speaker 0: well, it's a libertarian paradise It's a cast not a paradise.
Speaker 1: I didn't say it was a paradise.
Speaker 1: It said specifically is a capital L libertarian paradise.
Speaker 0: Yes, I guess you have to make sure that Libertarian paradise is in quotes and that you cannot construe paradise from it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is a paradise only for libertarians or at least it is what libertarians say they want.
Speaker 1: right now.
Speaker 1: It is a world in which the US government is incredibly weak and limited and everything in you know The United States or they guess the rest of the world?
Speaker 1: I don't know, but it's mostly.
Speaker 1: this story takes place in the United States or future United States.
Speaker 0: there's narcolumbia the corporation instead of Columbia the company exactly.
Speaker 0: There's Mexicali and and the fact that the mafia is just a franchise And you can just totally like get a job with it.
Speaker 0: Like you've got a job at McDonald's.
Speaker 1: all Everything in the country quotes right country is owned by some private company.
Speaker 1: All the roads are privately owned.
Speaker 1: So if you drive on say mafia roads, you have to pay mafia tolls to use those roads.
Speaker 1: They're not government roads for you know, everyone to share, you know You know if your your house is in one court, you're a citizen of a corporation, right?
Speaker 1: He's a hero protagonist didn't even say his name yet right is the main character.
Speaker 1: He's basically a hacker with a samurai sword, you know nerd porn.
Speaker 0: I just have to say in terms I don't think we need to really explain because we're assuming that everyone listening to this has read The book.
Speaker 1: All right, basically the hacker with the nerd sword What is he lives in like, you know, basically what.
Speaker 1: the equivalent of the Chinatown corporations like mr.
Speaker 1: Food.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Lee.
Speaker 1: Oh, mr Lee's something Hong Kong, right?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I love the giant disclaimer that come.
Speaker 0: it's like welcome to mr Lee's blah blah blah and then giant disclaimer, mr.
Speaker 1: Lee's something Hong Kong.
Speaker 0: Anyway, mr.
Speaker 1: Lee's greater Hong Kong.
Speaker 1: That's what it is.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, mr Lee's greater Hong Kong is fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: If I lived in the snow crash world, I would be a citizen of mr Lee's greater Hong Kong.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I might join the Mafia.
Speaker 1: The Mafia is also really cool.
Speaker 0: I got it.
Speaker 0: I gotta say this now Uncle Enzo is like the coolest fucking dude ever forget right easily.
Speaker 0: Seriously.
Speaker 0: Uncle Enzo is cool.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it's not like I'm a badass way, but I exactly totally cool do.
Speaker 1: Raven.
Speaker 1: I actually don't like Raven, but he is badass.
Speaker 1: But uncle Enzo is really.
Speaker 1: I think If there was someone in the book I wanted to be my friend it would be uncle Enzo.
Speaker 0: say this though I don't feel like uncle Enzo works as a character.
Speaker 0: He does not.
Speaker 1: I think that's why he played such as you know small at least.
Speaker 1: Uncle Enzo's the Mafia played a larger role, but him himself played a smaller Inconsistent and poorly conceived character.
Speaker 0: However in the vein of this book He is awesome because this book is a collection of nerd pornography.
Speaker 1: Well, it's that's the thing is that it's hard.
Speaker 1: the book does have a pile of nerd porn in it, right?
Speaker 1: It's got reason.
Speaker 1: it's got bat the badass thing with the nuke on the bicycle.
Speaker 1: It's got you know, those hacker guys who have all the gadgets hanging off of them.
Speaker 1: It's got cyberspace.
Speaker 1: You know, the main character is a pizza delivering hacker with a samurai sword.
Speaker 1: Okay, this is nerd porn all over it But it very easy for someone who doesn't give the book a big enough chance to misconstrue the entire book as nerd porn from cover to cover all the way down to the bottom and There is a lot of nerd porn.
Speaker 1: but the nerd porn is the surface level activity in this book.
Speaker 1: There is actually some deep high quality cyberspace Metaphors and things going on in this book and you could easily tell that same deep story with something else besides nerd porn on the top.
Speaker 1: But having nerd porn on the top just makes it better for us nerds.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: Am I right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 0: I mean, this is the book that has that famous speech We don't need to say the speech again about.
Speaker 0: you know, every man blah blah blah wants to be a badass.
Speaker 1: It's exactly what all nerd guys think and you know what.
Speaker 0: we're past the age.
Speaker 1: It's too late.
Speaker 1: I think we are past the age but Stevenson knows cuz he obviously was a nerd.
Speaker 1: He knows about the whole hog and you know Linux and whatnots.
Speaker 1: So he knew.
Speaker 1: so it was easy for him to write a book that tapped in to our Demographic because he's in our demographic and it doesn't seem like a large number of Successful science fiction authors are in our demographic and also are lauded and successful like Stevenson is.
Speaker 0: Now there's the only other.
Speaker 0: I guess I'll get all my criticisms out of the way.
Speaker 0: the only other thing that really kind of stood out is being bad about this book was there was a I Guess an attempt at a semi erotic scene between YT and Raven.
Speaker 1: see that for me I didn't.
Speaker 0: I remember all those days.
Speaker 0: that scene was written awkwardly, and I don't want to rag on Stevenson, but it was written as Though the person writing it had never had an erotic moment.
Speaker 1: right now first of all Right, the entire book has the Chekhov's gun of the stupid dentata, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that is you know, while a Chekhov's gun is a fine literary mechanic It was used pretty poorly because they showed you the gun too many times They kept bringing it up and bringing it up and bringing it up.
Speaker 0: It's like if Chekhov walks out on stage who says
Speaker 1: I had a fucking gun
Speaker 0: I'm gonna fucking use it and he does this At the beginning of every act and then walks away and leaves the gun there
Speaker 1: Right and with shining bright lights on it and say right
Speaker 0: like the spotlight keeps going back to the gun.
Speaker 1: exactly So it Chekhov's gun is fine, but not you know, the it was a little too.
Speaker 1: Chekhov's gun.
Speaker 1: e right They can't he get coming out and reloading it and everything all the time, you know.
Speaker 1: And then came the scene.
Speaker 1: and when that scene was coming up, right?
Speaker 1: I knew basically Here's the time you saw it coming a mile away was the first problem right a Chekhov's gun.
Speaker 1: for it to be successful You need to at least shut up about it right before it goes off, right?
Speaker 1: But no as soon as it was about to go off I said, oh and like, you know The next page is gonna go off and sure enough it did right.
Speaker 1: and in addition to that, right?
Speaker 1: I wasn't quite sure what was going on in that scene other than the fact that it was gonna go off.
Speaker 1: Really I couldn't tell otherwise what was going on.
Speaker 1: there was there Consensual activity which I think it actually was consensual activity, but not really.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It made not a lot of sense to me But it sort of happened and that it was what it was.
Speaker 0: but very specifically like the the scene where he's like got her up And he's like sitting on his lap.
Speaker 0: It was just.
Speaker 0: it was so awkward like even the first time I read this book a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I remember going Wow Awkward.
Speaker 1: yeah, it was It's not so great.
Speaker 0: but I got one other thing I just got to say Elbab Rife.
Speaker 0: Every time I picture him throughout the entire.
Speaker 0: No, I didn't picture Elron Hubbard, you know, I picture.
Speaker 0: I picture Duke Phillips from the critic.
Speaker 0: Look, I just I that is Duke Phillips is this guy like it is so him kinda.
Speaker 1: but I'm pretty sure I'm not.
Speaker 1: I'm just guessing here, you know, but just based on the nature of the character and the name that given to the character I'm pretty sure it's supposed to be an hour on Hubbard, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but Duke Phillips fits so much better because he's like this barrel so fit going around.
Speaker 0: You know devil may care guy.
Speaker 0: He's just.
Speaker 1: he's.
Speaker 1: No enough about Elron Hubbard the first time I read it to sort of get that Pictured him as one of those crazy TV evangelist guys, but he's also more an amalgamation of other people.
Speaker 0: I mean Bob.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it definitely some Bob there.
Speaker 0: Yep Anyway, but you know despite the fact that the book is a little poorly written and you know A lot of scenes really awkward and the action scenes are incomprehensible the book Makes up for that almost pretty much a hundred and ten percent.
Speaker 0: Yeah with charm with style and with ideas.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean we wouldn't be making this book a geek nights, you know book club I guess whatever we're gonna call this.
Speaker 0: if it was bad The book is just all right, I'd almost say it's a romp It's a ride and it's an excuse to bring out a lot of it.
Speaker 0: Well a lot of really interesting ideas a lot of prescient ideas and a lot of just crazy ideas that are nonetheless Interesting.
Speaker 1: a lot of these ideas have been used elsewhere before and after.
Speaker 1: you know Very I mean the Tower of Babel.
Speaker 1: myth has been used.
Speaker 1: how many times however about a bajillion?
Speaker 0: I've never seen a work of literature take that idea and make it so pseudo scientific as this book made it.
Speaker 0: I mean taking those myths and legends and turning it into what he turned into with the neuro linguistic programming and all that business was just Amazing.
Speaker 0: and I think that cuz you know old Samaritan like so monarchy taso and you think oh wow Yeah, and when you're reading this book Everyone for a moment will be like, you know that kind of makes sense before their brain says no It doesn't shut up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's that second where you're like, you know?
Speaker 1: Well, you know, it's not just you know.
Speaker 1: There's the there's the mat the the symbolism of the Tower of Babel and the neuro linguistic programming.
Speaker 1: But it you know.
Speaker 1: The reason that the book is all nerd porn and hackers actually fits because he's actually talking about.
Speaker 1: is you know Assembly language and how sort of the assembly language has been lost and everyone's talking and see in Python.
Speaker 1: But if someone managed to learn assembly they could get down to the roots.
Speaker 1: it actually fiddle, you know with the with the with the guts of.
Speaker 1: You know the brain.
Speaker 0: and I got to say when I was in high school hanging out with you know My high school D&D playing nerd.
Speaker 0: friends know me and Ken and Dan and Don, you know You play D&D then you watch some anime and then you all go to like the football field and hang out drinking soda looking Up at the stars and talking about stuff.
Speaker 1: that that's the kind of stuff you talk.
Speaker 0: if you record that Conversation and listen to it ten years later You just shake your head and go wow every 16 year old is like that if they're a nerd.
Speaker 0: But we had conversations like this like about this.
Speaker 0: we talked about the brain language.
Speaker 0: now, you know that you know.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like high school kids are effectively stoners when they have these conversations except there There was no high school nerds at least but there's no weed involved.
Speaker 0: You're just stoned on geek nerd stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like this book and you have got a high school kid and you read this book You're gonna be coming up with weird shit like that for weeks.
Speaker 0: Yes, but good God.
Speaker 0: but no we talk.
Speaker 0: you know lay in there after our D&D game all in like the football field about like.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the brain language, you know that language that when you're thinking right your brains not thinking in English like it is.
Speaker 0: But there's that undercurrent that other language down there.
Speaker 0: What if it's the same in everyone's brain?
Speaker 0: What if we could communicate with that?
Speaker 0: That would be hardcore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we could totally hack people If only we could understand it.
Speaker 0: and then this book is like.
Speaker 0: it takes that and it did.
Speaker 1: Well, it takes that it can it can compares and contrast it to you know, the computer programming hacking, right?
Speaker 1: But then also on the other level you have you know, the the reality of it Which is that language and you know The English language or whatever language you speak and does.
Speaker 1: that could be restraints on that language do restrain how people think.
Speaker 1: You know, how many times is there an argument that comes down to semantics and the semantics of the word you use?
Speaker 1: constrain your ability to come up with different ideas if you don't have the words to go with those ideas or or to communicate with.
Speaker 0: Now what's really interesting?
Speaker 1: how you can use words in a way to you're not directly actually Controlling people the way you control a microprocessor with assembly language, but you know propaganda and marketing and whatnot.
Speaker 0: But using words in certain ways you can control how people think and act, you know, I gotta say there's a point I can't really make because it would spoil other works.
Speaker 0: But Scott think about the all the business here and think about the way Magic and everything works.
Speaker 1: I was gonna say that I was actually trying to say that like a minute ago But I decided that I didn't want to do some Prince of Nothing spoilers in the snow.
Speaker 1: That's why I can't make the argument be fair.
Speaker 0: I can't make the argument I want to make but just the ideas of this book Really add a lot to the Prince of Nothing and vice versa.
Speaker 1: I'll go with this right is you know, you've listened to me and rim talk a lot, right?
Speaker 1: And whenever there's any idea or any any discussion of anything, right?
Speaker 1: What do we always do even with games with anime or with any you know with anything?
Speaker 0: We immediately boil it down to core semantics and then bitch about exactly.
Speaker 1: we head To the core when we look at something like wow, we ignore the surface level stuff We scrape that all off the barnacles, right?
Speaker 1: We cut it open and we look to the heart of the matter as if that is that is it really matters the fundamental Nature of the thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you've got this board game with all these great rules.
Speaker 1: Well, actually this game is just rock-paper-scissors at the core or you know, oh you've got this, you know great anime.
Speaker 1: Well actually at the core, this is just another, you know Monster of the week show even though the robots look really cool or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: We we go straight for the core and all of these different geek works here all sort of have this Idea that there is a there is a language or is there there is a way of controlling the core of Manipulating things at the core level going straight to the bottom ignoring the fluff, you know working with the the the true matter the Whatever it is the the pure essence of things and then thus, you know, the rest of everything comes out of that.
Speaker 1: I Don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's an idea We like a lot because it matches how we think.
Speaker 1: or perhaps, you know it being exposed to these ideas So much it shaped how we think but you know.
Speaker 0: Anyway, just to get back to the book itself one thing I can say that maybe it's because you know I read.
Speaker 0: I've read a lot of Kurt Vonnegut since I first read snow crash But I see a lot of Kurt Vonnegut ideas in snow crash.
Speaker 0: not, you know, there's some of it there.
Speaker 0: mostly, you know I read hocus-pocus which is one of my more favorite works of Kurt Vonnegut's and I didn't read that one.
Speaker 0: It's a good one But I feel as though there are strong Similarities in some of the overarching themes not the plot of snow crash but a lot of the themes of snow crash.
Speaker 0: Definitely, I don't know if they were drawn from hocus-pocus or if they're just parallel and analogous But I feel this connection that I can't really articulate deeply.
Speaker 0: unless you've read Kurt Vonnegut's hocus-pocus Which you should all read.
Speaker 0: it's a great if somewhat depressing book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean there's.
Speaker 0: It's also short.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's sort of reminds me at least a little bit of cat's cradle in which they sort of have that narrative structure.
Speaker 1: That's pretty typical and a lot of works of we give you some word or some phrase or something early on like snow crash Or ice nine or something something along those lines right away, right?
Speaker 1: And then you sort of don't learn what it is until later.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it's lame Sometimes it's hackneyed but like both around I never learn it.
Speaker 0: Boca Rado did it like the best I've ever seen anything.
Speaker 1: It's not a bad literary technique.
Speaker 1: It's used quite often to great effect and you can see why right is you?
Speaker 1: you give him someone's pretty solid.
Speaker 0: He's a prince of nothing, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you give somebody a label, right?
Speaker 1: But you don't know what the label is.
Speaker 1: So that now this you've created this empty box that they can't see all this closed box.
Speaker 1: They know the box is there They can't see inside of it.
Speaker 1: They know there's something in there and over time You slowly reveal or don't and then suddenly reveal or never reveal what's in the box.
Speaker 1: and That's a great way to keep someone reading something.
Speaker 1: is I want to know what's in the box?
Speaker 1: Oh, I don't know what's in the box and you can do it Well, and you can do it poorly and snow crash actually does it pretty well, you know, what is snow crash?
Speaker 1: Oh It's this, you know Neurolinguistic virus that can infect people and computers at the same time because it consists, you know The base or language or again babble nerd porn here.
Speaker 0: Is that not?
Speaker 0: I mean to to quotes a somewhat infamous movie?
Speaker 0: Hack the planet is nothing more pornographic to nerd hackers than the ability to hack the real world.
Speaker 0: Not much not much.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's what that's what hacking is all about.
Speaker 1: hacking isn't just about computers.
Speaker 1: hacking is about, you know Finding flaws in systems ways to to manipulate systems or pretty much doing anything you can to to boost You know power in unseen ways, you know You see something and you say aha actually I can get that to go twice as fast and twice as easily by just doing this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know that's that's what hacking is all about.
Speaker 1: so the idea of being able to control things at the lowest level is sort of like the ultimate in hacking because Having you know Root access and being able to just type in any assembly command you want Allows you the full power and once you've achieved that that is sort of like the be-all-end-all of hacking.
Speaker 1: I have controlling everything at the lowest possible level with the highest level of power.
Speaker 0: Now there's also there's a lot of little I don't know I keeps.
Speaker 0: I said charm a couple times But there are.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of really Interesting style to the way people talk or like.
Speaker 0: the best example of this is day it and I'm pretty sure I would pronounce his Name dead, you know dia is David but da5 ID real.
Speaker 1: I just called him in my.
Speaker 1: I was having.
Speaker 1: that's the thing.
Speaker 1: when I read it My mind is a hard time saying his name because I want to call it David, but there's a five there instead of a weird.
Speaker 1: But so I'm like is it day five ID day fit, you know, but I don't have that problem.
Speaker 0: But like the way
Speaker 1: I've ID
Speaker 0: the way my brain Processes names and I think it's partly because I got on the internet and I got online real early and I spent a lot of Time, you know back when avatars and shared spaces were a much bigger deal on the internet and like real-time Avatar based communication and like real-time Chad was real important compared to how important it is now.
Speaker 0: Well now you people are really into the time shifted Chad and I could do a whole show about that business.
Speaker 0: But back then like my I would process because everyone had a lead hacker name and when I say lead I mean Old-school lead like the lead that no one uses anymore.
Speaker 0: the lead that was really stupid had a name like that.
Speaker 1: Now people would think you were eight years old Yes but or 13.
Speaker 0: back then like a lot of people used words and names like that like day it and My brain processed all those names as blobs as like they were like there were not letters in the name.
Speaker 0: The name itself was a unit in my brain.
Speaker 0: so when I see this my brain just like uses the unit and Translates it kind of has a look-up table that translates it into a way to pronounce it.
Speaker 1: So my brain looks at you know date da5 ID and just sort of goes dead Id you know and it's just like I want to say David.
Speaker 1: But when I try to say David in my mind looking at that my brain goes
Speaker 0: ah, see, I think my brain I tend to make blobs like to the point where if someone has a title or There's a phrase even a long phrase or a sentence even that appears more than one time in a book It immediately becomes like compressed into this blob.
Speaker 0: So when I see it again I skip it and move on to the rest of the words just kind of already having known what that was.
Speaker 1: So see how nicely this conversation relates to the main idea in this book.
Speaker 0: That was kind of my intention.
Speaker 0: But yeah day it just immediately like I saw it and my brain said date and that was how I pronounced it.
Speaker 0: I feel like that's correct.
Speaker 1: I'll talk about him.
Speaker 0: I don't have a lot to say about him But just the name.
Speaker 0: and there's a lot of things in the book like that that really set up the way the internet is today.
Speaker 0: Just reading this book again You know, I just feel as though the world it sets up could never exist in the physical world.
Speaker 0: But the world it sets up is what the internet is like now.
Speaker 0: Yeah in a like in a direct and real sense
Speaker 1: and sort of debt and sort of trying to create this You know world of libertarian paradise He actually, you know created a physical world that matches our modern virtual world and his virtual world sort of matches the fictional Virtual traditional
Speaker 0: is a perfectly chromulant word.
Speaker 1: Yes, the fictional virtual world which sort of never going to exist, you know Sort of the idea that everyone always had of oh, well, I'll just sort of go and you know so like reboot which is sorry, I guess kind of like it but more like What was that really bad movie?
Speaker 0: you watch Avalon, oh my god, oh my god I'd forgotten about that movie that sepia tone piece of shit.
Speaker 0: That was one of the worst movies I've ever sat.
Speaker 1: it was pretty terrible.
Speaker 0: Then you realize that that is the lot because I'm one of those people who if a movie is bad enough I will walk out.
Speaker 0: I'll turn it off and say no not worth it.
Speaker 0: I've walked out of or stopped watching maybe Three movies in my life one of which was Clifford.
Speaker 0: I Think Avalon was the worst movie.
Speaker 0: I've not walked out on.
Speaker 1: I know I still don't happen.
Speaker 0: I know what happened.
Speaker 0: the movie tried to set it up self up to be deep and serious And then it had a turnabout and I was like, oh wow.
Speaker 0: Oh man, this movie's awesome.
Speaker 0: And then It had another turnabout which basically undid all the goodwill I had toward the movie and in an instant I went from wow This movie was okay - this movie was not worth any amount of investment or time.
Speaker 0: This movie is oh my god I hate that movie.
Speaker 1: I don't know why people hyped it up so much.
Speaker 0: that movie was terrible.
Speaker 0: if you like it You're a terrible person.
Speaker 1: If you know if you don't know what we were talking about don't ask or I'll say this I'm gonna spoil it.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not gonna spoil it.
Speaker 0: Don't watch it.
Speaker 0: It's not worth it.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 0: I'm not even gonna say why it's not worth it.
Speaker 0: It's not worth it.
Speaker 0: And if you don't believe me Well, you're a. you deserve what you get.
Speaker 0: trust me it's not worth it.
Speaker 0: It's an Odin.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's weird.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like the virtual world in snow crash is sort of like the virtual world that everyone wanted to come to be But hasn't yet and might never.
Speaker 1: but meanwhile the real world in snow crash is almost exactly like the word The.
Speaker 1: you know virtual quotes, you know internet world that we have today But
Speaker 0: not in a literal sense like the literal actions in the book like the way the metaverse is That the whole idea of the metaverse is something that came into being you know without the VR obviously but the metaverse existed and Then stopped existing because it almost immediately became obsolete in the eyes of the majority of people on the internet.
Speaker 1: Well only because the you know, we didn't have that, you know science fiction Virtual reality interface where you sort of tap in and suddenly you're in this other world and it's it's like another world You've actually transported to and you've.
Speaker 1: you're completely separate from the real world Feel and see and walk and you know spaces that were functionally like that with everything except the.
Speaker 0: you know Virtual VR immersion like second life.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, except like same came a lot later.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about a lot of earlier things then I'd Early second life's that were no good.
Speaker 0: I participated in all the second life is but it's like before.
Speaker 0: that thing became technologically feasible in the nerd pornography sense.
Speaker 0: other Unforeseen technology like time-shifting Communication did not really Exist back then like it does today.
Speaker 0: I mean we we've even time shifted chatting.
Speaker 0: What is Twitter?
Speaker 0: It is time shifted space shifted chatting.
Speaker 0: Yeah in many ways and and time the forums and all these things took off in a way that Obsoleted many of the benefits of the metaverse now obsolete.
Speaker 1: It is also perfectly crime.
Speaker 0: Yes, it is made obsolete provided obsolescence for yeah but I don't know.
Speaker 0: I feel like it was prescient in a lot of ways but the literal truth of it did not come to be.
Speaker 0: but What?
Speaker 0: Fundamentally the internet is today is exactly like the real world of snow crash and I keep saying that.
Speaker 0: but it's so true.
Speaker 0: It's this bogan eyes set of different cultures and you buy in you join The cultures that most agree with you and you're walled off from the cultures.
Speaker 0: You don't agree with.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the government is relatively weak, but present.
Speaker 0: Yes present But can't actually do anything to you unless you're stupid or you mommy.
Speaker 1: is it off the mafia or criminal element is?
Speaker 0: Actually, not that evil and people kind of okay with it and it's you know It's also perfectly legitimate outside of you know, like outside of the US things that are totally illegal are totally okay on the internet.
Speaker 1: Yep, there are plenty of cool places for just people to hang out and you know with each other and be cool like, you know Mr.
Speaker 0: Lee's greater Hong Kong with their robot dogs, you know, like the front row crew forums, which you should all join.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, I don't want to talk about the implications of the ramifications But the rat things that that was some great right that wasn't great writing, but it was great work
Speaker 1: Yep, and their religious nut jobs You know have crazy ideas and they completely separate themselves from the world and hide and do crazy things that actually Can harm lots of other people.
Speaker 0: I got to admit I got a little bit of a kick out of the fact that in the world of snow crash all Religion is basically boiled down to Scientology.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, aren't this two religions go?
Speaker 1: Well, there's.
Speaker 1: there's a bunch of religions, but there's two.
Speaker 0: but the sacrament of swiping the credit card I just yeah, it's kind of like wow.
Speaker 0: This point was made in a very inelegant way, but yet I still found it hilarious.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean cuz that's what it is right Is it?
Speaker 1: sometimes you can you know, you can be deep and subtle about making your point about you know The religion is sapping money or you can be blatant with it, right?
Speaker 1: You can come out and be like, yeah They're taking everyone's money but if you just say it like that, it's sort of rough and and sort of it's sort of like a to to I Don't know blunt, right but by pushing it out real hard, but also put a little spin on it You know how.
Speaker 1: the sacrament of the credit card?
Speaker 1: It's like ah now it's suddenly it feels a lot like, you know, the commercials in You know what it is, oh that's a good example, but it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not blunt like just a blunt ugly object.
Speaker 0: It's blunt like a snub nose bullet like it's.
Speaker 0: the example I would use is it is not the clean and elegant Weapon of days past aka the lightsaber.
Speaker 1: It's it's reason.
Speaker 0: it is more a blaster.
Speaker 0: Yeah, efficient and gets the job done.
Speaker 1: Yeah reason is not efficient, but oh my god Listen to it.
Speaker 1: The only reason he called that thing The only reason he called it reason is so he could make that joke by having that guy say they'll listen to reason and yet The book is full of things like that.
Speaker 0: Oh, by the way Juanita coming back at the end is total bullshit.
Speaker 1: I I agree with that camp.
Speaker 0: that was out of nowhere Bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah that whole like in fact, you know what.
Speaker 0: the whole resolution of the plot was pretty much bullshit But you didn't I see.
Speaker 1: the problem is is I think the plot.
Speaker 1: as soon as they had a scene with the helicopter That should have been the end.
Speaker 0: but instead there's that kind of BS useless fight between Enzo and Raven.
Speaker 0: It's like the one.
Speaker 0: this scene is poorly written - it serves no purpose.
Speaker 0: three.
Speaker 0: It's actually kind of boring and for It wasn't good.
Speaker 0: I didn't enjoy.
Speaker 1: if I made snow crash the movie the end of the movie would be they get in the helicopter.
Speaker 1: They say who are you?
Speaker 1: I'm the president United States.
Speaker 1: the helicopter takes off and that would be the end.
Speaker 1: That would be the end of Scott's snow crash.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what diamond age?
Speaker 0: not I'm not gonna spoil diamond age But it did the same thing where it climaxed Awesomely, and then there's another 20 or 30 pages of bullshit.
Speaker 0: You don't care about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's really got to work on his Demma, what's the word?
Speaker 0: Denim all.
Speaker 1: yes, that's the word.
Speaker 0: However, I'll point out I have not read his very recent work so I don't know if yeah, I have zodiac is on my floor and The Baroque trilogy the three monsters.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna get those someday, you know They're gonna be.
Speaker 1: I'll have a whole life to read them.
Speaker 1: All right, I'm not in a rush So we'll see what the deal is there.
Speaker 0: But well, you realize zodiac was his second work.
Speaker 0: No as it's all that was written in the 80s.
Speaker 1: Well, I'll check it out.
Speaker 1: I'll check it out and I didn't even know the work you wrote before that I've only read parts of.
Speaker 1: in the beginning There was the command line.
Speaker 0: see the thing is I didn't.
Speaker 0: I knew that snow crash was his third work But the only work I knew of he wrote before it was zodiac.
Speaker 0: So I just went over to Wikipedia right now and apparently he wrote something called the big you.
Speaker 0: when I was two years old.
Speaker 1: I never heard of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I haven't read Anything he wrote since kryptonomicon which by the way, I didn't read that one anything.
Speaker 0: kryptonomicon is great But it is just nerd pornography.
Speaker 0: It is it is there is almost.
Speaker 0: the thing is unlike Snow crash which brought forth a lot of prescient interesting ideas kryptonomicon Rehashes well-known ideas.
Speaker 1: Well, I did kryptonomicon come out where they will they well-known ideas at the time.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It was written in 99.
Speaker 0: It's basically talks about cryptography and the thing is if you don't know about Cryptography or about computers like on a really deep hacker level.
Speaker 0: It's a great book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the PGP stuff went down I think around then or a little before then.
Speaker 0: but if you know about corporate like basically it is pornography in the sense that Kryptonomicon is basically oh my god This is about the kind of corporation that every nerd wants to be a part of The kind of adventure that every nerd wants to have.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's not really like that.
Speaker 1: It's weird because you know, I'm having a hard time.
Speaker 1: You know snow crash and diamond age being the main books of his that I've read.
Speaker 1: It's like I sort of likes no crashes message, you know a little bit more the whole thing, you know the Tower of Babel metaphor and I like the.
Speaker 1: You know the stylings of snow crash But the actual story of diamond age and the climax and sort of the.
Speaker 1: you know the actual book.
Speaker 1: I sort of like that more.
Speaker 0: so put it this way snow crash is a fun romp nerd porn and It's just a collection of awesome and memorable scenes.
Speaker 0: diamond age has real-world Applicability.
Speaker 1: they die in that.
Speaker 0: if you could do which I think you can What was done on a fundamental level in diamond age in the real world?
Speaker 0: It would change everything.
Speaker 0: I think so - no crash has nothing to say about the real world today.
Speaker 0: Basically the its claim to fame in the real world.
Speaker 0: is it said what is going to be a long time ago And it was largely right.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: well isn't that that it was right in this weird almost wrong way?
Speaker 1: Yeah But I mean isn't that what all the great a lot more.
Speaker 1: many of the great science fiction works have in common.
Speaker 1: is that they?
Speaker 1: Were right ahead of their time.
Speaker 1: You know a whole bunch of science fiction books gets written the future happens the future ends up matching some of them and those ones Are looked at.
Speaker 1: so yes is why 1984 was so great.
Speaker 1: It's why brave new world is so great.
Speaker 1: You know is because That's the world.
Speaker 1: well some people would argue that brave new world is the world we live in and not 1984.
Speaker 1: But there are definitely 1984 aspects to the to the modern world and that is Fahrenheit 451. is is because that's what came to be.
Speaker 0: here's why I enjoy diamond age.
Speaker 0: more snow crash is about hey Here's what it's gonna be like.
Speaker 0: diamond age was.
Speaker 0: hey you morons do this.
Speaker 0: That is that is definitely true that snow crash doesn't tell you to do anything.
Speaker 0: well Well, you know what tells me to do.
Speaker 1: go go to the hills and become a Buddhist.
Speaker 0: No one does or because I'm already over 25 be uncle Enzo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wish I could be uncle.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Is he cool.
Speaker 1: It's weird.
Speaker 1: It's because the book has you know I don't really like.
Speaker 0: oh you know I this is not a spoiler for anything, but Uncle Enzo was a master.
Speaker 0: Raven was a professional.
Speaker 0: oh And that is actually deep If you see.
Speaker 0: if you if you've read and seen all the things that we've read and seen No, I haven't even seen a red, but I know what you're talking about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I get it.
Speaker 0: It's obvious.
Speaker 0: so with any of you Master Keaton is long and kind of slow but if you watch all of master Keaton and you know what a master is and what a professional is then The difference between Raven and uncle Enzo takes on this whole new interesting level.
Speaker 1: I think that is what as another key difference between two books is right.
Speaker 1: when you read a book Generally you want to like the characters in the book The only characters they sort of like and snow crash right or like I like the robot dogs, okay They're not really characters so much.
Speaker 0: I like uncle uncle Enzo.
Speaker 0: Like uncle Enzo I like YT's mom even though I'll say that I like YT too because you know You know what she is.
Speaker 0: she exemplifies one thing and one thing alone Punk kids.
Speaker 0: yeah, she is the good kind of punk kid.
Speaker 0: She is a good kind of punk kid, but you know what she really is and this is the frightening thing She is fortune.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: She is what that is.
Speaker 1: I don't like her that much though It's not like I'm like a huge fan.
Speaker 0: I'll say I enjoy the scenes with her a lot more than most of the scenes with Hiro.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he was no really sort of lay.
Speaker 0: the early scenes with Hiro are great because they're basically you know metaverse hacking blah blah blah But his action scenes all suck.
Speaker 0: YT's action scenes are at least passable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz she's got like you know the hovering stuff, and she throws the rope on like the.
Speaker 1: you know That's.
Speaker 0: that is one of the reasons why when someone said Poon you know PWN for the first time in a mega TF match I was in we all pronounced it Poon and in retrospect Poon Poon this book.
Speaker 0: there may be a Some sort of correlation.
Speaker 1: I think you're stretching it.
Speaker 0: I don't think I made that correlation, but I think someone out there did.
Speaker 1: I think you're stretching it Cuz.
Speaker 0: I know is that far all the people who use the word Poon in the quake one in quake two FPS and days say Poon.
Speaker 0: to this day everyone who started using it recently says Poon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can tell how old someone is by how they pronounce that way.
Speaker 1: I don't think that's in any way related to snow crash.
Speaker 1: for the fact that snow, but it's your linguistic programming.
Speaker 0: I Think we're done.
Speaker 0: unless we start getting into the minutia.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't I don't think you want to hear me talk about one minutia.
Speaker 1: I want to talk about which is.
Speaker 1: you know how he sort of relates.
Speaker 1: You know okay?
Speaker 1: It was the Tower of Babel right BABEL, but also BABB le That that's not pretty crash what that's old anyway.
Speaker 1: I know but that you know, but it's just pointing that out.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like you don't need to do that It's just sort of.
Speaker 1: it was a little painful when they actually it's like.
Speaker 1: it's like the thing you're not supposed to say.
Speaker 1: You know how it's like whether it's an obvious comparison And you've made it and you succeeded.
Speaker 1: and then you make you like you compare two words and make a bad pun.
Speaker 1: That's sort of what that was.
Speaker 1: no so like.
Speaker 1: ah yeah, well.
Speaker 1: It's like no don't say that you would set it up already.
Speaker 0: I can say one thing though The way the book ends while it is incredibly Dissatisfying and anticlimactic and just kind of Peters off and then ends basically the end of the book as I point out is Everybody you know all the punk kids the the couriers that kind of saved the day.
Speaker 0: I'll get bored and wander off after you know like up all right whatever and they just kind of wander away.
Speaker 0: And then YT is like like she does all this crazy stuff like she's had all these adventures And she's basically saved the world and all the blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: And then as soon as the action dies down even a little bit She gets bored and just wanders away.
Speaker 0: and that kind of epitomizes the the current General the generation after us on the internet.
Speaker 0: Get bored.
Speaker 0: wander away is like the rallying call of the internet.
Speaker 0: today It most definitely is and I don't know if that was intentional or if he just doesn't know how to end a goddamn book.
Speaker 1: I don't know it.
Speaker 1: You know if you It's it.
Speaker 1: without interviewing Stevenson It'd be hard to tell how much of it is throw shit against the wall And how much of it is.
Speaker 1: recognize things people are already thinking and figure out what they're gonna think next.
Speaker 1: or you know just match up with things people already thinking or I don't know.
Speaker 1: but There is there.
Speaker 1: definitely I can't not believe that there isn't definitely a significant element of throw shit against the wall And some of it's gonna match and some of it's not this.
Speaker 1: definitely that's going on All right, so actually there's a little tiny problem with the next book, but I'm not changing my mind.
Speaker 1: I tried to think of a book right.
Speaker 1: that would be really good because we're not gonna.
Speaker 1: We're not going with bad books here We're only doing top quality.
Speaker 1: all right.
Speaker 1: We don't give you no poop here at geek night.
Speaker 0: So as a result the next book is Ethan Frome.
Speaker 1: It's not Ethan from.
Speaker 1: Ethan Frome is terrible.
Speaker 1: anyone says otherwise it's stupid.
Speaker 1: um it goes down his sled and hurts himself.
Speaker 1: the end Okay.
Speaker 1: So I tried to think of a book right because you've also had a problem with people not Reading or not wanting to read or being unable to read.
Speaker 0: yes as much as I want the next book to be the count of Monte Cristo, I think one of you will read that.
Speaker 1: yeah, I mean Reading the entire count of Monte Cristo is equivalent to reading all three Prince of Nothing books and people had trouble reading the one.
Speaker 1: So I'm not gonna dump that on you, so I dare to think what's a really good book That is easy to read maybe shorter right yet Still has substance to it, and it's not like c-spot run right cuz I mean we could throw some dr.
Speaker 1: Seuss out there.
Speaker 1: That's pretty good, but it really wouldn't be a lot of episode.
Speaker 1: I mean oh man wasn't it great?
Speaker 1: when there are two fish How about?
Speaker 0: I'm all about blue fish.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: I think you're all about hopping on pop.
Speaker 0: Hop on pop is good.
Speaker 1: You missed my joke.
Speaker 0: I saw your joke and I went right past it.
Speaker 1: actually about the Lorax is the wind.
Speaker 1: but anyway The book we're gonna do all right is.
Speaker 1: I think it's a good choice I made.
Speaker 1: the choice is a Wizard of Earthsea by Ursula K Le Guin.
Speaker 1: It's a fantasy book right.
Speaker 1: you've probably heard of it.
Speaker 1: There was a recent Studio Ghibli movie based on it right pretty important fantasy book from the late 60s.
Speaker 1: But it's a book that really the reading level of it I could have read it in you know maybe sixth seventh grade.
Speaker 1: This is you know is the book perhaps on the same reading level is something like Lord of the Flies.
Speaker 1: You know it's sort of that level of reading.
Speaker 1: so Really everyone should be able to read it.
Speaker 1: You know it shouldn't take you that long.
Speaker 1: It's a book that I could read probably in a few hours.
Speaker 1: It's not difficult at all.
Speaker 1: I'm only gonna do volume one of it right and volume one is a complete story.
Speaker 1: if you like it a lot You can go and get.
Speaker 1: other are the other Earthsea books which sort of directly continue the story.
Speaker 1: All I'll say about Earthsea right the.
Speaker 1: the one thing I want to tell about right now is When you read a lot of fantasy novels right Lord of the Rings prince of nothing.
Speaker 1: right now I'm reading Thomas Covenant.
Speaker 1: right what not?
Speaker 1: white gold-wielding and such.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: There was always you know There's the current epic quest going on or whatever something like that.
Speaker 1: and there was always in the past right some Even greater quest that set the stage of the current world.
Speaker 1: right Lord of the Rings?
Speaker 1: Okay, the Silmarillion set the stage of the Middle Earth that you're.
Speaker 1: you know that Frodo is in.
Speaker 1: you know the great battles of The gods and everything happened in the past.
Speaker 1: and I always say I want to see those great battles of the gods with a million Dragons everywhere.
Speaker 1: how can we never see those?
Speaker 1: and the reason is because it's boring from a you know a book perspective.
Speaker 1: in Earthsea there is the great past with the dragons and all that stuff right to build the world upon but as it turns out the story that happens in that first book of Earthsea is Is Even if you don't realize it the stage-setter, it's actually like oh my god.
Speaker 1: This is it.
Speaker 1: It's the business and that's that really gives me a strong feeling about that book and it's significant in Many recent geek things.
Speaker 1: it's an important fantasy work.
Speaker 1: You should read it.
Speaker 1: It's easy.
Speaker 1: It's also cheap.
Speaker 1: Let me go look how much it is on Amazon.
Speaker 1: while rim says something Or all rim doesn't say anything.
Speaker 0: well pretty much I mean.
Speaker 0: the way we're doing this in the future is that Scott and I are gonna take turns picking books with Unilateral and uncontestable power are we?
Speaker 1: oh is that how we're gonna.
Speaker 0: Do that's how we're gonna Do it.
Speaker 1: see I gave you a chance to.
Speaker 1: you know cuz I picked it out And I don't you you had a chance to say so.
Speaker 0: I will say this I will not abuse this until you do so as long as we play civil.
Speaker 1: Oh is that how we're gonna.
Speaker 0: Do it is we're each gonna basically say Okay, yes, so basically if one of us defects like if I pick the brothers or Crime and punishment That's actually a good book.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not as good as crime and punishment Or the kind of Monte Cristo.
Speaker 0: there.
Speaker 0: Scott can hit me back with Ethan Frome.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna hit you back from.
Speaker 1: Ethan Frome takes five minutes.
Speaker 1: I would hit you back with something far worse than you can possibly imagine.
Speaker 0: you strike me down now.
Speaker 1: Wizard of Earthsea is ten dollars and twenty cents on Amazon, and it's really it won't take you long.
Speaker 1: I mean seriously you could watch that you've reading.
Speaker 1: This would take you less time than watching an anime series all right.
Speaker 1: so That's your reading Simon.
Speaker 1: kids Get to it.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm.
Speaker 1: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: if you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.