Speaker 1: It's Tuesday September 2nd.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, and this is geek nights tonight the penny arcade exposition part 1 Friday.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Hello, people's you have found us.
Speaker 0: Congratulations, you win.
Speaker 0: winner is you.
Speaker 0: we're working nights for all you new people.
Speaker 1: I hope you know that before you clicked on whatever you just clicked on yeah because otherwise a ricker all might have been waiting.
Speaker 0: but Real briefly of course to all our normal listeners of course we're back from the west coast back in the Safe and wanting harbors of the East Coast.
Speaker 1: hmm nice Atlantic Ocean.
Speaker 0: You know we didn't even get to see the Pacific Ocean.
Speaker 1: Well, it's so it's.
Speaker 1: actually I thought Seattle was like odd in the Pacific Ocean, but I was wrong.
Speaker 1: I had only looked at maps that were too zoomed out to realize yeah, well you learned something.
Speaker 1: But now I learned I slept to see this new Pacific Ocean.
Speaker 0: But real briefly for all you new people and I know there's a lot of you because we met a lot of you and there were like 58,000 people at PAX, but Geek nights four nights a week.
Speaker 0: This is Tuesday night.
Speaker 0: geek nights talk about gaming.
Speaker 0: we have other nights of the week.
Speaker 0: you can figure all that out from the closer bit if you don't want to hear about it now and In case you're wondering why this episode came out on a Wednesday night.
Speaker 0: That's just because we were fucking wrecked last night.
Speaker 1: It happens sometimes.
Speaker 1: I mean you try doing a show four nights a week and see how far that gets you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, especially because packs I mean for many of you packs was like the the event of the summer.
Speaker 0: for us packs was the last of many conventions Isn't New York?
Speaker 1: and a festival in three weeks.
Speaker 0: quiet you.
Speaker 0: I don't want to do it about that.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, so I'm like that.
Speaker 1: and then what you know cuts the constant February.
Speaker 0: But if you're here that means you probably enjoyed at least something we did at PAX.
Speaker 0: So uh you'll probably enjoy this.
Speaker 0: but in case you don't well I don't know.
Speaker 1: you can keep listening or just never listen again.
Speaker 1: Don't like it don't listen.
Speaker 0: however This is the point where normally we talk about gaming news of some kind.
Speaker 0: But I realized we've got like eight hours of packs coverage in our brains and like an hour or so to do it in the show.
Speaker 0: So I think we just got to move right along.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have to go to bed at some point tonight.
Speaker 0: All right, take work off tomorrow.
Speaker 1: so you want to just do it will do the things of the day and then we'll just do packs and With that things of the day.
Speaker 0: I think this bit for all you new listeners once again is kind of self-explanatory.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my thing of the day You know, I'll often make comments, you know about games mostly memoir pugas as the Yahtzee is known to say, right?
Speaker 0: You know, we did just talk about Eve online.
Speaker 1: They did.
Speaker 1: Okay, go check that out.
Speaker 0: It was pretty exactly what I thought.
Speaker 1: I didn't see that yet.
Speaker 1: But anyway You know, so I often make fun of those games and saying it's just a database.
Speaker 1: All you're doing is changing, you know data in a database somewhere like when someone buys money in.
Speaker 1: Wow They're basically paying someone to basically type in.
Speaker 1: Update set gold equals number where user ID equals them.
Speaker 0: Except the guy won't type that until you play a grindy minigame for like a thousand hours or give a bunch of money to someone In China, well, but then that guy does the grinding minigame for thousands of hours and the ultimate parody of this, right?
Speaker 1: Someone has made a game called MySQL game and really the MySQL game is not a MySQL game.
Speaker 1: I tried to do some injections to sort of mess with the game.
Speaker 1: What it is is basically an upgrading game that has the interface of SQL.
Speaker 1: It's like they'll have all these queries like instead of having a button that says, you know upgrade weapon They'll have a button that says update weapon, you know set attack equal attack plus one and Set user fuel You know points minus one.
Speaker 1: So it's basically you can type in the number to change the degree of the thing.
Speaker 0: So it's basically the same joke as progress quest only with a little a different kind of ironic little to it.
Speaker 1: Well, you do do something in this game.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's basically a Spend resources game to upgrade stuff game where the interface looks like SQL Resource.
Speaker 0: could I possibly be spending?
Speaker 0: I'm taking this.
Speaker 1: but because in in your user table they have you know, you have a row.
Speaker 1: you start with one row.
Speaker 1: that's your user row and One thing starts out as like a high number and all the other queries force that number to go down when you use them.
Speaker 0: But couldn't I just put in a query to make that number go back up?
Speaker 1: No, you can't type in whatever you want.
Speaker 1: when you see it You'll understand what I'm talking about, but it's an agent.
Speaker 1: It's interesting for the message not for the game.
Speaker 0: What message?
Speaker 0: it's the same message as progress quest.
Speaker 1: it's a slightly different message than progress.
Speaker 0: I think it's the same message.
Speaker 0: progress quest says that you don't even need to be doing this, right?
Speaker 1: Well, this says it's just a database.
Speaker 1: So you combine the two progress quest and MySQL game and you get the reality.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you couldn't tell we don't really like the memoir because that much but it's all tough Love because I played the realm for like three freaking years.
Speaker 1: I played mad muds back in the day.
Speaker 0: That was all just fluff to get out of the way partly because I don't want to edit my post-production script.
Speaker 0: It's time to talk about packs now.
Speaker 1: Did you do your thing today?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I guess I do everything today.
Speaker 0: Well, my thing of the day is a spoiler for pack.
Speaker 0: So if you did not read packs coverage and you just live under a rock and you don't know What happened at the end of the Omega thon?
Speaker 0: Well, uh wait until the end of the show before you watch my thing of the day because I had to show you this video.
Speaker 0: I don't Explaining it does not do it justice.
Speaker 0: You have to see the way the crowd reacted to the final round of the Omega thon.
Speaker 1: I have video of this but it's 1.6 gigs.
Speaker 1: It's actually really good video.
Speaker 1: I'm like my arm was getting tired while taking the video.
Speaker 1: So I thought it was bad But actually I watched it and it came out really well.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got to find a way to upload it.
Speaker 1: somehow mines a little bit of shaky cam here But that's what you get is a tiny bit of shaky cam, but not a lot less than I thought it was gonna have.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the one I got is pretty bad.
Speaker 0: I just went on YouTube and tried to find like the best one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll try to get mine uploaded.
Speaker 0: It was tricky cuz.
Speaker 0: yeah, I mean you had to get the build-up to it.
Speaker 0: You couldn't just show it.
Speaker 0: the build-up was.
Speaker 1: I got the whole thing from no one's on stage to go home.
Speaker 0: So so that includes sit your ass on that beanbag such as the BBS, right?
Speaker 1: I think the exact quote was get your ass in the beanbags.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so, you know before we can talk about packs 2008 We have to talk a little bit about the backstory about Little Mac working his way up to this because When packs first happened and you know We're not gonna talk about Fanny arcade or the history of facts or Necro Wamba con or anything.
Speaker 0: But when the first packs was announced, I remember thinking wow That'd be pretty cool If it wasn't on the other side of the planet.
Speaker 0: as far as I'm concerned cuz I'm pouring in college I'd probably go when packs is announced.
Speaker 1: I just knew that is the convention that I must go to and that is where the awesomeness is happening.
Speaker 1: But at the time I had not the means to go not the vacation days nor the fun.
Speaker 0: So you realize the truth is that you didn't really want it.
Speaker 0: I didn't want it.
Speaker 1: It's the same reason I haven't picked up a pigeon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we're sitting there, you know, all right.
Speaker 0: but then we start hearing these spotty reports from people who were out there.
Speaker 1: and Wasn't spotty reports Direct from the horse's mouth.
Speaker 0: I say spotty.
Speaker 0: I mean like ten minutes into it There were reports coming back that it was awesome.
Speaker 1: Basically everything all the news that came out of packs and all the descriptions of what it occurred at the first second third and fourth Packs is none of which we attended Convinced me absolutely 100% that this is the convention to end.
Speaker 0: all I mean the concerts alone would have been worth flying out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, especially they talk about these spiritual experience of what it occurred at the packs and I knew I was missing out on something And I had a lifelong regret ahead of me.
Speaker 1: There's nothing I could do.
Speaker 0: so we said next year we should go and then the next year came and we had neither money nor Times or we didn't go.
Speaker 0: and then the next year came and we had neither money nor time.
Speaker 0: Then the next year came and we probably could have gone but we justified not go and saying that ah, it's too expensive We'll just go to Otacon and Katsucon and all these things instead.
Speaker 0: and then the next year We still didn't fucking go because we're just morons at this point.
Speaker 0: So this year we said we're going no matter what it was about one year ago.
Speaker 0: today After the previous packs went on the show We committed in fact I wasn't really ready to come in and we kind of forced ourselves live on geek night
Speaker 1: committed and forced you into it saying We're going to packs no
Speaker 0: matter what
Speaker 1: come the hells and the high waters and high waters actually came to some other people.
Speaker 0: Oh Too soon too soon.
Speaker 0: So we committed on the air and then we put that episode up with no Retraction that we were going to go to packs and nothing was going to stop us.
Speaker 1: and so To not shit talk we did.
Speaker 1: we went yeah packs.
Speaker 0: and uh, I Don't want to spoil what we're gonna say for the next hour or two or however long this is gonna take.
Speaker 0: but packs was like the best goddamn convention I've ever been to.
Speaker 0: Yeah shows over that's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't need pretty.
Speaker 0: I'll say this if you like Games and I noticed I didn't say video games if you like games you need to go to packs.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter if you're like a candy land fanatic or if you're like a Starcraft fanatic.
Speaker 1: It's all good at pack.
Speaker 0: You don't need to like penny arcade.
Speaker 0: You don't even know a penny arcade is just go It's packs.
Speaker 0: It's it's a.
Speaker 1: knowing what penny arcade is helps a little bit, but it's not necessary.
Speaker 0: So, uh thus the odyssey of packs.
Speaker 0: now, of course, we've never been to the west coast.
Speaker 0: We've never been to see.
Speaker 0: I've never been west of Michigan until not that long before packs.
Speaker 1: You know if you judged conventions only by the life of Scott then you could come up with an equation that says as Longitude as a longitude of Convention goes west convention quality increases.
Speaker 0: Yes However, that does not go the same for road trips because the worst road trip we ever went on took us west That's true.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so the cool thing and I gotta say this, you know, we do geek knives.
Speaker 0: we've been doing this for a long time and Because you know most cons like we go to these anime cons and it's like hey con We'll do a bunch of panels for you We'll do events for you and then con says okay come and then we book and we go.
Speaker 0: Packs was we're going no matter what.
Speaker 0: and then it much later.
Speaker 0: I said, hey, maybe we should do a panel.
Speaker 1: Well, it wasn't.
Speaker 1: hey, we should do a panel.
Speaker 1: It's hey, they're allowing pan other there, you know putting out a request for panel applications You know, so we sent one in of course as we do.
Speaker 1: yeah, they gave us one and we had one.
Speaker 0: But the really cool thing is that you know, we do geek night.
Speaker 0: So as a result, we actually there were a lot of people on the West Coast.
Speaker 0: We kind of knew because they're in our forums They listen to our show and unlike going to other conventions where you're coming in out of the blue.
Speaker 0: You got to meet people from nowhere and kind of forge your posse out of nothing.
Speaker 0: We got there and we were greeted at the airport by row one of our awesome listeners and her boyfriend who?
Speaker 0: I just want to point out was holding up a geek night sign with like us doing the Carmel dancing on it at the airport.
Speaker 0: It was like a cross between Sir's car is waiting and oh my god geeks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only thing about that sign is I don't think I was had any pants in that depiction.
Speaker 0: Most definitely did not have any pants on that poster.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's not so good.
Speaker 0: That was fantastic.
Speaker 1: Room likes you with no pants.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: So yeah, you know little details.
Speaker 0: We stayed at the red line because red lion sounded like some sort of communist awesome and I couldn't pass that up.
Speaker 1: Is that really why you picked it?
Speaker 0: That's pretty much the only real.
Speaker 0: All right, basically, you know I don't know the West Coast.
Speaker 0: I go to the PAX website.
Speaker 0: They're like these are the hotels.
Speaker 0: I'm like, uh Google Maps, where are they?
Speaker 0: and the red line?
Speaker 0: one red line that that was one point two free internet.
Speaker 0: So, all right wet line, whatever.
Speaker 0: I don't even know where it was But it worked out.
Speaker 1: I would have I would have picked one with a you know A brand name just to be know that it was quality.
Speaker 1: who knows red line could have been anything.
Speaker 0: I I went on a hunch and I was right.
Speaker 0: The red line was awesome All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know, we just went to bed.
Speaker 0: what we got in it?
Speaker 1: like 1 a.m And the next day it was time for packs.
Speaker 1: We woke up packs time.
Speaker 1: Nope.
Speaker 1: We had reverse jet lag So we were ready to go but packs didn't start until 2 p.m.
Speaker 1: On Friday p.m 2 p.m.
Speaker 0: Oticon starts at like 9 on Friday.
Speaker 0: I didn't know what to do.
Speaker 1: I mean every convention on the East Coast every anime convention at least that has a Friday.
Speaker 1: The Friday is a full day The Saturday is a full day and the Sunday is just starts early but just ends a little early.
Speaker 1: so everyone can go home Friday starting at 2 p.m What the fuck?
Speaker 1: I mean that's too early for people to be home from work yet But it's still way late.
Speaker 1: You wasted the whole morning.
Speaker 1: I don't get it.
Speaker 0: So, of course wake up and I did something I've never done at nanomek on before one got a real breakfast Time.
Speaker 1: we had to kill before - so we were wandering out eaten Looking at stuff talking to people walking around looking around figuring our way around thing Discovering the.
Speaker 0: Seattle is a strange and foreign place where no one jaywalks, but us.
Speaker 1: it's basically a big shopping mall almost.
Speaker 0: But the one thing I can say is that walking around Seattle at like 10 a.m Now packs, you know The attendees of packs are not like the attendees of other accounts we go to.
Speaker 0: and yet at the same time You could point out with like a 95 percent accuracy 99 whether or not a person.
Speaker 0: well Some of the people we saw were just hipsters.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: who happened to live in Seattle?
Speaker 0: One of them was a hobo who happened to be hipster.
Speaker 0: ish, but pretty much everyone else who was like, that's a packs, dude That's a packs girl.
Speaker 0: Those people are all totally packs people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is even like later on after packs is over you could still tell from the remaining people in town Who is someone left over from packs and who wasn't?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we're wandering around Seattle.
Speaker 0: We got like a half mile from the convention center like the wrong direction, you know bomb the wrong place.
Speaker 0: and yet There were packs people everywhere.
Speaker 0: The city was diffused with packs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the packs who pretty much owned the town for three days.
Speaker 0: So, you know, we're walking around and we're thinking all right Are people gonna line up like what's the registration status?
Speaker 0: I mean, I know they may allow badges to people who pre-register but something that other conventions seem to worry a lot about.
Speaker 0: So how many people get mean like how many people could have possibly pre-registered?
Speaker 0: What's the?
Speaker 0: what's the deal?
Speaker 0: What's the line gonna be like?
Speaker 0: let's go to the convention center early.
Speaker 1: So we go to the convention center pretty early all mostly because we want to check out our VIP badge situation.
Speaker 0: yes, cuz actually it was cool that you know packs treated us as professionally as Professional for-profit money cons treat us.
Speaker 0: they were like to get your badges.
Speaker 0: go to the VIP booth on the fourth floor.
Speaker 1: We walked in and we met this.
Speaker 1: We bumped into a bunch of enforcers right away and they were awesome and they helped us.
Speaker 0: They hooked us up right away in stark Contrast to most other conventions.
Speaker 0: we walk in and we see an enforcer and they're blocked and basically there's a bunch of enforcers stand at The elevator escalator not letting anyone who doesn't have a badge go up there and we're like Okay, VIP badges and the guy doesn't say you gotta ask so-and-so and point like most cons do.
Speaker 1: the guy says oh I'll walk you over there Yep, and there are two other enforcers that were still there.
Speaker 1: So nothing was getting understaffed.
Speaker 1: It was all good and the line was like one dude.
Speaker 0: There was one dude in front of us in this line And I noticed that next to us is the normal reg line and there were maybe ten people in that line.
Speaker 1: That line empty was.
Speaker 1: basically the normal reg line was empty Totally empty because everyone got their badges mailed to them in advance.
Speaker 0: There was no one there and yet the people who were there it was like walk-up badge walk-up badge walk-up badge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean there was a will call and the will call had a little bit of a line But it's basically one booth the will call booth and the line was no bigger than the line.
Speaker 1: You'll see it like the movie theater.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now I don't want to talk a lot about us and our BS but no we had our guest panelists like special Whatever badges, but what we didn't bother with like, you know to come we had the panelist thing And we also had the press thing and all those things.
Speaker 0: I learned something really cool.
Speaker 0: Pax had like 500 media badges.
Speaker 0: they gave out, you know, press Media badges got you nothing.
Speaker 0: In fact, our special badge got us nothing either.
Speaker 0: So the Kotaku get like all the press.
Speaker 0: people for the most part did not get anything over a dude with a three-day badge.
Speaker 1: I think I read somewhere on Kotaku that like only one of them actually got like a yellow badge and everyone else got normal Badges of all people.
Speaker 0: the way Pax does it is pretty much the press get comped badges But that's all they get and they have.
Speaker 1: I don't even know if they got comped badges They might have I don't know.
Speaker 0: Well, some of the press I talked to said that they got comped badges.
Speaker 0: All right, because the comp badges didn't get you anything.
Speaker 0: But uh, you know and I got a backtrack a little bit when we're walking toward the convention center Which is like this giant glass edifice and also walking toward the convention center There was like this row of Pax banners in the street leading up to it.
Speaker 1: You know how the streets will hang like, you know These banners and all this on all the lights on the street to sort of oh my god.
Speaker 0: film festival.
Speaker 0: or please pretend our city's Awesome, right?
Speaker 1: They had a bunch of.
Speaker 0: they said Pax and they were all over the place and It really made me know like I was part of something.
Speaker 1: What other convention have I ever been to that was big enough to have those?
Speaker 1: Otakon doesn't even have those in the Baltimore City.
Speaker 0: Otakon had like a sign outside once and that was it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but sorry.
Speaker 0: and then we're walking toward the convention center thinking All right Let's see what kind of line there is.
Speaker 0: and I see this like kind of big line of people outside the convention center And I'm like, oh, I guess there is a red line, huh?
Speaker 0: No, that was the line for the stupid crepes.
Speaker 0: There was this crepe place outside the convention traps.
Speaker 1: All right that the old.
Speaker 1: there's a crepe place in the Atlantic City one of them.
Speaker 1: Right, it's all right.
Speaker 1: They're like four crepe different crepe places.
Speaker 1: I saw in Seattle.
Speaker 1: crepes are mad popular there and the place outside of the convention center directly attached to it was crepe voila and They had a line the entire convention.
Speaker 1: people could have just walked down to the other crepe place in The the food court of the mall got in a crepe and been back faster than waiting in that line.
Speaker 0: But not only is that like the line never ended.
Speaker 0: like every time I enter or leave the convention center I see this giant line there.
Speaker 0: But right next to them were these punk kids with a bunch of gameboys network together with cables and a bunch of speakers and amps Playing music and dancing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, chip to street performance of chip tunes pretty good.
Speaker 0: It was pretty badass and the music was pretty good.
Speaker 0: I gotta say it really I felt that bionic commando kind of vibe going.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they definitely had some nice effects.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but alright, so, you know enforcers badges we got our little con bag and of course, what do we do?
Speaker 0: We try to wander around as kind of like in a Zelda game where as soon as you get an item You wander around as far as that item will take you getting it as far as you can in every direction Before you start solving all the puzzles to get the next item, right?
Speaker 1: So it was nowhere near two o'clock.
Speaker 1: So basically the nothing in the con was open.
Speaker 1: We couldn't go anywhere.
Speaker 1: He couldn't go in the annex where the tabletop action was.
Speaker 1: He couldn't go in the expo room.
Speaker 1: We could I think wait in line to get into the con which I didn't really want to do at all You know.
Speaker 0: So so we went up the escalators as far as we could go to this like top floor where apparently there was some Pegs didn't even have the whole convention center.
Speaker 0: The top floor had this gender Odyssey conference.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was sort of freaky.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it won't freaky because packs really needed that space.
Speaker 0: I mean there were like 58,000 people there.
Speaker 0: That's like two Oda cons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some of the panel rooms that packs are effectively in the hallways.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, you know we go all the way up there and we bust out the bag.
Speaker 0: now the con bag.
Speaker 0: the con swag Had a lot of stuff in it Which made me remember Realize that the anime industry at least is not doing so well because you don't get so much in those bags anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Oh - con like oh - oh three maybe oh four.
Speaker 1: that con bag was full of stuff loaded.
Speaker 1: now It's like an empty barren wasteland.
Speaker 1: The packs bag was loaded with shit.
Speaker 1: I have all the shit right here.
Speaker 0: It was like overflowing with shit.
Speaker 1: Most of it is just like, you know, freaking flyers advertising stuff.
Speaker 1: But there were a few good things in there.
Speaker 1: First of all, you got a precipice of darkness demo disc.
Speaker 1: I already bought that game.
Speaker 1: So I didn't do demo disc but other people do.
Speaker 0: yeah I don't want to talk about all the ads in it But I got to say the little kind of thing talking about fallout 3.
Speaker 0: I really like the graphic design of this thing.
Speaker 1: That's the only ad worth mentioning was the fallout 3 card because it's like hey Saturday at 2 30 the main theater come see the demo and on the other side it says come to booth seat 632 and Fallout 3 was all over this convention.
Speaker 1: Yeah more on that later.
Speaker 1: Yes So also in the bag World of Warcraft trial edition, we don't have enough of those.
Speaker 0: All right Well, I think we have four.
Speaker 1: Yeah one up Network Temporary tattoos.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, there were a lot of temporary tattoos too, but more on that later.
Speaker 1: Yep There was a PAX 10 audience choice award ballot.
Speaker 1: now the PAX 10 Which is basically they pick 10 independent games and there's an area in the expo room where you can play them all and then You vote on which one you like by punching a hole and then you put it in the ballot box at that booth in the expo room Exhibition room or whatever and you vote on which one you like the most.
Speaker 1: and I think the winner Winners will be announced at the pack site after the show.
Speaker 1: So speaking of the participatory stuff, which is a word rim cannot pronounce They had this DTS thing.
Speaker 1: you might have heard about this before.
Speaker 1: basically the way this works distributed tournament system.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: the way this works is in your bag You get this there's a little ziplock baggie a tiny one the kind that you might store.
Speaker 1: You know pieces of a board game in and there's a slip of paper and two buttons pins if you will tiny circular ones that have a PAX logo on them and You put these pins on you.
Speaker 1: and when you put the pins on that means I am accepting challenges.
Speaker 1: If you see someone else with pins and you are also wearing pins you get two of these to start with.
Speaker 1: You can challenge them now.
Speaker 0: It pretty much says challenge anyone to any game for one badge, right?
Speaker 1: So you challenge someone to something.
Speaker 1: so I say rim.
Speaker 1: We actually mean rim had a challenge.
Speaker 1: the challenge was who will first see the red dragon t-shirt?
Speaker 1: See it you win.
Speaker 0: if you don't know what we're talking about it's Iconic of D&D nerds.
Speaker 0: It is that red dragon t-shirt.
Speaker 0: I did not see a single person with it and good God Did I look.
Speaker 1: I looked really hard because I wanted to win.
Speaker 1: I saved one of these pins the whole time just to try to win.
Speaker 0: now The idea is that you know someone at the end of the con is gonna have a bag full of these things.
Speaker 0: Right me a lot of people are gonna ignore it.
Speaker 1: You know a lot of people are gonna play.
Speaker 1: some people are gonna pull together with all their friends.
Speaker 0: I saw a dude wearing like a vest and he had like 60 of those things just pinned to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you just go around challenging people.
Speaker 1: now the people can refuse your challenge, you know.
Speaker 1: So if rim says Scott, let's play carcass own for one pin I could say no, but then I'm also losing cuz I'm also missing out on the chance to win rims badge.
Speaker 1: You know if someone challenges you and you accept you might get one from them instead of giving one to them.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 0: one We realize two things.
Speaker 0: I wanted to walk around just like Challenging people to like parkour or arm wrestling or punch for punch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and two We totally could have been griefers and go around and find the people who are really trying to win it and challenge them to A game that they don't realize will take forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean games that take a long time are really gonna hurt you if you're trying to win this You know because basically the idea is to get lots of them in this 50.
Speaker 1: There's like a hundred thousand of these buttons to get.
Speaker 1: so if the con really did have 50,000 attendees like they say they do But this I just think this was a really cool.
Speaker 0: I mean I've seen similar things like it at other gaming cons before but Pax was really.
Speaker 0: you could see the spirit of this with people throwing down challenges left and right.
Speaker 1: Yep, generally what happened was anyone anytime people played a game somewhere and they thought of it They did it, you know, like people would play a board game and they say hey, you know what?
Speaker 0: Whoever wins gets everyone else's pin, but I did see a few people walking around like challenging people openly and like just violently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean the top 25 players won prizes, let's talk about the prizes at PAX.
Speaker 0: Yes, they had much like most gaming cons a prize room with some enforcers sitting there and they had just you know All the prizes you can win.
Speaker 1: Yep And this room was like behind a little window and like a coat check area and good god Did they have some sweet prizes back there?
Speaker 1: Sweet prizes.
Speaker 0: Yes I was not willing to try to win any of them partly because I did not have room in my luggage.
Speaker 1: The way to win the prizes was to do some sort of you know Win tournaments or DTS or any.
Speaker 1: there was ways to win prize all around but I didn't win any of them.
Speaker 1: But if I if I wasn't actually doing stuff at the con, you know And I wasn't interested in a lot of the events.
Speaker 1: Maybe I would have sat around and tried to win tournaments.
Speaker 1: I mean, I know I would have done the Puerto Rico tournament if I was if it wasn't during our panel.
Speaker 0: Oh my god the Puerto Rico tournament.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right, two other things were in the bag of note.
Speaker 1: There was this VB Magazine, it's not and really I didn't look at it yet.
Speaker 1: It's not a really interesting magazine.
Speaker 0: through it had some articles.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what was interesting about it?
Speaker 1: It was basically they made a magazine for the San Diego Comic Con and PAX 2008 bags.
Speaker 1: this magazine was only available at those two places.
Speaker 1: brilliant I thought that was pretty interesting.
Speaker 1: and of course the con book.
Speaker 0: now the con book.
Speaker 0: I was taking it back You know, I'm used to Normal gaming cons which basically have a schedule full of an infinite number of small events or an anime con Which is you know, a million panels back-to-back all over the place.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much, you know us of relatively small number of Relatively high powered panels with like half-hour setup gaps between them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so here's here's what's in the con book for packs.
Speaker 1: Welcome the packs.
Speaker 1: Rules of packs.
Speaker 0: the rules of packs are pretty good.
Speaker 0: You should read them.
Speaker 1: Yeah the X. Oh you want me to read them right now?
Speaker 0: I think we should.
Speaker 1: okay the seven rules of packs Except for the long speak which are not gonna read ready I don't want to get into it.
Speaker 0: But basically the rules of packs and the way they were followed and the way the con played out Says a lot about the kind of convention it was.
Speaker 0: now I'm gonna talk about that more in another show later.
Speaker 1: seven rules of packs ready.
Speaker 1: drugs are bad.
Speaker 1: Don't steal Don't punch or kick people.
Speaker 1: No cheating.
Speaker 1: Don't harass anyone.
Speaker 1: Don't spray paint on stuff.
Speaker 1: Don't mess with things that aren't yours.
Speaker 0: now I don't think I saw anyone cause a problem in the entirety of this convention.
Speaker 1: No, it was amazing.
Speaker 1: Absolutely amazing.
Speaker 1: All right DTS.
Speaker 1: there were the explanation of the pins.
Speaker 1: I just gave you beginners guide to packs Friday schedule.
Speaker 1: Saturday schedule.
Speaker 1: Sunday schedule.
Speaker 1: Friday.
Speaker 1: Saturday.
Speaker 1: Sunday panel descriptions Omegathon description fact Wizards of the coast.
Speaker 0: schedule is ads of the coast and the packs 10 and that is the whole book.
Speaker 1: Other half of it is ads and there's a note page on the back.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's right.
Speaker 1: There's a map in the middle.
Speaker 1: There's a map of the exhibition room and There's a tear-out map of the Convention Center, but you know that aside You know, what can I say about the con book?
Speaker 0: It was everything it needed to be.
Speaker 0: I had no complaints about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know, we still got nothing to do.
Speaker 0: There's hours before the con starts.
Speaker 0: So we notice a Cisco router Basically a link sis router powered by Cisco.
Speaker 1: I took a picture of it.
Speaker 1: You see it in my flicker.
Speaker 0: It is iconic of something.
Speaker 0: It was.
Speaker 0: it was sad and yet at the same time it reeked of that kind of duct tape ingenuity common to all geeks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean Cisco.
Speaker 1: Well, you know Cisco at least sponsored a wireless network that they supposedly set up.
Speaker 0: Hey, there's no way they set it up because while they must have I mean they probably paid for it and provided the equipment.
Speaker 0: But in terms of wireless signal strength in area, they did not set it up well.
Speaker 0: That's that's one of my few complaints about the kind of wireless was mostly poop and it was actually really strong signal.
Speaker 0: But the signals overlapped and interfered with each other.
Speaker 1: but I'm pretty sure this is a case of Cisco providing equipment and sponsorship and then Non-professional, I believe that Cisco set up that thing that Scott took a picture of.
Speaker 1: Not at all, it definitely looks like an enforcer job.
Speaker 1: not to insult the enforcer.
Speaker 0: Yes, cuz that was totally awesome.
Speaker 1: It's not an insult to the enforcers to say that they're not technology professional.
Speaker 0: Let me say this uber con had almost the exact same wireless setup.
Speaker 0: The only reason uber cons worked is that there was only one of them.
Speaker 0: but anyway aside from that we still had nothing to do.
Speaker 0: so we watered over to the Handheld gaming lounges aka the DS lounge.
Speaker 1: There's not much to do but you know and technically the DS lounges which there are three of didn't open until the con started.
Speaker 1: But the convention center was actually the big open area.
Speaker 1: It's not like Otacon.
Speaker 1: We are locked out of the building.
Speaker 1: It's this convention center had like restaurants in it and businesses and it's a place that you can go.
Speaker 0: point of note Ro told us and other people also independently told us that the pizza place in the convention center is terrible and not to eat there.
Speaker 1: We saw a lot of people eating there.
Speaker 0: Yes, none of them looked happy.
Speaker 0: He ate plenty of other places But there oh my god that burrito place that was like super cheap and pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was alright.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got a good smoothie there smoothie.
Speaker 0: I can actually finish which is rare Yeah, but you know what we decided.
Speaker 0: what are we gonna do?
Speaker 0: We go up there and the way they did these DS lounges and I say DS cuz it was 90%.
Speaker 1: yes, I mean there was.
Speaker 1: the funniest part was you look at the schedule is oh my god They nominally had schedules for the DS lounges.
Speaker 1: I mean really they weren't super scheduled.
Speaker 1: I mean they didn't go around enforcing it, but it's basically like hey We'll put the schedule up and then maybe if someone really wants to play Mario Kart They'll show up at the Mario Kart time and their chances of getting a Mario Kart game going on will be better than otherwise.
Speaker 0: It was basically like 9 a.m.
Speaker 0: To 10 a.m.
Speaker 0: Mario Kart DS Bomberman DS blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: 10 a.m.
Speaker 0: To 11 a.m Pie cross D like all the different DS games and then be like 1 to 1 30 PSP time.
Speaker 1: That that I don't know.
Speaker 1: that tells you about the PSP.
Speaker 1: I think it tells you that the multiplayer the local wireless multiplayer for the PSP is weak.
Speaker 0: The thing is though there were.
Speaker 0: I mean not to discard because the PSP is a despite all expectations.
Speaker 0: the PSP gets a lot of credit for being a valid and Successful second place and there are good games on it, and it's a great Single-player console, and it does have some pretty good multiplayer games.
Speaker 0: Just it doesn't have the pickup game appeal of the DS.
Speaker 0: I mean I saw people playing Bomberman every time I walked by that lounge for the entire con Yep, but the important thing is these sumo bags.
Speaker 0: I might have seen him, so we're not it.
Speaker 1: We're not a big fan of bean bags here.
Speaker 1: I mean they're not that comfortable and they they always.
Speaker 1: they make you look like you know a poor college dude 70s dude.
Speaker 0: bean bags are one of those things like communism.
Speaker 0: that is awesome in theory not so great in implementation.
Speaker 1: They're usually real mushy, and you just sort of sink into them And you might as well be sitting on the floor.
Speaker 0: then they're kind of plastics you get all sweaty or their canvas Then they get stained.
Speaker 0: and bean bags are never the sign of a classy joint.
Speaker 1: That's why we only got banana chairs.
Speaker 1: You know they're much classier.
Speaker 1: I mean they're not perfect, but they're much better than bean bags, so Sumo Sponsored I guess packs by providing many many of their you know bean bags.
Speaker 0: Don't you say many many?
Speaker 0: I don't think you understand how many of them there were.
Speaker 0: they were everywhere.
Speaker 0: there were like a Hundred of them in the DS lounges.
Speaker 0: Oh by the way I say lounges because there were like three DSA B and C on three different floors connected by an escalator.
Speaker 1: well two of them were over on that's.
Speaker 1: B and C were over there.
Speaker 1: a Closer to the was on the floor with the console free plays and the rock band.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I didn't really spend a lot of time over by a.
Speaker 1: so no it was mostly above a because people in a sucked.
Speaker 0: But anyway, that's right so that these sumos are basically a bean bag plus technology.
Speaker 1: It's a bean bag right and it's filled with these foam balls and the whole con.
Speaker 1: only one of the bags opened up and spilled balls everywhere And it didn't smell too many of them And it's really packed pretty tightly not like a bean bag with lots of air.
Speaker 1: You know it's.
Speaker 1: it's packed pretty tight And it's got this really really good sort of plastic canvas II material that it's made of.
Speaker 1: it's not made of like you know What a bean bags made of which is basically the cheapest possible stuff.
Speaker 1: sewn together it is serious business.
Speaker 0: analogy I would use is like my air on chair where it's so it's a substance or off.
Speaker 0: the way It works is it's comfortable and yet it doesn't seem to stain and it doesn't like.
Speaker 0: it lets my sweat through and it was like a good substance.
Speaker 0: and Again, I don't think you understand how many of them were where there were I saw at one point an enforcer who had made A pyramid almost as tall as I was and was like asleep on top of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're really.
Speaker 1: I mean if you think one of these is comfortable because one alone not by itself is real comfortable.
Speaker 1: I want to have a house Configuration right but getting multiple of them on top of each other.
Speaker 1: I didn't want to move.
Speaker 0: you could turn these things into like couches but basically when you went into these DS lounges you would see a Whole ton of people like cuddling or just laying next to each other and all these crazy Configurations like all over the place it was.
Speaker 0: it was quite a sight to behold I see even without the gaming.
Speaker 1: It was really great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and a lot of people were just chillin.
Speaker 0: They're kind of playing single-player DS games.
Speaker 0: They were doing the kind of the thing kids do where you put like two four-year-olds together.
Speaker 0: They don't play with each other, but they play separate things next to each other.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a lot of that going on.
Speaker 0: I spent a good amount of time kind of chillin.
Speaker 0: They're like recouping between things.
Speaker 0: on Saturday I fell asleep there for like 20 minutes by accident.
Speaker 1: But yeah, generally, you know We were treated there quite a few times and so did everyone else at the car.
Speaker 1: These things were pretty much always full except for the rare occasion when there would only be you know And things are really busy elsewhere at the car there my oh, yeah, and they had power strips Everywhere and two.
Speaker 0: you could borrow Rechargers for PSP's and DS's.
Speaker 1: yes, so for once it wasn't taboo to lose your battery.
Speaker 1: You know a run out of battery.
Speaker 0: they can charge you up and then a lot of people were using them the enforcers running it We're like, oh my god, the enforcers running these things were like so on top of their game.
Speaker 1: Yep So the one thing I learned is after the con I went to the sumo website to see what the deal with these things were.
Speaker 0: pretty much I was thinking after laying on these Oh my god When we got a house we're gonna get like 10 of these and sip in the closet and every time the visigoths come out We're filling the basement with them.
Speaker 1: There are the cheapest one which the ones they had at PAX were the cheapest model.
Speaker 1: They have other models that are bigger and different but the cheap model is the one I want really.
Speaker 1: the other ones are not Really what you want.
Speaker 0: they are.
Speaker 0: they try $150 each.
Speaker 1: there were thousands of dollars worth of sumos all over.
Speaker 1: if they if I would have known they were so expensive I would have stolen them.
Speaker 0: $150 a beanbag is like 40 bucks.
Speaker 1: I guess that's why the price is Related to the quality.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as much as I want what I don't think I'm gonna buy one I might cuz they're.
Speaker 1: the thing is the banana chairs aren't really doing it for me anymore living room.
Speaker 0: And the problem is like having wanted be nice But the dream would be to have a whole bunch of them for when people come over.
Speaker 1: Yeah, having a whole bunch would definitely be way more awesome than having just like a couple.
Speaker 0: but then again, you know I thought I was looking for furniture and a nice couch is like $1,200.
Speaker 0: that's true.
Speaker 0: divide that by sumos.
Speaker 0: It's not that bad for a geek Of course that of course you'd want a couch and the sumos.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's rough couch upstairs sumos in the basement.
Speaker 0: I guess that could work kind of like a mullet, you know house upstairs stigmata of geekery in the basement.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right.
Speaker 0: All right, we get our before we.
Speaker 0: I got to talk about this because again the con has not started yet Right.
Speaker 1: So the con has this main events room, which is the biggest room.
Speaker 1: It's where the concerts are and all the major events are and next to it is the lineup room.
Speaker 1: the lineup room Allows you as entrances both into the main events room and also to the exhibition hall.
Speaker 1: It's in between both.
Speaker 1: so they use it for a lineup to me every main event.
Speaker 1: They also use it for lineup to the expo room in the mornings when it opens up.
Speaker 0: So, all right We're not gonna you know Wait in line for anything and there's a lot of people in that room and there.
Speaker 0: the line culture at PAX was great.
Speaker 0: People were like bopping beach balls and balloons around and playing DS games and yelling and screaming.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in addition to that there was the cookie brigade at every line, which I'm sure you've heard about by now.
Speaker 1: But basically people baked cookies.
Speaker 1: they brought them the packs.
Speaker 1: They sold them to people in line mostly but also out of line.
Speaker 0: They sold like five thousand dollars worth of cookies.
Speaker 1: It was a dollar for a cookie.
Speaker 1: They sold five thousand dollars of the cookies.
Speaker 1: That means someone.
Speaker 1: they baked together at least five thousand cookies.
Speaker 0: I bought four of those cookies I bought one I bought four at once I ate them all in less time than it took to buy them and then all the money went to the child's play.
Speaker 0: I can't complain about that.
Speaker 1: No, it's pretty crazy Yeah, so since it was a big line to get into the expo room right away the exhibition hall right away and made the big Events, you know the the keynote speech and the Q&A we gave in taiko, right?
Speaker 1: Wasn't?
Speaker 1: for a little while We started off our con going into the annex which we couldn't get into until 2. so 2 o'clock went to the annex.
Speaker 1: the annex Basically had the bottom floor of the annex was the Wizards of the coast floor We zads of the coast.
Speaker 0: the second part on the bottom floor Basically the whip the watch the area you could do watch the crab.
Speaker 0: They had a spot where they could.
Speaker 0: they were tricking peep.
Speaker 0: They were trying to get people to sign up to be game testers for them And then they had a giant beholder and a bunch of standees with faces cut out of them So you could put your face behind it like at a carnival.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those are first pictures of rib.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, there's pictures of me in a non.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, check out my flicker you can see all.
Speaker 0: yeah go to Scott's flicker this stuff there.
Speaker 1: No, I didn't take that many pictures, but I took pictures of that.
Speaker 0: We picked into the whiz ads all of the coast area and it was just whiz ads of the coast.
Speaker 0: Yep There was a card economy.
Speaker 1: There's a tabletop floor, which we had, you know So many tables in such a great configuration and then they had you know a place you could check out board games.
Speaker 1: They had a great selection, but the selection was not as good as say the kinetic on selection.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now we there was a third floor that for whatever reason at this point.
Speaker 0: We didn't actually go up there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the third floor had the serpent theater the fourth panel room.
Speaker 1: It also had the mystery space and another space with a lot more tables for more gaming in case the second floor filled up.
Speaker 0: But we didn't.
Speaker 0: we didn't even look like.
Speaker 0: we didn't know it was out there.
Speaker 0: We didn't go up there.
Speaker 0: We just kind of got distracted by stuff.
Speaker 0: So we hung out in the tabletop area.
Speaker 1: and what did we?
Speaker 1: how do we kick off the packs the greatest game?
Speaker 1: We didn't even get off to the start of the connection.
Speaker 1: starting now people How did we kick off this amazing con?
Speaker 0: by playing pretty much one of the best board games ever made?
Speaker 1: Tiggers and Euphrates.
Speaker 0: not only that but we played it with Ro You know awesome forumite who met us and Erin other awesome forumite who not only met us at the con It was totally cool and came from Canada, but brought us chocolate from Canada.
Speaker 0: I think she worked at the chocolate factory thus a Confluence of events that provided chocolate in my stomach and Tiggers and Euphrates in my hands And it was a pretty damn good game of Tiggers and Euphrates.
Speaker 0: I won by like a million points.
Speaker 1: Anyway at that moment at that game of T&E we realized there was a Puerto Rico tournament that conflicted with our panel.
Speaker 0: could go a Puerto Rico tournament.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Could we have won?
Speaker 0: Well, could I have won that?
Speaker 1: There's a Carcassonne tournament that conflicted with the keynote and Q&A panel.
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: should be fair because Scott and I probably had Completely equal chances of winning the Puerto Rico tournament and we probably would have spoiled to try to make one of us or the other win, I Think I could have won that Carcassonne tournament Handily, and I think if I had not been in it Scott could have handily won that Carcassonne tournament.
Speaker 1: But we didn't do those things.
Speaker 1: They conflicted with other things.
Speaker 1: I would have liked to though.
Speaker 1: Instead after our game of T&E we went to the keynote and then immediately following the keynote was the Gabe and Tycho Or Jerry and Mike Q&A panel number one.
Speaker 1: so Not as in they had a second Q&A panel on Saturday, which we didn't go to now.
Speaker 0: at this point We've resigned ourselves to doing the main events.
Speaker 0: I mean the big things at this con were the keynote which is basically the opening ceremonies and then The Q&A and our plan was alright, let's see the keynote because Ken LaVon if you don't know He's the guy, you know, he was the guy behind like System Shock 2 and Bioshock
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty important gaming guy Yeah,
Speaker 0: and he has a pretty cool story.
Speaker 0: and also how many cons out there have keynotes let alone industry awesome keynotes.
Speaker 1: I definitely think you know other conventions, you know, they Even if they have keynotes, that's usually a more businessy convention as a keynote, you know.
Speaker 1: And a lot of other cons they have like boring opening ceremonies.
Speaker 1: I think I just everyone should do a keynote for the opening ceremonies with an important related in person And I just think that's the way to go because it gets people to come against people to care gets people excited.
Speaker 1: It gets people inspired and ready in the right frame of mind for the rest of the event.
Speaker 1: Doing the lame opening ceremonies like every other convention does.
Speaker 0: it's kind of Blair and I got to say mr Levine did a really damn good keynote.
Speaker 0: Basically.
Speaker 0: It was in the sort of TED talk style.
Speaker 0: you know those TED talks are pretty much the small number of Very like relevant very insightful like super good slides But they're kind of the backdrop to the awesome narrative that weaves them all together the kind of talk talk talk talk talk talk talk slide and the crowd goes.
Speaker 0: ah Or he whatever slide comes out, you know, he talked about.
Speaker 0: he gives this really good life story about you know being a nerd being like this super nerdy Jewish kid when no one else around him was nerdy as a kid and being awkward and Getting into gaming and getting into D&D and getting into comic books.
Speaker 0: and he talked a lot about Logan's run And actually the whole date he did about Logan's run was really really good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only thing is you could tell this guy is a writer, right?
Speaker 1: He's talking about.
Speaker 1: he was a Hollywood screenwriter and stuff and his presentation was super well-written.
Speaker 1: But his public speaking skills were not the most amazing But his writing carried him through and he didn't have a lot of good things to say.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I just say that I mean if we're talking to your public speaking skills.
Speaker 0: He pulled it off 90%.
Speaker 0: He did a really good talk.
Speaker 0: It was just I think what it was.
Speaker 0: I think he was a little nervous.
Speaker 0: It could be especially, you know his whole life story.
Speaker 1: The thing is he was obviously reading it all off a piece of paper.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what most people do but you know a lot of it.
Speaker 0: He had a lot of asides and yeah, it was.
Speaker 0: it was a really good talk And I wouldn't really say that it was poorly presented.
Speaker 0: I think it was excellently presented.
Speaker 0: I think he was just a little bit nervous because the crowd that was watching him was frighteningly large.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much because it is the biggest room at the con and it was spelled to capacity.
Speaker 0: So I'll say this if nothing else if you ever go to a PAX, but you should be going to a PAX Oh my god Go to the keynote.
Speaker 1: Oh my god Go you did not go to the keynote every single time.
Speaker 0: Well, the funny thing is he brought up Logan's run and then he brought up the old comic book Logan's run I didn't know existed and he talked a lot about like how the internet changed everything.
Speaker 1: I remember the New York Comic Con.
Speaker 1: you can go bin diving for the Logan's run gun.
Speaker 0: Oh my god I kind of want to own it and then get him to sign it.
Speaker 0: But anyway Logan's run kind of became a running theme because it came up a couple more times this weekend.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was kind of weird.
Speaker 0: But uh, you know that ended and we were like, alright, let's stick around for whatever this Q&A is we'll probably walk out early because you know, I I expected this Q&A with the penny arcade Persons to be like any other convention Q&A totally lay.
Speaker 1: So first of all, you got to realize right?
Speaker 1: They didn't have another lineup for this.
Speaker 1: It was that lineup for the keynote in the line room was for the keynote directly followed by the Q&A Directly followed by the roosterteeth panel, which are the red versus blue guys.
Speaker 1: A lot of people didn't stay for that including us.
Speaker 1: We didn't need to see them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like half the crowd walked out that they're no good.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: I really wasn't interested in seeing their panel.
Speaker 1: So I walked out.
Speaker 0: well what someone said?
Speaker 0: that I felt bad But at the same time it felt sound like it was kind of justified.
Speaker 0: I overheard the words Oh red verse blue.
Speaker 0: That's so O'Byrne Total burn.
Speaker 0: I felt kind of bad hearing that though because someday someone's gonna be like geek nights.
Speaker 0: That's so.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so the Q&A now This was basically the keynote.
Speaker 0: the Q&A was not just a Q&A.
Speaker 0: It was the opening ceremonies.
Speaker 0: now The house lights go down the stage lights go down The super professional like a light show at the front begins.
Speaker 0: It was as if a rock star is about to appear not just a small-time rock star.
Speaker 0: I'm talking like a big rock star like the biggest rock star.
Speaker 0: the music starts playing.
Speaker 1: Remember, this is the concert stage.
Speaker 1: they had this full concert stage set up with everything and They use that for every main event.
Speaker 1: If you've got it might as well use it.
Speaker 1: Why would you hold it back?
Speaker 0: You know, the lights are going crazy.
Speaker 0: the smoke machine starts the music is building up to a crescendo and then two spotlights from crosswise come down on the two sides and Gabe and Tycho of penny arcade walk.
Speaker 1: Oh, you've got it wrong.
Speaker 1: You've got it.
Speaker 1: Totally wrong.
Speaker 0: Do I?
Speaker 1: Yes the curtain opens Revealing an orchestra.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes.
Speaker 0: You see this was so classy.
Speaker 0: This was classy and epic times a thousand.
Speaker 0: a freaking orchestra Starts playing.
Speaker 1: it wasn't a full orchestra like, you know, bros and rosa people, but it was you know No, they had a small section You know, there was some violins some flutes and some little horns and some you know, timpani actions.
Speaker 1: It was a conductor the whole thing.
Speaker 0: and to all this they walk out Tycho adorned in a cape and It is one of the few times in my life outside of a Renaissance Festival.
Speaker 0: I've seen someone wear a cape Non-ironically and pull it the fuck off And that was a scary cave - that wasn't like.
Speaker 1: that was like.
Speaker 1: that wasn't like one of those capes a larper wears.
Speaker 1: It was a nerd cape like a really nerdy game red on the inside with circular flappy things and man Is it nerd?
Speaker 0: I need to point out dude pulled it off.
Speaker 1: It was like it was a basically the in the world of capes if capes for hats.
Speaker 1: It was a beanie I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think I would call it the topest of top hat Because the way he carried it and the way it I don't think anyone could ever pull off wearing that cape but him.
Speaker 1: You definitely need a bald head to wear that cape.
Speaker 0: so They come out.
Speaker 0: and this is when if anyone you know didn't realize That that these two gentlemen are basically video game rock stars Even though they seem to not want to be or not admit they are but they are.
Speaker 1: they're rock stars At least at their own convention.
Speaker 0: the spectacle and the crowd was amazing.
Speaker 0: and then they start talking and it's amazing.
Speaker 0: And then they get right into the Q&A.
Speaker 0: they basically had a stud and up.
Speaker 0: this says something about packs Basically into the two main aisles and quite a bit back.
Speaker 0: They had two unattended and unguarded microphones.
Speaker 1: Danger will Robinson danger.
Speaker 0: Oh my god It would at any other con would that have spelled baba booey baba booey Howard Stern's penis disaster, right?
Speaker 1: I mean someone just gets up there says a bunch of stupid shit.
Speaker 1: You need an enforcer to run all the way over to the microphone to stop them.
Speaker 0: You know, I mean if I was running a con I would have enforcers at the microphone with like a taser Exactly, but no they basically say alright if you have questions, there are microphones and people line up and No One really asked a stupid question.
Speaker 0: It was kind of scary.
Speaker 1: I mean there were some people who were saying things that were a little you know Yeah, we're a little lab but most of it was you know, people ask, you know, what asked?
Speaker 0: stupid crap, you know, like dude You know and no one was like scary like some anime cons.
Speaker 0: You're up there some gaming cons.
Speaker 0: if there's a Q&A like this and there's the dude who asked like the really scary Question everyone the crowd is like really uncomfortable.
Speaker 0: That didn't happen.
Speaker 0: one girl was dressed up as a tentacle monster and she just walked up there and went rawr Yeah, I think she walked away.
Speaker 1: I think she's is really nervous and couldn't say anything.
Speaker 1: but or she was doing a performance piece as they suggested.
Speaker 0: But the thing is it wasn't just like.
Speaker 0: question then answer.
Speaker 0: It was like back and forth between them on stage and whoever was at the microphone and they alternated back and forth between the module.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically, you know Gabe covered the left side lane and Tycho covered the right side lanes Yeah, and they kind of go back and forth.
Speaker 0: It was kind of like a gong show or periodic like and Back to the right side.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly the correct side, you know people said stuff like, you know I came on the cross-country super trip blah blah blah or Son child's play blah.
Speaker 1: or you know, where are the special edition hardcover books?
Speaker 1: Why are we only getting the soft covers now?
Speaker 1: now a lot of legitimate, you know stuff that you know.
Speaker 1: It wasn't.
Speaker 1: some of it was really funny, but most of it was just kind of you know
Speaker 0: Yeah, and one guy like this and he starts talking starts to ask a question and he asked kind of along the lines of you Guys really didn't expect this you didn't get this it was like what.
Speaker 0: then he whips out a little little little little speaker box And he Rick rolls the audience.
Speaker 1: That was that was the first Rick roll they could mention.
Speaker 1: it was also the lamest but he was alright.
Speaker 0: It was alright because it was.
Speaker 1: it was done pretty well And usually if someone doesn't do a Rick roll just right you groan, but it was kind of like All right, man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I love how taiko is basically like that.
Speaker 0: Did we just get Rick rolled?
Speaker 0: I think he's Rick rolling us.
Speaker 0: You're totally Rick rolling us.
Speaker 0: Are you I mean wilds?
Speaker 1: And is really teeny coming out of a little tape player into a microphone.
Speaker 0: I think what gave it the most class was that he knew the proper time to turn the Rick roll off and give up his moment.
Speaker 1: Yes, it was perfect timing with the turn-off that saved it.
Speaker 0: Yes Pretty much everyone out there like they knew when like the steam of their conversation with the queue with the people up front Timed out and when they just kind of walked away and it worked really well.
Speaker 0: So, of course we're sitting there and we're like now.
Speaker 0: actually this was this.
Speaker 0: we came up with this like a while before.
Speaker 1: We didn't we didn't have anything to ask really right but as you're at the convention, you know We looked at our badges and they said special guest and what presenter or a panelist special guest and panelist bad?
Speaker 0: Our badge was light blue and it was it said on it specifically in square brackets sky blue.
Speaker 0: now I noticed it said sky blue.
Speaker 0: Why would it say sky blue?
Speaker 0: and then you know, we noticed that the normal attendee badge was red red being the second lowest color in Paranoia.
Speaker 1: and if you don't know paranoia, I'm not gonna explain it to you.
Speaker 0: and then we see.
Speaker 0: you know The media badge is yellow and some other badges blue and we see all these different badges.
Speaker 1: I just want to point out at this time that the musical guests also had sky blue badges because they were special guest.
Speaker 0: Yes, so we had the same badge as MC front a lot, which was totally my head like popped when I saw that.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: anyway, I noticed when we were sitting in the audience right because they have basically in this main events room Cameras lots of them because they make the packs DVD and they record everything right and They were you know They the cameras are aimed at gave in taiko and you can see them really big on the two giant projection screens
Speaker 0: and Scott looks up and he says I Think they have ultraviolet badges.
Speaker 1: the badges said, you know all access.
Speaker 1: I saw it for like a second said all.
Speaker 1: tycos badge said all access and it was purple clearly purple.
Speaker 0: Right now at this point there's no way it's a coincidence.
Speaker 0: So we're like, oh my god.
Speaker 0: Oh my god Oh my god, so Scott's like I'm gonna go up and ask and I was like, I'm going to let's go up there.
Speaker 1: So he plans it in advance.
Speaker 0: Now, of course as we do we walk up there and we're in line for a while and the guy this dude behind us is Like.
Speaker 0: it's a little bit annoying nice.
Speaker 0: Like I don't know if my questions good I don't know if they make funny me and I'm like.
Speaker 0: so so what are you gonna say?
Speaker 0: He's like well uh, I kind of quit my job because they wouldn't give me time off to come to the con and I kind of don't have a hotel room and I came out here like the last minute.
Speaker 0: I don't even have money And it was like.
Speaker 1: good luck with that.
Speaker 0: I'm done with that.
Speaker 0: But so we get up there and we basically we're like, I'm like look my badge is sky blue.
Speaker 1: and they're like, yep I'm like Regular tendy.
Speaker 1: what color is your badge?
Speaker 1: red red?
Speaker 1: Tyco, what's your badge up there?
Speaker 1: Is that is that ultraviolet?
Speaker 0: yeah, are you happy?
Speaker 0: said, you know the and we're kind of going back and forth with them.
Speaker 0: and Finally and at one point they're like this is kind of like a little show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz we get up there I'm like, you know, I'm Scott We're you guys we're from New York.
Speaker 1: No today and games like oh, it's like a little show like you thought we were so quaint.
Speaker 0: and then And then basically we get our paranoia question out and he's like, wait a minute You're making a paranoid cuz we didn't say paranoia.
Speaker 0: and he's like, wait a minute We're just like.
Speaker 1: we're just like does the computer know about this you communist?
Speaker 0: and he's like are you making a paranoia agent?
Speaker 0: Oh my god, I love you.
Speaker 0: He said it just like that.
Speaker 0: And then we said I said I want to play paranoia with you.
Speaker 1: And then we took the opportunity to pimp our panel.
Speaker 0: Yes And we totally got away with it because we we built up enough to where our time in the Sun our time in front of That microphone was not out yet.
Speaker 1: So we pimped our panel Sun burning wheel and he's like all burning wheels the shit.
Speaker 0: I totally want to play with you.
Speaker 0: I'm coming to your panel now.
Speaker 0: I knew he wasn't gonna come to the panel.
Speaker 0: Billion things like.
Speaker 0: they held up the spreadsheet that Robert coup put together and gave them telling them where to be when.
Speaker 0: So I I was pretty sure that beyond Dungeons and Dragons was not on his where to be when she.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it wasn't.
Speaker 0: Either it was a really complicated sheet, too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was pretty much a harsh harsh itinerary.
Speaker 0: Yes, so we had a little moment and we sat back down and all the other questions were awesome And it was a really awesome panel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, totally awesome.
Speaker 0: actually, one thing that was kind of funny was that a lot of people seem to have brought gifts for Gabe and Tycho like offerings and There's the one person who brought like a whole bunch of Candy from Canada that was unavailable to them.
Speaker 1: and then someone else came up and like my wife is like nine months pregnant She saw that candy go by and Tycho was like here.
Speaker 1: We know we know all about that here.
Speaker 1: take like three of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those two were really funny up on stage.
Speaker 1: Like they're their dynamic dualness is they sound just like they do in their podcast.
Speaker 1: They're actually were a large number of requests for them to sort of revive their podcast a bit because it's been lacking and It gives me some sort of hope that like this actually is like this demand for podcasts in a way that we just sort of I don't know got it like something can be done as opposed to podcasts are going to be the way they are forever.
Speaker 0: It was just funny though that like everyone who had a gift they say well bring it up to our altar and they'd like walk Up.
Speaker 0: and I remember one guy in particular.
Speaker 0: he walks up with his gift He has and he's like so nervous that he's shaking and he like walks over.
Speaker 1: He's like he's like his hand is shaking as he hands him like this envelope and he like puts it down.
Speaker 0: Then he scurries away as like a rat as fast as possible like they're going to bite him, which they are They probably would have if he'd gotten any closer.
Speaker 1: They like to bite Anyway Anyway, so yeah, one thing about this con is.
Speaker 1: I looked at the schedule, right?
Speaker 1: And when I look at the schedule I see like this I see stuff like on Saturday.
Speaker 1: there's the you know, make a strip panel, which we missed.
Speaker 1: we'll talk about that later.
Speaker 1: But as a line the lineup for it is longer than the panel itself.
Speaker 1: The concerts have a huge lineup the all the main events of these huge lineups and all the main events of the stuff I want to do.
Speaker 1: so I look at the schedule and I'm thinking man between eating and Going to these events and waiting in line and finding some time to go to the expo room at some point the exhibition room.
Speaker 1: I'm I'm not gonna do anything but wait in line and go to these events.
Speaker 1: It's got the whole con and I was sort of disappointed at that But I still felt like it was worth it because those events were so awesome.
Speaker 1: in reality I did a lot of stuff besides wait in line to go to these events because you didn't really have to wait in line the Whole time.
Speaker 0: now, I mean other than it on the last day We didn't really wait in any lines.
Speaker 0: like all the concerts We kind of walk.
Speaker 0: I mean there was a line to get in to get good spots But we just kind of walked in after everyone else was in no problem.
Speaker 1: And because the way they do a thing with the wristbands, you know.
Speaker 1: for the concerts Basically, if you get there really early in the morning get a wristband right away.
Speaker 1: But when the concert starts you can just go get a wristband, you know Because they there's a lot more than they ones they give out right crowd psychology little hint all you geek nights listeners We actually were right up near the front and every one of these events.
Speaker 0: and the way we did it was you walk into the Room, it's super crowded on the side by the entrance.
Speaker 0: if you walk around the back all the way to the other side and then all the way around like almost behind the stage and Then walk like back toward the center There's a big kind of gap there because just like crowd psychology everyone kind of crowds around by the entrance And if you get around those people you can get real close real quick
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so After the Q&A panel, all right, we go to the annex again and now like we're ready like, all right We got nothing to do until the concerts tonight.
Speaker 1: Let's totally play some game before dinner because then we're gonna eat dinner go to the concert.
Speaker 1: So we go to the get to say the checkout of board games room and we're looking and we're thinking maybe we'll play Agricola now to be known as Agricola.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I gotta point out though They had a lot of good games in there But they had the Dune game the game.
Speaker 0: we have the game.
Speaker 0: that's so awesome.
Speaker 0: It was special.
Speaker 0: you had to check it out special and you couldn't leave the room with it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we're thinking maybe a Agricola.
Speaker 1: because you know, that's the hot new game in the German games world.
Speaker 1: But then I see via Poletti and via Poletti is a game.
Speaker 1: it was a spiel de jar winner a while ago o2 or o3 or something like that.
Speaker 1: and It's sort of like a fancy Jenga.
Speaker 1: Right you build a little tower and you don't want to knock it over and you know stuff like that.
Speaker 1: But I'd never played it.
Speaker 1: I'd only heard of it and was intrigued.
Speaker 1: So we got it.
Speaker 1: I said, you know what?
Speaker 1: Let's just fucking get it.
Speaker 1: I'm getting it because the thing about playing games at a convention, especially use.
Speaker 1: you want to play a game You've never played before.
Speaker 1: if you played it before you're wasting your time at a convention Especially if you own the game.
Speaker 1: you want to play games.
Speaker 1: you don't own games.
Speaker 1: You couldn't plan another occasion.
Speaker 1: The problem is if you play games, you've never played before.
Speaker 1: now You're losing precious convention time learning and learning how to play the game.
Speaker 1: if I would have taken Agricola Right, which is even though I know that's the wrong pronunciation.
Speaker 1: I don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: We would have taken like an hour to learn the game read the rules and someone actually told us one of the enforcers manning the room there.
Speaker 1: However, the rules of Agricola were poorly written.
Speaker 0: We saw a lot a group of kids later on Playing power grid for the first time.
Speaker 1: Well, I harass them quite a bit and they didn't like you obviously.
Speaker 1: So I said via Paletti is a jangle light game, it's probably real easy to learn the rules.
Speaker 1: Let's get that.
Speaker 1: so we got it.
Speaker 0: You just stack things up on top of each other and then Scott knocks it.
Speaker 1: Oh, we're gonna do a whole show on it.
Speaker 1: All you have to know is that I've ordered the game.
Speaker 1: It's so good, but we played this game.
Speaker 1: We got two random packs people to play with us.
Speaker 1: They were awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah and then we got like.
Speaker 0: we played it a bunch of times and we got a couple other different people to play and Everyone in the room was kind of like.
Speaker 0: they kind of start watching like from the side like sidelong glances from their own games.
Speaker 1: basically we were playing this game.
Speaker 1: it became like the centerpiece of the room as the tower got bigger and bigger and as there were two tiny sticks holding up this gigantic tower and then eventually crash and Yelling and screaming and everyone starts yelling in the room and one guy claps.
Speaker 0: It was a. it was a good time But I got to talk a little bit about the room too because the game this is the best tabletop gaming space I have ever seen.
Speaker 0: it was basically a lot one large room that was Divided in the center by a low cubicle wall And all around it were tables and chairs like square big circular tables like six or seven chairs.
Speaker 0: It was also small square tables like lots of different configurations And then all around the perimeter were little hallways and in these little hallways were little rooms with like a table in six Chairs and a door you could close behind you.
Speaker 1: So pretty much like any table configuration that you were looking for was available and You know for gaming it doesn't get better than that.
Speaker 1: you can have a private RPG room a big miniatures table Whatever you want.
Speaker 1: They had it going on.
Speaker 1: It was totally freakin sweet.
Speaker 0: Yep Any other cool thing that they had set up that totally got to bring this to kinetic on?
Speaker 0: Was if you were looking for a game You just held.
Speaker 0: they had these signs for you ready.
Speaker 0: that said LFG and on the bottom what kind of game you wanted to play.
Speaker 0: You just walked around holding it and eventually people would congregate and play a game.
Speaker 1: So if like you wanted to play settlers You just picked up a copy of settlers in an LFG sign and you just sort of walked around with it and people would say What's up settlers?
Speaker 0: Let's rock and roll or you'd see like five people who would all congregate cuz they all had like LFG board game and then they all walked in as strangers to the room together checked out a game as a group.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if you wanted to play a game and you saw someone holding up LFG you to go to them and say hey Let's play.
Speaker 1: and at the same time it also helped because sometimes you had a gaming con you're playing a game People come up to you and say hey Can I play and you'll have to be like you'll feel bad because you'd like.
Speaker 1: now we've already got four.
Speaker 1: We already got five.
Speaker 1: So with the LFG signs.
Speaker 1: No one bothered you if you didn't have the sign because it.
Speaker 1: they assumed you weren't.
Speaker 1: LFG.
Speaker 0: And also the like all the people running this room.
Speaker 0: pretty much they left everyone in the gaming area completely alone Except sometimes enforcers would come and like play a game and the people managing the game checkout.
Speaker 0: We're like the most awesome together.
Speaker 1: people like they all and they were super knowledgeable at games, too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we walk in and I was like, oh my god, we should play teeny.
Speaker 0: What was like?
Speaker 0: that's a good game.
Speaker 0: Have you played Puerto Rico?
Speaker 0: and I'm like.
Speaker 0: We took turns naming games.
Speaker 0: I was like have you played this?
Speaker 0: she's like duh, have you played this?
Speaker 0: I'm like duh.
Speaker 0: Eventually named every good game.
Speaker 0: I was like, okay cool Yep, and you know we hang around there for a while and then eventually we go to eat.
Speaker 0: You know, we got to eat at some point at this count.
Speaker 0: All I want to say is I walk out I see that crepe line and I totally didn't eat there.
Speaker 1: We went to lounge B a little bit more and it was as around this time.
Speaker 1: Remember I said there were three DS lounges a B and C right or handheld lounges.
Speaker 1: Excuse me We hung out and B and then we hung out and B again and we sort of developed this allegiance to lounge B and unjustified Desired.
Speaker 1: it's completely justified.
Speaker 1: lounge a lounge C were shit and look out.
Speaker 1: B was awesome.
Speaker 0: lounge C tried too hard.
Speaker 0: Lounge a was shit.
Speaker 0: lounge B, especially sitting at the bottom of the lounge of Kings.
Speaker 0: I was sitting at the bottom of that escalator in my thing Like I felt like a king watching all my subjects filtered by even though Actually gave in.
Speaker 0: taiko were the Kings and we were just pretenders to the throne who were totally about to get punked by some army From the East.
Speaker 0: doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: Anybody isn't a large B sucks Technically army from the West.
Speaker 0: we were the usurper army from the East that failed to gather the support of the man.
Speaker 1: Anyone who isn't lounge B is awesome.
Speaker 0: All right, so what I think you mean?
Speaker 0: the opposite.
Speaker 1: I said anyone who is in lounge B is awesome.
Speaker 0: I thought you said everyone who isn't lounge B is awesome.
Speaker 1: No, I said everyone not in lounge B is poop.
Speaker 0: I can't say though.
Speaker 0: I saw one guy in lounge B on Sunday when I was walking by with an original gameboy playing a game on sweet That was so excited.
Speaker 1: You know lounge B is the best.
Speaker 1: All right, anyway After much to do it was time for the Friday night concert.
Speaker 1: So we go The Friday night concerts and they're looking for wristbands wristbands wristbands wristbands that we didn't get the wristbands in the morning.
Speaker 1: So we're sort of like and I don't know if we can get in shit standing there like idiots waiting for the alright everyone else come in announcement right and then that announcement never came.
Speaker 1: we walked away we came back and They were still saying wristbands wristbands wristbands.
Speaker 0: So then I see a guy walking by me with a wristband that is not on his wrist.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I'm about to be like dude.
Speaker 0: five bucks Yeah.
Speaker 0: and the guy's like guy like looks at me and he like Shoulders over toward this desk on the other side of the room the help desk for the con.
Speaker 0: and I see them.
Speaker 1: This is in the reg area.
Speaker 0: By the way, I see them tossing wristbands to people like water.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they just got wristbands out there.
Speaker 1: so I'm like, ah, all right, let's go get some wristbands.
Speaker 0: I walk over to the concert with Scott.
Speaker 0: we walk in and The one-up start playing.
Speaker 1: Well, the one-ups had been playing for a little.
Speaker 0: we miss like half of one song.
Speaker 0: Now the one-ups are really.
Speaker 0: they played kind of not smooth jazz But light jazz heavily influenced by video game.
Speaker 0: They would
Speaker 1: take the like the bass melody of a popular video game song or sometimes
Speaker 0: the harmony and melodify Right,
Speaker 1: and and then they would just jazz it up crazily like just play a jazz song where that was the seed and the song just grew out of it and It was pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: I would totally download their musics Yeah, but then you know, that was really exciting.
Speaker 0: then they ended and of course we went through this charade of Encore encore.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, then they came back and did more songs and then Freeze pop came out.
Speaker 0: If you don't know freeze pop my boss at work knows freeze pop and still listens to them.
Speaker 0: freeze bug is.
Speaker 0: pop is well-known Among older people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're in the guitar heroes.
Speaker 1: They do that.
Speaker 1: That's freeze pop.
Speaker 0: yes, I know others.
Speaker 0: they played it.
Speaker 0: the last packs also science genius girl and all that business, right?
Speaker 1: So we see them and I had heard from the last packs that they weren't the best live you know as well as they were recorded.
Speaker 1: and Hey, I could see why you would say that but he doesn't fucking matter.
Speaker 0: It was an amazing freaking concert and anyone who said everyone was rocking the house out Yeah, anyone who said it was a bad concert was wrong.
Speaker 0: and it was.
Speaker 0: this concert was great.
Speaker 1: Then dual key tars two key tars Two key tars like I mean it was.
Speaker 1: this was how many key tars?
Speaker 1: more than one.
Speaker 0: this is one of the better concerts I've been to in my life.
Speaker 0: Yeah Best concert but pretty good.
Speaker 0: and when I say this concert I mean freeze pop not the concert as a whole because you know freeze.
Speaker 1: and then there's the one part right where the dude Cuz remember first it was jazz then it was basically synth pop, right?
Speaker 1: Why one song right?
Speaker 1: the freeze pop dude put down his keytar and picked up a guitar and it was an electric guitar.
Speaker 1: I mean he played it.
Speaker 1: I was like, oh, yeah electric guitars are magic Cuz you sort of forget listening to the keytar how amazing the electric guitar is.
Speaker 0: and you know Like they played a slightly slow song.
Speaker 0: So like people are holding up the DS's and things.
Speaker 0: and then freeze pop is like no no no, all you do that house lights down and That was a fucking sight Cuz.
Speaker 0: I mean I mean dude was holding up his like 22 inch laptop.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, we everyone's been doing the hold up electronic device thing.
Speaker 1: You know ever since smoking became uncool and cell phones became cool, right?
Speaker 1: This is not something new.
Speaker 1: It's been around for a long time.
Speaker 1: the hold up your device for light at a concert right instead of a lighter.
Speaker 1: But you know you they took it a step further.
Speaker 1: You know, they said turn off all the lights only light from electronic devices, you know I downloaded one of those free flashlight apps for my iPhone.
Speaker 0: then in there in the room I was holding up my razor and my blackberry.
Speaker 0: I kept hitting the button on the side to make the light stay on so it was doubly cool.
Speaker 1: I don't think that'd be cool again.
Speaker 1: You know, he's just more of the same but one guy had the best I don't know to see it pushed to the limit.
Speaker 0: It was literally a animated picture of a lit lighter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they have those.
Speaker 1: you can get that for the iPhone.
Speaker 1: that it's yeah a pic.
Speaker 1: It's just like an animation of a flame on your on your iPhone, but freeze pop was really good.
Speaker 1: They really rocked out and then they went through the charade of having an encore.
Speaker 0: Yes And then of course their encore was like the fucking business.
Speaker 0: and then Jonathan Colton came out.
Speaker 0: now If you don't know who he is, he's the dude who joke.
Speaker 1: Oh, what's up?
Speaker 0: He wrote the portal song.
Speaker 0: You know, I'm not even angry.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that one yes, he he's basically the king of nerd music right now.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's like he's.
Speaker 0: I won't say he's filthy cuz he's really not he's.
Speaker 0: I feel like he's a step up from Phil.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is really it is felt.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's nerdy folk music.
Speaker 0: Yes, but you listen to other.
Speaker 0: Phil It does not sound like a is is the difference?
Speaker 1: is other people who do filk often do not have musical talent.
Speaker 1: Jonathan Colton is loaded with musical talent.
Speaker 1: He can sing and play the guitar Many other instruments.
Speaker 0: it was not Phil it was nerdy folk.
Speaker 0: Perhaps there's a difference.
Speaker 0: It is real full.
Speaker 1: You just want to give it a different genre because the quality is on another level.
Speaker 0: because listen to Phil Phil is usually like cringeworthy inside baseball.
Speaker 0: nerdery folk is Really soulful and I gotta say he's really.
Speaker 0: I mean his flicker song especially with the flicker images up on screen.
Speaker 0: That was actually.
Speaker 0: that was a really.
Speaker 0: that was a moment with the crowd like.
Speaker 0: that was really cool.
Speaker 1: Jonathan Colton is not only is he wicked awesome.
Speaker 1: And is the thing is he spans the gaming crowds, right?
Speaker 1: He's got the tech crowd right with his because he was a programmer before he was a musician.
Speaker 1: He's got the gaming crowd with his portal stuff, right?
Speaker 0: He's all about the Creative Commons open source business.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's totally with the open source crowd.
Speaker 1: He was on twit once or twice, right?
Speaker 1: He played rock band with Leo Laporte and them, you know, he's.
Speaker 1: he's all over Everything and he's totally awesome in every way.
Speaker 0: So, uh, you know, he does his concerts really good does a lot of great.
Speaker 1: He's wearing a shirt that was like the.
Speaker 1: you know, the internet is awesome.
Speaker 0: Every.
Speaker 0: it just said the internet is awesome.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Everyone's waiting for him to do the portal song and finally he's like, alright I'm gonna do that song and then Felicia Day walks out.
Speaker 1: I didn't know who that was but didn't master Scott's a heathen like bastard.
Speaker 0: It was some girl everybody liked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she was in dr.
Speaker 0: Horrible In one of the penny arcades.
Speaker 0: I believe a line that Tycho in the comic spoke was.
Speaker 0: I just want to you know groom her and Apparently supposedly he did supposedly because she's totally awesome.
Speaker 0: When they met she handed him a brush turned around and said groom away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he said Supposedly it was like petting a unicorn.
Speaker 1: Alrighty, so I have a wife Isn't grooming his wife like petting a unicorn?
Speaker 0: I don't think Emily would complain if I petted Felicia Day on the head with a brush.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I totally would too.
Speaker 0: She is so cool.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, she's good at singing answers.
Speaker 0: She covered.
Speaker 0: she sang the portal song.
Speaker 0: Of course also the entire crowd sang the portal song.
Speaker 1: How could they not?
Speaker 0: and it was quite was great and you know, his concert was awesome.
Speaker 0: But then he had visual components.
Speaker 0: cuz you know, he has this flicker song.
Speaker 0: and the deal with that was that he took Pictures from flicker that were Creative Commons Which is the point of the Creative Commons wrote a song about them and showed them during the song to the music.
Speaker 0: And he did this funny bit with the tech guy where he pulls up a bit this DVD.
Speaker 0: Oh the tech guy He's like put the tech guy.
Speaker 0: He's like put the day and yeah this back and forth.
Speaker 0: and the tech guy had a microphone.
Speaker 0: He snarked back at him a few times and they totally did this.
Speaker 0: who's on first business with?
Speaker 0: play the video.
Speaker 0: So he turns up the DVD and it says two buttons.
Speaker 0: play this one Not this one.
Speaker 0: and they did like this eight minute or maybe it was like five minutes, but who's on first?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: on third and of course the whole time the audience is like, you know, cuz it's basic psychology.
Speaker 1: There's the one he's supposed to click on and the one he's not supposed to.
Speaker 1: Everyone wants to see that.
Speaker 1: not supposed to one, right?
Speaker 1: Curiosity you can't resist.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna say this right now.
Speaker 0: No one in that fucking room saw it coming.
Speaker 1: Jonathan Colton saw it coming and so did up Bart the sound man.
Speaker 1: He might not have or Brad I think was his real name.
Speaker 0: It started with a B much like lounge B. You see.
Speaker 1: Yeah So he clicks on the one he's supposed to click on and it's the awesome flicker song, right?
Speaker 0: And then you know, he's like, alright, that's it.
Speaker 0: then Bart's like or Beth or bort.
Speaker 0: It's bored.
Speaker 0: He's bored now.
Speaker 1: his real name was Brad, but he made a joke of calling him Bart.
Speaker 0: all the time I'm gonna call him bored.
Speaker 0: All right, cuz there's no more board license plates.
Speaker 0: He's totally screwed and The crowd's like click on it and boards like.
Speaker 0: so should I should I click on it?
Speaker 0: And the thing is Jonathan Colton played it totally straight.
Speaker 0: He's like no don't click on that.
Speaker 0: What's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: Let's just move on.
Speaker 0: So he just clicks on it and it was totally a Rick roll.
Speaker 0: It was the whole music video Just there.
Speaker 0: Uh, it was brilliant.
Speaker 0: And the thing is I didn't.
Speaker 1: I didn't think a Rick roll could be brilliant again But there it was.
Speaker 1: the whole crowd should have seen it coming.
Speaker 0: No one groaned.
Speaker 0: Everyone basically said wow You got me you got us all.
Speaker 0: they played like half the music video.
Speaker 0: It was super funny.
Speaker 1: is he really played sort of like this sort of slightly antagonistic of the audience.
Speaker 1: He was like when people are yelling stuff at him like play this play that he was like, listen I have prepared a setlist to maximize your entertainment value.
Speaker 0: But maybe I should just throw that all away and play free bird cuz someone yelled it.
Speaker 1: He's like yelling free bird at a geek concert.
Speaker 0: So, uh, then he pulls out this device and he talks about his.
Speaker 0: you know, he did a thing with like every Friday He used.
Speaker 1: he did this thing called song a song a week where he played.
Speaker 1: You know, maybe as he wrote a song every week for a whole year and like, you know after two weeks He ran out of songs are good.
Speaker 1: Most of them are bad.
Speaker 0: So he tells the whole story about the mr Fancy pants song and then he basically pulls out the device.
Speaker 0: That was the only way he could make that song work The Zen drum.
Speaker 0: All I want to say about the Zen drum is that he did.
Speaker 0: It was a really great song as a result and he was really funny.
Speaker 0: That song was almost a stand-up comedy routine because of that device Reminiscent of Dana Carvey's stand-up back in the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you want to know more about the Zen drum?
Speaker 1: Basically, it's a MIDI controller that you can wear and then you know You touch the different parts of it to control whatever digital music you have prepared in advance and I didn't think He could.
Speaker 0: I don't think Rick Roll could happen again, but he pulled out the Rick.
Speaker 0: the one he had was $1,300 just so you know, he pulled out the Rick Roll a third time but in such an unexpected Well done classy way that it was like wow.
Speaker 0: He got us again.
Speaker 1: Oh my god I think you really hated the audience.
Speaker 1: You can almost think you really did hate us when he was doing that guys.
Speaker 0: And the only other thing I want to say is that the encore that he put on.
Speaker 1: of course They went to the encore charade yet again.
Speaker 0: Why must we go through this charade?
Speaker 0: Charade, but he did it.
Speaker 1: just wanted to repeat myself.
Speaker 1: They went through the encore charade for every band at both concerts every single time.
Speaker 0: Jonathan Colton's encore was like that made my con.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he did.
Speaker 1: He did the zombies and then people are still yelling.
Speaker 1: So he just played sweet caroline like whatever.
Speaker 0: yes, that was oh my god, so of course now it's like 2 25 a.m.
Speaker 0: And I went to oh my god.
Speaker 0: I had to go to bed and that Was Friday.
Speaker 1: there were two days left.
Speaker 0: So at this juncture, I realized we've been talking for a long time.
Speaker 1: It's 10 p.m.
Speaker 1: Right now as we're recording this on Wednesday, and this is supposed to be Tuesday shows.
Speaker 1: It's way overdue and We still have two days or one and a half days of packs to talk about, you know the full Saturday Which is the whole day of packs and then the Sunday which is almost the whole day
Speaker 0: not to mention the kind of press stuff we want to talk about like the like the the how and like the what of the convention itself and the Logistics and all the behind-the-scenes stuff and our suggestions and our ideas
Speaker 1: and we didn't talk about any of the actual Video games that were playable in the packs as a bit exhibition room that were not playable anywhere else yet.
Speaker 1: Cuz you know, it's sort of like an e3 ish thing.
Speaker 0: I think what we're trying to say here is that what you just heard was packs part 1 of N.
Speaker 1: yes, we don't.
Speaker 1: we don't know how many parts there will be But I guess this shows you that packs was so full and so huge that our trip to Seattle and our recent, you know Dirth of shows is now rectified because our font has been filled.
Speaker 0: my cup on the West Coast.
Speaker 0: so a little preview.
Speaker 0: on Thursday, we're gonna talk about Seattle, you know We didn't want to like conflate our West Coast trip with packs because we want to review pack separately.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna talk about the airports.
Speaker 1: We're gonna talk about the restaurant All that business the fact that no one in Seattle jaywalked except us.
Speaker 1: right that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: and The next Tuesday, right?
Speaker 1: We're giving you the whole big show schedule here.
Speaker 0: No, I'm just telling you don't worry next Tuesday for those of you who are looking forward to this because I know from the con a Lot of you packs people are looking forward to this.
Speaker 0: We're gonna.
Speaker 0: you know Saturday includes you know all the other stuff about the con that happened on Saturday in the exhibition room and of course our panel and the Aftermath and the fucking epic shit that happened after our panel with Luke Crane and Jared Sorensen and the fact that the packs enforcers Allowed us to do what we did
Speaker 1: Yeah, totally
Speaker 0: and all the burning wheel demos and all that craziness.
Speaker 0: And then we might even know how many shows this is gonna be.
Speaker 0: we're gonna have another show about.
Speaker 1: we're gonna do Tuesday shows Until we run out of stuff.
Speaker 0: Yes, so our normal schedule will hold as in every week.
Speaker 0: It'll be a Monday Wednesday or a Tuesday Thursday.
Speaker 1: Well, basically we're just gonna do a whole lot of shows from now until we empty this cup and cut it.
Speaker 1: Thanks, get it to a more reasonable point.
Speaker 0: I mean there's even gonna be a Wednesday on.
Speaker 0: Like how I realized anime cons need to be changed in a big way because packed like anime cons do not Live up.
Speaker 0: now that I have seen how a convention is through the lens of packs and the fire of penny arcade Yeah, oh my god.
Speaker 0: But now bed.
Speaker 0: so in some they're going to be Many many many more shows about packs to come and if you're a new listener because of packs Rest assured we have more to say.
Speaker 1: you get a lot more to say.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.