Speaker 1: It's Wednesday November 19th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is Detroit's metal city.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Are you ready?
Speaker 0: It's time once again for make rim and Scott feel old.
Speaker 0: you ready to play this game all right?
Speaker 1: I'm down with this.
Speaker 1: I saw at least one thing was ten years old today.
Speaker 0: Oh, what are you doing?
Speaker 0: stealing my bit?
Speaker 1: I I couldn't guess what your bit was.
Speaker 1: Scott said this thing lately where before every show you know we sit down like all right.
Speaker 1: What are we gonna do for the show about?
Speaker 1: let's talk about.
Speaker 1: I don't know balls.
Speaker 0: What's the like to talk about balls?
Speaker 1: a whole lot, so I'll be like hey for the news.
Speaker 1: I'll talk about that tech thing number one that it's on slash job.
Speaker 1: What's your news?
Speaker 1: It's gotta be like ah It's a secret.
Speaker 1: all right fine things of the day.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna use that video from college humor.
Speaker 1: How about you?
Speaker 1: It's a secret.
Speaker 0: I just need to know what rims doing so and as long as I'm not doing the same thing I don't need to say what I'm doing.
Speaker 1: well apparently that just failed.
Speaker 0: Apparently it just did.
Speaker 0: but to make you feel old anyway Penny arcade as of Monday is ten years old a decade.
Speaker 1: I have not lived through three of them.
Speaker 0: I was Let's see I'm 26 almost 27, so I was 17 when penny arcade came into existence.
Speaker 1: What's interesting is that penny arcade has been a stalwart companion to my life for much of that ten years Like I. it's difficult for me to.
Speaker 0: it's weird for it to be.
Speaker 1: I'm in my life before I read penny arcade.
Speaker 0: The weirdest thing is that it's ten years old, but I've only read it since like 99-2000. what was it?
Speaker 0: Did they?
Speaker 0: are they counting stuff before that?
Speaker 0: as like you know when are they counting the starting date?
Speaker 1: Clearly you count the same way we count geek nights.
Speaker 1: I mean the first episode we ever uploaded to the internet for you know real people not just Visigoths and front-row crew.
Speaker 1: It's to listen to was on November 1st.
Speaker 1: in what 2005 Mmm.
Speaker 0: I think so.
Speaker 0: or October 31st?
Speaker 1: No, no it was.
Speaker 1: it was November 1st, and we uploaded shows for that whole week, and then that weekend I retroactively Uploaded because we'd been recording shows for like two and a half weeks before that just not uploading them because they were terrible.
Speaker 1: But I decided after listening to it that the October 31st episode was good, so I retroactively uploaded it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: okay the first actual penny arcade comic put on the web was November 18th 98 1998 so I didn't.
Speaker 0: I didn't read it though until like 99 so it took me like a year to get to it.
Speaker 1: the 1997-98 season of Marching band in my high school.
Speaker 1: We played the Independence Day soundtrack When that movie was new and popular.
Speaker 1: Wow You know in retrospect that movie wasn't really that good.
Speaker 0: what I kind of like an event is there.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's not like I'd.
Speaker 1: it had the speech all the scenes With certain people punching people and yelling at people and dragging people through the desert.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I could have been at a barbecue and No Yeah, that was pretty good proof.
Speaker 1: That was it.
Speaker 1: the rest of the movie was crap.
Speaker 0: It wasn't crap It was just a normal average.
Speaker 0: You know average would become her blockbuster action movie with silliness.
Speaker 1: But if I but for all the action that was in it to any day.
Speaker 1: I'd rather watch the rock.
Speaker 0: I'm not I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying I want to watch in the pen.
Speaker 0: Don't get out of yourself.
Speaker 1: Independence Day lover.
Speaker 0: oh yes, it's my favorite of all time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what though?
Speaker 1: Anime will always make you feel young Because anytime you're at a con and you start feeling old because you look around and you see all the.
Speaker 0: you see that guy who's like Yeah, man, remember tow board the eighth man.
Speaker 0: You're like, yes, I'm not old.
Speaker 0: But then you see someone who comes around is like Sailor Moon's old school and you're like, no I'm old that guy with tow boards just older.
Speaker 1: I remember it Oda Khan.
Speaker 1: I overheard a conversation where someone was like, yeah, I only watch old-school anime, you know, like Dragon Ball and bleach.
Speaker 1: I don't like this Naruto business.
Speaker 0: Ah Isn't bleached newer than Naruto, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it is.
Speaker 1: I lump them all into that same era of anime.
Speaker 1: Good But I remember also, you know tow board the eighth man.
Speaker 1: I remember when some old men were talking about.
Speaker 1: I heard eight man and I turn around I see the old man The old man who used to always be on that old fart anime panel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I was like, hey eight man after and they were like eight man after they made that in life I Was like I never even seen it.
Speaker 1: Wow, I felt really young.
Speaker 0: It's like hey, I remember what you're talking about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing you remember that's old was the remake of what I remember.
Speaker 0: That's like.
Speaker 0: I remember Astro boy watching that in the 80s in color.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was the remake of what I remember from the 60s.
Speaker 1: Oh shit one thing I don't think our generation is quite as equipped to deal with as past generations were is the Fact that the media we consume will eventually die.
Speaker 1: I mean I've been reading penny arcade forever and The idea of penny arcade not being there or of gave in taiko not continuing to make that strip while I live While I draw breath, you just have to die before they do That such can easily be arranged.
Speaker 0: I know right.
Speaker 0: I see when they when you know I'll just kill you at Gabe and tycos funeral and toss you in with them Because of course they'll die at this exact same time and be buried together.
Speaker 1: I just I think about how much media has changed and then I don't know my life.
Speaker 1: I mean remember we were born in the 80s.
Speaker 1: What was media like in the 80s?
Speaker 0: It was like Voltron.
Speaker 0: now what's binding and forming together, but we're staying together.
Speaker 1: What's it gonna be like?
Speaker 1: are we just gonna be the old men going?
Speaker 1: Yeah Ava and cowboy bebop and eska flown They're already those.
Speaker 0: What are you talking about?
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: Are we real?
Speaker 0: Yeah, Sesame Street when snuffleupagus was still invisible.
Speaker 1: Are we still gonna be those old guys.
Speaker 1: when we're 16 70 will we ever find a new anime?
Speaker 1: To talk about in those glowing terms.
Speaker 0: Well, the question anything beat macross.
Speaker 1: Do you remember love?
Speaker 0: Lot of things beat.
Speaker 0: do you remember love?
Speaker 0: I'm not as enthralled with it as many people seem to be.
Speaker 1: it's a great move.
Speaker 0: It's not so great.
Speaker 1: I think it's great.
Speaker 1: I think I think in fact it was more succinct and thus more powerful.
Speaker 0: No, the TV show as far as peer in every fashion and just another bad compilation that diminished You know the quality of having any set of TV series anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I got a little bit of news here before Scott brings up the much bigger and much more commentary worthy news.
Speaker 1: But Emily told me quite some time ago about this manga that was done by someone I'm not gonna go through the whole story because eventually we're gonna review this business, but it was called Hetalia and it is about Eddie's head.
Speaker 1: He's about hit like hitting like Hetal a Useless another way to say useless.
Speaker 1: Okay, the way you're thinking of like Italian This was a manga that basically took all of the Socio-political powers of the poet like World War one era.
Speaker 0: Oh, I thought that I remember that I thought it was just like some like fan doujinshi kind of work.
Speaker 1: Them into pretty boys who then argue with each other and fight and it's generally hilarious.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I remember I remember that but I thought it was like a doujinshi and not a real-deal production.
Speaker 1: Well, yes, that's the news.
Speaker 1: You see it was basically like a little comic doujinshi kind of thing.
Speaker 1: One thing led to another.
Speaker 1: the anime is coming out.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, that's pretty hot.
Speaker 1: I am so excited about this for two reasons because one it proves that the amateur media Can be the gateway to the professional media.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: This is happening.
Speaker 0: That's what excites me about it.
Speaker 0: because think about all the.
Speaker 0: you know I mean anything that's on the same level as doujinshi, you know, but in the u.s.
Speaker 0: You know things like people making YouTube videos and stuff Right.
Speaker 0: any attempt to like take that and then actually go big with it sort of doesn't work.
Speaker 0: It always comes off ham-fisted or doesn't really make it You know as big as could be.
Speaker 0: you're like if we created like a sporting league in the backyard and started videotaping it.
Speaker 0: It wouldn't suddenly get on TV and be you know, like competing with the NFL time slots.
Speaker 1: It couldn't happen, but but I saw a basketball.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know right actually I didn't I knew better.
Speaker 1: It was made by Trey Parker.
Speaker 0: Thank he made.
Speaker 0: he made something.
Speaker 0: I didn't say.
Speaker 1: I don't know if he actually possible.
Speaker 1: I you know what.
Speaker 1: I'll look it up because all I remember is that that movie was bad anyway.
Speaker 0: The the fact that you know, someone can just draw doujinshi and then have it become an anime, you know People that always say oh man, how do I?
Speaker 0: you know, I have this great idea for an anime.
Speaker 0: I want to make it happen.
Speaker 0: Well, here's what you do draw doujinshi of it.
Speaker 0: And if it's good then an anime will be made.
Speaker 0: maybe There you go Now we can answer that question very easily.
Speaker 0: before it was like ha ha that's impossible.
Speaker 1: Now we have an answer but - I'm excited because one.
Speaker 1: I got rave reviews from Emily and all the other people who've read it Or know about it, but I like the idea.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's the main can is a clever idea is northern Italy and he's useless And he's kind of and everyone that with a big mustache.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, they're all pretty boys.
Speaker 1: Everyone's a pretty boy.
Speaker 0: But how does that work?
Speaker 0: Mussolini was just so bad.
Speaker 1: It's well before the Mussolini came into the picture.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's not it's.
Speaker 1: and do you know anything about what was going on in the world before World War one?
Speaker 0: Oh, I thought you said in World War two.
Speaker 1: No, I said, you know post World War one World War one.
Speaker 1: ish.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: Never mind.
Speaker 1: It leads up to World War two.
Speaker 1: the Kaiser's in there Kaiser's are there but they're all pretty boys.
Speaker 0: They did pointy hats.
Speaker 0: No Like they who wants to read this no Kaiser's the pointy hats.
Speaker 1: So yeah, you haven't seen this at all.
Speaker 1: No, I haven't All right.
Speaker 0: I'll say this I just remember seeing that I saw the homepage but actually see the comic.
Speaker 1: as long as they don't do fiss up Anime this is gonna be one of those greats that we're gonna watch in love like damecha dobutsu.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's gonna be that kind.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that is my hope.
Speaker 0: That's my favorite guy.
Speaker 1: They make it that kind of show.
Speaker 1: I'm all about it.
Speaker 1: or if they do like the asamanga daioh treatment where because they take the kind or the treatment of the show We're gonna talk about today.
Speaker 1: Yes same kind of treatment where you instead of trying to turn the comic into a long overarching possibly serious or just standard show you turn it into the kind of comic show like asamanga daioh.
Speaker 1: that Asamanga daioh was great because of that.
Speaker 1: It was a bunch of vignettes that were just set in the awesome world of azuma.
Speaker 1: Anyway check out Italia and we will probably be gonna spell that because I still can't figure H-e-t-a-l-i-a.
Speaker 0: Okay, cuz the way you say it it just sounds like you're saying Italia Italia.
Speaker 1: All right Whatever, you know, it's all right Italia Italia because Italy.
Speaker 0: but it sounds like you're not.
Speaker 0: it sounds like you're saying hits But the H is very quick and silent.
Speaker 0: So it sounds like you're just saying Italia like Italy.
Speaker 0: fine So, okay This news is just too crazy to possibly not say anything about.
Speaker 0: so I got to go over all these details One at a time and I don't know where to start.
Speaker 0: So let me just pick a place to start here by randomness.
Speaker 0: Crunchyroll the evil crunchyroll, right?
Speaker 0: We hated them so much.
Speaker 0: Why do we hate them so much?
Speaker 0: Well crunchyroll started out is basically a YouTube clone that only had Anime and mostly copyrighted anime that was uploaded by users and they were making money off of that.
Speaker 0: They even got venture capital Basically, so instead of a business that does nothing but break the law and made money off it.
Speaker 0: man If I knew you could get away with that, I wouldn't be here right now.
Speaker 0: That's for sure.
Speaker 0: And so these assholes who we don't like at crunchyroll, you know got the venture capital And then now that they had money they didn't need to be legal anymore.
Speaker 0: So they started going legit and whatnot.
Speaker 0: and now they're going super legit.
Speaker 0: on January 8th Crunchyroll will stop accepting user submitted videos and they will only host videos approved by copyright holders Ganzo Toei two other Japanese copyright holders of anime that are not listed.
Speaker 0: So that's the first thing.
Speaker 0: the second thing Crunchyroll is also going to provide right if you pay a subscription fee.
Speaker 0: So basically you subscribe to crunchyroll, right?
Speaker 0: You'll be able to watch Naruto about an hour after it's on TV in Japan.
Speaker 0: So it's on TV in Japan.
Speaker 0: 60 minutes later, it'll be on crunchyroll And if you pay a subscription fee, you could watch it on crunchyroll with English subtitles anywhere in the world.
Speaker 0: Alright, so the the companies is starting to make a move here.
Speaker 0: Obviously, you know, the fan says better watch out.
Speaker 1: I mean remember way back when digi selves and all these things first started coming out and then there were all the copyright issues and What everyone always said what every anime fan at the time was saying was that hey The reason we pirate is because you know price aside because they say a price whatever I'm watching the show I want to watch it when it's out in Japan.
Speaker 1: Why do I have to wait, you know, six months a year to see it in the u.s.
Speaker 1: And wait for some dub I don't even want to hear in the first place.
Speaker 1: If the anime companies would just allow me to pay him out his fee to see the shows as they come out Subtitled I would gladly pay it.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the chance to walk the walk because you know, but I don't like Naruto I know me either.
Speaker 0: but the thing is it's like, you know different people when they talk about copyright might You know side on yes or no or whatever.
Speaker 0: But they always have everyone sort of has a different reason or a different excuse They come up with.
Speaker 0: you know, one person will say oh, it's not digital.
Speaker 0: another person will say oh, it's DRM.
Speaker 0: Another person says it's not subtitled.
Speaker 0: You know, everyone says something different.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a bunch of people out there who did say that they don't want to wait.
Speaker 0: So for the first time possibly ever someone even though it's the shitty crunchyroll Is saying alright put your money where your mouth is bitches.
Speaker 0: Here.
Speaker 0: It is one hour after it's up in Japan with subtitles.
Speaker 0: are you going to pay for it?
Speaker 0: and I could see it going both ways You know.
Speaker 0: on the one hand I think that there are people who just wanted it quickly and did have the money and I think they will pay and watch it.
Speaker 0: on the other hand I still think that a lot of the people watching are high school kids with no money and they won't pay under any Circumstance even if it was just.
Speaker 0: you know The whole thing immediately live and download in the perfect quality for a penny.
Speaker 0: They wouldn't pay because they don't have a penny.
Speaker 1: Well, that's where the second part of this comes in.
Speaker 0: Yes, exactly seven days after an episode airs, right?
Speaker 0: So it's on TV Tokyo in Japan.
Speaker 0: one hour later It'll be on crunchyroll and people who pay monthly fees can watch it.
Speaker 0: I'm What can you subtitle in an hour?
Speaker 0: They must be working pretty closely to get the subtitles.
Speaker 0: Um seven days after that it will be able to watch the episode of Naruto free on crunchyroll But also on Hulu Naruto calm and a whole bunch of other websites.
Speaker 0: So it's pretty much gonna be.
Speaker 0: hey if you want to watch an hour to the last week's episode of Naruto.
Speaker 0: It'll be free to watch online almost anywhere now.
Speaker 1: I assume there will be ads here.
Speaker 0: I assume there's gonna be ads and you know, actually I look at this and I say, you know what this is Someone even though it's stupid crunchyroll yet again, right it part of it.
Speaker 0: Someone is actually smart and in control.
Speaker 0: right look Cartoon Network kicked all the anime off.
Speaker 0: tsunamis dead, right?
Speaker 0: They can't get their anime on TV.
Speaker 0: It's just not working.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna happen, right?
Speaker 0: Okay, the fan sub people are still downloading.
Speaker 0: They're still out there.
Speaker 0: You still see Naruto headbands at every convention.
Speaker 0: Naruto fans are still out and about right there all over the place.
Speaker 0: They have not really gone away.
Speaker 0: the manga sells the anime.
Speaker 0: DVDs do not sell.
Speaker 0: So they have this anime property which is the core of Naruto this animation, right?
Speaker 0: It's it, you know, and then the manga is right behind that.
Speaker 0: they can sell anything that says Naruto on it Naruto backpacks Naruto shoes Naruto headbands Naruto figures Naruto cards Naruto video games, but they can't actually sell the anime.
Speaker 0: They can't sell it on TV.
Speaker 0: They can't sell DVDs.
Speaker 0: They can't sell digital downloads.
Speaker 0: They can't sell it.
Speaker 0: No one's buying it, but they're still making it and they're still paying for it with sponsorships on.
Speaker 0: you know The ads that they show on Japanese television are still paying for this anime to be made.
Speaker 0: So why not?
Speaker 0: You know a week later put it on the internet, you know and make a few bucks extra off a couple of crappy ads.
Speaker 1: Well, it gives you a couple of things.
Speaker 1: one It gives you the moral imperative to get rid of the fansubbers now because their last excuse is gone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean What excuse to the fansubbers really?
Speaker 0: We wanted subtitled and we want it for free.
Speaker 0: Well you have both now.
Speaker 0: we want it immediately.
Speaker 0: Well, you can get that if you pay some money.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, it's a week late It's it's like how much faster do you really need it?
Speaker 0: Is it gonna make that much of a difference in your life?
Speaker 1: I foresee the thing is.
Speaker 1: the only thing they're not doing yet that I could see them doing Is having a third pillar of this and not like Nintendo's fake third pillar But a real third pillar if the show was on immediately for you know for the pay and then later for free.
Speaker 1: But there's the third option not DVDs but of buying Unencumbered DRM free versions that you can then watch on your iPhone and whatever that is.
Speaker 0: the one problem with this is by Streaming.
Speaker 0: there's no way to watch Naruto on the iPhone or anything like that Because have to be at a computer because it's out there free.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I think that'll really cut down on a lot of the casual piracy.
Speaker 1: So if you're doing it anyway, you might as well sell a really easy to watch like iTunes.
Speaker 1: Well, I think what it even if people pirated Yep Who cares?
Speaker 0: and I think even if it does not cut into the fansubbers right that they still prefer their fansubs to the.
Speaker 0: you know The the official release whatever.
Speaker 0: I think what it's gonna do is gonna get a. but you know There's only.
Speaker 0: so you go to look at a torrent.
Speaker 0: there's only like a thousand a few thousand people on these torrents, right?
Speaker 0: There's a lot more than a few thousand Naruto fans.
Speaker 0: I mean Otacon has 20-30,000 people at it, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, all of the Naruto fans in the world only a fraction of them get fansubs.
Speaker 0: So I think what's gonna happen is all the people who are not nerdy enough to even use bit torrent Which is which is stupidly easy are gonna go this way and you're actually gonna get a lot more Naruto watchers.
Speaker 0: you're gonna increase the Naruto audience and We're gonna go back to what the model for anime and such should be which is Put this stuff out.
Speaker 0: There's that people watch it and follow it and then make your money by selling them things that you know Actually are not piratable like Naruto headbands.
Speaker 1: Well, you know It's the same business model that South Park is using where you have the only replace the pay to watch it right away with Watch it right away on TV where the advertisers pay Mmm, but that's just one step away.
Speaker 1: I mean that's still within the grasp of the anime industry.
Speaker 1: the anime industry just needs to I don't know prove that it can play With the big boys and actually market to Americans average Americans normal people not just anime fans.
Speaker 0: Well, you know we said it a million times, right?
Speaker 0: Anime who's was big?
Speaker 0: if you look at the bigness of anime in this country when it's on TV It's big and when it's not on TV, it's not big.
Speaker 0: It's all about putting it on TV kids coming home from school watching it when they get home instead of watching something else, you know.
Speaker 0: And then going out.
Speaker 0: and you know I had Transformers and Voltron stuff when I was a kid because it was on TV when I got home.
Speaker 0: I would have never paid for Voltron on tape not in a million years.
Speaker 0: No, you know now I've got Voltron DVDs, but that's you know.
Speaker 0: besides the point it's not tape.
Speaker 0: it's not tape You know, it's all about if you you know making money off the stuff.
Speaker 0: when they put you know Back in the day when they put GI Joe on TV They were.
Speaker 0: you know The ads that went on TV with GI Joe were just there because they could.
Speaker 0: they didn't expect to make money off the show itself.
Speaker 0: They expected to make money by selling you GI Joe figures.
Speaker 0: that's how you make money with television.
Speaker 0: That's how it works, especially kids television, you know, even Sesame Street will sell you.
Speaker 0: tickle me Elmo.
Speaker 0: They don't give a shit and they're public TV.
Speaker 0: That's paid for by us and the government.
Speaker 1: and so what I really foresee happening now is I don't know if the mainstream You know on TV with ads again is gonna happen.
Speaker 1: But I definitely see this kind of fixing the problem where there are two classes of anime fans The younger fans or the casual fans who aren't willing to pay.
Speaker 1: and then you know the people like us who buy DVD box sets because Shows that are on right now the shows that appeal to the young Moneyless kids are the shows that'll be on Hulu all the time to watch.
Speaker 1: right now all the current stuff coming out that the kids really care about There's the classics the shows that are old and great that we want to watch or the shows that
Speaker 0: are already on DVD box sets
Speaker 1: Or the shows that just aren't popular enough initially to warrant this sort of attention.
Speaker 1: But then you know later people want those will be taken up by the DVD box sales.
Speaker 1: And I think in the end we're gonna have a kind of yeah Cuz if something balance has been restored to the force.
Speaker 0: Maybe cuz if this is just like you said if there's a show that's popular with the kiddies a kids show The only you can't make money from kids.
Speaker 0: you have to sell them You know by selling them video because they have infinite video and infinite time to watch it.
Speaker 0: You can only make money from kids by selling them toys and video games and stuff.
Speaker 1: But like ghost in the shell DVDs sold just fine from what I could tell.
Speaker 0: yeah You know you know ghost in the shell the anime sells itself You know and you put if you give that in the video of that away for free.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna.
Speaker 0: You can't sell too many ghosts in the shell toys because ghosts in the shell fans are not so much the toy buyers Really yeah, so I hope that's the way it goes And I hope they realize that just you know when you release an anime It's it's slim K You know it's.
Speaker 0: either go with the one model of free video and then sell merchandise or go with the other model of Immediate slim case box set skip all the other possible release models cuz no one wants that shit.
Speaker 1: Yep I guess the only other thing would be for shows that don't get kind of the full online treatment.
Speaker 1: If I were licensing stuff I would always make the first four episodes of any show I guess except a four episode show.
Speaker 1: yeah Four episode of OV sorry available for streaming if it was the show that I was gonna try to sell DVDs for.
Speaker 1: oh Yeah, definitely like that's not even like the fact that that isn't already done amazes me.
Speaker 0: mm-hmm plus I think you know.
Speaker 0: eventually when DVDs are sort of done You're gonna have to make some sort of you know download to watch in the iPhone and action.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know without DRM I've gotten to the point in my life where there's enough media that I Will no law like I will not stand for DRM.
Speaker 1: I'm streaming stuff.
Speaker 1: It's fine because I'm streaming it I don't care, but any media I download No amount of DRM is acceptable to me at this point because I could.
Speaker 1: there is always Unencumbered media that I already have that I can watch in lieu.
Speaker 0: I mean D. I mean DVDs technically have DRM.
Speaker 1: Effectively they don't.
Speaker 0: yeah, I know right a bit, but I what I do with DVDs these days I rip them to my iPhone format, and then put them away and don't look at them anymore You know.
Speaker 0: and then we just watch them by either streaming them from my computer down to the living room Or I watch them on my iPhone.
Speaker 0: We don't actually really put discs in the DVD players so much anymore Except for when the DVDs are really old and shitty and difficult to rip.
Speaker 0: yeah I guess yeah the best DRM in the world put the check.
Speaker 0: make shitty chapters on your DVDs.
Speaker 0: So no one wants to bother figuring that shit out.
Speaker 1: I can't say one thing though.
Speaker 1: I Wani fan subbers cried out at once and then we're suddenly silence.
Speaker 0: well We'll see most of the shows that you know.
Speaker 1: I guess the oh no They're gonna keep fans up and I know the way these people work.
Speaker 1: They're gonna keep fans up and keep pushing and keep trying to do their thing.
Speaker 1: But one I think there's gonna be a lot more legal pressure coming down on them, too.
Speaker 1: They're gonna lose the tacit support or at least the tacit indifference of the kind of Average anime fan who isn't a poor punk kid.
Speaker 0: see it's so weird right?
Speaker 0: It's like it's almost as if that when when the free Naruto streaming is not available Right the fan subbers seem bad like oh they deserve some sort of legal pressure right in some way They're doing right, but it's like imagine if I started um Recording South Park on my TiVo and then putting it on BitTorrent what?
Speaker 0: and it's online for free.
Speaker 0: who gives a shit?
Speaker 0: I'm not no one's even gonna download from me right, but somehow They're going to evolve separately.
Speaker 1: people who stay with the fan sub community are going to evolve much like the ouster's into a brand new breed of fan sub watching kids with different fan subs different words because I've know.
Speaker 1: eventually if that fan sub Documentary is true fan subs are just gonna be romanized versions of the Roger F and E's.
Speaker 0: I Don't know if this really counts as thing of the day, but whatever There's a website here den of geek and they made a little article right and the article was called.
Speaker 0: I think 70 comics that are being made into movies.
Speaker 0: And they went on to list 70 comics that are currently being made into movies and the year that they're expected to be released in.
Speaker 0: Then later they added five and I noticed that even after adding five and making it 75 comics being made into films right Surrogates is still not on the list and it says here pending updates and there are 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12 like 13 pending updates and surrogates isn't even listed there.
Speaker 0: So there are like a hundred comics currently being made into movies, but not surrogates Which was basically written so that Bruce Willis could.
Speaker 0: well, it's good.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 0: no I think surrogates is being made into movies.
Speaker 0: It's not on this list on this web page.
Speaker 0: is what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty long fucking crazy list.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of things on here and I would be surprised if 25% of the things in this list actually appeared in movie theaters.
Speaker 1: Where did they get their list from?
Speaker 1: did they just make it up?
Speaker 0: I think they just you know.
Speaker 1: Oh They have a link in every single one of these a link to one because I remember I recall I point out That when I was reading the Wikipedia are the links go to places like variety comm Ace showbiz.com.
Speaker 0: I don't know a lot of the comic book resources comm.
Speaker 0: most of them are to variety.
Speaker 1: point out the time we were talking about the scene at the tower in Seattle the Space Needle and There was that statement that was interesting about the guy punching out a bear and it was in fact cited Multiple sites.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm dubious of this list I am but the point is is that this is still a Pretty crazy thing.
Speaker 0: and if this list teaches you anything right is that Just buy some freaking comics.
Speaker 0: Why are you going to the movies?
Speaker 0: you can get all these things in their original forms well in advance for a lot less money.
Speaker 1: Well because movies and comics are different.
Speaker 0: Yeah But it's like really the whole.
Speaker 0: we should do a whole a show on the whole remake thing because on the one hand I don't have nearly as much vitriol as you do.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 0: it's not just.
Speaker 0: it's not really just vitriol.
Speaker 0: it's the fact that you know, we have, you know, these different mediums of artistic expression right and you know, there is Something to taking the same core idea and expressing it in different mediums and getting you know Not you're not gonna get the exact same result.
Speaker 0: It's impossible.
Speaker 0: right and there, you know things can be interesting that way.
Speaker 0: but there is also something to You know certain mediums right like movies.
Speaker 0: There's a lot, you know less original movie creations happening.
Speaker 0: At least it seems to be.
Speaker 0: then there used to be.
Speaker 1: yes I was about to say you're begging questions already.
Speaker 0: Whereas, you know in comics, you know, it's see, you know It seems like they're very a less percentage of remakes going on.
Speaker 1: I would argue that every continuing issue of x-men is a remake of x-men.
Speaker 0: I'm not counting I'm just counting your titles across the board.
Speaker 0: Not the x-factor x-force x-caliber But those are all.
Speaker 0: that's where those things are originally created.
Speaker 0: it wasn't comics it's not a remake.
Speaker 0: It's like it's a sequel.
Speaker 1: but I mean if different media can present different kinds of messages in different ways then sometimes it's just Remakes are for the better Like for example Lord of the Rings.
Speaker 1: the books are good and they're important and they're iconic and they're well-written and they're great.
Speaker 1: But I will admit that I enjoyed the movies more.
Speaker 0: Well, you're stupid.
Speaker 0: I mean the movies are great and all but the book is where it's at.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at the same time I'll admit openly that I skipped About half.
Speaker 0: maybe I can book.
Speaker 0: maybe that's why you didn't like it.
Speaker 1: They were walking and then I skipped a bunch and they were still walking.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was the important part in between.
Speaker 0: was the poetry that you missed?
Speaker 1: I've read the poetry It's just it didn't.
Speaker 1: what it conveyed was not the same thing that the movies conveyed?
Speaker 0: and no it was not.
Speaker 1: Yes, and I I didn't enjoy the books that much.
Speaker 1: I thought the Hobbit I enjoyed a lot more than the Lord of the Rings Actually enjoyed this Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: reading the Silmarillion was not terribly entertaining It was.
Speaker 1: it was almost like reading a Wikipedia article about a fantasy world.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is it's you got a brave.
Speaker 0: you take all of its parts together right as one unit Which it you know, it's the one book as a whole.
Speaker 0: it is sort of like a Wikipedia article.
Speaker 0: but if you treat these separate parts as almost their Individual novellas Then it comes across Completely differently like that that beginning part that like that's sort of like the Genesis story of Middle-earth is like on its own.
Speaker 0: It's like a man's and then you're like the the whole story of like You know Morgoth and a giant war with a million balrogs and a million dragons.
Speaker 1: and oh, man I don't find that.
Speaker 1: because the thing is that sort of story is no better than the dragon lands equivalent.
Speaker 1: Well, you know argue that dragon lands books existed solely to give you that moment over and over and over again.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing about the Lord of the Rings right books is that they were well written.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah It's not.
Speaker 0: you know in what the content of the stories were even though at the time that was relatively original content Relatively, you know, whereas today we have that same exact content repeated a million times in for said dragon lands books.
Speaker 0: But in that the fashion the poetic fashion in which it was written is the important thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, yes, and I very much I adore the poetic fashion But I guess my point is is that one I need a synonym for poetry to sound less.
Speaker 1: One books worth of it was enough for me.
Speaker 0: I can even read the you know, tiny Tom Bombadil short story that is separate from everything else and still be rocking the house.
Speaker 1: Well, that store is awesome.
Speaker 1: Why why don't you then go and read the collected works of works of Keats before we continue?
Speaker 0: Because I still have to read the collected works of Milton.
Speaker 1: Do you actually intend to read the works of Milton?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: but what I do know is that pretty much What drove you to read?
Speaker 1: the works of milk?
Speaker 0: I will.
Speaker 0: that was about to tell you.
Speaker 1: I'm just curious because it came up in Hyperion.
Speaker 0: I know All over the place right you did?
Speaker 1: you hit the word Milton ask near the end and suddenly think no No, it wasn't that.
Speaker 0: okay, it's that you know all over the place.
Speaker 0: throughout my entire life I've encountered, you know such-and-such works of Milton Milton Milton and I'm like.
Speaker 0: I don't even know who Milton was.
Speaker 0: I just I think how could he just have one name?
Speaker 0: He doesn't have two names.
Speaker 0: He only has one name.
Speaker 0: He's like Homer.
Speaker 0: just one name and somehow he's mentioned everywhere Must be important.
Speaker 0: He must have some works somewhere that I can read Mentioned so many places, but maybe I should read them.
Speaker 1: but what I would point out is that one you have access Scott to Infinite information more information than you could process in your entire lifetime.
Speaker 1: Yep at any time Yeah at any point in your life You could have looked up who Milton was and what he brought.
Speaker 0: at no point in time was I simultaneously Thinking about Milton and also in the access of Wikipedia to having nearby.
Speaker 1: and I also have to say Walt while Milton is very important.
Speaker 1: I have not come across people referencing Milton that often I was.
Speaker 0: he was referenced enough for me to remember his single name.
Speaker 1: people reference Dante a lot more and I'll be honest I did not enjoy the Divine Comedy.
Speaker 0: I did not read any Dante's.
Speaker 1: Anyway, my thing of the day to get right into the but I know more about him.
Speaker 1: I know the very important main bit here the show that I've been dying to talk about.
Speaker 0: Oh dying in hell.
Speaker 1: jikoku space invaders.
Speaker 1: jikoku Space invaders.
Speaker 0: this all right you think of the day.
Speaker 1: This is a touching music video.
Speaker 1: I it's touching.
Speaker 1: the music's good.
Speaker 1: the story.
Speaker 1: the story that there is, you know, it's a music video is good and it's space invaders.
Speaker 1: I like the song a lot.
Speaker 1: I like this a lot.
Speaker 1: I don't know what else I can say except that you should watch it and feel touched.
Speaker 1: Touched not in the way that Krauser Sama will touch Vader.
Speaker 0: He invades you and he touches you in a Krauser invaded something like the most famous early episode of South Park.
Speaker 1: Okay So tonight, that's all That I'm hoping none of you have seen because you should go out and watch it.
Speaker 1: It's short.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good.
Speaker 1: It's fresh.
Speaker 1: So all you people saying we don't talk about new anime.
Speaker 1: Here we go Detroit metal city Troy tomato lashiti AKA the wacky hijinks of Krauser Sahn and his merry pain Krauser time.
Speaker 0: So lately, you know, I've been really big on like these sort of like these shorter anime shows You know like they've existed before, you know, they're old shows like Ipatsu Kiki Musume where it's a. you know a bunch of short episodes, maybe not even a bunch maybe just like ten of them.
Speaker 0: right and Instead of going all out with a 26 episode series, you know And this is usually done for strictly like short comedy things Look at a show like Dama go dobutsu, right a lot of short episodes that are mostly just you know quick short funny stories.
Speaker 0: They don't have a lot of.
Speaker 0: you know, those quiet scenes of looking at the sky for 30 seconds.
Speaker 1: Hey, wait, what about that?
Speaker 1: Really bad.
Speaker 1: I will not name it because it was so bad Nazi show that was all short episode.
Speaker 1: If you say the name two more times, we'll have to watch it.
Speaker 0: You'll summon it from hell You know, I just that kind of show, you know, Gog manga VRE, you know like these shows that are just based on gag manga many of them and Translated into short episodes are just.
Speaker 0: they're really up my alley and I'm always looking out for them.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: when DMC first appeared I first found out about it because I download number one of every fan sub and I saw Detroit metal city.
Speaker 0: I said well got to download that.
Speaker 1: see I guess I already knew about it from Emily.
Speaker 1: But you know, there's live-action and the anime and the manga.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so basically the deal is those is manga, right?
Speaker 0: And I think the manga is still going.
Speaker 0: I've read all five Currently published volumes in scans lation form.
Speaker 0: the scans lations weren't that great but I understood what was going on mostly because I had seen the anime and Studio 4c took the first two volumes of the manga and translated each and every chapter Directly to anime.
Speaker 0: this is a direct like.
Speaker 0: we were just talking about how remakes and other mediums How you can't make the exact same thing.
Speaker 0: They came as close to making the exact same thing as you can possibly do right there the the at.
Speaker 0: you watch the anime and hold up the chapter of the manga in front of you and every single panel is animated and they look exactly the same and they didn't animate anything that wasn't in a panel at basically at all.
Speaker 0: and No, no panel is missing from the animation.
Speaker 0: Well much and the dialogue is almost identical.
Speaker 1: much of it is animated in this.
Speaker 1: I don't want to say sparse but it's often it looks like a manga panel like you had this perspective of a scene and then they've kind of Animated the characters moving around within that one scene.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like an animated manga panel.
Speaker 0: But so for example if there was a scene where someone's waving a guitar back and forth in the manga you see the person standing There with the guitar over their head and motion lines to indicate waving maybe a blurry guitar in three places Right and the anime.
Speaker 0: it's literally the same person standing in the same pose But the camera at the same angle and the screen is sort of cut off so you don't see any.
Speaker 0: you know anything around them.
Speaker 0: That wasn't in the original manga panel and it is animate them waving the guitar back and forth while their mouth moves and a voice Actor reads the line,
Speaker 1: but that's not to say the animation is cheap because
Speaker 0: a lot of the studio for see bitches
Speaker 1: The concert scenes and anytime they're kind of actually animating something as opposed to using
Speaker 0: this.
Speaker 0: look at the opener.
Speaker 1: Yes There a lot of like.
Speaker 1: the episode we just watched a little while ago was like the concert.
Speaker 1: They animated a good deal of concert and it would have been an awesome concert to be had.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I think it was great is out.
Speaker 0: Let us to spoil the episode, right?
Speaker 0: Well, let's tell the premise of the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know make more sense.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna read the plot summary from the anime news that come on.
Speaker 1: Detroit a metal city is a to Quickly rising independent death metal band.
Speaker 1: they garner fame by performing wildlife shows Songs filled with hate violence and rape.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: They say they're filled with hate violence and rape.
Speaker 1: They're filled with the words hate violence and rape primarily rape and and hell if you are not down With people making fun of rape and rape related situations.
Speaker 0: Well, it's weird.
Speaker 0: it's like on the one hand right you have, you know things like The works of Kazuko.
Speaker 0: Okay, where in some cases rape occurs and it's you know.
Speaker 0: It's like they're being a rape in a movie.
Speaker 0: It's you know, it's.
Speaker 0: it's not making fun of rape.
Speaker 0: It's there's a story and there's rape in it and it's.
Speaker 0: you can tell legitimate stories where rapes happen, right?
Speaker 0: And then you have other Kazuko came Aga where there are just sort of gratuitous Unnecessary rapes that are not cool and you sort of you know It's hard to figure out what to do with those and you can make tasteless jokes about them.
Speaker 0: And you have things like rape man, which are just tasteless all around.
Speaker 0: but in this This is I think the one You're treading very carefully.
Speaker 0: I know it's.
Speaker 0: it's like the way that rape is treated.
Speaker 0: it's like even I Think that maybe even someone maybe because I obviously never been raped.
Speaker 0: but If there was if there was a rape joke or a joke involving the word rape that a person who had been raped Could possibly in some universe laugh at if this is not it then it doesn't exist.
Speaker 1: I think what might help though is that they use the English word for rape most of the time do they?
Speaker 0: I?
Speaker 0: Can't tell.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: I use a lot of English words Yes, but basically the story is really about Nagishi show so itchy who is shoe each.
Speaker 1: Yes, a young guy fresh out of school wants to be musician.
Speaker 1: He's pretty good.
Speaker 0: He finished college.
Speaker 1: He's you know, 20 something is really into Swedish pop music and the really lame kind of Kind of music.
Speaker 0: yeah, he likes, you know sort of just like happy sing-song like he fokie pop.
Speaker 1: He listens to idol singers.
Speaker 0: He's basically if the dude wasn't so like having a crush on this girl from college.
Speaker 0: You would think he was gay, but he's.
Speaker 0: he totally has the super crush on this girl.
Speaker 0: So there's no way he's gay He's just so lame.
Speaker 1: I mean he's lame to the point.
Speaker 0: They really like use fashion.
Speaker 1: Music is lame among.
Speaker 0: he's got like a musician got like an Amelie poster on his wall And I like that movie, but I don't have a poster of it on my wall.
Speaker 0: cuz I'm not gay You know, he's just.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't use the word gay I just use the word really really really lame.
Speaker 1: Well, I is so lame Yeah, and wishy-washy.
Speaker 0: It's not lame It's just that his interests are those sort of interests, you know as among the crowd of people who have similar interest He's a cool happening dude.
Speaker 1: Uh kind of cuz.
Speaker 1: remember when he goes to that coffee shop and like hey you want to perform he sings a song and the Guy who's into that stuff is like wow Well, no, but he was.
Speaker 0: the thing is in that scene, right?
Speaker 0: It's like he's totally getting along with all the people who were hanging out there Except that his music is no good.
Speaker 0: cuz that's the thing.
Speaker 0: is he why he's a musician?
Speaker 0: He's actually good at singing and playing the guitar.
Speaker 0: The thing is when he plays the pop music.
Speaker 0: He likes to play He's bad at it.
Speaker 0: His pop music is no good.
Speaker 0: It's you know, the pot like the pop music he likes, you know to listen to like.
Speaker 0: well You keep mentioning like I don't know if it's a real pop singer or not, but like kahimi curry or whatever You know some pop singing girl who they made up for the show me.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what?
Speaker 1: Most of the reason why I think he's lame is that Personality wise he is really lame.
Speaker 1: He's wishy-washy He doesn't stand up for himself.
Speaker 1: He's passive-aggressive He's kind of selfish and stalker II.
Speaker 1: he's just really not a great person kind of a no I don't know.
Speaker 0: He seems to you know, he seems like want good things like, you know, he wants you know, like his Like his brother to do well in school and he cares about.
Speaker 0: He cares about his family and he you know any he cares about you know, his friends.
Speaker 1: There is definitely this this darkness that is just waiting to get out of him because the darkness comes out quite often.
Speaker 1: His real job the only job in music he could get is being the lead singer for a horrible death metal band Detroit Metal City.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 0: It's you know to him.
Speaker 0: It's horrible death metal to us.
Speaker 0: It's just sort of normal metal, you know, but We've been to many concerts that were harder than this Thing.
Speaker 0: is this the way metal is portrayed in this show is sort of a stereotypical kiss sort of metal, you know, it's It's not.
Speaker 0: it means a little harder than kiss and less partying but it's definitely that sort of.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, people are in a costume and the people in the crowd are moshing it and they're saying hell and rape a lot It's scary.
Speaker 0: No, it's just you know, it's just music.
Speaker 1: That's out at the same time it I feel you know.
Speaker 1: as a fan of metal I can't at least say that it.
Speaker 1: it takes a lot of the Things that are worth making fun of about metal and makes fun of them in a way That is funny to people who like metal, especially the best character in the show the president of the record label.
Speaker 1: The way she motivates the band is she'll be sitting there and they start playing a song she'll be like, oh But warning we're gonna be kind of offensive for the rest of this show.
Speaker 0: It's weird how this show Basically by being so overt in its offensiveness is not offensive.
Speaker 1: It's actually kind of inoffensive because it's so offensive.
Speaker 0: yeah, it like neuters the offensive things they're saying by saying them in such an Immature cheap and shallow way that they carry no weight that they would usually care.
Speaker 0: but
Speaker 1: like here's an example they're in the recording studio making a CD and he has to play his part and He plays it kind of okay and then the president walks in and kicks him in the balls and says and I'm quoting loosely Shit, fuck I can't get wet with that play something that'll make my cunt go crazy.
Speaker 1: Fuck.
Speaker 0: Yeah Great.
Speaker 1: Yes, and she just never stopped.
Speaker 1: like, you know in those cute shows like characters will like blah blah blah blah blah Icarus or Blah blah blah blah blah like they have their weird little catchphrase.
Speaker 1: She just ends every sentence with fuck
Speaker 0: Yeah, like there was one time where they were like, okay we need suggestions where the band should do and one, you know, he's like I want pop music and you're just like Yeah, and then the other guy's like hey something something she's like, uh-huh.
Speaker 0: And then like the drummer is just like I really want you know Some some kind of food like some salmon or something.
Speaker 0: She's like fuck and the middle fingers like pops up.
Speaker 0: That was all she said to.
Speaker 0: that was just.
Speaker 1: but the middle fingers pretty much always up It's just.
Speaker 0: it increases in intensity and she always has like a bottle of some sort of you know, alcohol.
Speaker 0: It's great.
Speaker 1: In one episode she's got a bottle of Jim Beam and it's just like on the desk and she's clearly swinging from it.
Speaker 1: The next episode she's got a bottle of wild turkey.
Speaker 1: great But it's like two episodes later.
Speaker 1: It's a bottle of Jack.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she just caused like spilling it all over herself But somehow she knows how to run the record company, even though she's completely insane.
Speaker 1: But the point of this show is that I mean what sums it up so that he you know He's the front man for this band.
Speaker 1: He's the lead singer.
Speaker 1: He hates it But at the same time he has this deep down sense of pride in what he does.
Speaker 1: I think what we'll explain to you why the show is awesome more than anything is.
Speaker 1: I think it's the second episode where He's trying to kind of distance himself from his work and he's trying to relax.
Speaker 1: So he goes out into the street and he's playing his lame crappy pop music.
Speaker 0: And You know, no one's even paying attention to them.
Speaker 0: They're just walking by ignoring him, but he's happy.
Speaker 1: and then here's noise And he looks and there's this crowd of people and they're around some guy who's a fan of DMC And the guys like playing a song pretty badly and everyone's getting all pumped up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's going like, you know He's basically got a guitar and he's going to did and he's going rape rape rape rape rape rape and every and all these people Start getting crowding around this guy with a guitar and a little amp going.
Speaker 0: And meanwhile, he's sitting there playing his pop music trying to ignore them and no one's paying attention to him at all.
Speaker 1: But he starts to think like, uh, if I if I just was the real crowds Well, he's.
Speaker 0: no he's like I'm the real thing and they're not paying attention to me.
Speaker 0: They're paying attention to that lame cover band over there.
Speaker 0: What the fuck.
Speaker 1: but then the crowd is like Telling him to be quiet because he's getting in the way of their enjoyment of this really lame concert and he loses it.
Speaker 1: So he puts on his Krauser costume and Krauser appears takes the guitar and Unleashes, you know, he's playing pretty wickedly but people don't believe it's really him.
Speaker 1: They're like, but Krauser really be here.
Speaker 1: How could this be?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it could just be someone in a Krauser costume.
Speaker 0: I mean if I put on a Gene Simmons costume, you know and I practice, you know learning to play some You know fight like five kiss songs go out into the subway and just start rocking out.
Speaker 0: No one's gonna believe it's him at all.
Speaker 0: And you know, so I would need to do something to prove that I'm him Like have sex with a thousand women and have an incredibly long tongue.
Speaker 1: So he whips out the patented ten rapes per second.
Speaker 1: Shout.
Speaker 0: He basically says that one.
Speaker 0: he has a lot of these.
Speaker 0: it's weird because in many ways the show while being a music show Sort of similar to Beck is also very similar to a shonen fighting show.
Speaker 0: He has all these moves like special attacks that he uses like the crazy teeth guitar.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like he plays teeth guitar.
Speaker 0: He plays guitar behind the head.
Speaker 0: That's also a special technique.
Speaker 0: He has the.
Speaker 0: was it the gold the demon?
Speaker 0: What's it called the demon jewel?
Speaker 1: Oh my god everyone in the audience.
Speaker 0: my god Transfers all their evil power to him and then he unleashes it in a giant loogie.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, but the did.
Speaker 1: the demon jewel comes into play in The most horrifying way you can imagine Later in the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's got a bunch of special moves.
Speaker 1: Oh my Moa Fashionable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the one special movie has is that he can say the word rape ten times in one second And he does that for one of the songs and of course the crowd is like it's really him.
Speaker 1: ten rapes Even we can do that.
Speaker 0: It's even a point in the manga where he sneaks up behind someone and he's not in his costume But he talks in the Krauser voice and he wants them to believe he's Krauser.
Speaker 0: She was like don't hurt.
Speaker 0: He's like don't turn around.
Speaker 0: They're like, oh my god, it's Krauser.
Speaker 0: He's like, how do I know?
Speaker 0: It's really you could be faking.
Speaker 0: He's like I will say right?
Speaker 0: He's like, how can I prove that?
Speaker 0: It's me.
Speaker 0: He's like say rape ten times a second.
Speaker 0: He's like he whispers rape ten times a second.
Speaker 0: Of course it's like oh, I know it's you I won't turn around.
Speaker 1: there's a plot of one episode Where he tries to kick it up to 11.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a good episode starts bleeding In the manga, he gets it up to 12.
Speaker 0: What I'm not dying.
Speaker 0: I couldn't tell you but Any more than that other than there are 12 rapes per second in the manga.
Speaker 1: now this is where the show saw shines where it's just you know, You get the cut between his real life and his real life and you know He's kind of real personality.
Speaker 1: and the Krauser personality and how he doesn't like being Krauser.
Speaker 1: He hates Krauser hates the band But yet he's still really really proud of how good he is at being Krauser because he's great at it.
Speaker 1: So he keeps having to prove to people how great Krauser is Even though he doesn't want to.
Speaker 0: he's also must be getting paid a lot of money to be Krauser at least relative to what it You know in a successful indie band gets because he doesn't really have to do any other jobs And he's always when he's not.
Speaker 0: you know being Krauser you can hang out and do it every once and he like he's living in A very small apartment, you know.
Speaker 0: in Tokyo though and in one episode the president comes over.
Speaker 0: It is like you're living in this tiny fucking apartment.
Speaker 0: You know what's wrong with you and he you know He has a reason for liking the small apartments where he lived in college and the guy who's the landlord.
Speaker 0: He's really friendly with him and he likes him and he's a cool guy.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: when the guy uncle she gay or whatever his name is the landlord got because the president decides to Metal up his life.
Speaker 1: So she brings these two Cho Aniki looking guys over.
Speaker 1: Okay She basically forces him down.
Speaker 1: I love this.
Speaker 1: This is the I guess present.
Speaker 0: They're more hard gay than show Aniki.
Speaker 1: this is kind of the perception that I guess Japanese people might have about.
Speaker 1: Americans are about marijuana, but Marijuana does not make people act.
Speaker 1: the way marijuana makes him act.
Speaker 0: Well, I think that was demonstrating that he didn't know how marijuana makes people act cuz he's a lame, you know.
Speaker 0: So it was you know, I think it was actually accurate in showing Hey, this guy doesn't know is is totally you know, not doing any drugs or anything and he that he smokes the weed But he doesn't inhale it and then he pretends to get high.
Speaker 0: and it's showing you him pretending to get high poorly.
Speaker 1: But I love the fact that they basically kidnapped the landlord and bring him into this crab and by the end He's like whoo Detroit Metal City.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even though he's like this old quiet dude who's kind of kind of cool.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's like a friendly grandpa.
Speaker 1: The show is full of just memorable moments, I mean it's okay after all I'm a masochist.
Speaker 1: That was like the funniest moment in the show.
Speaker 0: It was a pretty good moment right there.
Speaker 0: I mean, basically there's a guy who's part of the band capitalist pig.
Speaker 0: He's the capitalist pig right and basically he doesn't play any instrument.
Speaker 0: He just wears like S&M gear and crowds.
Speaker 0: he sits on the stage You know wiggling around and Krauser kicks him and beats him up during the show and then after the show he Apologizes to him like he's like, oh would I hurt you?
Speaker 0: He's like.
Speaker 0: no, it's okay I'm a masochist that you know, I like getting beat up whatever.
Speaker 0: and then you know because he you know, he in real life he feels bad about this guy that he kicks around all the time and He finds out that the guy is working at a convenience store and as a crush on a girl.
Speaker 0: So he tries to help him out and to make a long story short He fails to help him out and the guy ends up getting hurt, you know Because it's like oh he ruined his chances with that girl and the guy's like he smiles.
Speaker 0: He's like it's okay.
Speaker 0: I'm a masochist.
Speaker 0: he likes it that the guy tried to help him and I ended up hurting him because he likes being hurt and
Speaker 1: Things just escalate and escalate like I'm not gonna ruin this one, but there's a point where maybe a concert hall catches on fire yeah, and Maybe people are trying to get out and maybe he has to take his wig off.
Speaker 1: But but people see it and the way the crowd what the crowd assumes is going on when he is taking his wig off Versus what is actually happening?
Speaker 1: It's very fortune worthy.
Speaker 0: Oh very much.
Speaker 0: Oh my god I think it is very good.
Speaker 0: The anime is only 12 episodes long and it covers I think about 24 manga chapters.
Speaker 0: right now the fur.
Speaker 0: I said it covers the first two volumes of the manga.
Speaker 0: But there are a couple differences.
Speaker 0: the very first chapter of the manga not in there not at all, right?
Speaker 0: - there's.
Speaker 0: - Oh mock is cuz.
Speaker 0: every manga volume has no market at the end.
Speaker 0: The first Oh makay is not in there.
Speaker 0: The second Oh makay is in there.
Speaker 0: rim just saw it.
Speaker 0: And also one of the chapters of the manga was moved from its original Sequence to the end of the entire anime series
Speaker 1: much like Takashi real scale in initial D
Speaker 0: Yes, and for that was for dramatic effect because you need to end the anime series with you know Some sort of significant chapter.
Speaker 0: so they just moved this significant chapter where something kind of cool happens to the end In volume three of the manga.
Speaker 0: There's a tournament.
Speaker 1: I am NOT kidding you shown in fighting show.
Speaker 0: It is in many ways a shown in fighting show.
Speaker 0: But as soon as that the tournament ends the show and in fighting aspects diminish And they sort of go back to the back and forth, you know regular, you know, the the conflict.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 0: the show has three conflicts going on at once.
Speaker 0: right you have The conflict of you know, this kid not kid.
Speaker 0: This dude has a metal life and a non metal life.
Speaker 0: He's not metal, you know for real.
Speaker 0: But he is metal for real and it's he's got this internal conflict with him and in his daily life between these two things His jaw is his professional metal life and his regular life, but in his regular life within that world He's a conflict of trying to get with his girl Right, and of course the metal comes in and interferes with that.
Speaker 0: on the other hand girls tried to destroy the metal, right?
Speaker 0: He's got conflicts within the metal world You know DMC versus other bands and DMC trying to make it big and when he MC Trying to you know get better concert.
Speaker 0: But when he has to compete with the testicle girls this punk Anti-man all-girl band and when he competes with this hip-hop guy Right, and of course is you know, the fact that he's not really metal comes into play on that side, too.
Speaker 0: So that interesting sort of even though a lot of the Joe, you know Even though the show is hit or miss a lot of the time and the manga is really hit or miss, you know It's like wow that chapter was sort of lame or wow what happened in the chapter was sort of weird or annoying or Stupid or whatever.
Speaker 0: other chapters are just like tremendous win and The fact that there are multiple Aspects and different things the show can lean on at different times is what saves it because in any given episode Even if you know something lame happens in one department There's awesome stuff going on like in the metal world and you're like, yes there's always something even in the badge or the worst chapters to grab on to and Even though it's the same joke over and over again It's like at when I first saw the show and first found out about it.
Speaker 0: I thought it was gonna be one of those things where okay, I get the joke.
Speaker 0: I've seen the first episode.
Speaker 0: I don't need to watch anymore.
Speaker 0: It's the same joke a hundred times.
Speaker 0: I Could probably watch and/or read every DMC ever even if it's not they make it at least eight episodes before.
Speaker 1: the rape jokes are Not that funny anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like even though I can see the jokes coming a mile away and it's not that great It's not the greatest thing ever.
Speaker 0: I could still go for it.
Speaker 0: It's not, you know, it'll still be sort of funny and entertaining.
Speaker 0: It's like and it's still good situation.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'll admit by about it.
Speaker 1: right around episode eight I had started petering out for me because they just yeah, it definitely made the biggest rape joke like they made it.
Speaker 1: It was there nice.
Speaker 0: That was a great episode.
Speaker 1: He has performed the greatest rape you're going to see in this show.
Speaker 1: It's over that is it.
Speaker 1: and yet They just keep making less funny rape jokes after that where I feel as if they'd moved on to another rape joke.
Speaker 1: No joke, that wasn't rape and they could have done better, but they kept making the rape jokes instead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it does.
Speaker 0: you know if Peters around and is in sputters a little bit?
Speaker 1: and the other thing I can say is that the Krauser antics parts are always a lot funnier than the his real-life part.
Speaker 0: I definitely got to say.
Speaker 0: I also agree that You know the parts of the show where it's what's going on in the metal world.
Speaker 0: It's definitely the part of the show that I enjoy the most.
Speaker 0: but when you get to the tournament, right?
Speaker 0: You're pretty much getting all that.
Speaker 0: you're getting all just metal world.
Speaker 0: what's going on with metal, you know.
Speaker 1: And that's what I want because the legend of Krauser is all I really want to see evolving.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, it's kind of weird.
Speaker 0: it's like a lot of bands out there try to you know, either artificially or Not artificially create sort of like this mystical legend around themselves, you know Even the Beatles have sort of like, you know, they're all.
Speaker 0: Paul is dead You know, what's the?
Speaker 0: it's all like these secrets and mysteries and some sort of like, you know Magical history and if you like look through the CD be like the albums and the lyrics like this.
Speaker 0: maybe some story that's going on, you know, and That's a. that's a thing that a lot of bands especially metal bands will do and in this show One of the best things about it is they show how accidentally completely by accident not trying to They create this legend of DMC, you know They he wrote he killed his parents and raped their corpses and came from hell.
Speaker 0: and you know all these things that Krauser has done, you know not are not true or they're partially true and It's just kind of cool how you start to think well Maybe you know the real bands in the real world to have these sort of legends.
Speaker 0: Maybe they created them by accident.
Speaker 0: Also, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I just think it's kind of cool and kind of kind of clever sometimes how things that happen in the show Translate into the legend of Krauser.
Speaker 1: Yes, and the the big rape that I was talking about really plays into that.
Speaker 1: of course, you know pretty much every.
Speaker 1: They're all rapes at least for the first day of eight episodes.
Speaker 1: It's not all rape.
Speaker 1: Well, there's the one five times.
Speaker 0: It's just the word rape without any actual rapid Yes that you won't ever actually see a rape.
Speaker 1: However things happen that cause Fans and people remembering events to think back and think wow.
Speaker 1: He totally raped that blank.
Speaker 1: Yeah He totally killed those cops because remember Krauser was a demon born from hell who killed it and raped his parents.
Speaker 1: They don't really specify in what order.
Speaker 1: as a child Yep, yeah, I gotta say this.
Speaker 0: I think the main thing about that I think the main thing is that while the show like It's like if you listen to like a real disgusting offensive metal band like say a cannibal corpse or something like that that this is like The fact that this is just sort of in a way parodying that even though it's still doing the offensive things Really it's sort of like being offensive with like, you know a squishy hammer.
Speaker 0: in a way It's sort of you know what I'm saying Plus the show.
Speaker 1: watch this with a group of people because the more people are that are in the room with you The funnier it is all gonna be.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep I would I would definitely have showed this at the anime club where I saw a hundred times a million.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: In fact, I think I would have shown like one episode of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah at a time.
Speaker 0: my recommendation to people is that you should watch You know all 12 episodes of the anime and if you really really like it like you're still you watch them all and you're still like feeling it then you can read the manga and Then there's gonna be a live-action movie or there is.
Speaker 0: it's just not available in English in any way yet, you know, whatever I'm totally gonna watch that no matter what and but I can't say yes or no on it because I haven't seen it.
Speaker 0: But I'm gonna go out and get it ASAP just to see what the deal is.
Speaker 0: because if it's a live-action Movie, they'll actually probably tell you know, like one cohesive story They'll actually be people in crazy costumes and that can be pretty fun.
Speaker 0: Even if it's not gonna be good But it is a good show.
Speaker 1: I can say that much.
Speaker 1: and the opening song while it's not the best song in the world Satsugai is pretty pretty catchy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you.
Speaker 0: look at it.
Speaker 1: other shows It's not really death medley like while the lyrics are yes Well, it's not death metal.
Speaker 1: raise money rape your parents kill everybody murder murder.
Speaker 1: But it sounds kind of Metallica ish.
Speaker 0: It's sort of normal metal.
Speaker 0: It's not death metal, but the Other shows like look at like Beck I mentioned before and some others right that are about music.
Speaker 0: You know shows about music that are translated from manga.
Speaker 0: Right Beck was a manga that turned into an anime.
Speaker 0: and you look in the manga There are music lyrics and then in the anime they actually have songs that match a lot of those lyrics pretty closely and Are all.
Speaker 0: most of them are actually good songs or you know.
Speaker 0: and in DMC They in the manga there are lots of lyrics to songs and in the anime They made songs that use the lyrics from the manga.
Speaker 0: But the songs that they made aren't always good songs and you can tell that the quality of the songs was often limited because they had they were trying to stick to the original lyrics as they were in the manga and As such like only Satsu guy is sort of a you know Pretty good catchy opening kind of song.
Speaker 0: they can get you a little bit energized but a lot of the other songs either come off as weird or They only like sing a very small part of those songs as they obviously didn't come up with an entire song To match the lyrics or whatever.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's it's you know, it's alright.
Speaker 0: the music will not bother you and If you like metal at all, you might actually, you know, like some of the music I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's kind of lame.
Speaker 0: It's more about the jokes than about the music.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: I recommend this show to pretty much everyone Anyone anyone plus.
Speaker 1: if you need any further prompting I have three words for you Detroit moe city.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's by far the greatest part.
Speaker 0: That was the one part that I refused to tell and I made rim watch it just before we did this.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, because it it almost in a way Epitomizes the true spirit of metal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the old makay from the end of the second volume of manga that you know.
Speaker 0: That was animated at the end of like I think the like tenth episode of the anime.
Speaker 0: They just stuck it on the end there and it that's that's really what I you know.
Speaker 0: Like it not just metal but all geekeries is like.
Speaker 0: yes, that is you know, how even scary geekeries?
Speaker 0: You know people are like that and that's that's what's awesome is that kind of thing?
Speaker 0: And that's that's how people really are and you know go to like an anime con or a gaming con or any sort of.
Speaker 0: you Know gathering of like-minded people that is the sort of that You know.
Speaker 0: that really illustrates the sort of awesomeness and awesome feelings that go down.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front road crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.