Speaker 1: It's Wednesday August 6th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: very briefly and somewhat disorganized Lee we talked about Kinetic on.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well, it's Wednesday the Wednesday before Otak on which means I don't know how how good our show will be tonight because we got to get on the road at like 8 in the morning.
Speaker 0: I'm doing laundry as we speak.
Speaker 0: I have unpacking things as we speak.
Speaker 0: I'm rearranging the computer Still putting together two of our panels and Tomorrow morning in the car we go to be more.
Speaker 1: Oh and don't forget.
Speaker 1: We might have a sixth panel.
Speaker 1: what we'll see about that?
Speaker 0: Well only four of the panels we're doing so.
Speaker 1: yes one of them will be there, but Katzen or you'll be doing most of it.
Speaker 1: I'll be up there in armor fighting for my honor that smelly armor I feel bad for you and Scott will be in the background far away from the fighting with a video camera to catalog my Untimely demise.
Speaker 0: yeah, that'll be worth it.
Speaker 1: I guess Yeah, but you know once again welcome all you.
Speaker 1: Kinetic on listeners.
Speaker 1: I'm sure you're here for the con report that we promised yesterday.
Speaker 1: as you know geek nights is four nights a week blah blah blah and Wednesdays is anime manga and comics.
Speaker 0: Oh my god Are we gonna talk about anime manga comics not a lot?
Speaker 1: We're gonna talk about an anime con because you know as I said we're going to Otak on tomorrow.
Speaker 1: things are a little crazy.
Speaker 0: I don't know that you know before we actually get to it.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I mean sure we're gonna do.
Speaker 0: we are gonna do the Kinetic on review tonight But I really feel either it should have been split up into Tuesday Wednesday or more.
Speaker 0: really I think more.
Speaker 0: just Tuesday Kinetic on is an everything geek con.
Speaker 0: It's not just anime manga and comics.
Speaker 0: You know it's all.
Speaker 0: it's got web comics, but it's got a lot of gaming going on there a lot.
Speaker 0: And you know I feel like maybe even the Kinetic on review should be on a Tuesday.
Speaker 0: Or maybe we should move all convention related things to Thursday, or I don't know.
Speaker 1: see what I'm thinking is anime cons We should talk about on Wednesdays Cons we should talk about on Tuesdays Kinetic on and things like that.
Speaker 1: We should probably talk about on Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well that's okay, then because you know what we were supposed to do a Thursday episode this week.
Speaker 0: What do you say?
Speaker 0: we put this episode up and just tomorrow now?
Speaker 1: We should put it up tonight because it's a Wednesday show.
Speaker 0: yeah But I mean it should be.
Speaker 0: you know we are supposed to do a Thursday this week and not a Wednesday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there are recording it Wednesday because we have to leave Thursday, so Whatever, it'll be a Wednesday show because we said it would be and we'll kind of rearrange all this business.
Speaker 0: It's okay.
Speaker 0: We can do some post-hoc retcon Haha later.
Speaker 1: and also just in case you're wondering we're gonna be out of town next week on our annual writers retreat Which is a codename for doing jack and shit and fuck and all.
Speaker 0: but Have no fear and you're in mom.
Speaker 1: for the many previous years We would have guest hosts of geek nights and this year We I totally dropped the ball and didn't follow up on any of that at all.
Speaker 0: I mean we had some volunteers.
Speaker 1: We didn't really follow up.
Speaker 0: We went around and some people agreed to it.
Speaker 0: some people couldn't do it on time.
Speaker 0: Basically we are too busy doing other shit, and we didn't do it and we suck however Instead of not doing shows for a week.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be in Wildwood, but we've got internet access.
Speaker 1: We've got a Marantz We've got our microphones.
Speaker 1: We've got everything.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do some geek nights live at the beach.
Speaker 0: We're gonna try to do some geek nights live at the beach.
Speaker 1: I promise there will be at least one episode of geek nights uploaded at some point next week.
Speaker 0: That is very likely more than one.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't bet.
Speaker 1: maybe not maybe or four.
Speaker 0: No to it most people.
Speaker 0: that's what you're gonna get.
Speaker 0: maybe?
Speaker 1: yeah, we might have geek nights live at the beach.
Speaker 1: We might have geek nights live in Atlantic City.
Speaker 0: Also, here's something else right.
Speaker 0: if you want to do a guest episode of geek nights and you can record it and edit the whole mp3 and do the whole thing on your own and Email either email it to us or better yet email us a link to a place We can download it.
Speaker 0: then we could actually go and pretty easily.
Speaker 0: if we just go to internet cafe You know go and add it to the website, so all right I'm gonna say it right now.
Speaker 1: not many of you are capable of doing no very few people.
Speaker 0: I mean we're gonna listen to it And we're gonna make a pretty quick judgment like within a minute of whether we deem it worthy.
Speaker 1: You mean like all those people who came from Connecticut and have already turned us off exactly exactly all right.
Speaker 1: So we're unlike the normal format of geek nights because you know we got to get this show on the road as in go to Baltimore.
Speaker 1: so we're gonna dispense with the usual news and kind of just right get right into this Connecticut thing.
Speaker 1: But first I do want to point out last weekend Connecticut this weekend Otakon.
Speaker 1: so August 8th 9th and 10th We're gonna be in Baltimore at Otakon doing a ton of live shows too many if there is such a thing.
Speaker 1: so Friday noon to 1 in panel 1 anime.
Speaker 1: you should see this has been the standing room only like batshit crazy panel.
Speaker 0: I don't know why but I guess it works.
Speaker 1: I know exactly.
Speaker 0: do it works right?
Speaker 0: if you don't understand it You don't like it.
Speaker 1: It's confusing, but we know we understand exactly.
Speaker 1: It's easy to get into anime.
Speaker 1: a lot of people got into anime.
Speaker 1: They don't know what to watch after they watch it.
Speaker 0: You know what I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: Do is after that panel I'm gonna ask people like why they came to it and really see what they're thinking.
Speaker 0: Well,
Speaker 1: we asked him last year and more than half the crowd raised their hands at I don't know what to watch now
Speaker 0: Uh-huh,
Speaker 1: and then like the other third was pretty much It was a half of them were I don't know what to watch and the rest didn't really were non-committal.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, yeah, and you know it is kind of hard to figure out what to watch.
Speaker 1: I mean how many good shows are there?
Speaker 1: not just an anime, but in any.
Speaker 0: this is what I don't get.
Speaker 0: I mean It's like these people.
Speaker 0: the only explanation I could think of is that these people don't talk to anyone And they don't go on the internet at all and they don't even read Scott Scott, and they don't even What magazine tells you what anime is good.
Speaker 0: it tells you at least something.
Speaker 0: it It might tell you wrong, but at least you'll listen to it and watch something bad.
Speaker 1: No, and then they watch bad things and everything they watch is bad, and then they stop watching anime.
Speaker 0: I know, but what what?
Speaker 1: do they go on the internet?
Speaker 1: Where do you?
Speaker 1: unless you listen to animal world order us or maybe fast karate people are gonna tell you to watch bad shows?
Speaker 1: Probably there's really nowhere to get Reliable recommendations for anime to watch except geek nights anime world order and fast karate.
Speaker 0: for the gentleman there had to be somebody.
Speaker 1: I defy you.
Speaker 0: it's gotta be some blogs out there.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: There's one blog.
Speaker 1: That's okay that ba ba suga su.
Speaker 1: However that blog reviews everything and the reviews really kind of glowing.
Speaker 0: I mean these people really must live under a rock if you go.
Speaker 0: gee I don't know what anime to watch at all.
Speaker 1: I mean.
Speaker 0: I think we just I know too many.
Speaker 0: I know more anime to watch than I can watch.
Speaker 1: no anime that you know are good.
Speaker 1: I mean basically think of this.
Speaker 1: you just got into anime like you've.
Speaker 1: someone said hey watch this anime you watch Akira And it was awesome.
Speaker 1: and now in a vacuum you think all right.
Speaker 1: I liked Akira.
Speaker 1: I like anime.
Speaker 1: What should I watch?
Speaker 0: at the very least I go to the best But I look at the shelf and I pick something judging on the cover way way way in the title way.
Speaker 1: That's not gonna get you very far.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: No it won't go to Best Buy.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I think I understand exactly why this panel is because it is hard to find out What good anime is out there because the industry is not conducive to people watching good anime anymore.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 0: That's for sure.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry.
Speaker 1: I misspoke.
Speaker 1: the anime industry is not conducive to existing anymore.
Speaker 1: Anyway Friday 3 p.m.. To 4 p.m.. In workshop 1 Comics for the manga reader.
Speaker 0: yeah, this is a panel I came up with.
Speaker 0: I didn't plan it But we could just wing it.
Speaker 0: we're at each in each convention We're doing.
Speaker 0: we're gonna wing one panel sort of and the basic idea this panel Is that a lot of the people at Otacon are gonna be people who like anime and people who like manga.
Speaker 0: those are gonna be?
Speaker 0: You know big interest for them.
Speaker 0: I mean there are video game fans There.
Speaker 0: you know all sorts of geeks there but mostly there's gonna be anime and manga geekdom even more anime than manga.
Speaker 0: right and All these manga readers right obviously enjoy comics because manga is comics, and they enjoy manga.
Speaker 0: There's a manga library there.
Speaker 0: They'll be people in there reading manga.
Speaker 0: They paid all this money to read manga.
Speaker 0: They must like it.
Speaker 0: But these people don't tend to read American comics and I've been American but non-japanese comics.
Speaker 0: I partly understand any from any publisher.
Speaker 1: because one You're not gonna find a lot of those really good French comics anywhere accessible or you'll know what they are.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if you go looking for American comics unless you know where to look you're gonna find mostly underwear perfect.
Speaker 0: Yes, I mean you could pre-order with the crazy spreadsheet.
Speaker 0: who's gonna do that?
Speaker 0: who isn't on the inside?
Speaker 0: you go to a comic-book Store.
Speaker 0: who's gonna do that or doesn't have body odor and a giant gut.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's real harsh.
Speaker 1: I know it's morning thing all right go to you go to a comic.
Speaker 1: you go to borders.
Speaker 1: Well, no the way you buy the manga.
Speaker 1: the problem is you go to a comic store, and it's mostly underwear perverts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you go to a borders where all the manga is and there is a shelf of you know non manga comics And it's so disorganized and difficult to figure out what's what and you don't even know what any things are.
Speaker 0: More importantly it's all underwear pervert mostly, but you know more and more.
Speaker 0: There's not.
Speaker 0: this is not underwear perverts on there But not that much.
Speaker 0: I would say about 25% at the average borders will be not underwear perverts.
Speaker 0: That's a job space.
Speaker 1: That's not enough.
Speaker 0: It's not enough at all.
Speaker 0: But 25% of the non manga graphic novel shelf space will be not underwear perverts on the average at the average borders I've been to.
Speaker 1: yeah, yeah, the thing is even so a lot of it You can't tell unless you don't even know what it is.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna tell at this panel Pete manga readers what non manga comics They would probably like.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna spoil the panel right now.
Speaker 1: Batman the Dark Knight Returns Watchmen V for Vendetta Scott Pilgrim Runaways Anything by Brian gave.
Speaker 1: I think we're gonna do a whole aside.
Speaker 1: I think we're gonna do an aside about alright.
Speaker 1: There's also manga.
Speaker 1: You should read that none of you probably have.
Speaker 0: maybe we'll see.
Speaker 0: Imagine I think over the way we'll tie it in is we'll say these are the great mangas this one.
Speaker 0: We'll talk about that great manga.
Speaker 0: Like if you like that great manga Then you'll like these great non manga and then picking and then we're done with that thread.
Speaker 0: We'll pick another great manga and then continue.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I don't want to get into this long discussion of all our panels now.
Speaker 0: Friday 8 p.m.
Speaker 1: To 9 p.m Panel 3 We're doing know your creators from Osamu Tezuka to Osamu Tezuka.
Speaker 1: I don't think we need to say much more about that.
Speaker 1: I think that'll be fine.
Speaker 0: We're gonna tell people Pay-attention to who the hell makes your anime and your manga.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because it's important the end Saturday morning 10 a.m.
Speaker 1: To 11 a.m.
Speaker 1: In workshop - we are doing Advanced Wars because Otacon was desperate for panels and I happen to have suggested this as like a second string panel Earlier in the year and they basically came back before the con and said yeah Could you run that?
Speaker 1: and I said, oh, yeah, sure.
Speaker 0: I think we could do.
Speaker 0: we didn't have a better suggestion.
Speaker 0: They could have faked instead.
Speaker 1: Well, we're already doing.
Speaker 1: know your creators comics for the manga reader anime You should see and we could have done beyond D&D instead of Advanced Wars.
Speaker 1: That's so less related to anime.
Speaker 0: I know I know.
Speaker 1: however, however I've been talking to them and there is a tiny chance.
Speaker 1: We might run beyond D&D Saturday morning at some point.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, because best panel we came up with this year.
Speaker 1: Basically, the gist of all this is come to the geek nights tables in the artist alley.
Speaker 1: You will find us we have 11 of them and Over there, we'll have our schedule posted on our table and we might be doing extra panels all over the place.
Speaker 1: So make sure you stop by.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we all have a little stand-up schedule and we'll have a little stand-up something else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Scott only said that because he knows that I happen to have bought two table tripods Yep, and of course on Sunday from 1 p.m.
Speaker 1: To 2 p.m.
Speaker 1: Katsunori Matsushita will be talking about kendo the way of the sword and all I can say is that Katsu runs one fucking kendo panel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I heard that the one from last Otakon was too epic.
Speaker 0: The Katsu-Kan one was mildly epic.
Speaker 0: It was a little smaller room.
Speaker 0: I think it hindered him.
Speaker 1: I think the small room is the only thing that held him back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I think that the Otakon won.
Speaker 0: I see no reason why it wouldn't be as epic as the last one Especially since Katsu will be very excited to hit rim with a stick and rim will be very unhappy.
Speaker 0: Not that he gets hit with a stick which won't really hurt wearing armor.
Speaker 0: But I will no longer be the undefeated honorable vice president To be in a really smelly sweaty armor.
Speaker 1: Oh that armor is real smelly.
Speaker 0: It's it's full of bo anyway.
Speaker 1: Yep, and of course Saturday from 1 to 2 the Apple geeks panel and panel 2 with our good friends talking enough.
Speaker 1: Oh, very nice very nice.
Speaker 0: We'll probably be there I think panel at the same time don't we?
Speaker 1: Saturday from 1 to 2 we most definitely don't.
Speaker 1: okay awesome I don't know where you got that.
Speaker 0: there was something at the same time.
Speaker 1: I forget whatever at the same time.
Speaker 0: the Apple Geeks panel is better than anything at the same time.
Speaker 1: Make sure you come by our table because we are going to be scheduling other things throughout the con.
Speaker 1: for example We have our tradition of going to the ultra-violent movie.
Speaker 1: If you I'm not gonna talk about it cuz we have to decide which ones we're going to.
Speaker 0: but I want to go to that Bushido one and I want to go to machine girl.
Speaker 1: I think I only want to go to machine girl.
Speaker 1: That's fine I don't want to go to the other ones so much but basically we will be scheduling things that we are going to go to.
Speaker 1: and If you're gonna be at Otakon check our schedule.
Speaker 1: And if you want to be where the awesome is be where we're gonna be.
Speaker 0: yeah on our little schedule probably have events.
Speaker 0: We're running events our friends are running and then events.
Speaker 0: We are attending so that you know where we're gonna be at.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it is time for things of the day.
Speaker 1: I've got something real light real quick.
Speaker 1: I just thought this was cute.
Speaker 1: It's a comic by Sarah Mensinga called dragon girl, and it's really short.
Speaker 0: It's a generic name.
Speaker 1: there it is.
Speaker 1: It's a really simple short comic, and it's just you know 20 or so Images accompanied by 20 or so paragraphs attacks, then isn't that's?
Speaker 0: and that's not a comic.
Speaker 0: That's more of a light novel.
Speaker 0: Light novel yeah, incredibly light novel.
Speaker 1: I would call it a comic.
Speaker 0: It's not a comic if it's the art isn't sequential.
Speaker 1: the art is sequential.
Speaker 1: It just has a very long sequence.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see we'll see.
Speaker 0: anyway continue.
Speaker 1: I don't see any reason why you wouldn't call this a comic if nothing else.
Speaker 1: I'd call it a one-off webcomic Because it could be.
Speaker 0: it's an illustrated work of prose as opposed to a comic which are two different things.
Speaker 0: There's a line at which you go from illustrated book to comic.
Speaker 0: There's there's a very distinct line there.
Speaker 1: See I don't make the distinction at all and I couldn't care less.
Speaker 0: There is there's a very very important artistic distinction that we won't get into now.
Speaker 1: Fine it is a rough illustration and text.
Speaker 1: good God Scott.
Speaker 0: I know I didn't look at.
Speaker 0: it might be a comic.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's a really cute little story about a king and a little girl who is kidnapped by dragons.
Speaker 0: Does the king have an awesome beard?
Speaker 1: Actually, he does.
Speaker 0: I'm totally reading it.
Speaker 0: He does.
Speaker 0: is this is the king awesome.
Speaker 1: Uh no not really.
Speaker 1: Basically all I'm gonna say is it's cute, and I really like the ending even though.
Speaker 1: It's a little cliche.
Speaker 1: I thought it was cute.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay, so check this out I'm not sure, but I have.
Speaker 0: basically this is a really quick thing of the day.
Speaker 0: What fleshes it out as I have suspicions?
Speaker 0: all it is.
Speaker 0: the video is pretty simple.
Speaker 0: some people at a Tokyo?
Speaker 0: Convention Center are on an escalator.
Speaker 0: so many people are on the escalator the escalator goes in reverse and they all fall off.
Speaker 0: Now that's it.
Speaker 1: no no that's funny.
Speaker 0: It is pretty funny, but here's the thing I have.
Speaker 0: suspicions number one No the top.
Speaker 0: well it could have been not the weight of the people But there were a lot of people on there, but someone flicking the switch.
Speaker 0: It's possible.
Speaker 0: Another thing all the people on there are nerdy looking dudes.
Speaker 1: You're thinking.
Speaker 1: It was not like comic.
Speaker 0: I think this is a comic at situation.
Speaker 0: That's my suspicion.
Speaker 0: so someone watch this video and then confirm or deny.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's all I got.
Speaker 0: and you know watching people fall off an elevator elevator Elevate escalate it's an escalator.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not too many people fall on elevators.
Speaker 0: No It's pretty funny because you do.
Speaker 0: the thing keeps coming down and the people keep spilling off of.
Speaker 0: it causes like spill spill Spills bills, but it just doesn't stop.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 1: You know I have a little bit more trouble laughing at own videos when it's not the person getting owns fault.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they're not owned too badly.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much you.
Speaker 0: I burped there.
Speaker 1: That was fantastic.
Speaker 0: I know it's pretty much.
Speaker 1: We're all about professional.
Speaker 0: it's pretty much just fall off get up fall off get up fall off get up.
Speaker 0: lots of screaming It's no one's really good.
Speaker 0: No, one's really getting owned here.
Speaker 0: It's just sort of like oh, no.
Speaker 1: Oh, no All right, okay, so I don't know how long we'll spend on this But we're gonna give you at least a brief overview.
Speaker 1: slash counter part of kinetic on 2008 which we were at Already.
Speaker 0: you want to do chronological.
Speaker 1: What do you?
Speaker 0: let's just do this chronologically all right, so we went there Late-ish Friday.
Speaker 1: well they originally and I was gonna take work off.
Speaker 1: I ended up not like all this business.
Speaker 1: we ended up getting in you know late on Friday and Friday night.
Speaker 1: the con was basically dead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we got there.
Speaker 0: There was nothing happening.
Speaker 0: I couldn't tell if there are any events.
Speaker 0: You know we discovered they had a new layout for the con.
Speaker 0: everything was really sparse.
Speaker 0: there weren't a lot of people.
Speaker 0: there wasn't anything Happening.
Speaker 0: you know we.
Speaker 0: it was pretty.
Speaker 0: it was really not.
Speaker 0: it was very bad.
Speaker 0: Basically, that's the only word I can come up with.
Speaker 1: I mean just.
Speaker 0: I tried to think of a nicer word But I couldn't.
Speaker 1: well it was just.
Speaker 1: you know we show up in the world.
Speaker 1: things kind of came together.
Speaker 1: We got our badges we dealt with all that, but it was just.
Speaker 1: there was really no one around.
Speaker 1: there wasn't any energy.
Speaker 1: Like there was a very small crowd of people kind of very morbidly and slowly and quietly and grumbly Wandering about and that was it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was very Blair, and I wasn't getting a good feeling.
Speaker 0: I had a pretty Pessimistic view.
Speaker 0: as soon like we were there for maybe 15 minutes on Friday, and I was looking not forward to the Saturday and the Sunday.
Speaker 0: I was like oh This is gonna be real bad.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be no good.
Speaker 0: I can tell already I got bad vibes all over the place.
Speaker 0: No good.
Speaker 1: No good Yeah, so basically we just decided to go to our hotel You know how we're not here, and we left because we weren't actually supposed to show up till Saturday anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we didn't really do anything Friday.
Speaker 0: We basically walked around real quick said hi to people got badges Didn't do so much.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 1: We went to the hotel room.
Speaker 1: We watched some Ava.
Speaker 0: all right We watched that.
Speaker 0: we watched Ava up from my iPhone to the TV pretty cool And I played a bunch of Civ 4 and we went to bed.
Speaker 0: Here's a tip for people.
Speaker 0: if you want to connect something to your hotel television It's all fancy, but the input button on the side You know cuz they always give you a weird remote and the weird remote doesn't give you the input buttons, right?
Speaker 0: But there's an input button on the side of the television that doesn't seem to be working.
Speaker 0: Disconnect the telephone cord from the television and now the input button will suddenly work Because it's no longer talking to the hotel system.
Speaker 0: And then when you're done plug the phone cord back in and no one will say wary.
Speaker 1: at some hotels that sets off an alarm And somehow it's all that you will not be able to turn off An alarm that says someone is stealing the television.
Speaker 0: however at the hotel We were at it didn't do that so it was all good.
Speaker 1: either that or no one was watching that alarm Which is fine?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but but my one warning is that that alarm is not always silence.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's also true.
Speaker 0: usually though a lot of times the alarm cord is a little different from the other ones.
Speaker 0: It's a little more.
Speaker 0: You know physically secured more thoroughly.
Speaker 0: You know like have a big metal lock on it of some kind.
Speaker 0: You know anyway Why would you do that?
Speaker 1: because as long as the if as soon as it gets broken the alarm goes off and then you send?
Speaker 1: Someone up to the room.
Speaker 1: They can't get a TV out that quick.
Speaker 0: Well the idea is that you know we slow them down and getting the TV out.
Speaker 0: They lock not only that cable, but the other one.
Speaker 0: so it's like if they break the alarm cable.
Speaker 0: You know that anyway forget it.
Speaker 0: talk about Connecticut, okay?
Speaker 1: Because I don't think you've seen these things so much before what they look like anyway.
Speaker 0: I've seen a bunny.
Speaker 0: I've been a lot of hotels.
Speaker 1: have you now mr.. Hotel big shot.
Speaker 0: Yes No, I've never been to hotels before Scott's.
Speaker 1: he did now except for Connecticut.
Speaker 0: right right.
Speaker 1: so Saturday morning We wake up early because we have the anime match game scheduled for two hours on Saturday morning from 8 a.m.. To 10 a.m.. Now the only Concern I had was that we had not yet met the people at the convention who were responsible for us being there.
Speaker 1: We had figured out we had the match game because we got a schedule Went through it looking for names of events that we had submitted and assuming that they were ours.
Speaker 0: Yeah, last year when we arrived at Connecticut.
Speaker 0: They had badges for us.
Speaker 0: right well They had to make one for me But they had them and they had our names on a list to prove that we were actual guests.
Speaker 0: They checked us out to make sure we were guests And then they had pre-printed itineraries telling us what to do.
Speaker 0: that was pretty cool this year.
Speaker 0: We walked in and we said hey, we're geek nice Basically and we had to make our own badges.
Speaker 1: well basically the thing is what happened was we walk in we're like all right.
Speaker 1: Hey, we're getting nice badges.
Speaker 1: and the funny thing is I see katsu's badge on the top of the stack.
Speaker 1: Yep, it was like why does katsu have a badge, but the person who got him a badge doesn't have a badge.
Speaker 1: luckily We didn't even have to argue or anything because the con chair Recognized us because we're at every freaking major con on the east.
Speaker 0: was it the con chair?
Speaker 0: is it someone else?
Speaker 1: That was the con chair all right, so he's like.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you guys you recognize me actually and not Scott at first alrighty, and then he's like oh, okay, whatever.
Speaker 1: and The point that basically the con chair asked us where the panels person was which we said Great, so you know we Saturday morning.
Speaker 1: We go to our match game, and we're getting ready to go, and then we're thinking all right our Convention guests going to show up so we can run this or Not.
Speaker 0: and well last year last year They didn't tell us whether or not we actually had guests, and we couldn't get a confirmation all day.
Speaker 0: But when we showed up to the panel guests appeared Miraculously awesome guests.
Speaker 1: that was actually a really good match game.
Speaker 0: the thing that really got me worried about this year was not just that They didn't tell us guests were coming or not But because it was 8 a.m.. Guests don't like to make up at him and to.
Speaker 0: if I looked at the convention book There wasn't really people who were good guests for anime match games.
Speaker 1: I was like even if they said guess who are they gonna say they were awesome guests.
Speaker 1: I mean don't get me wrong actually a fan of some of these people But they are not going to be able to deal with the air.
Speaker 1: well You know what they probably could have dealt with our anime match game.
Speaker 1: just fine because after we had Peter Fernandez on and we kind Of rewrote everything we have two sets of questions.
Speaker 1: the everyone is a hardcore anime fan.
Speaker 1: Let's go set and the people kind of know anime.
Speaker 1: Let's have generic magic game questions with an anime thing.
Speaker 0: I definitely think that the that the only raid that the people kind of know anime match game works is If the people on the panel have enough star power.
Speaker 0: if they weren't big star amazing people Then you really can only get by with the very knowledgeable match game or else.
Speaker 0: It won't be entertaining.
Speaker 1: So there's Scott and I are sitting in a room Basically alone and no one's in the panel.
Speaker 0: so we're like alright People trickled into the con and people actually trickled into the room.
Speaker 1: yeah, but I'm saying at first no one was there And we're like awesome.
Speaker 1: This is gonna be awesome.
Speaker 1: You know people trickle in bit by bit.
Speaker 1: So we basically just start Talking to each other on stage and kind of talking to the audience a lot like geek nights actually And we kind of just did geek nights for about a half about 20 minutes or so Yeah, and the crowd kept growing and growing and the thing is no one left.
Speaker 1: in fact people kept coming in to see what was Going on and sitting down the crowds growing and growing.
Speaker 1: We did an abbreviated version of know your creators because we weren't running it at the con And we didn't have the index cards because we weren't running it at the con.
Speaker 0: actually I thought we were running at the con.
Speaker 0: I forgot the index cards, but didn't matter because we weren't running it at the con.
Speaker 1: Yes, so you know we do that and everyone loved it.
Speaker 1: And then eventually there was a pretty large crowd in the room, and they're all being entertained.
Speaker 1: so we stopped and said wait a minute You guys want us to just run the match game for you guys.
Speaker 1: and the crowd was like oh my god.
Speaker 1: And there are actually some people in the audience from last year who showed up only because they remembered How absolutely badass the match game was last yeah?
Speaker 0: And the girl who bothered us all year and wanted a prize is actually not annoying.
Speaker 0: She's just like I want my prize.
Speaker 0: I'm like okay.
Speaker 0: I brought some prizes here.
Speaker 0: take them.
Speaker 1: yep Sadly the t-shirts that we were also going to give here her are arriving a Friday morning at Otacon.
Speaker 1: great, so I'm gonna mail her one as soon as we get back before packs.
Speaker 1: okay, so if you're listening yes You're gonna get your t-shirt.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It's awesome alrighty, but so This actually started this one really well.
Speaker 1: We got uncle yo up and I got to say uncle yo has gotten better and better.
Speaker 1: at the anime comedy like every time I see him he's funnier on stage, and he's trying real hard.
Speaker 0: I mean you know you got to give the guy some credit.
Speaker 0: He tries he's putting everything.
Speaker 0: He's got into that and he's you know he's improving himself.
Speaker 0: Which is what you got to do?
Speaker 1: I mean well one thing listen to the first few episodes of geek nights say no more.
Speaker 1: But I gotta say this as a match game guest.
Speaker 1: He was hilarious.
Speaker 1: I kind of want him.
Speaker 1: I always want him to be my ringer if we don't have enough guests.
Speaker 1: that was great.
Speaker 0: And the other thing is what I did is that when we were trying to select people for the game I actually sort of quiz the audience to get you know people who actually knew about anime.
Speaker 0: I was like who knows what a road to katochi is?
Speaker 0: and one guy said legend of the overfeed and I said who knows what?
Speaker 0: you know Itano circuses and one guy knew and I was like yes And the best part is we were.
Speaker 1: I mean we figure with these game shows people might lie or something.
Speaker 1: so at first we're like All right, if you lie and get yourself up here.
Speaker 1: You're only gonna make a fool out of yourself.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I also I asked questions, and I made sure the people answered them.
Speaker 1: So there's no way that they were lying.
Speaker 0: it was like it was trivia And it was hard anime trivia And I was very surprised that people in the audience actually knew like.
Speaker 0: I'm surprised.
Speaker 0: I got one person.
Speaker 0: It was pretty good, and yeah They're great panelists.
Speaker 1: It was funny because one of them I was like who is seen Gundam?
Speaker 1: and everyone raised their hand and I was like double Oh 80 and all the hands of a two went down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know we get these people up and Running this match game.
Speaker 1: Just kind of winging it.
Speaker 1: It was real fun like everyone had a super good time and people kept coming in to the point that Just as the panel was ending the room was half full.
Speaker 0: yeah, but not not super full like it was last year.
Speaker 0: But that was because the guests, but here's the deal.
Speaker 1: this started a trend that kind of surprised me.
Speaker 1: We're at Kinetic on right which is not an anime con.
Speaker 1: it is a geek Webcomic gaming anime con like all these rolled into one.
Speaker 0: It's very in fact.
Speaker 0: I'd say there's more web comics and gaming than anime.
Speaker 1: I mean what anime stuff was happening at a con has better gaming than most gaming conventions.
Speaker 1: I've said that before.
Speaker 1: I'll say it till I die.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Good.
Speaker 1: God is the tabletop gaming at Kinetic on vent.
Speaker 0: Just cuz they have enough tables.
Speaker 0: I mean ubercon didn't have enough tables at that hotel in Jersey.
Speaker 1: the only thing They're lacking is Luke crane And I'm going to do everything within my power to get him.
Speaker 1: he is going to pecs right yes And we'll all get to that a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: Yes, all right in fact.
Speaker 1: I've worked out to where he's.
Speaker 1: he's going to be ready Hopefully I mean we got it.
Speaker 1: unless something that comes up to run a burning wheel the sword or something demo Immediately following our beyond Dungeons and Dragons panel awesome.
Speaker 0: is he gonna be on our panel though?
Speaker 1: I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: I think he might be in the audience.
Speaker 1: my plan would be he could be in the audience.
Speaker 1: We do the panel cuz I think he'd really like.
Speaker 0: oh, and then we and then we do that We praise him at during the panel.
Speaker 1: I'll just because I want to I'd love to see him in person like sitting there in an audience where he is called by two Strangers a rock star.
Speaker 1: yeah, I'd love to see that.
Speaker 1: and then I'd love to be like ladies and gentlemen you're a rock star.
Speaker 1: Let's say yeah, we'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: But this trend that at every panel we ran, and I'm saying every single panel at Kinetic on There were more hardcore knowledgeable awesome anime fans here than at any anime con we've ever been to that we did.
Speaker 1: panels at we at katsu khan were like How many of you have seen cowboy bebop?
Speaker 1: and out of a hundred and twenty people like a third of them raised their hands?
Speaker 0: It was pretty shameful.
Speaker 0: I was like oh my I was in pain.
Speaker 1: We go we were here right at this panel.
Speaker 1: I'm like you know.
Speaker 1: here's some anime.
Speaker 1: You should see you know.
Speaker 1: We're just talking in the beginning.
Speaker 1: I'm like millennium actress blah.
Speaker 1: I start naming Satoshi khan stuff and someone's like yeah, Satoshi khan I'm like wait How many of you have seen all of the Satoshi khan's movies?
Speaker 0: and like everyone raised their hand and is the one girl like the?
Speaker 0: Back left corner who had seen every anime in the known universe.
Speaker 1: Oh god She was a little excited, but but it was great cuz she wasn't lying at the at the very end.
Speaker 1: you know at anime You should see which we did later We're like oh real quick And we're rattling off like obscure good anime or at least anime that you should probably watch.
Speaker 1: and as soon as we started to say Jojo's Bizarre Adventure she ran up and showed us the Jojo's Bizarre Adventure PVC that she had just bought.
Speaker 1: yeah But yes Every single panel we ran had hardcore Amazingly knowledgeable anime fans.
Speaker 0: that was the hardest core match game We've ever run outside of the RIT anime club and by announcing what panel I mean at every panel We said these the panels are doing later these the panels are doing later, and it worked.
Speaker 0: We saw the same people come to all these panels one after the other because they enjoyed our earlier panels so much.
Speaker 0: I couldn't believe like it's never worked before, but it totally worked a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: I don't want to sound like we're full of ourselves, but we were basically rock stars by the end of the con.
Speaker 0: I know it was really weird the kinetic on size wise Smaller than a lot of other cons we'd go to.
Speaker 0: you know smaller than Otacon smaller than KanzaCon by a lot, right?
Speaker 1: You know I think it's actually now with our new no small cons policy the smallest convention We attend.
Speaker 0: yeah But you know what?
Speaker 0: for some reason we had such a stronger and bigger connection with the fan base at Connecticut than we had at any con ever.
Speaker 1: yeah, and it was.
Speaker 1: it was really cool like the audiences We're really into it And they seem to really enjoy it and it seems like audience members are going around like I saw people in the halls Telling other people to go to the rest of our panels, and they did.
Speaker 0: but like you like every hallway I walked down every room I went into.
Speaker 0: there were people that I had seen earlier in the day.
Speaker 0: there are people that I knew.
Speaker 0: you know on some level They were and there were people.
Speaker 0: I saw them one day And then they played a game with them the next day And I'm like I remember you.
Speaker 0: in fact
Speaker 1: out of all this there was a bunch of cool geeks we ended up playing a long game of power grid with on Sunday and a bunch of them played in like the burning wheel stuff and Now these people are cool enough to where they're probably going to be joining one of our burning wheel games like here in our real Lives.
Speaker 0: yeah, I mean I played the sword.
Speaker 0: I ran the sword for some people on Saturday night And then on Sunday we played this incredibly long game of power grid And one of the dudes who was in my sword was in the power grid.
Speaker 0: I was like I remember you.
Speaker 1: yeah So basically every panel we did.
Speaker 1: so the next panel you know later in the day And they pretty much if you didn't get it at this point Friday was dead.
Speaker 1: Saturday was rocking in a big way.
Speaker 0: No, we're super rocking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we do.
Speaker 0: I mean I don't know about the con itself, but as far as we were concerned the con was rocking Which is all I care about because that's what we promised.
Speaker 0: we say if we go to a con No matter how much the con sucks we will rock and we fulfilled.
Speaker 1: well We'll get to that because actually there were very few real complaints about the con as far as the con feedback session was concerned.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, so next we did anime You should see and the fun thing was that panel.
Speaker 1: that panel probably needed to be in main events because there was a line Like 20 minutes before filling the hallway.
Speaker 0: I don't have a need to be in main events But it could have definitely been a panel one.
Speaker 0: easily we.
Speaker 1: the room was filled to the point that every single seat was taken.
Speaker 1: Every possible space on the floor was filled.
Speaker 1: there were people standing up like against all of the walls.
Speaker 1: There are people standing in the doorway.
Speaker 1: the door was open.
Speaker 1: people were like Standing in the hallway with their heads in and there was a crowd outside being turned away for fire code.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: I'm thinking we got to do.
Speaker 0: Here's what I think with anime.
Speaker 0: You should see right on it twice and be no I can at Otakon and katsu con and cons that have a more this general Public audience do the anime that everyone should see at kinetic con.
Speaker 0: We're obviously more people know what anime to see.
Speaker 0: All we do is bring up.
Speaker 0: These are obscure anime.
Speaker 0: You should see we should do now.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: We should be really for kinetic on because there are two audiences.
Speaker 1: We do two panels and I don't know what to call them.
Speaker 1: one is the anime.
Speaker 1: Everyone should see that.
Speaker 1: You know all the like super big names that people might just not know.
Speaker 1: I know Ava ask a bebop all those things.
Speaker 1: Then we do the other panel.
Speaker 1: That is all the like KO century beast Dominion tank police all that stuff people know.
Speaker 0: tank police.
Speaker 1: Well people at kinetic on no tank police.
Speaker 1: That's right God.
Speaker 1: at the match game someone started singing it.
Speaker 1: as soon as someone said Dominion tank police and that you know.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna skip ahead to the con feedback session.
Speaker 0: But you know the guy who was sort of the guy who ran the panels and events at Kinetic on was sort of thrown into it the last minute.
Speaker 1: Yes This is there were a lot of problems with panels at kinetic on but They really weren't the guy in charge of its fault because it was one of those.
Speaker 1: Ah shit the cons fucked You fix it.
Speaker 1: and he said, ah crap Oh.
Speaker 0: and he did the you know As good a job as can be reasonably expected from someone in that position.
Speaker 0: and I could tell from listening to him at the feedback Session which he had to handle on his own Right where last year at kinetic on the feedback session was handled by the you know, the entire head staff.
Speaker 0: So the end he handled it real well And I could tell that he was the right person for the job and he knew his shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much we're gonna be joining the staff along with him next year to handle panels.
Speaker 1: No, yeah, so they can.
Speaker 1: kinetic on is gonna be awesome.
Speaker 0: But what he said at the you know feedback panel, which is something I think is very true for kinetic on is that?
Speaker 0: Even though kinetic on is understaffed.
Speaker 0: They know that right kinetic on has its problems and you know logistics.
Speaker 0: We know that.
Speaker 0: you know, there's all these things.
Speaker 0: the people the members the people who come to kinetic on are really the people who make it happen and You get so only true.
Speaker 0: you look around the con It's not.
Speaker 0: the staff aren't going around making big magic like happens and say katsu khan where they make huge magic.
Speaker 0: You know this.
Speaker 0: the there aren't you know, there are big guests, but there aren't tons and tons of huge guests and amazed.
Speaker 0: There's no industry presence at all Right, but awesome things are happening and it's all the people who came to the con making it awesome for each other Especially the thing that's so crazy about kinetic on.
Speaker 1: I think I talked about this last year, but it always amazes me.
Speaker 1: Every other con I go to Otakon katsu khan, even though his staff and an amazement.
Speaker 1: and you know all these There were always like you needed crowd control everywhere.
Speaker 1: You needed people like constantly keeping everyone in line and keeping everything organized.
Speaker 1: Basically unless there was like something going on like an event you would really never see a kinetic on staffer.
Speaker 1: and yet There were practically zero Problems.
Speaker 1: there were like you didn't need people walking around yelling at people to move and get out of the way.
Speaker 1: crowd control was it?
Speaker 1: It's really amazes me that nothing goes crazy at kinetic on for how little security there is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that says a lot about the people who can.
Speaker 0: I know they need a little help, you know Which I'll believe but you know what as Bad, you know, even though those things might not have been a hundred percent smooth.
Speaker 0: They weren't completely Disastrous they they weren't.
Speaker 0: they were you know, okay.
Speaker 0: It wasn't the end of the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but Anime, you should see that was like.
Speaker 1: that was crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we didn't even say much.
Speaker 0: I don't remember what I said during that battle.
Speaker 1: and then you know We did the skip a bit cuz I actually I really gotta start packing for Otakon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm still doing laundry here But you know then we did our how to run an anime club.
Speaker 1: Which?
Speaker 1: what do we say?
Speaker 1: we we know how to run an anime club like perfectly.
Speaker 1: we ran the biggest anime club in the country for a while and This panel is always like super good and the people there.
Speaker 1: They thought this is intently.
Speaker 1: they ask intelligent questions We give them the right answers and it's a fun panel to do.
Speaker 0: I was kind of hoping we would get one of those questions.
Speaker 0: Like I'm a trucker.
Speaker 0: I want to run anime club But that was so awesome that guy wasn't there.
Speaker 1: So I know.
Speaker 0: but then I'm always looking for that guy dressed up as the guy from Ranma who runs.
Speaker 0: what's his name?
Speaker 1: Yeah, Oh Ryoga.
Speaker 1: I thought you had the name of the trucker guy.
Speaker 0: No, the trucker was dressed as Ryoga.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know but I don't remember the truckers name.
Speaker 0: No, I don't remember the truckers name either.
Speaker 1: I find a trucker named Ryoga hilarious.
Speaker 0: Kineticon trucker Ryoga If you if you listen to this email us geeknightsafrontrecruit.com.
Speaker 1: Yes, so.
Speaker 1: then we had our Headlining panel beyond Dungeons & Dragons the event that we were running at the penny arcade expo Which the only event we're running in the penny arcade expo.
Speaker 1: also the one thing on the schedule most I mean most events We run at conventions are kind of like the show like they're organized and they're good, but they're kind of this back and forth They're kind of ad hoc.
Speaker 1: They're usually like they're really entertaining but they're Beyond Dungeons & Dragons is one of those rare ones kind of like the gecky guy panel.
Speaker 1: We ran before where it's a we presented more like a serious lecture and it's a really like we actually put together a polished sort of like We model them as best we can after the TED talks.
Speaker 1: We're just insane much because we can't really aspire to that level yet.
Speaker 0: No, we're not, you know by that awesome.
Speaker 0: We can't even go to TED let alone speak at it.
Speaker 0: Yes, but you gotta be good enough to go before you good enough to talk.
Speaker 1: but this was more like a lecture than a panel and The only thing I want to say is that when we arrived to do this panel And I saw that line going all the way down the freaking hallway for us and as we walked out people were going Oh my god, it's them.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, this is gonna be awesome.
Speaker 1: That really meant a lot to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was alright.
Speaker 1: Well, I get a much bigger hard-on for attention than you.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I was just like what's up people's.
Speaker 0: let's go you know, it's sort of like, you know, I guess that's it's one thing is I People?
Speaker 0: sometimes they have fans look at their fans like oh man, these people like me Oh man, but it's like I look at fans more is like a posse.
Speaker 0: It's like what's up guys.
Speaker 0: Let's go rock the house.
Speaker 0: It's not like.
Speaker 0: oh, yeah, these people love me.
Speaker 0: Oh my god I'm super famous and oh my god, it's like haha.
Speaker 0: What's up, dudes?
Speaker 0: Let's rock.
Speaker 1: But that panel was kind of awesome.
Speaker 1: And then of course Sunday, we got to watch a lot of people playing burning wheel.
Speaker 0: I mean people are playing burning wheel all day Saturday.
Speaker 0: I mean Alex.
Speaker 0: he ran the sword.
Speaker 0: I think what five or six times he's.
Speaker 1: he ran it until he was sick of it.
Speaker 0: He didn't run the lacuna But yeah He was complaining.
Speaker 0: You know that he did.
Speaker 0: Running the sword and not changing the scenario was getting a little boring to him and I could see that but he kept on doing It to see was basically selling a game.
Speaker 0: That was someone else's game.
Speaker 0: It's like if rim wrote a book and I went around selling copies of it on my own time And he was doing it awesomely and he never had the same person play twice and he had at least three people in every game.
Speaker 0: So he introduced like 20 to 30 people to burning wheel and they all had an awesome time.
Speaker 0: I ran the sword once, you know, and that was a little bit rough.
Speaker 0: He ran it how many times?
Speaker 1: One funny thing I noticed is that what we were doing this panel to you know, we're it was just a lecture.
Speaker 1: you know anime cons like people always try to like say stuff to you or they raise their hand cuz they want to like interject something.
Speaker 1: and There were a lot of the people in the audience were very clearly hardcore Dungeons & Dragons fans and when we first started a lot like I saw a lot of people like raise their hands when we started talking about D&D and they're like
Speaker 0: and
Speaker 1: After another five or ten minutes, they all put their hands down.
Speaker 1: I think by the end we converted almost everyone in that room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know it was.
Speaker 0: I was expecting there to be like outcries of you know, people saying ah D&D doesn't suck.
Speaker 0: And we weren't really saying the D&D suck.
Speaker 0: We were saying the D&D only plays this one kind of game which is crawl in the dungeon fight the monster Which is true and I was expecting you know, the typical fanboy outcry.
Speaker 0: but I think we the way we presented ourselves really sent a clear message of This is us talking and you listening time.
Speaker 0: There's no talking during this panel and the questions at the end there were.
Speaker 0: you know, I allowed time for like three quick questions or so and none of them really Confronted us in a negative way.
Speaker 0: even better and everyone was smiling and laughing and then cheering and excited.
Speaker 1: well, I think part of that was the That picture of the train that made sure the train works real well.
Speaker 1: That picture is just one of my favorite pictures.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's a good picture.
Speaker 1: It's one of those pictures where if there's a crowd of people you just have to show it to them and I'll start laughing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean putting it in context is doubles the power.
Speaker 0: That's that.
Speaker 0: love me.
Speaker 1: That's one thing as much of a hardcore anime love and base.
Speaker 1: there was a kinetic on.
Speaker 1: Only like only two or three people in the audience got that joke until we explained it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, that's a Dragon Warrior joke Dragon Warrior One and you had Dragon Quest.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you had to get.
Speaker 0: we're talking about slimes and Drake ease.
Speaker 0: It's something else right?
Speaker 0: Dragon Quest, right?
Speaker 0: They have rocket slime.
Speaker 0: the Drake II gets no love.
Speaker 0: the Drake II is far superior to the slime.
Speaker 0: Where the fuck is it?
Speaker 0: There's no Drake II game.
Speaker 0: What the hell?
Speaker 0: I want Drake ease sure.
Speaker 1: It's not Drake.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it's Drake II dr Iky At least in the translation.
Speaker 0: Anyway, uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I believe anyway, they're so cute.
Speaker 0: They have to have a white the Smile.
Speaker 1: I always felt bad about killing monsters in that game.
Speaker 0: Well, not until later when they're horrible and disgusting but Early on it's slimes and Drake is yay.
Speaker 1: And of course we spent the rest of the con just hanging out with awesome people.
Speaker 1: We met a ton of you.
Speaker 1: everyone we talked to with this con was awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there were no.
Speaker 0: like I usually had a con I always expect, you know, annoying fanboys to talk to me like hey Scott.
Speaker 0: I love your Hey, oh my god.
Speaker 0: and There weren't any no smelly fan.
Speaker 0: They're probably there but they did not approach me.
Speaker 0: They did not bother me I did not notice them.
Speaker 0: It was a very non fanboy con which there was a lot of bo.
Speaker 0: in fact I'd say there was more bo than I've smelled ever but there was no fanboys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're gonna wrap this up short This wasn't the most organized show or whatever.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: We're going to Otacon.
Speaker 1: so for all of you who might tune into this episode either because you've saw her sauce at Connecticut or You got back to geek nights sometime between Otacon and when we record a show after Otacon We're gonna get back in the swing of things pretty much after packs.
Speaker 0: All right, so it just real quick.
Speaker 0: Do we want to schedule an official like meetup place in time at Otacon?
Speaker 1: come to our artists alley table?
Speaker 1: There will be one scheduled.
Speaker 0: So we'll just put it on the paper there.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Good idea Okay, and I just wanted to let people know if you have an iPhones or I touch.
Speaker 0: You should probably get a Twitter account and install the twinkle app and then everyone at Otacon can tweet.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew.com Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.