Speaker 1: It's Tuesday August 26.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, and this is geek night tonight Bionic commando Rearmed.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Alright, this is it this weekend Friday Saturday Sunday.
Speaker 0: We're actually going to be at PAX in Seattle.
Speaker 0: Oh my gosh.
Speaker 1: Oh my gosh We are not the shit talkers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean about a year ago We're like yeah, we're gonna go to PAX and then we on the air kind of forced ourselves to commit to it.
Speaker 0: And I think you were like yeah, we'll probably go.
Speaker 0: and you're like no we're going.
Speaker 0: I was like yeah, we're definitely going.
Speaker 1: That's because of our ultimate strategy of if we're not sure we're gonna actually do something say We'll do it and then not.
Speaker 1: but I know we say it.
Speaker 1: You know vaguely like maybe we'll do this.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna make a promise of when but this will happen at some point probably most Definitely kind of sort of go to fact.
Speaker 1: so we said you're definitely gonna go to PAX and we definitely are Unless something happens like, you know something crazy.
Speaker 1: No planes exploding.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be in Seattle pretty much Friday Saturday, Sunday, Monday.
Speaker 0: So we've already talked to some listeners one awesome listeners actually going to pick us up at the airport.
Speaker 1: if they fail We'll just take a cab.
Speaker 1: It's alright.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I rent a car or something.
Speaker 1: I don't think we need to rent a car.
Speaker 0: You know, it's not that far be useful to get around the town.
Speaker 1: I think we'll just walk.
Speaker 0: I could foresee us renting a car on Sunday or Monday To go around and do stuff because Seattle is not known for its mass transit at least not compared to New York City.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point is we're gonna be there.
Speaker 1: We're doing one awesome panel on Saturday.
Speaker 1: at what 630?
Speaker 0: Yeah at exactly 6 o'clock p.m.
Speaker 0: On Saturday August 30th in the satellite theater room 307.
Speaker 1: I believe that is the Wolfman theater.
Speaker 1: I like how they give names to their to the rooms there the Wolfman theater Scott and I will be performing Once again second time ever beyond Dungeons & Dragons, which I Don't do dragons the reprise.
Speaker 0: I think I believe it's pronounced for prize.
Speaker 1: Well, I keep I always mess it up.
Speaker 1: I was thinking reprise and I said reprise thinking I'll be whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway, the important thing is of all the panels we've done at conventions and they're like 30 or 40 on the list right now Beyond Dungeons & Dragons is all I would say the best one we've ever done.
Speaker 1: When we gave that panel the audience was pretty rockin and we were pretty rockin and it felt real good doing that.
Speaker 0: pan It did and I think part of it was that we didn't let the audience talking to.
Speaker 0: We actually put a little bit of thought into this one.
Speaker 1: We put thought into some of the other panel.
Speaker 0: Yeah we did but there's the difference between.
Speaker 0: Here is a whole bunch of stuff from a manga and we're gonna talk about it versus giving a semi academic lecture.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then the other thing is that we're it's something we're really super passionate about and also, you know Doubly not passionate, but I thought gecky guy was all about passion.
Speaker 1: We are I'm passionate about the gecky guy, but I'm only half as knowledgeable about the gecky guys some other people.
Speaker 0: That is one thing.
Speaker 1: I mean, we know a lot about you know, the gecky guy like we do a lot of anime It's like we know more about that stuff than the average person.
Speaker 1: But there are people who know way more than us way more and those people need to do more panels.
Speaker 0: I guess they do granted Otakon edelup over there.
Speaker 0: This is neither here nor there.
Speaker 0: What is there is this weekend Saturday August 30th 6 p.m Satellite theater room 307 Wolfman.
Speaker 1: Yep in addition to that If you are going to PAX and you want a geek night's t-shirt, right?
Speaker 1: We will not have a table or anything there.
Speaker 1: So and we won't have any way to bring stuff with us a lot of stuff because we're on an airplane We can only bring so much.
Speaker 1: So if you want a t-shirt a geek nice t-shirt, it's $14 $15 it is standard t-shirts small medium.
Speaker 0: I make a mistake like that 14 Oh 15 15 dollars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sorry They're regular, you know unisex t-shirts they are anvil blends.
Speaker 0: Yeah, very nice We have sizes small through extra-large.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: We don't have XXL or XS or anything like that and Certain sizes might run out.
Speaker 1: You'd have to email us before packs right before we leave to email us before Tomorrow at like 8 p.m.
Speaker 0: Eastern Daylight Time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 1: You have to email us pretty much ASAP and tell us which size you want And if we have one left We will try to pack it and bring it with us and then I guess you have to buy it from us at our panel And that's gonna work.
Speaker 0: if you want to find us at the con pretty much Look in the forum because you know, we'll have internet there.
Speaker 0: So I might post randomly.
Speaker 0: Hey Saturday, blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: We're going to such-and-such for dinner and drinks.
Speaker 1: I'll also probably be tweeting it up a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Scott's it.
Speaker 0: Scott's the Twitter shitters.
Speaker 1: I guess I'll tweet, you know when we're shitting and when we're not shitting and you'll be able to find us.
Speaker 0: and also I would like to point out that we're doing beyond Dungeons & Dragons, which is I Don't want to call it a hour-long ad for burning wheel.
Speaker 0: It's about a 20-minute ad for burning wheel.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know.
Speaker 1: we do significantly talk about other non burning wheel game.
Speaker 1: Well, actually the thing is we actually talked a lot about primetime adventures and inspectors.
Speaker 0: well, the thing is it?
Speaker 0: what it really is is it's about 40 minutes of academic lecture followed by equal parts burning wheel inspectors and Primetime adventures.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's mostly a bashing of D&D more than it is a You know course when we say Dean if the funny thing is it was so great.
Speaker 0: We're like, hey blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: And we're kind of talking about how D&D is a bad system and I saw all the nerds in the audience Much like I would have done if I had been in that audience
Speaker 1: if I had been in that audience in 2002
Speaker 0: if I'd been in that audience anytime before I met Luke crane in my life I probably would have started me like.
Speaker 0: that is true.
Speaker 1: It's true.
Speaker 1: The first time you told me about the burning wheels, right?
Speaker 1: I was like, yeah Cuz I was skeptical pretty much any time anyone had ever come to me in my life and said I got a better role-playing System.
Speaker 1: It was just always some stupid nerdy shit.
Speaker 0: It was always like I use deep 30.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was no better It was no.
Speaker 1: it was just another piece of crap, whatever.
Speaker 0: or there were the weird ones like l5r.
Speaker 0: That was really fun, but difficult to play because no one knew it.
Speaker 0: He had to teach.
Speaker 1: burning wheel was the first one.
Speaker 1: that was actually different.
Speaker 0: but seeing the audience go What are these are and like that one guy even raised his hand and look they all wanted to stop us like we're about to commit some profane act and the only thing they can do is object and stop the horrible demon from being summoned.
Speaker 0: but basically About ten minutes later the fact that all of them put their hands down and were listening and by the end all of them Wanted to play burning wheel.
Speaker 0: I was real happy.
Speaker 1: It was good time.
Speaker 0: So if you want to play burning wheel It just so happens that Luke crane the creator of burning wheel and perhaps the only person in the history of the world Who actually and truly deserves the title?
Speaker 0: Rockstar game master.
Speaker 0: and if you don't think that that is justified you need to play a game with this man.
Speaker 0: It is frightening.
Speaker 1: I'm sure he'll be running the game in the tabletop room Which actually I've heard that the tabletop gaming at PAX is actually going to be in a separate building Because there's no room for it Which is actually kind of good because then it'll be nice and quiet and away from the hubbub.
Speaker 1: So
Speaker 0: the plan is and I have talked to Luke crane about this because they're going to be there We are going to run our panel and then we're going to direct and possibly lead the entire crowd of anyone who is willing Gathering ne'er-do-wells and spirits along the way Directly to Luke crane's doorstep.
Speaker 0: We will darken his door and he's gonna run some motherfucking burning wheel for your kids Speaking of burning whale summoning demons and darkening doors.
Speaker 0: What about death magic?
Speaker 0: Oh my god death magic.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, if you want to summon some demons of your own There is a book that tells you how to do this and that book is the magic burner mag boo The long-awaited mag boo.
Speaker 0: didn't it sell out.
Speaker 0: Can you actually buy it again?
Speaker 1: There was a pre-order.
Speaker 1: you had to I. basically I reloaded the page crazily to get in.
Speaker 1: I got number 141 out of 200.
Speaker 1: I'm sure you'll be able to order them again when there is another print run.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the status is right now.
Speaker 1: watch burning wheel calm for news.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I got this book in the mail this past weekend as did seemingly everyone else who ordered it.
Speaker 0: It is well worth all of your monies It's one of you know, that's the thing about burning wheel.
Speaker 0: that is really amazing.
Speaker 0: I mean, I've had the same experience.
Speaker 0: reading Joke games like reading the rule book to human-occupied landfill is really funny And I really enjoy it.
Speaker 0: playing the game is not fun or possible really but reading bird like anytime I read a burning wheel book a laugh at something that I didn't notice before And I'll have some sort of insight into like what it is to roleplay and the mag boo is that times 10.
Speaker 1: There's one thing even if you're never going to play burning wheel ever in your entire life Really you should buy as many burning wheel official burning wheel books as you can because Just reading them alone is like this treat, you know.
Speaker 1: reading D&D is mostly a reference book, you know.
Speaker 1: And burning wheel books have some reference in them.
Speaker 1: But even the reference material has content to it humorous content.
Speaker 1: He's a Jonah Jonah that one, you know when you're reading through and you see okay that life path has a trait.
Speaker 1: He's a Jonah that one.
Speaker 1: that's funny stuff.
Speaker 1: There's funny stuff going on.
Speaker 1: and basically here's the deal with the magic burner.
Speaker 1: Let me I'm not gonna review the whole book, but let me sum it up for you.
Speaker 1: Right, the original burning wheel had rooms for rules for magic, but the rules for magic were not super fleshed out They were just sort of baseline and they applied equally to all kinds of magic.
Speaker 1: Right the new the magic burner splits it up into all the different kinds of magic.
Speaker 1: right art magic Necromancy, which is death art, you know, just setting people on fire.
Speaker 1: That's our you know, magic items.
Speaker 1: Everything is split up Alright religion magic nature magic like druid stuff.
Speaker 1: and What it's done is it didn't actually introduce.
Speaker 1: it introduced some but not many new mechanics mostly.
Speaker 1: what this book does is show you how to use the existing burning wheel mechanics right to get these magic systems as many of them or as little of them to work in your game as you want and You can sort of choose, you know how you want the different magics to work.
Speaker 1: They're like, hey if you you know, it's not like D&D where it's this spell does this.
Speaker 1: it's more like well If you want a world, you know where there's only some gifted people have magic.
Speaker 1: do this.
Speaker 1: if you want a world where?
Speaker 1: everyone uses magic to sort of you know, fix all the broken stuff in their house do this.
Speaker 1: and basically to sum up the rules in the book.
Speaker 1: This is this is the summary of the book.
Speaker 1: if someone wants to do something in burning wheel You know you roll the dice.
Speaker 1: if you succeed hooray.
Speaker 1: if you fail consequences, that's burning wheel.
Speaker 0: Burning wheel if you succeed hooray.
Speaker 1: if you fail hooray Exactly, but it's consequences when you fail.
Speaker 1: The magic rules are if you want to have a better chance of doing something if you want to take your magical Power and use it to help you do something there is a chance that either a you'll have a better chance of succeeding or B you'll be able to succeed at something better than normal.
Speaker 1: if You do succeed with magic aid You will succeed but there's a price to pay for that magical power.
Speaker 1: But if you fail when using magic the consequences are doubly horrible doubly horrible.
Speaker 1: Oh, they're horrible because you failed at magic.
Speaker 1: Good God You'll blow shit up or kill people.
Speaker 1: who knows what's gonna happen?
Speaker 1: But usually when you fail epically with magic There is some slight benefit that comes out of it some like oh you died Your soul is damned for eternity along with all your family everyone you've ever met.
Speaker 0: But out of the ashes came a sword and trusted with all those souls and it's wicked badass and your son is not wielding.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's all sorts of stuff like that.
Speaker 1: And you know, it applies to every realm of magic.
Speaker 1: There's just different rules.
Speaker 1: My favorite stuff in the book are sort of the alternate consequences kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: It's like well remember how someone rolled circles, you know, and they failed as the enmity clause.
Speaker 1: Well, if they're corrupt as rules for corruption in the book, right when you're like a nasty old ugly wizard with eyes falling out You're corrupt, right?
Speaker 1: There's rules for corruption where for corrupt person fails a circles test.
Speaker 1: instead of the enmity clause you could go with the creepy clause Or you could go with the mortal enemy clause.
Speaker 0: I mean the sum total of all this is that this is a really really Fascinating and fantastic book that really expands on burning wheel and a lot because the only complaint I've ever heard Really levied against it from people who played it and tried it out for any length of time Was that in with the default rule said it wasn't easy to shoehorn a high magic world in.
Speaker 1: yeah Well, it's designed.
Speaker 1: burning wheel is specifically designed for low magic worlds.
Speaker 0: However, this book lets you do pretty much anything you could possibly imagine and do it Well and interestingly for good role-playing.
Speaker 1: it basically prevents the high Magicness that would have destroyed an original burning wheel game from destroying a burning wheel game.
Speaker 0: the other thing is it kind of reveals.
Speaker 0: I mean I don't think it appears that Luke Crane and them have never read the prince of nothing books.
Speaker 0: because if you read those books You think wow, this is a burning wheel campaign.
Speaker 0: and if you play a burning wheel you think wow This is the prince of nothing.
Speaker 0: and yet no, they're not related at all.
Speaker 0: He based his magic on something completely different.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you look in the book, they make lots of references to fantasy novels all the time and in the magic burner They're mostly referencing, you know Earthsea and such.
Speaker 1: and you know Earthsea by Ursula K Le Guin is awesome And it has a great magic system and basing it on that totally fits.
Speaker 1: But they don't mention prince of nothing at all, which tells me they haven't read it.
Speaker 0: I'd really be curious to see I got.
Speaker 0: I feel like I should just bring him a copy of the first book and just leave It on his desk or table or wherever he's gonna be at.
Speaker 1: Just bring the three volumes and give them to do whatever you want on the plane with all the other crap.
Speaker 0: I gotta carry it.
Speaker 0: all.
Speaker 0: those t-shirts were probably have to be to log in and probably buy it at a bookstore in Seattle.
Speaker 0: That's not a bad idea.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, the best part about the magic burner is the beginning.
Speaker 1: There's an essay by Tor Olavsrud who is sort of like Luke's right-hand man.
Speaker 1: is you know, we interviewed him, right?
Speaker 1: He was on that interview.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you guys you know, you're curious you're new to geek nights Which I hope you are.
Speaker 0: a lot of people probably medicine packs and oh, it's a geek nights thing.
Speaker 0: We interviewed Luke crane a long time ago at uber con.
Speaker 1: It was actually a great interview.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll put a link to it.
Speaker 0: It was really fun.
Speaker 0: Basically Scott did it while I sat there fiddling with knobs.
Speaker 0: that was back and we were kind of Shall we say?
Speaker 1: Amateurs at this whole radio business and we did a lot better than some of the stuff we've done recently.
Speaker 0: Oh my god,
Speaker 1: but yeah that interview, you know Tor was there and Tor wrote this essay about magic and fantasy worlds and how it plays into the story and the different kinds of magic users and the archetypes and it's really fascinating and it it Helped me learn a lot about you know, my role playing as well as you know, the use of magic and fantasy worlds.
Speaker 1: It's it's great.
Speaker 0: So speaking of all that On slash shot I've here's the headline Wizards of the coast Declares gleam axe site.
Speaker 0: a critical failure.
Speaker 0: now gleam axe.
Speaker 0: Thus I wondered gleam axe?
Speaker 0: so I went.
Speaker 0: you know, I was like, all right gleam axe.
Speaker 0: calm I'm presented with one of the ugliest websites I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay, Scott can see it from Craig's list.
Speaker 0: It's pretty.
Speaker 0: I would rather be at Craigslist because Craigslist Sacrifices form for function.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: This does not.
Speaker 0: it sacrifices everything for nothing For not.
Speaker 0: I say wow.
Speaker 0: All right one.
Speaker 0: There's a weekly poll on the right Medusa.
Speaker 0: his first pick snakes.
Speaker 0: What will you choose for your supernatural hair?
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 1: What are the choices with the choices?
Speaker 0: mangeese clever clever for choosing mangeese as opposed to mongooses.
Speaker 0: Yep squid tentacles scorpion tails Venus flytraps lobster claws Semperini Semperino.
Speaker 0: Semperini is not that Lobster claws.
Speaker 1: What do you pick?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna pick mongoose and see what happens.
Speaker 0: Ah, it's all about the mongoose.
Speaker 0: Ah Scorpion tails wins by a land.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's all right, so Gleam axe is Apparently and I had no idea.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone we knew had any idea.
Speaker 0: the fact that I didn't know Probably explains why it failed.
Speaker 0: Gleam axe was Wizards of the coast online social networking site quotes Originally designed to create a central hub where gamers could meet discuss and play games online.
Speaker 1: So they're just trying to make a Facebook for gamers only.
Speaker 0: but I had never even heard of it.
Speaker 0: I'm really kind of on the inside here.
Speaker 0: I honestly I'd never heard of it.
Speaker 0: I had no idea it existed.
Speaker 0: so I can't imagine how they thought this was gonna succeed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was probably just like, you know a thing that they spell.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's an obvious idea.
Speaker 1: Of course, it'll just succeed if we just do it.
Speaker 0: We don't need to try that Yeah, but but I got a read from the official gleam axe for one gleam axe who named that.
Speaker 1: Oh my Glee, is that supposed to be something glee?
Speaker 1: Is that a rat?
Speaker 1: Is that a reference to one of those D&D fantasy worlds like forgotten around?
Speaker 0: No, or No, Lance.
Speaker 0: I have no Exes but up quotes post maximum glee Randy B Randy B Wizards of the coast Wizards up.
Speaker 0: that has made the decision to pull down his gleam axe social networking site in order to focus on other aspects of our digital initiatives especially Magic online and Dungeons & Dragons insider.
Speaker 0: now Eve writes a bunch more paragraphs and they don't matter But here's what I'm interested in.
Speaker 0: one Magic online is probably gonna do pretty well among punk age.
Speaker 1: I think magic online's been around for a long time I know but it's still around.
Speaker 0: so but I'd like to point out that according to Every comment I can find on the internet internet in or not D&D insider is terrible and everyone isn't that where you pay money to get like extra D&D shit.
Speaker 0: Yes Yeah, so I don't know what's going on here.
Speaker 0: The only thing I can really say is that Wizards of the coast and by extension TSR though TSR had a little better luck They never seem to have understood the internet and what the internet is and what the internet is for and what the internet does.
Speaker 0: I mean?
Speaker 0: remember when D&D third aid came out and There was this CD.
Speaker 1: They almost had it right when they had the d20 system was open.
Speaker 1: They were there was the right step to do that and the SRD showed up and people started making all this d20.
Speaker 0: Well, well, well, well, it was the right step until I realized the fundamental flaw of d20.
Speaker 0: I like at the root basis level Yeah, but that that's a discussion for burning wheel.
Speaker 1: enough for the point Is that the openness was the right idea to get on the internet?
Speaker 1: But now they're going backwards with their openness and that hurts you on the internet.
Speaker 1: Not you realize that.
Speaker 0: there's something simple if you go to the D&D official websites you will not find the character sheets from every version of D&D ever which seems like the.
Speaker 0: If I had a website if I was watsy I would have every D&D character sheet ever and I have this whole open like free Downloads of all the old stuff and I'd pay for the rights or whatever because that sort of business.
Speaker 1: You own the rights you own TSR.
Speaker 1: You own the original D&D.
Speaker 1: Well then Who else own?
Speaker 1: if they don't own it who?
Speaker 0: The point is though, you know I'm reading through all these comments and the slash shot in particular and this seems to happen all the time degenerated right away into an argument about Fourth that is great versus fourth that is crap.
Speaker 0: third ed was great versus second ed was great and d20 ruined everything versus every Edition is just they add.
Speaker 1: they just segregate the fanboys even more.
Speaker 1: before it was third verse second verse first now It's fourth verse third verse second verse.
Speaker 0: first thing is I've never met anyone who was actually human who thought that anything before second edition Was better than second.
Speaker 0: I Also have not then there, you know players option that was.
Speaker 0: that was something special right there.
Speaker 1: The reason that you don't find people rooting for before second edition stuff They're always dead.
Speaker 1: knows cuz all those people play hack master.
Speaker 0: Ah, yeah, which if you're into that sort of thing hack master is the best way to go I can't deny.
Speaker 1: but you know if you're into that sort of thing, which I'm not.
Speaker 0: but the thing is it's like I saw all the Arguments.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna get into it because I want to.
Speaker 0: I really want to talk about the thing we're talking about Lee Max.
Speaker 0: Yes, I want.
Speaker 0: no I don't want to talk about me next but these arguments.
Speaker 0: There's an elephant in the room the elephant being that D&D is not a role-playing system.
Speaker 0: It's just a combat based conflict resolution system That is more and more becoming just World of Warcraft the paper game.
Speaker 1: don't give away our panel and you spoil it and yet No one touches on that.
Speaker 0: all the arguments are fourth ed lets me play the character this way instead.
Speaker 0: No, but third ed let me do this.
Speaker 1: Oh, but fourth ed has a better combat because they're arguing within the context of the assumption that D&D is You know this certain kind of game, but they don't think outside of that box.
Speaker 1: They're arguing within the box whereas we have broken out of the box, and we're looking at the box going.
Speaker 1: Why are these people bouncing around inside that box?
Speaker 0: I thought.
Speaker 0: but I thought saying that you're thinking out of the box was a pre web 2.0 idea And the idea was that we're gonna get back in the box.
Speaker 1: We do but getting back in the box doesn't mean going to play D&D again But just but that's the box.
Speaker 0: that mean there's two boxes.
Speaker 1: there could be a lot of boxes getting back in the box.
Speaker 0: Anyway things of the day in case anyone has not played the original game or seen it I must make my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: the the end of bionic commando the real the real bionic commander Hitler.
Speaker 0: No, Fukatsu Hitler.
Speaker 1: no top secret.
Speaker 0: That's all I got master D the first time I ever saw swearing in it in a NES game.
Speaker 0: Oh, man guy explodes and also one of the most innovative and best platformers ever made since Mario.
Speaker 0: yep That's all I got to say about it.
Speaker 0: It's the end of bionic commando.
Speaker 0: It's great space.
Speaker 1: You're saying hey people don't play the game watch the end.
Speaker 0: well Thing of the day the thing is if you watch this video The guy plays the exact same way I do like he beats the.
Speaker 0: you know the I guess the second to last boss the same trick I always used and even better he does the same kind of crap I do when he's waiting for stuff to explode.
Speaker 0: he's running around shooting stuff all over the place and just kind of.
Speaker 1: That's the NS way the natural selection method.
Speaker 0: We need a term for that.
Speaker 0: maybe jumping on the cheese.
Speaker 1: Anyway, my thing of the day is a flash game called fantastic contraption.
Speaker 1: I think it's pretty old But I discovered me and my co-worker discovered it pretty recently and the way this game works is.
Speaker 1: it's a physics game.
Speaker 1: right and You have a little screen and on the screen.
Speaker 1: There's some objects some pink objects You know maybe one or more and there is a pink goal area, and then there is a blue Machining area and you can build a machine in the blue area and then when you're ready you start that machine and The goal is to get the machine to somehow move
Speaker 0: the
Speaker 1: objects into the goal area.
Speaker 1: now The objects must be 100% within the goal area right all of the end.
Speaker 1: if there are multiple goal objects All of them have to be 100% in the goal area at the same time.
Speaker 1: So and then you win.
Speaker 1: so basically you have like 20 something maps And you're trying to find mission design machines to solve all of them.
Speaker 1: the great thing about this game Is that there are multiple solutions to any map?
Speaker 1: I mean you can make a vehicle you know, but some maps a vehicle doesn't work.
Speaker 1: You know some maps you can make sort of like a trebuchet.
Speaker 0: I mean basically the thing is what makes this game great is that you have very few components to work with.
Speaker 0: it's not It's a. it's a very complex, but extremely simple game at the same time, and that's what makes it fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could.
Speaker 1: basically you have water sticks wood sticks clockwise balls counterclockwise balls Non-moving balls, and that's about it.
Speaker 1: That's all you got and you got to build everything using those.
Speaker 1: you know five pieces, and it's not easy But it's all possible.
Speaker 1: You can actually pay for the game to get user generate user made maps if you if you get bored of the existing maps.
Speaker 1: But the best thing about this game is looking after you beat a map Looking at how everyone else solved it and all the really creative crazy solutions out there.
Speaker 0: There are some crazy machines on YouTube.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: it's just really fascinating and I think that when people talk about user generated content and video games You know they keep getting it wrong.
Speaker 1: And I think this is what user generated content is where the playing of the game is the generating of the content.
Speaker 1: You know I play this game I solve a puzzle.
Speaker 1: my puzzle solution itself is content that is entertaining to other people.
Speaker 1: That is the way to go games.
Speaker 1: like you know line writer you play the game you draw this line.
Speaker 1: now The line you drew becomes content.
Speaker 1: that is where user generated content and games has to go And I can't wait to see other games that do the same sort of thing
Speaker 0: but Much like when we talked about portal, and we could not help but talk about portal as it was Possibly the most perfect release of any video game in the history of video games.
Speaker 0: Here we are having just finished.
Speaker 0: well not finished, but having beaten enough to talk about by on a commando rearmed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean we talked about this last week or two weeks ago or something whatever, but that was you know unplayed.
Speaker 0: We watched that trailer, and we talked about how excited we were and I was downloading it during the show.
Speaker 0: if I remember well It hasn't been that long and this this game was like one.
Speaker 0: This was the most fun I've had playing a game since portal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, definitely I have to agree 100% but I had a commando rearmed is like the game if you buy any video game This year so far by portal, and if you haven't if you've already this year, I don't even know.
Speaker 0: hey Why not?
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: I think so.
Speaker 1: whether it was or not Right by the commando rearmed is either the best or second best game of the year.
Speaker 1: now The thing is by the commando rearmed.
Speaker 1: right is just a remake of the original by on a commando.
Speaker 0: however That is a game.
Speaker 0: well that does and does not do it justice.
Speaker 0: if you have played the original by on a commando Then saying that is all that needs to be said because by on a commando is Probably the game most in.
Speaker 0: what was the game most in needing of a sequel on a modern console since Kid Icarus?
Speaker 1: Absolutely Kid Icarus.
Speaker 1: Good.
Speaker 1: God.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is Kid Icarus was a fun game But it was frustrating and not that good of a game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well I mean I talked about how Capcom is coming through reviving all the old games right in a good way.
Speaker 1: They got the Mega Man 9 coming right.
Speaker 1: Street Fighter 4 is in the Chinatown arcade.
Speaker 1: Holy shit, right.
Speaker 0: and By the commander we are I mean if any game was ever so true to the original content and yet at the same time Took advantage of modern technology to make a better game.
Speaker 0: It fixed everything.
Speaker 0: what little there was to say badly about the original by on a commando And it added more.
Speaker 1: it was and everything they have added more has only been for the better and not for the worst.
Speaker 1: They didn't go crazy adding too much stuff to ruin the game right.
Speaker 1: they added stuff that made the game better and Removed only what made the game bad, and it's basically they took off.
Speaker 1: It's like going into your closet finding something really old and cruddy But you loved it when you were a kid and polishing it and making it like new and giving a new paint job.
Speaker 0: I mean, they just they understand and I've said this before but It's proven beyond a shadow of a doubt now They understand what it was like the essence of these old games that made them good, and they take that essence alone Extracted from an old game.
Speaker 0: that is not.
Speaker 0: those old games don't stand up to modern games or at least the what modern games could Be but they take that essence and they make new games that have everything that was good.
Speaker 0: It's all right the game is just the original by on a commando, but I mean what do they change?
Speaker 1: By the way just just some people know we played the PC version for $15 on direct-to-drive.com.
Speaker 0: buy it however be warned the DRM Socks just deal with.
Speaker 1: yeah, if you have an Xbox or a ps3 get it that way don't get it with the PC version.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the difference is though.
Speaker 1: if there's if there is any difference all I know is we play the PC version And that's all I know about.
Speaker 0: I'll say one thing you're gonna need a controller and to don't use one of those gravis pads.
Speaker 0: They're terrible.
Speaker 0: yeah get.
Speaker 1: you probably want an Xbox 360 Controller for the PC.
Speaker 0: however if you've got a USB thing I just connected my old ps1 controller to my DDR pad connector, and I plug that into my computer.
Speaker 0: It worked okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that works just fine too, but Xbox 360 controller for the PC is the way to go, but I mean What does this talk about?
Speaker 0: what they've changed?
Speaker 0: this first one the boss battles in the original bionic commando were laughable.
Speaker 0: They were.
Speaker 1: they were basically the way those boss battles worked.
Speaker 1: you would walk to the end of the screen where the boss was.
Speaker 1: You would stand still and shoot until the boss died.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you had to fight a little bit.
Speaker 1: sometimes you occasionally had to grapple up.
Speaker 1: shoot a brunch grapple down shoot a bunch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't grapple down, but you know fall.
Speaker 0: they were trivial.
Speaker 0: the.
Speaker 0: they basically redid every single boss battle But yet they kept the style.
Speaker 0: I mean that robot still says PvP.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's weird.
Speaker 1: It's like it's the same boss somehow yet It's a completely different boss.
Speaker 0: the best one by far is There's always the first platoon in the second platoon and there'd be the guy at the top like waving that sword going attack attack attack.
Speaker 0: Yep, what they did with him.
Speaker 1: That's so fantastic.
Speaker 0: I laughed so hard.
Speaker 0: I died.
Speaker 1: I didn't laugh that hard when I saw it.
Speaker 0: But I don't think bionic commando is quite as near and dear to your heart as is to me now.
Speaker 1: But they definitely load it up on the humor in this game big time.
Speaker 0: I mean the fact that here's what bionic commando was taught me.
Speaker 0: Number one the more facial hair you have the higher ranking you are unless you're the leader.
Speaker 0: and all the interactions between like the bad guys when you hack into the computer are classic.
Speaker 0: because you know the guys basically just have Unless they're a main character or a boss one face and it's kind of this Soviet idealized like propaganda art and the foot soldier.
Speaker 0: the private is this Glowing Adonis of a man with a perfect chin And he's just kind of looking up with admiration and pride and his commander has a mustache.
Speaker 0: And then at the end of the game or near the end of the game you see that guy's commander And he has a full beard, but they're otherwise the exact same guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and just the dialogue.
Speaker 0: It's almost like this avid and Costello kind of straight man crazy It's.
Speaker 0: so I don't I can't really express to you.
Speaker 0: How funny it is.
Speaker 1: They really load it up on the humor.
Speaker 1: I mean there's also some other funny stuff in the game, too.
Speaker 1: Like you'll have these machines that are bosses and some of the machines are just automatic And then they'll have this dialogue between you know the body commando and this Robotic boss and the dialogue is like the boss of like PPP.
Speaker 1: He'll be like shut up It's.
Speaker 1: I don't know why it's funny.
Speaker 0: It just is what I mean in terms of forget gameplay in terms of essence I keep saying essence here.
Speaker 0: They took all the things that were weird about the original bionic commando but kind of like things that added to the atmosphere like The guys that piloted any machine and bionic commando were midgets.
Speaker 0: basically just because of the way the sprites were like there's little half-tall dudes in This game.
Speaker 0: they made that cannon and they basically the way they explained.
Speaker 0: It was just that.
Speaker 0: alright The cute like this boss get you destroy him by pulling him down with weight like you hang on to it pulls the thing down You blow it up whatever.
Speaker 0: so to let you in on this secret.
Speaker 0: They basically talk about how yeah I can't hold any extra weight of course you idiot.
Speaker 0: That's why we have midgets to pilot everything.
Speaker 0: and sure enough you argue with the midget And then you fight him and then you kill him.
Speaker 0: yeah Midgets are hilarious.
Speaker 1: the midgets are definitely the funniest characters in the game Especially the first one who's riding the tank and the fact that all the dialogue is like gatekeepers like everyone is point yell dramatic pose dramatic pose Good times.
Speaker 1: I love how the So-called boss you know refers to the leader.
Speaker 1: He's like yes that leader.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we've revived him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's definitely a nod to the fact that the original bionic commando was Reskinned away from Hitler no Fukatsu in order to not offend the sensibilities of Americans.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like at the end of the game.
Speaker 0: I remember as a kid playing.
Speaker 0: It's like this game is fun and really hard.
Speaker 0: this game is fun.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Is that Hitler basically Hitler?
Speaker 1: Just kill that guy and then swear at me the original bionic commando Which is I think super spy or secret spy top secret.
Speaker 0: it was an arcade game.
Speaker 1: It was top Senjou no Okami.
Speaker 1: yeah Hitler no Fukatsu right?
Speaker 0: no no no the arcade game was top secret Senjou no Okami Okay, and then the NES game.
Speaker 0: well the fact the Famicom game was top secret.
Speaker 1: Hitler no Fukatsu All right, but anyway that game was like Hitler Hitler Hitler.
Speaker 1: But the US version took out the Hitler But you knew it was Hitler in the nuver in the vert.
Speaker 1: in the new version bionic men are rearmed.
Speaker 1: They basically go like they don't say the word Hitler They just wink and nod all the time like you know leader nudge nudge wink wink say no more.
Speaker 0: You know with a big mustache from that war a long time ago, and then at the end of directing him It's the same nudge nudge and all the dialogue is different because the dialogue was kind of broken.
Speaker 0: the original game You know bad translation, whatever.
Speaker 0: Every single line that was in the original game that was hilarious or just stood out Or was memorable is in this game in some kind of altered context which makes it hilarious.
Speaker 0: I mean when what's-his-name yells you damn nerd.
Speaker 0: I about crap myself.
Speaker 1: There's definitely a lot of joke damn nerd get out of here.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of things that are just references to the original game.
Speaker 1: I mean even if you never played the original game, it'll still be awesome.
Speaker 1: But if you did play the original bad at commando, and then you play this and you see all the references.
Speaker 1: You're just doubly awesome.
Speaker 0: I mean when the helicopter pilot is making fun of the fact that you don't wear armor And then later on you get a helmet.
Speaker 0: She's like oh, it's about time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't want to keep going on.
Speaker 0: I'll just start spoiling.
Speaker 0: This is gonna turn into the kind of like if we ever tried to review a good comedy movie like I don't know Ferris Bueller.
Speaker 0: Let's just quote it.
Speaker 1: Let's play about the gameplay right.
Speaker 1: first of all one thing you can do is you can change weapons on the fly And you don't have to pick the right goddamn communicator.
Speaker 0: It just handles that.
Speaker 1: yeah these two things Makes the game so great and also because the original bad at commando You can only bring one weapon into a level.
Speaker 0: that was it But it didn't matter because basically you beat the first level.
Speaker 0: then you immediately went and got the bazooka.
Speaker 0: Use the bazooka in every single level that you could until the end of the game.
Speaker 0: Everything else.
Speaker 1: the bazooka is pretty awesome, but there are different uses for different weapons.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you want to use a different gun besides the bazooka.
Speaker 0: I use every weapon on a regular basis except the main gun.
Speaker 1: However, you also have these awesome grenades.
Speaker 0: Here's the deal.
Speaker 0: all the grenades add so much to the game, but in the original game You know you go talk to district.
Speaker 0: basically you got to save Super Joe and then you talk to.
Speaker 0: you know he tells you which of the destroyer brothers to talk to.
Speaker 0: and The game you know tried to be all cool.
Speaker 0: like you have to get the code and then talk to the right destroyer brother.
Speaker 0: it doesn't work, but if You just knew which guy to talk to you could get Super Joe's gun and it sucked ass and you didn't use it.
Speaker 0: in This game Super Joe's gun is one of the most satisfying Things I've ever used.
Speaker 0: in a game that there is a gun in it's basically an awesome rapid-fire machine gun of us But it feels so good.
Speaker 0: I mean it Shooting this gun pushes you backwards.
Speaker 0: It is so wonderful to fire that weapon.
Speaker 1: yep another great thing They added to the game is that if you get the shotgun, right?
Speaker 1: If you fire this sometimes in when you're playing by on a commando right the way the hook because you can't jump But the way the hook works is you shoot the hook now You're swinging back and forth.
Speaker 1: if you reel in the hook because usually you're when you want to climb up You reel the hook in and then climb.
Speaker 1: But if you reel in the hook and then you realize uh I can't go up And I want to go sideways and under me as a whole what do I do?
Speaker 1: You're just sort of screwed and a lot of situations you'll just be caught hanging there And you'll die.
Speaker 1: if you have the shotgun you can shoot it to start swinging again.
Speaker 1: That is awesome.
Speaker 1: It is so awesome.
Speaker 1: It lets you get out of all these situations You would be stuck in before and it also gives you new options for getting through.
Speaker 1: you know existing situation.
Speaker 1: I mean all the maps in the game except for the secrets are the same as the original maps 99%.
Speaker 1: but because you have all these new abilities in terms of you know the Upgrades to the weapons and the shotgun and the grenades there are new ways to go through the levels that didn't exist before And it's a lot of fun,
Speaker 0: and you know let's talk in terms of just raw game playing What the game is like to play.
Speaker 0: it is difficult, but unlike a lot of games that I see lately This game has a really good difficulty curve.
Speaker 0: I mean Scott played through it on easy first, and I played through it on easy is a joke.
Speaker 0: basically I played through it on medium because I can beat bionic commando in about five minutes longer than it takes for a speedrun.
Speaker 0: I mean I. I played that game a lot as a kid yeah But the original NES one playing it on medium is the perfect.
Speaker 0: perfect.
Speaker 0: if you were good at bionic commando Playing it on medium is absolutely perfect.
Speaker 0: It's the exact right difficulty level.
Speaker 1: it ramps it up beautifully Yeah, and on easy you're missing a lot of the game.
Speaker 1: I mean there are basically bosses that die in one bazooka shot, but normal.
Speaker 0: Scott was watching me playing medium.
Speaker 0: I'm fighting like the big front-end loader like that giant thing the siege cannon thing yeah And he's.
Speaker 0: he's watching me, and I blow up the trade.
Speaker 0: And then he's like ah it didn't end.
Speaker 0: and then I had to do all this other stuff pulling bolts out that he just didn't Have to do.
Speaker 1: yep easy basically just lets you win the game without having to do anything.
Speaker 0: however if you have never played bionic commando You should probably play through the game on easy first.
Speaker 1: yep another thing that's added to the game is sort of like these VR training Rooms.
Speaker 1: all right, which is sort of basically?
Speaker 1: Can you pull off can you get from here to here quickly using the hook and it just it's sort of a test of your?
Speaker 0: Hook skills see this really draws into.
Speaker 0: like what I like about this Megaman 9 and bionic commando Was that bionic commando was really innovative game and it had this mechanic that was never really explored After bionic commando until now and the game did a good job of forcing you to use it in clever ways But it did not kind of explore the full potential of all that was possible.
Speaker 0: And if you played bionic commando the original game enough You basically become as good as that game allowed you to be because there was nothing else fancy You could do.
Speaker 0: you were the most fancy, dude.
Speaker 1: It's as if it was pole vaulting and they just never raised the bar above.
Speaker 1: you know a certain number of feet.
Speaker 0: I believe That this bionic commando raised the bar of that limited tool set of.
Speaker 0: you know grappling hook shot.
Speaker 0: You know all the things.
Speaker 0: you get in the game To the absolute top.
Speaker 0: I think it is perfect.
Speaker 0: I think it the skill you could possibly attain by playing this game and practicing is The most that could be done gameplay wise with this tool set mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I mean hard is balls hard, and then there's a gism.
Speaker 1: super hard mode.
Speaker 0: I have not even deigned to click on super hard.
Speaker 1: I think I'll try it after the show.
Speaker 0: I can't even.
Speaker 1: I mean on hard.
Speaker 1: you died in front level one.
Speaker 0: Yes me Oh my god.
Speaker 0: The thing is basically easy is easy.
Speaker 0: medium is the original bionic commando in terms of level of difficulty.
Speaker 0: in Hard the bad guys do things.
Speaker 0: that bionic commando bad guys never did before they run away.
Speaker 0: They shoot at you at angles.
Speaker 0: They they're smart Super hard, I can't imagine I imagine the albatross and Hitler to show up right away and kill you.
Speaker 1: yeah, who knows what happens?
Speaker 1: but Anyway, the other things are added to.
Speaker 1: the game is a lot of secrets in the game.
Speaker 1: A lot of the secrets are sort of just like blow up a wall Or you know pull off this amazing trick and go into an area you couldn't get into in the original game and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: And if you go and get these secrets, they're cool stuff, and there's weapon upgrades There's unlocks of secret VR rooms There's all sorts of secret stuff and the secrets are really hard to find like I'll think I found every secret in a level.
Speaker 1: I'll get to the end of the level to be like yeah, you found one out of four secrets.
Speaker 1: I'm like where the fuck were they?
Speaker 1: oh my god.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, so even if you beat the game it's fun to go look for the secrets because it's actually cool stuff in there.
Speaker 0: and What else can I say?
Speaker 0: the game is great.
Speaker 0: So we should talk about the other parts.
Speaker 0: because this game They didn't think they did what was perfect.
Speaker 0: they didn't just take the game reskin and fix everything and make it this awesome game Did all those things it would have been if this was it.
Speaker 0: this is already like.
Speaker 0: I would not have any less praise to say about it.
Speaker 0: the game also has co-op and versus multiplayer.
Speaker 1: I so the co-op.
Speaker 1: basically the way the cop works is Two people can play the single-player game at the same time together.
Speaker 0: It's implemented the possibly the best.
Speaker 0: the only thing it is lacking is Network play.
Speaker 1: well at least if there is network play in the PC version.
Speaker 1: I couldn't find it.
Speaker 1: there might be network play in the Xbox or ps3 versions I don't know, but play.
Speaker 0: it was so enjoyable to play it.
Speaker 0: now the thing is we played it You know wondering what's this gonna be like and the normal levels are just super fun.
Speaker 0: There's no friendly fire into that BS.
Speaker 0: It's just Absolutely hilariously amazingly fun to play this game on co-op.
Speaker 0: Scott and I are probably going to beat it on co-op on medium and then hard.
Speaker 0: but Then we got to the boss and we asked ourselves, so is it just gonna be the same boss or what?
Speaker 1: yeah?
Speaker 1: I'm like hey if this boss is the same as it is in single-player, and they didn't change it for co-op It's gonna be a joke cuz you'll throw the barrel at it to get it to fall down And then I'll shoot it with my Nintendo finger right away, and we'll kill it.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's a spoiler to say they changed the bosses.
Speaker 0: It's totally awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we had to work together in order to kill the boss and call it movie.
Speaker 1: both had to throw barrels You know with good timing and then they doubled its health.
Speaker 1: So he both had to shoot it if he wanted to kill it in the same number of tries.
Speaker 0: That's co-op game of the year.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, definitely The problems with the co-op cuz not perfect right?
Speaker 1: is that the camera?
Speaker 1: you know of course if you get far away from the other Guy the camera starts to zoom out and sometimes it was a little disorienting, and I fell off the map.
Speaker 0: well So that was you.
Speaker 0: you basically died left and right and you fell off the map also once.
Speaker 1: the other thing is that?
Speaker 1: There there are three modes.
Speaker 1: right if you get really far away from the other guy It doesn't want to zoom out anymore, so it splits the screen.
Speaker 0: this is Brilliant because how many games like gauntlet back in the day, or how many you know and you try to have a co-op game?
Speaker 0: But it sucks because if you can get stuck because you can't leave the screen together or like one guy's pull another guy long Or it teleports you off, or you die or all these sorts of back together ways.
Speaker 1: now The thing is there are three choices for split-screen is horizontal vertical and auto right.
Speaker 1: Horizontal means whenever they split the screen they'll always split it horizontally.
Speaker 1: vertical means they'll always split it vertically.
Speaker 1: auto means the game will decide on its own how to split it and sometimes it's okay, and sometimes it's not.
Speaker 1: like you'll be trying to go up and Sometimes you get a horizontal split And it's like you can't see what's above and below you and it's not so great.
Speaker 0: see the same.
Speaker 1: sometimes You'll be wanting to go from left to right, but you have a vertical split So you'll be basically having being forced to jump into mystery.
Speaker 0: I might have the bias that I basically have the game memorized from from when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't have the game memorized so well.
Speaker 1: You know I tried to jump to the right and I fell in a hole forgetting it was there But it didn't bother me at all and it was.
Speaker 0: it was such a fluid transition that I just kept playing.
Speaker 1: it is a pretty fluid transition But you know I think really just when you're playing the co-op and you're getting far away from the other guy You have to concentrate a little bit more.
Speaker 0: at the same time playing the co-op is definitely.
Speaker 0: It wouldn't be fun If that was your first time through the game.
Speaker 0: playing co-op is definitely for two people who are similarly skilled or good at the game At least yeah.
Speaker 0: And then you're kind of going through it for this additional.
Speaker 1: it's like if someone has never played the game before played it co-op with like VRM like you just leave you behind and You just sort of be stumbling along dying and then you would die completely and the other person would go on to beat the game.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: it's really really fun and well implemented.
Speaker 0: yep, so Multiplayer versus one you can pick characters.
Speaker 0: you can play as generalissimo kilt.
Speaker 1: There's four characters and Gottfried is kilt Gottfried Super Joe, and you know Spencer, right?
Speaker 1: And there are three modes deathmatch mode, which is who gets the most frags in the time limit, right?
Speaker 0: It's really fun.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean what else can I say right?
Speaker 1: or who gets ex frags first or whatever?
Speaker 1: then there's survival mode which is?
Speaker 1: Who get?
Speaker 1: who can live?
Speaker 1: who can you know not die five times?
Speaker 1: who could not die ten times?
Speaker 1: it's it's Smash Brothers stock and you know.
Speaker 1: basically the way it works is a bunch of maps to choose from and Everyone has a hook and a gun normal just buying a commando weapons.
Speaker 0: You can turn items and weapons on and on.
Speaker 1: you can turn items and weapons on and off.
Speaker 1: the way that works is these items Parachute themselves into the game and you have to hook them to get them and you have and can also turn that off if you Can just grab them.
Speaker 1: yep, you have a choice of.
Speaker 1: you know either touch an item to pick it up or use the hook to pick it up and You get these items and you can get shields.
Speaker 1: you can get you know all the different weapons in the game.
Speaker 1: You can get health.
Speaker 1: you can get all this stuff and all the items you pick up have ammo and Like Super Joe has more ammo and he does a little.
Speaker 1: he does average damage but he does less health.
Speaker 1: and Kilt has not so much ammo, but he does a lot of damage and he has okay health you know and all the care.
Speaker 1: and you know Spencer's even across the board and so you'll pick up a bazooka, but you only have like two or three shots, and then you don't have it anymore.
Speaker 1: you take a hook another weapon and It's really good.
Speaker 1: Now the best thing about the multiplayer mode is they don't touch the floor mode.
Speaker 0: It is remember when you were a kid.
Speaker 0: don't touch the carpet.
Speaker 0: the carpet is hot lava.
Speaker 0: That's what this is and you don't take damage.
Speaker 0: It's just a kind of grabbing.
Speaker 0: if you play the other game any any of the other modes It's basically a test of using the weapons properly and maneuvering well enough to use the weapons properly and get the items.
Speaker 0: Playing in this other mode reminds me a lot of ricochet the old half-life 1 mod Which I love and we should play as a forum.
Speaker 1: we played it.
Speaker 1: I was playing it a few weeks ago.
Speaker 0: I know we got to play it some more cuz.
Speaker 0: that game is great.
Speaker 1: It is great.
Speaker 0: It's a lot like that.
Speaker 0: It's really really fun.
Speaker 0: It's all about grappling skill and posturing and rhythm And I can't imagine how great that'll be with four people based on the way It works.
Speaker 0: everyone has the regular gun everyone has a grappling hook and grenades and you need each other and try to knock each other Back and make the other guy touch the ground while not touching.
Speaker 1: no one actually takes damage.
Speaker 1: You're just trying to get.
Speaker 1: I already said you're just trying to get the other guy to fall off the mat.
Speaker 0: I already said that too, so it's kind of like Smash Brothers.
Speaker 0: It is it's real fun.
Speaker 0: The only problem is well.
Speaker 0: It wasn't really a problem because the game got into a stalemate for a little while.
Speaker 0: But you eventually get bored.
Speaker 0: then it doesn't stalemate And I don't think it can stalemate if you have more than two right.
Speaker 1: we had two people.
Speaker 1: so what happened is me and rim Are facing each other right and it's pretty much shoot shoot shoot, and then you can use your hook to block shots.
Speaker 1: So you're using the hook to block all the shots.
Speaker 1: everyone was shooting and blocking everything course.
Speaker 0: then I just kind of swung around and started fighting again, and right I discovered there is a Almost unbeatable strategy of sitting in this one platform and one of the maps and just shooting in either direction and not letting Scott Get up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it worked real well for like three games in a row.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's it.
Speaker 1: basically you know if you do a certain thing It's really hard for the other person to make a comeback.
Speaker 0: the thing is it's still really fun because much like how tag or Marco I guess I could have waited it out.
Speaker 0: Here's an example Marco Polo.
Speaker 0: The best strategy is to always stay as far away from the guys possible.
Speaker 0: duh But that's not fun.
Speaker 0: you want to show off the people who have the most fun playing Marco Polo.
Speaker 0: are the people who are like standing right behind the guy like holding their hands in front of him and splashing?
Speaker 0: yeah So uh it's the same deal here.
Speaker 0: You start showing off.
Speaker 0: you start like hanging down by the spike standing right on the edge.
Speaker 0: look at me look at me look at Me and that makes the game great, and then if you play with I don't know three or four people oh My god, this will never get old.
Speaker 1: we've never played it with more than two people cuz we've only played it once today.
Speaker 1: That was it, but I can imagine with three or four people that multiplayer has got to be some hot shit.
Speaker 0: This was just seriously the best game.
Speaker 0: I've played since portal, and I I can't even pretend to be exaggerating.
Speaker 1: It's so cheap.
Speaker 1: It's $15 to the PC.
Speaker 1: I think it's $10 in the Xbox dollars.
Speaker 1: Yeah 15 isn't that weird.
Speaker 1: portal was also this great game.
Speaker 1: didn't portal on its own cost like $20 or something like that?
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 1: portal was a better game Yeah, but I'm saying is that look at this the hit games the big games now $15.
Speaker 0: it's just the production values are so high.
Speaker 0: I mean usually when I pay $15 for a game I expect something not so great or at least I expect something great that is not polished or not professional looking.
Speaker 0: This game is so great and also You know I hate this It's not a charity.
Speaker 0: don't buy games just to support the gaming industry or whatever.
Speaker 0: But if more people buy this game they might make more games like this.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: They're making great.
Speaker 1: They're making a 3d next-gen bionic commando, and I'm 50/50 on that.
Speaker 1: I don't know what to think about.
Speaker 0: I've watched all the trailers.
Speaker 1: the controls are really bad.
Speaker 1: From who?
Speaker 1: someone who played it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I kotaku will see because I watched all the trailers And it.
Speaker 0: it didn't look like it was necessarily bad And it could be good, and they've got great voice actors and a lot of talent lined up.
Speaker 0: I'm just I'm 50/50, but it has potential and I will buy it and try it for what?
Speaker 0: well I'll probably play it on someone else's Xbox.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh all right.
Speaker 0: I gotta try it.
Speaker 0: It's bionic man.
Speaker 1: I don't know is that gonna come up for the PC or not.
Speaker 1: It's a good question.
Speaker 0: I just buy an Xbox.
Speaker 0: It's getting to that point.
Speaker 1: Well, I was thinking I was gonna wait till we get HDTV and then get an Xbox for which?
Speaker 0: but we gotta buy a house.
Speaker 1: Sorry Xbox 3 because the Xbox 360 is actually the Xbox 2.
Speaker 0: Alright, so we have to buy a house Then we have to buy an HDTV to put in that house, and then I will buy an Xbox.
Speaker 0: yep And then bionic commando yep Alright, we're gonna stop right here.
Speaker 0: There's really only gonna be one show this week because we have to fly to Seattle for packs.
Speaker 1: I think we might put up some shows that other listeners did.
Speaker 0: maybe we got to figure that out.
Speaker 0: those things will come up and For all you listeners who are wondering where the Monday shows went That's just luck of the draw starting.
Speaker 0: probably the week after.
Speaker 0: next week We'll have some sort of like two Mondays in a row just to you know.
Speaker 0: set things right again.
Speaker 1: Maybe we'll do like a couple full weeks in a row or something.
Speaker 1: who knows?
Speaker 0: we'll figure something out.
Speaker 1: Let's see what's going on.
Speaker 0: suffice to say Saturday August 30th 6 p.m.. Satellite theater room 307 Wolfman beyond Dungeons and Dragons.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.