Speaker 0: It's Monday September 15th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight IPV6.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: I live I'm back.
Speaker 1: That's not good.
Speaker 0: I'm no longer hacking up my lungs.
Speaker 0: I'm no longer sick.
Speaker 0: It's a good feeling.
Speaker 1: you know last week I was like really wanted to do episodes, and I still want to do episodes too I mean, but I don't want to do them as much as I wanted to do them last week.
Speaker 1: It's all your fault.
Speaker 0: Oh, so you don't want to do the show.
Speaker 0: we could just stop right now I do.
Speaker 1: I just don't want to do it as much as I want to do it before.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, I think you just want to do things you get.
Speaker 1: a few people are getting a slightly lesser quality show because of rims.
Speaker 1: Non-immunity to illness.
Speaker 1: you know I said in the house full of sick people for a week and nothing happened to me.
Speaker 0: all right Let's chalk that up to your sedentary lifestyle.
Speaker 1: I Shouldn't be so.
Speaker 1: you're saying the sedentary lifestyle is a barrier now.
Speaker 0: It's more that I guess I get out.
Speaker 0: I'm exposed to more things.
Speaker 0: I put myself at more risk for greater reward.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay, I think that's definitely the cause.
Speaker 1: no I think how could I be at more risk than in-house for the sick people.
Speaker 0: you pretty much avoided us And we avoided you though It's not it's same house.
Speaker 1: It's all good.
Speaker 0: anyway We're back and to make up for the fact that the only show we did last week was a somewhat Abbreviated Friday night party line where I basically sat there quiet or slowly went off and rambling tangents because I was sick and tired.
Speaker 0: But we're gonna do three shows this week.
Speaker 0: So I guess the way I would put it is it's a Monday Wednesday week, and we just we're gonna do a Tuesday to be nice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we've got too much packs that we still have.
Speaker 0: not I think.
Speaker 0: all told we're gonna be able to say that there were at least seven episodes directly caused by going to packs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much Luckily only two maybe three of them.
Speaker 0: I think three and a half of them are going to be about packs and the rest are just tertiary.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we're gonna do some tech news, right?
Speaker 1: But we've got how many like weeks worth of tech news we haven't talked about.
Speaker 0: And the worst thing is I have this list of like nine articles.
Speaker 0: I really wanted to talk about.
Speaker 0: I mean last Monday I had a ton of news.
Speaker 0: I wanted to talk about if I hadn't been sick, but Scott has some news.
Speaker 0: that kind of is just breaking that.
Speaker 0: Really it made us kind of have to forget about all that other BS I got.
Speaker 1: all these news is no I got to do one that I just saw Just now a second before we started doing the show and worse than that, right?
Speaker 1: It's like Apple put out there like new nano and whatnot, right?
Speaker 1: Well, we got two.
Speaker 1: Apple news is but they're not related in any way to the announcements They just made which were pretty in.
Speaker 0: I know I mean pretty much though I mean the feeling I had is like man.
Speaker 0: I totally got to talk about all this awesome news.
Speaker 0: and then someone walks into the room and they're like, oh, hey Microsoft went open source.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a hundred percent Damn savers repealed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Bill Gates just wrote you personally a check for a million dollars because he felt like it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what I feel like right now.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: It's not the good news.
Speaker 0: It's actually the bad news.
Speaker 0: It's more like Microsoft sued Linus Torvalds and then shot him.
Speaker 0: Yep Oh, well, so I gotta I'll talk about this first because once we get on to Scott's news, there's really no turning back.
Speaker 0: so Apple in their infinite wisdom has decided that this a scourge has got to end.
Speaker 0: They're done with this bullshit and they're gonna file a patent to make sure that people don't pull this crap off anymore.
Speaker 0: No more shenanigans, you see Apparently, oh, no.
Speaker 0: No, you know what?
Speaker 0: I'll quote from the patent application.
Speaker 0: quote Apple.
Speaker 0: Some people have taken it upon themselves To remove the sensor from the special pocket of the iPod linked Nike plus shoe Place it in inappropriate locations like the shoelaces or place it on non Nike plus shoes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: So Apple is filing a patent for clothing DRM in order to try to make it illegal and in and/or You to take this little cheap sensor from this Nike shoe that's special and branded for Apple and Put it on anything else or must with it or move it to the shoelaces.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess think about this, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, you know shoes look different and some shoes feel different and fit people's feet Differently and some shoes are better for one thing or better for another thing, you know It makes a difference.
Speaker 1: or I mean no shoe is gonna let you jump as high as Michael Jordan And a Chuck Taylor or in well Air Jordans.
Speaker 0: There's a difference between cross trainers and running shoes, right?
Speaker 0: If you're running by where cross train.
Speaker 1: Apple made this deal with Nike for this Nike plus thing And basically what they did is is alright We'll put this technology in the iPhone that links it with your Nike shoes so you can track.
Speaker 1: You know, you're running or whatever and you know, it's it.
Speaker 1: people are having a lot of fun these days You know having pedometers and all sorts of things like that and heart monitors to to track their physical fitness stuff Combining the workout with the technology.
Speaker 1: So the deal with Apple and Nike did the whole point of it was Nike's like hey If we get if we're the only people who are allowed to put this technology in our clothing We'll sell a bunch of Nike shit, and then it's
Speaker 0: not
Speaker 1: see Nike logos all over the place.
Speaker 0: But the patent is not for you know Someone else making a similar device?
Speaker 0: the patent is to prevent you from taking the device that's in the Nike and putting it in Because they about Nike.
Speaker 1: right, you know, if you were just let's say you're just trying to sell shoes Oh, wouldn't you just make the best shoe and then people would buy it.
Speaker 1: but they slap Nike logos on everything.
Speaker 1: And the reason is because a lot of what you know clothing is is you have your brand on the clothing So people see it and if people don't see it Then it sort of defeats the purpose.
Speaker 1: and they Nike made this deal with Apple You know, they're paying money to make sure that you know.
Speaker 1: Those things are only in Nike shoes and people see.
Speaker 0: Nike logos are the amazing thing.
Speaker 0: It's not like you can pirate that sensor.
Speaker 0: anyone who has that sensor?
Speaker 0: Someone along the chain bought for money a Nike shoe that had it, right?
Speaker 1: But you know if Nike what is gonna sell?
Speaker 1: you a shoe and then somehow you were going to be able to Wear that shoe, but no one sees the Nike logos and and you're basically denying them.
Speaker 1: It's like the shoe comes with advertising.
Speaker 1: It's like you're taking the ads out.
Speaker 1: if you're gonna take the ads out they would have charged you more.
Speaker 0: What I like is that you basically pay for the privilege of the advertising.
Speaker 1: I know right?
Speaker 1: So it's like they're selling you a shoe that is subsidized by the advertising on the shoe.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like the high school fashion.
Speaker 0: I mean kids were I guess the Abercrombie or whatever and Abercrombie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I granted I'll admit most of my clothing was from Abercrombie when I was a kid I I just had clothing that was just colors part of that just because I really only went shopping in the mall.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it's like most of their clothing is basically just a normal t-shirt that says their brand on the front of it.
Speaker 0: But I just I think Nike's worry too is that once the Nike shoe wears out No one's gonna buy.
Speaker 0: well geeks at least aren't gonna buy another Nike shoe to get another sensor.
Speaker 0: There's gonna keep taking the sensor and putting it on their new balances.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz if you that yeah, if you if you're stuck with the shoe wears out, but the technology like that doesn't.
Speaker 0: yeah Cuz the thing is I mean most people.
Speaker 0: if you're not active I mean shoes last a long time, but if you're a runner you'll go through like two pairs of shoes a season.
Speaker 1: No, depending on what shoe you get.
Speaker 1: Well any if you're actually around where you run You're running like a gym and like a shit with a shiny floor.
Speaker 0: No If you're a runner and you run every day even on a shiny floor gym with the best running shoes in the world Those things are gonna wear the fuck out.
Speaker 0: but anyway This patent like it bothers me.
Speaker 0: The Apple fanboys came out of the woodwork and they basically said no no Apple's not being evil.
Speaker 0: Nike is forcing them to do this because if they don't then Nike you'll get mad and they'll take their business Elsewhere.
Speaker 0: or Nike's forced him to do it because of the licensing deal and they have to do good faith and blah blah blah blah And more and more.
Speaker 0: I feel like I've got shenanigans on that.
Speaker 0: I just I don't feel like Apple can use.
Speaker 1: Apple makes the technology here.
Speaker 1: They hold all the cards.
Speaker 1: Nike is probably paying them for the exclusivity.
Speaker 0: not yet.
Speaker 0: every time Apple has a anyone gets mad about Apple DRM that people always seem to say no No, no, they're forcing Apple to do it.
Speaker 0: They're forced Apple to do it.
Speaker 1: Apple is the DRM King.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is the company that doesn't want you to put their OS on another piece of hardware.
Speaker 1: It's the company that has DRM in their iTunes store.
Speaker 1: It's the company.
Speaker 1: All right, Apple is DRM everything.
Speaker 1: this is not Nike's idea All right.
Speaker 0: So speaking of DRM because I just had to talk about this but Scott let it rip.
Speaker 1: so the one thing we've always said right is that We need a portable device that there's no Technological reason that this should not exist and shit could have existed three years ago, right the PSP basically does it?
Speaker 1: Yeah a piece of portable technology with Wi-Fi and or cell phone in it.
Speaker 1: Right that can get wireless data that can subscribe to download and play Podcasts on its own without any other device helping it.
Speaker 1: There is no technological reason.
Speaker 1: This couldn't happen, right?
Speaker 1: all you need is pretty much a headphone hole a Processor some flash memory and a Wi-Fi card and a CPU.
Speaker 1: That's all I said.
Speaker 1: processor That's all you need.
Speaker 1: you connect those four things.
Speaker 1: You're done.
Speaker 1: That's the whole technology right there.
Speaker 1: I guess you need a screen and a user interface.
Speaker 0: I want to preface this whole discussion by pointing out that it is my belief and the belief of a lot of people that Podcasting and kind of independent non radio audio in general and video - yeah.
Speaker 0: But I think audio is the thing that could benefit the most.
Speaker 0: Yeah is basically floundering and the reason it is is that People want to just listen to the radio without any effort and when they're in their car the place where most people listen To audio nowadays outside of you know cities where people do it in commutes They just turn on the radio and they just listen to.
Speaker 0: they don't have to like synchronize anything prepare anything.
Speaker 0: hit the button It's there.
Speaker 0: they listen to something right they want to listen to something but most people hate the radio.
Speaker 0: People complain about it all the time.
Speaker 1: There's ads and shit.
Speaker 0: if they could just like a bad reception to their internet radio or their internet audio.
Speaker 1: Well, this is why satellite radio exists right.
Speaker 1: satellite radio doesn't have a lot of the bad reception problems.
Speaker 1: that what?
Speaker 1: FM am has right and it has a billion stations.
Speaker 1: so you can just pay and is Relatively a lot less commercials, you know, you have to pay a fee for it.
Speaker 1: But you know, you basically have a satellite radio.
Speaker 1: you say I listen to blues music.
Speaker 1: There's like three blues stations.
Speaker 1: you pick one.
Speaker 1: blues music just starts coming at the same time.
Speaker 0: It's still not enough for the geeks because it's not balkanized enough.
Speaker 0: I can't listen to the obscure weird music I like because it's not there.
Speaker 0: and still none of the podcast none of the time shifted.
Speaker 0: independent cool stuff.
Speaker 0: Look at this Podcasting.
Speaker 1: right as podcasting is right now.
Speaker 1: You're obviously all listening to a podcast.
Speaker 1: It's Fickle and difficult for normal people, right?
Speaker 1: They have to go to a website.
Speaker 1: They have to figure out RSS and subscribing.
Speaker 1: they have to figure out syncing.
Speaker 1: they have to manage the downloading and the deleting and the downloading again and the you know, The whole it's a thing to manage.
Speaker 1: It's a lot more work.
Speaker 1: You can't just go BAM, right?
Speaker 1: Imagine if for example, you had a satellite radio, right but instead of all the different numbered channels It was just.
Speaker 1: there was a geek nice channel and you went in the geek nice channel And then there's a list of every geek nights episode and you picked one.
Speaker 1: you push play and it just played.
Speaker 1: right that could be.
Speaker 1: there's no reason that technology is Doesn't exist today other than no company has bothered to make it.
Speaker 0: and without the cell phone and without the direct on demand Why do I need to tether my stupid iPhone which has multiple ways of getting data?
Speaker 0: Even if it's not just?
Speaker 0: you know, I'm out there and I listen to things streaming real-time.
Speaker 0: Why do I need to go to my computer to sync?
Speaker 0: Why can't I just subscribe on the iPhone?
Speaker 0: It has iTunes.
Speaker 1: There's no reason that any device with Wi-Fi or even Bluetooth, right?
Speaker 1: Even if it has Bluetooth I should be able to connect to my computer with Bluetooth to sync.
Speaker 1: Why do I have to plug the device into the computer?
Speaker 1: Right the Zune has to plug into the computer.
Speaker 1: everything has to plug into the computer.
Speaker 1: There's no reason for that.
Speaker 1: if I may if I was a company that made, you know, mp3 players or you know digital You know portable multimedia devices, there would be no cable.
Speaker 1: There would be a charging cable.
Speaker 1: That would be it.
Speaker 1: The cable would only charge and everything would be over the air on its own.
Speaker 1: now Think about what this does for a second.
Speaker 1: this technology that we're talking about here.
Speaker 1: Isn't just a convenient thing for Podcast listeners right to to be able to get a podcast say if they haven't been home in a few days?
Speaker 1: or you know They can get a new episode if suddenly the episode shows up while they're outside and they don't have a computer handy But they have their iPod ready.
Speaker 1: It is that.
Speaker 1: but what it really is what this technology really is is no matter where you are You have on-demand radio on-demand radio.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I mean that's even better than satellite radio satellite radio.
Speaker 1: You have a hundred certain stations be it.
Speaker 1: I'll listen to what the station is playing right now.
Speaker 1: on-demand radio is listen to anything you want whenever you want at any time in any place and something that can subscribe and download and stream podcasts with Wi-Fi or cell phone is That now it's completely revolutionary.
Speaker 1: It's amazing.
Speaker 1: It would change the way people listen to everything and podcasts would suddenly explode all over the place.
Speaker 0: Someone made it before we go into the news.
Speaker 0: the other point that I need to make just in case you're not a hundred Percent aware of this, you know iTunes can do it and Apple very pointedly very on purpose disabled over the wireless Podcast to anything.
Speaker 1: well, they didn't disable it.
Speaker 1: They just this.
Speaker 1: the iPhone has all the hardware necessary to do this in it.
Speaker 1: It has Wi-Fi it has cell phone.
Speaker 1: It can play mp3s.
Speaker 1: Right it can.
Speaker 1: that people have made RSS readers for it.
Speaker 1: It can do it.
Speaker 1: this hardware.
Speaker 1: If the iPhone had no software and it was just a piece of hardware and you wrote all the software for it You can make it do that trivially up and also software.
Speaker 0: it runs iTunes.
Speaker 1: It does.
Speaker 1: It can download music from the iTunes music store right over the air But it can't download a podcast episode over the air.
Speaker 1: They just they just.
Speaker 1: this is the thing that Apple does all the time right?
Speaker 1: is that?
Speaker 1: see?
Speaker 1: This is why you know open-source people are so crazy.
Speaker 1: if I have a piece of hardware, right?
Speaker 1: Let's say I have a fork right I go to the store and I buy a fork.
Speaker 1: Well, I can eat spaghetti with the fork right I can eat bread with the fork I guess right.
Speaker 1: I can do all sorts of things of the fork.
Speaker 0: I mean pry a nail out of the wall if you really want to.
Speaker 1: I know a fork can do so many different things Right?
Speaker 1: anything that you can think of to do with a fork if you bought that fork.
Speaker 1: You can do it with that fork if you can think to do it, right?
Speaker 0: But Apple likes to attach a device where and they say you can use this for for anything you want Except spaghetti fuck spaghetti.
Speaker 1: Well, no, it's actually worse than that.
Speaker 1: What it is is here.
Speaker 1: You have bought the fork Here is the fork the fork can do nothing and here is software.
Speaker 1: This software allows this fork to do what things.
Speaker 1: one two and three.
Speaker 1: the fork cannot do anything else Except for one two and three because that is the only software we have made.
Speaker 1: I put that program the fork to do anything else except for these few specific things.
Speaker 0: I put that fork into some Unapproved spaghetti and the prongs just fall right off.
Speaker 1: and my well, it just doesn't even go.
Speaker 1: you try to put it in it It doesn't?
Speaker 1: it's impossible.
Speaker 1: prongs fall off The pork just flies back into the kitchen and goes in the drawer stabs your mom along the way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right This is why people are so crazy with Linux, right Linux might be a little difficult for normal people or whatever And I get into that right now.
Speaker 1: The point is is do you have Linux on a piece of hardware?
Speaker 1: It's open source.
Speaker 1: if there is something that the hardware can do You can do it because the software lets you do it no matter what.
Speaker 0: to summarize now This is before we even get into the news.
Speaker 1: yet The iPhone and this is true not just with the iPod the iPhone but all Apple products.
Speaker 1: OS X does not let you do everything that a Computer hardware does running on is capable of but but in some for the specific news Apple pointedly does not allow you to do this.
Speaker 0: one thing that a lot of people would really like to do.
Speaker 0: that really couldn't hurt Apple in any way.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not that they don't allow you to do it.
Speaker 0: It's that they have not enabled you to do it yes, but the thing is they basically you can't do it and So what could someone else let you do it?
Speaker 0: Could you write something else to do it?
Speaker 1: So so, of course the App Store comes out right and it's not just us that have seen this obvious gaping hole.
Speaker 1: Everyone in the freaking podcasting universe is seen as gaping hole.
Speaker 0: This was like the first thing when Kotaku was like, oh my god iPhone there were like can't do podcast WTF mate?
Speaker 1: Well in gadget not Kotaku Kotaku doesn't care.
Speaker 1: All right, but pretty much everyone wants this.
Speaker 1: So of course the App Store.
Speaker 1: it was only a matter of time before someone did it.
Speaker 1: So someone did it and they submitted it to the I the App Store pretty much right away and It was rejected from the App Store on the grounds, right?
Speaker 1: And here's where we start getting in trouble.
Speaker 1: They made this app that basically does exactly what we said.
Speaker 1: you can just subscribe to podcast download them or stream them audio or video over the Wi-Fi and Over the cell phone network.
Speaker 1: just you know, wherever you have a connection to the iPhone.
Speaker 1: It's all good.
Speaker 1: All right, the only problem with it is because you know the way the apps on the iPhone work.
Speaker 1: It doesn't integrate with the iPod software on the iPhone So it's not like you can add the podcast to the iPod section.
Speaker 1: You can only play them, you know from within.
Speaker 1: the you know, the plate the app itself, you know Which is a little bit annoying but it doesn't matter because it's still great even you know, forgetting that small problem right now I'm gonna play the the naive optimistic person.
Speaker 0: So so here's here's here's my little roleplay Golly gee now I can listen to podcasts on my iPhone without having to synchronize it to my iTunes.
Speaker 1: hot damn Yeah, well, they rejected it from the App Store and the reason they said they rejected it from the App Store was because it duplicates the functionality of iTunes.
Speaker 0: now now now now now now now.
Speaker 0: so Apple won't let me Synchronize podcasts over the air with their software and if someone writes software that does just that one thing.
Speaker 0: They say it competes with their own software.
Speaker 0: that doesn't do that.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing though, right?
Speaker 1: This is where it gets kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: First of all, it doesn't compete with their software because it doesn't duplicate anything.
Speaker 1: It adds functionality that iTunes doesn't and the iPhone don't have.
Speaker 1: Secondly, there are people out there making apps for the iPhone such as weather apps and calculator apps and all sorts of other apps That do just duplicate existing functionality of the iPhone and iTunes and don't do anything else.
Speaker 1: so those apps are allowed in.
Speaker 1: yet this one isn't.
Speaker 1: and The only thing is puzzling is why don't they want this technology?
Speaker 1: now this turn on competing, you know, they They're not friends with the satellite radio.
Speaker 1: What do they give a shit about?
Speaker 0: No, that's why this is such an important and interesting news because this tells us something.
Speaker 0: This tells us that there's something we don't know.
Speaker 0: There's some specific reason Apple does not want us to have this functionality.
Speaker 0: because I mean before I mean They could have had a bunch of internal reasons.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know dev teams are they might say well this feature blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: Let's just not bother with it.
Speaker 0: They could have a bunch of Semibs, but good enough reasons, you know, who cares?
Speaker 0: it's a company they whatever they want, but the fact that they didn't include it and then they very Specifically disallow this means that there's something.
Speaker 0: there's some Specific direct reason why Apple as a policy reason does not want us to get I to get podcasts over the air.
Speaker 1: And this is this is something that people want.
Speaker 1: millions like millions of people want this and people who don't even know they want it Yeah on it.
Speaker 0: So this doesn't exist.
Speaker 0: That's the question.
Speaker 0: What is it?
Speaker 0: What is the reason?
Speaker 0: Why does Apple not want this Apple?
Speaker 1: Why is no company just jumped on this?
Speaker 1: I mean, well the PSP Is too big I know but it's the zoo.
Speaker 1: and did this everyone would have Zunes.
Speaker 1: what the fuck is Microsoft smoking?
Speaker 0: But what's I mean, I'm really creative.
Speaker 1: creative makes a million every SanDisk.
Speaker 1: There's so many Samsung.
Speaker 1: someone do it good and this is why right this is what open source is all about.
Speaker 1: if the Hardware is the only thing that actually requires a big company and money and all this You know such with open source.
Speaker 1: if it can't be done and people want it to get done It gets done.
Speaker 1: No If they're you know.
Speaker 1: If somehow right instead of having like portable devices that were controlled by companies portable devices were like PCs or you just could put whatever operating system on there you wanted.
Speaker 1: all of them would do this every single one of them.
Speaker 0: It would be you know, but but still I like.
Speaker 0: I really I want to know.
Speaker 0: I'm curious What do you guys out there think like?
Speaker 0: Why what is it that I mean?
Speaker 0: Do they think it'll compete with them selling stuff in the iTunes to podcast?
Speaker 1: I mean if they were worried about podcasts actually like succeeding and somehow Nobody pays for any music or listens to any streaming radio or anything anymore.
Speaker 1: ever, you know It kills satellite FM and iTunes store and everything and suddenly Podcasts are the only thing left.
Speaker 1: if they're worried about that Why do they even have podcasts and iTunes in the first place?
Speaker 0: maybe because they added it and then you know to get iTunes out There and then they kind of don't want it to get any further and they're just hoping it'll die quietly.
Speaker 1: Because you know if iTunes didn't have podcasting at all wouldn't use an iPod.
Speaker 1: That's for sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I definitely wouldn't either I. I basically only use my iPod because it does podcasting better than anything else.
Speaker 1: And that's another thing right.
Speaker 1: even if no one else is gonna go for the wireless podcast go for the big score.
Speaker 1: Why don't you at least just do podcasts as well as iTunes does it?
Speaker 1: everyone else is?
Speaker 1: Podcasting it does.
Speaker 1: they do it like poop.
Speaker 1: It's like completely useless.
Speaker 0: even well part of that I think is just it's a catch-22.
Speaker 1: not even like not Applications like Amarok and and such and such don't do podcasting on their own, but that's really good as iTunes does.
Speaker 0: It's really obvious why that it's a catch-22.
Speaker 0: Not enough people listen to podcasts for anyone to care about doing that because not enough people isn't a podcast.
Speaker 0: There's no benefit to be had.
Speaker 0: but there's a difference between Apple saying it's not worth our effort to support this in any way and Apple saying we're going to pointedly You from doing this even when someone else did all the work for us.
Speaker 0: yeah, so the story doesn't end there.
Speaker 1: No, it doesn't.
Speaker 0: so that this is.
Speaker 0: this is where this is why we're talking about this.
Speaker 0: everyone get ready to raise a big finger in the sky alright, so Normally right.
Speaker 1: the only way to get software onto your iPhone is to either get it from the App Store or jailbreak right.
Speaker 1: well The people who made this podcasting software that was rejected from iTunes have come up with something better.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: basically what they've done is first of all you go to their website and watch a video of the software to be suitably Impressed.
Speaker 1: they're not geek nights listeners, but you know they listen to.
Speaker 1: you know all the all the podcasts.
Speaker 1: You know the tech ones like the twits and the buzz out loud and all those things right.
Speaker 1: anyway They have made their software Available to people who have not jailbroken their iPhones But not through the App Store.
Speaker 1: the way they've set it up as far as I can tell right is.
Speaker 1: you go to their website You give them her email address Then you give them the UD ID which is basically the unique Identifying number from your iPhone and they have instructions to tell you how to you know.
Speaker 1: give them the number.
Speaker 1: You give them the number.
Speaker 1: what it appears to me is they're taking this number putting it in there.
Speaker 1: You know I iPhone dev kit, or you know iPod touch dev kit or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it has to be iPhone I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: and then They are using that to deliver the software to you via their dev kit it seems.
Speaker 1: So they're basically circumventing the App Store to get this app out there because they care about it that much.
Speaker 0: Okay, so one what this means is that Apple is going to sue the fuck out of them.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna see what happens here.
Speaker 1: But I totally I'm going for it all out.
Speaker 0: everyone out there jump on this now.
Speaker 0: The more of us have it the more damage we can do.
Speaker 0: yeah,
Speaker 1: of course you know people are speculating about you know Apple being able to remotely delete things and such and such and such But I I hope there's some sort of court action where we bring to light some sort of like you know industry Conspiracy or you know collusion to prevent a particular technology from coming into existence.
Speaker 1: that would be obviously Beneficial or something like.
Speaker 0: I mean it might be far-fetched to say that like the technology industry at large has some sort of consortium or conspiracy.
Speaker 0: yeah It is a little crazy But it is not at all crazy to say that Apple very specifically is trying to keep this under wraps And why I don't understand why they don't want to do it.
Speaker 1: if if Steve Jobs said enough I think about this Steve Jobs Just did his little announcement.
Speaker 1: He's like new nanos yada yada yada right?
Speaker 1: Imagine if his announcement instead was new nanos.
Speaker 1: by the way the nanos have Wi-Fi and by the way Over-the-air podcast.
Speaker 1: people would be going.
Speaker 1: Instead people are going.
Speaker 1: yeah boring you got nothing good.
Speaker 1: We didn't get new MacBooks.
Speaker 1: Fuck you Steve come back next time, right?
Speaker 1: It's so easy.
Speaker 1: It's like a pile of gold is sitting there, and no one's picking it up.
Speaker 1: But we can't pick it up because we don't make hardware.
Speaker 1: If I somehow got money from some like any investor at all I would just do this immediately, and I'd be immediately rich.
Speaker 1: It's a guaranteed hit.
Speaker 1: I don't even care.
Speaker 1: if no one has me do it someone else do it.
Speaker 0: good God Things of the day.
Speaker 0: so actually this is one of my favorite movies even though It's a terrible movie for from almost any perspective.
Speaker 0: It's full of one-liners bad special effects the plot is uh Hilarious and the thing is it's hilarious partly because it takes itself completely Seriously almost the whole way through this movie is the running man.
Speaker 1: what the running man is not terrible.
Speaker 1: What's wrong with the running man is awesome.
Speaker 0: that movie is terrible and all.
Speaker 1: no It's just awesome and a non-ironic fat.
Speaker 0: wait wait wait wait now terrible.
Speaker 0: Scott you realize that the word terrible and the word awesome Depending on what definition you use and what connotations you bring along have very similar meanings.
Speaker 0: I've been the terrible the awesome and powerful.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: well it is awesome and the running man is a fine piece of cinema.
Speaker 0: Money big prizes.
Speaker 1: I could maybe I'd have to actually make a list.
Speaker 1: it might make my top 100 but maybe 200, but it's way up there, and you know cuz there's so many movies Good ones, but he says I'll be back, and he's totally back But not for like a half-hour.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I love the running man.
Speaker 1: It's great.
Speaker 0: It is a great movie.
Speaker 0: It is great awesome, and it's fantastic and not terrible.
Speaker 0: It is very much terrible.
Speaker 0: good Lee awesome and terrible.
Speaker 0: good Period it is goodly.
Speaker 0: now anyway what I have for you is the original theatrical Trailer to the running man, and let me tell you in the era before Thunderthroat movie trailers Really really sucked.
Speaker 1: does that mean they're gonna suck again?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: because I don't.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen any movie trailers in a while.
Speaker 0: I haven't gone to a theater.
Speaker 0: I mean the thing is well I see like a lot of independent film movie trailers But they're never like normal movie.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 1: They don't hire Thunder through.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 1: No one's hired him.
Speaker 0: now Someday, we're gonna have the capability to just recreate his voice.
Speaker 1: perfectly well start smoking now, and you'll you'll get there.
Speaker 0: No, I'll probably just sound like this in about five minutes.
Speaker 1: No, that's what you're gonna sound like when you're 80 when that the mid-range in your 50s sound great.
Speaker 0: Yeah But anyway because that's not enough of a thing of the day The bonus pack because they both have the same word in the title at least the same root word.
Speaker 0: I have the three minute long theatrical trailer to Logan's run.
Speaker 0: now If you think that movie trailers from the running man era are bad.
Speaker 0: Feast your eyes and ears upon the terribly good trailer To the running man, which is also a fantastically Awesomely terrible movie.
Speaker 1: I could go on a slight tangent about comics for a minute if you want.
Speaker 0: That's fine Okay, so check this out right.
Speaker 0: I'm checking at PAX Ken Levine.
Speaker 1: he was given the keynote.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah He talked about how he was buying the Logan's run comic when he was a kid right and how it disappeared Because there was no internet.
Speaker 0: he had no way to know what happened to it, right?
Speaker 1: And of course it was canceled cuz no one's buying it.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm a fan.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean, they're not big on the superheroes obviously if you haven't listened to a Wednesday episode, but in Marvel Comics There's the Cosmics which are basically it's all the comics about what happens in space, you know It's not about Iron Man and Captain America.
Speaker 1: It's about the Silver Surfer and Galactus Thanatos, right?
Speaker 0: Right exactly Oh Thanos I don't read any of that underwear pervert crap, right?
Speaker 1: So there's a dude Adam Warlock in space and he's pretty fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: he's he's my man, right.
Speaker 1: and the thing is I've never read like the old old old Adam Warlock comics and Recently Marvel came out with this hardcover.
Speaker 1: That's like Annihilation classic.
Speaker 1: It's like it's basically.
Speaker 1: they took a bunch of classic space comics put them in a book and that and they sort of labeled them with the same label.
Speaker 1: that's on the new space comics and it's sort of like Hey read this to get some background information on the new space comics, right?
Speaker 1: And there's an Adam Warlock comic in there that I kind of want to read and there's some Rocket Raccoon and whatever.
Speaker 1: But Logan's run number six is in there Six.
Speaker 0: Yeah that far.
Speaker 1: I think there must be something in Logan's run number six that ties it into the.
Speaker 1: You know Marvel something there.
Speaker 0: There can't be.
Speaker 1: there must be what?
Speaker 1: But I'm not gonna buy the book to find out because it's hardcover only.
Speaker 1: but if it's ever softcover I'm gonna buy it and find all this easier way on a Wednesday.
Speaker 0: Just ask people to tell you what the link is.
Speaker 0: someone out there is gonna own that thing.
Speaker 0: Maybe anyway.
Speaker 1: So check out this news.
Speaker 1: Thank you.
Speaker 1: thing of the day not news.
Speaker 1: I did my news.
Speaker 1: So it's you know, the US military has good and bad parts of it, you know.
Speaker 1: But the best part of it according to Scott good parts made the internet bad parts killing people.
Speaker 1: Exactly is that the good parts are that we give it so much money In order to spend?
Speaker 1: because in the way government works is you get money from the government and that if you're a government Department or agency and if you don't spend all the money Let's say I get I own a lab a government lab and they give me a million dollars one year for my budget and I spend 800,000 they'll say oh, I guess you didn't need a million.
Speaker 1: Here's only 800,000 next year and you go fuck Right good.
Speaker 1: And then if you try to do something more well now you're SOL.
Speaker 1: So the you know military gets lots and lots of money and since a lot of that money goes to defense contractors those defense contractors say hey if we want to make more money the only way for us to make more money because you don't have any customers but the government right is to tell the government to increase the military budget.
Speaker 1: and it goes in a cycle basically of the Military spends all its money on research and making shit.
Speaker 1: then the government You know has to increase that budget because the contractors make them and because they're the ones who get the money in the end.
Speaker 1: And so on and so forth and the result of this despite it being sort of bad in many ways you know with the military industrial complex is that many many awesome technologies are developed and Many of those, you know besides, you know, the ones that are pretty much only military use like space death lasers
Speaker 0: are
Speaker 1: used for.
Speaker 1: You know civilian things later on like the internet which is meant for one thing but is now meant for me talking to you right now.
Speaker 1: So one thing military has developed right is basically little you know Unmanned like like flying little airplane guys, right so That was some eloquence right that was.
Speaker 1: I mean Spy drone basically like a robot spy plane, but like a big spy plane like a little one that you could hold.
Speaker 0: But yes, I would use the word drone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not as small as like a paper airplane.
Speaker 1: It's like about a you know meter wide or so, maybe like that.
Speaker 1: It's hard to tell, you know It's pretty big.
Speaker 1: you pick it up and you can throw it right, but it's it's big.
Speaker 1: It's like as wide as you know a person or wider than a person Right and you throw it and then it flies to its pre-programmed destination.
Speaker 1: It's got like a GPS.
Speaker 1: It's got little motors to control the rudders and such, you know, it's got a motor to keep it going.
Speaker 1: You know a little propeller whatever it is in the back and you know You can.
Speaker 1: you could put like a camera on one of these throw it Program it to fly over the enemy base take a bunch of pictures It comes back with the pictures or transmits the pictures to you over the air or something like that, right?
Speaker 1: it's a military technology and You know, we try to think of what use could this technology have for the civilians.
Speaker 1: and you think well I guess you know, you could use it for fun right like use an RC helicopter for fun, right?
Speaker 1: but what you know.
Speaker 1: or you could use it for sort of mundane things like spy in your neighbor or Follow your kids around if you're remote control it or something like that, right?
Speaker 1: But they have found perhaps the best use of this technology for civilian purposes.
Speaker 0: What Scott could it be?
Speaker 1: Do you know what it is now?
Speaker 1: so basically what they did is they slapped two red crosses on the bottom of it, right and in Africa.
Speaker 1: what they do with these now, or at least what some people are doing with these is they go out and they get like You know some blood samples and then they throw it and then it goes to the lab.
Speaker 0: Brilliant, right?
Speaker 1: It does more than that, right?
Speaker 1: Oh, no, I'm in the jungle and I got bit by the poison spider.
Speaker 1: I make a phone call they attach the antidote to the plane and they throw it and it comes to me with the anecdotes How does it know where you are?
Speaker 1: They know basically they know where you are because you have a GPS.
Speaker 1: they program the GPS cord Flies itself like you tell it where to go.
Speaker 1: you throw it and it gets there the vast majority of the time.
Speaker 1: it can go Against winds that are like 40 kilometers an hour and get there.
Speaker 0: I can think of another thing to use this for right totally awesome note passing.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah Yeah, but you know you could.
Speaker 1: basically I think they said it can carry 500 grams or something like that.
Speaker 1: So you can carry a lot of shit this thing.
Speaker 0: I can think of another use for it suddenly, but awesome drug dealing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna paint mine black You know throw it at night.
Speaker 0: I realized this.
Speaker 0: that's gonna be like.
Speaker 0: that's not that far from the future.
Speaker 0: No, it's not that far from the future at all.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: that's like the best way to deal drugs and not get caught.
Speaker 1: Oh my gosh, right You can just throw these right.
Speaker 1: you get Western Union's fuck cuz all the people if they want to send their money back Right over the face.
Speaker 0: already a big problem where people are smuggling cell phones and drugs and things into prisons.
Speaker 0: My shooting have this thing like shooting model rockets over the walls Which is trivial to do.
Speaker 0: I can shoot a model rocket into the downstate correctional facility From my window if I want to do.
Speaker 0: it's right there.
Speaker 1: Yep So yeah, these are getting pretty good with these things and I'd like I'd like to have one.
Speaker 1: that'd be pretty cool I think.
Speaker 0: how much are they?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: just buy it.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's a thing for sale.
Speaker 1: It's like a military technology here.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna have a hard time getting one someday.
Speaker 1: I'll get one someday someday, but right now it's.
Speaker 1: it's just cool.
Speaker 1: and there's a video and there's an article on new scientist.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: So I realized we've never really talked.
Speaker 1: I was the one who realized it.
Speaker 0: Well, we realized we've never really talked about this and it came up in a somewhat unrelated conversation.
Speaker 1: that's I sort of.
Speaker 1: I was thought up an idea and Simultaneously thinking up the idea realized we hadn't talked about what the topic of yeah I was like, what if we did this?
Speaker 0: and I was like ipv6 already does that?
Speaker 1: well No, I was saying what if we did this with ipv6?
Speaker 1: will it work?
Speaker 1: That's what I said.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well the thing is the idea.
Speaker 0: we're not gonna get into the idea, but basically we haven't talked about ipv6.
Speaker 1: No, we haven't.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: It's kind of moot because ipv6 is Not moving quickly in at least as far as any of you would ever be concerned.
Speaker 1: No Basically people who don't realize this right right now.
Speaker 1: people talk about IP Addresses and such.
Speaker 1: the internet and all your home networks pretty much unless you know and everything, you know about the internet is ipv4.
Speaker 1: Everything is ipv4.
Speaker 1: I bet you didn't even know.
Speaker 0: there was a one two and three, you know 127.0.0.1 IP addresses IP Version.
Speaker 1: for yeah, that is it's the fourth version of the IP internet protocol.
Speaker 0: now before anyone says so what's ipv5?
Speaker 0: It's something unrelated involving streaming Don't?
Speaker 0: it's the same reason why all the 802.11 some things are completely different things.
Speaker 0: There's no rhyme.
Speaker 1: It's like why was there a Bg?
Speaker 1: what happened to CDE?
Speaker 0: and they're all there.
Speaker 0: you can look up the list.
Speaker 0: You don't care about what any of them are.
Speaker 1: believe the only ones that are important to you are the ones that you see letters for.
Speaker 1: you know H I J K LM are not important to you and is a Wasn't too important.
Speaker 1: Well, it's.
Speaker 1: it's a little bit a little more important than any of those other letters besides BG and N.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but 802.11 not 802.11. god ipv5 basically pretend it doesn't exist ipv6.
Speaker 0: now the deal is pretty simple.
Speaker 0: ipv4 and what we use as IP addresses was conceived and put together a long time ago when the world was very different and when when the government still owned the internet and things were broken up into classes and routing was pretty simple.
Speaker 0: and there are a lot more devices than anyone ever expected or intended on the internet.
Speaker 0: and The only reason we're still able to use ipv4 is by Continually hacking it together and making little changes and netting and cider.
Speaker 1: and yeah Basically ipv4 on its own is not capable of handling the internet as it is today.
Speaker 1: In order to make the internet work.
Speaker 1: We have somehow Miraculously, I don't know how it happened I'm amazed that it works every day built all these other technologies on top of Ipv4 to make it work.
Speaker 1: We've made crazy routers Unbelievably crazy routers that shouldn't have to be made but they were made and now they need.
Speaker 1: we need them.
Speaker 1: We've made NAT which is something we never would have needed.
Speaker 1: Well net net and pad that has some uses other than that But really we wouldn't need net if ipv4 wasn't poop.
Speaker 0: However, the thing is a lot of interesting things have come out of this like for example because everyone is using well Technically, you know someone says they have a net router.
Speaker 0: No, you have a pat router because it's port address translation, but I digress That that like the proliferation of that sort of network design for consumers has actually gone a long way to Protecting you from the terrible secret of space aka the real internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and ipv4 the biggest problem with it long run problem Is that even with NAT right you will run out of addresses?
Speaker 1: Eventually, I mean the biggest address you can have is 255 285 285 285 and that's not a lot of the addresses You can't even use because they don't you know, they're not real addresses.
Speaker 1: They're special for something.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing any sort of hierarchical system like that kind of like phone numbers.
Speaker 0: when they originally conceived and area codes They were used in an era.
Speaker 0: I mean there were no cell phones There was no phone number portability.
Speaker 0: phone numbers to a large degree, you know area codes and all those different like parts of a phone number Denoted geographical areas for purposes of routing phone calls.
Speaker 0: and that became increasingly useless with things like cell phones and routing got really complicated.
Speaker 0: and actually one of the biggest failings of ipv4 is that Routing became incredibly complex because we wanted you know We wanted to split up the way networks were originally designated and the hierarchy went all to shit And they used to attach right the numbers to the physical world.
Speaker 1: So they would say oh your number is you know this well that means it's in New York somewhere.
Speaker 1: So now we know to route it over this cable and it was basically by having that that that tie-in Between the structure of the numbers and the structure of the real world Setting up routing was really easy and simple.
Speaker 1: It was just sort of like oh this goes that way.
Speaker 1: this goes that way.
Speaker 1: You do anything complex.
Speaker 0: you could simplify routes like you knew all the 129 dot anythings are gonna be in that direction From all these different locations.
Speaker 0: you even care what's actually over there or where specifically it is.
Speaker 0: You just know that way that way that way.
Speaker 1: So if you had like three different, you know network connections coming out of your router.
Speaker 1: I go and you know one goes west one goes east one goes north.
Speaker 1: You pretty much say this third of the IP addresses go left this third go right this third go north.
Speaker 1: all done Right easy easy as pie.
Speaker 0: now, of course We're grossly oversimplifying but of
Speaker 1: course like
Speaker 0: one example of how we've really hacked this together is It wasn't that long ago that cider CID our classless inner domain routing was introduced and this was basically To break up the very rigid structure of IP addresses in order to allow us to take advantage of addresses that existed That due to the structure of the way we used IP addresses couldn't actually be used.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like if you built a house but in order to support the house you had to build this big column in the middle of the house and Inside of that column which was a big square was void space that could not be accept.
Speaker 0: It was in no way accessible to people just because of the way you built the house.
Speaker 0: You know, there was like it was used for pipes and stuff, but now you really need that extra space.
Speaker 0: So you tore down all those walls and basically rebuilt the inside of the house with this very Complex and incredibly difficult to understand system just to use that extra space that was there anyway, but inaccessible.
Speaker 0: but as a result you lost a lot of the advantages of the original structural design.
Speaker 0: and I'm not gonna explain how cider works But for anyone who has a little like just enough knowledge to be dangerous.
Speaker 0: Here's the simplest way I can explain it.
Speaker 0: I hope you can figure out the rest.
Speaker 0: a Class C address is the old way of talking about something, you know a subnet mask 255 255 255 dot zero Nowadays, that's a slash 24.
Speaker 0: I hope you can figure out the rest from there.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, so we had this crazy system that's way old and antiquated But somehow we have put things on top of it and modified it and come up with different things To make it still work for modern purposes.
Speaker 1: But it's also
Speaker 0: partly due to the unintended, you know Part of the reason we thought we'd run out of addresses is that as more and more people got Devices that were capable of going online, you know every cell phone every computer every chair every every refrigerator gets online You suddenly run out of public IP addresses.
Speaker 0: but it's turned out that that that future never really came to be and all the devices that are becoming online are largely passive or hidden or They're not really content publishers to the world.
Speaker 0: They're content publishers to local subnets or their content receivers.
Speaker 0: I mean, no one's hosting a web page on their cell phone, right?
Speaker 1: We've been able to use Nat slash Pat to avoid that problem.
Speaker 1: pretty much come almost completely.
Speaker 1: but one day That problem will happen and we will run out of IP addresses.
Speaker 1: He's gonna be really slow a lot slower than we thought it was gonna be years ago.
Speaker 1: We years ago.
Speaker 1: We were like, oh shit We're gonna run out.
Speaker 0: I mean dude in high school.
Speaker 0: I remember saying oh man, we need IP v6 We're fucked right.
Speaker 1: and then you know, Nat sort of saved the day.
Speaker 1: and people realized though We're not gonna run out but we are going to run out in a while 15 years.
Speaker 0: really it's cider that saved the day.
Speaker 1: But anyway that too those two things combined have saved the day regardless.
Speaker 1: IP v6 is the long-term solution and it has many other Advantages and the really the only disadvantage of IP v6 is that everyone has to switch and it's a pain in the
Speaker 0: ass Yeah, but at the same time there are a lot of ways to make that transition and there is actually a lot of infrastructure that None of you can see.
Speaker 0: that is IP v6 compatible.
Speaker 0: IP v6 works.
Speaker 0: There are ways to tunnel IP v4 and IP v6 through each other also IP v6.
Speaker 0: The first thing you'll notice about IP v6 right is that the IP addresses aren't easy to remember which in a way is good because IP addresses are Really this kind of back end that you shouldn't need to know anymore kind of.
Speaker 0: it's a bad analogy.
Speaker 0: But in the old days, I knew someone's phone number and if I didn't I looked it up.
Speaker 0: Nowadays, I kind of cashed my knowledge of the phone number in my cell phone.
Speaker 0: I don't know a single per human beings phone number in the world now except my own and my cell phone My own.
Speaker 0: well, I know my own because I memorized it a long time ago.
Speaker 1: I'm still memorizing my.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so IP v4 addresses.
Speaker 1: you've seen IP addresses like 192 dot something that's on the Sun, right?
Speaker 1: IP v6.
Speaker 1: here's an example IP v6.
Speaker 0: It is eight groups of four digit hexadecimal numbers, right?
Speaker 1: So it's 32 symbols and the symbols could be anything between 0 and F. So 0 1 to the rise of 89 ABC de hexadecimal.
Speaker 1: so I could have f f1 a b7 for a One one one one one four one one, you know It could be 32 F's and there's a colon in between every set of four F. So four F's colon four F's colon four F's colon and then one two, three, four five more sets of four F's.
Speaker 0: Granted that that's a. I mean the the colons and things are just to make it easier to remember and write kind of like the dots In IP v4 exactly.
Speaker 1: So if you think about that, right how many?
Speaker 1: Impossible?
Speaker 1: how if we used every IP v4 address in the world How many addresses?
Speaker 0: would that be far fewer than you think because most of them are useless, right?
Speaker 1: Well, even if all of them were useful, right?
Speaker 1: That's 255 times 255 times 285 times 285, right?
Speaker 1: That's let's see.
Speaker 0: I'm surprised you didn't do this calculation ahead of time and or have it memorized.
Speaker 1: I think it's like 4.2 billion Addresses.
Speaker 0: maybe there's a much simpler way to put it.
Speaker 0: IP v4 is 32-bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's 32 bits.
Speaker 0: IP v6 is 128 bits.
Speaker 0: that is more IP addresses than like the entire current population of the world Per square meter of surface area of the world with plenty to spare.
Speaker 1: Exactly, you could if we used IP v6.
Speaker 1: That means you could have right.
Speaker 1: billions of IP addresses billions of billions of IP addresses and billions in one square inch of the surface of the earth.
Speaker 1: in other words if One day we want to have like nanobots and we want every single nanobot to have its own IP address IP v6 can do that with no problem.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: We got IP address to spare.
Speaker 1: go nuts.
Speaker 1: We're good.
Speaker 0: now It's actually like the ramifications of such a large address space go far beyond.
Speaker 0: OMG will never run out of IP addresses.
Speaker 0: and I kind of want to spend a little bit of time just talking about you know This is kind of the the primer to think about what you can do when given more Resources than you need because usually as computer scientists or IT people We're always in the situation of do as much as you can with as little as possible.
Speaker 0: Here's 4k of RAM.
Speaker 0: write that program.
Speaker 0: Here's 5 bucks.
Speaker 0: make that network.
Speaker 0: IP v6 is the equivalent of here's a billion dollars.
Speaker 0: connect those two computers together.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Now now think about this.
Speaker 0: Currently, you know, we have I have a computer and I don't want to you know program the IP address every time I use it.
Speaker 0: We use something called DHCP Dynamic host configuration protocol.
Speaker 0: it basically is the thing where I turn on my computer It gets an IP address from another source from my links is right.
Speaker 1: when you when you have a computer with IP v4 There's two things you can do.
Speaker 1: you can either type into that computer with your hands This is your IP address computer or you can have a server on the network And when the computer turns on it'll talk to that server on the network and say hey server on the network What's my IP address?
Speaker 1: and the server will tell it.
Speaker 1: or it'll say no fuck you You're not getting one right, but you have to set up this server.
Speaker 1: You have to.
Speaker 1: actually can someone somewhere your network administrator Had set up the server with their own hand?
Speaker 0: or if you have a links as routers does it?
Speaker 0: and people?
Speaker 1: Your links is router?
Speaker 1: does it on its own?
Speaker 1: But it's it's.
Speaker 1: it's serving somebody with their hands had to make the IP addresses happen.
Speaker 0: Now the thing is or you can just do it all yourself.
Speaker 0: But there is a third way and this has been done in IP v4 And I'm not going to talk about all the different ways to do it But Microsoft actually did it better than most people.
Speaker 1: you ever heard of the other quickly.
Speaker 0: But no it works better than most.
Speaker 0: the auto configuration you ever noticed how if you don't get an address and you have a Microsoft Windows PC sometimes you'll get like an address.
Speaker 0: That's all weird.
Speaker 0: It's like 60 something dot something and basically what it does.
Speaker 0: and I'm simplifying obviously.
Speaker 0: but Windows computers if they're set up this way if they can't get an IP address, and they don't have one configured will pick in a certain range that Microsoft happens to own a random IP address paying the local network to see if anyone has that address.
Speaker 0: and if no one does they'll take it for themselves.
Speaker 0: and a bunch of Windows computer computers can kind of make their own ad hoc network.
Speaker 0: Yeah on their own with very little if any interaction.
Speaker 1: I mean it rare it's rarely useful.
Speaker 1: But on occasions if you just take a bunch of Windows PCs and you know plug them all into a switch Right they can sort of start networking and you know it is like a Windows for workgroups.
Speaker 1: You know sort of fallback kind of thing is there.
Speaker 1: they can start connecting to each other They'll sort of come up with addresses on their own and some things will work that you can talk to each other.
Speaker 0: Now before we talk about how what you can do with ipv6.
Speaker 0: that's cool with this.
Speaker 0: I want to talk about the fact that because there are so many IP addresses There was a lot of really interesting structure built into ipv4.
Speaker 0: I mean there's the whole multicast group.
Speaker 0: There's the experimental group.
Speaker 0: There's all like the broadcast and all these kind of different things and hierarchies and kind of built in structure That is inherent in the design.
Speaker 0: But when you've got so much extra space with ipv6 you can you have a lot more room to work.
Speaker 0: as a result.
Speaker 0: you could Theoretically think of this what if you set aside in any given network a billion IP addresses just random ones and Any computer in that network can use some sort of semi random?
Speaker 0: Seeding mechanism to pick an address in that scope if it doesn't have another way to get one?
Speaker 0: Odds are it will be a unique address and basically you can have DHCP without a DHCP server And there's so much leeway that it'll just work.
Speaker 0: and you define you know ways to automatically find Routers and automatically say hey, I'm a new computer.
Speaker 0: Are there any routers and routers in your local network can say hey I'm a router now.
Speaker 0: I know you exist.
Speaker 1: Let's play in other words because there's so many IP addresses and the odds of anyone picking the same one as someone else are Effectively zero because there's just so many.
Speaker 1: you can just sort of have networks that configure themselves well Really without doing anything.
Speaker 1: you just plug computers in.
Speaker 1: boom they're working their network.
Speaker 1: That's all good internet.
Speaker 1: Go you don't have to fiddle with your network settings.
Speaker 1: You know one has to set up the router.
Speaker 1: You know someone has to set the router But they don't have to set it up as much as they would.
Speaker 1: an ipv4.
Speaker 1: You know there's a lot less tinkering and you're gonna have a lot less problems where all my you know networking is not working.
Speaker 1: now It's not much gonna be.
Speaker 1: are you plugged in?
Speaker 1: is your computer broken?
Speaker 1: and those things are yes?
Speaker 1: No Your computer is plugged in and it's not broken.
Speaker 1: It's probably gonna just work with ipv6.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean the really interesting thing is that this idea like the root idea here is the future.
Speaker 0: This is the future of everything right here right now.
Speaker 0: if you don't realize it this kind of non-deterministic Ad-hoc self configuration of multiple nodes is the future of all computing.
Speaker 0: This is the future of CPUs.
Speaker 0: This is the future of networks.
Speaker 0: This is the future of software.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're talking about things like right now, right?
Speaker 1: Let's say me and rim have cell phones, and we're sitting in public space right we want our cell phones to talk to each other.
Speaker 1: Well, let's let's pretend that these are awesome open source cell phones with Bluetooth and Wi-Fi and everything and the software is Linux.
Speaker 1: Okay, what do we have to do?
Speaker 1: Well we can.
Speaker 1: You can do an infrared link.
Speaker 1: or one person has to say host and the other person has to say connect and we have to Aim them at each other.
Speaker 1: or you know someone has to say I'm making a Wi-Fi network and the other person says I'm joining your Wi-Fi network and the other.
Speaker 1: or you could you know and then the guy who's hosting the Wi-Fi network has to run like a DTP server and tell the other guy an IP address and a whole thing.
Speaker 1: or if you're doing Bluetooth one guy has to be like Bluetooth discovery mode the other guy right with IPv6.
Speaker 1: if you pretty much just like hey What's up click?
Speaker 0: IPv6 is not the thing that's going to cause that.
Speaker 0: I'm talking more about the root concept because IPv6 Still has a lot of limitations, and you know there's limitations.
Speaker 0: that pretty much Is that IPv6 is not going to make any of these things happen.
Speaker 0: IPv6 is just a very rudimentary very kind of initial and very explorative exploratory Exploration of these sorts of concepts, but the future on a core to not talk about the technological underlying layer Non-deterministic ad hoc networking and communication is the future.
Speaker 0: and this non-deterministic is with this big space.
Speaker 0: IPv6 allows a very rudimentary form of this to happen.
Speaker 0: I mean another example of this.
Speaker 0: I mean this is not a new idea.
Speaker 0: Token ring was deterministic.
Speaker 0: you could calculate bandwidth perfectly.
Speaker 0: everything was controlled.
Speaker 0: every network device was Intelligent.
Speaker 0: every piece along the way was controlled deterministic.
Speaker 0: You know exactly what was happening.
Speaker 0: Ethernet basically just shot its crap all out all over the internet and all just kind of worked out.
Speaker 0: if things ran into each other Everyone just said whoa backs off they wait a random amount of time before trying again and everything's kind of random and fuzzy and non-deterministic, but as Speeds got better and as you know technology got better these non-deterministic means always win out over the deterministic means of communication in the end and We're going to see a lot of cool things in these fronts in the future.
Speaker 0: IPv6 is one tiny Tiny tiny example of this.
Speaker 1: yeah, here's another another cool feature of IPv6 right?
Speaker 1: is the the multicast anycast?
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 0: yes, there is multicast and IPv4, but let me let me explain to you what this means.
Speaker 1: all right IPv4 does have Multicast, but it doesn't really work super as you would want it to.
Speaker 0: well It's partly experimental and you can like I we use it for a lot of things at our job and IBM We used it and like Cisco uses it a lot.
Speaker 0: But there are a lot of problems with IPv6 and it will with Multicast and IPv4.
Speaker 0: yeah, what IPv6 is done?
Speaker 0: because you know before there was you know broadcast unicast multicast.
Speaker 0: there is no such thing as broadcast in IPv6 because the idea of broadcast and broadcast domains and collision domains are Basically archaic nomenclatures that in modern networking Don't make sense.
Speaker 0: so as a result they got rid of that.
Speaker 0: there is just multicast.
Speaker 0: multicast is defined multicast is universal Multicast is broken up into to not use all the jargon multicast to my local network multicast to all the routers on my network Multicast to my broad segment multicast to my geographical area.
Speaker 0: all these kinds of defined multicast Addresses or multicast networks that allow for really really interesting things.
Speaker 0: Maybe not so much for you personally yet, but for large networks for configuration for organizations for backbones This is a killer app.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean think about it right now.
Speaker 1: You have a computer.
Speaker 1: I want to send a video to rim.
Speaker 1: so I have to say I open up a connection directly to rim.
Speaker 1: You know even though it's packetized It's not like a telephone network where it's a solid connection.
Speaker 1: But I'm connected to rim and I send him stuff.
Speaker 1: You know to him only I want to send the video to Someone else at the same time.
Speaker 1: well now.
Speaker 1: I have to use twice as much bandwidth.
Speaker 1: I'm sending the same video two times over the same wire to two different people.
Speaker 1: if 20 people want the video I'm sending the same video 20 times over one wire.
Speaker 1: And this is why sites go down because they're you know the million people come and say give me give me give me give me.
Speaker 1: And then their bandwidth fills up and the pipe that connects to their one computer, and then they're done.
Speaker 1: if we actually had multicast with ipv6 Which is a lot more useful than the ipv4 one in that you could actually do other things with it besides You know network management.
Speaker 1: It could actually be relied upon to do what you wanted to do.
Speaker 1: I could send out the video just once Over my wire and then he would go to the next router and the next router and it would only split up When there was actually people to split it up amongst you know it would go to one router and say all right everyone This is going to is still in that direction.
Speaker 1: Okay, and it only takes up one space worth of itself until it gets somewhere.
Speaker 1: Okay, some people who want to watch this video or to the left and some people want to watch it or to the right?
Speaker 1: So now we'll split it up But now it's only taking up to yet.
Speaker 1: at the other at the farthest end of the network there could be a hundred people Who want to watch that video, but we're only sending one copy of it over the network because it's a broadcast.
Speaker 1: now Make it there.
Speaker 0: It's not really gonna work like that in the real world.
Speaker 0: I mean basically it is Primarily going to be used within individual networks as opposed to on the global network.
Speaker 0: I mean it's more for like the.
Speaker 0: the uses people like out there will have you will have is that if it's more Understood more well implemented and just works better, and there's more space to use it There'll be a lot of software like say you want to watch a movie on your like you want to stream your anime fans up Or whatever in your local dorm room or your house You'll just it'll automatically stream with this to all the devices that want to see it on your local network Without going on all the links that don't need it and all sorts of fun stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean think about for right now, right?
Speaker 1: Let's say rim wants to watch a video that's on my computer right and then I want to watch the same video downstairs.
Speaker 1: So now my computer has to read this video and send it to two different computers and our network bandwidth in the house starts filling Up real quick and it gets slow.
Speaker 1: and Blair With if we had IPv6 and we had it set up properly with the new technologies It would be all good, and it would just send the video to both places But only send it once of course
Speaker 0: only with specialized software and only if we're both watching at the same time.
Speaker 0: Or we have some sort of very complex caching mechanism, but I digress.
Speaker 1: I mean Yeah, I get into the specifics, but here's a really good example of how to make everything awesome.
Speaker 1: Let's say you want to play a game at a LAN party right?
Speaker 1: Instead you know instead of having the.
Speaker 1: you know The game server right.
Speaker 1: send the game state updates to having to manage sending the state updates to each individual player It'll just broadcast the game state.
Speaker 0: I'm well thing is you realize that most land like if you pick land instead of something else?
Speaker 0: it does that anyway really?
Speaker 1: I've never seen to do that unless you do the IPX BS.
Speaker 0: Well like steam and a lot of things do that.
Speaker 0: I mean if you just play low like most games, and you just click pick land it'll broadcast a whole bunch of information around.
Speaker 0: every game does it differently.
Speaker 0: and The other caveat here is that most game publishers probably won't care because most people play online.
Speaker 0: But you can do interesting stuff with this.
Speaker 0: the real interesting thing about ipv6 The real interesting thing along these lines is something called anycast.
Speaker 0: now the idea here is that?
Speaker 0: You have an IP address or whatever a destination that exists wholly and completely in Multiple places and routers basically use the routing protocol updates They get from their neighbors to route your requests and its responses from the nearest node to you.
Speaker 0: So say I I am valve and I have steam and I want to.
Speaker 0: I want to have you download software from me.
Speaker 0: I have multiple steam distribution servers in multiple geographical locations And if you connect to a steam server you connect to an anycast address.
Speaker 0: that is just basically the steam download server.
Speaker 0: Routers.
Speaker 0: take your request to the nearest and nearest is a logical thing not a physical thing Server and you just get the updates from there, but it's all seamless to you.
Speaker 0: You don't need to know or care.
Speaker 0: in fact There is theoretically no way for the end-user to know that an address is an anycast address as opposed to a unicast address.
Speaker 1: His isn't it right?
Speaker 1: right now things like this are actually happening, but they're doing it a very hackneyed way.
Speaker 1: for example Look at Google right.
Speaker 1: try to ping google.com.
Speaker 1: It's gonna show up as an IP address.
Speaker 1: Alright, maybe if you ping Google from somewhere else.
Speaker 1: You'll actually see it's a different IP address.
Speaker 1: What's happening there is Google uses Akamai and I could talk about Akamai as a company that basically does this thing.
Speaker 1: and The way it works is you ask the DNS server?
Speaker 1: Hey, what IP address is google.com?
Speaker 1: and depending on many factors?
Speaker 1: It'll tell you a different IP address to match up the name.
Speaker 1: What with ipv6 the difference is instead of asking for google.com and getting a different answer all the time You ask for google.com.
Speaker 1: if it's ipv6 you're always gonna get the same answer.
Speaker 1: But and that number will be the same for everyone.
Speaker 1: but that number is actually just sort of a nickname or Alias for a bunch of other numbers that are where the servers really are.
Speaker 1: and it decides on the routing layer a lower layer.
Speaker 1: It does this on its own.
Speaker 1: Basically, the Akamai company will go out of business if ipv6 comes into play.
Speaker 0: No, they won't because you don't think so.
Speaker 0: well, the thing is that the whole reason this is secure is the same reason the internet kind of works is that Large networks and like the top the higher tier providers peer with each other.
Speaker 0: They trust each other and this happens at a low level protocol layer to where you.
Speaker 0: you trust the routes you get the route updates.
Speaker 0: the you know routes are the things that tell packets where to go basically and you know you need to get your routing information from your neighbors and from other people out on the word on the world and they get their routing information from other people and You have to choose who to trust and you not to trust.
Speaker 0: So for any cast to work the big-name players and the people who really matter on the internet have to trust the routes that are being propagated and any cast will Probably for a long time only really be available to very big players Which is for the best because otherwise it is the biggest freaking security hole in the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, but I mean if we've solved all these problems on top of I know we have Only solved them because If we've solved other problems on top of IPv4 I'm sure we could solve you know, the problems in IPv6 just disease.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah What I'm saying is that things like anycast a lot of these cool functionality works because of the same reason the internet works.
Speaker 0: now Very very large networks trust each other on a very specific Technological level and you do not have access to that trust and no one is going to trust you.
Speaker 1: No, it's trusting you at all.
Speaker 0: truck like trust on the internet is pretty much the most important commodity at a network level.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so a lot of the things you think you can do that are all cool You cannot do because no one will trust you except your friends.
Speaker 1: That's the simplest way you can do them with your friends.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes, most definitely.
Speaker 1: But in fact you can do with your friends.
Speaker 1: right now I pb6 is just your computer probably has everything it needs.
Speaker 1: You just need to set it up.
Speaker 1: You can set up a little LAN with IPv6 real easily Yes, but getting your IPv6 onto the real IPv6.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna get into this much more difficult.
Speaker 0: Just google for IPv6 You'll find how-tos.
Speaker 0: I mean I actually used to have a whole ton of addresses on the six bone back in the day because you know We went to our IT.
Speaker 0: We're in access to internet too and all those sorts of fun things.
Speaker 0: So I requested a ton of IPv6 addresses and my own IPv6 network on the six bone Because I was in a class where I had to do a big thesis on IPv6 and interoperability.
Speaker 0: I dropped out of that class right away But I didn't give up my space and I played with it for a long time.
Speaker 0: that space is now gone But that's that's the end of that story.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't do anything cool with it.
Speaker 0: I basically just played around and failed.
Speaker 1: but basically I mean as for using IPv6 now and trans up and you know moving the internet over to it, right?
Speaker 1: It's basically a huge pain right now.
Speaker 1: some things you can do are you can you know connect to other?
Speaker 1: IPv6 enabled things out there across IPv6 networks, but they're not easy to find.
Speaker 1: you sort of have to know It's more than your.
Speaker 0: you probably have IPv4 connectivity and IPv6 might be tunneled a lot of IVSPs.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna have direct IPv6.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it really depends on who you are where you are what you're connected to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's far out of the scope of this episode to talk about that.
Speaker 0: Suffice to say if you were at all interesting interested in networking and IP and IT and all these things if you try to learn how IPv6 works on a fundamental level and if you want to try to learn how to connect to it in The process of learning that you're going to learn a lot about networking and you're doing you're going to become Very competent on a theoretical level very quickly.
Speaker 0: So look at IPv6 not as practical knowledge But as a kind of far-out goal that if you seek that goal You will learn a ton on the way kind of like installing Gen 2.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean they're doing all sorts of weird things these days like they're putting IPv4 addresses inside of IPv6 addresses in there.
Speaker 1: You know, they're tunneling IPv6 over IPv4.
Speaker 1: So it's like well, I have an IPv6 network and you have an IPv6 network But there's only an IPv4 network between us.
Speaker 1: But we can make this little tunnel and sort of.
Speaker 0: now we sort of have an IPv6 network between us and because I mean For most consumers IPv6 is not going to actually matter to you for a long time And even then it's going to be completely transparent to you.
Speaker 0: You'll never really be affected by it.
Speaker 1: Yes, but the reason is taking so long.
Speaker 1: This is basically everyone has to switch all their stuff and no one's in a rush to do that because they don't need to Right now.
Speaker 1: this and there's no benefit that you will notice right away You'll you?
Speaker 1: basically if I had two networks set up with the same computers and one was six and one is four You couldn't tell a difference.
Speaker 1: It's all.
Speaker 1: the difference is all where you can't see it.
Speaker 1: It's completely invisible to you as a user but much like Xavocom the possibilities are endless and less possible.
Speaker 1: billions and billions of possibilities per square inch.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at frontroadcrew.com Or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an Odeo on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 1: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.