Speaker 1: Hey, it's Wednesday, July 29th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight our long-awaited coverage of Otacon.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Oh Shit, it's geek nights.
Speaker 1: We're back.
Speaker 0: We're kind.
Speaker 0: we were back Monday.
Speaker 1: We were back, but it was Monday neckbeard night.
Speaker 1: not everyone listens to that and this is the night Everyone was waiting for I guess isn't it?
Speaker 0: you know?
Speaker 0: I think there's a problem though, and we.
Speaker 0: it's like this constant battle.
Speaker 0: It's like we could have done this episode earlier But we stick to the schedule.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm sticking to the schedule means we're not gonna be timely.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I feel like you know if we were timelier.
Speaker 1: It would have been better, but in some ways.
Speaker 1: But at the same time I feel like the slightly faded memory of the convention Kind of crystallizes the things that matter and the stuff that doesn't matter falls to the wayside.
Speaker 1: I guess I guess well you know schedule no schedule.
Speaker 1: if we did shows whenever we have an idea We do like ten shows in a row, and then like have a month of nothing.
Speaker 0: Well if we could record the ten shows in a row and just put them out We could but we've never successfully done that.
Speaker 1: the one time ever we were ahead on shows We were like two weeks ahead.
Speaker 1: We just stopped doing shows put them all up, and that was the end of that.
Speaker 0: it sure was.
Speaker 1: Plus the news is aren't timely yeah, but you know we had our usual after Otacon a week of awesome But sadly Scott and Emily had to go back to Beacon and work in the city while I went to the week of awesome.
Speaker 1: Alright, but what we did do and people who know me might go.
Speaker 1: Why did rim do this?
Speaker 1: we watched all of the new x-men cartoon?
Speaker 1: And now you might be thinking but rim don't you hate the old x-men cartoon?
Speaker 0: I would have been like oh, that's understandable.
Speaker 1: the new x-men cartoon Wolverine and the x-men.
Speaker 1: it's fantastic.
Speaker 0: I Can't say I've not seen it, but I will.
Speaker 0: of course I'm very skeptical.
Speaker 1: pretty much everyone all of us was excited about it.
Speaker 1: We watched the whole thing in almost one go.
Speaker 0: Really is it so?
Speaker 1: the show is over or season one is over and season one.
Speaker 1: the plot kind of goes from beginning to from.
Speaker 1: Oh shit is Wolverine - oh shit.
Speaker 1: It's Wolverine.
Speaker 0: So is it?
Speaker 0: how long is the season?
Speaker 0: if it's not a Jeff It's not an anime.
Speaker 1: It's like 13 14 episodes.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's it.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay I think I'm pretty sure that what didn't seem like there were that many.
Speaker 0: so it's like a South Park season something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right, but I liked it, okay Ah, so you want to.
Speaker 1: So we did a show, you know.
Speaker 1: And then we disappeared and went to Otacon.
Speaker 1: and now we're back and we're going to Connecticut this weekend.
Speaker 1: So Friday Saturday and Sunday, which is Friday, July 31st, Saturday, August 1st and Sunday, August 2nd We will be at Connecticut at the Hartford connecting Center in Hartford, Connecticut.
Speaker 1: Connecticut's not really an anime con.
Speaker 1: It's kind of a.
Speaker 0: it's an everything con.
Speaker 0: right on the front of the con book They say everything but the kitchen even though while it's an everything con.
Speaker 1: It's basically an anime con a webcomic.
Speaker 0: It's not even that much an anime con.
Speaker 0: I mean this anime fans and this cosplay but there's really not that much anime content.
Speaker 1: Well, there's a ton of anime screening rooms.
Speaker 1: that has all the accoutrement of an anime con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but mostly it's a webcomic con because it's a ton of webcomic.
Speaker 1: It's also a better gaming con than most gaming cons in the.
Speaker 0: it's a pretty great game.
Speaker 0: The board game tabletop roleplay miniatures collectible card is strong as a dealer's room.
Speaker 0: I guess the dealer's room has a lot of anime merchandise.
Speaker 0: There's an artist alley which you know, I guess is somewhat anime related.
Speaker 0: There's a video game room, which is kind of good and There's a the sci-fi type guests the kinds you'll see it, you know.
Speaker 0: a sci-fi con Yeah, but also usually a lot of voice actors and a lot of webcomic artists and us being yes We it's actually gonna be real easy to talk about what we're doing at this con because we don't have to list all our panels.
Speaker 1: All right, I think I can sum this up panel 5 from 10 30 Panel 5 because that means I could do.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Panel 5. panel 5.
Speaker 1: I'm excited about that.
Speaker 1: when I saw that I was ready.
Speaker 1: I gotta get though.
Speaker 1: I gotta get the table 5 just get it YouTube.
Speaker 1: This goes to yeah table 5 but we're going to be running every event in panel 5 either running personally or presenting From 10 30 a.m On Friday until like 5 30 on Sunday for as long as the con goes.
Speaker 0: if there's ever anything You know you're not sure what to do.
Speaker 0: come to panel 5. we will be in there doing something or another front row crew person will be in there doing something or Luke crane slash Jared Sorenson will be in there.
Speaker 1: Uncle Joe's gonna be in there we.
Speaker 1: and the thing is you look at all the other panel rooms Our room is dense compared to the rest of them.
Speaker 0: So kinetic on isn't everything awesome?
Speaker 0: con.
Speaker 0: we are running an entire room at this con and also Jared.
Speaker 0: we're bringing, you know, I saw I said already we're bringing Jared Sorenson and Luke crane with us and I guess at their prerogative They will be running many RPG type demo games.
Speaker 0: You know while we are doing panels in panel 5 and also other front row crew peoples will be running many burning wheels and other tabletop role-playing games.
Speaker 0: So this kinetic on this is your opportunity if you live near kinetic on you know to come and read days Of rim and Scott three days of rim and Scott and front row crew and burning wheel and everything else.
Speaker 0: That's awesome.
Speaker 1: So a lot of people email us all the time about the beyond Dungeons & Dragons panel And this is the penultimate time we are doing that panel.
Speaker 1: We will try to film it.
Speaker 1: But if you really want we're doing it.
Speaker 0: thrice more rice.
Speaker 1: Oh crap.
Speaker 1: Well I will count both taxes as one con.
Speaker 1: We're good.
Speaker 0: All right As they're doing in a kinetic on Pax West and one more time and then Pax East and then the panel is over.
Speaker 1: and well between Those three I think we'll video it three times and if we don't get a good take from that I give up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we should have videotaped the Otacon one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we should have.
Speaker 0: did I have anyone videotaped that?
Speaker 0: YouTube it over?
Speaker 0: that'd be nice.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So, uh, let's be quick on the anime.
Speaker 0: Thing is right.
Speaker 0: We're usually like at a loss for anime manga comics news Like sometimes we'll do like a geek bite instead But because it was San Diego comic-con and Otacon is a pile of it.
Speaker 1: So let me mention the extra week where we didn't even do shows.
Speaker 0: Yep So let me just do two from San Diego.
Speaker 0: real quick right one of them requires explanation.
Speaker 0: one of them really doesn't.
Speaker 0: number one Pan a Hall H at San Diego comic-con was a fiasco.
Speaker 1: I heard great tell of this.
Speaker 1: I didn't really read any of the news.
Speaker 0: basically Hall H is this big room where they have a video screen and they do panels And mostly it's Hollywood showing shit off.
Speaker 0: so you can go in there and see Trailers and previews of all sorts of things that you know before you're gonna see them on the internet or anywhere else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like avatar.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Hollywood type stuff, right?
Speaker 0: So it's not like, you know, I'm sure it's leaked on the internet now.
Speaker 0: But if you wanted to see it first, that was the place line for this room.
Speaker 0: What happened here was you know, San Diego comic-con?
Speaker 0: I mean even though it's a Hollywood con Traditionally the audience for the con is nerds and I guess people in the industry, right?
Speaker 0: You know, you don't really get normal people coming to San Diego comic-con too often.
Speaker 0: I mean they go but not in great great quantities, however There was Twilight shit going down And the words got out and apparently a bajillion bajillion Twilight chicks came to San Diego comic-con just because of Twilight and they wanted to see some Twilight shit and some Twilight people in Hall H. So what did they do?
Speaker 0: They basically got to San Diego comic-con lined up for Hall H Got into Hall H and the room never cleared.
Speaker 0: now So those Twilight people stayed in Hall H And they never left until the Twilight thing happened.
Speaker 0: And then the Avatar thing, wait, according to the anger video game nerd who was there with Spike TV, right?
Speaker 0: Doing stuff I guess cuz he has a contract with them.
Speaker 1: I remember we saw his first video and there's a crazy line behind him.
Speaker 0: In his second video He showed his journey to Hall H. He wanted to see the Avatar in Hall H Which he knew was after the Twilight.
Speaker 0: So he figured all the Twilight people would leave and he would get in even though the line was long, right?
Speaker 0: But no, the Twilight people didn't leave.
Speaker 0: they stayed in there and he was shut out like right before the door.
Speaker 1: Ah, just like Mike Tool.
Speaker 0: And he didn't get to see the Avatar trailer and such.
Speaker 0: But he didn't get in to see like some other shit in there.
Speaker 1: I have two points of order.
Speaker 1: Point the first, there's an XKCD.
Speaker 1: That's basically about that.
Speaker 0: One thing I do want to say the anger video game nerd said, well James Rolfe said, is that you're not amused in park.
Speaker 0: The line is long, but you know that if you get in the line, you're guaranteed to eventually ride the ride.
Speaker 0: Not so and I think that's that's a problem.
Speaker 1: Well by my second point This is much more important one and considering we're doing a review of Otacon 2009 and our coverage of that It's worth noting that cons like Otacon solved that problem more than a decade ago.
Speaker 1: Whenever there are big events or a room like that They clear the room between every panel And seeing as Hall H everything is a big event.
Speaker 0: They should have cleared the room between every single thing.
Speaker 1: So SDCC, now you're fucked up.
Speaker 1: Now you're fucked up.
Speaker 0: News number two.
Speaker 0: There's a little bit of complicated news.
Speaker 0: People don't know the backstory So I'm going to keep it short and I'm probably gonna get some stuff wrong, but it doesn't matter, right?
Speaker 0: Here's the deal.
Speaker 0: Back in the olden days of comic books, there was a comic book called Marvel Man, right?
Speaker 0: And it's a golden age corny ass comic book, whatever.
Speaker 0: And the rights to Marvel Man were all disputed and who knows?
Speaker 0: Told right because it's Marvel Man, but it wasn't owned by Marvel Comics or was it?
Speaker 0: and whatever?
Speaker 0: right at some point There was a comic book called.
Speaker 0: they couldn't call it Marvel Man.
Speaker 0: I think they did call it Marvel Man in the UK, but in the US it was called Miracle Man Right by Alan Moore slash Neil Gaiman and apparently it's this great great comic book and I really don't have doubts about that because the names Alan Moore and or Neil Gaiman are on it and I the thing is you know this ran into also some sorts of legal troubles
Speaker 1: and there
Speaker 0: was actually a court case like Neil Gaiman versus Todd McFarland and who owns the rights to this thing and blabbity blabbity blah, right?
Speaker 0: And what happened over time was people would like dig through the bins at comic conventions trying to look for Miracle Man issues And they go.
Speaker 0: now if you try to buy it It goes like a bajillion dollars.
Speaker 0: one guy got all the issues and he bound them together in a hardcover book You know with the library binding company and he sold that on eBay for like a bajillion bajillion dollars.
Speaker 1: So has someone just scanned this in?
Speaker 1: Is there a torrent?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go, you know, I feel you know totally validated in going to find a torrent and now that I'm you know I'm gonna go look for one after the show.
Speaker 0: because you know, whatever the thing is the news in San Diego.
Speaker 0: Is that Marvel?
Speaker 0: Definitely definitely has the rights to Marvel man, they bought it them from the original Marvel Man creator.
Speaker 0: so this now brings back all these questions of Is the Miracle Man gonna be re-released in the nice trade hardcover omnibus, you know, whatever it is, right?
Speaker 0: It's it's.
Speaker 0: we're getting close to those time.
Speaker 1: Here's the trouble.
Speaker 1: They might they might have to broach this carefully because how many people who collected that are gonna be angry if it gets re-released.
Speaker 0: Well, you know fuck them.
Speaker 0: It's you know, it's all about.
Speaker 0: That's not Marvel's concern.
Speaker 0: Marvel's because Marvel doesn't make any money off that.
Speaker 0: their concern is.
Speaker 0: they very much want to be able to Publish a report reprint Miracle Man, which will sell like crazy and trade in hardcover making Marvel a ton of money.
Speaker 0: They couldn't give a shit about the collectors who paid a lot of money for it.
Speaker 0: Now the thing is there's.
Speaker 0: you know, there's still issues with Todd McFarlane Guyman.
Speaker 0: more Miracle man isn't the same as Marvel man.
Speaker 0: What's gonna happen?
Speaker 0: question mark question mark All I can say is I'm hopeful that this supposedly and probably amazing comic book will be read by me at a reasonable price.
Speaker 1: But anyway, we have a lot to cover for Otakon.
Speaker 1: So things of the day The AMV contest was pretty good.
Speaker 1: It wasn't the best AMV contest at Otakon, but I'm seeing.
Speaker 0: we didn't even see the whole contest.
Speaker 0: Of course We only see the winners as we do.
Speaker 1: the secret of Otakon is that if you want to see the AMV skip the entire AMV contest.
Speaker 0: it takes too long and it sucks.
Speaker 1: but go to closing ceremonies.
Speaker 1: You will see all the best AMVs and even if the crowd is stupid and they vote for bad ones.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter because the staff will almost always pick the one like unknown or neglected video and put it in there.
Speaker 1: that's how we saw 2525 and That is how we saw the Krauser video.
Speaker 1: my thing of the day is the last anime music video that won an award at the AMV is no to count 2009 because Surprisingly despite the popularity of Detroit Metal City.
Speaker 1: There was basically zero DMC.
Speaker 1: at Otakon.
Speaker 1: I didn't see a single cosplayer.
Speaker 0: There was not.
Speaker 0: I mean there might have been I mean everyone I've talked to about Otakon, you know reports seeing different cosplayers.
Speaker 0: Some people saw like a hundred Michael Jackson's.
Speaker 1: I saw three people's right.
Speaker 0: So I asked the audience at one panel like who here seen a Vashta Stampede and everyone raised their hand.
Speaker 0: I'd like.
Speaker 0: I seen zero and then after that I saw one.
Speaker 0: I was like wow, but other people saw like ten.
Speaker 0: so like it's.
Speaker 0: just the con is so big and people move in such patterns that like everyone is gonna have a different perception of The quantities of which characters are cosplayed and the only way to actually figure it out would be to like count or have people Write it down or so, you know some sort of real Scientific study, but
Speaker 1: as far as I can see no one dressed up as crowd.
Speaker 0: It was not nearly enough Krauser definitely.
Speaker 1: But one thing I can say is that you know We went to the Vamps concert on Thursday and I didn't realize till after it that what's his name?
Speaker 1: the guitarist who was playing with Odd.
Speaker 1: yeah, he did the guitar part for the opener to DMC.
Speaker 1: apparently Apparently he likes DMC.
Speaker 0: How could you not like DMC?
Speaker 1: Well, of course That's.
Speaker 1: that's beside the point.
Speaker 1: There's no Krauser this whole con other than arguably Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: I was actually before the con.
Speaker 0: I was sort of thinking like, you know What anime do I really want to see, you know busting out at the con?
Speaker 0: I'm like, you know, I'd like to see some DMC.
Speaker 0: I'd like to see some Krauser cosplays You know, I'd like to see some you know, that sort of stuff Merchandise in them, you know dealer's room if I can get that really good, you know.
Speaker 0: So tech Krauser that everyone don't see a lot.
Speaker 1: I saw one Jojo, but you really don't see any fist of the North Star cosplay.
Speaker 0: It's not an easy cosplay.
Speaker 0: No one's really got to be big.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or you got to be really tiny without with huge huge.
Speaker 0: You should go as the North Star peasants.
Speaker 0: Yes anyway But the thing is I didn't see crowds of the whole con and I stopped thinking about it.
Speaker 1: and then as the closing ceremonies That's not as crazy video comes up There's like no Krauser no Krauser no Krauser.
Speaker 1: I've resigned myself to a Krauserless Otakon.
Speaker 1: and then this pretty good music video plays.
Speaker 1: so it's worth watching.
Speaker 1: If you don't know what DMC is this will make you realize that it's great.
Speaker 1: All right, I mean he killed his parents.
Speaker 0: All right My thing of the day is not actually anime my comic related, but whatever awesome.
Speaker 0: It's this thing called Pixlr.
Speaker 0: It's a web-based Photoshop basically, but it's not quite Photoshop, but it's not quite the gimp.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like.
Speaker 0: it's better than MS Paint and it has features.
Speaker 0: It has nice UI and it's in your browser and it's free.
Speaker 0: What you know and it's really good for like, you know, you can use the Firefox extension.
Speaker 0: Let's say you're on a website and you see an image like you're and you want to edit it real quick.
Speaker 0: You know, maybe like paste a face into it or something.
Speaker 0: You can just use the Firefox extension open the image right up edit it real quick and then you know Save it paste it whatever and you're all good.
Speaker 0: So it's.
Speaker 0: it's a handy handy tool for image editings on the Winternets.
Speaker 1: So the moment you've all been waiting for Otakon 2009 we've been going to Otakon every year since 2002 seven years.
Speaker 0: eight years because including the o2.
Speaker 1: I've been doing panels at Otakon since 2002, right?
Speaker 1: Sometimes surreptitiously.
Speaker 1: Yes Only one of my panels at Otakon was me taking over a panel that the person who was supposed to run it didn't show up.
Speaker 0: Also for many of the years all the only panel that was done was the club summit.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: It's funny.
Speaker 1: You look at the con resume.
Speaker 1: It's like anime club summit anime club summit anime club summit and then we busted out with gecky guy And then after that, it was just crazy panels every year.
Speaker 0: Yep, so I think this.
Speaker 0: you know I like to follow a Chronological structure not because I think that makes a good show but because it's easy for me to remember everything that happened at the con.
Speaker 1: Logically it gives us a more narrative style.
Speaker 1: We kind of pull ourselves out of the meta.
Speaker 0: However, I think that it would be a good idea if we take like the big hitting parts of the car.
Speaker 1: Alright Scott, so just before we do the show I'm like so Scott.
Speaker 1: Here's my idea.
Speaker 0: I didn't say I came up with the idea.
Speaker 0: I said I think it would be a good idea.
Speaker 0: as in I agree with the idea that you came up with my idea.
Speaker 1: That's
Speaker 0: fine You can have the credit but I think it's a good idea if we take the big Hitting topics that we have to talk about Get those out of the way and then do a nice easy chronology because usually if you go straight into the chronology It's like you go you go you go and then you spend way too much time on something.
Speaker 0: you go you go And it's sort of you know, it's not fluid.
Speaker 0: the other thing is that big things to the front.
Speaker 0: Then the chronology will be nice and smooth.
Speaker 1: Well more importantly the big things we want to talk about are pretty much the only negative things We have to say about Otacon this year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean Otacon as always is the second biggest anime con in the US.
Speaker 0: It's totally awesome.
Speaker 0: And as always just a few problems that glare and everything else is totally a great time.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, why the hell would I keep paying all this money to go every?
Speaker 1: this is well, but we don't pay for badges.
Speaker 0: You pay a lot of money for the hotel and we driving and the damn you Renaissance pay vacation days.
Speaker 0: I mean I took unpaid days to go down there.
Speaker 1: Ah, that's harsh.
Speaker 0: That's alright I got.
Speaker 1: the other reason is that with the sort of narrative chronological thing and by cutting out the major bad things It's very easy for people like us who've been going to conventions forever to Dwell on the things that stand out to us which are the bad things and it's very easy to get a very negative Impression if we just talk about the things that stand out.
Speaker 0: I mean remember you.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's true You're getting.
Speaker 0: you're getting an impression of the con from people have been to at seven times.
Speaker 0: Somebody went this is their first Otacon was probably blown away and was like, holy shit This is crazy.
Speaker 1: I remember back when we had friends who would still not yet gone to Otacon We'd always have this ritual of like, alright, you haven't been to this con before All right Close your eyes and we take him into the dealers room like into the middle and we'd be like open your eyes and spin in a circle.
Speaker 0: I Mean the dealers room, you know, it might not have the best stuff anymore, but it's still Gigantamous, I mean especially the first time you see it.
Speaker 1: You're not expecting that.
Speaker 0: you're not expecting any roommates ginormous.
Speaker 0: I thought I could piss them off more with gigantamous.
Speaker 1: Gigantamous is okay.
Speaker 1: It's more cromulant.
Speaker 1: I think than ginormous.
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: Anyway, because gigantamous reeks of hit up hippopotamus and hippopotamus is okay in any capacity.
Speaker 1: All right anyway.
Speaker 1: So the other reason the narrative is that I've learned that about a third of the people who listen to our con reviews Haven't gone to the con.
Speaker 1: They want to find out what they missed.
Speaker 1: but it seems like most of the people who listen to our con reviews and I get This impression of a lot of other people who cover conventions.
Speaker 0: They were at the con and they just want to reminisce.
Speaker 1: They just want a replay of the con for nostalgia purposes.
Speaker 1: So there you go.
Speaker 0: All right, so the big hitters?
Speaker 0: What's big hitter?
Speaker 0: number one?
Speaker 0: For
Speaker 1: the first time, you know I always praise Otacon that while mailing away badges is difficult and I understand why fan run conventions generally don't do it And I've always forgiven Otacon for that because they handle their pre-reg line to a degree that is staggering and even now despite the problems They process more than 10,000 people on Thursday night for a bunch of volunteers.
Speaker 1: That's pretty amazing.
Speaker 1: like that Props to Otacon for the fact that they are able to handle that many registrations per second continuously, but It's not enough.
Speaker 1: Well every year you have been able to show up at the reg line after a few hours of being open and just kind of
Speaker 0: Feel bad because we told everyone the strategy that worked in all the years past, you know Don't wait in the reg line Thursday or you know Just show up to the reg line on Thursday at like 8 or 9 p.m And by then the line will have cleared out.
Speaker 0: You can just walk in get your badge walk out without any waiting.
Speaker 1: for the first time ever The line was interminable.
Speaker 1: The line was a disaster.
Speaker 1: There were just so many people in line and it never abated.
Speaker 1: and Otacon says that they cut the line off.
Speaker 1: at the end They got everyone in who showed up Thursday night to get their badge.
Speaker 1: But I saw numerous reports of people who were turned away from the line near the end as they brought the line inside and shut the doors.
Speaker 1: and A lot of people wanted badges on Thursday who couldn't get them.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So I guess that I didn't see that.
Speaker 0: so I don't know which way it is, but I'll believe either story.
Speaker 0: But that doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: the point is if I had had there was no point at which you could walk in get your badge and Walk out which means the line was not processed quickly enough on Thursday regardless of whether people were shut out.
Speaker 1: Getting out of hand.
Speaker 1: there's Otacon is too big and the thing is people who didn't get their badge on Thursday or couldn't show up on Thursday Friday was even worse trying to get your badge and Emily forgot to pre-reg.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, non pre-reg people and pre-reg people were in mostly the same boat, though.
Speaker 1: So it's not like you were really any better off if you didn't get the yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, actually if you think about it, right there was 17,000 pre-reg and they said what 26,000 ish total.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which means 9,000 reg reg.
Speaker 0: You got to think those 9,000 reg reg.
Speaker 0: most of them were there all at once.
Speaker 0: So that was a line of 9,000. if the you assume the pre-reg was split half half Thursday Friday, then that's what like says 8,500 which is still too many.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's Each.
Speaker 0: the lines are about equal.
Speaker 1: here's what it comes down to one it this cannot stand.
Speaker 1: It's getting out of hand.
Speaker 1: It's only going to get worse.
Speaker 1: It's never going to get better and I don't think Otacon can handle the line better than they already do.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's the only one way they could do it is if they also Set up reg boots in another place and had you know Just like twice or three times as many reg boots.
Speaker 1: and that's not gonna have.
Speaker 0: that's not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: cuz where are they gonna put?
Speaker 0: Them, you know, they can't put him in the fountain lobby and there really isn't another lobby to lobby.
Speaker 0: No, no Hilton doesn't have a space for that.
Speaker 1: from a selfish perspective I'll just point out that Otacon is the only convention we go to where they make us wait in line for anything.
Speaker 1: I mean we do a million panels at all these cons and you know We always talk about the perspectives.
Speaker 1: how if you're a panelist or you're a staffer or you're in the dealer's room at the artist alley You have a very different kind of view of the con and all the structures of the kind of very different for you.
Speaker 1: for us Otacon is the only convention we ever go to where we have to stand in lines and It's getting to the point to where it's actually very difficult for us to manage having to stand in this line Just to have the privilege of doing panels at this con Mm-hmm and the only reason it was terminal.
Speaker 1: it was bearable this year was that We went to the Vamps concert and they gave anyone who went to the Vamps concert who had a ticket Cut to the front of the line pass.
Speaker 1: So we were like among the first five people to get badges for Otacon.
Speaker 0: I know it's Thursday.
Speaker 0: people have been waiting in line for hours.
Speaker 0: We have tickets to this concert and we just walk right up and get our badges immediately.
Speaker 1: And Scott was the person who tweeted out the badge Picture right away because they didn't put up the placards of badges like they usually do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's actually.
Speaker 0: I think that actually slowed the line down some because people would get up to the registration desk and look And pick out a badge at that point in time rather than if they had the placards up with the badge designs.
Speaker 0: people would decide while they were waiting in line and then just Walk up and be like badge three.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess some indecisive people would stop.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is Otacon is the only major convention I know of that.
Speaker 0: lets you even pick a badge and picking the badge is Nice, it's a cool thing.
Speaker 1: It's fun But is it really worth waiting in line hours and hours Even if it takes ten seconds for someone to pick their badge and to deal with all the?
Speaker 1: you know All the logistics of people picking their badges.
Speaker 1: ten seconds times 17,000 pre-reg is.
Speaker 1: that's unacceptable.
Speaker 1: now, that's already.
Speaker 1: you're gonna get a significant return by cutting that out.
Speaker 0: I think what they should do is either a not have you know badges you can choose from anymore.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: B they could have Sort of like rent.
Speaker 0: they can make all this badge art with the Otacon mascots and sort of.
Speaker 0: you get a random one.
Speaker 0: or you know That'd be kind of fun.
Speaker 0: or C right part of the badge could be sort of like this standard badge and Part of the badge would be blank.
Speaker 0: and then you could fill in that blank part of the badge with whatever you want.
Speaker 0: You could get someone to draw something on an artist alley.
Speaker 0: You could bring some art to put there.
Speaker 0: You could put stickers there, you know.
Speaker 0: and the rest the other part of the badge would be the unforgeable Uniform part so that you would know you had a real badge.
Speaker 1: The the other solution and to jump very far forward into our coverage the con feedback session.
Speaker 1: This was echoed at the con feedback session and every time someone brought it up and it was brought up numerous times The crowd cheered louder than I've ever heard a crowd cheer at a con feedback session.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean I remember in years past when people recommended mailing the badges and the audience would be like The audience would be like, yeah, maybe you know.
Speaker 0: and the excuses sort of were like, okay.
Speaker 0: But this year when they said mail the badges everyone was like, yes Yes mail the badges.
Speaker 1: and the thing is.
Speaker 1: it got to the point to where I think the second or third person who went up and was like look mail the badges out.
Speaker 1: and Otacon's response was well No other fan run con does and that person was like Pax.
Speaker 1: does Anime central?
Speaker 0: does San Diego comic-con?
Speaker 0: does New York anime festival does New York comic-con does?
Speaker 0: well Comic-con is nonprofit, but I know it has a large industry.
Speaker 1: but Scott New York comic-con New York anime festival are not fan.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying those are read exhibitions.
Speaker 0: for I know that I'm just saying is that conventions even though they're for-profit Nonprofit whatever right?
Speaker 0: The fact is is that Otacon is larger than those conventions and even though it may not have you know Have more resources that it spends because it's not for profit.
Speaker 0: It has that size of resource and therefore should be able to do it now.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna dwell on this any further because we'll have to do a separate show on this.
Speaker 1: I emailed anime central.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to get all the different cons and get all their takes on it.
Speaker 0: I think that Pax just contracts it out to someone.
Speaker 1: Well, here's my thing.
Speaker 1: I don't care how Otacon does it?
Speaker 1: I feel like Otacon should whatever it takes Otacon should mail out the badges.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean, they have some valid excuses and they have some other excuses, which I think are just excuses.
Speaker 0: But regardless of whether they are valid or not The fact is that it is possible even though it may be difficult and Pretty much.
Speaker 0: they have to conquer that difficulty and do it no matter how difficult it is Even if it was harder than climbing Mount Everest ten times in a row.
Speaker 0: They have to do it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, tough shit.
Speaker 0: Just do it.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is even if Otacon doesn't have the manpower which they don't they clearly doubt they can't get that much staff to Show up.
Speaker 0: Yeah in the offseason.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's it's not gonna happen.
Speaker 1: they should just work it into the budget pay a company to just handle it and that's the end of that.
Speaker 1: but a Corollary to that.
Speaker 1: Here's a quote from an Otacon staffer dot dot dot.
Speaker 1: since badges are so commonly lost.
Speaker 1: I Personally replaced over 250 lost badges this weekend.
Speaker 1: now right there Otacon should not replace a lost badge under any circumstances.
Speaker 0: Should there ever be a badge replaced if you lose your badge?
Speaker 0: is the tough shit rule.
Speaker 0: you pay $65 to get a new one.
Speaker 0: Sorry that I mean if I lose my baseball ticket at Chase, you know like a Citi Field Dang good.
Speaker 1: They kick my ass out.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna be give me a replacement.
Speaker 1: all across the anime convention circuit I see more and more con saying look no replacements You got to pay.
Speaker 0: and if I lose like if you lose your San Diego Comic Con Take you think they give you a replacement.
Speaker 0: if you lose your vamps concert ticket You think they're gonna let you in cuz like oh I lost my ticket.
Speaker 0: Can I get a replacement?
Speaker 1: and I just.
Speaker 1: I feel like every excuse that Otacon has to not do It really falls flat in light of all the evidence that They have to do it.
Speaker 1: There's no excuse for this.
Speaker 1: It's only going to get worse.
Speaker 1: and imagine the resources that would be saved in terms of manpower and frustration.
Speaker 1: if They didn't have to do the get your badge lineup Well, they would still have the.
Speaker 0: you know Buy your badge lineup day of con.
Speaker 0: but think about these resources that would be saved.
Speaker 0: and actually I got it.
Speaker 0: This is I guess it can don't start a conspiracy theory about this, right?
Speaker 0: But it is true Right.
Speaker 0: a lot of people buy Thursday night hotel rooms to get in the Thursday pre-reg line.
Speaker 0: That makes the city of Baltimore and surrounding hotels a lot of money.
Speaker 0: if they mailed the badges I would show up Friday morning I wouldn't show up no Thursday night and that would hurt Baltimore and there might I'm not.
Speaker 0: obviously I'm not suggesting there's any conspiracy there or anything along those lines But
Speaker 1: if
Speaker 0: Otacon actually cares about its members Most then it could save us a lot of money by mailing the badges and thus Saving us the trouble of having to stay in Baltimore an extra day and spending another day's worth of parking costs day's worth of eating out dinner costs and another vacation day at work, you know and Another day of hotel room,
Speaker 1: but we're not gonna dwell on it.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do other shows in the future.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about this a lot but Otacon you have like this is no longer acceptable.
Speaker 1: It is just out of control and it is definitely do.
Speaker 0: would you not go if they didn't mail the badges next year?
Speaker 1: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: I If I have I don't know if I would be willing to wait in that line regardless of what we were doing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think if I could skip the line because of my not so special status I would still go.
Speaker 0: but if I had to wait in that line and they didn't mail the badges I might not go to Otacon next year unless there's like some crazy crazy crazy guests that I just can't miss like You know a Yumi or something like that.
Speaker 1: but anyway, we don't want to dwell on that because Otacon was super awesome this year, but Major Problem the second and this is such a multifaceted issue that we have tied into the first issue a little bit.
Speaker 1: Also, it's more tied into like four or five issues that followed from it because it'll all come down to the root cause.
Speaker 1: but Daryl Surratt the infamous Daryl Surratt is awesome.
Speaker 1: He's anime world order guy one of the one of the three people and He did a panel with us and he tried to.
Speaker 1: you know, he gave us all these videos for know your creators.
Speaker 1: He's like, I want to show all these.
Speaker 1: Issue which director was it?
Speaker 0: crazy guy the ninja scroll guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah We're rank amateurs And such.
Speaker 1: yes Alright, and he sent us all these videos right before the con to show and they were good videos But almost all of them included a female breast.
Speaker 0: and well, it wasn't just the container breast.
Speaker 0: They showed a nipple or two and I was first like Daryl.
Speaker 1: We can't show these.
Speaker 1: It's Otacon.
Speaker 0: It's Otacon and always at Otacon is 10 a.m.
Speaker 0: On Friday in a non 18 plus panel.
Speaker 0: We can't show a nipple.
Speaker 0: So not that I personally have an objection to it, but we'll get in trouble.
Speaker 0: Trouble for showing you know, right man at an 18 plus panel, which is perfectly legitimate.
Speaker 1: Yep, and I still point out to this day Otacon showed Ebola syndrome that nothing I could do could ever top that.
Speaker 0: I do think that's kind of crazy is that Otacon will show Ebola syndrome in an 18 plus video room But they won't allow Content that's even close to that level of nastiness right in one of its panel rooms also 18 plus.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is they did allow the panel.
Speaker 0: We didn't get in trouble No, but they did call us in and yell at us, but I think they were concerned.
Speaker 0: I think they were not concerned about Ebola syndrome thing is.
Speaker 1: I think they yelled at Gerald because we kind of threw him under The bus.
Speaker 1: we were like, yeah that other guy brought that video.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Everyone got away with it But anyway, it was all good.
Speaker 1: Story had a panel titled animes craziest deaths.
Speaker 0: I wanted to see this panel real bad But I'm sure I can just get Daryl to send me all the videos.
Speaker 1: the line for this panel caused an enormous Problem at Otacon.
Speaker 1: it blocked the entire 300 level for a while.
Speaker 0: First of all, they put in panel three and this shows that they did not put quite enough thought into which panels go into which Rooms, they obviously put some thought into it But not enough because I think regardless of you know, it might be difficult to guess on other panels How many people want to show up?
Speaker 0: But if something is called animes craziest deaths I mean that is obviously needs to go in the biggest available panel room, right?
Speaker 0: There's just no question that is gonna get a huge line and they put it in a big room But not the biggest room.
Speaker 1: The line was like I'm not exact Scott kind of cut in the line and I went all the way to the end of the Line to see what was going on In the panel.
Speaker 0: six in the Hilton.
Speaker 1: there were and I'm not exaggerating thousands of people in line to see this Thousand.
Speaker 1: the room only held a few hundred and the like peep and everyone every person that line was super excited about it.
Speaker 0: This was gonna be like the biggest thing and somehow when they closed the door and didn't let anyone else in my tools It was Mike tool me and a whole bunch of FRC type people's all right at the front.
Speaker 1: Mike tool was the very front person in the line.
Speaker 1: I came over and I was like you didn't get in.
Speaker 1: He's like, yeah, what are the odds?
Speaker 0: All right, so it's like we're all staying there.
Speaker 0: It's like wow, so it happens to be us.
Speaker 0: the friends of the panelists can't get into the panel So we all agree to bail.
Speaker 1: We're like, alright, let's just go get lunch.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the obvious strategy.
Speaker 0: You can't waste your time at an Otacon where you have such a. you know, your time is limited there.
Speaker 0: spend it It's precious.
Speaker 1: 15 minutes later I'm standing out there and I get an SMS to you hanging with the princess tutu cosplayer.
Speaker 1: Yes We'll talk about them in the chronology.
Speaker 1: Yes to the effect of the panel was shut down WTF.
Speaker 0: and I was like, yeah, I know it was shut down and filled up.
Speaker 0: They're like.
Speaker 0: no he got shut down shut down Like they kicked everyone out of the room and the panel was over.
Speaker 0: and I'm like, wow Now the only times I've heard of that are the 4chan panel and another panel.
Speaker 0: that also happened.
Speaker 1: So here's the high-level overview.
Speaker 1: Otacon decided the panel was not appropriate for non 18 plus content.
Speaker 1: So they shut it down immediately and they gave no recourse to have it rerun or schedule later or anything.
Speaker 1: It was done.
Speaker 1: they gave no option of Warning.
Speaker 1: no no option of you know shows things that don't violate the rule.
Speaker 1: they just shut it down and there was no appeal whatsoever.
Speaker 1: and I'm going to say right now before we get into the details of it that all things considered I can't blame Otacon for shutting the panel down and while they could have handled that aspect of it better.
Speaker 1: I Agree with Otacon shutting down the panel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean obviously they had to do something right?
Speaker 0: They could have done something better, but this was obviously a Satisfactory that you know, it's not something you can say you shouldn't have done that.
Speaker 1: You know, there were so many empty slots in the panel schedule because Otacon did not fill their panel.
Speaker 1: In fact when we went to check in for our panels the panel guy was like, yeah, can you guys do some more panels?
Speaker 1: No, yeah, we refused to but they they had a lot of open play.
Speaker 1: they could have Trivially put this in like the panel room between our two panels.
Speaker 1: That panel room was gigantic and could have held at least a quarter of the crowd that wanted to see it.
Speaker 1: Yep But anyway, the art while Otacon was right at that point a lot of question was to where did the blame lie?
Speaker 1: Did Daryl pull a fast one by not making this 18 plus?
Speaker 1: and the answer is unequivocally this is 100% Otacon's fault but not for the reasons you might think mm-hmm because you see Otacon Did not read their panel Applications as far as I can tell at all.
Speaker 0: They basically there is no evidence that they have read them and there is a mountain of evidence that they did not read them or at Least did not read them very thoroughly.
Speaker 1: what panel descriptions for our panels were?
Speaker 1: like the taught like me telling Otacon what the panels were?
Speaker 0: Yes, they put our panel proposals in the pocket guide as opposed to our panel.
Speaker 1: It was like yeah this panel We ran it at PAX.
Speaker 1: It runs 55 minutes.
Speaker 1: It needs a projector.
Speaker 1: I think it's pretty slick and cool and you should let us run an Otacon blah blah blah And that's what it said in the con book.
Speaker 0: Also, they seem to have removed like all the commas basically the pocket guide that has the descriptions of all the events was a complete Unedited disaster.
Speaker 0: and while I understand that a person bailed out of Otacon at the last second and they needed to rush to get it Done that is a very very important thing and you cannot afford even if you have to rush to get it done.
Speaker 0: There is still sort of like a minimum level You know of job that has to be done on it before you can send it off to the printer.
Speaker 0: and they just didn't Do it, you know, I mean, it's it's somewhat, you know, they could have even like called me up and said hey Do you want to edit this pocket guide?
Speaker 0: and I put it, you know, if they needed it the next day I would have stayed up overnight and made sure it was.
Speaker 0: I could have made it a lot better than it was.
Speaker 0: Let's just say that much now.
Speaker 1: It wasn't just there just as another example of this sloppiness, which is leading up to why this happened Gekoku Inoue who is the voice of Belle dandy.
Speaker 1: She's a super popular voice actress and she's pretty famous and is really cool that she came to Otacon.
Speaker 1: She was a voice actress for Oh Yankee Clinic, which is a hentai a horrifying hentai.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure how horrifying it is, but it's a hentai and I wouldn't watch.
Speaker 1: I have a one of the manga of it over there that we really do.
Speaker 1: it was given to me by Wyatt.
Speaker 1: It was signed by Steve Bennett.
Speaker 0: Oh that.
Speaker 0: Oh, Genki Clinic.
Speaker 0: Yes I didn't really.
Speaker 0: I thought that that was just a American thing that Steve Bennett did for him.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize it was an actual anime.
Speaker 1: Oh, Genki Clinic is a horrifying hentai.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is horrified.
Speaker 1: It is true that Gekoku Inoue was a voice actress in it and there's a lot.
Speaker 1: there's a whole bunch of debate about this, but she they never released a Version of it in America legitimately with her doing the acting.
Speaker 0: they also Like, you know her agency or whatever doesn't let that information get out Like they don't list her as having been in it and that's why you it's hard to get Oh Genki Clinic in Japan Apparently and
Speaker 1: presence like presence of it in America Conventions that talk do anything with her.
Speaker 1: People are very respectful of this and they don't print that in the con book and hardly anyone knows it.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, even ask a question about it.
Speaker 1: I like I'd heard rumors, but I didn't really know the story until this happened.
Speaker 1: Oh to kind of just printed this in the book.
Speaker 1: So someone at one of her panels was like blah blah blah Oh Genki Clinic and he wasn't.
Speaker 0: you know He didn't realize there was a controversy like we didn't realize it.
Speaker 0: he just read it in the con book and asked about it and she got mad upset and the people who knew that this is a Really
Speaker 1: the whole crowd was like, oh my god
Speaker 0: You know people in the crowd knew this is a sensitive issue But this guy just read it in the con book.
Speaker 0: So that guy isn't at fault.
Speaker 0: Otakon was at fault for letting that be in the convo.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing.
Speaker 1: I would never ever fault someone for telling the truth and I'm not an advocate of censorship and I wouldn't necessarily Like the fact that Otakon did it.
Speaker 1: if they did it knowingly I would have taken a position that yes It's an asshole thing to do but you know what they have the right to do.
Speaker 1: clearly I think it's obvious that Otakon Regrets that being a con Otakon screwed up because Jim would never have let that happen if he had read this and clearly a staffer At some point along the way fucked up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if it was our convention We would have intentionally printed it in there like or or we would have paid made very especially, you know We would not have printed it there.
Speaker 1: We would not have fucked it up.
Speaker 0: Yes, you know it's one of the two but if it was intentional it was okay.
Speaker 0: It was accidental it, you know, then it's like.
Speaker 0: it's not okay and it was accidental by Otakon.
Speaker 0: It was a failure in editing but these two things together.
Speaker 1: now back to Daryl's anime craziest death panel.
Speaker 1: now There is a whole controversy about the fact that I'll link to in our things that are in the post The clip that got the panel shut down and here's the pro.
Speaker 1: the real issue I would take is that if there had not been two kind of distant nipples in this video Gigantic not anywhere near realistic.
Speaker 1: Yeah nipples By Otakon's own admission at the con feedback session.
Speaker 1: This panel would have been fine because America has this crazy double standard where violence is great, but a nipple is verboten.
Speaker 0: Yes, but like I you know We talked about someone at the con.
Speaker 1: feedback was like so you're saying that if it'd been just as violent But you didn't show a nipple.
Speaker 1: It would have been fine.
Speaker 1: and the staffer was like, yes Absolutely, and I you know watch this video.
Speaker 0: It is a horrifying explosion of The thing is I want to bring up something.
Speaker 0: Carol Bart's who's the newer CEO of Yahoo?
Speaker 0: Someone questioned her at a press conference and said, you know, Yahoo Why are you being all you know doing business in China and censorship and all that right?
Speaker 0: and we always think you know Google Yahoo, Microsoft Censorship in China, they're bad Right.
Speaker 0: The thing is she said something that I sort of have a hard time arguing against even though I still feel there's something wrong With this argument and that is she said Yahoo wasn't created to fix China.
Speaker 1: Right, and that's the same thing for anyone who says that Otakon she just said blah and gone for it.
Speaker 1: It's not Otakon's responsibility to fix American Puritan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Otakon's, you know, Otakon's mission statement is not fix.
Speaker 0: the United States is pure in ways.
Speaker 0: You know Otakon's mission statement is you know Exist and spread anime and you know, love otaku generation, etc, etc.
Speaker 0: And it has you know, nothing in there about fixing America.
Speaker 0: So, you know since that's not part of what Otakon sits out to do in all other aspects They're just going to act within the laws and regulations of the Convention Center the city of Baltimore the state of Maryland the United States The UN etc.
Speaker 1: So did Daryl Surratt just not check this as 18 plus when he should have?
Speaker 1: well Maybe he did not check it.
Speaker 1: But you realize Otakon has this form you fill out to submit a panel and in the form There's a section that says is there anything important?
Speaker 1: We need to know about your panel and I put a whole bunch of stuff in there on all our panels which apparently Otakon didn't read because or at least they didn't.
Speaker 0: They didn't.
Speaker 0: it didn't.
Speaker 0: they didn't.
Speaker 0: we didn't have any evidence whatsoever that they read it.
Speaker 1: because Daryl in his submission I'm gonna paraphrase because I have what Daryl actually wrote here But he said in that section the content in this panel contains strong graphic violence and the possibility of nudity But no graphic sex or hentai beyond what would be seen in an upper tier like r-rated movie.
Speaker 0: That is the reason why I did not check it as 18 plus Yep, and apparently, you know Otakon did not publish at least not anywhere that I saw, you know I didn't look for it granted, but I didn't see anywhere a policy about what makes 18 plus.
Speaker 1: No, and you know what in the panel, they're really, you know as a panelist and it never really made it any.
Speaker 1: They never said what you when you have to take it when you don't and to it is Otakon's responsibility to determine that not the panel.
Speaker 0: Yep, and also You know Daryl Ran this exact panel at many other conventions in non 18 plus time slots with no issue whatsoever.
Speaker 0: So so Otakon has a different standard from other conventions, which is fine, but you can have a different standard.
Speaker 0: You just have to make it known.
Speaker 1: but it's not obvious and to no one read this at all.
Speaker 0: No obviously No one read it at least any whoever read it did not act on it or think about it or anything and they accepted the Panel just fine and they let him run it without the 18 plus like in the afternoon.
Speaker 1: Yep Otakon is just so at fault here and I don't know what to do about it.
Speaker 1: Let us take over panels I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would read all the panel descriptions That's at least.
Speaker 0: at the very least.
Speaker 0: I would read all the panel descriptions and the pocket guide wouldn't be messed up and Big panels obviously crowded panels would be in bigger rooms And other than that, I would probably run everything else the same as it is now.
Speaker 0: and there you go.
Speaker 1: So that was pretty much the biggest Disaster of Otakon because that was as far as I can see based on the count of people in line.
Speaker 1: That would have far and away been the most popular panel of the entire con.
Speaker 0: possibly All right.
Speaker 0: So are there any other big things that Otakon we have to cover before we do the chronology?
Speaker 1: Oh big big things.
Speaker 1: There was the bleach panel thing, but we can talk about that later.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's it.
Speaker 0: We'll do that chronologically because that was something we heard about afterwards and was not.
Speaker 0: so, you know It wasn't that big a deal.
Speaker 1: It was pretty cool.
Speaker 1: There's one last thing I do want to mention about Gophers and gopher ring because this came up at the feedback session and it came up again on the forums.
Speaker 0: I just want to mention we brought it up in a show how to fix anime cons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but one of the staffers at Otakon when someone complained about how you know being a panel it or being a gopher It really like.
Speaker 1: isn't that fun?
Speaker 1: at Otakon?
Speaker 1: and as you know panelists I can say that by and large the gophers I ran into couldn't act like they could not answer any questions I had
Speaker 0: like every gopher that I ran into Otakon and I ran into quite a few and tried to you know Get help from quite a few of them.
Speaker 0: They all see they were all nice.
Speaker 0: They were all trying to be helpful.
Speaker 0: They were all well-meaning and hard-working right?
Speaker 0: They were all great gophers.
Speaker 0: The thing was is that they just.
Speaker 0: they were obviously improperly trained.
Speaker 0: They didn't know their way around the convention center.
Speaker 0: They didn't know the schedule.
Speaker 0: They didn't know even where the information desk was which had moved this year.
Speaker 0: That was the first thing.
Speaker 0: when I walked in the con The information desk was replaced by the lost and found and the information desk had moved.
Speaker 0: So I asked a nearby gopher.
Speaker 0: Where did the information desk move to?
Speaker 1: Oh Now the worst part is and not to really disparage Otakon, but the staff were largely the same way.
Speaker 1: I I rarely encountered a staffer who could answer any question I had.
Speaker 0: basically, it's it's not that the staff aren't hard-working or Such.
Speaker 0: is that they have this sort of attitude that I think is harmful to the convention and They just they just need to fix it.
Speaker 0: There's no that that's pretty much the bottom line that these staff and gophers of Otakon have an attitude and a culture that is harmful.
Speaker 0: They are not particular often You know disrespectful to guests, you know, not guests of the members of the con badge holding.
Speaker 0: You know attendees as well as you know gophers.
Speaker 1: not saying this is not across the board It's just a general attitude, you know About the relevant quote and this started out shitstorm in the forum quote Gophering is not supposed to be fun.
Speaker 1: You're put where you're put if you don't like it.
Speaker 1: Don't do it.
Speaker 1: It's as simple as that.
Speaker 1: and all I want to say we don't want to dwell on this year.
Speaker 0: This is a whole separate show that we have the show on it already.
Speaker 1: Yes anime cons Yes, but we we will highlight it again at some point because we're going to PAX and everything.
Speaker 1: But I bring it up because in the forum that same staffer basically said enforcers.
Speaker 1: What are you kidding?
Speaker 1: Yeah, like they they they clearly did not understand what needs to change in staffing.
Speaker 0: Yes I think that you know that I mean, here's it here.
Speaker 0: Let me I can sum it up by doing two impressions.
Speaker 1: I got emails from some Otakon staffers who were first-year staffers and a few of them posted in the forum to Basically saying like you know what we try But we just like no one told us what to do and a lot of times I watered around with nothing to do.
Speaker 0: Yep here I'm gonna do two impressions here and I think these impressions will sum up everything we have to say.
Speaker 0: and let us get a move On and not extend this episode any further, right?
Speaker 0: This is my impression of an Otakon staffer Managing a line to an event in which no cameras are allowed.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I know you're gonna do Basically yelling at the people in line as if they are children right yelling at them like hey you punk kids This is the rules.
Speaker 0: That's an Otakon staffer right.
Speaker 0: there actually is an Otakon staffer.
Speaker 0: I don't even know their name But they do exist and I've run into them at my first Otakon in o2 and I ran into a similar person If not the same person at the Otakon o9.
Speaker 0: now here is a Pax enforcer in the same situation.
Speaker 0: Dude, no cameras.
Speaker 0: What's up?
Speaker 0: Oh, come on.
Speaker 0: Listen.
Speaker 0: All right here.
Speaker 0: Give me your camera I'll put in lost and found and then after you get out of here, you'll find it.
Speaker 0: All right, cool Go man, right improvisation Treat it treating.
Speaker 1: Here's the attendees.
Speaker 0: with respect improv being helpful.
Speaker 1: improvisation come knowing solutions got things.
Speaker 1: improvisation comes with one thing and that is authority the fact that any Enforcer from the lowest to the highest rank has equal authority to improvise on the spot and make things work.
Speaker 0: Yep, and they're also, you know train.
Speaker 0: They're also trained enough that they are trusted with that authority.
Speaker 1: If you don't believe that our anecdotal evidence here's a specific example Darryl's and you know panel craziest anime deaths shut down kind of ham-fisted Lee Otakon staffers could have like fixed it by moving the panel somewhere.
Speaker 1: do it like.
Speaker 1: they could have done something to make everyone happy and Solve the situation if they had just had the authority to think on their feet and improvise.
Speaker 0: when we ran beyond D&D at PAX and a mob of Panel like hundreds of people yet Unexpectedly for the old for the first time we went over to where the gaming tables were and they were all full which had not Been true for the entire con.
Speaker 1: So the packs enforcers all these
Speaker 0: people with no tables to
Speaker 1: say all these packs enforcers saw our trouble and they came over like guys You need some help and we're like, yeah, we got this mob We got to run like another panel on the fly and they were like, uh, let me check and they get on the radios And they're like panel room.
Speaker 1: Whatever is empty go there.
Speaker 1: We'll put up a sign We'll point everyone who's trying to find you guys over there.
Speaker 1: and then they sent us all these other Enforcers to like set up microphones for us and to run this panel room for us on the spot at like 11 o'clock at night.
Speaker 0: Yep They just completely improvised and just they grabbed tables from somewhere and they set up this panel room and made it happen on the spot.
Speaker 0: They saw there was a problem.
Speaker 0: They saw there was a crowd that was doing something.
Speaker 0: That wasn't you know, quite right?
Speaker 0: They had nowhere to go.
Speaker 0: It was lost.
Speaker 0: They saw it They descended upon it and they fixed it.
Speaker 1: and before you say but PAX is a for-profit con Pax enforcers are not paid.
Speaker 1: They're just as volunteer as Otakon gophers.
Speaker 0: Yes the only difference is in their attitude the way they are managed the amount of training they have the Enthusiasm they have the respect they have for each other the respect they have for the attendees and the respect the attendees have for them.
Speaker 1: And I think that I used to think that anime con culture and anime con demographics could not support something like that.
Speaker 1: I've changed my opinion.
Speaker 1: I think it's because I know Otakon staffers who are exactly like that and I think you could get enough of those staffers If you just change the culture around anime conventions.
Speaker 1: But the culture of anime con staffing is a whole separate issue and we want to get to all the awesome stuff from Otakon.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I think the one the Otakon's major difficulty is its inertia.
Speaker 0: It's been doing it for how many years it's gonna.
Speaker 0: It's very hard to change it.
Speaker 0: Whereas Pax started off on the right foot Yep.
Speaker 1: Also Pax kind of started in a vacuum and kind of didn't have all the accoutrement and the baggage of old gaming cons and old Anime con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they just made it up as they went along.
Speaker 0: They didn't you know, they barely looked at other cons, you know.
Speaker 0: So they didn't do anything according to the status quo.
Speaker 0: They did things according to the way that they thought it should be done.
Speaker 0: So anyway, yep, let's do the chronology of Otakon.
Speaker 1: All right now This is this is very concert.
Speaker 1: very pointedly this capsule is gonna be long, but that's fine.
Speaker 1: You guys like this stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but very pointedly we did not get press passes this year and we tried to wander around the con straight up as attendees.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean panelists don't get a special badge.
Speaker 0: So we had the same badge as everyone else only we were running some panels.
Speaker 1: Yep, so consider this a almost a blog post as opposed to like objective press coverage.
Speaker 1: We're gonna talk about like I was trying to get dinner and stupid Baltimore and everything.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So we showed up Thursday like we always do at noon and for the first time in Seven years the Renaissance Hotel just fucked us.
Speaker 1: every year like we have this ritual we show up at noon We get a room like right next to the elevator like at noon at the Renaissance Early check-in.
Speaker 1: we like hang out We go skip the line and get our badges because we're panelists and then we go and like swim in the pool and have a super Awesome party all night long.
Speaker 1: Thursday The Renaissance Hotel just screwed us.
Speaker 1: They didn't give us a room to like three the rooms.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they gave our friend a room immediately Yep.
Speaker 1: and And we registered the room like we got the room like months before they did and the rooms felt like chlorine.
Speaker 0: and this is right next to the pool and the staff becomes far away from the elevator as possible.
Speaker 1: and Beyond that the only reason we stayed in the Renaissance every year was because Right near the Renaissance over in the power plant is where all the good restaurants are but the one good restaurant out of business Yep, and basically like everything was fail and I've given up.
Speaker 1: they've crossed me for the last time.
Speaker 0: Yep, next year.
Speaker 0: We're gonna stay in the Hilton.
Speaker 1: Yeah They also gave us a one king-size bed despite us having reserved the room for two beds and four people Like the week after Otacon last year.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah Fail on the hotel.
Speaker 0: also the parking is still way too expensive.
Speaker 0: Yeah Next year the Hilton which is attached to the con I think will actually Save us a lot of time because how many times do we have to like walk back get the banner and stuff?
Speaker 1: course?
Speaker 0: a lot Of those trips can be a very much.
Speaker 0: we can save a lot of time if we stay in that hell.
Speaker 1: a lot of people had Trouble, however with the Hilton I'll get into that at the con feed.
Speaker 0: I don't think we'll have trouble.
Speaker 1: we won't.
Speaker 1: but four or five years ago.
Speaker 1: We would have that's true.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, so the vamps concert on Thursday, but of course we skipped the pre-reg line Which is insanely long because we had vamps concert tickets.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that worked very well that line.
Speaker 0: Skip we got our badges.
Speaker 0: We went over to the vamps concert.
Speaker 0: We took a cab with a cool cabbie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he was all nice.
Speaker 1: and now we took the cab because we're really sure where the place was.
Speaker 1: But the place is like a couple blocks from.
Speaker 0: yeah, it looked much farther away on the map than it actually was.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's just Seattle syndrome.
Speaker 0: We got in line.
Speaker 0: We met all kinds of cool people at the concert people We knew.
Speaker 1: particularly behind us There was this really cute anime girl with her mom and her mom was like totally lazy Matsumoto like super awesome, like awesome, like I talked to her the whole time in line about like she is like old-school awesome.
Speaker 0: We also walk past a weird like Satan Church.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I got some pictures of that like some other weird stuff on the way past like that scary-looking like rusty Blood-covered looking like can top and then later we saw the hobo can.
Speaker 1: it was associated with.
Speaker 0: yeah Anyway, so we event, you know, regardless there was weird stuff in the line for the concert.
Speaker 0: The line was a bit long.
Speaker 0: concert started a little bit late, but that was all right.
Speaker 0: Yep, we eventually got in the room and we were greeted with an awesome concert.
Speaker 1: Any a lot of people we know we're like, I'm not interested in that concert or I don't want Your loss, you're all stupid.
Speaker 1: Anyone who thinks they don't want to go to a concert because you know I don't like that style of music unless it's phantom ass live music is always badass and
Speaker 0: 99% of live music is badass Regardless of genre or whether you know it already or don't know it already or anything Even like a band that usually like people would be rate.
Speaker 0: It can be pretty awesome live, but here's the thing.
Speaker 1: Here's the awesome part, you know hide the frontman for this band Vamps one.
Speaker 1: They're a lot more like hardcore and hard rocky a little bit of metal than they used to be.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, he used to be.
Speaker 1: it was a great concert and they did this interesting cover of Lucy in the sky with diamonds near The end.
Speaker 1: that was pretty cool.
Speaker 0: That's pretty good.
Speaker 1: But During the concert, you know, he stops and he addresses the crowd.
Speaker 0: He's like hello Baltimore And the thing is at what we never go to these j-rock concerts in the US, right?
Speaker 0: They typically don't speak a lot of English.
Speaker 0: the highs English is you know, it's alright.
Speaker 0: He's definitely learned about it.
Speaker 1: Yes is very specific.
Speaker 1: He's always like hello Baltimore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know, he'll say he won't say a lot right, but he'll say like a few things with a lot of power.
Speaker 0: He'll be like, yeah, we're going to take care of you.
Speaker 1: He reminds me a lot of that metal band.
Speaker 1: We saw in in Poughkeepsie.
Speaker 1: Do you like Christians?
Speaker 0: Yeah So anyway, you know if anyone knows back at the Larkin CL concert, you know five years ago whatever right he did similar shtick and one of the shticks was Did you eat crap?
Speaker 1: and that was the famous.
Speaker 1: the whole audience?
Speaker 1: He's like blah blah.
Speaker 1: the audience goes And he's like do you eat crap?
Speaker 1: and there's this slight pause as the audience goes And then everyone cheers anyway because clearly he doesn't mean crap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then he's talking about eating crab because as Emily tells us the thing to do in Japan This is all about the local food, right?
Speaker 0: It's like Emily went to see him in.
Speaker 1: doing this concert in New York is like I eat pizza Slice as big as my head, which that's New York pizza.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you ever go to Japan I think that it would probably be a very good idea to learn the local special food of wherever you're going Because then the people will like you and possibly be less xenophobic towards you.
Speaker 1: actually It's France is pretty much the same way.
Speaker 1: if you're in some little French town and you just order Maybe I just take that as a general travel tip for the world learn the local foods except in America and always eat the local Specialty wherever you are because then you might end up with scrapple.
Speaker 0: You might end up with Yeah, you might have a grits also anyway, but that you know that he realized on the stage shoe.
Speaker 1: He's like what I say wrong what I say wrong.
Speaker 1: Oh, well.
Speaker 0: Yes You know for years and years and years that has been an inside joke with us sort of an outside joke.
Speaker 0: We'd always be like did you eat crab?
Speaker 1: and as far as I can tell it has been a joke among just pretty much a Lot of people who went to that concert.
Speaker 1: like people.
Speaker 1: it resonated people remembered that.
Speaker 0: something about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, did you eat crab?
Speaker 0: just stuck?
Speaker 0: and I didn't think that he would remember.
Speaker 0: I'm like how would he know that people remember that?
Speaker 0: how would he know?
Speaker 0: and then oh, you know?
Speaker 0: I'm like the whole concert every time.
Speaker 0: I'm like.
Speaker 0: you know I was actually really looking forward to the parts where he said stuff instead of singing.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: I was like is He gonna say something about the crab what he's gonna say?
Speaker 1: he comes out, and he's like hello Baltimore Did you eat crab, but he says it and then he gets like he kind of cocks his head like he like.
Speaker 0: he's like.
Speaker 0: He knows like.
Speaker 1: he knew he's so new and everyone was just like yeah Because every everyone in that crowd knew like.
Speaker 0: everybody knew Everybody knew the score, and then he said a few other things you know.
Speaker 0: and then he said do you eat crab again?
Speaker 0: Cuz he knew it was a man.
Speaker 0: it was a fantastic.
Speaker 0: That's like if you went to like a Rick Astley concert, and he came out.
Speaker 0: He's like be like Rick roll, but you know Chris.
Speaker 0: He does do that, but you know I'm just saying it's the same.
Speaker 0: It's like if he knew before you thought he knew Anyway, but the concert was awesome.
Speaker 1: awesome concert shoutouts to everyone we met cuz we hung out with like a ton of cool.
Speaker 0: We hung out with so many people at this con.
Speaker 0: I don't remember all of you.
Speaker 1: I remember some I know your name Cool girl and your mom who were hanging out behind us in line.
Speaker 1: cool people in front of us punk kids behind us.
Speaker 1: That is also where I saw the gothical leader with the tiny hat and I decided that my goal in life is to see someone Wearing four of those tiny stupid.
Speaker 0: we decided three hats.
Speaker 1: I think you got to go all the way to four three like in a crown like in a circle and then one on top Of one of the other ones a
Speaker 0: little pyramid
Speaker 1: something like maybe ten
Speaker 0: in sort of like a bowling pair like a
Speaker 1: stack of pancakes
Speaker 0: Or a stack of cups.
Speaker 1: anyway anyway, and like we met Erin who we met at PAX as well Yeah, she came all the way from Western Canada Bus from Western Canada and stayed in the hostel by Otakon.
Speaker 0: that's dedication.
Speaker 1: She's pretty cool, too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, totally awesome, but we also went to the seven a 7-eleven after the concert and they had individual servings of simply lemonade.
Speaker 1: And then you know in the 7-eleven.
Speaker 1: all these people are like oh my god, we're in Scott Yeah, woo in the 7-eleven everyone knew us.
Speaker 0: so yeah We should have hung out the 7-eleven the whole time to meet the listeners anyway, so Saturday morning at Otakon Friday Friday morning.
Speaker 0: I meant Friday, but I said Saturday so Trouble Friday morning.
Speaker 1: now Otakon has never gotten those goddamn doors open at the right time, but this year It's 8 o'clock.
Speaker 0: the cons supposed to be open doors.
Speaker 1: a shot this year They got them open relatively quicker than other years, but we had a problem.
Speaker 1: We had a panel pretty early on Friday at 10 and the second panel.
Speaker 1: there's a line like one.
Speaker 1: none of the doors are open and there's this line like this crazy crazy line to get into the con.
Speaker 1: So we go to the front the other privacy that street entrance because no one will let us in any other door.
Speaker 0: and well I mean, it's understandable.
Speaker 0: They can't open the middle street doors.
Speaker 0: What's that Street?
Speaker 0: I forget the middle street doors because you know the red line is passing by there.
Speaker 0: So they can't open those until the red line is passed.
Speaker 0: understandable.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: They never opened the sky wall They never opened the sky walk, but actually they did open the sky walk this year.
Speaker 0: But the thing is they don't open enough doors on the regular entrance.
Speaker 0: They open one door and the people trickle in also too little too late.
Speaker 1: and the the crux of this was Panels started at 9 and the doors open like at 9 15 and there was no one in the Convention Center Except the people were getting their pre-reg badges that morning.
Speaker 1: So basically all the nine o'clock panels were empty.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was the thing if you got your pre-reg badge, right?
Speaker 0: Because the reg doors opened on time.
Speaker 0: So you got your pre registered or registered and got your badge immediately like your first in line Friday.
Speaker 0: You just stayed in the con.
Speaker 0: So those people got in before people who bought their badges got their badges Thursday and waited for these other freaking doors to open.
Speaker 0: They need to open all of those doors.
Speaker 0: Not obviously not the ones that you can't open but all of the openable doors.
Speaker 0: open all of them immediately at the opening minute.
Speaker 1: Or don't schedule panels when no one can possibly be in the center.
Speaker 0: Also a good idea.
Speaker 1: more importantly we had a panel we couldn't get in.
Speaker 1: we find some staff.
Speaker 1: We're like look we got a panel we got to get in and finally the guys like alright fine.
Speaker 1: And he let us in and we go to panel ops and we set everything up.
Speaker 1: We barely make it to our panel, but Other panelists weren't so lucky and one panelist very specifically like.
Speaker 1: they went in and they're like look we got again.
Speaker 1: We got a panel at nine and the staffer said to them You should have gotten in line earlier like everyone else.
Speaker 1: Whoa, whoa is right now later.
Speaker 1: Oh two counts.
Speaker 1: official response was and I quote whoever said that was misinformed.
Speaker 0: Yes I think that's you know.
Speaker 1: I think again the problem of too many staffers are misinformed and too many staffers take this Adversarial.
Speaker 1: they're misinformed or malinformed or uninformed and they take this kind of adversarial Like this bad guy position when they could have worked something out.
Speaker 1: but this also is the problem that Otacon is trying to prevent the other problem of People sign up to do panels just to get the perks and then just don't show up for their panels.
Speaker 0: I think Otacon sort of has this assumption that anyone who's gophering or doing a panel or whatever is just out for a free Bad.
Speaker 0: here's the thing and only the staff and the button is the people who are really working hard.
Speaker 0: Otacon tried to go to the con.
Speaker 1: Otacon tried to fix this problem by making it to where you basically get Jack for shit if you're a panelist and they still had tons and tons of panels.
Speaker 1: just not show up just not do their panels.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the thing is someone's doing a panel and showing up.
Speaker 0: That's someone who cares about the convention.
Speaker 0: They're just like the staff.
Speaker 0: We're not trying to scam a free badge, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, I'd probably pay the cost isn't the problem, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, it's it's.
Speaker 0: I want to help the con just as much as the staff.
Speaker 0: But here's I'm helping in a different way.
Speaker 1: I don't want to dwell on that any further other than to say that a bunch of Otacon staff have come up to us several of them independently of one another and a couple as a group as a group and it basically says that they're going to sponsor us To like take control of one panel room or one video room and run stuff in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah We're working on something for next year.
Speaker 0: That could be awesome.
Speaker 0: We'll possibly become staff or who knows what but yeah We're gonna.
Speaker 1: we're gonna do our best to do some fixings within our power because our policy as always is if we're told to put Up or shut up.
Speaker 0: We're always willing to put up and then if you deny our put up then we can trash you.
Speaker 1: That's why we drop Katsu Khan.
Speaker 1: We weren't willing to put up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we shut up okay, so So we caught our way in and we did.
Speaker 1: you know the panel staffer to his credit?
Speaker 1: I had the packs attitude because we were like Can we leave this banner in here overnight?
Speaker 1: And he's like the no you can't the policies No, and I was like we were like, so is it?
Speaker 1: no we can't or is it?
Speaker 1: you won't stop us.
Speaker 1: But if it disappears, it's our fault.
Speaker 1: and he was like, I'm not gonna stop you.
Speaker 1: So we hit it in the corner and it was fine.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: See that's a packs attitude that guy had.
Speaker 0: That was the panel staff guy that the guy was in panel ops.
Speaker 0: Yes, very much like, you know, we are not responsible for lost or misplaced items.
Speaker 0: and we're like, thank you We'll leave this right here.
Speaker 0: Good day.
Speaker 1: Good day, sir.
Speaker 0: See that is the correct attitude to have and he was also the one improvising.
Speaker 1: Can you guys do more panels?
Speaker 0: Yeah, we didn't know we did.
Speaker 0: so we went to our first panel know your creators Which I have to admit was not the greatest panel.
Speaker 0: The major problem with it was that we planned to retool it.
Speaker 0: We failed to retool it and be we did not do enough preparation.
Speaker 0: We planned to meet with Daryl Surratt.
Speaker 0: It was also on the panel on Thursday, and we failed to meet him on Thursday.
Speaker 1: The fact that almost every video he sent me had boobs in it Yes, so it was very difficult.
Speaker 0: And also we had a technology fail which is rims fault.
Speaker 1: now I have.
Speaker 1: well the thing is while I had some problems with that with the videos Other an industry panel had a similar problem in the same room.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I was at the Bana entertainment.
Speaker 0: I was at a portion of the Bana entertainment panel in that same room and they had similar difficulties.
Speaker 0: So it was not entirely our fault.
Speaker 1: However, I will say this it was partially rims But I think Daryl Surratt was trying to sabotage our panel.
Speaker 1: He was not trying to say it's with the boob because I noticed that the boob screwed him later And he was trying to bring us down with him into hell.
Speaker 0: Okay, anyway, but yeah, that wasn't our best panel.
Speaker 0: It didn't have enough preparation But considering that it was at 10 a.m.
Speaker 0: Right not a lot of people showed up But considering that it was at 10 a.m.
Speaker 0: And not a lot of people.
Speaker 0: a lot of you was still waiting in line.
Speaker 0: It was a lot of people considering those factors.
Speaker 0: It just wasn't a lot of people in total.
Speaker 0: It was in the biggest panel room the same panel room they use for closing ceremonies and such and it had People.
Speaker 1: it was you know, and also despite me thinking that that was a pretty weak panel on our part We got a lot of feedback.
Speaker 0: We got some negative feedbacks though, which was pretty accurate.
Speaker 0: one person was like Yeah, the con Pete the people running the panel, you know, we're sort of talking to each other about.
Speaker 0: you know They're issues with the you know, and it was like yeah, that's exactly true.
Speaker 0: It's cuz you didn't prepare Yeah, and in the future you will prepare this panel much much more.
Speaker 0: and the panels, you know, it's almost run its course anyway.
Speaker 0: So, yep, that was that panel Alright, so let us fast forward a little bit here.
Speaker 0: that point I don't want it around try to do a lot of wandering because there wasn't a lot I wanted to see right away at least, you know, I went to the artists alley, you know when it opened and Artists alley this year.
Speaker 0: very nice artists alley, you know just as big and awesome as last year.
Speaker 1: The art show was pretty solid - I gotta say.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Our show was pretty solid.
Speaker 0: I mean there wasn't anything in the art show that blew me away.
Speaker 0: I did notice there was the giant big old statue though That was something epic to behold.
Speaker 1: and if I if I had not just like purchased a house I kind of considered it because that would have been a cool thing to own.
Speaker 1: it wasn't that it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing was it was like you had to You know basically pay for shipping of the thing, which is like $1,000.
Speaker 0: and I'm wondering how did they ship it to Otacon?
Speaker 0: And did anyone buy it?
Speaker 0: You know, it's like whoa, really sort.
Speaker 1: of course It's partly you ship it to Otacon just to show it off like look why I rot.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Look ye mighty ye not guilty.
Speaker 0: They're also a lot of.
Speaker 0: there are also more models in the modeling contest in the art show Which I thought was pretty interesting.
Speaker 1: and I modeling is coming back.
Speaker 0: I think modeling is coming back and princess tutu is coming is making a research.
Speaker 1: I think we are primarily responsible for princess tutu's comeback.
Speaker 0: I don't think we're responsible for the modeling comeback.
Speaker 0: We're not but princess tutu definitely needs to come back.
Speaker 0: He's the come.
Speaker 0: it's a come for princess tutu and a come for modeling.
Speaker 1: Anyway Our friend speaking of that Every year we always go to the 18-plus section of the art show because it is invariably hilarious and it did not disappoint.
Speaker 0: Yep, there was some funny stuff in there.
Speaker 0: Our friend Eric Marisak was doing his awesome chalk arts.
Speaker 0: Yep, I did, you know pretty much he did the Otacon con book cover Nice crabs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, his stuff is always impressive and he's at like every time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you go to a nerdy con be it, you know, I think he's gonna be a Pax.
Speaker 0: He's at New York anime festival New York comic-con.
Speaker 0: He's at all sorts of cons.
Speaker 0: Eric Marisak is the guy who's always doing the chalk art on the big piece of paper.
Speaker 0: Definitely stop and say hi to him.
Speaker 0: He's really cool.
Speaker 0: He likes to take a break, you know from drawing his chalk.
Speaker 0: So if you go and talk to him, he'll stand up and talk to you.
Speaker 0: just we can give his arm a rest.
Speaker 0: You know, he's got a lot of cool stuff to say.
Speaker 0: I learned that he gets the chalk in bulk really cheap from this company that doesn't have a website.
Speaker 0: So, you know that it's.
Speaker 1: that's something to keep in mind This vision of buying Like just tons and tons and tons of it and just giving it to a whole to everyone in line at Otacon.
Speaker 0: That's what I was about to say.
Speaker 0: I would you know remember at Pax when he waited in line to give everyone pipe cleaners about.
Speaker 1: you know Another example of Pax being awesome.
Speaker 1: Good God, but there was this crazy line that was gonna be like two hours long.
Speaker 1: so Pax enforcers just went and got like all this pipe cleaner and Just pass it out in bulk and said do what thou wilt and everyone made awesome crafts in line at Otacon.
Speaker 0: People are taking you know people in line some stupid morons in line.
Speaker 0: These were attendees, by the way We're using like permanent marker to like draw on, you know, basically vandalize the city while they were alive.
Speaker 1: Jackass is because because it was Otacon.
Speaker 1: It was the BCC.
Speaker 1: Otacon probably had to cover the cleaning of that.
Speaker 0: Yep Who knows?
Speaker 0: Well, I don't know.
Speaker 0: it could have just been.
Speaker 0: you know That the city because it's not remember remember and any issue regarding the line or outside the con Otacon does communicate with the city.
Speaker 0: But I think it does, you know, it is the city's responsibility.
Speaker 1: Yes, but if it's on the convention center, there might be agreements to the.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I have no idea how that works regardless up in the jackasses.
Speaker 1: But if we just bought chalk in bulk The kids wouldn't use the Sharpie to draw the penis when they can use the perfectly easily wash off chalk to draw the penis
Speaker 0: Yep, and that also would have occupied people in line, you know who are bored and sitting there for hours and hours.
Speaker 0: They should just hand it out chalk to the whole line and I bet there are plenty of artists out in line.
Speaker 0: artists People who could have drawn some really good stuff out on this You know and it would have.
Speaker 0: also as people drove by after the line cleared They would have seen all this awesome anime arts all over, you know And they probably the only thing that you probably what I had to do was get some sort of permit from the city and Otacon Already probably has to get a bunch of permits from the city.
Speaker 0: How much work is one more permit?
Speaker 1: really think about our economy.
Speaker 0: that art festival is going on at the same time I think Baltimore would be anyone about yeah, and it would have made, you know The convention center look totally Otacon styling during Otacon would've been awesome.
Speaker 0: You know, it's that kind of creative thinking that you know people need to work on.
Speaker 1: Anyway, they're they're lucky because I didn't know about this.
Speaker 1: My other plan was to buy like 10,000 kazoos in bulk.
Speaker 1: Haha, I mean if you think butts got ya butts got ya was annoying imagine Thousand kazoos.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right thing is, you know, I don't you want to talk about the butt-scratching or just skip it.
Speaker 0: We should mention it.
Speaker 0: So so apparently I heard I didn't hear anyone at the con actually say this.
Speaker 0: never.
Speaker 0: once in post Con a lot of people complained that people were saying butt-scratch up And I didn't know what the deal was.
Speaker 0: butt-scratcher I thought it was some sort of 4chan thing sort of like seeking fuck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: But later on after we got home We did a YouTube search for butt-scratch up and we found out what it was.
Speaker 0: and actually I kind of think it's it's funny.
Speaker 1: Well, it was funny because well one it's an interesting exercise in memes and I don't want to get into that But we've talked about that a lot and it is like this beautiful example of the fitness of a meme and that's and the Susceptibility of people different kinds of memes but someone posted in the Otacon forum cuz someone was like, where did that start?
Speaker 1: Oh my god, and this guy was like, sorry guys.
Speaker 1: I think it was me and I'm not kidding.
Speaker 1: basically There were all those people like bums and people with permits walking up and down the pregrudge line and the line Friday morning.
Speaker 1: they're like ice cold water.
Speaker 1: get you ice cold water here trying to sell, you know water.
Speaker 1: and One guy in line after every time they walked by.
Speaker 1: I was like but scotch I get you but scotch.
Speaker 1: Ah, but scotch I make fun of those guys and apparently just started spreading up and down the line and it echoed for the entire Convention even though I never heard it once.
Speaker 0: That tells me how big this con is.
Speaker 0: that there was a nut.
Speaker 0: it was enough of a problem that multiple people complained about it But it was all.
Speaker 0: it wasn't big enough that I found out about it.
Speaker 1: The thing is for anyone to complain about that.
Speaker 1: There's nothing you can do about me.
Speaker 1: the people who go to anime cons are more susceptible to memes than average people.
Speaker 0: You already took away the signs.
Speaker 0: It's a good move.
Speaker 0: You can't take away yelling stuff.
Speaker 1: It can't take away the butt-scratcher, right?
Speaker 0: So Also the video game room at Otacon was oh my god.
Speaker 0: It was actually quite good.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's pretty much the same as it's been in years past.
Speaker 1: They had these pump machines in the corner.
Speaker 1: that was rocking.
Speaker 0: people were actually saying the pump machines are really good.
Speaker 0: They didn't have a GDS DDR but not machines of DDR.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I actually played you know, the sort of quirky Japanese shmups.
Speaker 0: I played this one little star, whatever.
Speaker 0: Well, we played the twinkle star whatever for the.
Speaker 0: I guess it was the ps2 version.
Speaker 1: became is so great.
Speaker 0: It's the versus witches Monster.
Speaker 0: shoot him up space shooter shmup, right?
Speaker 0: We also played.
Speaker 0: I played this game that was basically saying it was the Sega Saturn game.
Speaker 0: That was basically Gradius, but you had all these different characters you could choose from.
Speaker 0: you could choose the Gradius ship.
Speaker 0: You could also choose like stick figure riding a paper airplane or flying pig or all these other like the dragon guy You know sitting on a rocket all this sort of stuff and it was.
Speaker 0: it was a pretty good Gradius game and infinite continues.
Speaker 0: It was fun.
Speaker 0: I also played this Xbox 360 game That was sort of a versus shmup.
Speaker 0: You know It's sort of like a versus bullet hell where you charge up and you turn into a boss and everything.
Speaker 0: and it was.
Speaker 0: it's a pretty Good game and you know, so there is some interesting stuff going on in the Otacon video game room.
Speaker 0: And you know, actually the time I went there was like right away on Saturday or Sunday.
Speaker 0: no right away on Saturday I went in there.
Speaker 0: I think just like immediately as soon as the con opened and You know, I said it wasn't too crowded when I was in there They had to wait in line and you know, I had a good old time.
Speaker 0: But apparently, you know when it was crowded there was of course issues But I was not party to them as I was there very early on Saturday.
Speaker 0: Yeah So yes good time in the video game room at Otacon any uh, you know, it does like.
Speaker 0: why the dealers room?
Speaker 0: Right dealers room at Otacon There was a lot less industry presence because the industry is down in the crapper, right?
Speaker 0: You know, there was like a media blasters booth and a funimation and that even those industry booths are much smaller.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but however in years past Otacon is you know, the way the dealers room has worked is they would still have this big industry space, right?
Speaker 0: They would just be less and smaller industry booths resulting in one area of the dealers room being sort of airy and wide open And the rest of the dealers room being, you know booths booths booths booths booths.
Speaker 0: The thing is this year they crammed the whole thing with booze booze booze booze booze, you know as the whole there was equal tightness.
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't tight.
Speaker 0: All the aisles were wide and comfortable, you know You were never cramped unless you wanted to get up close to a booth.
Speaker 1: But there were just a ton of smaller vendors with a lot of really interesting stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it wasn't like some great great dealers room.
Speaker 0: There weren't amazing deals.
Speaker 0: There weren't like that.
Speaker 1: I gotta say Sadly enough, you know the deep discount DVD like 25% off sale was also going on during Otacon.
Speaker 1: Yeah But here's what I noticed No dealer had a deal that even came close to just the standard Amazon price on freaking any DVDs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the ones that did have deals like the always awesome sci-fi continuum.
Speaker 0: It was.
Speaker 0: I've already cleaned out sci-fi continuum and you're in all the 20 conventions I've seen them at so they didn't have anything left for me to clean them out of.
Speaker 0: so anyway You know if you're looking for treasures or if you're looking for deals.
Speaker 0: the Otacon dealers room didn't have it But what he did have was quantity and what it did have actually was model kits.
Speaker 0: there was and you know There was just there's some resurgence.
Speaker 0: I noticed the anime Boston.
Speaker 0: I noticed it at Otacon.
Speaker 1: Oh now an anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Scott was like, I think there's a resurgence.
Speaker 1: There's like there's more of this stuff.
Speaker 0: or I saw more people just anecdotally walking out of the dealer room with Gundam model kit.
Speaker 1: But then we get to Otacon and there's like this one.
Speaker 0: That's just model kits and it is packed the whole con.
Speaker 0: it was a poorly laid-out booth.
Speaker 0: It was hard to walk around in this one-way maze, right?
Speaker 0: But they had model kits.
Speaker 0: people were at the booth was constantly crowded.
Speaker 0: There was always someone at the cash register for as long as the dealers room was open.
Speaker 0: They had good stuff and I saw lots of model kits being sold and I saw Lots more of them at in the dealers room in general.
Speaker 0: so model kits are making a comeback at the dealer rooms in the cons and that is a good thing.
Speaker 0: I say and That's that's you know, that's really all there is to say about the Otacon dealers room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, it's it's a dealers room.
Speaker 0: They sell stuff.
Speaker 1: now in terms of panels, right?
Speaker 1: Obviously I'm not gonna talk about every panel I went to but I saw some pretty good panels.
Speaker 1: I didn't see any bad panels, but I'll point out way in the end in the con feedback session Numerous people complained not you know, oh, they're bad panels But that there are a few panels that happen every year by the same people every year.
Speaker 1: that are terrible every year Yep, but I skipped all those.
Speaker 1: but one thing Otacon did.
Speaker 1: that was great and I'm glad they did this.
Speaker 1: They need to never stop doing this.
Speaker 1: They made a 15-minute break between every single panel.
Speaker 1: panels did not abut against each other.
Speaker 0: Yep, that was very good.
Speaker 1: So as a result unlike every other Otacon ever when we had a panel we would be in the room We'd be set up the time would start and our panel would start immediately and it was great.
Speaker 1: They're like brilliant Otacon.
Speaker 1: I'm glad you did that.
Speaker 1: It made panels a million times better.
Speaker 0: Yep Another thing they did is they made it very clear when there would be a room clear and when they would not if there was No scheduled room clear.
Speaker 0: the room would not clear and if there was a scheduled room clear the room would clear and the only times They really scheduled room clears were like before the vamps panel, you know a very crowded panel before 18-plus starts in the room.
Speaker 0: You know obvious reasons and if there was some sort of reason that they had to do a room clear Like I heard that there was a technical difficulty in one of the rooms where they had to do some rewiring For liability reasons they had to do a room clear because they couldn't rewire it while there are people in there.
Speaker 0: You know just in case something happened insurance, etc, etc, and you know, and that is perfectly understandable.
Speaker 1: So again great I mean Otacon base exactly what they should have done Other than because we might not mention everything in the show exactly what they did do what they should have done.
Speaker 1: Yes, other than the big bad things we talked about at the beginning of the show every part of Otacon was just great Yep, like pretty much without question.
Speaker 0: So that's that's the thing is usually like if it was your first con right you're just gonna be like, oh man, this is awesome.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, this is awesome.
Speaker 0: Oh, man this right the thing is we sort of take all those for granted because we've been going for so long and They tend not to stick out to us and we don't make a big deal out of them.
Speaker 0: so we tend to focus on the negative and the thing is any.
Speaker 1: you know, anything that wasn't negative was totally awesome and In fact, I this was probably my most fun Otacon in years.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I know it's like in recent years going to cons I've sort of like been disenchanted with actually doing events at cons.
Speaker 0: It's only been running the events.
Speaker 0: that entertains me.
Speaker 0: going to the events You know I've sort of been disenchanted and I'm not too excited about.
Speaker 0: but this year actually went to some panels and went to Stuff and I enjoyed going to stuff and it was awesome again.
Speaker 0: So, you know that was that was cool and it made this Otacon pretty great.
Speaker 1: The other thing is that we actually and this is totally a non Otacon aside But it's hard to eat anywhere in Baltimore cuz one Like everything's going out of business because Baltimore is not doing so.
Speaker 1: well Nope, and to the power plant are full of jerks.
Speaker 1: We'll get to that.
Speaker 1: and the restaurant we wanted to go to was closed.
Speaker 1: Anyway, and three everything closes early and four there's Otacon.
Speaker 1: So everything that isn't closed or expensive is crazy crowded.
Speaker 1: You can't.
Speaker 0: even if it's not crazy crowded It takes forever to eat.
Speaker 0: So like every time we wanted to eat it always took way long way longer than it had in the past.
Speaker 0: and I'm actually Considering next year like for lunches at least just buying the food from the overpriced con vendors because Even though it might be overpriced and not so good It'll fill me up and it'll be done quickly and I can have a lot more con time and that is worth that slightly Exaggerated price.
Speaker 1: but the secret is to go to expensive places.
Speaker 1: a Friday night We got the front row crew together and we just went to the Capitol Grill, which is this great chain.
Speaker 0: It still takes a long time, but it takes as long as the Capitol Grill takes didn't take extra long, you know.
Speaker 1: Yep, there was no one in there but us and we had a very expensive awesome liquor filled steak dinner.
Speaker 1: It was great.
Speaker 0: Of course, you know.
Speaker 0: as a result, you know, we were in a rush to get to events that happened around meals You know and I think next year I'm just gonna eat lunch in the con, but I'll still take the time for the dinners.
Speaker 1: I think the fancy dinner Friday night at Otacon is now a tradition.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes I'm not saying anything about the dinner.
Speaker 0: the dinner will stay Yeah But the lunch I think I'm gonna eat lunch at the con next year just to have more time and not be rushing to get to events after a meal.
Speaker 1: You know, I didn't get to go see Ava 1.0 But actually I found out glad we didn't because the projector was screwy and apparently the concert next door was super loud.
Speaker 0: I also heard it was the dub which I didn't have any interest in seeing if I would have known that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so but the thing was, you know, I was I did want to get to the event at the time Before I knew these things post-hoc.
Speaker 0: So, you know, I wasn't able to because my you know, I had to eat anyway
Speaker 1: Yep, but I don't know what else really happened on Friday and every part of the con was great Yep,
Speaker 0: I mean, let me try to think of some of the panels I went to.
Speaker 0: I don't remember when these panels were.
Speaker 0: I Went to.
Speaker 1: the ones I really think about are the ones they went to on Sunday the Murayama the show the shot You girl.
Speaker 1: Yeah shot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I always said showed until I was corrected by shot.
Speaker 0: Yep Um, I went to this kung best kung kung fu fight panel.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: That was a great panel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, some people were complaining about it but you know what.
Speaker 0: I saw some videos of some awesome fight scenes from movies and There were ones I hadn't seen before and I learned some things.
Speaker 1: I didn't know and regardless of you know, I Went to the panel with Daryl Daryl Surratt.
Speaker 0: So we were sitting there and yeah, regardless of any other flaws in this in the panel I took some pause.
Speaker 0: I took positives away from it and I liked it.
Speaker 1: Well, I had never seen that, you know end weapons of the why and that was like the best fight.
Speaker 0: That was pretty great.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, I can't believe that cop and I fight.
Speaker 0: that was pretty good too.
Speaker 1: Yeah little too Realistic when it ends.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was that was a little you know, but that's what made it cool.
Speaker 0: There's a realistic knife fight.
Speaker 0: Yeah This you want to talk about any of the concerts at the con.
Speaker 0: I didn't go to any of them.
Speaker 0: I didn't attempt to go to any of them.
Speaker 1: We just didn't have time but from what I gather the concerts were all pretty badass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there were some complaints I heard.
Speaker 1: those can all be alleviated.
Speaker 1: most of the complaints where the people said a The concerts were too loud.
Speaker 1: the answer if you ever go to go to concert that's not like symphonic music without musicians earplugs You're dumb.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Just that's it.
Speaker 1: You're wrong.
Speaker 0: Well, there was one thing though.
Speaker 0: Is that you go to anime Boston in the big panel rooms?
Speaker 0: They have speakers at the front and speakers in the middle and that allows them to keep the volume down and allows people to hear The panelists regardless of where they sit.
Speaker 1: Why does Otakon fail at that?
Speaker 0: Otakon only has speakers in the front of the room.
Speaker 0: the result and they turn them up loud.
Speaker 0: So the people in the back in here and the result is that if we're sitting up front is too loud And you were sitting in the back is too quiet Pay for an extra set of speakers in every room
Speaker 1: our panels
Speaker 0: necessary
Speaker 1: in the Hilton on Saturday where it was very difficult for us because there was this crazy echo because of the really Crappy audio setup and Otakon is a crappy audio setup and all the panel rooms every year and they always have.
Speaker 1: you know What.
Speaker 1: it's a solved problem.
Speaker 1: anime Boston does it.
Speaker 1: just fine do it that way.
Speaker 1: and if the Union says otherwise Well, they just.
Speaker 0: I think they just.
Speaker 0: I think my guess is that the only thing they would have to do is pay DSL more money for more.
Speaker 0: for two extra speakers you have to in each of the two.
Speaker 0: There's only two large panel rooms, right?
Speaker 0: So four speakers would solve this problem
Speaker 1: trivially
Speaker 0: and I guess in some of the larger video rooms I'm I don't know what the speakers are like in there But in panel four and panel six just put an extra pair of speakers in the middle of the room and turn the volume down.
Speaker 1: The other complaint was that at the when the one idol gave her announcement like this is my last song Half the audience ran out of the room to get in line for like autographs and crap.
Speaker 0: Well, I think they.
Speaker 0: I think it might have been for autographs.
Speaker 0: I think it was also a swag line and it was very, you know.
Speaker 1: The only thing I can say about that is there's nothing Otakon can do about the fact that the majority of fans The anime cons are super disrespectful of Japanese guests in general.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're super disrespectful of just anything in general.
Speaker 0: It's like it's like so weird these people come to this con and I mean, I guess if autographs your thing That's understandable.
Speaker 0: but people come and wait in hours and hours in line for an autograph or a free swag and they put that as a higher priority Than like all this other stuff and I just don't understand it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not even that they're trying to be disrespectful It's just that they care about free like garbage.
Speaker 0: Yeah they care about someone signing a piece of paper or Getting a free piece of crap that they're just gonna throw away or put in a drawer and ever look at again.
Speaker 0: I mean more than they care about, you know sitting and enjoying someone's wonderful music or you know talking with someone or see learning things at a panel.
Speaker 1: the autograph I can understand because you get that couple of moments to like say Something like if you are the biggest biggest biggest fan of like Trigon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean who are you really the biggest biggest biggest fan of this person?
Speaker 0: more than anyone else in the world?
Speaker 1: There are people who are.
Speaker 0: there are but hundreds and hundreds and I.
Speaker 1: it's so weird.
Speaker 1: It is though I've seen.
Speaker 1: I don't get it I've seen evidence of it But the people who complained that like I was the hundred thousandth person in line and they didn't sign my autograph.
Speaker 1: What the shit.
Speaker 1: those people are just wrong.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right.
Speaker 0: What else can I remember from this cut?
Speaker 0: Oh, of course Violent movies.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: so as is the tradition at Otacon late at night in a lot they have one day a lot of video showing rooms and You know, they there's some that show anime.
Speaker 0: one of them shows classics.
Speaker 0: They always show otaku no video right away at the beginning of the con, you know It's it's a. the rooms never quite fill up all the way But they always have a surprising number of people in them watching anime, you know And I want.
Speaker 1: I didn't get to see all the violent movies I wanted but this was the best year for violent movies since Eachie the killer, I don't know since each of the guy I think since Ebola syndrome.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that's a different kind of best But yeah, it's better than last year in the year before.
Speaker 0: So anyway, we go in and on Friday I watched Machine girl light which was just a hilarious spoof on machine girl.
Speaker 1: It was kind of perverted.
Speaker 0: It was a lot more funny if you had seen machine girl and had lots of innuendos, but it was funny.
Speaker 0: It wasn't perverted.
Speaker 1: the crowd was enjoying it.
Speaker 0: Then they showed Chanbara beauty which I found out later was based on a video game and it was not so good at all.
Speaker 0: It was just a bad.
Speaker 0: It was a just a bleh meh zombie movie based on a video game.
Speaker 0: one thing that was good in it that I will say is that The guy who plays the sidekick was the gut was Kuma from the live-action Gogasen drama, so I'm a big fan of that guy.
Speaker 0: He's he's cool.
Speaker 1: I like him but while you suffered through this stupid movie, I wandered off drunk.
Speaker 1: Good job, but the thing is I ended up in the right.
Speaker 1: Well, basically I ended up with some of the crew and then our friend cat low water by with her friends to go to the Rave, so I just followed them.
Speaker 0: Oh the Otakon Rave.
Speaker 0: This the Otakon Rave.
Speaker 0: It's usually doom doom doom doom doom with smelly fanboys that are real crowded.
Speaker 0: You know hardly anyone's dancing except for a few people who think they can breakdance Glowstick swinging around hitting everyone in the face.
Speaker 0: That's the Otakon Rave.
Speaker 1: So the rave one.
Speaker 1: as I'm walking up I hear music and I don't believe my ears.
Speaker 1: It's the Ava theme remixed.
Speaker 1: Oh shit, so as I get closer, I look in the room.
Speaker 1: I don't see any circles.
Speaker 1: There are glow sticks, but there's always been glow sticks.
Speaker 1: But there are people dancing and having a good time to techno-y anime music.
Speaker 0: Was it smelly?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Wow How could it not be smelly?
Speaker 1: I go into the side room and I see what they did.
Speaker 1: They moved the lame-ass rave music into that little side room and in the main room It was just like anime remixes and upbeat music and they've kind of at least Friday night.
Speaker 1: They dropped that Minimalist four-beat like trance crap and it was upbeat edging on happy hardcore music.
Speaker 1: It was awesome.
Speaker 1: I danced until my frail 27 year old old man body failed me an hour and a half later and then I went to bed.
Speaker 0: So rave good good good on fixing the rave.
Speaker 0: Otakon is the first the anime music Yes, seriously, and also there were staff whatever DJ.
Speaker 0: that was double plus.
Speaker 1: I saw two different Otakon staff members break up two different circles.
Speaker 1: Otakon knows the score now good.
Speaker 0: Very good.
Speaker 0: Okay, so on Saturday the violent movies I saw oh my god Saturday was the best ever.
Speaker 0: We didn't get to see video clip.
Speaker 0: I saw the very end of video clip because we were at dinner.
Speaker 1: I was looking forward to video clip.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I from what I could tell from the ending I couldn't really tell if it was good or bad.
Speaker 1: I don't think it was good.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I saw deathbell.
Speaker 0: It's called deathbell because it was about a school, you know.
Speaker 0: So a crazy killer in a school and he would.
Speaker 0: you would kill people whenever the bell rang.
Speaker 0: So is the deathbell right?
Speaker 0: and actually I was expecting a you know a violent movie and it was.
Speaker 0: there were violent deaths.
Speaker 0: You know in this in a Hannibal Lecter kind of way it was very reminiscent of saw Yeah, but actually it was just sort of a good movie.
Speaker 0: It wasn't a great movie.
Speaker 0: It was just sort of good.
Speaker 1: There's the thing what you know sort of good in one way, but it was a little contrived Little bit it was.
Speaker 1: I would characterize it as the ending was supposed to be a twist, but I saw as uncomfortably violent with a Pointless twist and a confusing plot that wasn't that interesting.
Speaker 0: The plot wasn't confusing It was just sort of obvious I think.
Speaker 1: No the plot was confusing because the editing was just terrible and it jumped around all the time.
Speaker 1: You couldn't tell who was who and it just.
Speaker 0: I didn't have a problem with that.
Speaker 1: Well, no near the end like it would cut around to these unrelated scenes.
Speaker 1: But it like the cutting didn't add anything to the movie just draw.
Speaker 1: It was just like it drawed out the.
Speaker 0: it could have been.
Speaker 0: it could have been a little bit compressed.
Speaker 0: You know, it was.
Speaker 0: it was a little bit stretched out there.
Speaker 1: It was pretty weak.
Speaker 1: It wasn't worth seeing really.
Speaker 1: No, I think I don't.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't go and say rent this or download it or spend your time to see it.
Speaker 0: But you know like I was.
Speaker 0: you know It caught my attention and I was.
Speaker 0: I was relatively into it.
Speaker 1: I was bored and like sitting on Twitter the whole time.
Speaker 1: It was not that good But I liked.
Speaker 1: I liked death bell and was it?
Speaker 0: I would give it a three and a half out of five.
Speaker 1: I give it like a two and a half out of five after death bell.
Speaker 1: See, there's the thing.
Speaker 1: death bell was only worthwhile because it was.
Speaker 1: it was post seeded by black Magic.
Speaker 1: that was like magic to that movie.
Speaker 0: Uh, it was basically a General voodoo Like it was a perfect movie for late-night Otakon.
Speaker 0: It was some real doctors versus witch doctors.
Speaker 1: I will sum the movie up with the with the quote of the movie.
Speaker 1: I'm actually 80, but I look 30 because I drink breast milk.
Speaker 1: and then you get a uncomfortably long scene where you learn how exactly a voodoo witch doctor Gets breast milk and what he does to get it and how he used.
Speaker 0: the best scene in the movie was Basically the za.
Speaker 0: the voodoo witch doctor had these zombies and the way the zombies worked is they're basically just corpses.
Speaker 0: But he would hammer nails into their heads and when he did that they would turn young and you know alive.
Speaker 0: But they would still be zombies under his control, right?
Speaker 1: But they would turn his racket.
Speaker 1: he keeps selling the same decrepit old zombie to like stars, right?
Speaker 0: But it looks like a young hot beautiful woman because it has the nail in her head.
Speaker 0: Well, well, you know some guy ends up doing this young beautiful zombie chick, right?
Speaker 0: And when he's doing her the nail comes out of her head and while he's doing her she turns into an old zombie corpse and That is the best scene in the movie.
Speaker 1: That was I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think when he gives that woman to shave.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is what I expect to see at late-night Otakon live-action movies.
Speaker 0: horrible fucked up shit like that.
Speaker 1: It is the difference between uncomfortably violent and hilariously violence or grotesque All right.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about our panels on Saturday.
Speaker 1: So on Saturday, we did anime.
Speaker 1: You should see the panel.
Speaker 1: We like always do at conventions and it turned out the same way.
Speaker 0: usually turns out a bunch of people show up a bunch of people enjoy it.
Speaker 0: the one thing I want to say is that there are people there who had been to that panel before and Apparently they have confirmed that our spread of princess tutu is working.
Speaker 1: You know how we spread it some more like a surprising number of people not to toot our own horn Came up to us before during after that panel and said dude.
Speaker 1: I came to this panel again.
Speaker 1: You guys are totally right.
Speaker 1: I'll watch everything you princess tutu.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: It's the best thing ever.
Speaker 0: There's people who cosplayed as princess tutu and they came up and told us they were cosplaying as princess tutu Because we told them to watch it at a previous anime.
Speaker 0: You should see panel.
Speaker 1: Yes, there are pictures of us.
Speaker 0: I gotta get their pictures of us on flicker with with them cosplaying as princess tutu and they came to our panel and it was Awesome.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the best thing we got the picture afterwards.
Speaker 1: So, you know, they're like.
Speaker 1: will you pose for a picture?
Speaker 1: and we're like, yes, you guys are awesome.
Speaker 0: Our panel totally worked now.
Speaker 0: then there was a break and we sort of just hung out in panel 4 during this panel 6 Which is in the Hilton, which is great.
Speaker 0: It was nice and quiet over there.
Speaker 0: It's like this great retreat from the con You know and at these big panel rooms and we sort of retreated over there until it was time for our another panel Beyond D&D.
Speaker 0: now We didn't really want to run beyond D&D because it wasn't anime related didn't really fit into Otacon.
Speaker 1: I originally pitched it as beyond besom but Otacon agreed that yeah No one's gonna know what that is, right.
Speaker 0: So we ran beyond D&D at their request even though we were slightly reluctant.
Speaker 0: But we ran it and it was a great running of it.
Speaker 0: We ran it very very well.
Speaker 0: We learned, you know some of the slight flaw.
Speaker 0: It was a great panel to begin with and we made it even better.
Speaker 0: The place was packed and I Think we fixed the number one problem with the panel which is that after the panel people would always come up to us and say don't trash why you trash in D&D and At people just love the panel this time they didn't come up to us and ask why we're trashing D&D.
Speaker 0: They respected they realized we weren't trashing D&D and that we like D&D.
Speaker 0: and it was just so great.
Speaker 0: And the panel room was full and even though it was Otacon and I felt bad that we were doing D&D at Otacon It was great and and awesome.
Speaker 1: now the I was honestly floored by how many people came to that panel.
Speaker 0: I did not expect the room to be full.
Speaker 0: It was panel six the biggest panel room in the hell and effectively completely full.
Speaker 1: it was between eight and twelve like it was so many people and they were standing in the back.
Speaker 1: a bunch of Otacon staffers came in partly because I Told all of them if you want to see an example of what one of our real panels go here.
Speaker 1: So a bunch of Otacon staff kind of came in and watch from the back.
Speaker 1: Yeah halfway through it was great and The only trouble was unlike the rest of the convention center We're like you can kind of slip into those back touch like there are ways to escape from crowds.
Speaker 1: The crowd that followed us out of that panel room was unmanageable And we basically to anyone who wanted to talk to us and you eventually lost us.
Speaker 1: The secret is we will leave a room like that if there's no back way and walk until the crowd is manageable And then we stop.
Speaker 1: yep, so if people don't just wander off.
Speaker 0: We'll keep walking But if not enough people wander off we'll keep walking until we get to our hotel room, but that was an epic panel.
Speaker 1: That was amazing.
Speaker 0: also went to a Fred shot Q&A slightly before we had to do our panels And and I didn't get to it until it was close to over which was sad And a lot of the things he a lot of the answers to questions He was asked were things I had read online already and already knew But it was.
Speaker 0: it was quite excellent And it was very disappointing in that it was in the smallest panel room.
Speaker 0: that was in the healthiest Fred shot And it has.
Speaker 0: the room wasn't even half full.
Speaker 0: What the French shot?
Speaker 1: Muriyama Ishiguro all these people.
Speaker 1: we had ten times that many people in our panel, which is fucked up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, totally fucked up.
Speaker 0: We went to all.
Speaker 0: we went to panels with Muriyama Shot an Ishiguro, and they were amazing panels.
Speaker 0: we learned amazing things.
Speaker 1: Here's the recap in the 70s with Tezuka.
Speaker 0: yes Here's the recap.
Speaker 0: Fred shots amazing old-school pictures of him with Tezuka and other like old anime clubs from way back in the day Muriyama becoming an official member of the Otakon staff getting a t-shirt and bat and staff badge from
Speaker 1: very bad
Speaker 0: honorary badge Staff badge from Jim Valls and Ishiguro going on a big rant about.
Speaker 0: you know The Japanese government wasting money on an anime and manga museum when they should be spending the money to preserve old anime and manga Which are getting destroyed?
Speaker 0: Whereas you know he compared it to Disney in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Which keeps snow white in a giant tunnel so that it will you know be preserved forever.
Speaker 1: like one example Mushi to preserve Astro boy would have cost about three thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: digital digital preservation digital $3,000 an episode.
Speaker 0: they're spending like billions of yen to make this museum and create government jobs when they could be spending it to preserve Thousands of anime episodes and movies
Speaker 1: that well if we have time at the end We'll talk about those panels in more detail, but those panels are all great.
Speaker 0: Those are all awesome panels on Saturday and Sunday And if you go to a con and you're not going to the these kinds of panels What are you going for really?
Speaker 0: I mean it was just so sad.
Speaker 0: these are in small panel rooms, and they weren't really full.
Speaker 1: I mean Ishiguro.
Speaker 1: they ran out of questions to ask him in the audience.
Speaker 0: That's why he went on his rant, which I think was actually better than questions from the audience which sucked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus people always ask the same questions.
Speaker 0: There was a resurgence of L.O.G.H.
Speaker 0: fandom which all the questions asked of him were.
Speaker 0: L.O.G.H.
Speaker 0: questions.
Speaker 0: Talk about the for tax reasons panel that we didn't.
Speaker 1: so I was gonna get to that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but for tax reasons they did all like she.
Speaker 1: she she's a bombshell or I'm in your manger.
Speaker 1: all that stuff.
Speaker 1: Yep, the Pirates of Silicon Valley not Pirates of Silicon Valley.
Speaker 0: It's Community College DX whatever whatever it was called.
Speaker 1: something else though too wasn't there a subtitle?
Speaker 0: Pirates of something?
Speaker 0: Pirates of Dark Water College DX?
Speaker 1: yeah, but uh that you know.
Speaker 1: the guys who did venture brothers?
Speaker 1: no But they get.
Speaker 1: that was their whole shtick was that everyone thinks that the guys who do the venture brothers But they're not right.
Speaker 0: they have a similar style.
Speaker 1: But they gave actually an awesome panel even though half the panel is just showing the movies again.
Speaker 0: But even though I've seen the movie also showed there the final part which contains a robot fight pretty now available online Spoiled it.
Speaker 1: Oh, no in case they haven't seen it yet those guys are super cool And I want to.
Speaker 1: I want to interview them or do stuff with them in the future.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean they're friends of Dave and Joel Well Dave Riley and they.
Speaker 0: Emily knows them because she went to school with them And we know them from this and there's a lot of connections going on there We need to take.
Speaker 1: really I really want to get them hooked up at PAX East because I think they would go over really well.
Speaker 0: They would go over really well at PAX East.
Speaker 0: I agree plus.
Speaker 1: They're really funny in person like sometimes you have the situation where someone can do something cool like they have a webcomic Or something like that, but they're not really funny in person.
Speaker 0: these guys are Situation like Randall Monroe where he is really funny in person, but he's just really shy.
Speaker 1: yeah Yeah, but these guys are Dave and Joel style.
Speaker 1: funny on just in person.
Speaker 0: All right, so what else do you have to cover?
Speaker 0: you want to talk about the closing ceremonies and the feedback?
Speaker 1: We already sort of skip over a bunch of stuff and just kind of rush to the end here because we've gone on for a While.
Speaker 0: the thing is I don't think this really.
Speaker 0: I think we've sort of covered everything.
Speaker 0: I mean can you think of anything we didn't think a lot of interesting things to talk about?
Speaker 1: Like mostly it was things that came from the feedback Ceremony not the feedback ceremony the feedback session and the closing ceremonies.
Speaker 1: like one Closing ceremonies they they announced all the dates and everything for next year.
Speaker 1: They pushed the dates back a little bit And they showed the opening animation of Otakon again, which was again done by madhouse and which was again awesome.
Speaker 1: Jim Bowles was drawn as Java the Hut.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that's I remember that now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's good Yeah, and I'd say still like the I read the other one better.
Speaker 0: I think that by making it You know while it was sort of funny for us putting all those staff people into it because we knew who they were Right I mean that doesn't really.
Speaker 0: that's sort of like for the staff.
Speaker 0: I mean most of the con goers don't get it, and it's not.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's as enjoyable for the.
Speaker 1: It's cool because it's this inside anime.
Speaker 1: It is cool.
Speaker 0: I do like it.
Speaker 0: I Definitely keep doing it.
Speaker 1: It's definitely awesome, but you know you're missing the point cuz I think they're gonna do this every year from now on.
Speaker 0: oh yes But I think that making all the jokes like with these like the spaces of the staff Scott you're miss They're not.
Speaker 1: I don't think they're going to next year notice how the style was very different, too.
Speaker 1: I think every year they're going to change it up a lot because I agree I Didn't say they're gonna do it next year.
Speaker 0: I said that doing it this year sort of you know made it less enjoyable for many of the con goers who didn't get it.
Speaker 0: I'm saying is that I think like why does job without have an ugly face.
Speaker 0: I think doing it You don't realize it's a staff They don't know the staff thing.
Speaker 1: doing it that way was kind of this Omaze to fandom culture.
Speaker 1: because you look at fandom culture like anime con sci-fi cons like where these cons Really started in the 70s and that style of homage was like the thing to do.
Speaker 0: yes But including the.
Speaker 0: I'm saying that style of homage is definitely the thing to do.
Speaker 0: It's the same style you see in like the daikon animation including Star Wars including star right but including the staff is the part Including staff and in jokes like that was the style of the times.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: I've never seen that but anyway We've never been to like an old gaming con where they do yes regardless I think including the staff reduce the appeal of that particular opening animation for the con goer.
Speaker 1: So I think it was.
Speaker 0: I would have just you know, but it was still great.
Speaker 1: It was just a slight a slight complaint very tiny I don't I disagree and I think that putting it there was great because it makes that year really stand out.
Speaker 1: every year is going To stand out.
Speaker 1: I mean the first one stands out because it was the first one and because they had the exploding manhole covers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this one will stand out because it was all the staff and next year is gonna stand out because it'll be like super flat Or something now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe Yeah, you can definitely tell though that you know while the animation is great It is definitely the Madhouse B team.
Speaker 0: I mean if you look at what the Madhouse or at least they're not putting a team effort into it Even if it is the a-team.
Speaker 0: because you look at Madhouse a team animation and it's like whoa And you look at this and it looks it's great animation But it definitely looks like an anime from a few years back and they're not putting in you know the full You know full the kind of effort they would put into like a big movie.
Speaker 0: Well one funny thing Obviously, it's unreasonable to expect that I'm just pointing it out.
Speaker 1: one funny thing Mariana did point out in his panel because people kind of pointed out that Yeah, your shows kind of peter out or you know no sequels or anything like that, and he basically said yeah I kind of get bored halfway through any series.
Speaker 1: I just want to do something new.
Speaker 0: yeah He's like he always wants to do something new and he doesn't like doing sequels or repeats or extending something too long.
Speaker 0: And I think I think if you look at it You know Madhouse doesn't really do the long shows like the Dragon Balls or whatever and they don't do a lot of sequels either.
Speaker 0: So it's you know I think that's that's something to say.
Speaker 0: that's a big plus for Madhouse course.
Speaker 1: It was also interesting Madhouse's and their perspective because someone has you know there's that Trigon movie coming and someone actually asked It was like one of the few good questions at the con.
Speaker 1: You know why a Trigon movie?
Speaker 1: I thought it was very unpopular in Japan and it was okay popular in the US and the manga didn't really sell and all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 1: and His answer was basically that we're not releasing Trigon for a Japanese audience or an American audience.
Speaker 1: We're releasing it for the worldwide Trigon audience.
Speaker 1: It's a Western.
Speaker 1: Westerns aren't really popular in Japan because they're not.
Speaker 1: they're difficult for the Japanese.
Speaker 1: You know zeitgeist to wrap around there's.
Speaker 1: there isn't all the history and knowledge.
Speaker 0: And I think that's definitely the attitude that not just anime But all industries in the world need to start having.
Speaker 0: too many people are doing Targeted marketing.
Speaker 0: you know I mean even look at the way the advert the world of advertising is structured these days, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say we sold ads on geek nights.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: well I'd say a good large portion of our audience is outside the US right?
Speaker 0: let's say the US arm of some company They're advertising agent bought ads from us.
Speaker 0: They would only pay us for our US listeners even though they're getting the international listeners.
Speaker 0: It's just you know we're in a global world and too many companies They're still operating on a single country or regional mindset.
Speaker 0: And you really everything you do these days has to be operated on a completely global mindset.
Speaker 0: if you're making a video game To sell it to the whole world at once.
Speaker 0: immediately.
Speaker 0: your valve is figure this out, but Nintendo hasn't you know?
Speaker 1: But Mariama and madhouse have clearly figured clearly figured it out.
Speaker 0: I mean like the other and that's a good plus for them.
Speaker 1: We couldn't make it more palatable to a Japanese audience because then it wouldn't be Trigon anymore.
Speaker 1: So what's the point?
Speaker 0: and there is regardless of region?
Speaker 0: There is a big enough worldwide Trigon audience to support a Trigon movie about that.
Speaker 1: There is not a big enough Trigon audience in any one place But there is a big enough one in aggregate to where they can make this movie.
Speaker 1: that if they just made this like in Japan for Japanese people and there wasn't this worldwide audience or if they tried to like sell it only in Japan or try tried to you know Then package it and move it somewhere it would have failed or wouldn't have gotten done, but by taking this global perspective We're gonna get a Trigon movie And I'm really looking forward to that because I think Trigon is One of the better and more interesting anime out there partly because it's different
Speaker 0: even though the manga is bad.
Speaker 0: One incomprehensible gibberish.
Speaker 0: one interesting thing I did at the bandai entertainment panel, which is black and it was very unprofessional.
Speaker 0: I think it was actually sort of a bad panel because what anime industry is there?
Speaker 1: What's bandai gonna do?
Speaker 0: I know but there one thing I did learn at that panel.
Speaker 0: That was very good.
Speaker 0: Right is remember we saw sort of the stranger.
Speaker 0: bandai entertainment has that.
Speaker 0: that's their show their movie, right?
Speaker 0: And that's on DVD.
Speaker 0: I think now and they talked about how they showed it in theaters They're going to show the Eureka seven movie in theaters the same way.
Speaker 0: They showed sort of the stranger Which I think is very good and I look forward to them putting more things in theaters.
Speaker 0: and while I'm not sure if I like Eureka seven or not.
Speaker 0: I've never watched it.
Speaker 0: Apparently I asked around and the movie has is can be watched separate from the TV show.
Speaker 0: So when that's in the theaters, let's go.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 0: We'll go see it the same way.
Speaker 0: you saw sort of the stranger Yep And hopefully they will continue to put their movies in the theaters like that and we'll continue to go see them See all this cool stuff.
Speaker 1: and we got from these panels that no one goes to.
Speaker 1: these are the panels to go to.
Speaker 1: it's all The cool stuff happens.
Speaker 0: I know right.
Speaker 0: Where are you going?
Speaker 0: You're going to like that You're going to like that survived the zombie apocalypse panel every single year or that same lame shit Dungeons & Dragons when you could be going and listening to the director of Macross Legend of the Galactic Heroes and space battleship Yamato talk about.
Speaker 0: you know Like Japan and how they're wasting their money and such and such, you know, what's better?
Speaker 0: All right, where are your priorities?
Speaker 0: Yep, or I guess though if you're listening to this podcast, you're probably not making this mistake.
Speaker 1: Like how'd you mano you po was the last cell man animated show at Madhouse?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's an interesting thing to learn.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there you go.
Speaker 1: One little thing.
Speaker 1: and that their biggest focus was to not make it look like it wasn't sell animated anymore.
Speaker 0: He talked about how.
Speaker 0: you know, the newer season was, you know, digitally animated.
Speaker 0: but like they're like look, you know The cell animated digital animated looks the same, you know, so they proved a point by doing that.
Speaker 0: but they you know It's just not economically feasible to do the cells anymore.
Speaker 0: Take it's just more honest.
Speaker 0: It's just a lot of work.
Speaker 0: That's sadly unnecessary, you know when you could do it with a computer.
Speaker 0: So That's that's it.
Speaker 1: Other Otacon was fantastic, but there are a bunch of interesting things.
Speaker 1: I want to note one the escalators worked for almost the entire con and that is crazy and amazing.
Speaker 1: Yep, for the first time like ever.
Speaker 0: Yep, very good - they're sort of lax in bad checking.
Speaker 0: Sometimes they would be very strict and they want to see the hologram.
Speaker 0: Sometimes they wouldn't check it all.
Speaker 0: I could walk in with like the badge in my pocket.
Speaker 1: You could just walk in without a badge most of the time.
Speaker 1: It was kind of sad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they really need to step up the badge checking but Otacon This is the responsibility.
Speaker 0: the security hired security mostly and Otacon knows that the hired security basically sucks.
Speaker 0: Here's an example of the hired security sucking.
Speaker 0: I was in artists alley.
Speaker 0: The artists alley men's bathroom was out of order.
Speaker 0: There was a unisex bathroom though But of course it only has one toilet because it's mostly a handicapped bathroom.
Speaker 0: That bathroom was broken last year also so over entire year they didn't fix it right - there's a bathroom Right outside the exit to the artists alley.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I went out.
Speaker 0: I just went immediately outside of the exits like literally.
Speaker 1: Like you can see I exited.
Speaker 0: the artists alley went into the out that bathroom That's immediately outside the exit and then I went to the security guy and he said it's exit only.
Speaker 0: I'm like, I know it's exit only but seriously.
Speaker 0: I just went in this bathroom.
Speaker 0: I'm like, I know it's exit only.
Speaker 0: there's not really a crowd here right now.
Speaker 0: Just let me in dude, and he wasn't mean.
Speaker 0: but he was like, sorry dude can't you know, he couldn't just be like Okay, go in, you know, he was a security guy.
Speaker 0: I think it was a blue or red shirt.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: It was a blue shirt.
Speaker 0: I think he might have been red anyway But you know, you just he wouldn't let me back in.
Speaker 0: I had to walk all the way around and I understand the traffic flow issue.
Speaker 0: that should be exit only I agree.
Speaker 0: But seriously, I just went to the bathroom.
Speaker 0: There wasn't a traffic flow situation at the moment.
Speaker 0: He could have just been like, okay, dude, go in right, but he wasn't cool and he wasn't improvising.
Speaker 1: There's nothing Otacon can do about that.
Speaker 0: No, but it's just you know, it's just the Security staff would have not had this problem.
Speaker 1: I don't think we'll ever get a quality security staff at Otacon.
Speaker 1: I think it's impossible.
Speaker 0: I think they just gonna have to pay.
Speaker 1: I think no, I think they do.
Speaker 1: I'll bet here.
Speaker 1: This is total speculation.
Speaker 1: I'll bet the BCC has a list of approved bonded Securities consultancies and they all suck and you have to use one of them and they also maybe this one.
Speaker 0: that does I think if there's One that doesn't suck and is very expensive.
Speaker 0: I think it might be worth it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'll bet there isn't.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know what the situation is there.
Speaker 0: All I know is that they have to explore any possibility whatsoever of getting a different or better security.
Speaker 0: There was apparently because they're obviously not gonna get these people to do a better job So the only way they can fix it is to take the money elsewhere if possible.
Speaker 1: There is apparently a situation where a bunch of people dressed up as straight-up SS like Gestapo soldiers Yep, and they had perfect cosplays of this and a small a small number of people to come were super offended.
Speaker 1: They raised a big stink in the forums.
Speaker 1: But it looks like Otacon is taking the correct policy of not going down the road of censoring cosplay.
Speaker 1: That doesn't violate Otherwise very clearly marked rules like don't be naked.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I can understand it.
Speaker 0: The people were actually Nazis, you know if they were actually, you know KKK people if they're actually spreading hate or acting in a hateful manner at the convention.
Speaker 0: Immediately, you can just kick them out and no one's gonna complain.
Speaker 0: But if someone just happens to have a costume with swastikas on it or whatever, I mean I have to do megalopolis cosplay with swastikas.
Speaker 0: I mean that's a legitimate hit.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm a Jew Hitler.
Speaker 1: no Fukatsu is a Japanese video game.
Speaker 1: I can dress up like Master D if I want to.
Speaker 0: yes That is a legitimate cosplay and if you're not actually spreading hate or being hateful or anything like that or doing anything inappropriate a Cosplay that has a symbol on it isn't hurting anyone and it's perfectly appropriate.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing, especially if it's a cosplay.
Speaker 0: don't anime manga video game, etc.
Speaker 1: I don't want to dwell on it because Otacon seems to have taken the right position and said, you know what?
Speaker 1: No, we're not gonna do anything about this.
Speaker 0: Very good.
Speaker 1: Ah There was the in so-called fortune.
Speaker 1: Rick rolled the con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think it was fortune.
Speaker 1: Well, but anyway, what do you mean?
Speaker 1: You don't think it was fortune.
Speaker 1: There's.
Speaker 1: no it wasn't the staff of fortune, but that doesn't mean that's not what people mean No one really knows.
Speaker 0: the point is is that there was a philosophy of bleach panel that was approved and scheduled, but it was based.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, we can sum this up real quick.
Speaker 1: They don't want to dwell on it.
Speaker 1: quote the Otacon staff When it was brought up a con feedback.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we basically just got Rick rolled by.
Speaker 0: that They came and ran was supposed to be a philosophy of bleach panel But was actually they just dicked around and did stupid shit and gave out goodie bags that had like quote gay porn in them.
Speaker 0: And who knows what else happened there?
Speaker 0: I didn't go.
Speaker 0: I'm just repeating what I heard post-hoc and It was they closed the panel down as soon as they realized what was going on And that was a very appropriate closing the panel down.
Speaker 1: Here's the problem.
Speaker 1: I am fairly certain that after this year There's going to be a lot more of that next year at all the cons.
Speaker 1: and the only way around that is to have good people vetting out panels.
Speaker 0: But the thing is right.
Speaker 0: they can't actually vet the panels because they nobody at any con can.
Speaker 1: actually why there is one way To and it is to take a more proactive role and to solicit good stuff as opposed to just relying on fans submitting.
Speaker 0: Yes, they ought they have an open, you know, they have the industry submits their panels, but then they have an open submission.
Speaker 0: I think the cons really need to.
Speaker 0: you can't.
Speaker 0: obviously you're never gonna be able to look at the panels or screen them beforehand.
Speaker 0: You know, that's not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: That's impossible.
Speaker 0: I agree.
Speaker 0: What you can do is go and actively solicit panels.
Speaker 0: Go and say we want panel X. then go and look for someone out in the world who can run panel X. Say hey you we want you rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: We know that you're great at this.
Speaker 0: Please come and run this panel.
Speaker 1: Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Um, right.
Speaker 1: They were like come to our con.
Speaker 0: Exactly instead of saying who wants to do panels.
Speaker 0: say we want you to do panels.
Speaker 0: We want you to do panels.
Speaker 0: We want you to do panels and even better.
Speaker 0: We want you to do this panel.
Speaker 0: We want you to do this panel and that eliminates any possibility of rick-rolling or at least it greatly Decreases the chance of rick-rolling because you're not gonna get you know, no one's gonna be able to just submit their rick-roll panel.
Speaker 0: You're gonna go out and ask for panels from people and you know, you're gonna get to have a better.
Speaker 0: You know the condo have more control over the content that is at the con and it's just a better thing overall Even though it's more work, but it's not an impossible of matter of arc of work.
Speaker 0: It is an impossible amount of work to screen all the panels But it's not an impossible amount of work to solicit the panels.
Speaker 1: But we've dwelled on that forever and a few cons are taking us up on it But not every yep anime Boston solicited us.
Speaker 0: We had to solicit Otakon.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 1: Kinetic on took whatever.
Speaker 0: They gave us a whole panel room and they said yes to whatever we put in the con feedback session.
Speaker 1: I actually and I'm gonna do a thing about this later.
Speaker 1: I noted every single question people asked and 90% of them were stupid questions.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: Yes I have a. this is a feedback about the con feedback and it's actually also sort of a feedback about panels in general.
Speaker 0: Is that people don't know how to ask questions?
Speaker 0: They suck dick at asking questions and there needs to be some sort of question asking filter.
Speaker 0: Here are some possible question asking filters.
Speaker 0: number one Instead of people walking up to the microphone and asking questions Have them walk up to a staffer and ask them the question.
Speaker 1: the staff will write the question down on Paper and then well it when it's time for a new question Everyone walks up and first of all the staff will be like look Just be quick and you only get to have one feedback.
Speaker 1: and then for the first three quarters of the panel Every single person has like four feedbacks and they don't shut them up.
Speaker 1: if they let people use the microphone They need to literally just like cut people it's strange.
Speaker 0: I think they have no problem like being mean towards con goers outside, but at the feedback panel that to be super nice to them You know.
Speaker 0: and like it's like if that is the time to shut someone up like, you know They should have a but they should be able to turn the microphone.
Speaker 0: if you're gonna let people walk up to the mic at Least give someone the ability to turn it on and off.
Speaker 0: So turn it off as soon as the person has asked their first question and don't let them speak anymore.
Speaker 1: Is like my name is blah and I've been going to Otacon for X years and to this day No one has taken the Thunder out of those sales.
Speaker 1: You like my mix metaphor there you can say Better better than our friend Peter Olson who two or three years ago at the con Walked up and he was like, hi.
Speaker 1: My name is Pete.
Speaker 1: I've been going.
Speaker 1: This is my like 400th Otacon.
Speaker 0: and Yeah, I it's okay to say who you are and how many Otacons you've been to.
Speaker 0: that's okay.
Speaker 0: But then your question should be one or two sentences and that's it.
Speaker 0: I mean, but that's it.
Speaker 0: you're done.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't be sitting up there like explaining explaining and explaining and explaining, you know If you want to do that make a podcast like we do or you can spend two hours explaining.
Speaker 1: There's the thing it used to be that the problem with feedback was.
Speaker 1: that is a million cosplay things I think because Otacon runs the masquerade in the arena.
Speaker 1: There was almost nothing about the masquerade in this.
Speaker 0: so it was very strange because I mean Usually you expect a ton of masquerade feedback to the point at which we would suggest doing that.
Speaker 0: anime Boston doesn't separating masquerade feedback and regular feedback, but actually You know Otacon had barely any masquerade feedbacks.
Speaker 0: Most of the feedbacks were related to you know, things like Daryl Surratt's panel getting shut down the 4chan panel Oh my god, pretty bad security Etc.
Speaker 0: Etc.
Speaker 1: We've already meant you some of the entire panel.
Speaker 1: The most asked question was I'm stupid and I either didn't read the book or have a really ludicrous idea that Otacon could never do?
Speaker 1: Yep, the second most common thing was you shut down the best panel at the con.
Speaker 1: Seriously, Daryl Surratt's panel.
Speaker 1: Yep, and number three mail out the badges.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Yep Yeah, they really need to rework the feedback panel Maybe even a not having it at all.
Speaker 0: Because even having the feedback panel has you know has these various suggestions that go well You know, it suggests certain things.
Speaker 0: Pax doesn't have a feedback panel.
Speaker 0: What why is there feedback?
Speaker 0: Why should you come and why should there be?
Speaker 0: why should our panel close with on this negative note of everyone fucking complaining?
Speaker 0: You know, why should you even be allowed to complain?
Speaker 0: if you want to complain send us an email or come to the forum later.
Speaker 0: The con is not the time to complain.
Speaker 1: Well, here's one thing though.
Speaker 0: There's an argument to be had.
Speaker 1: Enjoy the feedback.
Speaker 0: I enjoy it too, but I'm just saying there's an argument to be made.
Speaker 1: But it's really simple to fix the feedback panel.
Speaker 1: one only let people give one feedback and they make them go to the end of the line to Before.
Speaker 1: if the first 15 minutes go through all the things that you know people are gonna ask and you're already aware of
Speaker 0: and just answer them off the bat and say if you ask any about any of The things we just said you're gonna sit down and you're not gonna ask
Speaker 1: Like people.
Speaker 1: every year people ask the same like ten.
Speaker 0: yes It's like we sit down for the feedback panel.
Speaker 0: We already know what the big think topics are gonna be.
Speaker 0: So if they would just address that if they know what they are - they know that you know This panel was shut down.
Speaker 0: That was a big deal.
Speaker 0: This is a big deal.
Speaker 0: Just address the big deals right away and then say if you have a question about anything else I mean seriously come up.
Speaker 1: There's the person who was like why don't you get a panel about X every year?
Speaker 1: account staff is like well We can only get panels if people submit him.
Speaker 1: If you want to do the panel, that'd be great.
Speaker 1: And then every year they say the exact same thing because someone asks the exact same question.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's like someone always gonna understand if you were not there the in previous years.
Speaker 0: if it's your first Oticon It could understand if it's your first feedback panel.
Speaker 0: I can understand if you came into the feedback panel late Regardless that stuff because there's a like a thousand people in that room who aren't you?
Speaker 0: so Send an email later.
Speaker 1: Ah We should just cut this short.
Speaker 0: I think I think we're done.
Speaker 0: We talked about the feedback panel.
Speaker 0: I'm sure this stuff we missed.
Speaker 0: we covered as much as we could.
Speaker 0: Episode is gonna be long.
Speaker 0: It needs to be long to sum it all up.
Speaker 0: Otakon is great Otakon.
Speaker 1: This was like my favorite Otakon in a long time.
Speaker 1: It was super awesome.
Speaker 0: I've been to seven Otakons is definitely in the top three four three or four.
Speaker 0: It might be the fourth best awesome people.
Speaker 1: Everything was great except the few complaints we had.
Speaker 1: However, if I have to stand in a three-hour reg line, I might not go back as much as I love Otakon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they gotta mail the badges.
Speaker 1: no excuses Whatever it takes mail those badges because Otakon is like if it means.
Speaker 0: even if it means like one less Japanese musical guest if it Means, you know, I don't care if I have to pay like 20 more.
Speaker 1: I would pay like 20 or 30 bucks just to not have to stand in line.
Speaker 0: In fact, you know making Otakon more expensive while it even might reduce attendance which Otakon I think they just really don't want to do anything that will reduce attendance.
Speaker 0: Like they're really obsessed with the numbers.
Speaker 0: I think it would actually make the con a better con if I raise the price and also advertise.
Speaker 1: I think if Otakon advertised they could get 10,000 more people, but I don't know if they could handle that.
Speaker 0: No but I think if they raise the price of the badge and Use that money to a mail the badges and market that I think it would balance out because with that extra money They would be able to mail the badges and handle more people.
Speaker 0: So there you have it.
Speaker 1: So Otakon 2009 super awesome, and I'm going to bed.
Speaker 0: Yep, the end.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has Everything.
Speaker 0: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.