Speaker 0:
Speaker 1: It's Wednesday April 8th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight a bunch of comics and manga and anime.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: We were having a little trouble watching anime lately since the boxy subtitles stopped working.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think in a recent update some subtitle stuff got messed up, but I think in a more recent update It got fixed.
Speaker 0: so I got it.
Speaker 0: Yeah I just got to install the latest latest and we'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: it was that most Infuriating problem where they didn't just not work at all because then you go you don't watch anime.
Speaker 1: They worked for a while and then bit by bit every now, and then we'd miss like one subtitle.
Speaker 0: I think it was dropping frames for some reason and thus because it dropped the frame it dropped associated subtitle.
Speaker 0: So even in the subsequent frames the subtitle wasn't there because the frame where the subtitle was supposed to be was dropped.
Speaker 0: So the other time never appeared.
Speaker 1: and but it's infuriating because you know Well, we'll miss a line and neither one of us will say anything.
Speaker 1: because alright just one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you think.
Speaker 0: sometimes the fansubbers, you know intentionally drop out a line.
Speaker 0: for example if someone's like, Ohio They don't put a subtitle in.
Speaker 0: not every you know, it's not fans.
Speaker 1: But yeah Even if you know you're losing them, you know, we know we have this problem.
Speaker 1: You keep watching because you can still like if you're an anime fan, you've watched enough anime.
Speaker 1: I understand it of Japanese To get a lot further than I would expect.
Speaker 0: but if the voice acting is good You don't even need to know what the words are Pictures and just the tone and you're good, but depending on the show I mean if it's a talking heads show good luck with the longer it goes on.
Speaker 1: However, like if I miss every fifth line, I kind of still know what's going on from context and responses.
Speaker 0: But if you miss a few in a row, you're in trouble.
Speaker 1: Yeah It got to the point where a character is like says something long and complicated with no subtitle and then the person responding says Yeah, what are you thinking?
Speaker 1: And I get that subtitle even though I didn't need that one.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right But then it would just get out of control.
Speaker 1: and one thing I learned is porphy's long and tedious adventure.
Speaker 1: Okay, it seemed I don't know I was interested in it before when I was missing all these subtitles and I thought something was going On but watching it with the subtitles.
Speaker 1: I realized that nothing was going on and there's like a hundred episodes of that thing.
Speaker 0: Is there really?
Speaker 1: I don't know how many there have to be.
Speaker 0: you look it up.
Speaker 1: No, I have no idea.
Speaker 1: All I know is that it was about a long journey.
Speaker 1: He did not leave his house in the first episode.
Speaker 1: So, I don't know what kind of journey he was going on to the outhouse and back.
Speaker 1: That show had all the tedium of Romeo's blue sky without the crippling tragedy to back it up.
Speaker 0: It might add crippling tragedy just not in the first episode.
Speaker 1: By the point we gave up on porphy's in Romeo's blue skies He had already had like every member of his family die of cancer house burned down goat dead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, does anyone out there besides us even know what Romeo's blue sky is let alone watched it.
Speaker 1: I'm sure Daryl Surratt knows Maybe I like Romeo's blue sky.
Speaker 1: I enjoy it.
Speaker 0: It's it's not a the worst anime.
Speaker 1: It was fun watching and I remember just every time things start to get a little bit better.
Speaker 1: Like I remember this scene early on where the house the farm burns down because the evil guy burned down their farm To force the family to sell the child into slavery.
Speaker 1: and you're like, all right the house burn farm burn down Father's gonna have to sell the son into slavery.
Speaker 1: This is what we expected.
Speaker 1: and then the dad's like, you know what?
Speaker 1: We can still pull this off even though it all got burned down.
Speaker 1: We're not selling you into slavery.
Speaker 1: We're gonna make it.
Speaker 1: Two seconds later father has like a heart attack.
Speaker 0: I think or he goes blind or something happens Forget but it's pretty much just the most tragic things imaginable.
Speaker 1: It's just like oh Yeah Tragedies, but at least we got the subtitles working and we got to see the wonder that is Valen noir.
Speaker 1: No great I think that's the best show this season.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it's not from the season That's not let alone other things that are wrong with what you just said Ignoring those.
Speaker 0: it's not from the season.
Speaker 1: Anime news for me.
Speaker 0: No, there is no anime news, you know anime industries in the shitter yada yada yada.
Speaker 0: nothing new, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I got I'm gonna do a. we're gonna talk about I guess a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 0: this episode I think I don't know but I wanted to talk about something that you didn't read.
Speaker 0: that way It is not delayed in its deliverance to the to the listeners.
Speaker 0: All right, but I read all hail Megatron I know but you did not read a drifting life by Yoshihiro Tatsumi.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is you realize how high up that got on my cue from when I first knew it existed, right?
Speaker 0: So this this is a book Yoshihiro Tatsumi.
Speaker 0: we've talked about him before.
Speaker 0: he is the father of the Gekiga, right?
Speaker 0: This is his memoir.
Speaker 0: So you when you read this right it like It doesn't have all the stuff that hit these actual non memoir comics.
Speaker 0: have you know, like, you know treating women badly and and dour society and all those sorts of things.
Speaker 0: it's just it's.
Speaker 0: it's very Autobiographical as a memoir is and he's still alive.
Speaker 0: Actually.
Speaker 0: I think he's like 80 something now anyway.
Speaker 0: So this book is actually gigantic.
Speaker 0: It's like an 800 something page memoir.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like 800 and something pages from drawing quarterly the same people who publishes other stuff in the u.s and it is $30, but it's probably a lot less than that on Amazon or something like that.
Speaker 0: and Like I thought this is gonna be you know epic.
Speaker 0: This is like beyond epic because what this does right is in the u.s.
Speaker 0: There's sort of like this this, you know comic book history in the United States You know that and there's.
Speaker 0: so there's many things in that comic book history.
Speaker 0: You know, it's you got Simon and Schuster making Superman and then losing the rights and you got the whole, you know Eisner and Eiger thing going on you get the Stanley and you know, Jack Kirby and then splitting up thing going on, right?
Speaker 0: There's all these things in comic book history that that comic book, you know US comic book nerds know about and it's all sort of.
Speaker 0: actually it's.
Speaker 0: it's almost like a mythology in and of itself even though it's You know 90% true, yeah, but it at least takes on the same proportions of like a crowsers legend, right?
Speaker 0: Right, right, but if you look at you know, Japanese manga history, right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there are plenty of people who know all about it, right?
Speaker 0: But you know manga fans in the US typically don't know too much about it.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: I know more about you know, the superhero comic history than the manga history.
Speaker 0: I mean, I know stuff like Tezuka came around and he was the business and then there was this gecky gun movement and Nowadays, it's you know, it's all that was quite a skin all shown and jump.
Speaker 0: That's like drag.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there were these Greeks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Romans conquered him and then super high.
Speaker 0: It's like you don't know too much about it, right?
Speaker 0: but you read this and Like this is like oh shit.
Speaker 0: Oh Shit.
Speaker 0: and you like I. now this has like all the business in it Like oh my god, I can't even begin like everything from when Tatsumi and his brother were like sending in little strip comics into Manga shonen and then like getting medals as awards for you know for putting it sending in the best comics like up to like dealing with all these different publishers and like You know having the publishers like move them from place to place, you know.
Speaker 0: and like fighting over You know, which artists work for which publishers.
Speaker 0: and you know, one guy was like, you know You know, no, this is gecky guy.
Speaker 0: The other guy is like, you know, it's like something else, you know they're fighting over which name to call it and you know all this kind of in all the different like Anthologies that they work it.
Speaker 0: and you know, I'll get my work into this publisher and I'll get it over.
Speaker 0: you know work over in this one and all these different people.
Speaker 0: and you see like the The gogo 13 guys in here and Tezuka is in here.
Speaker 0: The thing is Kazuo Koke was only mentioned once in passing unless someone in this is Kazuo Koke And because some of the names are changed like it's weird, even though it's a memoir, right?
Speaker 0: He changes his own name.
Speaker 0: It's not a you know, like.
Speaker 0: it's not Yoshihiro Tatsumi in the book, even though his byline is on the cover of the book It's like, you know a slightly changed name that basically sounds just like his name Yoshihiro Batsumi.
Speaker 0: No, it's it's something along those lines.
Speaker 0: Let me let me see what it is.
Speaker 0: Hold on.
Speaker 0: I think it's like.
Speaker 0: I think it's like Like something katsumi Aha.
Speaker 0: Yeah, by the way, that's the point is is that this is like so amazingly fantastic like in so many ways and it's gigantic and Like.
Speaker 0: it might be one of the best not just one of the best like, you know Biographical comics I've read because I've read quite a few.
Speaker 0: this might be one of the best like Autobiographies I've read or memoirs at least because it was interesting a memoir and an autobiography.
Speaker 0: What is there a difference?
Speaker 1: Um, you know what.
Speaker 1: I was about to make something up, but I don't really know.
Speaker 0: Well, I think you know, well judging from this right?
Speaker 0: Uh, I guess not.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't know but the point is this is really really amazing and if you care about Manga at all, even if you don't care about gecky guy or whatever, right if you're a person who reads manga This is something to read for reals like times a billion
Speaker 1: and we will almost not.
Speaker 1: almost We will be doing a show on this at some point.
Speaker 1: I got to finish reading Kevlar and clay first.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then we could do a show on that one.
Speaker 0: Maybe we could just make this the book club.
Speaker 0: it is big enough.
Speaker 1: I think we should.
Speaker 0: my that might work.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll see.
Speaker 0: we'll just we'll figure it out.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: All right, so, uh That's a geek bite.
Speaker 1: I have three nouns that have all appeared in the same News headline and the nature of these three nouns makes that all together surprising.
Speaker 1: now in the first Leonardo DiCaprio All right.
Speaker 1: All right now in the second Smap.
Speaker 0: All right
Speaker 1: now in the third ninja scroll, okay,
Speaker 0: I
Speaker 1: Don't I don't want to get into this because you know, the whole thing about movies don't actually get made and whatever but it Apparently one thing is led to another and Leonardo DiCaprio Wants to cast Smap in the upcoming live-action ninja scroll anime movie
Speaker 0: Adaptation.
Speaker 0: is that coming out before or after?
Speaker 0: Live action Ava live-action Akira.
Speaker 1: This has a lot more shots in life.
Speaker 1: I'll say this live-action Dragon Ball happened Live action Ava is a scan.
Speaker 1: That'll never happen.
Speaker 0: I'm actually cowboy bebop.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I honestly think that's gonna happen, too.
Speaker 1: I don't know Because these are situations where you've got people with money and connections in the industry who for whatever reason want these to come to pass And I mean we the cowboy bebop thing.
Speaker 1: Keanu Reeves Knows Watanabe and they have talked about it.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, yeah, no that was actually.
Speaker 1: that's pretty verified.
Speaker 0: So if a famous but basically you're saying because the famous person is involved that it's gonna happen Well, here's a famous person involved with your Leonardo DiCaprio.
Speaker 1: What I know what I'm saying is I'm pretty sure This is gonna happen or at least it's gonna get to the point where it was gonna happen.
Speaker 1: Maybe they'll do something and then it'll fall apart.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be tear if it happens.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be terrible.
Speaker 1: I don't think this is the Ava movie situation, which I am so sure is just a money-making scam.
Speaker 1: I don't think that.
Speaker 1: like that the odds of this are Slightly better than the odds of Duke Nukem forever actually coming out right right after the Phantom game console.
Speaker 1: Well Duke Nukem got so close the Amazon pre-order appeared again.
Speaker 1: And yeah, that was a while ago.
Speaker 1: I'm not even gonna bother with the rest of this article, but I found that interesting.
Speaker 1: my real news she's so absurd is that the Japanese anime TV rankings have something interesting.
Speaker 1: Lupin the third versus detective Conan kicked the shit out of everything.
Speaker 0: That's why is that interesting?
Speaker 0: That's totally obvious that that would happen.
Speaker 1: No, because it even beat us as I saw.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's you know, it's that's not a big deal.
Speaker 0: I mean sadly sign is always gonna be there, you know.
Speaker 0: So it's like, you know, it'll always.
Speaker 0: it's like the Simpsons, you know Doesn't have to be number one.
Speaker 1: Interesting was I I knew about Lupin the third detective Conan.
Speaker 1: I kind of just you know, I figured I'd watch it at some point.
Speaker 1: one thing I did not realize until it was put into stark contrast before me.
Speaker 1: Is that Neither's character design has in any way Accommodated the other.
Speaker 1: Conan looks like Conan and Lupin looks like a red Lupin.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what do you do?
Speaker 0: You can't you're gonna modify one of the other here.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna work.
Speaker 1: But as a result, it looks so weird.
Speaker 0: Yet it's the most watched.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean the reason is the most watched.
Speaker 1: I mean if you took that's like if if it was Simpsons South Park, and I don't know cuz I could to make it epic enough In America, I got to pick some old cartoon like Mighty Mouse.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right or like, you know, Mickey Mouse and Bugs Bunny, that's what you know.
Speaker 1: Well, we kind of got that in who framed Roger Rabbit.
Speaker 1: Almost almost it was that was the closest we ever got.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean, you know, it's you take Something.
Speaker 0: that's so.
Speaker 0: Lupin is so popular right that even though there's no TV show And I don't know if there's a running manga currently that they can make multiple TV specials every year.
Speaker 0: you know and people watch them and they did.
Speaker 0: it's worth continuing to make more.
Speaker 0: it's too popular.
Speaker 0: Lupin is and Detective Conan is popular enough.
Speaker 0: that is TV show and manga I think are still continuing sort of perpetually.
Speaker 0: so if you combine the two, it's a guaranteed winner and that's why they did it.
Speaker 0: and I think What really is that Japan doesn't do these things often enough, you know in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Anything like that I would like to point out milked it to fuck.
Speaker 1: I would like to point out for everyone who does not remember The Jetsons meet the Flintstones.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but those are the same company.
Speaker 1: It was but it was but it was still.
Speaker 0: yeah, but the point is, you know That stuff is all you know, if it's not two companies competing with each other, right?
Speaker 0: that stuff gets milked to all hell just to get the most money possible.
Speaker 0: and Japan with an ailing anime industry, I think might start doing stuff like that more.
Speaker 0: But if they do too much it won't work anymore.
Speaker 0: So you gotta you know plus things like that have always been popular in Japan and you know in manga and doujinshi And you know video games like super robot wars, right?
Speaker 0: So why not actually make an anime that say is like Gundam and macross, you know, they should go for it.
Speaker 0: That would be a huge huge hit.
Speaker 1: thing is what I'm curious about is Conan's got nothing on lip on duh.
Speaker 1: So how is this even a competition?
Speaker 1: I mean, it's red lip on to it.
Speaker 0: What are you shot him?
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: But I do have one more news.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's not much anime news, but Yeah, well I Noticed something interesting that I kind of want to bring up out there.
Speaker 0: for anyone who's curious anime news networks The only place to get my news.
Speaker 1: if you want to do a panel at Otacon I don't think it is going to be hard for you to get your panel.
Speaker 1: I This is totally based on speculation on my part.
Speaker 1: This is not any like insider information.
Speaker 1: I know sometimes we get the inside scoop from some of our friends at Otacon But this is purely coming out of my mouth.
Speaker 1: So I can't back this up at all.
Speaker 1: I don't think Otacon is even close to having enough panels to filling their panel rooms this year.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh Point.
Speaker 1: the first they could not fill them last year.
Speaker 1: That is why you saw rim and Scott do the advanced wars panel in a workshop room.
Speaker 1: They just they didn't have enough panels.
Speaker 1: There was a bunch of empty space.
Speaker 0: So I think the problem there was.
Speaker 0: they didn't have enough workshops.
Speaker 0: not that enough panels.
Speaker 0: Well, they they devoted a couple of rooms to workshops But couldn't get enough workshops for them.
Speaker 1: thing is they obviously were willing to put panels to fill up the space and weren't able To do that either.
Speaker 1: Yep So as a result gig nights did the advanced wars panel which actually It kind of saddens me how many people showed up to that and how many of those people seem to think that we were somehow In the industry or somehow new.
Speaker 0: so I don't know they didn't.
Speaker 0: they didn't think we're Indian.
Speaker 1: The questions they asked were questions that I would ask like the creator of advanced people.
Speaker 0: It's it's amazing how You know I've been to a lot of panels at a lot of conventions and it's like People who go to these panels and ask questions are people who don't read the internet at all?
Speaker 0: They just don't know they never been to go Taku, right?
Speaker 0: So if I stand up and say, you know, like what's big in the video game news right now stuff about like we motion plus, right?
Speaker 0: Most people don't even know we motion plus exists.
Speaker 0: If I go up and I do a panel on we motion plus people start asking me questions like I'm from Nintendo because they have no clue and I'm standing in a position of authority.
Speaker 0: I'm not I don't work for Nintendo or anything.
Speaker 1: It's it's amazing how much authority you get by Wearing a jacket and standing behind a tape, right?
Speaker 0: So then I say some things that these people have no idea about because they don't know the internet exists and they don't read blogs Even though it's common knowledge amongst anyone who reads blogs and knows what the hell's going on.
Speaker 0: It pays attention to the news.
Speaker 0: So suddenly I to them.
Speaker 0: I'm someone who knows crazy things.
Speaker 0: Oh my god as the guy knows so much.
Speaker 0: So they'll just start asking me like any question they have without any amount of thinking, you know Whether that's actually a question.
Speaker 0: I'll be able to answer or not because they'll have.
Speaker 0: so because as far as they're concerned I'm someone who knows amazing things.
Speaker 0: They can't possibly be known so they have no context with which to discern what questions I would be able to answer and what I wouldn't because if they did have that context They would have be a blog reader and would know everything and I would never think nothing to teach them.
Speaker 0: So if you want to give a panel right at conventions and sound really smart to the like most people just like read anime news network and then do a panel on like something that's In the news and like 80% of the people who come to your panel of you know You'll.
Speaker 0: it'll be all new information to them Even though it was just you know.
Speaker 0: You're telling them what you learned from anime news network like a few weeks ago.
Speaker 1: Don't really do that because we're trying to end panels like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a bad panel, but I'm just saying that works here.
Speaker 1: Here's the problem and that's why the advance or his panel worked aside from the fact that last year Oh to count did not have enough panels and we Kind of filled in for that.
Speaker 1: but this year I'm gonna read a quote from the Otacon panels application page Which they have reminded people exists a couple times so far Clarification about the maximum number of panelists.
Speaker 1: this year due to expansion into the Hilton Increasing the number of panel rooms and other factors we have had to adjust the maximum number of panelists.
Speaker 1: This is to ensure that we have the ability to provide panels and panelists for all our rooms.
Speaker 1: There is a limit now of two panelists per panel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there can be more than two but those people will not be compensated now.
Speaker 1: clearly they do not have enough panels and They want to fill out all their panel space.
Speaker 1: So they're trying to thin out the existing panels.
Speaker 1: They're trying to get people who would normally have four people run one panel Submit two separate panels of two people each and then schedule both of them.
Speaker 1: This does not bode well at all.
Speaker 0: a lot of thing is majority of the panels that had a lot of people on them were the kind of panel were like maybe one person decides to have one and then like all their friends like.
Speaker 0: And then it's like just the friends go in a blob.
Speaker 1: now see originally when they said only two people get compensated I thought this was great because this really weeds out the people who get you some giant panel so they can get a bunch of Badges and it really makes it that only the serious people would get panels.
Speaker 1: But now I worry that that's not the case.
Speaker 0: I mean, I think obviously it seems as if right.
Speaker 0: we'd like them to raise the bar But it seems like raising the bar might not fill the rooms.
Speaker 0: Well, especially because they have more panel rooms, which yeah, maybe a mistake maybe but the thing is they got more rooms And they're using every room they've got.
Speaker 0: so they figure and you know things fill up and people are sitting on the floor.
Speaker 0: So it sort of makes you know, I think what they need is you know Not more rooms, but the same number of rooms only bigger room.
Speaker 1: That's not so doable though.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: However, I guess or at least if instead of you know, you get the more space, right?
Speaker 0: So that way you still have the same number of rooms But like, you know say workshop one and two were next to each other.
Speaker 0: You can sort of there's a wall in between.
Speaker 0: I think it's movable maybe right.
Speaker 0: So you like move that wall and now you just have big workshop over there.
Speaker 1: You could do stuff like that, right, but even then remember it's all new space too in the Hilton.
Speaker 0: I know right.
Speaker 0: I don't know what that space looks like either.
Speaker 1: So it's a total total and I guess what's gonna hurt more is that Up until recently especially with anime cons and cons.
Speaker 1: We like like Otakon we would always kind of accommodate like we like.
Speaker 1: we did I think eight or nine panels at a Kinetic on ones because they didn't have enough panels and We filled in for Otakon last year.
Speaker 1: But our policy this year was to not do a panel.
Speaker 1: that isn't one of our awesome a-list panels.
Speaker 1: So I only planned on doing like three panels at Otakon.
Speaker 0: We plan on doing something else, but they haven't contacted us.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm still.
Speaker 1: I still got to push him on that front, but Fill up a lot of space.
Speaker 1: if they said yes I'm gonna tell all of you because we're not gonna do it at this coming New York anime festival.
Speaker 1: But there's a good chance.
Speaker 1: We're going to do it at the next New York anime.
Speaker 0: really to New York.
Speaker 0: Okay festivals away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're already scheduling that one.
Speaker 0: I'd like to do it at Otakon, but I thought we were gonna do it at this coming in your gay festival.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they they have trouble getting enough space at that one.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh of all things We're gonna do like three or four panels at the upcoming one and that's it.
Speaker 1: But we basically offered to take over an entire room and schedule it for the entire con Start to finish all on our own and we had all the panels and all the staff lined up to do it.
Speaker 0: Yep, so, I don't know if that'll happen at Otakon But if they need help filling space, all they got to do is say yes, and we can make it happen.
Speaker 0: They don't.
Speaker 0: just all you got to do is give us You know projector and a tech guy and some microphones and that's it.
Speaker 0: You're done You don't have to do any more work and you know, you can trust us cuz we're totally awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, nope.
Speaker 0: We've always done everything we said we do.
Speaker 1: I can't just indict Otakon though because more and more sadly The anime convention circuit does not I don't know accommodate us quite like the video game convention circuit does.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it just has to do with you know, the professionalism levels.
Speaker 1: Well, I think the sad truth is that the cons that are for-profit have a lot more resources to spend toward Accommodating the people who do events.
Speaker 0: I think it simply comes down to the fact right that Someone whose job it is to run a convention checks their email every day there because it's their work email, right?
Speaker 0: But someone who is doing a fan convention as opposed to a professional convention, right?
Speaker 0: It seems like these people just don't check and respond to their email.
Speaker 0: I mean You got her.
Speaker 0: if you have email you must check it and respond to it at least once a day.
Speaker 0: If you are not that you are not a professional and if you have a responsibility associated with that email Then you have failed.
Speaker 1: do you want to be a professional?
Speaker 1: because as we learned in master Keaton Yeah You want to be a master.
Speaker 1: to become a professional is to sacrifice your humanity.
Speaker 0: Even if you are running like the rinky-dink local con in like the local community center That's like gonna be like for one day with like three rooms if you're not even the chair if you're just like running panels at that convention if There's an email address on their website that goes to you for panel information.
Speaker 0: You have to check that every day and respond to anything in there The day that it comes in or the day after.
Speaker 0: otherwise you have failed and it's you know.
Speaker 0: Big conventions are failing to do this and that is the number one problem.
Speaker 1: I'll break it down right now.
Speaker 0: Nothing else really matters except for the just the failure to email.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna name names or anything but going down the list New York anime festival I get an email in like 12 hours from read.
Speaker 1: every time I correspond with them and look we're already scheduling The next two New York anime festivals for geek nights.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, New York Comic Con same deal like same company.
Speaker 1: Yes, they respond immediately.
Speaker 0: packs East is also the same come.
Speaker 1: Yes, but packs West also.
Speaker 1: I get a response like usually within a few minutes.
Speaker 0: packs West is not read.
Speaker 0: exhibitions.
Speaker 0: packs West Petty arcade.
Speaker 1: Yes, but at the same time they respond immediately.
Speaker 1: Yep, Connecticut We we don't know we went from Theoretically being co-chairs of the panels department to having not been able to contact anyone on the staff For almost a year.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I Worry, this is gonna be like last year where it literally we showed up at Connecticut Couldn't find anyone went in and just took badges from the badge room.
Speaker 1: We found a con schedule flipped through it and saw that sure enough.
Speaker 1: We had a panel scheduled And then went and did them on our own.
Speaker 0: Yep It's not it was not the the experience we had at the first Connecticut At least the first one that we worked right because there was one that we just went to right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, you know was they?
Speaker 0: we walked in they knew who we were.
Speaker 0: they gave us an itinerary Which still no other convention is done Right.
Speaker 0: That's one thing that that Connecticut on that particular year beats out every other convention ever.
Speaker 0: Wait, even the professional ones packs.
Speaker 1: However did give us a gigantic information package.
Speaker 0: They did but they didn't give us our personalized itinerary because we didn't need one.
Speaker 1: We were doing one event.
Speaker 0: I know that but I'm saying a personalized itinerary is like it's not awesome.
Speaker 1: But we were doing one event and we had the room for the entire hour before and the entire hour after to sort out.
Speaker 0: I know I'm just saying no one's done that.
Speaker 1: now they haven't.
Speaker 0: I said that should be done.
Speaker 1: anime Boston.
Speaker 1: I've actually got a lot of communication But that's just because you know, we work directly with Lou as opposed
Speaker 0: to you know, see we are so he's yeah We didn't go to his email
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we kind of skipped a lot of their process and just worked with him directly and he responded like right away.
Speaker 1: So enemy Boston props Otakon, I haven't gotten much yet and I've emailed pretty much everyone.
Speaker 1: I know I'm trying not to bother the higher-level class.
Speaker 0: The thing is like you feel like emailing so much is bothering people But at the same time they're not responding and you need a response.
Speaker 0: So what can you do except email again?
Speaker 0: There's no.
Speaker 0: you have no other option because you basically email that.
Speaker 0: it went to a black hole and you got nothing back.
Speaker 0: So you have no choice but to email again or email a different person.
Speaker 1: Yep, actually of all things Tora Khan the small anime Khan at our IT.
Speaker 1: They responded immediately.
Speaker 1: all the time We were all set to go.
Speaker 0: people are technologically intelligent.
Speaker 1: we were all set to go and then I had to Regrettably cancel our appearance there because I'm going to be in Costa Rica for the entirety of torque on.
Speaker 1: well Oh, well, yeah, but we gave enough advanced.
Speaker 0: I'm not really a big fan of going to Rochester It's all.
Speaker 1: I gave them a backup plan.
Speaker 1: So maybe Scott Johnson will run our panels.
Speaker 0: Oh Scott Johnson wants to go to Rochester.
Speaker 0: That's all him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he'll probably go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the status is.
Speaker 1: I worked I Extricated ourselves.
Speaker 1: Hopefully we'll be at the Tora Khan in 2010.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'll be ready to go to Rochester in 2010.
Speaker 1: I'd like to go back.
Speaker 1: I wanted to go back this year, but Costa Rica, how about 2020 Costa Rica?
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: so what was my thing of the day?
Speaker 0: I kind of forgot All right, right, right, right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Scott's going out of town tonight.
Speaker 1: So I had to come up with the thing of the day real quick and I kind of randomly and Scott wandered in it Wanted to know how I found this and what I searched for but I'm not gonna reveal that.
Speaker 1: but I discovered Hatsune Miku singing the Israeli national anthem and the I don't know.
Speaker 1: it was pretty interesting to hear Vocaloid which forces you to sing in a crippling Japanese accent trying to pronounce Hebrew words.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty good.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of sounds it can't make that it needs to make.
Speaker 1: yeah, Japan does not have that kind of sound.
Speaker 0: No, they don't have that sound.
Speaker 1: but then Scott said hey find the Italian one.
Speaker 0: That one's hilarious Really have like vah.
Speaker 1: So I searched through and I found this compilation of Hatsune Miku singing a whole bunch of national anthems and I got to say American not so great in Hatsune ease Italian great in any ease.
Speaker 1: Yes The Italian national anthem though doesn't quite beat the Russian national anthem.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: There's something sorrowful about it.
Speaker 1: I love it.
Speaker 1: Oh Well, you know what nothing beats the one-piece national anthem in Italian.
Speaker 0: It's not a national anthem.
Speaker 0: It's just an opener.
Speaker 1: That should be the national anthem of Italy.
Speaker 0: No, the one they have is better.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, okay.
Speaker 1: So what do you got for me?
Speaker 0: Oh, so I Couldn't find a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: So I went into an old Old place that used to get Wednesday things of the day from Japanese television and what I found was this comedian and he's doing sort of like this funny bit about you know, like taking a driving test right or driver's ed and You know, it's not Rakugo, but it is very Rakugo like in that, you know He's sitting in his little fake car and there's a screen and on the screen is showing you like what he sees out the windshield And he's sort of acting as if he's driving this car as
Speaker 1: I think I've seen this.
Speaker 0: all this stuff happens on the screen there.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure I've already seen this.
Speaker 1: I didn't know what Scott's thing of the day was.
Speaker 0: but have you seen it?
Speaker 0: because I just I just went to the TV in Japan and picked the funniest thing on the front page.
Speaker 1: I remember something just like this.
Speaker 1: I would think I watched it with Emily.
Speaker 0: that involve a Mario Kart.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yes That's what this is.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: All right, it's okay.
Speaker 1: So, uh, it's kind of just wing this.
Speaker 1: I read all hail Megatron, okay.
Speaker 0: So so I was in a forum somewhere a comic book forum and I said everybody read Pokemon adventures.
Speaker 0: I'm not kidding Don't be pooing cuz it's Pokemon for serious.
Speaker 0: This is the real deal.
Speaker 0: So some guy was like I'll read Pokemon if you read all hail Megatron, right?
Speaker 0: So I'm like, I've read a few recent Transformers comics, right?
Speaker 0: You know cuz I like see I'm not like a huge transformers fan like oh my god transformers Oh my god, but you know, I kind of like transformers.
Speaker 0: They're cool.
Speaker 0: You know, they're robots.
Speaker 0: the transform It makes a fun toy.
Speaker 0: Optimus Prime is the man Decepticon.
Speaker 0: all the other Autobots are lame.
Speaker 0: Megatron is cool.
Speaker 1: Shockwave is the best Shockwave.
Speaker 0: Starscream is cool except he's nice and soundwave is also like the second best, you know.
Speaker 0: Anyway, shockwaves burden check waves burden.
Speaker 0: Come back here you bitches you can't aim for shit shockwave.
Speaker 0: So You know, so I've read a few transformers comics I've read like transformers like generations or evolution or whatever that like where the like.
Speaker 0: they were all Steampunk II transformers and then I read like generation one, which is alright, you know.
Speaker 0: But they were all not bad But none of them were like good enough to where I wanted to read like a whole bunch more You know, it was like read the first volume be like, alright, it's transformers and then I'm done with it Right, and I've never found like an awesome Transformers comic that was so great that I wanted to just read it forever and ever until when it ended, right?
Speaker 1: They always seem to be either a fan service mashup of some kind.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm or just fan service.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, they just seem to be like retellings that are just.
Speaker 0: they're not super awesome Retellings they're just you know, it's just like stuff in the transformers universe.
Speaker 0: That's it You know.
Speaker 0: the same as like GI Joe comics, you know, it's the same kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: so That he said read all hail Megatron.
Speaker 0: So the things I can tell already is number one.
Speaker 0: the concept is that the bad guys win which is you know, awesome Which interesting too because what are you gonna do with that?
Speaker 1: The Decepticons goals were kind of get energon.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, all right.
Speaker 1: You've got it now what?
Speaker 1: yeah?
Speaker 0: And then second thing is I look I saw the cover of it and the cover was Awesome, like the cover art on this book is holy shit.
Speaker 0: Remember a long time ago.
Speaker 0: There was a thing of the day It was like if the x-men looked like this.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that was like oh my god I would read every issue of x-men.
Speaker 1: I Desperately want a large movie poster size just poster of that.
Speaker 0: So do a lot of people.
Speaker 1: I would pay a lot of money for that.
Speaker 0: I would pay like 50 bucks.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so the cover to this looked like that.
Speaker 0: so I was like, oh shit, so I'm like, all right I'll totally read that, you know, and you'll read the Pokemon.
Speaker 0: It'll be all good.
Speaker 0: So, you know the book shows up, you know, well actually I bought it in the complex store because I was in the city And I walked in the complex store and even though I don't like to buy stuff in the complex store because a lot of money.
Speaker 0: I feel bad standing in there for like a half hour and I'm not buying anything.
Speaker 0: So I bought it because I had to you know wanted to read it anyway and I agreed to read it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and You know, it was sort of the same as the other transformers books I read.
Speaker 0: it was good, but it wasn't anything.
Speaker 0: I want to read some more of it.
Speaker 1: Just it doesn't seem like it's going anywhere interesting.
Speaker 1: Good guys are gonna win in the end after the bad guys won in the beginning.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like all the characters are kind of the same static transformers archtypes Megatron and Starscream have the same conversation like three times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's Thing it has.
Speaker 0: what the book has right is first of all It sort of has a lot of balls to have the Decepticons just fucking like, you know Kill a whole bunch of people all over the place Like they smash Times Square, right?
Speaker 0: And the other thing it has is lots of like these cool scenes.
Speaker 0: Like there's a scene where there's modern f-22 Raptors with human pilots in them against the f-15s of the Decepticons, right and they're like F-15s, you know, oh my god, and you know, it's.
Speaker 0: it's like, oh, it's cool.
Speaker 0: But then is another cool part where people are hiding in a subway station and then the trains coming and like oh We're saved the trains coming.
Speaker 0: Oh shit the train transform And this cool stuff like that, right but Cool scenes and sort of those are sort of fan service.
Speaker 0: he scenes also right are not enough to you know, make an entire book.
Speaker 0: and I think the thing that really bothered me the most was that You know, it's like you knew the bad guys were sort of coming back, you know It wasn't like it should have been right the bad guys.
Speaker 0: They should have started like they started with the bad guys winning already, right?
Speaker 0: I think they should have started before the bad guys had won.
Speaker 0: then have the bad guys win and then have that be the end I would have.
Speaker 0: I would have liked that a lot more then to see.
Speaker 1: I think the problem is that marketing was The concept is the Decepticons won.
Speaker 1: if they start a regular story and then the Decepticons win People are gonna go rabble rabble rabble and they're not gonna buy it for the concept.
Speaker 1: Only the existing fans will just buy it because it's another thing.
Speaker 0: Maybe that's my old thing is they could have called it all hell Megatron and still had you know some I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I guess what?
Speaker 1: Yeah, what really bothers me is that for a brief moment when I was reading it I thought hey Maybe they're gonna do something cool and meta because the Decepticons goals were kind of stupid and Maybe they were gonna mean they didn't really have goals.
Speaker 0: It was always just good guys for his bad guys.
Speaker 0: I want power.
Speaker 0: We want a rule Cybertron.
Speaker 0: We want energon.
Speaker 1: That's the point.
Speaker 0: We hate Autobots We hate December.
Speaker 1: maybe what I thought maybe what they're gonna do is all right.
Speaker 1: We have these stupid, you know 90s cartoon bad guys with you know, these blame goals.
Speaker 1: What if we make them win and then explore the fact that they didn't really have any goals, you know What now?
Speaker 1: you've conquered the world Megatron.
Speaker 1: what now?
Speaker 1: and maybe you could have ended with Megatron and one by one murdering all the Decepticons Because they always needs more ruins the world, you know ending alone on some destroyed planet.
Speaker 1: Look ye mighty style, but instead Nothing interesting happens and Starscream and Megatron have these pseudo philosophical crap discussions over and over again that don't go anywhere.
Speaker 1: Clearly Starscream is gonna betray Megatron at some point clearly the bet.
Speaker 0: and the thing is it's so obvious that the bad guy.
Speaker 0: You know the good guys, you know our cons are slowly building up to fixing everything.
Speaker 1: You know the bad guys won and the whole comic was their decline and then it didn't end with the good guys winning.
Speaker 1: But if ended with just everyone losing that would have been great.
Speaker 0: Oh that would.
Speaker 0: yeah, cuz right now, right?
Speaker 0: It's like the Autobots are on Cybertron and you're constantly seeing them You know struggling with each other struggling to survive Struggling to make a comeback and you're also seeing you know The humans struggling to to rise up and do anything because they're totally powerless right again in the face of you know Decepticons without you know having Autobots to help them fight them.
Speaker 0: So but you see like, you know, they develop a technology and they go to deploy it, but they get smashed.
Speaker 0: But one guy doesn't drown and there he is with the secret weapon.
Speaker 0: He's gonna do it on his own.
Speaker 1: awesome I would just love to see that.
Speaker 1: There's no chance.
Speaker 1: the good guys Oh, yeah, and they don't win and then watch the bed actually would like to see.
Speaker 0: You know, like all the Autobots just kill them all just but not end of the Autobots.
Speaker 0: No more.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: Tamino didn't direct this.
Speaker 1: What do you?
Speaker 0: I know but that would have been totally like just blow up all of Cybertron.
Speaker 0: Boom It's all gone.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Cuz like look they got they got they got Optimus Prime sitting there.
Speaker 0: He's all broken, of course, right?
Speaker 0: But then you know, he's gonna wake up like at the end and be all awesome.
Speaker 0: Better if he was actually completely broken give me that fucking matrix back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's also some allusions to an Autobot traitor, which I think is Rodimus, but I'm not sure but that's what it seems to me.
Speaker 0: It's so like it's so lame ham-fisted.
Speaker 0: You know, it's not it's not smooth and deadly.
Speaker 0: I mean, maybe if the traitor were optimist and he had some sort of I don't want to bring him back at the end and then he turns around and helps Megatron and the bad guys win for reals.
Speaker 1: Okay, maybe a betrayal.
Speaker 1: I don't want to spoil other works we have read and watch and talk about but Optimus Trump Prime being the betrayer would harken to a lot of greater works.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is that in this first volume they didn't get.
Speaker 0: you know Even if there is some sort of redemption in the later volume There wasn't enough in the first volume to where I'm gonna get any more, you know.
Speaker 0: But what it was I guess despite all these that you know Criticisms I have of it It's probably one of the best transformers comics I've read.
Speaker 0: because transformers comics really aren't.
Speaker 0: you know what I mean?
Speaker 0: There are lots and lots of good Transformers comics just plain old good average middle-of-the-road.
Speaker 0: There are none that I can think of that are great.
Speaker 0: You know me which one is great.
Speaker 0: Oh Right.
Speaker 0: I mean even the original ones aren't great.
Speaker 0: So this one is a little bit better than good, right?
Speaker 0: So it's probably the best transformers comic.
Speaker 0: If you really want to read a transformers comic book, this one is not bad.
Speaker 1: But I think we should talk about something a little bit better.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's talk about good stuff All right.
Speaker 1: so of course we're gonna do a show on this but I figure it's worth pointing out now because if you're looking for something to Read you should be reading 20th Century Boys.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah pretty much what's happened here, right is Monster finished publishing in the United States, right and I've bought most of it Like I only had two volumes of it but then I recently acquired all the remaining volumes except I'm still missing like 10 and 12 and I'm waiting for them to send them to me.
Speaker 0: but They've also as a result because monster is finished publishing Viz is now bringing out both Pluto and 20th Century Boys, you know in English.
Speaker 0: So every month this year, you're either gonna see a new volume of Pluto or a new volume of 20th Century Boys on the shelves.
Speaker 0: So this is really.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be the year of Naoki Urasawa in America.
Speaker 0: There is you know, there's no question about it.
Speaker 0: I mean the Eisner nominees just came out and I'll probably use that as my news next week once you know.
Speaker 0: There's some more discussion and I know what more the books are and monster is on.
Speaker 0: there is like best continuing series of 08 right.
Speaker 0: So, you know, this is a Year of Urasawa.
Speaker 0: So we already did a whole show on Pluto.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: So 20th Century Boys is Also the business.
Speaker 1: I don't think we should like really say anything about what it's about other than it is a Naoki Urasawa Manga.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I think when you all that that entails I think we do have to know about it, right and this is this is basically the only way to summarize the plot without spoiling anything right is?
Speaker 0: It's a story that just you know, the the jumps around in time.
Speaker 0: So they'll show you the the end the beginning the middle, right?
Speaker 0: It's not Chronologically told and it's a story about these a group of Japanese dudes who are all friends.
Speaker 0: when they were little kids You know, they had like a little club when they were kids, you know sort of like a Boy Scout Sandlot kind of club and somehow it is heavily alluded to that later on in life.
Speaker 0: They save the world like for reals and Possibly through rock and roll possibly through rock and roll or maybe From giant robots.
Speaker 0: who the fuck knows?
Speaker 0: it's totally mysterious.
Speaker 0: and you know, Urasawa He is the master of suspense.
Speaker 0: There is no questioning that but it jumps around in time.
Speaker 0: Well, because it didn't jump around in time all the secrets would be revealed.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing it jumps around in time but not in context.
Speaker 1: is the way?
Speaker 1: Yes, the context of the narrative is all like throughout.
Speaker 1: an entire scene will always be the same But yet it jumps to different times.
Speaker 0: Yeah So it's showing you how the thing that happened when they were kids relates to the thing that happened when they were middle-aged Relates to the thing that happened in the future, you know
Speaker 1: The way it's done is very novel and it this is the one of the most compelling manga I have picked up in a long time.
Speaker 0: It's crazy.
Speaker 0: Like, you know, I mean Urasawa stuff is pretty great.
Speaker 0: You know the master Keaton and the the fashionable judo girl and the monster, right?
Speaker 0: But you read more and more of his stuff Pluto 20th century boys, and he is not the one-trick pony I mean.
Speaker 0: sure everything he does is always very suspenseful and has the same high quality to it But is not?
Speaker 0: he's not doing the same thing over and over again.
Speaker 0: You know, he every manga is different yet.
Speaker 0: Every manga is also great.
Speaker 1: Yep, I mean monster is a every up every volume you go.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: Oh shit Yeah, and 20th century boys is just more of a. I don't want to say anything else about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, you should be.
Speaker 0: you should be picking up all these urasawa things every month if you're a human being.
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus I just a little while ago read Pluto - Wow I am digging that.
Speaker 1: I Don't know if my favorite character is the one I don't know anything about yet or the other one I don't know anything about yet or Maybe Hannibal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think I like Hannibal the most.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it is about him.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I would like a photo if he was there.
Speaker 0: I Haven't seen photo yet.
Speaker 1: I Think something cool is gonna happen with photo so far if there is a photo so far every time a new character is revealed In the next volume there's two volumes.
Speaker 1: obviously so far that we have.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something cool happens with that character.
Speaker 0: Yep, so we'll see.
Speaker 1: We will see plus the context of what happened in the astro boy.
Speaker 1: I Speculate and I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think that it'll stay true to the original.
Speaker 1: I think it will too and it amazes me like to a degree that you don't really.
Speaker 1: you can't really comprehend That urasawa was able to take the story of that astro boy and turn it into this While at the same same time being painfully faithful.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean think of you take like was really, you know a great story but not a very complex or deep or fleshed-out story a very sort of skeletal story and Filling it in so amazingly.
Speaker 0: yet Still, you know, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Naroki Urasawa is a genius.
Speaker 0: People need to do that with other things.
Speaker 0: You know like other, you know, really sort of like, you know bare-bones stories.
Speaker 1: take like The transformers and make a good manga.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, just fill in all the blanks in the transformers to make it good Yeah, all right.
Speaker 1: Yeah We've actually talked quite a while we should talk about.
Speaker 1: I think one more thing.
Speaker 0: I don't you know a bunch of quickies All right Do you want to talk about some of the?
Speaker 0: it's a new anime season.
Speaker 0: you want to talk quickly about some of the animes we?
Speaker 0: Watched that are new.
Speaker 1: Well, there's that joke show.
Speaker 0: All right, so there's a show.
Speaker 0: What's it called?
Speaker 0: Charities daily joke or something.
Speaker 1: It's just a joke.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically they're gonna make 365 episodes.
Speaker 0: They're all really short and each episode is just telling you a joke.
Speaker 0: That's it And they're all.
Speaker 0: it's just a little animated joke and that that's all there is to it.
Speaker 0: The first one was hilarious the second one not as hilarious And I've got like three more so we'll check those out.
Speaker 1: The the thing that will tantalize you is that the watch the first episode.
Speaker 1: they're so short you can always just watch it.
Speaker 0: You're gonna spend as much time if you watch.
Speaker 0: let's say you wanted to watch all these in a row.
Speaker 0: The openers and closers would take a significant percentage of the time perhaps more than oh my god Remember when we marathon for the anime?
Speaker 1: Risky safety and we showed the opener and the closer with the Eiffel Tower every time.
Speaker 0: or is it the Tokyo Tower?
Speaker 1: I think it's the Tokyo Tower.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I barely remember.
Speaker 1: I kind of like that show But it was cute the openers and closers Or longer than the show and it became I don't know became this kind of epic memory of the anime club.
Speaker 0: Risky always reminded me of a kamako kamako.
Speaker 1: Okay, but if you watch the first one of these jokes You'll see what kinds of jokes these are and then you'll realize why we like it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm probably gonna just watch these into in as long as they're funny often enough I'll just watch them all cuz they're so short.
Speaker 0: It doesn't hurt, right?
Speaker 0: What else do we watch?
Speaker 1: we saw the first episode of cayenne which is the Newest moe show that isn't also perverted.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, it's funny.
Speaker 0: It's like I started notice something.
Speaker 0: There are shows out there that are actually like total moe, right?
Speaker 0: They're nothing but moe like.
Speaker 0: what was that one?
Speaker 0: Charcoal tan or whatever.
Speaker 1: I've been show time in show time.
Speaker 1: Nothing but moe.
Speaker 1: that show was just yay.
Speaker 1: I woke up.
Speaker 1: look at the Ducks penny shot.
Speaker 1: I don't think there was actually no.
Speaker 0: no But it was just moe right and or really fairies, right?
Speaker 0: And the thing is those shows.
Speaker 0: if you haven't noticed they're not very popular, right?
Speaker 0: I mean been show time is not huge popular as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: I might be wrong.
Speaker 0: Correct me But the shows that are popular that are also moe They also have another element usually a comedic element.
Speaker 0: For example Chobits has or you know, it's it's moe but like half the show is comedy and half the show is moe or Kayon half the show is comedy.
Speaker 0: It was a four panel gag comic, right?
Speaker 0: You know Haru he it's.
Speaker 0: you know, there's some moe in there, but there's also something else And I think what it is is that these shows it's the something else in them.
Speaker 0: That is the popular part and they just happen to have moe Which you know isn't hurting.
Speaker 0: lucky star was primarily a comedy.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: and look at the other shows That are that are popular in other sort of anime genres, right?
Speaker 0: Look at the robot shows that are popular.
Speaker 0: It's not the robot shows.
Speaker 0: the robot shows that are just robot shows are not very popular except among the robot fans Just like the moe shows that are just moe shows aren't popular unless it's with the moe fans.
Speaker 0: It's the robot shows that are also something else.
Speaker 0: big O also something else.
Speaker 0: Gundam seed also something else Right.
Speaker 0: Those are the robot shows that get popular because they're more than just a robot show.
Speaker 0: They're a. you know, there's something else going on there and I think that You know, we look we tend to look at an anime and look at its visual Genre.
Speaker 0: we pigeonhole it based on what it looks like immediately more.
Speaker 0: So you well, you know, but that's what you got to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at the same time like look at princess tutu at first glance.
Speaker 1: That is a moe craft show.
Speaker 0: It's not moe at all.
Speaker 1: It's got a bit of that.
Speaker 1: it's a kids show.
Speaker 0: yeah, look it's a magical girl show.
Speaker 0: it's not a boy show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think there are moe elements there.
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: I think the the clumsiness and the way she is portrayed early on.
Speaker 1: if you just Took some stills from that and showed it to people.
Speaker 1: I think a lot of people would say oh some motion.
Speaker 0: I think it's magical girl.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's moe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'm talking like just look at the art and take a bunch of stills.
Speaker 0: at the main counter The art looks like magical girl art.
Speaker 1: I Disagree watch Sailor Moon.
Speaker 1: It doesn't look anything like that anyway.
Speaker 0: The point is is that you know K on I mean, you know, it's not the worst thing ever But it's not like I want to watch all the episodes either.
Speaker 0: You know, it's the first one.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like.
Speaker 0: it's so formulaic.
Speaker 0: I see what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: So I just kind of I kind of want to watch like the last few episodes Just to see the outcome that I expect and that'll be enough for me.
Speaker 1: See I actually I kind of enjoyed it.
Speaker 1: I'll probably watch it idly and as long as it stays good.
Speaker 1: I'll probably watch all of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think if I was gonna watch a show along those lines I would go back and finish watching The one where the girl was like interfering code.
Speaker 0: What was it?
Speaker 0: Was it code something Cody Cody?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was a good show.
Speaker 0: Yeah I only watched a few episodes of that and I could I got I think I got a lot more of them.
Speaker 0: and there was Another season.
Speaker 0: there was like code each something else or code G or code F?
Speaker 0: I don't remember but I'd watch that before I watched Kayon cuz.
Speaker 0: that had a.
Speaker 1: I know I think Kayon had had enough subtle and actually funny humor in it.
Speaker 0: And you know, of course, I didn't laugh too much compared to.
Speaker 0: I mean it started.
Speaker 0: the episode started with the toast.
Speaker 0: It was just like toast.
Speaker 0: really I can.
Speaker 1: I can be down with the toast.
Speaker 1: I'll admit I kind of like the aesthetic of the toast.
Speaker 0: I can't.
Speaker 0: I like the aesthetic of the toast.
Speaker 0: But once you do when you actually do the toast, it's like how can I respect you?
Speaker 1: But unless I mean you could do the toast in the lame way, but if you go with the toast.
Speaker 0: But they didn't really go with the toast.
Speaker 0: It was just there.
Speaker 0: They didn't go full-on hardcore with the toast like they could have.
Speaker 1: I think they went on with the toast in this cut.
Speaker 1: I think it was a self-referencing.
Speaker 0: I was making a moe show.
Speaker 0: right the show would open with the toast right and the toast would be big like you would see.
Speaker 0: Like the show would start looking at the toaster the toast would come out the hand would grab it.
Speaker 0: You would see, you know, you would zoom in on the toast as it was dangling from the mouth as they run out You know to the street on the bicycle.
Speaker 0: You'd get the side shot of the toast swinging back and forth and then for the funny joke Sitting in the classroom with the toast still in the mouth.
Speaker 0: That'll be my boy show Like that.
Speaker 1: But one thing I can say high production values compared to most of the rest of the stuff we watched.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, because it's you know, it's actually a money-making kind of show.
Speaker 0: It's you know big monies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we watched a little bit of a porphy's tedious journey.
Speaker 0: I was porphy's tedious journey.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we watched a little bit of What was the one that was the school city?
Speaker 0: Oh Valenoir, right, so I downloaded something called school city Valenoir.
Speaker 1: You should just let that one be for now.
Speaker 1: All right I think I think you should all watch it.
Speaker 1: No, and yes, and I Think that deserves a show.
Speaker 1: a Dave and Joe Ling.
Speaker 0: There are a few other little things we watch.
Speaker 0: None of them were particularly exciting and nothing stood out.
Speaker 1: a couple of shown in fighting shows.
Speaker 1: a couple of shows that just didn't.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was one.
Speaker 0: It was sort of a normal showed in fighting show.
Speaker 0: another one was like a sort of a school show with a ghost.
Speaker 0: Another show was sort of a kiddie fighting show and none of them really stood out at all.
Speaker 0: Another one was at the samurai show right the eggs, whatever.
Speaker 0: It was not exciting.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: that guy was pretty big and the way he passed out in that boat.
Speaker 1: I kind of liked Yeah, but other than that that that show could be worth a lampooning at best.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we're still waiting, you know to see what the good stuff is this season.
Speaker 0: I haven't I downloaded by having to watch that new messenger show.
Speaker 1: I still have to finish Baccano.
Speaker 1: I got like three episodes to go and that was like the best freaking show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll watch that someday.
Speaker 1: It's on DVD I think yeah, and I got to finish watching a birdie the mighty decode - which I've been.
Speaker 0: There's more seasons of that now.
Speaker 0: I know you're in trouble.
Speaker 1: I'm happy.
Speaker 1: I like that show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio.
Speaker 0: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.