Speaker 1: Hey, it's Wednesday September 30th, and this is geek knives tonight the rewatching of anime.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Gave a co-worker cowboy bebop.
Speaker 0: today you give that to a lot of co-workers.
Speaker 1: I do.
Speaker 0: you also give them gonorrhea often what yeah?
Speaker 1: Kind of joke.
Speaker 1: is that just you know something else you give the co-workers all the time came out of nowhere And at least make a syphilis joke.
Speaker 1: you could bring it into sci-fi.
Speaker 0: Well, I was gonna say got a sip of herpes aids, but people don't get that.
Speaker 0: I Think they would have got.
Speaker 1: I think they would have gotten the joke though They wouldn't have gotten the deeper meaning of the gym.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: There's a far deeper meaning to the gun.
Speaker 0: is it for herpes?
Speaker 1: Seriously gonorrhea, that's what you come up with.
Speaker 0: it was the first part of the goddess of herpes.
Speaker 0: So I just I went right into it.
Speaker 1: usually when someone makes that joke they just say like AIDS Gonorrhea a little too specific there.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 0: It's funnier when you're specifically regardless.
Speaker 1: this dude You know my co-worker.
Speaker 1: He plays Left 4 Dead.
Speaker 1: He's kind of geeky He's he's getting into heroes right now, and he's really liking it.
Speaker 1: But I know he's gonna go through the same thing.
Speaker 1: everyone goes.
Speaker 0: I'm not a fan of the television obviously But I've heard people talk about that television.
Speaker 1: everyone smart agrees here.
Speaker 1: They say that like one season was good and all the other seasons Yeah, the first season is basically it's as good as like an average like pretty good anime like it's kind of like that.
Speaker 1: And then they do what they do at every show in America as they water it down and span it out.
Speaker 1: a bunch more crap Seasons mm-hmm, so you know he was complaining about that like yeah, I hear the show's gonna be crap after the first season.
Speaker 1: Why do they water it down?
Speaker 1: And I was like I got a show that doesn't get watered down and the dude already likes Guy Ritchie movies and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: so There's no way he's not gonna like cowboy bebop.
Speaker 0: There's no way any human being would not like.
Speaker 1: It's not a no true Scotsman.
Speaker 0: It's a. it's a perfect alien detector.
Speaker 1: you see Most aliens like it, so it doesn't really help you out.
Speaker 0: well No, but it's it's.
Speaker 0: it's like it has False negatives, but never.
Speaker 0: I mean you know what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: It gets sometimes.
Speaker 0: it won't detect an alien when there is one, but if it detects an alien you know it detected an alien.
Speaker 1: Well, I'll say this I mean like when we talk about Evangelion a lot of people say they don't like it, and there's debate about it.
Speaker 1: while I think those people are all wrong.
Speaker 0: No, that doesn't detect aliens.
Speaker 0: It takes stupid people.
Speaker 1: I Think he's gonna watch.
Speaker 1: I told him you know cuz just to be sure I was like watch episode 5.
Speaker 0: Just you gotta watch episode 1 first.
Speaker 0: It's far.
Speaker 0: I mean episode 5 is clearly a superior episode.
Speaker 1: I will say this and we did.
Speaker 0: we did watch episode 5 first.
Speaker 0: however we watched episode 5 Already being anime type people.
Speaker 0: I think episode 1 is far more accessible to the general.
Speaker 1: I would argue that it depends.
Speaker 1: you can.
Speaker 1: Every different person has to watch a different episode of cowboy bebop first if you were getting them into anime from nothing.
Speaker 1: Some people are episode 5 kinds of people.
Speaker 1: some people are episode 1.
Speaker 0: I think most people are episode 1 kind of people.
Speaker 1: some people are episode 2 kinds of people.
Speaker 0: no kids mostly Yeah, but episode 1 I think is the as the widest appeal thing is.
Speaker 0: I think you know pretty much straight-up action western adventure that Everyone can dig with guns and fighting.
Speaker 1: There's not so much gun in the first episode as there is good kung-fu.
Speaker 0: No, there's a good gun in the in the in the bar.
Speaker 1: there is it's okay.
Speaker 0: And then there's the kung-fu outside in the.
Speaker 1: regardless, I know what's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: He's gonna watch episode 5 and go holy shit.
Speaker 1: He's gonna watch the rest of the DVD.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna give him the box set and then I'm gonna give him standalone complex And then we're gonna go down this room have standalone complex.
Speaker 1: I ordered it.
Speaker 1: I'm cheap on Amazon And you know what cheap was it.
Speaker 1: it was $55.
Speaker 1: That's a lot.
Speaker 1: You know what it's worth it.
Speaker 1: That shows just too great.
Speaker 0: I know I gotta watch it again.
Speaker 1: I know we'll watch it again together with the wine cellar.
Speaker 0: Oh, I forgot to tell you when we were at that Italian restaurant in the city Downstairs was like the fanciest fans.
Speaker 1: You did tell me and I said when you went down there Did you think about that fan service the episode with Arimaki in the wine cellar?
Speaker 0: Did you go?
Speaker 0: you should have gone down to see the wine cellar?
Speaker 1: I should have anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, oh my god.
Speaker 1: You know I say this a lot, but I gotta say it again.
Speaker 1: I like anime.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of good anime.
Speaker 1: I've seen most of the good anime and or I've seen.
Speaker 0: if I haven't seen an anime I've seen one like it, but I mean that you know getting different moods different kinds of anime.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you're in the mood for that late night Always in the mood for another ghost in the shell standalone complex type show and there aren't enough of them.
Speaker 1: the other day You know I was working on something And I just in the on-demand put on like a random episode of standalone complex And it was even the dub and it was just some random episode.
Speaker 1: wasn't even that good of an episode.
Speaker 1: That is the show I want to watch right now.
Speaker 0: I want to watch the boxing episode anyway.
Speaker 0: Ah let's That's.
Speaker 1: he got any got any news?
Speaker 0: Well you see it's been a while since we did a Wednesday show or we forgot this news.
Speaker 0: on the last Wednesday show I'm not sure, but there was a gigantic Wednesday news Epic proportions Wednesday news that the Walt Disney corporation purchased the Marvel corporation.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what to do about that.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 1: it is one of those things where I heard about it.
Speaker 1: I heard rumors, but I hear rumors about everything.
Speaker 1: I ignored them when it actually happened.
Speaker 1: all the first thing I thought was that's a joke and then the second I thought someone's obviously hoaxed everybody and the third was really.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know it's like.
Speaker 0: the thing is.
Speaker 0: it's like I don't.
Speaker 0: there's just so much going on there.
Speaker 0: It's like I don't know what to say about it.
Speaker 0: really.
Speaker 1: we have to do like a whole show on it But we got to wait and see what happens.
Speaker 0: right the thing is is that first of all I don't think anything is gonna Happen in the short term.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be just same business as usual in the short term right.
Speaker 0: the only thing It's gonna happen the short term is stock market shit, right?
Speaker 0: In the long term.
Speaker 0: I know a lot of nerds out there are worried about the Marvel comics.
Speaker 0: It's gonna happen in the Marvel comics.
Speaker 0: I don't think they're gonna do anything with the Marvel come.
Speaker 1: not yet I think I see I have this vague idea of what I think they're going to do really is Poached bit by bit all the intellectual property of Marvel to make like feature films.
Speaker 0: well No, they're just gonna continue the Marvel filmmaking as it is and just get all the money out of it Which is how they do?
Speaker 0: The same way that Pixar just keeps going about its business making its hot y'all movies and Disney just gets all the money.
Speaker 1: I think the biggest change is going to be that's gonna come out of this is I think They're going to use like the infrastructure of Marvel like all that stuff, and they're going to have Lots and lots of comics made about Disney stuff that are really just promotional material because doesn't cost them that much to make it in House.
Speaker 0: I don't think they'll do that.
Speaker 1: I think they already have.
Speaker 0: you know the Disney comics are currently being done by boom studios.
Speaker 0: They'll probably just wait for the boom studios contract to run out eventually when it does and then they'll move all You know the duck whatever comics to just have Marvel print them instead, but the same people doing them You know I don't.
Speaker 0: I don't really foresee like a big any big moves.
Speaker 0: They're not.
Speaker 0: they're too big a corporation.
Speaker 0: They're too dumb and unwieldy.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna do anything.
Speaker 0: That's agile or clever or a big chain.
Speaker 1: It's sad too because they're a big enough company.
Speaker 1: They have so much money.
Speaker 1: basically the amount of money Marvel makes as far as I can gather is Like not even a blip on the radar of Disney over.
Speaker 0: well Here's something real interesting right?
Speaker 0: think about this.
Speaker 0: they bought Marvel for like four billion dollars right?
Speaker 0: I read recently that Adobe bought this company Omniture Which is a web stat company for two billion dollars.
Speaker 0: that means if that Omniture guy who sold Omniture could have bought half of Marvel right Spider-man is pretty big, but spider-man is like maybe 40% of Marvel.
Speaker 0: that means he could have traded his web stat company for Spider-man, what would you do with spider-man?
Speaker 0: I would rather have spider-man than a web stat company.
Speaker 1: I tell you that much, but what are you gonna do with spider-man?
Speaker 1: make some comics well first?
Speaker 0: I would like you know I would take all the Merchandise right - I would start the comic over from zero.
Speaker 1: now I would do the same one pissed off all the fanboys.
Speaker 1: I would milk the merchandise to a degree that would make grown men cry absolutely.
Speaker 0: I would also make a lot more clever merchandise than they have made in the past, so I would make a spider-man Everything oh yeah, and I would make sure that there was quality Spider-man on TV around the world.
Speaker 1: first I would like have this plot like I'd commissioned internally some secret plot that led up to spider-man like dying and like and then After I made enough money to you know make it worth it.
Speaker 1: I would public domain spider-man see now I would be much more of a creative commons spider-man.
Speaker 0: something like that be awesome of a jerk about it.
Speaker 1: to make money I would definitely definitely Compromise on open-source.
Speaker 1: you know whatever to make money I would.
Speaker 0: but the thing is I've already made two billion dollars.
Speaker 0: I saved enough left over.
Speaker 0: I don't need to make more money.
Speaker 1: I'd make more money and I humor all the world's problems that my own space program.
Speaker 0: The thing is if I was gonna solve the world's problems I wouldn't use the two billion dollars from selling my web stack company to buy spider-man.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying spider-man could generate more than two billion dollars pretty handily.
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: I think I bought all of Marvel for four.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I mean what you know.
Speaker 1: all the merchandising all that I have the crazy like the gigantic like oh my god They killed spider-man for serious, and then I make the further like big new all this press.
Speaker 1: Just I'd make all the spider-man price.
Speaker 1: the next thing I do after that is Publicly like fire, but I wouldn't really fire like it.
Speaker 1: he paying him under the covers fire everyone involved in spider-man and act like yeah He's dead.
Speaker 1: Why would we make more comics?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I'd wait like six months, and then I'd be like you know what we're bringing him back with a 100% reboot, and it is no longer tied to Marvel in any way.
Speaker 1: there is no continuity.
Speaker 1: This is a completely separate brand new fuck all you fanboys universe which again would generate crazy Bad press which means good press because this thing is bad press.
Speaker 1: yep, and then I make like a thousand spider-man movies.
Speaker 0: That's what ultimate spider-man is.
Speaker 0: is they started it over again.
Speaker 0: The thing is they started it over again a long time ago already was years ago already, so they built up cruft again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like it's not it is.
Speaker 1: It's weird.
Speaker 1: superheroes are like ships at sea.
Speaker 1: They know if they're out there too long.
Speaker 1: they get barnacles all over their asses, and you got a periodically I don't know.
Speaker 1: kill him and get all the barnacles up.
Speaker 1: my analogy breaks down there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's all right.
Speaker 0: anyway This is too much to say Right now.
Speaker 0: it's too much to say about this.
Speaker 0: It's crazy.
Speaker 0: really nothing's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: nothing super big.
Speaker 0: It's nothing that anyone any Disney or Marvel.
Speaker 1: We've made.
Speaker 1: our you know our wild claims what we would do and we Cannot really make any good predictions other than nothing's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: Everything's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: I don't know nothing's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: I think not for years and years.
Speaker 1: I think we would be in a better position if we wait it until something happens and then talk about.
Speaker 0: I think that is The way to go, but it's gonna be years many years.
Speaker 1: We'll see we'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: Yep it the thing is I Don't care Necessarily.
Speaker 0: oh, you know what's gonna happen in the short term.
Speaker 0: all the Marvel employees again I've like changed their insurance and do all this HR paperwork, and it depends depends on what kind of redundancy.
Speaker 0: No, I'm sure there are.
Speaker 0: cuz I saw some tweets from some Marvel people.
Speaker 0: They're like moving offices, and you know It's that kind of thing.
Speaker 1: so we were at the New York anime festival over the weekend.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna do a whole show on it But there are newsworthy noteworthy items from it.
Speaker 0: a lot of mangas were licensed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we should start with the the bad first because I always hate to talk about just the bad stuff in a convention.
Speaker 1: But there was one really really bad thing at the New York anime festival And you said thing is it came out of a really good thing.
Speaker 1: I won't dignify that with comment, so They got to me.
Speaker 1: No you know kill them all to me.
Speaker 1: No Gundam to me.
Speaker 0: no the creator of Gundam period the guy areas and they obviously wouldn't say that he was.
Speaker 0: you know He said he did it.
Speaker 0: of course He did it with help, but I know a lot of people involved in New York.
Speaker 1: anime festival is nuts and independently of that I know a lot of them are very smart, and they did like the right thing.
Speaker 1: they got to me No, and they made him the keynote speaker very good a keynote.
Speaker 0: yay Well attended.
Speaker 1: They made a big deal about it.
Speaker 1: more people showed up to that keynote then showed up to like Ishiguro anything at Otakon.
Speaker 1: yeah very good job anime festival, and it was all set.
Speaker 1: it was super like and you know They had a problem were like a lot more people lined up than even they expected.
Speaker 1: so they moved it into the biggest room They had like.
Speaker 1: they did everything they could do to deal with the situation.
Speaker 1: all these people come in they got the cameras and everything And I don't know who the guy was that they had to translate for him, but the dude did not speak Japanese.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they had a translator who basically couldn't translate at all.
Speaker 0: like it started out like he was going to have a professional translator.
Speaker 1: People like the dude was doing pretty badly and Emily's sitting with us And she's like that's not what Tamino said.
Speaker 1: and so she starts like whispering in our ears into the real Translation.
Speaker 1: and like as this is going on the audience is grumbling more and more because Tamino We can tell that he didn't know what he was doing.
Speaker 1: because Tamino would say like this very long thing and Emily would translate it.
Speaker 1: It was this really insightful like comment and the translator would translate in like this one Kurt sentence Yeah.
Speaker 1: And at one point like Tamino said a bunch and the translator paused for a while and said something really Kurt.
Speaker 1: And then Tamino like looks at him with these eyes of you didn't translate me for shade.
Speaker 0: Yeah like Tamino didn't speak English, but you don't need to speak English to know when the translator is fail.
Speaker 1: so finally I you know he had all his staff up there and finally one of his staffers this lady and While it may have been slightly unprofessional.
Speaker 1: I think it was warranted.
Speaker 1: She basically just said in English to the crowd.
Speaker 1: I would just like to note that we will have the proper translation online and available for everyone later.
Speaker 0: Oh Snap.
Speaker 1: and then the translator guy gets all pissy and starts arguing with her and I couldn't see the conversation.
Speaker 1: but he's like me me me me me and she smacks him the fuck down.
Speaker 1: and Basically, eventually they just had him shut up and he sat there quietly not talking for the rest of the keynote While all of the staff up there who obviously were not ready to translate and are not professional translator Did the best they could.
Speaker 0: thing is they had this guy up there who wrote some book and lived in Japan And you know he lived in like Tokyo and New York or something.
Speaker 0: and I'm like why did that guy translate like?
Speaker 0: he was acting Like?
Speaker 0: he was like the emcee even though no one cared about him whatsoever and he was sorta a. but If he lives in Japan, shouldn't he know Japanese?
Speaker 1: Pointed out.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's one thing to be able to translate It's another thing to be able to translate on the spot in front of an audience, you know It's not.
Speaker 0: even if he did it slowly if it was correct, it would have been better.
Speaker 0: secondly He would Tamina was giving a prepared speech.
Speaker 0: when someone's giving a prepared speech.
Speaker 0: You can have the translation already done in advance Yes, and someone can just read it.
Speaker 0: hint all of you need a translator.
Speaker 1: when we we've done this sort of though It's very good to have one.
Speaker 1: We've done it.
Speaker 1: I mean it depends.
Speaker 1: I don't know how prepared his speech was and how much he gave them at a time But it is a common trick if you're doing a very staged event where you know Someone's giving a so-called impromptu speech, but really like you've prepared everything ahead of time.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: You just translate everything ahead of time.
Speaker 1: That's how the whole industry does it and then you still need a translator.
Speaker 0: though If you know people any if he says something that's not in the script or what?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the worst thing was you know Emily was just translating for us and What he was saying was great.
Speaker 1: His message was basically look you fanboys.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna talk about your fanboy stuff I'm gonna talk about like what it really takes and it was really insightful and he yeah I was surprised like you expect Tamino to be one of those crazy dudes, right?
Speaker 0: But really he was just like all you know, some of the other anime creators were.
Speaker 0: really all he cared about was film, right?
Speaker 0: He's a big film guy like all the bit, you know Like Miyazaki is like Oh tomorrow is and like Satoshi khan is.
Speaker 1: but it was really telling when someone asked him Like how'd you get into all this?
Speaker 1: Like how did you and he was basically like, you know They paid me a lot of money.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like he.
Speaker 0: he's been in the industry so long and he's like so locked in he's got like tenure.
Speaker 0: So he was like just willing to just be completely honest and scathing.
Speaker 0: He just came out with it Like they're like.
Speaker 0: why did you go back to Zeta Gundam again for the money?
Speaker 1: there's like.
Speaker 1: what was it like to work with?
Speaker 1: Tezuka he's like.
Speaker 1: I won't comment because I'd make a lot of people mad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like he dissed Tezuka He was like, yeah, I was like, oh shit doesn't does.
Speaker 1: no I think part of it too was that you know, he obviously he had a lot to say.
Speaker 0: He said the Gundam design was like a mega design.
Speaker 0: He didn't like it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's like.
Speaker 1: I had great disagreements over the designs of the Gundams and we came to a compromise but I wasn't too happy Yeah, but part of it I think was that.
Speaker 1: I think honestly I believe he cut his speech short because of the translation problems because obviously the nuance was not getting across and there was a lot of nuance.
Speaker 1: there was indeed and He talked a lot about Star Wars, which is interesting because every keynote I've heard recently had pegs everywhere like everyone was inspired by Star Wars.
Speaker 1: then we showed the Daikon for animation at the New York Anime Festival and of course, there's all those Star Wars references in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just lately like this just constant emphasis at least as you know in my its way.
Speaker 0: It's what's it called?
Speaker 0: What's the name for that?
Speaker 0: where you keep the confirmation bias?
Speaker 0: Yes, definite recent confirmation bias Towards, you know seeing Star Wars everywhere and having it continually emphasized to me that like Star Wars changed everything.
Speaker 0: Star Wars Star Wars Star Wars.
Speaker 0: Oh my god Star Wars from anime to video games everything.
Speaker 1: It was all Star Wars.
Speaker 1: guy at work I'm showing cowboy bebop has never seen a Star Wars movie all the way through.
Speaker 1: He's seen little bits.
Speaker 1: He does not know the plot.
Speaker 0: I know there's people like that.
Speaker 0: I know they exist.
Speaker 0: jeez when I worked at the dry cleaners and I was in high school The no people there who work there had seen Star Wars.
Speaker 1: the next time we run the animation see panel Can you just do the thing?
Speaker 1: We're like, you know, everyone in the audience is like, ah You know don't tell us the obvious stuff and we're like, alright guys Anyone who's not seen cowboy bebop raise your hand and like half the room will raise the hands and the other half the room goes.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: We got to do the same thing for Star Wars just to make the broad point that everybody's.
Speaker 1: uh, yep The sad thing is more people have seen Star Wars than have ever read like any Shakespeare.
Speaker 0: That's just because there's more people now and because they could if they could distribute the Shakespeare in the olden days And there was many people to distribute it to and they were literate.
Speaker 0: Then maybe yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah and style the times anyway, but that aside also You know Star Wars is much more accessible whereas Shakespeare not so much.
Speaker 1: anyway I think that in addition to cutting his speech short he gave very Kurt Funny aphorism answers as opposed to long.
Speaker 1: Yeah when anyone?
Speaker 0: yeah when anyone asked him questions He always gave this short like searing answer as opposed to an elaborate answer and also Shot the fanboys down like one guy was like.
Speaker 1: what?
Speaker 1: Would win?
Speaker 0: Like?
Speaker 1: he looked and he was like and they just asked another question.
Speaker 1: yep, he clearly does not want to bother with fanboy crap anymore and It was so refreshing and great and I I just I'm so sad that the translator fucked it all up because I'm sure he had A lot more cool stuff to say.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The only other thing I got to say about the nyaf that's negative.
Speaker 0: Is that it's sort of disorganized ish like just walking around?
Speaker 0: You sort of get this feeling like you had a Children's Palace when it was going out of business like, you know Children's Palace by the way is a toy store that when it went out of business like everything was ultra discounted.
Speaker 0: It was and they basically got rid of all the employees except for the checkout employees.
Speaker 0: So basically it's like imagine giant giant shelves of toys and just all over the floor and all the hall Shelves knocked over.
Speaker 1: I found like a Super Nintendo game under a pile of stuff and bought it for like five bucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I mean walking around the New York anime festival.
Speaker 0: It just sort of feels like like some moe like vomited all over the whole jab.
Speaker 1: It's the same time.
Speaker 1: I've realized like, you know, a lot of the problems with the New York anime festival.
Speaker 0: I really have its fault.
Speaker 1: They have nothing to do because the the people who run the New York anime festival They obviously are doing all the right things.
Speaker 1: They're doing it.
Speaker 0: It's plainly obvious that someone out there is listening to our show and taking our advice directly.
Speaker 0: They made a keynote They put.
Speaker 0: they called change the volunteers to heroes.
Speaker 1: Yes, and the volunteers like it showed the volunteers were like really trying.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were doing a lot better than previous years.
Speaker 0: It was pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah They spaced all the panels out like there was just a 15-minute gap between each panel which was just enough time to clear the room Sort everything out.
Speaker 1: They had the volunteers going around like holding up the 10-minute 5-minute signs making sure the panels ended on time.
Speaker 1: All the tech people were great.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well the tech people are the union guys.
Speaker 0: for some reason they're great But the other perhaps the union guys who did the loading and unloading not so great depends on what union.
Speaker 0: I think I don't know Who knows what the situation is with that.
Speaker 0: but the tech union at the Javits is good.
Speaker 1: But like every like they did everything right and I realized the biggest problem really just is that the Javits Sucks like.
Speaker 1: it is a terrible convention center for this kind of convention.
Speaker 0: Absolutely.
Speaker 1: And also, you know where they put the NAF this year, you know in the bottom part of the Javits It's just the atmosphere of the building is kind of oppressive because it's really high but it's really like dark and dreary.
Speaker 0: So it really it feels like the ceiling is low like an Otakon Like the cement rooms like the artists alley like everything is bright white, you know, even the ceiling is bright white.
Speaker 0: It's it's you know, even though you're basically in a basement with no windows it's like you might as well the Sun might be might as well be shining in there and the ceiling is very high.
Speaker 0: and the Javits the ceiling is kind of high not as high as the Otakon ceiling but it feels very low Like it's right on top of you.
Speaker 0: It feels crowded.
Speaker 0: It's sort of dark.
Speaker 0: It's not bright and white and awesome in there.
Speaker 0: So it just sort of makes this feel to the show.
Speaker 1: that's sort of yeah plus the space like they.
Speaker 1: just they can't isolate sound And it's really just one big room with partitions and that's the biggest problem with anime.
Speaker 1: next the last time we went to that Much of the space was in that big like open area.
Speaker 0: It's just one room with partitions and you can hear everything all the time.
Speaker 0: But there's like the sound is a mess in addition to sort of like the feeling of a physical mess.
Speaker 1: But there's nothing you can do about that and I don't move, you know where?
Speaker 1: I Mean do what Beth did spread out all over the city.
Speaker 0: I sort of like the idea.
Speaker 0: I sort of like that.
Speaker 0: They're gonna combine with the New York Comic Con.
Speaker 0: I think that's gonna work well.
Speaker 1: Oh really especially if they do the combined show floor and they put it in the good part of the Javits.
Speaker 1: because if they take All the show flooring stuff out of that downstairs area and just put like the panel rooms down there.
Speaker 1: It'll work a lot better.
Speaker 0: I think so, too.
Speaker 0: Also, if you notice when you go to the Javits for like a convention in the upstairs part like some conventions It feels dark like the New York Comic Con actually feels sort of dark, right?
Speaker 0: But in the artists alley it actually feels bright and like if you go to the car show It's like the brightness or darkness will vary totally by like which card your company you're next to, you know.
Speaker 0: So it's really all about what you bring to the space and the space itself is really flexible and you just really have to try Hard to make it right.
Speaker 1: Yep, but in the end, I mean why I can't come.
Speaker 1: it's one of those things You can't complain about like yeah, the staff of the BCC or crap for Otacon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: you can't get rid of them all that stuff, but The combined one.
Speaker 1: I'm really looking forward to the combined comic-con anime.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm gonna be there all three days.
Speaker 1: We're gonna stay all three days.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do crazy programming for it.
Speaker 1: Like I'm awesome.
Speaker 1: I'm excited But I am.
Speaker 0: it's like, you know, it's like the New York Comic Con.
Speaker 0: I was like, okay one day New York Anime Festival Okay, one day combine them.
Speaker 0: It's like oh shit.
Speaker 0: That is like big level plus, you know.
Speaker 1: all that aside Everyone seemed to be having by and large a really good time.
Speaker 1: Like the kid the show was doing really well.
Speaker 1: There were a lot of people there.
Speaker 1: Yep, and you know, we did our panel anime.
Speaker 1: You should see.
Speaker 1: you know, I'm Saturday night.
Speaker 1: Like that was our big panel at it.
Speaker 1: a ton of people came.
Speaker 1: There was a gigantic line.
Speaker 1: They almost had to clear the room out.
Speaker 1: It was like standing room only and It went really great.
Speaker 1: The audience was really cool if a bit unruly.
Speaker 1: seriously people.
Speaker 0: Yeah calm the fuck down I think I really think it's.
Speaker 0: you know, we just talked about how I've sort of felt like a children's palace.
Speaker 0: I think the psychology of the space Affects the behavior of the people and sadly very significant way.
Speaker 1: like we have advice like when conventions have problems Usually we know like do this do this to fix it and it usually works.
Speaker 0: to fix this problem You're gonna need like those people who design casinos and shopping malls to like arrange the space in a way that is Psychologically conducive to be.
Speaker 1: I don't know the psychology of it But I do know this.
Speaker 1: anime Boston unlike Otacon is a much more subdued like overall feeling.
Speaker 0: I think it's.
Speaker 0: the building is just brighter No Look and has a mall attached has the same thing and both packs.
Speaker 1: Similar buildings are similar buildings.
Speaker 1: They're very vertical as opposed to horizontal and they have malls attached.
Speaker 1: Yep I don't know.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's something there but So things of the day.
Speaker 1: I found this and I just thought it was really cool.
Speaker 1: It's a picture gallery not a video.
Speaker 1: for once Oh college humor.
Speaker 1: It is a picture gallery of a scarecrow a scarecrow called the Tin Man and I don't really want to.
Speaker 1: I don't want to spoil it at all.
Speaker 1: I don't?
Speaker 1: I just go look at it.
Speaker 1: It is a creepy Motherfucking scarecrow, let me tell you but I don't know.
Speaker 1: I really like this.
Speaker 1: and the coolest thing.
Speaker 1: at the bottom You'll see the sign.
Speaker 1: It's like Tin Man.
Speaker 1: Please do not oil and you'll see why.
Speaker 1: Man, it's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess I could there's a quote again into the October Halloween season here.
Speaker 1: It is The men were broken wooden buckets metal pails pistols and rifles all empty.
Speaker 1: only a quarter of the original mob remained alive.
Speaker 0: You know Halloween will be the fourth anniversary of geek nights.
Speaker 1: the Tin Man beta geek night was finished half his body.
Speaker 1: now one solid rusted joint Dragged by the other slowing half with a low creaking mode of metal and rusty froze His axe finally at rest above his head a drop of blood the last movement to come from.
Speaker 0: All right, whatever this thing's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: so Yeah, what was my thing today?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: It is the Halloween season as I was just mentioning.
Speaker 1: This is Halloween.
Speaker 0: This is Halloween Yes, and angry video game nerd James.
Speaker 1: Oh crap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's awesome, dude He does awesome stuff.
Speaker 0: It starts tomorrow and every day in the month of October He is going to do a video just like he did the year before and the year before it is Monster Madness 3 Monster Madness 1. he basically reviewed a horror movie every day in the month of October Monster Madness 2 Movie every day in the month of October and this year, I guess he's going back to horror movies.
Speaker 0: We'll find out Starting tomorrow or I guess today depending on where you listen to this or maybe even a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Anybody listen to this.
Speaker 0: October 1st 2009 is the first day of Monster Madness 3.
Speaker 0: James Rolf the angry video game nerd will make a video every single day relating to horror in the month of October.
Speaker 0: Whoo All right, one thing I wanted to mention about the nyaf that we didn't mention is that The attendance numbers are actually kind of low.
Speaker 0: It's like they put out a number where that's like 20,000 or something like that, right?
Speaker 0: But the thing is they're counting the turnstile unlike Otakon who counts, you know, the straight-up people Right, so you divide that number by about three.
Speaker 1: Maybe not three because I know a little bit less than three like two in a fraction Even more or less because I saw a lot of Saturday only bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are a lot of one-day badges, but regardless It's not anywhere near 20,000.
Speaker 1: It's like it's hard to say what it is though because it was like crazy crowd.
Speaker 0: It was crowded, but it wasn't a very expansive space either, you know in terms of you know floor space.
Speaker 0: So how many people were actually there is is difficult to say and you'd have to have them count it But regardless is nowhere near 20,000 Yep, and the thing is I just want to say I'm really surprised that you know There's a lot of industry announcements at the New York Anime Festival.
Speaker 0: compared to other cons like it's sort of become You know, it's like Anime Expo and New York Anime Festival is where the remaining anime manga industry makes its announcements.
Speaker 1: I'm really interested.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a relatively small con.
Speaker 1: I'm really interested to know why not Otakon, right?
Speaker 0: I think it's because Otakon is eschewing the industry or what's left of it.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they are though.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't have a lot of insight, you know, we've theoretically joined the Otakon staff But I still don't know anything about.
Speaker 1: apparently Otakon doesn't really start any planning or anything big until after the you know First of the year in other words until it's too late.
Speaker 1: It's just kind of weird, you know We're trying to get stuff ready for Otakon and yet like we've already scheduled some panels for Kinetic Con.
Speaker 0: I know right?
Speaker 1: Oh Well, so I've seen I don't know Eska Flonay Three and a half times.
Speaker 1: I've watched Cowboy Bebop three times.
Speaker 1: I've seen Utena four times.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna watch ghost in the cell chandelier standalone complex a second time.
Speaker 0: I Don't even know I could die.
Speaker 0: I'd be here all night trying to figure out.
Speaker 1: we've seen Trigon twice.
Speaker 1: I've seen beautiful dreamer like seven times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've seen a lot of things a lot more than one.
Speaker 1: Take the gas station.
Speaker 0: I've read the Akira manga like three or four times Star Wars.
Speaker 0: it.
Speaker 0: I've realized I forgot the meta moment.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, I've realized with all the Media I consume with anime more so than anything.
Speaker 1: There's this rewatching happening.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I reread books But not nearly with the frequency that I rewatch anime and it's almost like it becomes this ritual.
Speaker 1: It's not just us a lot of people.
Speaker 1: I remember I was having a discussion with someone in the crew and they said something like yeah It's about that time to watch Eska Flonay again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Replay some video games like I played Zelda 1. how many times?
Speaker 0: Yep So we were thinking about it and we tried to figure and let's do a show on it, I guess yeah I mean like why is it the first of all, you know, there's a few questions that to answer here.
Speaker 0: Why are we rewatching anime, you know, why are we doing it?
Speaker 0: You know if we're doing it more so than we are for other mediums of entertainment.
Speaker 0: What's the reason for that?
Speaker 0: Should you even rewatch anime?
Speaker 0: Is that a waste of time?
Speaker 0: You know, what?
Speaker 0: why?
Speaker 0: why do you enjoy rewatching it?
Speaker 0: Like if you know what's gonna happen already, it's like you already seen it Double dip it when I think about it.
Speaker 1: It's really just the TV shows because we're watching a movie whatever I mean that happens every watched movies a lot.
Speaker 1: So if I'm saying whatever it's not like it's not as novel of a thing.
Speaker 1: But how many TV shows do you watch?
Speaker 1: Maybe it's just that anime is the only place where there are Really these kind of story in a TV show from start to finish.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think it's good.
Speaker 0: It's not only that start to finish.
Speaker 0: It's that it's you know, usually not incredibly long.
Speaker 0: I mean, you're not gonna rewatch all of Dragon Ball Z. Well, maybe some people will but most people won't.
Speaker 0: but you can rewatch like a 26 episode TV series as a beginning middle and an end, you know, and it's sort of like the same.
Speaker 0: mean you rewatch Star Wars.
Speaker 0: You don't even think of that, you know, it's just rewatch Star Wars whatever cuz it's you know a couple hours.
Speaker 0: But it's sort of like rewatching an anime.
Speaker 0: It's sort of in between.
Speaker 0: It's like it's it's there's an.
Speaker 0: it's Difficult enough that it feels like rewatching.
Speaker 0: It feels like a significant activity.
Speaker 0: But then again, it's not so daunting and large like rereading a long difficult book or rewatch or you know Something or rewatching like a gigantic TV series, you know rewatching a 26 or 13 episode series Isn't big enough that you're not gonna do it.
Speaker 1: I mean what at most 12 hours or so.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: So it's like you're gonna do it because it's not so big but doing it is more than just watching a movie.
Speaker 0: So it feels it feels big.
Speaker 0: so it's it's like of note when you and you don't know dad You know how many times you watch Star Wars But you note how many times you rewatch cow Viva because it's it's it takes you a while.
Speaker 1: Well, I think really it's almost.
Speaker 1: it's partly has to do with the format and notice how we only obviously Rewatch the good stuff.
Speaker 1: but really when you look at it, you know, the only shows that get rewatched in their entirety are the ones that are a Succinct story like a story that is compact.
Speaker 1: There isn't really filler.
Speaker 1: It's just a really long movie.
Speaker 1: Yep,
Speaker 0: and The other thing about rewatching right is that it's like you Get more the second time around, you know If it's a good thing like when you read a book if you read the book the second time if it's a good book There's always gonna be stuff that you see in the next go-around even comic books like Watchmen.
Speaker 0: Watchmen is the perfect example of when you reread and reread and reread.
Speaker 0: There's just more and more every single time.
Speaker 0: So when you have a good anime series, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say you have a good movie like Star Wars you watch it again and again and there's more every single time But there's only like an hour or two of material.
Speaker 1: So eventually like I know everything that however, however, the last time I watched Star Wars, which wasn't that long ago.
Speaker 1: I noticed something I'd never noticed before and remember we were sitting there and we realized how great of an actor obi-wan Kenobi was when he Just raises that eyebrow so subtly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's mention of Luke's father.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I just never caught that before.
Speaker 1: The subtlety of his acting.
Speaker 0: that was a good.
Speaker 0: I thought I was like really what did we notice?
Speaker 0: and you said the eyebrow?
Speaker 0: I was like, oh, yeah, we didn't notice the ever but anyway, yeah, but when you rewatch something like how to be Bob It's so big.
Speaker 0: It's you know, like 13 hours big that you are going to.
Speaker 0: you know Re-watching you're gonna dig up you're gonna be able to dig up stuff over and over and over and even if you watch it ten Times you'll still be digging up stuff just because it's such a bigger field to dig in.
Speaker 1: one Look at cowboy bebop.
Speaker 1: It is paced such that if you watch it It never like it is as plot and comedy and action dense as a movie.
Speaker 1: The entire series just non-stop great.
Speaker 1: There's no like lol no middle filler episodes.
Speaker 1: Nothing.
Speaker 1: So Think about the intensity of watching Star Wars like the kind of the build-up and everything all the way through.
Speaker 1: You get that for the entirety of a show like cowboy bebop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's also.
Speaker 0: you don't have to watch the whole thing at once You don't have to do a marathon.
Speaker 0: You can do the one episode at a time Like I had seen Robo tech when it was on Cartoon Network, right?
Speaker 0: but then I got the Matt cross box set that I pre-ordered and You know for $300 way back in the day.
Speaker 0: if you you know If you didn't pay $300 for your original Matt cross box set you didn't buy the right one.
Speaker 0: You're not cool.
Speaker 0: I Met a guy in New York and a festival who bought that same set and paid the same amount of money and pre-ordered like two Years in advance just like me and I was like, yeah real macro.
Speaker 0: Yeah so Yeah, I when I was at RIT I watched it one episode a day until it was over and I think I'm gonna rewatch it again soon one episode a day.
Speaker 0: Cuz he can't watch 50 something episodes all at once.
Speaker 0: It's just the same time.
Speaker 1: Look at that.
Speaker 1: that does that break a little bit with?
Speaker 1: you know, that's a very long show.
Speaker 1: It's very drawn out that long.
Speaker 1: It's still pretty long.
Speaker 0: I watched an RIT like a quarter or less than a quarter even.
Speaker 1: well, how about go to the extreme?
Speaker 1: Are you gonna rewatch Galaxy Express 39?
Speaker 0: That's a hundred and seventeen episodes.
Speaker 0: probably not but I will rewatch the movies a bunch of times.
Speaker 1: Well, I noticed it's weird If a show gets beyond a certain length you do the sort of selective rewatch like I watched all of Sailor Moon once I've seen Every single episode of Sailor Moon which I point out is longer than Galaxy Express.
Speaker 0: Wow 200 episodes damn.
Speaker 1: and for movies not too much in Amish on Natsuko.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'm only talking about the original Galaxy Express 70s 80s TV series.
Speaker 0: I'm not talking about Galaxy railways or any of those.
Speaker 1: the entire Legimashimoto verse.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but is that?
Speaker 0: where's the Sailor Moon verse?
Speaker 0: it ends with those 200 something episodes.
Speaker 0: That's it I did watch.
Speaker 0: remember that Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: you're saying it's 200 episodes.
Speaker 0: It's actually Sailor Moon Sailor Stars Sailor, whatever.
Speaker 1: As super s are Sailor Moon are one thing I can say those I I rewatched it, but I skipped most of it.
Speaker 1: I basically watched like the 20 like episodes that matter in great.
Speaker 0: That's like watching the six that the cow would be about the episodes that are the real plot.
Speaker 1: But even with a good show like I'm not gonna watch all of master Keaton again.
Speaker 1: I got everything out of master Keaton.
Speaker 0: I've seen all of my stuff to watch master Keaton one time.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I will watch certain.
Speaker 1: I've know like I remember showing people and this is actually a big part of rewatching.
Speaker 1: It's not so much necessarily watching it yourself But there's a certain joy in watching someone else who has not yet watched a show watch it.
Speaker 0: Well, that's what I did with Gundam seed, right?
Speaker 0: I had watched all of Gundam seen on my own and then I watched it again with like Riven Emily and it was like Oh snaps.
Speaker 0: Yep And it really helped that I had forgotten pretty much a lot of what happened.
Speaker 0: like especially like.
Speaker 0: I knew the ending There was like the giant thing, but I forgot like the details.
Speaker 0: It's like all right, though that dude gets killed like this and yada yada.
Speaker 1: It was like the whole thing at the end.
Speaker 1: not no spoiler here, but it's just some guy who does it I know right that made the entire series really forgot that like, you know entirely.
Speaker 0: so when I saw it again It was still oh snap It wasn't even just me and Emily.
Speaker 1: a lot of it was just you and me and you'd seen it all.
Speaker 0: you did not watch Every episode with me while I watched it but like you came in and watched like I remember watching every episode I'm pretty sure I think I skipped the recap episodes that I knew were recap episodes like with Emily.
Speaker 1: She watched some of it without me But like I was there watching her watch all the like big episodes namely all the ones with the different music plays.
Speaker 1: Yes, the good.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: the Opera House or on the island.
Speaker 0: It's like attack the gas station.
Speaker 0: We've seen it so many times not because we it's you know, so so great.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's great, but it's not so.
Speaker 1: so I wouldn't just like watch it right now.
Speaker 0: But we watch attack the gas station because whenever there's someone who hasn't seen it already So we can a indoctrinate them into our inside attack the gas.
Speaker 1: It is difficult to impress upon you all of you listeners out there how Important to front row culture attack the gas station is.
Speaker 1: like every inside joke is from that movie, right?
Speaker 0: And we got it.
Speaker 0: So it's to indoctrinate them into the inside jokes, but it's also just a watch.
Speaker 0: and you know It's like.
Speaker 0: I don't know why it is that people are like, why do we enjoy watching other people?
Speaker 0: Laugh at something that we no longer find funny, but once found funny I think there's is.
Speaker 0: it's like prove to ourselves that yes, it was funny.
Speaker 0: I wasn't just stupid.
Speaker 0: There are two aspects.
Speaker 1: All I can think about now is cooking master pot.
Speaker 0: Yeah Perfect example of that.
Speaker 0: and you know, it's like we saw that geeky got here and it was so awesome.
Speaker 0: So it's like now you just want to see someone else like discover that get he got to your awesomeness that you know Oh my god when assumes them on his eye, but no there are two aspects.
Speaker 1: That's right, but aspect the first Is that when you watch someone else watch it you already know what's going to happen.
Speaker 1: so you have this kind of anticipation of the moment and you get excited like oh Man, the totally awesome thing that comes out of nowhere is about to come out of nowhere and they don't know.
Speaker 0: it's coming in many ways Isn't it like telling someone about your D&D character?
Speaker 1: in a way, but you're not.
Speaker 0: it's almost as though Showing them your D&D character.
Speaker 1: No, your D&D character is real and is doing the cool thing again And you're just watching someone else.
Speaker 1: Enjoy it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but to the second aspect.
Speaker 0: This is why I like sort of you know want to do more showings at conventions because like you show someone awesome stuff You know and then you see them laugh at it.
Speaker 0: It's like nothing you show like the daikon.
Speaker 1: Nothing has done that more for me than a kinetic.
Speaker 1: on.
Speaker 1: and then the New York Anime Festival We showed people the daikon animation after explaining just what the big deal was and It's so inspiring to like watch it in one.
Speaker 1: I'm inspired just watching it.
Speaker 1: like every time every single time You just get this feeling in your heart.
Speaker 1: Like wow, what am I doing with my life?
Speaker 1: Look at that and that music and ah that song gets stuck in my head.
Speaker 0: and do the music.
Speaker 1: No, but the music so fits it.
Speaker 1: like they picked the perfect song, but every time we show it to people at a con like They get it you can see they get it.
Speaker 1: and like showing someone one episode of it's all about how you present it to showing one episode of princess tutu to a crowd of people does more than like an hour of talking about princess to show in some DMC some Damaka dobutsu.
Speaker 1: No one trusts us on Damaka dobutsu, but then we show it to them and they're like Animals are no good, but the second watch some after the show I can pass the show I can rewatch over and over again.
Speaker 0: Not maybe not over and over again.
Speaker 1: But partly it's that it's that there's so little commitment.
Speaker 1: cuz it's your short and partly again cuz only when I'm showing it to Other people, you know, it's you know, it's weird.
Speaker 0: It's like whenever there's a new anime, right?
Speaker 0: I'll end up watching like the first episode a ton of times right.
Speaker 0: isn't that it happens to me with so many shows?
Speaker 1: I think it's partly because we have such a wide friend group.
Speaker 0: It's like I've seen like if you like there are some shows where I've only seen the first episode But I've seen it like five times.
Speaker 0: just cuz I keep showing it to people.
Speaker 1: it's because of our friend group.
Speaker 1: We have such a large friend group nearby and we don't.
Speaker 1: we all get together different parts at different times And if some show like we think it's awesome We're gonna want to get all the other people into it.
Speaker 1: So we keep showing the first episode all these different groups of people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's like I know I'd be later episodes I barely even remember.
Speaker 0: It's like you.
Speaker 0: you show me a show.
Speaker 0: It's like I'll remember the first episode.
Speaker 0: I won't remember any of the later episodes at all.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll remember the ending.
Speaker 1: it creates this weird situation though to where I'll almost Watch it.
Speaker 1: so because then I'll remember it as I rewatch, but I'll be like tired of a show like I've like cowboy bebop.
Speaker 1: I saw the first five episodes like a bajillion times.
Speaker 1: A bajillion is to the point that when I watch the first five episodes.
Speaker 1: I can almost feel impatient like am I doing this?
Speaker 1: but then I see episode six is like, oh right this show shit.
Speaker 0: Awesome Yep, but the second aspect that I keep doing even jelly and I've seen the first episode of evangelical like ten times But I've seen evangelical like two or three times.
Speaker 1: I want to talk about Ava separate.
Speaker 1: I have a whole thing to say about Ava and rewatching.
Speaker 1: Yeah But the second aspect is the you can't ever see a show again Unless you have memory problems the first time you see cowboy bebop.
Speaker 1: There's that feeling when the show ends and you've seen it all that that there's that that sense that you can only get once from any experience.
Speaker 1: but while you can never ever reclaim that Watching someone else have the same experience lets you almost vicariously through them relive it just a little bit.
Speaker 1: You get a little bit of that glimmer of what it was like to see.
Speaker 0: you're basically using other people to To channel your nostalgia.
Speaker 1: Yes I remember when we showed Pete all of cowboy bebop because he hadn't seen it and Watch.
Speaker 1: I didn't even look at the screen.
Speaker 1: during the end I watched Pete and I relived that feeling just by seeing him go.
Speaker 1: Whoa Yeah, like at the end he literally he sat there and the credits roll.
Speaker 1: at the end he just goes Was it Alex or Pete?
Speaker 1: I don't remember might have been Alex But that's that's another thing about rewatching.
Speaker 1: is that especially, you know separately the whole topic of marathoning?
Speaker 1: It can come out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: that time whether it was Pete or Alex We did not intend to watch all of cowboy bebop.
Speaker 1: I did not intend to watch any of it.
Speaker 1: He was just over.
Speaker 1: we'd moved back into our IT like no one else was around.
Speaker 1: So we're like here.
Speaker 1: We'll put on cowboy bebop.
Speaker 0: The TV was still on the opposite wall.
Speaker 0: Yeah on the left.
Speaker 1: Yeah weird we're like you watch this while we like, you know clean the apartment up and move back in and do all our stuff.
Speaker 1: and You know, he turns it on.
Speaker 1: in the first couple episodes plan I keep like walking into the room like watching all the good scenes while he's watching them and We just kind of kept watching and then after about ten episodes Me him and Scott are just sitting in the room like watching every episode in order without stopping and then the whole show was done And we there was nothing we could have done to prevent that from happening.
Speaker 1: Nope And it's the same thing with some shows.
Speaker 1: force you like eska flown a. you better be ready to marathon that whole show If you watch one episode, yep, any of those cliffhanger II shows Gundam seed kind of does that too?
Speaker 1: They break it up with the recap episodes and things But towards the end you get those episodes every episode ends and you just you're gonna kill someone if you don't watch the next one.
Speaker 1: It can force you into the show is just making me want to rewatch all the great shows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is it's like I can't be rewatching the stuff.
Speaker 0: I got new stuff to do.
Speaker 1: but at the same time I Think a lot, you know I've seen like eska flown a and cut like.
Speaker 1: I've seen like this set of like 15 different anime a bunch of times and they happen to be some of the anime I respect the most.
Speaker 1: I think are the greatest the best the most worthwhile and I'll sometimes give myself the argument that rim.
Speaker 1: you only like these shows.
Speaker 1: you've seen them a million times and you're like partial to Them.
Speaker 1: you keep rewatching them and it's all just bias and nostalgia.
Speaker 1: But and this brings back the Ava point we watched Evangelion again recently and all it did was remind me that no Objectively and independently of all the rewatching is everything.
Speaker 1: The reason I keep rewatching these shows is because they're brilliant.
Speaker 1: It's the same reason I keep rereading Hamlet.
Speaker 1: It's just it's brilliant.
Speaker 1: Evangelion is a brilliant.
Speaker 0: It's like I you know And it wasn't biased right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I watched it.
Speaker 0: I liked it.
Speaker 0: when I watched it then over time I doubted.
Speaker 0: I doubted that it was as great as I remembered and I was you know I was sort of approaching it with sort of like, you know Oh this time I'm gonna watch it again and all these years later and I'm gonna see why everyone's complaining about it.
Speaker 0: and then I watched like two episodes and I'm like Everyone's a moron is the best thing ever right?
Speaker 0: So even when I approached it with the negative attitude You know, I saw it for what it really was and you know.
Speaker 0: that proves that you know people say Oh, you didn't want to like it.
Speaker 0: So you weren't gonna after you wash it.
Speaker 0: Well, no, look here's the counter example.
Speaker 0: I I thought it was gonna be bad and it wasn't.
Speaker 0: and so rewatching allowed me to you know Refresh and you don't remember the truth that I had forgotten.
Speaker 1: I just want to rewatch all these shows But it also you know kind of not enough hours in the day.
Speaker 1: to me It comes back to the whole like the anime industry because I look at every.
Speaker 0: take a day off of work and we didn't sleep.
Speaker 0: There's 20. we could get over 24 hours in I think and you could rewatch a show and maybe nine hours of 26.
Speaker 0: We could probably watch three whole shows.
Speaker 0: We could probably at least watch kawaii bop and Evangelion definitely with night Day off work.
Speaker 1: would we just watch like 12 hours of anime with like a group of people too often Oh my god, not often enough.
Speaker 1: back when time was our one of our most We had more time than we had.
Speaker 1: anything.
Speaker 1: that's right.
Speaker 1: time was like the biggest resource we had.
Speaker 1: we could waste it.
Speaker 1: However, we wanted.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: time is precious like hamburgers.
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: Cherish.
Speaker 1: But it's not just that it's on a more You know general scale.
Speaker 1: look at the great shows the shows that are great or the shows that stand the test of time.
Speaker 1: I mean Galaxy Express is still a relevant and good show today that you know.
Speaker 1: Endures the test of time.
Speaker 1: Ava endured the test of time and The lens of time is the only real way to filter the objectively good and the objectively noteworthy From the momentarily awesome.
Speaker 1: I mean Fullmetal Alchemist was totally awesome when I watched it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Like we were like.
Speaker 0: basically you're desperate.
Speaker 0: every time a new episode came out and everyone got together and watched it like that night.
Speaker 0: Immediately you're in a big rush to watch it.
Speaker 0: It was huge.
Speaker 1: Everyone was all over it.
Speaker 0: now rewatching that again Now I'm probably never gonna rewatch Fullmetal Alchemist, you know, I mean it's like it was good at the time, but there's no Rewatching action.
Speaker 0: It didn't really have the quality.
Speaker 0: It had this sort of momentary Entertainment value.
Speaker 1: It's a rare show that has the rewatch ability.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's how you know, something is really good.
Speaker 0: You can watch Star Wars a hundred times.
Speaker 0: You can watch Indiana Jones a hundred times.
Speaker 0: You can watch I don't know Another great movie a hundred times.
Speaker 0: You can reread Watchmen a hundred times.
Speaker 0: you can rewatch Ava a hundred times, but you can't rewatch Fullmetal Alchemist.
Speaker 0: You can't rewatch.
Speaker 1: I don't know what else but I think that's so great.
Speaker 1: That is in the end a big reason why the anime industry and the DVD industry in America really collapsed so much is that All the anime that they seem to be really have pushed and tried to market and get people to watch and out there like it's not
Speaker 0: Watchable
Speaker 1: Naruto and all that.
Speaker 1: These are not shows where you're gonna go buy the entire box set.
Speaker 1: It's not like every Naruto fan is gonna buy all of Naruto.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the only people who are gonna buy those things are like collectors and uber fans, right?
Speaker 0: It's like with movies.
Speaker 0: There's some people who are like movie buffs and they get like a huge collection of DVDs.
Speaker 0: But most people just buy the DVDs that they're like gonna rewatch a bunch.
Speaker 0: They're really really into.
Speaker 1: look at the anime I own or Scott owns.
Speaker 1: most of the crew own.
Speaker 1: we'd only own anime.
Speaker 1: not even that will rewatch because a lot of anime that I Would rewatch I don't own but that will shut we want to show to other people.
Speaker 1: Yes I only buy anime that I will pointedly be lending to other people like you.
Speaker 0: just let the common bebop to the co-workers today.
Speaker 1: Yes with the with the packaged in syphilis, but think about what that does to the anime industry.
Speaker 1: Just look at it.
Speaker 1: Alright, so one people really people are only gonna buy the greatest anime that they're going to show to other people.
Speaker 1: So one dude at the center of a social circle buys cowboy bebop.
Speaker 1: He lends it to everyone else in his group.
Speaker 1: Yep, how they gonna sell DVDs.
Speaker 1: The answer is they're not.
Speaker 0: no they got to do something else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Don't know what to do about that.
Speaker 1: There's no way back.
Speaker 1: It's not like I'm gonna not lend animated people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Got it.
Speaker 1: That's quite a hiccup there.
Speaker 0: That was a big one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wish I could not redo the hiccups every time.
Speaker 0: So you want to end the show before my hiccups take it over?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we should probably just end but I Don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't want to go through a list of anime every watch but I have a really like striking example because I always used to say, you know, like shoujo kakame utenna is my like pretty much one of my favorite anime ever But really like my favorite
Speaker 0: only watch that all the way through once.
Speaker 1: I've seen it all the way through four times that show.
Speaker 1: Every time you watch it, you notice something.
Speaker 1: That's a watchman.
Speaker 0: I'll have to watch it again again.
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 0: soon I think
Speaker 1: because I'm feeling like it's time to watch it again because I just got a bunch of other people to watch it and They're coming back and like oh man when such-and-such happened and all I can think is aw, man I want to watch that again.
Speaker 1: That was so good But irresponsible captain Tyler like I used to always say like that show influenced my life more than any media I had ever consumed.
Speaker 1: but I watched like the first two like VHS tapes subbed and then I watched like spread like I'd only seen maybe 75% of the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I watched the first four episodes, but then I watched like up to episode maybe nine or ten But I was only barely paying attention and it was a tiny TV.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that's all I ever saw.
Speaker 1: like all that I'd seen like I saw a lot of bad fan subs I watched like one raw episode and Like some of it like someone were just unwatchable or stuff would skip and I wasn't really sure what episodes I'd seen and hadn't.
Speaker 1: But like the show had made such an impression on me and recently, you know I finally just got the DVD box that cuz it was reprinted I didn't have to buy that stupid expensive out of print box.
Speaker 0: So you didn't get the tea the movie or the.
Speaker 0: when are there OAVs?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the OAVs are really good, but they're easy to get.
Speaker 1: and there's the movie.
Speaker 1: But I I saw I watched that in like a 320 by 200 RM.
Speaker 1: Yeah But the show like.
Speaker 1: I remembered it as being like this life-changing show like this amazing show that I just loved and loved and loved.
Speaker 1: But it'd been so long and I'd seen it in such a shady and dodgy way that I wasn't really.
Speaker 1: I was kind of worried Going into it, you know watching it again especially being older and wiser and seeing How my views of shows like utenna and Ava and hokuto no Ken changed with age and wisdom.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I watching it again and I watch it like halfway through.
Speaker 1: then I watch it again again with Emily cuz.
Speaker 1: she'd never seen it.
Speaker 1: and One there is this one episode that I had never actually seen that was so great Like I don't know how I can't imagine that I hadn't like.
Speaker 1: it's amazing to me that a great episode I'd never seen but to the show was fucking amazing.
Speaker 1: It's so great.
Speaker 0: Yeah rewind I was like I'd stepped in.
Speaker 0: I was like I saw part of an episode and like it all came back to me and I was Like, oh, yeah, this show is freaking amazing.
Speaker 0: I forgot Yeah.
Speaker 1: And the weird thing is I think about how much an influence that show had on me having watched it in such like a poor Format and having missed so much of it I don't know what my life would have been like if I had seen all of the show when I was younger because it probably Would have influenced me even more.
Speaker 1: it is it.
Speaker 1: I'll put it this way there are episodes that are basically It looks like Oh rim is this way because he saw this anime in this episode when he was younger But their episodes I hadn't actually seen.
Speaker 1: yeah It was kind of weird.
Speaker 1: Like it was it was very strange to be watching this but the show is brilliant.
Speaker 1: So watch irresponsible captain Tyler and I guess if you have anime and you feel like rewatching it It's probably because it's great and you should probably get a friend over and just rewatch it.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right, you want to.
Speaker 0: I want to do the meta moment that we forgot the meta minute.
Speaker 0: you met a minute whatever It's metamucil, right?
Speaker 0: The ad contest.
Speaker 0: I think I'm just gonna pick a winner at this point.
Speaker 0: No winner because nobody is entering but I forget the name of the winner.
Speaker 0: So I'm going to go and the next episode.
Speaker 0: I will announce the already selected selected Winner who will receive the full set of Akira manga all six volumes yep, and Also, what other meta do we have?
Speaker 0: they don't really have any.
Speaker 0: oh we do have some meta.
Speaker 0: Uh, let's see.
Speaker 0: I'm moving and rims got house house buy-in and who knows what is going on here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there may be in the neck in the coming weeks a short hiatus of geek nights But yeah, do not fear geek night just going nowhere.
Speaker 1: And in fact the you know, we're not.
Speaker 0: maybe some service disruptions and then we will return to your regularly scheduled programming.
Speaker 0: So if like we miss an episode don't you know coming question us out.
Speaker 1: just I'll say this though We miss the last we're gonna miss some.
Speaker 1: we miss the previous Thursday episode.
Speaker 1: That was just me totally bailing.
Speaker 1: That wasn't any interruptions there.
Speaker 0: We're gonna you know for the next month or two.
Speaker 0: things are gonna be a little shaky.
Speaker 0: We'll still try to get episodes out when we have time, but you know, we can't.
Speaker 0: And then we'll be back to the scheduled programming.
Speaker 1: as soon as everyone is Resettled and I realize especially I feel like around Halloween We should do a kind of state of the podcast show because you know that we've four years since 2005 since October 31st.
Speaker 0: It's older than that, but that was the first publicly released episode little-known fact.
Speaker 1: The first publicly released episode was actually November 1st or 2nd 2005. we then retroactively like a week later took an episode We'd recorded but not released and put it up for Halloween because we thought it was good enough.
Speaker 1: There are two weeks of shows before that the none of you will ever hear Or maybe they will dun dun dun.
Speaker 1: as I've said in the past they are on the internet if you know where to look.
Speaker 1: Yep Someone found them a while ago.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone's ever found.
Speaker 1: someone emailed me a long time ago and we're like is this it?
Speaker 1: and I was like yeah Don't tell anyone they were like I didn't.
Speaker 0: I've never seen.
Speaker 0: I've never seen anyone find them.
Speaker 1: I find that email and show it to you.
Speaker 0: They keep trying but I don't think anyone's ever found them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but Not only is geek nights not going anywhere.
Speaker 1: No I hate.
Speaker 0: you basically have to guess the URL because there's no links to it.
Speaker 1: and not only is this you know These few interruptions that are coming entirely temporary But in fact geek nights is on a very large upward spiral and we've got some like seriously spiral.
Speaker 1: I don't want to spiral upward spiraling out of control.
Speaker 0: We want an upward swing.
Speaker 1: Let's just say that we've got Big works in the Prague in progress that have been I guess in the works for a long time and they're starting to come to fruition in surprising ways.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I don't really want to say anything because we haven't confirmed all the things we're doing yet, but big stuff is coming.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you that it's big.
Speaker 0: Jerry big hopper.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.