Speaker 0: Hey, it's Tuesday August 4th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk a bit about the board game.
Speaker 0: ha Sienna That was stupid.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: We're back from Connecticut, and we finally have a break at least a little bit of a break also.
Speaker 1: We live beware.
Speaker 0: Yes, you could say something like that along those lines.
Speaker 0: We didn't really miss any episodes because we.
Speaker 1: Thankfully much as I think the reason we didn't miss episodes is because I'm not sure if last week was actually supposed to be A Monday Wednesday week.
Speaker 1: we sort of did that for convenience sake.
Speaker 0: it was but we've messed it up previously.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really matter yeah.
Speaker 0: But I'm very glad that despite the fact that I really wanted to go as I always do that We didn't go to SDCC.
Speaker 0: that just would have been too much No, but we will go eventually maybe next year.
Speaker 1: Maybe the year after.
Speaker 1: you know the thing is it's so Hollywood.
Speaker 1: I'm not really in a big rush.
Speaker 1: You know it's like and if I did go like I wouldn't actually You know because I would just refuse like if I go into San Diego right I'm not gonna waste my time waiting in lines.
Speaker 1: So if I do go to that I'm only gonna go to stuff that doesn't have big lines.
Speaker 0: if you don't want to wait in Lines you're not gonna get to see any of the cool stuff.
Speaker 1: Well, I get to see all the stuff on the floor But I wouldn't get to see any event type stuff unless I got in line way early, but luckily it does have four days.
Speaker 1: So You sort of do have time to see.
Speaker 1: you know to wait in a couple lines.
Speaker 1: But yeah, if I plus if I went there it also just want to spend some time in San Diego someplace.
Speaker 1: I've never been where I hear the weather is perfect every day, so yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: But anyway had a more personal note before we get into this.
Speaker 0: My bike got stolen.
Speaker 0: Oh shit now the worst thing is my whole life I've been biking like basically for as long as I could walk.
Speaker 0: I've always had a bike.
Speaker 1: I've had two bikes stone.
Speaker 0: I always carried a little bike lock.
Speaker 0: I've never had a bike stolen in my life and while I always locked my bike.
Speaker 0: I never worried about it I always just thought you know what no one would steal my bike, and I locked it just because you know I kind of did.
Speaker 0: it was just this thing and One day you know a couple days ago.
Speaker 0: I rode my bike to the train station in a hurry.
Speaker 0: You know I was almost gonna miss my train, and I forgot my bike lock, so I thought you know what?
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna leave it here with all the other bikes.
Speaker 0: What are the odds?
Speaker 0: and you know what?
Speaker 0: a hundred percent the one time in my life that I ever don't like my bike up.
Speaker 1: It is stolen immediately, so I got some bike stealing stories, right?
Speaker 0: Well the thing is though.
Speaker 0: I'm Beacons not that big.
Speaker 0: unless some kid just stole it and ditched it in the woods.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna see some punk kid biking around on my very obviously mine bike Possibly, but here.
Speaker 1: I got two bike stealing stories, right?
Speaker 1: I'll tell the less interesting one first even though that's reverse chronological order.
Speaker 0: All right, I was uh I had a bike right let me guess and then it got stolen.
Speaker 1: now it was.
Speaker 1: it was at my house, and I was at summer camp.
Speaker 1: right and I was at summer camp, and then we summer camp went on a field trip to Dorney Park.
Speaker 1: I think so.
Speaker 1: whenever you're on a field trip at summer camp you always use the payphone to call your parents collect right in those non cell phone days.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: so I did and that's when I found out my bike was stolen while I wasn't there And I had left it locked up.
Speaker 1: so that means when I was away somebody else You know did something not so good.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: We had locked up.
Speaker 0: We're like at your house.
Speaker 1: Yeah my house.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine a bike being stolen from someone's house.
Speaker 0: Perhaps.
Speaker 1: I should ask my parents again Maybe now they will admit that like they were poor and I don't know they're not.
Speaker 1: they were never poor But you know they sold it needed money or gave it away, or who knows what anyway?
Speaker 1: Here's the more interesting story right You Know back in the olden days when he's to hang out with the kids on the block We all rode the bikes around like a bicycle gang, but there was no other gang.
Speaker 1: It was just us and just three streets, and that was it.
Speaker 0: we had a rival gang and we had like eight streets.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that's suburbia, so We you know I dropped the bike on the lawn, and I went in the house was playing some video games Heard some noise outside looked out the window saw some people biking past.
Speaker 1: that were not anyone we knew But I didn't pay much attention to it.
Speaker 1: I just sort of noticed it cuz you know it was a quiet weekend day nice and sunny out right.
Speaker 1: Then we sort of realized bike was missing and my friend's bike was missing, too.
Speaker 1: He also left his on his lawn And it was like what the hell some kids must have come down our street and took all our bikes and then biked away.
Speaker 1: So you know I guess you know there was some police call-in action.
Speaker 1: Whatever it was like in the days that were police would actually respond to a stolen bike.
Speaker 0: they respond.
Speaker 0: I went to the beacon police station.
Speaker 1: I filed a report Like this was like you know respond as in a bunch of cops getting cars and start driving around Response looking for him.
Speaker 0: I'll bet if I'd been a kid as opposed to me I could have gotten the police and beacon to do that, but my dad also drove around.
Speaker 0: Dad beat up some kid get your bike back.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: He definitely got the bikes back.
Speaker 1: Bet my handlebars.
Speaker 1: I don't know if he beat anyone up, but I think he was like chasing them And then like the cops came from the other direction and the kids like jumped into the woods.
Speaker 1: You know it was a situation Wow.
Speaker 1: so even living in Detroit I never had anything like that, but well That's the thing is that it was such a non-crime place that you know a stolen bike was like cops are like hell's.
Speaker 0: yeah I work to do, but bike never gets stolen in like Detroit.
Speaker 0: You know leaving it outside like the One wants a freaking bicycle.
Speaker 0: Are you kidding one day?
Speaker 0: I was riding my bike to work and a gang of kids Attacked this other kid across the street beat him up and took his bike.
Speaker 1: wow yeah They must just not like the kid, why would they want the bicycle?
Speaker 1: I mean they give.
Speaker 1: they're gonna do that.
Speaker 1: you can beat up someone to take a motorcycle Right if you're willing to beat someone up.
Speaker 0: So well the thing is the kid was like seven and the kids have beat him up or like 14.
Speaker 0: They're not gonna be beating anyone up who owns the motorcycle.
Speaker 1: Yes, yes, I don't understand though is like if you're willing to beat someone up to take something right you're already gonna be.
Speaker 1: you're already basically guilty of you know assault and robbery and such and such right and That that assault charge doesn't change depending on what you steal only the stealing burglary robbery large Changes based on what you steal.
Speaker 0: well it depends.
Speaker 1: so at least as far as I know.
Speaker 1: not being a lawyer It's got any way shape or form.
Speaker 0: I've always you know when I think about committing crimes all the time It's the engineer's mind.
Speaker 0: you look at the armored car And you know all geeks look at it and think I could take that I wanted out.
Speaker 1: You know an armored car heist is like.
Speaker 1: I just want to do it to prove.
Speaker 1: I could do it.
Speaker 0: See that is that is the edge of the line.
Speaker 0: You know it's like.
Speaker 1: I just want to be in the armored car and have them open the door and be like I dude it.
Speaker 0: It's just like that scene in Dominion tank.
Speaker 1: I don't want the money I just want to prove.
Speaker 0: I dude it where the head of the tank police like.
Speaker 0: what kind of world is this for the criminals?
Speaker 0: Blah blah, you know what?
Speaker 0: Why don't we just run?
Speaker 0: I mean let you look around a bank.
Speaker 0: I've always wanted to.
Speaker 0: I've just been keeping myself.
Speaker 1: I mean you look at that armored car.
Speaker 1: It's this big metal box That's meant to keep you out, and you're like I can fucking get in there.
Speaker 1: Hells.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that would be so fucking awesome You're not so they do everything they possibly can to keep you from getting in there.
Speaker 1: if you can get in there What's more badass than that?
Speaker 0: It's like a rabbit that lives with a lion.
Speaker 0: Exactly anyway I just I can't believe.
Speaker 0: you know faith in humanity mine is.
Speaker 0: mine is that my whole life bike never gets stolen.
Speaker 0: the one time ever I leave it unlocked for like nine hours amidst a bunch of other bikes.
Speaker 0: So that means that someone went up there and was looking for an unlocked bike.
Speaker 0: Yep Oh Well, but Kineticon we were there last weekend, and we're not really gonna talk about it tonight because you know what.
Speaker 0: it's not a gaming Con it's not an anime con.
Speaker 0: It's a generic on.
Speaker 0: so we're going to talk about it on Thursday.
Speaker 1: Oh great excuse to fill up a Thursday episode for which we are sorely lacking ideas.
Speaker 0: I got a ton of ideas.
Speaker 0: you just never want to talk about him.
Speaker 1: It's a cop-out, but it is a totally valid cop-out, and it fills a Thursday episode.
Speaker 0: hooray We got to cover Kineticon right away, but yeah anyone who was in panel five that was our room.
Speaker 0: And a minor announcement, I'll just point this out now, but we are now the heads of panels and workshops for Kineticon.
Speaker 0: It's official complete, so We'll have this all scheduled within a few weeks.
Speaker 1: if you're an awesome person And you know who you are you want to submit and you want to come to Connecticut next August.
Speaker 1: probably You know what they announced.
Speaker 1: the dates actually didn't they?
Speaker 1: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: it's probably it's probably Early August late July.
Speaker 1: you know a week or two after Otacon It's not gonna be the same weekend as Otacon or San Diego right it's probably gonna be the week after those.
Speaker 1: That's the usual timing of it.
Speaker 1: And you want to come to Connecticut then and do awesomeness in a. you know gaming anime anything kind of geeky action Called.
Speaker 1: you know how to call us.
Speaker 1: so We're waiting for you.
Speaker 0: Wow you trailed off and made that sound very unexciting.
Speaker 1: No, it's you know.
Speaker 0: Kineticon is great though for one reason one reason alone.
Speaker 0: We're there.
Speaker 0: and second reason I'm there Action Castle.
Speaker 0: I think Action Castle was the second most popular thing at the con after art fight.
Speaker 0: It's pretty popular all things considered alright, but anyway Gaming news.
Speaker 0: we got a little bit of gaming news.
Speaker 0: Let's talk about packs.
Speaker 1: It's strangely light on gaming news.
Speaker 1: I think everyone's saving for packs.
Speaker 1: in fact that is my my guess, but anyway packs.
Speaker 1: Due to the fact that there's still a little gaming news everyone saving it for packs.
Speaker 0: Let's just talk about packs Penny arcade expo which is pretty much the best gaming convention in the world in Seattle every year over Labor Day weekend.
Speaker 1: You know what I did today?
Speaker 0: Thought about packs.
Speaker 1: well and my little tweets on my iPhone right I can have columns for tweet searches right.
Speaker 1: so I had a tweet search For Otakon so I would see everyone talking about Otakon even if I wasn't following.
Speaker 0: You know as far as I can tell more people have tweeted about packs in the last month and tweeted about Otakon while Otakon was Going on.
Speaker 1: so then I you know I deleted that column and I created Kineticon column.
Speaker 1: then I today I deleted the Kineticon column and made a packs column.
Speaker 1: So you know when I'm making a column for it that it's coming up.
Speaker 1: so at packs we me and rim are doing three Three five is right out.
Speaker 1: three panels three.
Speaker 1: they are beyond D&D Which is the same exact thing that we ran yes last year.
Speaker 1: only we are more practiced at it.
Speaker 1: So it is slightly better, but it is the same material.
Speaker 0: Captains you're making this your news.
Speaker 0: What are these things scheduled?
Speaker 0: What rooms?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: you don't know all right.
Speaker 1: It doesn't really matter beyond dungeons and dragons.
Speaker 0: We're reprising it on Sunday Sunday up.
Speaker 0: don't get sued in the Raven theater.
Speaker 0: Raven did One day back on Saturday.
Speaker 0: We're doing our new panel.
Speaker 0: losing should be fun at 1030 in the Wolfman theater.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we practice that at Kineticon pretty good and beyond.
Speaker 0: Candyland is Friday at 1130 a.m.. In the Raven theater again.
Speaker 1: I wonder about that Friday 1130.
Speaker 1: I hope it does not conflict.
Speaker 1: wait 1130 a.m Yeah, Wow packs didn't even start until like like what two or three last year, right?
Speaker 0: This is the tentative schedule, and they have not published the official schedule.
Speaker 1: They might be starting earlier this year.
Speaker 1: That's interesting, but anyway I hope that does not conflict with any of the things I would like to see such as Keynote etc.
Speaker 1: etc.
Speaker 0: thing is other than the keynote.
Speaker 0: I go to the concerts because they're awesome But the who what could someone possibly ask in the Q&A that will top last year's Q&A only really need to see that one?
Speaker 1: No, I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's the only thing I'm concerned with Conflicting with is the keynote.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 1: I'd like to go to many of the other main events and things But I won't be like.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: I'd rather do my panel than do say I you know gave and taiko Q&A or the draw a comic panel which I missed last year.
Speaker 0: I do want to go to the Q&A just to continue the trend that we started last year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I do not want to miss the keynote for anything, so I hope that we do not conflict with it.
Speaker 0: But that aside don't forget that the penny arcade Expo East Coast is going to be in March in Boston.
Speaker 1: Is it the week before or the week after anime, but I don't know.
Speaker 0: I haven't even figured out our schedule for panels yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got to figure out how I can stay in Boston for a whole week.
Speaker 1: Hello friends who live in Boston get a couch ready.
Speaker 0: I'll probably just stay in a hotel.
Speaker 1: Maybe for a whole week I got money.
Speaker 1: It's a lot of money.
Speaker 0: It's not that much.
Speaker 1: Maybe we can stay in a hotel during the con you know like right next to the convention center But then like the Monday through Thursday in between staying like a motel like a little bit out of the ways Mad cheap.
Speaker 1: It's a possibility some free internet as opposed to the expensive hotels Which usually don't have.
Speaker 0: my only debate is whether or not to take an entire week of vacation or?
Speaker 0: To see if I can work quote unquote from home.
Speaker 1: That was my plan to work from quote unquote.
Speaker 1: Boston thing is.
Speaker 0: I'd rather just not work and just have a vacation on the West Coast.
Speaker 1: I Mean I it's on the East Coast.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, Boston.
Speaker 0: I want to take a week off on the West Coast - yeah I liked it.
Speaker 1: well if I can get my work to let me go to Django con which is the week after packs then maybe I get to stay on the West Coast after packs.
Speaker 0: and Except you already bought your plane ticket non-refundable back after packs didn't you?
Speaker 1: That's fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can deal with that Can you?
Speaker 1: hey I can cancel.
Speaker 0: it gotta pay a hundred bucks to cancel it now.
Speaker 1: You know how you do?
Speaker 1: No, it's not that bad.
Speaker 0: It's a hundred bucks though.
Speaker 1: It's not that bad.
Speaker 0: It's not that bad, but it's a hundred bucks.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's a hundred bucks.
Speaker 0: It's a hot It's they're not jet blue.
Speaker 0: tickets like that are non-refundable, but it is a hundred dollars to change which includes the cancellation.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh Whatever doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: That's how it works.
Speaker 1: Hey my company if I thing is I'm staying out there as soon as PAX is over.
Speaker 1: It's my company's dime.
Speaker 1: So yeah I'll pay a hundred bucks.
Speaker 1: if that means I'm gonna basically they'll get me a rented car and they'll get me a You know hotel in Portland where I'm gonna have to stay for the Django con.
Speaker 1: and you know plus.
Speaker 0: We'll see if this even happens right anyway, so in actual gaming news outside of conventions Namco Bandai or Bandai.
Speaker 0: Namco's Sales figures are out, and they're this longer part of all these things No one cares about.
Speaker 0: but for a quarter 1 2010 you know what.
Speaker 0: the top selling game that they made was Far and away almost double anything else.
Speaker 1: I'm guessing like Pac Man iPhone or something afro samurai.
Speaker 1: Wow, they're not doing too.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: How many how many sales was it?
Speaker 0: half a million?
Speaker 1: That's not good.
Speaker 1: I mean usually games.
Speaker 1: You know they need like a million sellers.
Speaker 0: But third down on the list is Dragon Ball Z Attack of the Saiyans in Japan only on the DS.
Speaker 1: Wow That's and that was less than a half million.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the other two big games were we ski and snowboard and we ski I Didn't even know there was were two different games.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: I hope we ski is like free ski, though Then I'll buy it.
Speaker 1: Will you is there an abominable snowman who eats you at the bottom inevitably?
Speaker 0: You know he won't eat you if you're good You can.
Speaker 1: I've died.
Speaker 1: how many times have you dodged him in a row you know?
Speaker 0: I don't even know.
Speaker 0: I just remember that I got that get way back when I didn't know how stuff worked.
Speaker 0: I basically thought games were free and then when I realized the games weren't free and my friends were just pirating them and giving me Copies yeah, I went to the store, and I bought what ended up being actually a bootleg collection that was sold semi legitimately.
Speaker 1: We actually had a legitimate Microsoft best of entertainment pack.
Speaker 0: no I had this like 35 games pack that we bought at like electronics boutique got chat with chat.
Speaker 1: I have a legitimate copy of chips challenge.
Speaker 0: I have a bootleg copy of chips challenge, and I bought at an EB, and you know what.
Speaker 1: we can't possibly tell the difference.
Speaker 1: It's just ones and zeros that are exactly the same.
Speaker 0: of course nothing ever be just ball.
Speaker 0: no I just ball also legitimately But more and more we haven't talked about this.
Speaker 0: I do want to bring it up at least a little bit that you know.
Speaker 0: the boy and his blob game is coming that the remake of a boy and his blob and It's looking more and more fantastic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've seen everything I've seen.
Speaker 1: if it tells me.
Speaker 1: That's the awesome win I mean it really looks like Co-op though.
Speaker 1: or one person can be the blob and one person can be the bull.
Speaker 0: all they did was take the concept and then Just fix every bad game academy because the boy in his blob was an unbeatable impossible Horrifying game back in the day.
Speaker 1: yeah But the idea of having a blob follow you and give it a jellybeans is a great idea.
Speaker 0: The only thing they kind of took away that I'm a little bit sad about is that they made the game cartoony and cute.
Speaker 1: They made it not more Indiana Jones like it used to be.
Speaker 0: well No, it's just.
Speaker 1: it used to be all Indiana Jones pitfall night.
Speaker 0: It's cool cool and cute, but the original styling of the game was Vaguely just disturbing and dark.
Speaker 1: We it was Indiana Jones pitfall.
Speaker 0: No, look at the graphic design of the original game.
Speaker 0: It's just very.
Speaker 0: the whole thing was dark and absurd and kind of frightening.
Speaker 0: It was Indiana Jones and pitfall and you realize only a tiny bit of it was that.
Speaker 0: and then the rest was our candy corn.
Speaker 1: Well the candy corn was something else.
Speaker 0: that was the real game.
Speaker 0: The first part of the game was just get the treasure to buy the vitamins to get to the real game.
Speaker 0: Yeah That was that was it and I don't recall Indiana Jones swimming with bubbles.
Speaker 1: He's fine with the barber spikes Within the snakes.
Speaker 0: there weren't so many snakes.
Speaker 1: Hey snakes.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 1: okay Yeah, I'm looking forward to this and I'm actually hoping that we see.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: firstly the body commando rearmed right which is basically a Remake of the original bionic commando.
Speaker 1: But this is taking an old concept and from a game that didn't have a lot of polish.
Speaker 1: I'm so sad again with modern polish.
Speaker 0: the original remake of the original game was great But the new game they made based on the concept the actual 3d bionic commando.
Speaker 0: It was pretty weak sauce as far as anyone could tell.
Speaker 0: it was just sold so poorly.
Speaker 1: No one's buying it.
Speaker 0: It was a terrible game.
Speaker 0: It is a terrible game But it says something for the game industry that if they just take is some old game That was known to be good or at least had a good concept and just remake it with modern technology But still make it a 2d.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of things out in this world right that only failed not just in video games But in general there are a lot of failures out there.
Speaker 1: that only failed because they lacked the necessary Surface polish and they have some valuable good meats on the inside.
Speaker 0: What are you talking about?
Speaker 0: the bionic commando?
Speaker 0: that game was hugely popular in the u.s..
Speaker 1: Well, I'm not talking about bionic commando I'm just talking about the remake of that, but you know You know the boy in his blob right.
Speaker 0: they took these old good night game was actually also pretty popular.
Speaker 0: as far as I recall It sold really well.
Speaker 1: I don't know how well it sold.
Speaker 0: Anyway consider how much of an enduring legacy it has that people remembered that game and talked about it.
Speaker 1: people remember a lot of things.
Speaker 0: It didn't sell at all So but they remember it and liked it.
Speaker 1: plus people remember Zelda CDI just as much as they remember.
Speaker 0: Actually as far as I can tell the vast majority of people didn't even know Zelda CDI Existed.
Speaker 1: the vast majority of people don't even know.
Speaker 1: the point is blob exists now But I think game you don't even know earthbound exists.
Speaker 0: I think gamers more knew more about earth down in a boy in his blob than they did about the Zelda games.
Speaker 1: It's hard to tell.
Speaker 1: anyway.
Speaker 1: the point is is that I hope there are more remakes of old good yet unpolished Game.
Speaker 0: I point out that there was basically zero buzz about the CDI games on the internet Until the AVGN covered them.
Speaker 1: no he wasn't.
Speaker 1: There were buzz about them way before.
Speaker 0: he covered them occasional tiny buzz But it never got out there.
Speaker 0: most people didn't know.
Speaker 0: hardly anyone in our friend group had ever heard of these games and our friends Are gamers and I knew about them for so long.
Speaker 0: Yes But everyone knew boy is blob and everyone knew bionic man.
Speaker 1: the point is is a ton of games out there.
Speaker 1: I can come up with a whole bunch like monster party.
Speaker 0: I wasn't a game monster party.
Speaker 1: Oh come on.
Speaker 0: That was a terrible game Dr..
Speaker 1: Chaos, okay silver surfer terrible game.
Speaker 1: right these games if they just repolish them They'd be great silver surfer.
Speaker 0: That's just saying make a shmup.
Speaker 1: now It's got to be the silver surfer.
Speaker 0: why the core concept?
Speaker 0: silver surfer is better off not being a shmup?
Speaker 1: No, it's better the silver surfer has got to be a shmup.
Speaker 1: What else could it be?
Speaker 0: besides you're forgetting There's only one game that really needs to be remade other than tie fighter.
Speaker 0: There's an already being remade Well actually and that is metal marines for the s.
Speaker 1: Oh metal marines the other good choice?
Speaker 1: No, actually you know lucas arts is starting to do a lot of remakes They're doing.
Speaker 1: they did the monkey island doing some other action, right?
Speaker 1: Somebody asked them about the tie fighter and the x-wing and the lucas arts person said I can't say anything yet.
Speaker 1: Just wait dot dot dot something something.
Speaker 1: maybe the problem is that wink nudge That is all.
Speaker 0: that is equally code in marketing for we have something, but we can't announce it yet, and We haven't done anything, but we're pretending.
Speaker 0: We might have to gauge interests.
Speaker 0: Either way is good by me.
Speaker 0: I don't know how much interest there is.
Speaker 0: it's a chicken and egg situation where there's there's just now that flight stick Which is weird because that basically a coincidence.
Speaker 0: a chicken appears Conspiracy.
Speaker 0: a chicken appeared, but there was no eggs.
Speaker 0: suddenly there was a chicken.
Speaker 1: There's a but there's a chicken and there's a wink for an egg.
Speaker 1: There's a wink and a nod suggesting that there's the hens gonna lay an egg Which is which is more than we've had in since.
Speaker 1: Lizzie.
Speaker 1: when did tie fighter come out over a decade?
Speaker 0: No, there was x-wing alliance was it was a fantastic come out.
Speaker 0: I don't even know but after tie fighter And to be a long time ago and after x-wing versus tie fighter, which I can only describe in one word abortion.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter I have Actually, I don't really care because even if this game comes out by the time it comes out I'll just be playing ns2, and we'll give a shit.
Speaker 0: That's the only game that matters right?
Speaker 1: so?
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: What do you got for me?
Speaker 1: So you know people like to do versus right.
Speaker 1: they do like.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Voltron versus Messenger like a fanboy.
Speaker 1: see Star Wars very Star Trek or Superman vs.
Speaker 0: Batman right all right.
Speaker 1: Are you ready for the ultimate versus?
Speaker 0: I've already seen Megaman versus Donkey Kong.
Speaker 1: Henry Rollins all right versus techno.
Speaker 0: Viking Rollins Definitely Rollins.
Speaker 1: well no, but there's basically this is video.
Speaker 1: They mashed up Rollins complaining about techno music and techno Viking.
Speaker 1: they took the two videos and put them together in a funny way in fact in a way that creates a techno song And I enjoy this very much.
Speaker 1: So I hope you enjoy it very much.
Speaker 0: So who would win then?
Speaker 0: Rollins in a Cosby sweater or Bruce Campbell in a Cosby sweater?
Speaker 1: What's what's the competition?
Speaker 1: I mean is it chess chess boxing?
Speaker 0: shooting eating Puddin pops Puddin pops We'll talk about.
Speaker 1: we know that when you wear a Cosby sweater you have infinite Puddin pop eating powers.
Speaker 0: We'll talk about that on a Thursday, but suffice it to say Cosby sweaters were a big part of a kinetic on.
Speaker 0: So oh yeah You know in old Cartoons when like there'd be a mouse or something talking really quickly like in Tom and Jerry and everything
Speaker 1: Or in like peanuts or like the teacher Particularly
Speaker 0: with Chip and Dale and Apparently with Popeye all they would do is get someone to say something and then speed it up And then use that as the audio.
Speaker 1: well good idea.
Speaker 0: one thing you can do that is very clever because you know the way audio works Is slow it down, and you can hear what they're actually saying and usually it's something lame.
Speaker 0: But what I have here from College Humor is a gem.
Speaker 0: This is a 1952 Popeye Shut-eye.
Speaker 0: Popeye.
Speaker 0: Popeye is trying to sleep.
Speaker 1: I like me some Popeye.
Speaker 1: I was actually thinking about getting this Popeye box set.
Speaker 0: I only like the old racist black-and-white Popeye.
Speaker 1: What are the Popeye would you watch?
Speaker 0: like Popeye Aladdin?
Speaker 0: just him basically be.
Speaker 1: what other kind of Popeye is there?
Speaker 0: It's just this scary saddled sailor with Tourette's beating people up exactly, but Popeye He's trying to sleep in his garbage can And the mouse.
Speaker 0: you know the mouse wants to sleep and Popeye snores.
Speaker 0: the mouse yells at him.
Speaker 0: But if you slow it down it as far as I can tell it's this voice actor saying Yeah, give me some lines to say I can't really read this goddamn.
Speaker 0: Whatever No, it's just some guy saying that kind of pissed off, and that's the audio they used.
Speaker 0: apparently Maybe they got some bum off the street handed him a script.
Speaker 0: That was it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's pretty interesting though to like uncover like these hidden data It's sort of like.
Speaker 1: remember how they were.
Speaker 0: you know what it's sort of like the that infamous picture on eBay of someone selling a teapot and in the reflection of the teapot if you use a Photoshop filter to Deprospective it from the teapot surface.
Speaker 0: There's a naked guy holding a camera.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: No it's sort of like.
Speaker 1: Remember they were doing those studies.
Speaker 1: or if you take old pottery and sort of run like a record needle across it You know because of the pseudoscience mostly Scott.
Speaker 0: I know almost entirely pseudoscience.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone legitimate has ever read anything into that.
Speaker 0: I know but Like it's like the same idea it is except one idea is made up and one idea works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the same idea?
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, that's it alright, so We got to do a show on gaming.
Speaker 1: No one's been playing any video games.
Speaker 1: We definitely haven't been playing the same video games.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't think you played any blood Bowl, but Despite being at Connecticut and basically you know running 20 like 38 hours worth of panels We did manage to play one board game.
Speaker 0: we played two games.
Speaker 0: we played one all right.
Speaker 1: wow We should talk about you once about both of them.
Speaker 1: I forgot about the other one.
Speaker 0: we played well We played the sword.
Speaker 0: well, okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's not a board game.
Speaker 0: I didn't say board game.
Speaker 0: I said game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 0: We played the sword and pretty epically mostly because I won and you lost your strategy that you've been telling me.
Speaker 1: basically Scott I didn't get to use the full extent of my strategy.
Speaker 0: Scott told me this strategy a long long long time ago.
Speaker 0: He's like I can win the sword.
Speaker 0: I just have to be the elf and I punked him as the rat.
Speaker 1: That's all right.
Speaker 0: partly because Luke crane told me how to win as the rat I just did exactly what he said and do anything.
Speaker 0: you just sat there while I got stabbed Basically, I took whoever's side was winning at all and I waited until everyone was.
Speaker 0: I made a.
Speaker 1: I made one flaw in In in trying to appeal to you and not appealing to the human.
Speaker 0: I paid me, so I didn't give a shit anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I had to get you out of the way so that the only one.
Speaker 1: cuz if I if I can't get at The team no no no no no strong against the door, but the rat is in the way I have to move the rat aside to get the door.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: There's a better way.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh tell the dwarf.
Speaker 0: You know what fine.
Speaker 0: You can have it.
Speaker 0: I give up my claim to the sword.
Speaker 0: let him and the rat fight and then take the sword.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not so good.
Speaker 0: That'll work Every time.
Speaker 1: no because the elf has the.
Speaker 1: you know when someone is hurt.
Speaker 1: You know sue them.
Speaker 0: Yes, sue them with a sword.
Speaker 1: I don't know how soothing the sword is anyway.
Speaker 1: We did play two board games.
Speaker 1: I got both or just one.
Speaker 0: talk about both But we should talk about hacienda in a little bit of depth though the thing is it's a board game.
Speaker 0: That's simple enough to where.
Speaker 0: don't have a lot to say about it.
Speaker 0: Just it's a good game right.
Speaker 1: well Hacienda, let's talk about that first cuz it's fresh in the mind right.
Speaker 1: I knew how to play hacienda from back in the day because of the website spiel by web.com.
Speaker 1: S-P-I-E-L-B-Y-W-E-B.com.
Speaker 1: you know you can play by web in German where you can play Hacienda online for free.
Speaker 1: and they have a bunch of other games too like reef encounter and Santiago which I don't know how to play and a few others.
Speaker 1: I'm an ray right which I do know how to play and I used to go on this website a whole bunch and I'd always Be playing it back in the day.
Speaker 1: But I sort of stopped after a while just because they didn't add me new games, and I was sort of eh.
Speaker 1: But then I knew that you know rim never played these games.
Speaker 1: You know pretty much no one else, but me had ever gone to spiel by web and played there.
Speaker 1: I think Alex might have anyway.
Speaker 1: We were at Connecticut and we finally had a chance to play a board game, and I saw Hacienda there, and I was like all right.
Speaker 1: Actually, that's a great choice because I kind of know how to play.
Speaker 1: and the thing is when you're at a convention like this If you pick up a board game You've never played before and you're good to take like two hours or an hour just to read the rules and figure it out And set it up and teach everyone how to play.
Speaker 1: and you don't have a lot of time at a convention time is you know?
Speaker 1: Precious.
Speaker 1: so a game that I knew how to play from playing it online already And I only had to review the rules quickly.
Speaker 1: that was a very good choice.
Speaker 1: So we played Hacienda and then me and rim started an online game of Hacienda today.
Speaker 0: So Hacienda is pretty much this game it up.
Speaker 1: it has a theme nominally of the theme is not a it doesn't go.
Speaker 0: so it has a theme nominally of Haciendas basically out in the prairie build you know taking land getting the famous giant bone getting animals out in the land Driving them to the market, but the game mechanics backing up this theme are so So shallow pretty much.
Speaker 1: the game is a combination of two things.
Speaker 1: number one.
Speaker 1: It's Tron like through the desert right.
Speaker 1: It's that game plus Resource management sort of like to call where you have action points and also resources.
Speaker 1: right and that is Hacienda.
Speaker 1: It's all you do is you have resources you have every turn you have three actions and you have money and you have cards and you can buy cards the money gets turned into cards cards turn into stuff stuff turns into money and Victory points.
Speaker 1: and then you use the money to buy more cards to get more stuff to get more money and victory points.
Speaker 1: and you Get this cycle going on and the stuff goes on the board.
Speaker 1: and when you put the stuff on the board you try to put It out Tron style.
Speaker 1: you're blocking the other guy off and surrounding things And you know you're trying to get really good layouts to to get in the other guy's way.
Speaker 1: You're competing over the territories to get you know big long strings of land or strings of Animals and herds.
Speaker 1: you know that without getting them blocked.
Speaker 1: It's longer the better.
Speaker 0: It's a game of getting you know physical combos.
Speaker 0: There's restrictions where you can put stuff, so it's it's through the desert.
Speaker 0: Which is camel Tron, but with Almost less of a theme, but more mechanics to beef it up.
Speaker 1: Yep The thing about this game I sort of it's.
Speaker 1: it's sort of weird because it's like the the.
Speaker 1: it's not that complicated right?
Speaker 1: you look at like a lot more Complex games like Puerto Rico's more complicated teeny right.
Speaker 1: this really isn't that complex.
Speaker 1: It's in fact is less complex than even like El Grande.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'd say it's slightly more complex than Carcassonne right yet You know it's also so straightforward, and it's pretty much get action points Spend you know get stuff.
Speaker 1: It's just your decisions are so Distinct.
Speaker 1: you think oh, I should be able to solve this and just have a perfect play.
Speaker 1: right, but it's actually for some.
Speaker 1: You know it's it's.
Speaker 1: it's not easy to get a perfect play.
Speaker 0: well now.
Speaker 0: I would disagree that in a vacuum It's kind of like it's an Agricola.
Speaker 0: sit in a vacuum.
Speaker 0: Yes, well as in.
Speaker 0: it's the same thing with Agricola where the first couple of plays you're figuring out kind of the optimal means of Generating victory points the optimal means of controlling things you need to control.
Speaker 0: but Much like an Agricola the real game is not making the factory work.
Speaker 0: the factory working is the trivial solution.
Speaker 0: The problem is interacting with the other players such that you get what you need and you can make your machine work within the construct Of their machines.
Speaker 1: that's one thing I think is very good about this game is that there are multiple ways to get victory points and they balance each other out quite Nicely like let's say you try to connect to a bunch of different markets.
Speaker 1: that's one way to get a lot of victory points right.
Speaker 1: if you're cut off from that you can still get just as much points doing say haciendas or water or strings of land Or any of the other victory point.
Speaker 1: machines are equally fruitful if you milk them enough And you can never milk all of them equally unless it's like a two-player game.
Speaker 1: There's basically no fighting over resources whatsoever In a three four or five player game.
Speaker 1: It's two to five right.
Speaker 1: there's a lot more competition for the resources on the map and You're not gonna be able to get the victory points in all the different categories.
Speaker 1: So you're just gonna have to pick a few of them and go all out and it's a good idea To go for ones that other people are not going for.
Speaker 1: so there's less Competition.
Speaker 1: if you try to go for a big string of land and someone else is going for a big string of land Good luck with that You know.
Speaker 1: if you try to go for you know just connect to a lot of different Markets all over the place and someone else goes for a string of land You're probably both gonna be able to make it happen.
Speaker 0: kind of the two-player game is fun And it definitely won't run out on us now.
Speaker 0: We're playing it halfway through and it's a pretty Even match.
Speaker 0: we're both using different strategies, but I'm enjoying it, but it has the same I don't know.
Speaker 0: little effort needed to jump in and play not that much setup and yet Enough variation.
Speaker 0: the two-player doesn't get stagnant.
Speaker 0: that I think it's the same reason I like tempest so much.
Speaker 0: I can just sit down and play tempest.
Speaker 1: yep It's also another game where you can vary the map a lot.
Speaker 1: the default map is the dog bone But you can.
Speaker 1: there's a map on the reverse side and if you play online There's a ton of maps you can play on.
Speaker 1: I'm sure some of them are stupid But you know in case you really do get bored with the bone map and you sort of figure it out You can try all sorts of different stuff which might be a lot more interesting.
Speaker 1: You know at least to mix it up some.
Speaker 1: the other thing is the game does have that sort of lots of little decisions Mechanic the same thing that ticket to ride has where instead of people having very long turns We do a lot of things.
Speaker 1: everyone has little tiny turns.
Speaker 1: So you're always doing something and you're always making very small decisions that all add up to each add up in the long run Which makes for you know a more fun play.
Speaker 1: as you know it's your turn more often.
Speaker 1: turns are quick You don't have to think about a whole lot to get your turn done.
Speaker 1: people bevagon.
Speaker 0: Well it has a very important, you know it has that I love the mechanic the end of a gun.
Speaker 0: sorry Yeah, it has two really cool mechanics.
Speaker 0: One is the end decker of risk management and that you can basically always you'll buy a known Animal or a known land like a known card for one amount of money or buy one unknown from the top of the stack.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, that's the same thing.
Speaker 1: you see and take it to ride and also turn in taxes.
Speaker 1: Right is the?
Speaker 1: is the the draft where there are face-up cards and also you can also get the face-down card.
Speaker 1: So it's like do you want to get the face-up card and know what you're getting?
Speaker 1: or do you want to?
Speaker 1: Risk it and get the face-down card in which case you don't know what kind you're gonna get.
Speaker 0: it's a great mechanic.
Speaker 0: I just I love it.
Speaker 0: I absolutely love it.
Speaker 1: It's really I think a lot.
Speaker 1: I think you know a lot of other games that have draw from card We can't draw from a deck.
Speaker 1: mechanics would do well to incorporate this.
Speaker 1: I mean magic.
Speaker 1: the gathering would even do well to incorporate something like this.
Speaker 1: You know, but you know, that's never gonna happen.
Speaker 0: And the other part is has a really cool ebb and flow.
Speaker 0: It's that that's something that actually isn't in a lot of games and it's not.
Speaker 0: it's almost.
Speaker 0: it's not really a mechanism design thing It's just the way the rules will the way people will play will come.
Speaker 0: you can move between Building victory points or building money or something like that where you have two or three different directions to go but going in any one direction.
Speaker 0: the more you go in.
Speaker 0: it kind of Forces you to need the thing in the opposite direction more and more and more and more.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like if you start building a ton of stuff right.
Speaker 1: first of all You want to build faster than the other people because you're fighting over this territory.
Speaker 0: But you can't build faster than you run out of cards.
Speaker 0: No, because everyone has the same constraint.
Speaker 0: So no matter how much you pull in one direction You can't get ahead in an absolute sense not counting victory points of anyone else.
Speaker 0: It's just a matter of when do you build?
Speaker 0: when do you save?
Speaker 0: when do you harvest all the?
Speaker 0: it's all the way.
Speaker 1: You got to build before the other people but if you build before then you run out of cards.
Speaker 1: That means you're gonna be you know one.
Speaker 1: you'll be like, yeah Yeah, yeah, you're building stuff and you're like surrounding something the other guys getting blocked off.
Speaker 1: You're like fuck you I win.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then you run out of cards.
Speaker 1: So you spend a few turns spending your money to buy some cards and during those turns The other guy starts playing all the cards.
Speaker 1: He was buying when you were building.
Speaker 1: You're like no no, no No, no, no, and then he runs out of cards.
Speaker 1: You start building with the cards you just bought and it goes back and forth like that.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you're building at the same time and sometimes you're mixing up the building.
Speaker 0: Well, that's especially with the three and four player game.
Speaker 0: It's the ebb and flow of knowing when to capitalize.
Speaker 0: It adds a lot of tactical elements to the game that would otherwise be lacking.
Speaker 1: one thing I definitely learned though is you don't want to do like, you know, I mean you think okay Why don't I just every turn buy a little bit and build a little bit?
Speaker 1: well Because then sometimes you need to build like two or three things at a time in order to get a lock and if you build One piece of land then the other guy knows where you're going and he'll cut you off over there.
Speaker 1: and now you wasted that build Right where.
Speaker 1: if you would have built land animal animal you would have gotten your mood You would have gotten in there all at once and you wouldn't have foreshadowed your move before you executed it.
Speaker 1: So it's sort of the game sort of forces you to.
Speaker 1: you know Do the big moves instead of doing lots of little ones in terms of building?
Speaker 1: So you tend to.
Speaker 1: you tend to do lots of similar actions, you know, bye-bye-bye build build build take card Take card take card all at once.
Speaker 0: I also really like.
Speaker 0: I like the fact that you have all these different mechanisms to get money and mechanisms to get victory points and They feel like unfair combos the first time you play.
Speaker 0: like you look at how scoring works to get money from animals And you think well, what if I just like build all the way around that market?
Speaker 0: I'll score it every time but everything in the game is like that.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: The other thing is that You know, it's I forgot what I was gonna say, right?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Well here are two other things.
Speaker 0: one Most games, you know older German games tended to have these scoring rounds mechanic as opposed to continuous I was gonna say or in-game scoring.
Speaker 0: Like I remember Al Grande had the neat you go turn turn scoring around turn turn scoring around turn turn scoring around.
Speaker 0: This is basically the college class Semester version of that.
Speaker 0: there are two scoring rounds Once when the animal deck is depleted the first time and once when the animal deck is depleted the second.
Speaker 1: you basically cut the animal Deck in half and when it runs out you score.
Speaker 1: and when it runs out again you score on the game's over and you score The same way both times.
Speaker 0: It's amazing.
Speaker 0: You have to either I just count how many victory points I have and how many victory points the other person has Every round and just keep it in my head.
Speaker 0: Yep, but You have to be ready.
Speaker 0: Like right now we're playing the game.
Speaker 0: There are four animal cards left in the deck.
Speaker 0: If anyone buys an animal card, the other person has the ability to force scoring immediately.
Speaker 0: Yep, and The ebb and that's why I did not buy an animal card my last turn because I want to leave it at four.
Speaker 0: We're in an interesting situation to where Scott has no cards left at all.
Speaker 0: None, no animals.
Speaker 1: No thing, but I have a shit ton of money.
Speaker 0: you do so you can buy stuff But then I can force the scoring ground.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I go second.
Speaker 0: So as soon as I force it you don't get to do anything.
Speaker 1: The thing is instead of you know buying cards on my turn I can buy water.
Speaker 0: You can buy water, but I can buy animals.
Speaker 1: That's true Anyway, so yeah, the thing is with this game right is?
Speaker 1: it's sort of easy to get a lot of money?
Speaker 1: Right, but getting a lot of money doesn't necessarily get you a lot of victory points.
Speaker 1: Like you could just surround a market with animals and you get a pile of money But you won't really get a lot of victory points for that because it's only one market.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the unique part of this game.
Speaker 0: It is possible to remove yourself effectively from the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is also it.
Speaker 0: well Here's an example.
Speaker 0: you can basically if you are stupid or if you're trying Put yourself in a situation where you don't have enough money to buy any cards.
Speaker 0: You have already played all of your cards And you cannot use any of the existing mechanics in the game to get any more money Mm-hmm, and there there's no way in the rules to recover from that.
Speaker 1: not that I know of there's.
Speaker 0: I read the rules.
Speaker 0: There's no way to recover.
Speaker 0: It's just you're done.
Speaker 1: The other thing.
Speaker 0: I think rare to see a game like that like in Puerto Rico.
Speaker 0: There is no way to make yourself 100% destitute because there's the prospector.
Speaker 0: Yes, there isn't even a prospector.
Speaker 0: if you've harvested you're like one plantation and then you spend all that money.
Speaker 1: Even if you're playing Puerto Rico without a prospector the balloons will pile up on the thing nobody wants and you can take that thing.
Speaker 1: the
Speaker 0: thing is it's interesting that this trap is here because it's the equivalent of the Platform that you can't jump off of in a Mario game where the only way off is to wait for the time it'll run out Or to jump in the pit Mmm, and usually that is the hallmark of poorly thought-out design.
Speaker 0: I wonder if they anticipated it or they just assume that no one would be stupid enough to do it.
Speaker 1: I mean It's so easy to get money and they start you off with so many so much stuff That it's kind of it's.
Speaker 1: it's kind of hard for it to ever happen.
Speaker 1: It's you're really dumb.
Speaker 0: It's trivial if you go for it, though It is true that you go for it.
Speaker 0: You can go for it and just be out of the game.
Speaker 1: the other thing about the game though, is that it's trivial to get money right but It's you.
Speaker 1: actually.
Speaker 1: the actions are a scarcer resource than the money.
Speaker 1: It's like you can't spend all your money unless you spend it all on Haciendas and water.
Speaker 1: if you spend all your money on cards and actually use the cards to get more money You're just gonna have so much money that you're not gonna know you can't spend it all.
Speaker 1: so it's like money isn't really a limitation.
Speaker 1: But even so you're still.
Speaker 1: you think money isn't a limit, right?
Speaker 1: So I should just concern myself with my actions and not worry about how much money I have and that's true to an extent.
Speaker 1: but more money is more victory points because every ten dollars is a victory point and while money means more I You know, if you have a big lineup, you can get ten dollars.
Speaker 1: with like one card play Like you play one animal you get ten bucks.
Speaker 1: So That's a whole victory point, which is kind of a big deal when they add up turn after turn.
Speaker 1: That's the other interesting thing, you know, so even though you don't need more money You're still gonna be trying to get more.
Speaker 0: be difficult to fall into trap of.
Speaker 0: I'm out of the game is there.
Speaker 0: There's also the subtler trap of.
Speaker 0: it's very easy to for a novice player to get focused on Generating money and kind of forget to generate victory points.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a novice player would definitely make that mistake.
Speaker 0: I feel like what would add to the game is to Have a scoring chart and just keep your score up to date all the time.
Speaker 1: like the online version has a checkbox You can check.
Speaker 1: that will keep score every turn.
Speaker 1: Yep So if you want to do you can also.
Speaker 1: there's nothing stopping you from doing that.
Speaker 1: I mean the game, you know has the standard scoring track around the board, you know You can just move your guys every turn.
Speaker 1: if you really want to know nothing stopping you from doing it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I feel like you should.
Speaker 0: I think it would make it.
Speaker 0: otherwise it just adds the.
Speaker 0: you know A lot of earlier German board games will have the memory mechanic where things aren't hidden from the players.
Speaker 0: but you have to remember it all and I Like Tigers and Euphrates.
Speaker 0: once I started counting who needed what color I did a lot better in the game.
Speaker 0: And it like is in El Grande.
Speaker 0: if I just counted how many stupid people are in the Castille It's almost trivial to win if no one else is counting.
Speaker 0: Yep, and other people never count.
Speaker 1: yeah, and the thing is I do kind of like the The halfway through scoring because it sort of makes you think about like, you know, okay You know if I do something in the first half of the game, it'll get scored twice, right?
Speaker 1: so but if I do something in the The second half of the game, it'll only get scored once right?
Speaker 1: It's like save your hacienda.
Speaker 1: right that hacienda will count double if you buy it early enough in the game.
Speaker 1: So it's sort of Scoring twice makes you sort of.
Speaker 1: but you know, it's like ah shit I gotta buy the hacienda now early in the game to get more points instead of later in the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So it's sort of it adjusts your purchasing patterns based on how if the animal decks about to run out and stuff Wouldn't happen if you scored every turn how's the end is it?
Speaker 0: You know, it's a pretty good game.
Speaker 0: It's worth the money if you're a German boarding fan, and I'll just buy it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, it's it's.
Speaker 1: you know It's a normal.
Speaker 1: I think it comes in the same style box as Attica, right?
Speaker 1: I think yeah same company.
Speaker 0: I feel like it has the same level of staying power as like.
Speaker 0: It's better than a game like to call that's for sure our Maya or Mexico or all those games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's sort of like a night.
Speaker 1: It's not like an a-plus game.
Speaker 1: It's like a solid b-plus a-minus game.
Speaker 1: You know that you'll keep on your shelf.
Speaker 1: You'll bust it out once in a while.
Speaker 1: really good It's.
Speaker 1: it's really good for people who are not like super German board gamers and they'll learn a lot of basic German board game mechanics like, you know buying resources using action points Drafting from a from a draw pile and positioning on a board Tron style, you know,
Speaker 0: you know what?
Speaker 0: I don't know why it's it.
Speaker 0: I can't really articulate why I feel this way, but I realized it.
Speaker 0: It reminds me a little bit of Lachita, but not game mechanic wise just in terms of I think it has the exact same Staying power before we'll get sick of it that Lachita does.
Speaker 1: it has some similarities to Lachita in terms of the positioning on the board with the hex tiles So and also the politics cards draw Drafting.
Speaker 0: but at the same time Lachita is so much more limiting and it has the influence factors and all the completely separate different game.
Speaker 1: I think what I like about Hacienda is that it just sort of takes all these like extremely Fundamental and basic German board game mechanics.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have a stick.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have anything fancy, you know.
Speaker 1: It's totally just bread and butter.
Speaker 1: But it's like that really good bread and butter you get when you sit at when you.
Speaker 1: they serve you before you eat a meal At a fancy restaurant, you know, nothing special, but it's just solid.
Speaker 1: Does the basics really really well with really nice polish, you know, and it comes out a very nice game.
Speaker 1: Very happy with the haciendas.
Speaker 0: So should we even bother talking about another game at this point?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: How long has it been?
Speaker 0: as long as a normal show?
Speaker 1: All right, it's up to you.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week Covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front road crew calm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Speaker 1: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 1: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.