Speaker 1: It's Monday November 2nd.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: Scott didn't record the opener with me, and this is geek night tonight the ruins of the Internet's.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So you know what this is this episode of geek nights right here, which once again has Scott live from Skype Crab people.
Speaker 1: yeah, I got Scott Bo Scott over the Internet, but you know what I can see out my window.
Speaker 1: What can you see out your window?
Speaker 0: Manhattan.
Speaker 0: ah You know what it's not a giant blue penis like.
Speaker 1: tell you that you know I wasn't gonna make a giant blue penis joke because it seemed like you know the only joke to make those the only reason to even say But he's not even a doctor.
Speaker 1: It's just Manhattan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I also see a bridge, but I'm not sure what.
Speaker 1: but there's something else important about tonight's show.
Speaker 1: It's actually the first episode of season five of deep nights.
Speaker 0: You're counting the season.
Speaker 1: remember we up.
Speaker 1: we used to put the seasons in the id3 and then we stop Five.
Speaker 0: it's season 20.
Speaker 0: It's year five your five.
Speaker 0: Why is it season 20 then?
Speaker 1: Four seasons per year now, but it's one overarching season, and then we have different story arcs like cowboy bebop or get sack.
Speaker 1: Those don't have story arcs at all yeah, but internally there's the standalone episodes and the complex episodes But they're all part of the same season, but we don't have any complex, but we have Monday Tuesday Wednesday and Thursday.
Speaker 0: Which ones of those are complex?
Speaker 1: pretty much only the Mondays and The other four shows are basically review media or bitch about stuff and then Monday is like failing in last.
Speaker 0: today other four shows.
Speaker 0: What's the picture?
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: the other four shows from nothing?
Speaker 1: the specials?
Speaker 1: Okay Yeah, but you know that aside for Halloween we kept saying we're gonna do a state of the podcast on Halloween.
Speaker 0: And then now you kept saying I didn't say shit the Royal way, so we Maybe I've been part of your way, maybe to differentiate that.
Speaker 1: There's a tasteless joke.
Speaker 1: I'll skip there, but maybe instead I should always whenever someone's using the Royal we I feel like you should say whoa like some sort of like way.
Speaker 1: Maybe put a roll the R.
Speaker 0: That's silent That's not rolling the art.
Speaker 1: if it's a silent R. It's definitely rolled.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so here let me do Some Sort of opening bits.
Speaker 1: I was about to say instead of you know doing a state of the podcast We just went into the city with a bunch of our friends and watched the Halloween parade Which the theme this year was here be dragons.
Speaker 0: Yeah that That part with the with the water in the old-school map that was good stuff.
Speaker 1: That was pretty hardcore.
Speaker 1: That was there was that the highlights of the parade were pretty much that which was like the main thing and that one Gigantic crawling skeleton that was far bigger than I thought.
Speaker 0: Yep, let's see what's going on over here.
Speaker 0: I got the TV today.
Speaker 0: Okay, okay, okay?
Speaker 1: No couch now.
Speaker 1: Did you order a couch?
Speaker 1: you haven't picked a couch yet, and I picked the couch.
Speaker 0: I just have an order to get cuz I need some money.
Speaker 1: yeah Couches are surprisingly expensive and the weird thing is because this one's actually you know come I look.
Speaker 0: I was look at it.
Speaker 0: I was like it was like $200 delivery from Ikea like.
Speaker 0: But actually it's.
Speaker 0: even.
Speaker 1: then it turns out like other couches like 1200 before delivery, so I'm like well I'm looking at couches to do my possible house and the more I look it's like the more expensive.
Speaker 1: the more like minimalist and simple the couch is the more expensive it is.
Speaker 0: Now this.
Speaker 0: I'll show you this one that I'm gonna get.
Speaker 0: maybe you can get the same one.
Speaker 0: It's really.
Speaker 0: it's very good for sleeping on to.
Speaker 0: I laid on it at the IKEA And it was like oh
Speaker 1: so kind of this vague idea of I want like one kind of small stylish couch with maybe Like a built-in table on it like fancy style and low and then I want a bunch of like low Stylist change lounges upstairs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, here's the thing is like I got this TV and the TV is pretty low.
Speaker 0: It's not like high up.
Speaker 0: So if I sit in my freedom chair I sort of have to look down at it say you should have mounted it higher or mounted it on one of those arms.
Speaker 0: It's not mounted on the wall It's sitting on the thing mounted on the wall.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: I can't.
Speaker 0: I could do that.
Speaker 1: Why not just pay someone?
Speaker 1: they'll do it.
Speaker 0: the thing is I got until I get a couch Or like a sumo.
Speaker 0: it's real uncomfortable TV.
Speaker 1: I'm definitely thinking
Speaker 0: I get a rug the couch and like maybe one or two sumos eventually
Speaker 1: I'm definitely thinking about when I get the TV wherever I am mounting it If not on the swivel arm at least on the you know angle the TV slightly in any direction arm.
Speaker 0: That's the thing is odd.
Speaker 0: What's on the stand and went because it's on the stand.
Speaker 0: I can aim it at the kitchen and I can aim it at the computer Or I can aim it straight ahead at the couch.
Speaker 0: that doesn't exist yet, so it's like.
Speaker 0: I can aim it any which way It's very good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking about in the kitchen because I don't in that if I get that house Then I don't need the kitchen monitor and the kitchen computer with the kitchen sound system because it's kind of close enough to the living room.
Speaker 1: see the TV.
Speaker 0: yeah, I have a bedroom and I have the Core CV sound system.
Speaker 1: I've saved up.
Speaker 0: I just need something for the computer here.
Speaker 0: It's very annoying to have no audio on the computer.
Speaker 1: sadly I've saved up so much money.
Speaker 1: You know just as this house has taken so long to buy because apparently the people owed it before me never Ever paid property taxes and the bank's trying to sort that shit out I've saved up so much money.
Speaker 1: I might just buy a bigger house nearby at this point and just forget this the house.
Speaker 0: I'm waiting on What you gonna do.
Speaker 1: yeah, I got a lot of money in the bank because I expected to have a mortgage payment.
Speaker 1: So I was being frugal, so I've got all this money.
Speaker 0: No frugal right now The only things I'm buying are necessities like food right.
Speaker 1: I only spent a thousand dollars last month.
Speaker 1: total.
Speaker 0: Yep, I'm buying.
Speaker 0: you know rent obviously paying the bill You know all the.
Speaker 0: you know transportation all the necessities, and then the only other things.
Speaker 0: I'm spending money on our household things, and that's it.
Speaker 0: so that's like Until I have all the household things sorted out not buying any luxury of any sort.
Speaker 1: Oh, no beacon got a lot more exciting.
Speaker 1: I was not running yesterday and I see you know there's all those like all around beacon.
Speaker 1: more and more I'm seeing those weird Verizon trailers.
Speaker 1: They're like a little trailer with the door on it and then a bunch of cables just come out and go up into the poles.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not quite a few of those.
Speaker 1: so I finally went up to one and I looked at it and on the side It said Verizon FiOS something and then behind it they put the labels on whatever.
Speaker 1: no behind It was a big sign that was like and it was pointing at the street.
Speaker 1: I just never noticed it because it faces the street of like another subdivision Right next to where I live now, and it was like FiOS installed here, and it pointed at a house that had FiOS.
Speaker 1: So I was like oh shit, so I look online and FiOS is here at this house.
Speaker 1: I could get it if I was gonna stay here.
Speaker 1: It's not at the other half of beacon yet, but all the beacons getting FiOS real soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean there was that house that was like on the edge of fish killed near the highway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now it's all the way up.
Speaker 1: You know that subdivision on the road that goes up to the prison right at the edge of beacon they have FiOS.
Speaker 1: now Oh Yeah, like right next to that the rice store.
Speaker 1: So I'm kind of excited and I'm looking.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking more and more.
Speaker 1: I might get the business class FiOS and we could theoretically Bring the geek guides hosting fully in-house and have a lot more capability to do crazy bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think you know let's leave it at lino.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I think my plan We should always have a line.
Speaker 0: Oh, you should know what we should do with that sort of hosting is video.
Speaker 1: We can house video and game servers to start well.
Speaker 0: We could do that.
Speaker 0: We could bring we get rid of the libs in you know and you can all.
Speaker 0: yeah He servers you know all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 1: basically what I want to do is one.
Speaker 1: I want to keep the line out cuz it's good to have a secondary site and to have you know distributed hosting especially if we start consolidating.
Speaker 0: But I just love the idea of having like so their electricity is a little bit more reliable than say you know your house Yeah, but at the same time.
Speaker 1: I'm planning on getting beefy equipment.
Speaker 1: cuz remember.
Speaker 1: I have access to the old like IBM gray market.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna buy gigantic ups.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna buy ups big enough to at least keep a server rag going for a couple hours Mmm.
Speaker 1: No you know one of the as big as I would need it for a couple of servers on the cat.
Speaker 1: That kind of rack would be like 400 bucks.
Speaker 1: Huh even so anyway, that's half a couch almost yeah, but I've to be fair as I whip out my penis I make a lot more money than you.
Speaker 1: I have money to just piss away on bullshit.
Speaker 0: You know make that much money Almost twice what you make The What's it called.
Speaker 0: I had to buy some HDMI cables right and luckily they showed up today.
Speaker 0: But I ordered them from that mono price calm that everyone seems to love.
Speaker 1: that's a good site.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got a two HDMI cables.
Speaker 0: guess how much they were individually.
Speaker 1: You wouldn't ask unless it was real high or real low.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna say six bucks.
Speaker 0: They were like a dollar ninety two I.
Speaker 1: The thing is six bucks.
Speaker 1: I would have thought yeah, that's a great deal You know.
Speaker 0: and the thing was I was gonna get him from Amazon basics.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: Amazon has this new thing Amazon basics Or be here, which is exactly what it sounds.
Speaker 1: you're almost gonna say basically, and then you didn't.
Speaker 0: it's basically like Amazon.
Speaker 0: there goes It's Amazon branded stuff and one of the stuff.
Speaker 0: They have is you know cable.
Speaker 1: I didn't know they were doing that.
Speaker 1: that means by Amazon stock Jesus.
Speaker 0: You can get like an Amazon branded USB cable you know.
Speaker 0: and thing is they have some HDMI cables here, let's see HDMI cable for about six bucks, but mono price beat Amazon.
Speaker 1: You know it's interesting because Amazon beat everyone in the world except for specialty tech stuff like cables or Electronics.
Speaker 1: you got to go to like Newegg or one of those specially cable place.
Speaker 0: one more one more thing about this And then we will proceed with our show.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: HDMI cables that I got there.
Speaker 0: HDMI version 1.3, so I was like what the hell was version 1.0.
Speaker 0: Are we on version 2. yet am I sure about getting the right one?
Speaker 0: I'm like what the hell's the difference right.
Speaker 0: so I went to Wikipedia, and you know what it says what it said.
Speaker 0: Well first of all 1.3 is just fine.
Speaker 0: That's what you want right now right, but coming very soon is 1.4.
Speaker 1: It's like the different DVI's where you could use DVI like one cable have two different monitors on it or like That DVI dual link.
Speaker 0: that's completely different
Speaker 1: because there's also like some DVI cables can support the old analog stuff like in Parallel and some cans
Speaker 0: now the straight-up upgrade you know alright, so here's the thing HDMI 1.3 can do our you know color video right in either RBG mode or YC BCR mode.
Speaker 0: it's basically DVI video.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right it can do DV audio super audio CD Automatic lip-syncing true HD something Dolby something DTS audio stuff, right?
Speaker 0: That's what HDMI 3 1.3 can do.
Speaker 0: HDMI 1.4 can also Am number one.
Speaker 0: it has an audio return channel so audio can go both ways on it at the same time Alright.
Speaker 0: number two it has some sort of 3d over HDMI, which I think is possibly for 3d movies.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure exactly.
Speaker 0: It's it's something.
Speaker 1: yeah Well, I see more and more 3d stuff is I think gonna pick up because that I can't keep that in the realm of the theater.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not sure exactly what it is, but it's 3d over HDMI.
Speaker 0: Whatever that means it can support a much much larger resolution video.
Speaker 0: I like a red camera hooked up with HDMI almost.
Speaker 0: It's 4k alright And you know what else you can have on there with all that other stuff on this one cable You're not gonna.
Speaker 0: You know you're not gonna say HDMI 1.4 can also have Ethernet at the same time.
Speaker 1: Ha that's actually what.
Speaker 0: with one cable you can have Ethernet in both directions.
Speaker 0: audio in both directions.
Speaker 0: 3d ultra high definition video in one direction and by the way the audio is basically perfect.
Speaker 0: digital audio One cable.
Speaker 1: It's a good cable that that's what happens when you move everything to digital And you don't need analog for anything anymore.
Speaker 1: you can have longer cable lengths, and you can cram more into the cable.
Speaker 0: Yep, see the reason that this cable can do all this though right it's good.
Speaker 0: think about it.
Speaker 0: None of those that you know you can't people like.
Speaker 0: oh welcome USB isn't?
Speaker 0: you know that great?
Speaker 0: You know it's like.
Speaker 0: well because this is just a dumb cable.
Speaker 0: USB as actually has a serial data transfer protocol that needs thinking.
Speaker 0: You know both ends.
Speaker 0: HDMI is just like take the audio shove it down the wire.
Speaker 0: You know there's not a lot of thinking going on in the protocol.
Speaker 0: It just sends it down the wire straight up, and it assumes.
Speaker 0: You know reliability and such.
Speaker 0: so All right.
Speaker 0: So new that's going on.
Speaker 1: I got a bunch of news.
Speaker 1: Do you have any news?
Speaker 0: Do I have a news?
Speaker 0: Well there's so much tech news going on.
Speaker 0: I don't know which one I'm gonna talk about.
Speaker 0: I don't feel like I have a lot to say about some of the really good ones.
Speaker 1: You know I want to talk a little bit about even though it's more society than it is really technology.
Speaker 1: But there's that whole story about the blogger that supposedly humiliated an entire set of town counselors into resigning by basically calling them out on whatever.
Speaker 0: Actually, it is enough.
Speaker 1: people read his blog that cared and mattered from what I can gather and obviously not all the details are readily Available and I did not engage in any significant amount of journalism.
Speaker 1: I basically read slashdot comments, and then I followed like one link some slashdot guy linked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the opposite of journalism.
Speaker 1: I would argue that that's more journalism than was put into the majority of newspaper articles I attempted to read in print in the last month Maybe I bought a New York Times not that long ago.
Speaker 1: I was curious.
Speaker 1: I was curious how low the rabbit hole went kind of like how I went back to dig the other day.
Speaker 0: It's just old news.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: It's not even just that.
Speaker 1: it was old news.
Speaker 1: It was poorly written old news.
Speaker 1: like I could write a better article just by looking on the internet.
Speaker 1: I'll tell it anyone understand it that I'm not even talking poorly written like written at the seventh grade level like most newspapers are.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about just poorly written even for a seventh grader.
Speaker 1: I can write good But there's a lot going on here and as far as I can tell the guy basically was blogging about what was going on and pointing out what the counselors were doing.
Speaker 1: and Enough people Found out about this in his blog to where it wasn't that they read his blog and then got angry.
Speaker 1: It was that they read his blog and then started showing up at the council meetings to see what was going on.
Speaker 1: And as far as I can tell these counselors It's a volunteer position anyway And all that just could not in any way handle public scrutiny and people asking them questions and challenging them in person.
Speaker 1: So they all quit because they couldn't take the heat.
Speaker 1: And I You know, I didn't read all the details.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's a lot more going on here But this is not a story of oh my god blogs are now the future of journalism blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: The real story here.
Speaker 1: Is that Technology is getting to the point to where it is very trivial for one person doing any amount of investigative journalism In a non national realm like anything local anything small To bring enough physical local pressure on to people to make stuff happen.
Speaker 1: I mean most local politicians get no Examination whatsoever except like the old biddies who show up to the town council meetings at four o'clock on a Thursday while the rest of us work.
Speaker 1: but if you get if a blogger in the local town gets just enough people interested enough to force them to Do something or come under any scrutiny?
Speaker 1: I don't think a lot of people can deal with scrutiny and especially as far as I can tell the people who resigned were Basically the really conservative people from the conservative part of town who got elected.
Speaker 1: but a lot of other people in the area are more liberal And I've seen this trend where generally at all levels of government.
Speaker 1: people who are reactionary or conservative Really can't actually defend their opinions or their positions against any amount of public questioning or scrutiny.
Speaker 0: I think that's just any.
Speaker 0: most people period yeah Any opinion they have regardless if it's a political Recently questioning whatsoever.
Speaker 0: I
Speaker 1: saw a video recently about it was I think was a state government thing and there was another one at the national level where there was a debate about whether or not to legalize marijuana and All the people who were pro legalization had actual arguments and when confronted with counter arguments responded.
Speaker 1: and all that Without question.
Speaker 1: everyone against the legalization of marijuana Had talking points and the moment anyone questioned those talking points or provided an argument that they didn't have a talking point for they had no answer at all and More and more.
Speaker 1: I think it's just you know the old argument that people say the media is biased toward liberals or that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: I think it's just that the meat more and more the facts are biased toward the right answers and it's harder and harder to hide from the fact that your position is indefensible when Very few people can use technology that more and more of the people defending indefensible positions don't understand to bring to light their indefensibility.
Speaker 0: Could be?
Speaker 0: I mean You know is it?
Speaker 0: is it that there are certain positions that are only held because their holdovers from a time when we didn't know Better?
Speaker 1: and by and large that's the kinds of positions that I see on the wrong side of the people who are also technologically proficient.
Speaker 1: Yeah But also look at this.
Speaker 1: remember sanctuary right, what were they trying to do in sanctuary?
Speaker 0: the goal wasn't really a cousin.
Speaker 1: That aside let that finger fly.
Speaker 0: Did you watch the latest South Park with the whales?
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Fuck you It was genius, but did you notice?
Speaker 0: there's a big boat full of Japanese people.
Speaker 1: yes, and I thought about sanctuary.
Speaker 1: I also thought about sanctuary, but the thing is that was an episode where the whole time I'm like where are they going with this?
Speaker 0: I knew where they were going with it.
Speaker 0: that chicken and cow.
Speaker 1: I saw a chicken and cow coming, but I did not expect the method like the the method of the Enola game Thing right before it.
Speaker 0: I did not know I did not.
Speaker 1: when they zoomed in on that picture Suddenly it all clicked But I'm glad that they waited until the last line of the episode and they're like now.
Speaker 1: you made them normal, and it's like oh Yeah, I knew that was coming.
Speaker 0: yeah still genius yeah.
Speaker 1: But Anyway in sanctuary remember their goal was not take over the government.
Speaker 1: the goal was get people Interested in government again because the people take direct involvement.
Speaker 0: the whole system falls down the old people out And young people.
Speaker 1: all you have to do is bring the baleful gaze of the youth on to government and active And it all.
Speaker 1: it all just works itself out in the end.
Speaker 1: And that's kind of what this guy did here.
Speaker 1: I mean who reads blogs who blogs?
Speaker 1: I mean how many towns are gonna imagine this?
Speaker 1: I imagine the scene ten years from now town council meeting and all the councilors are like old men and old women.
Speaker 1: and then Suddenly like at one town council meeting 20 punk kids show up and start asking questions and using words that the old people just don't understand.
Speaker 1: And then all they don't want.
Speaker 0: the one thing about this those right people always talk about.
Speaker 0: you know they want open government.
Speaker 0: They want to know they want to see what's going on right, and it's like well first of all We had c-spans.
Speaker 0: the government is actually pretty open when you think about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the problem is I born That's true, but if you look at like you know things that have happened.
Speaker 0: like you know I remember there was an article about this.
Speaker 0: It was a Cory Doctorow thing where he talked about how there were like these protests in in the UK and basically there were videos Just police beating up protesters, and it was totally wrong.
Speaker 0: and everyone thought the videos are everywhere.
Speaker 0: It was not a secret.
Speaker 0: it was totally transparent right and Nothing happened, and he's like transparency doesn't matter without justice.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's like You're mad going on if you can't do anything about it.
Speaker 0: It's you know.
Speaker 0: it's like think about it.
Speaker 0: if those people went and questioned those town council people and the town council people were dicks And just ignored them then none of it would have mattered.
Speaker 1: But at the same time the sense of social justice.
Speaker 1: so 20 punk kids show up right and they Basically show up and they get blown off.
Speaker 1: either They don't get mad and they give up or they get mad.
Speaker 1: they get mad.
Speaker 1: and if they get mad Like the guy in the movie that we talk about all the time now if they get mad in the non rioting way and they just keep coming back to the council meetings and they force debate if it's one of those councils where they can if they Force fucking Roberts rules of order every time and be as legally pain in the ass as they possibly can.
Speaker 1: I Don't think the old people ruining things can keep up with that and then fight it for too long without getting tired and Independently of that say they don't win even doing that.
Speaker 1: the next step They go out and they start getting everyone else riled up because think about it you and me Could put to bear enough resources to pause to probably like change everything in local government in like beacon.
Speaker 1: I mean we could print more flyers than anyone printed in all the campaigns combined for the election.
Speaker 1: now We can make websites and blogs and we could just we could do crazy media that the people currently running for office Don't even know how to do.
Speaker 0: The thing is they can walk around town to every house.
Speaker 0: We can't really do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I don't think you need to do that anymore because if you just get enough people angry I mean How did Michael Moore get elected?
Speaker 1: you get all the 18 year olds to vote for him and 18 year olds voted in more numbers Than everyone else combined.
Speaker 0: That's when he was 18 and in high school and he knew all the 18 year olds in his small.
Speaker 1: So if you and I if we go to a high school and we're all hip and cool and we don't Arrest us as soon as you walk onto the grass now Because what you got to do is fake it all and be like lecture series.
Speaker 1: I want to do an assembly and we're business professionals.
Speaker 1: We can easily get an assembly at a high school.
Speaker 0: The school has you to do an assembly you don't ask them to do.
Speaker 1: now a lot of assembly people approach high schools.
Speaker 1: be like I have this assembly.
Speaker 1: Will you let me do it?
Speaker 0: Maybe we should get in the assembly business.
Speaker 1: I want to.
Speaker 1: I really want to.
Speaker 1: I just haven't spent much effort on it.
Speaker 0: You're gonna make the greatest assembly.
Speaker 0: like kids.
Speaker 0: your grades don't mean shit, but if you got bad grades, you're a moron.
Speaker 1: and also You pull the bait and smash.
Speaker 1: your assembly is like you start doing something normal and then you're like Wargle-bargle.
Speaker 1: come to the assembly meetings vote for me.
Speaker 1: We'll change everything I'll make your I'll drink big age 18. just lie to them and then they'll all show up Steve.
Speaker 1: oh But I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think I think that.
Speaker 1: Well, look at our, you know Scott Johnson our friend of FRC member the good Scott Johnson.
Speaker 1: He is running for local government and he's like the youngest dude to run like ever out there.
Speaker 0: I think we just need to change the rules that say you have to be like what like 40 something to be run for president.
Speaker 0: I mean that's complete bullshit at this point.
Speaker 0: Yeah Because it's in the Constitution, I know we need an amendment big time.
Speaker 0: We should also need to really amend even more.
Speaker 0: so the one with the age limits on Congress.
Speaker 0: You're 18.
Speaker 0: You should be able to run for anything.
Speaker 0: period you know, and if people you know, if people actually believe You know what if you're 18, you know the smoker drink is not qualified then don't vote for this not even further.
Speaker 1: I think the age of whatever we pick the age of majority to be should be.
Speaker 1: it should be 100% rights.
Speaker 1: But I mean no qualification at all if you're 18 and that's the age of majority Drinking smoke and everything.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: It's hypocritical.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: You know to give one and not the other.
Speaker 1: But then I won't be able to buy any more ultra porn.
Speaker 0: No, I can't rent ultra porn anymore.
Speaker 0: All right, I'll do this one thing of the day real quick Just one side thing of the day Thing of the day.
Speaker 0: news real quick.
Speaker 0: All right, so apparently there's actually some movement in the department of web fonts.
Speaker 0: I don't know if people understand the situation here, right, but basically In your web browser their web pages really only use like a handful of fonts.
Speaker 0: and the reason they use that handful of fonts is Because those are the only fonts that are like guaranteed to be on every computer.
Speaker 0: because Microsoft I think of the Microsoft like core fonts like Microsoft perp You know put them out there and said these are the fonts everyone can have for free.
Speaker 0: and if you think about like copyright and music Copyright on fonts is like the worst in the universe.
Speaker 0: like This is the real it's.
Speaker 0: it's so horrible like just all the fonts that are like standard font.
Speaker 0: You just can't get it's like, you know, a lot of people like don't even appreciate like, you know.
Speaker 0: They install Photoshop and they get like a bajillion bajillion fonts.
Speaker 0: That's probably the reason Photoshop is so expensive even worse.
Speaker 1: There's so many free fonts and by and large.
Speaker 0: They're awful Terrible, right?
Speaker 1: I mean they look nice if you don't know better, but then we try to use them typographically.
Speaker 1: They're just like they're unbearable like your website looks bad and you don't understand why because it's like some subtle Typographical thing because the font was poorly designed like the kerning is off or something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, typography is actually really complicated and people just you know, if you need anyway the.
Speaker 0: so The thing is like let's say I want to use a font on my website But I don't.
Speaker 0: I can't guarantee that rim has this font on his computer.
Speaker 0: if he comes to my website He's not gonna see the font that I picked.
Speaker 0: he's gonna see like Ariel All right, and that sucks because now I can't make my website all fancy.
Speaker 0: Now what I could do is I could type that fancy font in Photoshop save an image and use that But now Google doesn't see that.
Speaker 0: Google just see image.
Speaker 0: It doesn't know that the image has text in it in my fancy font to make my site look good, right?
Speaker 0: So the ability to use any font on any website and just you know When if rim visited the site and he didn't have the font he would download it somehow.
Speaker 0: That is like a like a holy grail of websites.
Speaker 0: So much because you could make your site look.
Speaker 0: however, you want it typographically with any font that you had.
Speaker 1: Think about the fucked up in this of this situation.
Speaker 1: Wow, fuck up in this is now my favorite word.
Speaker 0: Really fucked up in this.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So imagine this I log out of some NS server or counter-strike server and it has an entire map that I don't have.
Speaker 1: It automatically downloads the entire map and then I can play immediately with the same map as everyone else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I go to a website and that doesn't happen with a font Exactly.
Speaker 0: And the reason is because the people who make fonts like these complete copyright douchebags like you can go online and look like individual fonts and There'll be people like charging like hundreds of dollars for a font like just one font to have it.
Speaker 0: You know and like there's a website it's actually a really good website called blam bot Right, and it makes these webs.
Speaker 0: It makes it's his guy and primarily he makes fonts that are used for like comic book lettering and he actually has these really good Fonts for comic book lettering and he's like a really good Typography guy.
Speaker 0: the thing is, you know, he's got free fonts, but he's also got pay fonts that he's also got Limited edition fonts, you know and the pay fonts are not cheap.
Speaker 0: Let's see 20 bucks for one font.
Speaker 0: So, you know, I mean it's good and if I was doing comic book lettering.
Speaker 0: I would probably pay him to help me out because he you know, he's got really good fonts, but 20 bucks for a font Jesus, you know, and so there's no way these people will let you you know Download a font just because you visit a website of someone who has the font.
Speaker 0: then you'll be doing huge You know, where will they get any money if everyone has all these fonts on their computer?
Speaker 0: So Mozilla and other people are finally making progress on Making, you know some fonts that I'll be able to download onto other people's computers.
Speaker 0: So there's going to be support for it in the next Firefox.
Speaker 0: And so we'll see how this goes.
Speaker 0: Hopefully it will work out and not suck.
Speaker 1: So things of the day.
Speaker 1: This is my favorite kind of prank.
Speaker 1: It's the nice knife for a good knife for flying prank.
Speaker 0: Well, it's the kind of inexplicable except the thing is this only the first only the first person who reacts to it reacts in that kind of way.
Speaker 1: Little girl who just looks under there, you know there's a lot of study about how little kids are generally much less easily fooled by Randy bullshit and everything because When confronted with something unbelievable, they ask direct questions and look for direct evidence.
Speaker 1: But adults will go to a chiropractor.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: but anyway that the problem with this prank is that the the video is pretty good because it shows you like how to do the Prank and the good idea, but they don't fully execute the prank the way it needs to be executed.
Speaker 1: The best rank is you make a model that looks exactly like a real kid dressed up as something trick-or-treating And you leave it on someone's doorstep.
Speaker 0: So, you know, they you know trick-or-treat they open the door There's a kid that you have to knock on the door and then you have to hide with a camera that zoomed in so you Can see what's going on or you just leave it there and wait.
Speaker 1: So what?
Speaker 1: but you leave it there right and then you knock on door.
Speaker 1: a person comes out and they react like oh cute Kid the kid doesn't say anything.
Speaker 1: they go kind of whatever.
Speaker 1: they put the candy in the basket The kid still doesn't move.
Speaker 1: close the door kids still doesn't move.
Speaker 1: perfectly stationary uncanny valley on the door.
Speaker 1: again person gets creeped out But the video doesn't really go all the way.
Speaker 1: The real way to do this prank is to get like four or five kids in on it.
Speaker 1: So the kids are all at the door, right?
Speaker 1: So you have like two kids at the door and the fake kid knocking the door trick-or-treat.
Speaker 1: They all take their stuff They all walk away the one kids still there.
Speaker 1: the other group of kids comes up does the same thing the one kids still there.
Speaker 1: Then you knock a third time and just that kids still there.
Speaker 1: and then you just you leave it there and wait for the see What the person does and if they go back into the house or wait you just leave that fucking kid there.
Speaker 1: Or you take the kid away and you put them at the street looking at the house all Style.
Speaker 1: you put them in the bushes looking at.
Speaker 0: the problem is that the people if they look out their window They'll see you moving the kid around.
Speaker 0: that's the difficult part.
Speaker 1: No, cuz it's dark and you have to you know You time it.
Speaker 1: you look through the.
Speaker 1: do you see where they look?
Speaker 1: you'd have to be careful and clever, but you could do it.
Speaker 0: And also if you fail I imagine if they were at the point of being freaked out.
Speaker 1: They would just be in their window looking at the kid though And and as soon as you've gone to that point you have won and you just never touch the kid again.
Speaker 0: Just leave it there and the police would come and take your thing away.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: That's so worth it All right I mean you could go so much further.
Speaker 1: you put it leave it in their backyard just abandon it.
Speaker 1: so they forget about.
Speaker 1: you Know man that creepy kid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then he left and then the next day they walk out the back door.
Speaker 1: He's just standing there.
Speaker 0: I was watching this TED talk and the TED talk was about sabbaticals and how great they are
Speaker 1: Dude, so you leave it there right and then after like a few times you get another kid in on it And you leave him you have him scream and then he lays there like bloody in front of the kid.
Speaker 0: Okay So I watch this TED talk about sabbaticals and how great they are and basically this dude He just he's like hey, I know what I'll do.
Speaker 0: I'll take five years off of my retirement and every seven years I'll go on a sabbatical you know, so he's doing that and It was totally awesome for him.
Speaker 0: and I'm thinking yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: Maybe I could do that too.
Speaker 0: I'm you know working for seven years like 2012 2013.
Speaker 0: I'll go on it's not bad.
Speaker 1: I can you know if I quit my job right now or go on sabbatical and I don't buy that house I have enough money to live for like a year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know, I'm thinking I'd like 2013.
Speaker 0: I'll do it maybe so.
Speaker 0: Anyway the at the end of the video he played like this clip of something and Basically, I researched this thing and I found that on YouTube and what this is is it's a little bit Randy.
Speaker 0: It's it's laughing yoga, you know, and basically the idea is, you know You laugh a lot and then all your stress goes away.
Speaker 0: but also, you know, there's some Randy about like, you know kidneys or whatever.
Speaker 0: right, but The point is is that if you actually watch this laughing yoga guy do his laughing yoga stick.
Speaker 0: It is like anime hell solid gold material.
Speaker 0: this dude is fucked the fuck up and he is like.
Speaker 0: You can't tell if like he's laughing naturally or if he's just sort of like, you know doing the physical motion you know the the Yes, but also just watching him makes you like laughs like he's Laughing.
Speaker 1: the the the the the the the the the the the.
Speaker 0: that's exactly the way he makes you laugh.
Speaker 0: Exactly that way.
Speaker 1: You even almost laughed a little bit at that.
Speaker 0: That's that's the way he makes you laugh and it's like, you know, he's been doing this for however many, you know His whole life I guess, you know, he's a yoga dude.
Speaker 0: So he's probably studying laughing yoga for decades or whatever.
Speaker 0: So that's what he is mastered.
Speaker 0: that so to watch it Watch this is like a minute clip of this dude doing his stick and you know You could do the whole bunch of other videos of him on YouTube doing this stick.
Speaker 0: It's It's something to see before you before you.
Speaker 0: are you still in this war hope?
Speaker 1: So, all right, I guess it's time for the Metamucil, oh That's right.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So here I remembered We did the meta bit the meta moment, right?
Speaker 0: And I forgot that the original one of the original reasons I wanted to do the meta moment was So that we could constantly remind people of the book club.
Speaker 0: and yet that is the one thing we have forgotten to do.
Speaker 1: Yes, it's all all one of you who read Steppenwolf Right.
Speaker 0: I think I think maybe five people read it anyway.
Speaker 1: Alright guys, seriously, if you didn't read Stephen wolf it ends with a game called murder car.
Speaker 1: It's not actually called that but that is what it is and you will see what I mean.
Speaker 0: And that's that's not a lie That's absolutely true.
Speaker 0: So the next book club book is the Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy by Douglas Douglas.
Speaker 0: Douglas I have already almost finished reading the first book I bought like the you know, the five-in-one and I'm pretty much gonna be done with this like in a day.
Speaker 0: So If you don't read it you suck.
Speaker 0: I don't think I have a copy of it anymore But I bought the five copy the five volume thing on it.
Speaker 1: I gotta buy it again.
Speaker 1: you guys cuz I was packing up, you know, I'm moving right?
Speaker 1: I packed up almost all my books into boxes.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it's in one of those boxes.
Speaker 1: fuck Yeah, I love to dig through forever.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna buy it again.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so that'd be book club book the Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy only the first book.
Speaker 0: You can read more if you want and probably will but we're only gonna do that that first one and It's short.
Speaker 0: It's easy.
Speaker 0: I hope I'm pretty sure it's a book that people actually read.
Speaker 0: I've already thought of another one that people actually read for the next time.
Speaker 0: So anyway, that's that.
Speaker 0: Any other meta bits we got going on here?
Speaker 0: Oh, there's a convention this weekend.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, Zenkai con which I still have to write material for the match game Are we do?
Speaker 0: I didn't know we were doing them.
Speaker 1: Yes, we're doing the match game with good game fact.
Speaker 1: two of the guests are people who have been on the match game with us.
Speaker 1: Oh those Yeah, and they all know their anime shit.
Speaker 1: So this is gonna be a more - this is gonna be possibly one of the better match games we've ever run.
Speaker 1: All right Let's go for I'm excited now because it always sucks to run the match game with people who like don't know anything about The like.
Speaker 0: the topic of the convention, you know, I should get the magic.
Speaker 0: we should get the match game music and then we should also.
Speaker 0: Why don't we just get a bunch of original match game questions?
Speaker 1: I did that.
Speaker 1: That's how I wrote that.
Speaker 1: remember when I rewrote all the questions to be more generic.
Speaker 1: I just took original match game questions and change them to sound to have anime proper nouns.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's Let's just you know, let's do some more of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's get like 20 more.
Speaker 0: We should be set.
Speaker 1: But yeah, thank icon is this weekend in, Pennsylvania.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you could equal link to it.
Speaker 0: You can go to it and see.
Speaker 1: yeah Well, the front row crew is gonna be there is gonna be a lot of gaming going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know burning real stuff happening.
Speaker 1: all that it.
Speaker 1: if you want to hang out with us at a con Really?
Speaker 1: You can't hang out with us at any big cons anymore.
Speaker 1: I mean Otacon.
Speaker 1: we got shit to do.
Speaker 1: Connecticut We're running like panels.
Speaker 1: So we're not gonna be able to talk to you at all.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be like hiding in offices yelling.
Speaker 0: It's one day.
Speaker 1: I think yeah, it's like all day Saturday crazy awesome stuff.
Speaker 0: Good, then I'll have actually time to get back to my house.
Speaker 1: I forget if it's two days or not, but whatever I figure we got to plan out all that travel I can.
Speaker 1: either I can take the car down to pick you up in the city and then go straight across or you can take The train up here and then drive all of us.
Speaker 1: The
Speaker 0: problem is it's hard to park at my house at my apartment on well
Speaker 1: No You see because we're going to Jersey one way to do it would be if you took the train to like Tarrytown or something And then I pick you up in Tarrytown and then you start driving from there because then we go right across the Tappan Zee and Then down through Pennsylvania,
Speaker 0: you're better off parking in Jersey near like a path train cheaper.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is dry.
Speaker 1: I've got to drive all the way down through Jersey park the car there and then go to work.
Speaker 0: You could park at my apartment here if there was a spot on Friday with that.
Speaker 1: Granted I am the master of parking in in the city ever since working in the Bronx.
Speaker 0: I can park No, but I have one of the sides of the street gets swept on a Friday.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I'm used to that double triple parking parking on the sidewalk.
Speaker 0: We can't leave it there all day like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've done that before with my car to no ill effect though I once just parked on the sidewalk.
Speaker 1: No one died.
Speaker 0: No trouble Alright, anyway, let's what's the show gonna be about today?
Speaker 1: Well, actually I had a conversation with remember Ken juror from the forums.
Speaker 1: He's an old friend of mine from high school.
Speaker 1: I think he quit the forum a couple times and finally quit it for good because we always talk about how shitty Yeah, but I randomly started talking to him again after you know finding him on LinkedIn and while I was whole I think I was Home sick.
Speaker 1: I forget exactly why I was home, but I was laying in bed tired.
Speaker 1: Maybe I was doing the night shift and we started talking on instant messenger and he found something really Really interesting on the internet.
Speaker 1: and I'm gonna paraphrase all of this.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna like link to all these different pages, but basically He had geocities and angel fire websites much.
Speaker 1: Like I had geocities and angel fire websites man.
Speaker 0: Mine don't exist anymore.
Speaker 1: We linked to each other right because we were friends like all our friends like we linked to each other's websites and signed each other's guestbooks and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: and He was grabbing all the archives and you know say archiving and saving all this juice.
Speaker 1: They didn't know.
Speaker 1: these Granny weird parts of it are still online.
Speaker 0: I don't understand.
Speaker 0: Ah, it's all.
Speaker 1: it's ruins of the internet, which we'll get to.
Speaker 1: so whoa Whoa, you made a weird noise.
Speaker 0: No, you cut out that came over Skype.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: In fact, I can prove it came over Skype because I'm multi tracking here You know, let's let's roll back a little bit now, let's just leave it in fast and loose fast karate for the geek nights great.
Speaker 1: so he points out that his old angel fire website, you know, he had his domain and At some point someone else owned this domain because it was like his screen name.
Speaker 1: But then he got it and then he let it go.
Speaker 1: and all this business.
Speaker 1: So at his old he had found this angel fire website Which had in its URL his screen name, which is also that other guy who once owned the same domain screen name.
Speaker 1: Alright on that website is a pre blog blog as in a table that the guy updated the top with with like these blog posts.
Speaker 1: and this guy who is not Ken is Kind of racist as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: But It's obviously not Ken, but here's the weirdest fucking part.
Speaker 1: He has a link on this page.
Speaker 1: I think he stole the structure of this page from a website that can had once put up or something Because he has a link to quote.
Speaker 1: I got the inspiration to do this from my friend Brad.
Speaker 1: All right, and there's a link on the word Brad.
Speaker 1: if you click on the word Brad The link is to angel fire comm slash NC slash rim.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I click on this as Kevin did.
Speaker 0: no HTML
Speaker 1: and what it links to is not My website not Brad's website but an angel fire site that has the word rim in it and It just has this angel fire ad and there's a quote that says and in the end when all is said and Kings rain the day Fools shall sing and dead shall bring while angels lose their way rim rest in peace.
Speaker 1: And then there are three links talk to the dead remember the past and Email me.
Speaker 1: so email me goes to some I don't even like I want to email this to something on this weird domain.
Speaker 1: talk to the dead is to sign a guest book and remember the past is a Guest book as in an internet guest book that looks like finally stopped getting updated around 2006 Was basically was basically nothing but spam from like 2001 until 2004 like that makes it.
Speaker 1: I've read through the thing like percentage of spam increases as time goes on And if you go all the way back to like it's weird.
Speaker 1: Reading through this and for a while.
Speaker 1: I was trying to figure out if maybe this was like us like a stolen Guest book from like one of my old website.
Speaker 0: It seems like someone like just like copied and pasted some HTMLs and then edited some bits in them but unless all the rest of it intact and didn't know what was going on.
Speaker 0: or.
Speaker 0: but
Speaker 1: at the same time I never
Speaker 0: had a people hacked into like angel fire geocities and just took over whatever site they wanted to and so
Speaker 1: I started poking around more of angel fire and I found all these weird Websites that look like it's like, you know A bunch of hobos break into an abandoned factory and start squatting in it.
Speaker 1: It's almost like internet hobos at the end of the 90s era of the internet like in the early 2000s Broke into old websites and squatted in them.
Speaker 0: You know, they do that today.
Speaker 0: the thing is, you know people usually notice them event.
Speaker 0: It's called vandalism because it's you know,
Speaker 1: but I found all this weird Weird shit all over the internet and the fact that some of this stuff like It's the fact that I found this link on this guy's website with a different name But still links to a website that has my name in it and then like again, I don't know I just don't get it cuz it's not like rim.
Speaker 1: RYM is a common name on the internet Especially the english-speaking internet let alone from the early 2000s when most websites that had rim in them were mine.
Speaker 0: What about the Republican youth majority?
Speaker 0: They don't have brand of underwear that brand of underwear.
Speaker 1: I feel like I should buy that underwear To give people a perspective back in this day like, you know 1999 when I was like doing this stuff on the internet.
Speaker 1: if you searched for rim on the internet You would basically find a bunch of gibberish some of which looked vaguely Gaelic.
Speaker 1: You'd find this weird old etymological website that said it was like an old root of Miriam and it From like old Hebrew languages and it didn't really say much else.
Speaker 1: and he found all my websites.
Speaker 0: Well, you actually found website.
Speaker 1: Well, well, well, well, you found websites.
Speaker 1: insofar as websites could be found in the year 1999 on Alta Vista You find like broken links to like a geostasis page that I'd gotten rid of stuff like that.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So how does this lead into a show topic here?
Speaker 1: There are internet ruins all over the place and We did a show a long time ago on ye olde internet and stuff that used to exist on the air.
Speaker 1: that doesn't exist anymore.
Speaker 1: And I kind of want to talk about that again because I suddenly like remembered Guess that he's got taken down Yeah and I I remembered guest books and I remembered that there used to be a time when I would go to a website and if It was cool.
Speaker 1: I would sign the guest book and be like, hey your website's cool.
Speaker 1: I was here.
Speaker 0: Why don't we make a Facebook guest book?
Speaker 1: There's I think don't like guest books of old but with Facebook doesn't that wall or whatever it is basically do the same thing?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we can make it so that you can put a wall on a page on the internet.
Speaker 1: But isn't that just the same as the side wiki or poop on this website calm or all those things?
Speaker 1: I Guess it's just another place.
Speaker 1: Plus.
Speaker 1: can something like that even work in the modern world?
Speaker 1: because back then there were so few people on the internet and the barrier To entry was so high that there was really no shit cocking him.
Speaker 1: You made a place that people could post stuff.
Speaker 1: People would honestly post stuff.
Speaker 1: There wasn't even really spam for a long time.
Speaker 1: And then like it suddenly there was a bunch of spam and then eventually the spam got kind of overwhelmed by just absolute shitcockery like just just GNA.
Speaker 0: a craziness a GNA.
Speaker 0: I saw somebody on the street.
Speaker 0: They had one of those grocery push carts Yeah, and it it was it a sticker on.
Speaker 0: it said GNA but it was some other GNA.
Speaker 1: But I could if you could die whoever I got a look cuz whoever thinks that they're the GNA They should really change the name because I don't think they know.
Speaker 0: I don't know what was going on there The GNA.
Speaker 1: okay, if you search for GNA you still find the actual bad GNA.
Speaker 1: Okay Wow, yeah, but the second thing down is the Nashville Something The Greater Nashville Apartment Association.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, okay So yeah, but I mean what you're saying there about like old ruins of old websites.
Speaker 0: That's sort of what you know, I mean look at something like SourceForge, right?
Speaker 0: It's like SourceForge is like where all the open source projects went to die back in the day and like 99% of everything on SourceForge is just some old Project that someone started and never worked on.
Speaker 0: and I think what's happening right is because the internet is That you know people used to do things and not finish them.
Speaker 0: We're not very far with them.
Speaker 0: Well, they just had an idea and they started working on it one day But then they stopped and that was it.
Speaker 0: the thing is now because people are working on the internet that thing that you The idea you had and worked on for an hour and then never went back to in your whole life It's out there sitting there taking up space.
Speaker 0: It's a web page.
Speaker 0: Someone can find it Someone can look at it.
Speaker 0: There is you know be on SourceForge or GitHub or Geocities or who knows what?
Speaker 0: It's like they're out there.
Speaker 0: I've got a whole bunch of them.
Speaker 1: It's almost like the internet has become so big and it's evolved so much for so long that I mean look around any city like the city grows up and then like parts of it decay and disappear.
Speaker 1: and We basically the Internet's been around for so long that we have ruins just like real cities do and we have.
Speaker 1: like when geocities Went down that was the equivalent of like in the Bronx bulldozing an old abandoned warehouse full of oboes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the thing is right is actually the reason I think people don't see these things.
Speaker 0: that often right isn't because they aren't there.
Speaker 0: I think there's more and more of them.
Speaker 0: I think it's because how great Google is?
Speaker 0: Google will just never send you there ever because it's like why the hell would you want?
Speaker 0: To go there.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like imagine if you're in a town in the middle of the town was nice and beautiful and these huge Skyscrapers and with clean and polished and amazing and everything outside the town was like this this slum.
Speaker 0: So it was like the infinite slum Even if you sort, you know, there might be some interesting hilarious things out in the slum You know like really creative cool stuff out there.
Speaker 0: But you will never find it because Google will never point you in the slum.
Speaker 0: no matter what you want to find It'll always find someplace in the skyscraper for you to go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's basically the way it is plus the people.
Speaker 1: you know, the old analogy of surfing the web is basically dead.
Speaker 1: No one surfs anymore.
Speaker 1: You don't follow links on a path unless you're like on Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we don't need no web ring.
Speaker 1: God right web rings.
Speaker 1: I mean that was how you'd find a lot of weird stuff.
Speaker 1: cuz you know web ring you'd follow it and you'd have the pages You found were abandoned or disappeared or broken links or whatever.
Speaker 1: Some people would in the web ring take you to a site and they use a frame to like break the web ring and take you Somewhere.
Speaker 1: scary you'd find like Exploring the internet used to be like exploring an abandoned building or exploring a building people were using and now we just the internet is kind of Modernified and we don't find that stuff anymore But it's still out there in fact growing and also think about it.
Speaker 1: when the internet first kind of got big Very there weren't that many Unmaintained websites and very few people put any thought into like.
Speaker 1: what do they do?
Speaker 1: Like they make a website and then if they lost interest in it, they might just forget about it.
Speaker 1: But now there's been so much web siting like we're.
Speaker 1: imagine 20 or 30 years from now I mean penny arcade all this like all the stuff we do.
Speaker 1: Will it be maintained forever?
Speaker 1: Not everyone has the ability to create a corporation to ensure the longevity of the things they create on the internet after their deaths.
Speaker 0: You want to see something?
Speaker 0: You want to do something really crazy, maybe?
Speaker 0: Okay, so Berkshire Hathaway, right?
Speaker 1: I?
Speaker 1: well my 401k is invested in that pretty heavily.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's a company.
Speaker 0: It's what the 17th biggest company in the world something like that.
Speaker 1: Well, they're complicated.
Speaker 1: I mean look on Google Finance look at brk.a that is their primary stock and Look at how many dollars it is to buy one share of that a bajillion, right?
Speaker 0: So Here's I just want to show you something interesting.
Speaker 0: All right, you open up your browser and go to www.berkshirehathaway.com.
Speaker 1: All right, I'll do that.
Speaker 1: There's all this silence.
Speaker 0: talk while I type When you see this website, then you'll understand exactly why I sent you there.
Speaker 1: Wow, it looks exactly like the best website in the world in 2001.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It looks like the best website in the world in 1998 to me.
Speaker 1: I don't know Maybe 2000 because this is because look 1998 it wouldn't have been this polished I know.
Speaker 0: and look it looks like it was actually updated.
Speaker 0: I mean look this part was updated in March of 2009.
Speaker 1: Maybe this is like you've got say you've got an old man who's been living in the same house for 60 years.
Speaker 1: He maintains the house very well, but the house still looks like a house.
Speaker 1: That's 60 years old.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's never renovated it.
Speaker 0: He's got the same refrigerator The same manual garage door the same furniture.
Speaker 0: All right, but it all works.
Speaker 0: it's all still there.
Speaker 0: it's all still updated.
Speaker 0: It's the old man still lives there just fine with his old stupid stove.
Speaker 1: I don't know why he has an ad on the website though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's sort of weird, right?
Speaker 1: You really need that money.
Speaker 0: I mean like even you know people have ads but I mean like You know like mcdonalds.com doesn't have an ad on the front page.
Speaker 1: Microsoft.com does not advertise anything but Microsoft products.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's see mcdonalds.com.
Speaker 0: yeah, there is no ads on mcdonalds.com that are anything but McDonald's, you know.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so yeah I just you know, I mean this is sort of crazy that you can have things like this that are still around.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like don't you think that such a big company would have something modern?
Speaker 0: but no not really.
Speaker 0: They're still using the same old website from a hundred years ago.
Speaker 1: But I wonder where this trend is going to lead.
Speaker 1: I mean imagine we're gonna get to the points where a lot of the people kind of like how Children of the 80s right now are going through the.
Speaker 1: all the celebrities from my childhood are dying because they're getting to that age where people die and every generation kind of goes through that.
Speaker 1: but the internet generation is gonna go through that in a really weird way because Stuff doesn't stick around.
Speaker 1: Past your own death unless you have all these legal structures Like you might have like podcasting might have all the skills to do like a podcast about something But if you don't know about technology and about audio and about websites, you still can't really make a good podcast.
Speaker 0: Think about that.
Speaker 0: think about how many people started podcasts and then stop them.
Speaker 0: think about how many podcasts are out there.
Speaker 0: They're like two episodes five episodes and they're just sitting there with no listeners and eventually they'll disappear on the internet.
Speaker 0: They're there for now on iTunes and find them.
Speaker 1: but like think about geek night say Scott and I, you know We know about technology.
Speaker 1: So we got geek nights like really good technology wise Let's say we didn't know anything about Like corporations or money or anything like that and we never incorporated and we never like set up all the structures the meta structures that would survive us and continue the geek nights or at least you know, Like I'll trust to ensure that geek night stayed online forever like the archive website.
Speaker 1: So then what if we died, you know and eventually at least Scott will die.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'll be I won't die but Ever but Eventually will die.
Speaker 1: and then geek nights would eventually, you know all the websites we created like the legal custody of that might go to our families or something.
Speaker 1: if we didn't set the wheels up Ride and it eventually would all corrode and disappear.
Speaker 1: disappear unless someone saved it with money in law.
Speaker 0: So that's an archive that argues about.
Speaker 0: but think about it.
Speaker 1: That's the only people doing it one person And most of the internet has not only no legal wherewithal but no technological wherewithal.
Speaker 1: I Mean myspace and Facebook in places like that are just now barely Getting to the point of setting up structures to handle that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: and I mean you look at things like parthenon and sphinxes and pyramids and castles, right it's like There it's a there it's like on the internet.
Speaker 0: people put houses and it's not even you know 20 years old 30 years old in terms of public access and already they're completely gone.
Speaker 0: You know all of Geocities were totally wiped out.
Speaker 1: Yeah As we Peter off into silence, I don't think there's that much else to say and I'm really really hungry and Skype always makes this difficult.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anything else going on by you there?
Speaker 1: And I really I want to get some dinner.
Speaker 1: my house is basically this weird because I'm the only one living in it.
Speaker 1: really.
Speaker 1: so Nothing moves unless I move it and it's an interesting experience that I have not had for a long time.
Speaker 1: Things not moving is a strange experience.
Speaker 1: like You did move a lot of things at least in the downstairs of the house All around the living room my stuff would move and now just nothing moves.
Speaker 0: I Things moving or not moving in my apartment here the other thing and it's not related to Monday at all.
Speaker 1: But today I was looking at the board games and I really wanted to play a board game.
Speaker 0: I Also really want to play a board game.
Speaker 0: Maybe you should come over play some board game.
Speaker 1: Oh, we got zinc.
Speaker 1: I would get something for me to sleep on and I'll come over.
Speaker 0: Help me on how lend me some money.
Speaker 0: I'll buy that couch.
Speaker 1: I think I'm gonna buy an inflated mattress and leave it at your apartment.
Speaker 0: You could do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually, that'd be pretty good to be something to lay on.
Speaker 0: while watching this TV.
Speaker 1: We have a zinc icon other than the panels we're doing.
Speaker 1: I pretty much am just going to sit and play board games and burning wheel with people.
Speaker 0: Sounds good to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, I think we're done here Fast karate for the geek nights.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna keep saying that until we get better technology technological solutions to these.
Speaker 1: Skype.
Speaker 1: Scott in I ordered a.
Speaker 0: I ordered a headset but that's better than this Xbox 360 headset that I'm using but it's not.
Speaker 1: it's not like an expensive Thinking about so maybe doing a Thursday episode where you know since we're skyping anyway Maybe we'll Skype someone else in in addition to us and do some sort of roundtable or something or another Profile and geek like we were doing for a while.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's get some people going on.
Speaker 1: I think we got.
Speaker 1: do we ever get Darryl?
Speaker 1: cuz we got Gerald on a long time ago.
Speaker 0: We did have Gerald.
Speaker 0: Hey, we should get Darryl Maybe but he would just be.
Speaker 0: you know, he's troublesome troublesome.
Speaker 1: Eh, maybe I'll try to get like Dave Riley or something.
Speaker 0: He's more troublesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah We get him to sit still for five minutes.
Speaker 0: Let's get someone who's less trouble.
Speaker 1: Who's less troublesome?
Speaker 1: Scott Johnson.
Speaker 0: Not a bad choice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, look at Scott Johnson on after the election because uh, I don't want to sabotage his electoral aims.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do love though, you know, we're talking about all these words to resign after hitting, you know.
Speaker 1: instead We're talking to old people in government, right?
Speaker 1: So to cover up the fact that he's so crazy young compared to everyone else in the government You know what?
Speaker 1: His article says the official article Scott Johnson a Hatboro area resident for 29 years.
Speaker 1: Mmm, cuz he's 29 years old that he was born in Hatboro.
Speaker 1: Yep, but notice how they sidestep that and try to make him sound older than 29 years old.
Speaker 1: It's clever clever girl ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's fine.
Speaker 1: All right, we're done all old people voting gonna get some food go to bed and Maybe play a little bit an ass before I go to bed.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.