Speaker 2: It's Tuesday, May 12th.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 2: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 2: Tonight we have an amazing interview with the proprietor of the Retro Arcade Museum in Beacon?
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 2: I really gotta get some more games to play on the train.
Speaker 1: What game are you gonna play on the train?
Speaker 2: Well, I was playing Civ IV for a while, but I started playing Advance Wars again.
Speaker 2: Days of Ruin.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 2: Well, because I had two bees left, and I got rid of them, and then I got rid of almost all my A-Ranks, and then I decided I should never play Advance Wars again.
Speaker 1: That's a good idea.
Speaker 1: Alright, so, here's a little story, right?
Speaker 1: We're not gonna do a news or a thing of the day today, and I will tell you why.
Speaker 1: We live in a town, or city, of Beacon, New York.
Speaker 1: Beacon as in a beacon of light.
Speaker 2: Yes, actually named after beacon fires that were lit during the Revolutionary War, George Washington, all this stuff.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of Revolutionary War shit around these parts.
Speaker 1: There's a George Washington head in the town.
Speaker 2: It's pretty big, too.
Speaker 2: It's coming.
Speaker 1: It's pretty big.
Speaker 1: And, you know, West Point is relatively close and such.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, in Beacon there's this main street, and the main street is pretty long, and it's got all sorts of city kind of stuff on it.
Speaker 1: It's this
Speaker 2: weird crossbreed between one of those kind of falling apart cities along the Hudson River Valley, but at the same time it's got that almost gentrified bit where the two ends are nothing but coffee shops and art galleries, but the middle is still like the bodega and the old gas station.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, one day, we were driving past the main street, and we see a sign on one of the, you know, a lot of the places on main street are just empty commercial space that no one can rent, and the prices are ludicrously low.
Speaker 1: And we saw a sign on a previously un-rented place, and it said, "Retro Arcade Museum," and the styling of said sign was retro indeed.
Speaker 1: It was perfect.
Speaker 1: And it had a picture of an arcade cabinet, and we were like, "What the
Speaker 1: fuck?".
Speaker 2: There's no way.
Speaker 1: Holy shit.
Speaker 2: So, you know, we're peeking in the window.
Speaker 2: I can't really find, like...
Speaker 1: It doesn't have a lot of windows, really.
Speaker 2: Well, there's like the front door with that, and I was peeking in.
Speaker 1: It has a little curtain, though, on the front door.
Speaker 2: But it wasn't even set up yet, so we just see this sign, and all I can think is, "Man, whatever that was that failed, I want to buy the
Speaker 2: sign.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, you know, I assume that, you know, it's Beacon, right?
Speaker 1: So, this was some place that set up, didn't make enough money, and closed, right?
Speaker 1: Or maybe someone bought the sign, and they were gonna set up, and they were gonna fail.
Speaker 1: Or, you know, I just... I didn't get my hopes up.
Speaker 1: I was the pessimistic times of bajillion.
Speaker 2: We have to drive, like, a half hour to the nearest gaming store, and it's primarily an airsoft and paintball store that happens to have, like, one set of burning wheel books.
Speaker 1: It's actually now primarily, like, a collectible card game store.
Speaker 2: Well, every gaming store.
Speaker 2: You can't even count that.
Speaker 2: That's just that.
Speaker 1: Even Millennium.
Speaker 1: Also some miniature action.
Speaker 2: Lots of clicky things.
Speaker 2: Even Millennium is primarily Pokemon kids playing their CCGs.
Speaker 1: That's true, but at least they have lots of board games.
Speaker 1: This place does not have the lots of board games Millennium has.
Speaker 2: The thing is, I'm starting to realize that at Millennium, I guess that a good two-thirds, maybe three-quarters of those games have not moved since I found out about Millennium.
Speaker 2: Since I first stepped through those doors, no one has bought or will buy, like, 1942 this specific battle in Russia.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the retro arcade museum.
Speaker 1: So, of course, we had to investigate.
Speaker 1: There was, you know, even if we were pessimistic, being geeks in a town that is not the kind of town that can support an arcade, investigation and supporting was very necessary.
Speaker 2: Yes, I mean, Beacon doesn't...
Speaker 1: How could we not?
Speaker 2: Beacon can't even support a normal arcade.
Speaker 2: Well, I would argue that nowhere supports normal arcades anymore.
Speaker 1: So, yeah.
Speaker 1: While amusement parks can't even support arcades.
Speaker 2: Well, we used to drive, you know, a half hour or so to play DDR because that was the nearest arcade.
Speaker 0: In a mall.
Speaker 2: Yeah, in a mall.
Speaker 2: There used to be an arcade over by IBM, and I used to go there like every day over lunch, but that shut down like five years ago.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So, we go to investigate.
Speaker 2: And there's eight people.
Speaker 1: And what do we find?
Speaker 1: but an actual arcade, but not just an actual arcade.
Speaker 1: You see, this arcade was special indeed for two reasons.
Speaker 1: Reason number one, it was actually open for business, but it was not open for business.
Speaker 1: Come in and pump pump your quarters.
Speaker 1: It's open for business parties only.
Speaker 1: So, you don't just walk right in and go, "Hey, let's play some
Speaker 1: games.".
Speaker 1: You got to be like, "Hey, I'm having my birthday
Speaker 1: party.".
Speaker 1: You know, a lot of arcades.
Speaker 1: when I was a kid, they would do the birthday party thing, but you could also walk right in.
Speaker 1: And when you had a birthday party, they just gave you a fistful of tokens, right?
Speaker 1: This place is like, what is it?
Speaker 1: I think he's charging $10 an hour per person, something like that.
Speaker 2: Yeah, we'll link to all the relevant details.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the website has all the prices.
Speaker 1: And so, you have a party and you pay per person per hour and you get unlimited play.
Speaker 1: And it's for birthdays and shit.
Speaker 1: Secondly, barely any of the games in this arcade are video games.
Speaker 2: You see, when you think of the earliest arcade games, you probably think of things like Centipede, Pac-Man, all these kind of, you know, what you think of as retro.
Speaker 1: Space Invaders.
Speaker 2: There was an entire generation of games that were primarily mechanical in nature.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know, pinball, right?
Speaker 1: Pinball before, I mean, more recently, there are video pinball machines that have, you know, video screens in them and holograms and shit.
Speaker 1: But in the olden days, you know, pinball was mechanical, right?
Speaker 1: There were springs and solenoids and rails and flippers.
Speaker 2: Now, even most pinball machines that are like that now, they still have, like, the electronic scoring.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: There are pinball machines where the scoring is just gears flipping numbers.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like an odometer in your car.
Speaker 1: You know, the thing, you know, spins around to keep the score and, you know, so they had mechanical pinball machines and everyone can understand a mechanical pinball machine.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But what some people don't remember are mechanical arcade games that are not pinball machines.
Speaker 1: You might remember, I don't know, like those shooting alleys where, like, you know, you have a gun and you shoot at these targets and, you know, but it's not using a light gun or a laser or anything like that.
Speaker 1: You know, it's.
Speaker 1: it's, you know, using some mechanical method to determine, you know, if you if you hit and then when you hit it, you know, the mechanical things make like, you know, a cowboy jump out of a barrel or something like that and go, you know, and, you know, there's lots and lots of these old mechanical arcade games that are not pinball that all disappeared as soon as Pong and Space Invaders and all the video games appeared.
Speaker 2: I mean, just an idea of how old these games are.
Speaker 2: Sega had a game in nineteen sixty seven called Rifleman.
Speaker 1: Whoa.
Speaker 2: Nineteen one Sega to nineteen sixty seven.
Speaker 1: So Pong was in nineteen seventy two and what rifle man was in sixty seven, you said?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 2: And they're there.
Speaker 2: These games are old and crazy.
Speaker 2: They're amazing.
Speaker 1: They're they're quite fantastic.
Speaker 1: The cool and to have a whole arcade full of them in the town in which we live.
Speaker 2: I mean, I remember I walked in and I see right up at the front Seawolf.
Speaker 2: And the one thing I remember about Cedar Point that I don't know if it's still there was that they had an old arcade, but it wasn't like this intentionally retro arcade.
Speaker 2: They just had all these really old arcade games and they had a lot of these, but almost all of them were broken.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, these are the kind of things because they're mechanical, because they're one of a kind, you know, no two are alike, really, unless there's someone who really knows what's going on.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, video game machine, if it breaks right, you replace some boards, you attach the wires.
Speaker 1: It's relatively easier to maintain and fix as long as, you know, something on the board doesn't actually get fried.
Speaker 1: You know, you can you can fix it.
Speaker 1: But this mechanical game requires like an expert to maintain it and keep it going, you know, and made fixing a mechanical pinball machine is not simple.
Speaker 1: You know, you need skills, need knowledge, you need tools, need things.
Speaker 1: So, you know, these even if you can find these games out there, finding working ones, let alone an entire arcade full of working ones was already epically awesome.
Speaker 1: So we went to investigate.
Speaker 1: We found the arcade of awesome and we found the guy running the arcade of awesome.
Speaker 1: And of course, we had to interview such a man.
Speaker 2: because I think very specifically, you know, we've seen this sign.
Speaker 2: We didn't know what was going on.
Speaker 2: We kept thinking, you know, we got to check that out.
Speaker 2: We got to find out what's going on with it.
Speaker 2: But one day we were walking with the whole crew.
Speaker 2: We tried to eat at one restaurant.
Speaker 2: They were full.
Speaker 2: We decided to walk to the other restaurant.
Speaker 2: And as we're passing, I see the sign and I point out to the front row crew, hey, yeah, check out this sign.
Speaker 2: We've been waiting for this thing to open to see what the deal is here.
Speaker 2: We don't know what's going on.
Speaker 2: And then we stop and we see that now it is open.
Speaker 1: Oh, shit.
Speaker 2: Doors unlocked and there's noise inside.
Speaker 2: The crew walks in and we're just dumbfounded.
Speaker 2: And the owner is kind of standing there hanging out with his wife and kid.
Speaker 2: And 10 of us just kind of walk in awestruck.
Speaker 2: And this leads to about an hour of us talking to him about how amazing he is.
Speaker 1: So we went and interviewed this amazing man.
Speaker 1: And that's why there's no arcade.
Speaker 1: are the news and thing of the day, even though this interview was conducted a long time ago, months ago.
Speaker 1: Rim, rim's fault.
Speaker 2: Yeah, we were busy.
Speaker 2: Plus this was intense.
Speaker 1: That's all right.
Speaker 1: Because the arcade is still there.
Speaker 1: They were having a party the other night.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 2: This was intended to cover for an episode when we were out of town, but that never happened.
Speaker 1: No, it didn't happen.
Speaker 1: So listen to this, you know, amazing and epic interview with an amazing and epic person who has an amazing and epic retro arcade.
Speaker 2: And seriously, if you're in the mid Hudson Valley, you should check this place out.
Speaker 2: This is pretty hot.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, even if you're like in New York City, if this is your, if this is your deal, right, this is the kind of thing that's not in New York City.
Speaker 1: You, you, and if you really want to see it, it might be worth your while to get your ass on the, the choo choo train and come up here.
Speaker 2: Plus, I mean, how many people take the stupid train from the city up here to beacon to go to like the DIA or the art shops or the coffee shops or all that stuff that they get people to come out of the city for.
Speaker 2: convey kids.
Speaker 2: I know a lot of you are in high school.
Speaker 2: Convince your parents to do that and that you heard beacons, a nice place and tell them you want to go to a museum.
Speaker 1: No, tell me you want your birthday party at the retro arcade museum.
Speaker 2: You know, all you have to do is tell them you want to go to a museum and bacon.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: You don't want my birthday party at the museum and beacon New York.
Speaker 1: So cool.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Plus, you know, your parents will love it cause this will like, you know, it will, it will nostalgia them to death.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: Cause remember this isn't just an arcade to play these games.
Speaker 2: He's also got this display in the front of ancient, like he's got an odd, he's got a lot.
Speaker 1: You can go and see all the pictures of all the crazy shit he's got, but basically he has retro this place the fuck out.
Speaker 2: I mean in the back where he's got like the kitchen snack room, he's made a replica 1950s kitchen with all the bake light and everything.
Speaker 1: It's crazy.
Speaker 2: He's got a set of subway doors that he's like putting in so that you can open them real subway doors from New York.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 2: He got them off an old subway.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's a lot of stuff going on in this little retro arcade and beacon that is a worth investigating.
Speaker 2: And the only other thing I really want to say is that at some point in the future, probably after con season settles down, I mean we're going to a lot of convention in the winter.
Speaker 2: at some points we're going to run some sort of geek nights events at this place.
Speaker 1: Not too many people can fit in there.
Speaker 2: This will be some very exclusive event.
Speaker 2: It'll have to be either invite only or maybe we'll do a charity auction.
Speaker 2: I don't know.
Speaker 2: We'll figure something out.
Speaker 1: Charity thing might be really good.
Speaker 2: Yeah, that's a good idea.
Speaker 0: My name is Fred Barbara and this is the retro arcade museum.
Speaker 0: It's what I like to think of as a living museum.
Speaker 0: Not only can you see these beautiful works of art that were made by master craftsmen and real artists back when things were hand built, but you can experience them.
Speaker 0: So it's a, it's a, it's a visceral museum.
Speaker 1: So what started all of this?
Speaker 0: When I was a boy growing up in the sixties, my dad took me to an arcade in flushing Queens.
Speaker 0: My, my grandparents lived in flushing and there was an arcade there.
Speaker 0: It's it's a, it was a wonderful place.
Speaker 0: And that was back in the days when there was actually an airport in flushing, the flushing airport.
Speaker 0: and right across the road, across the parking lot from the flushing airport was the adventurers in, and it was an amusement park.
Speaker 0: It was an arcade.
Speaker 0: It was everything.
Speaker 0: And it was probably there from like, I'm guessing the 1950s through the eighties.
Speaker 0: And I was probably there during the hay day because that was the crossover from when there were no video games.
Speaker 0: It was really the video games had just come out and say mid to early seventies.
Speaker 0: So primarily I had the leftover electromechanicals to play with.
Speaker 0: And those are some of my fondest childhood memories was going with my dad.
Speaker 0: And when I got into my forties I don't know if you want to call it a midlife crisis or whatever it is.
Speaker 0: I wasn't ready to buy a vet.
Speaker 0: So I decided I I'll just buy one of the games that I remember playing when I was a boy with my dad.
Speaker 0: And that first game was a, it was a sea devil.
Speaker 0: And that was it.
Speaker 0: Once I got the first game, I got it delivered.
Speaker 0: I started playing it.
Speaker 0: It was, it, it's an obsession.
Speaker 0: It really turned into something beyond anything I imagined.
Speaker 0: And it's another one of those stories where life leads you places you never think it will.
Speaker 0: So this is about my fourth career and this is you know, just another, another stage.
Speaker 1: So the machines in this arcade, are these all the ones you have?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: In fact, there are about 40 machines here.
Speaker 0: This is, I haven't counted recently, but this is probably a third to a quarter of the total machines.
Speaker 0: The rest of the machines are in a warehouse about 10 minutes from here.
Speaker 0: And I'm going to try and rotate machines in and out on an as needed basis if I get tired of something.
Speaker 0: Or if I see that people are not playing a particular game, I'm going to want to share, you know, a new game with them.
Speaker 0: Or if something comes in that I'm really excited about.
Speaker 0: There are some games that are, that are just so collectible that they'll probably never make it to the game room because they're, they're so rare and they're so valuable that if a private collector would want to see them, they can make an appointment to come to the warehouse.
Speaker 0: And I'll be glad to show it to them, but it's not something I would put on public display.
Speaker 0: Although, you know, there are some things that I may, you know, loosen up on.
Speaker 0: There, there are certain machines here that I swore that I'd never put out and then I ended up putting them out.
Speaker 0: So, you know.
Speaker 2: So what are some of these rare games that you're not going to put out?
Speaker 0: Some of the super rare games that I'm concerned about putting out on the floor are something called the Casco Star Five.
Speaker 0: It's a sit down game.
Speaker 0: It's about seven feet long and you sit in the cockpit of a spaceship and you have your control in front of you.
Speaker 0: And it's sort of like the old Star Wars games.
Speaker 0: The difference is it was all electromechanical.
Speaker 0: So there's this planet inside that you have to shoot these targets on.
Speaker 0: Well, it's sort of like a basketball that moves on this gimbal in all different directions.
Speaker 0: And it's just one of the coolest effects ever.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's, you know, that's one of those things.
Speaker 0: I have some games that are like still in the box, new old stock games, they call them.
Speaker 0: So from like 1967 or 1970, I have an Allied Leisure WhatsApp.
Speaker 0: It's literally still in the original box.
Speaker 0: It came in a cardboard box.
Speaker 0: The thing probably weighs 300 pounds.
Speaker 0: Most of these games weigh between 250 and 400 pounds.
Speaker 0: And this particular game, you know, it's literally still in the box that it came in.
Speaker 0: And, you know, I take it out, you know, to look at it.
Speaker 0: All the machines have counters on them.
Speaker 0: That's a whole interesting aspect of this.
Speaker 0: So every time somebody plays the game, you can tell that, you know, a play took place.
Speaker 0: And on some of the original games, they'll have three on the counter.
Speaker 0: On some of my, you know, games that I play here, I have 90,000 plays.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's a testament to how well they were built and all that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: If you can only imagine that somebody cycled through these things 90,000 times and they're still reparable, they're still, you know, they function almost like they did when they were new or as maybe better in some cases.
Speaker 1: So what makes these arcade games different from the ones that we're used to?
Speaker 0: I say there are two categories of arcade games.
Speaker 0: There's video arcade games and there's non-video arcade games.
Speaker 0: And like if you go to eBay, that's how you find these games.
Speaker 0: You put in non-video games.
Speaker 0: Then there are all these other subcategories, these little subclasses.
Speaker 0: There are games called trade stimulators, which aren't games per se, but they get you to do things.
Speaker 0: So you get interested in it.
Speaker 0: So that would be like a Mutascope viewer where you're actually looking at, you know, like images that go by like cards that create an animation.
Speaker 0: or an example of a trade stimulator would be some of my card machines from the thirties through the sixties that dispense postcards and people would collect these postcards.
Speaker 0: That's a whole separate like sub hobby of these hobbies.
Speaker 0: But I think the biggest difference is in video games, starting in say 1976, that was really the cutoff when they stopped making electromechanical games.
Speaker 0: The real difference is that the electromechanicals had no video screens.
Speaker 0: At the very end, they started using microprocessors.
Speaker 0: So occasionally, in some of the allied leisure games, you will find chips.
Speaker 0: You'll find like 7400 series chips.
Speaker 0: They're really super pre-8888 chips.
Speaker 0: These weren't computer chips.
Speaker 0: They were TTL logic chips.
Speaker 0: So they were the really earliest.
Speaker 0: And they still didn't perform all the functions because there's still bicycle chains and relays and gears and wipers and motors and all kinds of things inside.
Speaker 0: But what really differentiates today's machines is that today's machines are almost purely electronic driven and even the input devices, like the steering wheels and all that, they're digital in nature so that they cause a digital signal to take place within the electronic circuits.
Speaker 0: But these are, I go in and I have to grease these things up like it was a mechanic's garage.
Speaker 0: I'll walk out of here and my hands will be covered with motor oil or grease or whatever when we're working on these things.
Speaker 0: So that's probably the biggest difference.
Speaker 0: And the other difference is that these are all wood, handmade, and they were literally hand-wired.
Speaker 0: And I was in the music business for a long time.
Speaker 0: My background is in music and television production.
Speaker 0: I went to film school back in the early 80s.
Speaker 0: And back then, again, it was a more visceral kind of thing.
Speaker 0: When we made film, you would touch the film.
Speaker 0: You'd work on an editing console.
Speaker 0: You'd work on a Steenbeck or on a Provost.
Speaker 0: And, you know, you'd have your bins and everything would be hanging up.
Speaker 0: Everything today is an analogy to what it was in the past.
Speaker 0: So they still use the word bin for your story clips on a non-linear edit system.
Speaker 0: But they got the word bin because we used to carry these bins around.
Speaker 0: We used to wheel these things around that actually were giant laundry bins, basically.
Speaker 0: And the analogy is sort of there with the games.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of similarities with the games, except what they did back then was they recreated the effects that you create today inside of a computer.
Speaker 0: And the comparison to the audio and the music is that what I would consider state of the art, which was the golden days of music when they were recording Beatles and Rolling Stones and Led Zeppelin albums back in Abbey Road Studios and they were recording on Neve consoles, they were called discrete consoles because of the circuitry that was used in them and because they were hand wired and they didn't use integrated circuits.
Speaker 0: They used transistors and they used capacitors and they used devices to amplify and to make the sounds have that warmth.
Speaker 0: And there was a reason why things looked and sounded and felt that way.
Speaker 0: And that's the experience that you get with these machines.
Speaker 0: They were literally hand wired by an individual.
Speaker 0: Not to say that they don't do that now, but every element of these things was hand built from cutting the glass to the wiring to assembling and testing it and stapling in, you know, the instructions and, you know, just a whole different feel.
Speaker 1: Can you tell us some of the more clever tricks that the designers of these games used?
Speaker 0: Some of the really interesting stuff was back in the early 70s, the earliest of holograms.
Speaker 0: You know, for a while holograms were like the hot new technology.
Speaker 0: Now it's on everybody's credit card.
Speaker 0: But when holograms were used to do actual 3D depth and depth perception, an example of a game that used a hologram would be a Casco Bank Robbers, which I don't have on the floor.
Speaker 0: That's one that I keep off the floor.
Speaker 0: But that used holograms.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to acquire another holographic game right now.
Speaker 0: And so it really gave you that sense of depth and it gave you the 3D perspective.
Speaker 0: On almost all of these games, they used a lot of tricks, using half mirrors, half coated mirrors.
Speaker 0: And what the mirrors did and what they do was to create this illusion of depth.
Speaker 0: You'll notice that the machines are fairly shallow, but they're very tall.
Speaker 0: And the reason for that is because all of the backgrounds are vertical and the mirrors that are facing towards you are horizontal.
Speaker 0: And it creates this depth of illusion because you're looking at a three and a half, four foot play field on the mirrors, but it's only about two feet in front of your face.
Speaker 0: So they don't have to make the machines five or six feet long in order to get that feeling, to get that effect.
Speaker 0: So, you know, they use the word smoke and mirrors.
Speaker 0: It was really done with mirrors and, you know, some of the most unique things were done with mirrors.
Speaker 0: And then combining things like, for instance, the Roadrunner game.
Speaker 0: It's a very desirable auto racing game.
Speaker 0: And they use the combination of the mirrors, this kind of holographic trick where the car is projected onto another background, onto another mirror.
Speaker 0: So you're seeing a projection of the car in a mirror.
Speaker 0: So when the car gets into an accident, when you hit another car, another car hits you, the car is on a separate motor.
Speaker 0: So it flips around in 3D space and it's physically flipping in 3D space, but you don't know that to you.
Speaker 0: It just looks like there's this car, you know, on the track that just did a rollover.
Speaker 0: And it's pretty amazing.
Speaker 0: The creativity that these engineers used is unbelievable.
Speaker 0: The other side of it is the artisans that created the back glasses.
Speaker 0: In many cases, the back glasses are as valuable or more valuable than the machines themselves.
Speaker 0: Because you can buy parts for the machines.
Speaker 0: You can buy relays.
Speaker 0: You can buy the switches.
Speaker 0: You can buy all of these parts.
Speaker 0: And if you can't find something specific, you can almost always fabricate it or find something.
Speaker 0: But the artwork is just incredible.
Speaker 0: They used a very complicated process of lithography, mirror backings, to create that illusion of transparency or opaqueness in certain parts of the glass.
Speaker 0: And the other side of that is just.
Speaker 0: the artists were just phenomenally talented.
Speaker 0: It was just beautifully done.
Speaker 0: You know, I've had people come in that came from, for instance, they came from an exhibit at the Dia Beacon, and they look at this artwork and said, you know, that this is as fine an artwork as you would see in what you would consider legitimate art.
Speaker 0: You know, it's just done for a different reason.
Speaker 0: And you can also tell the difference in the cultural differences, the generational differences from the '60s to the '70s to the '80s.
Speaker 0: The art had a different feel and had a different look to it.
Speaker 2: So what was your first machine?
Speaker 0: The very first machine that I acquired, and I think I found it on eBay, was a Midway Sea Devil, a 1969 Sea Devil.
Speaker 0: And it's a submarine shooting game, and it has that 3D depth illusion.
Speaker 0: The reason why I liked it when I was a kid and the reason why I like it now is because it's got a periscope on it.
Speaker 0: And the fun part about these games is that they've got real steering wheels from real cars or what feels like a real periscope.
Speaker 0: It's not just that you're simulating this 3D experience, but you're also touching these three-dimensional objects that feel so real.
Speaker 0: So I collect a lot of submarine games.
Speaker 0: That's like a big hobby just on the side of collecting these submarine games.
Speaker 0: But that specifically was the one that when I was a kid I had these really strong memories of.
Speaker 0: Here in the place I have several games that I remember so vividly from when I was eight years old or nine years old.
Speaker 0: And for instance, Allied Leisure Super Shifter or the Mutascope Drive Mobile Trainer.
Speaker 0: And while these games aren't necessarily the most collectible or anything like that, those are the ones that I remember playing because to me, to an eight-year-old, what could be more exciting than driving a car?
Speaker 0: And even today, I'll put an experienced driver behind the wheel of one of these things, and their jaw drops, and there's this rush of panic in their face.
Speaker 0: What do I do?
Speaker 0: Well, it's just like driving a real car.
Speaker 0: It's a clutch-shift-guess.
Speaker 0: Clutch-shift-guess.
Speaker 0: And you go over this with them, and it's like, "I can't do
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 0: They get very nervous, and they'll move on to another game.
Speaker 0: I'll try and coax them back.
Speaker 0: I don't want them to give up.
Speaker 2: When you finally got a hold of these games again, older and wiser, were they as good as you remembered?
Speaker 0: They were better, yes.
Speaker 0: When I acquired these games as an adult, they say that love is sweeter the second time around, and these games are sweeter the second time around because not only do I get to enjoy them, and I do enjoy them so much, but it brings back that rush of memories.
Speaker 0: It's the sense memory.
Speaker 0: These games have, I mean, literally, they have a feel.
Speaker 0: They even have a smell.
Speaker 0: You can smell the wood.
Speaker 0: You can smell the electronics.
Speaker 0: It's the whole experience of everything, so I enjoy every bit of it as much, maybe more now.
Speaker 0: I think now, I think what I get out of it now is when people sit down in these who've never experienced them before, I get a huge rush out of that because exposing someone to something that may disappear in the next 10 years, that's a great feeling, and being able to rescue that feeling.
Speaker 0: The other thing is people that do remember them who are in my age or maybe a little bit older, I've seen people almost in tears when they walk over to a game and they remember it, and their memories just come flooding out in such minutia, in such detail that I feel like I'm experiencing something with them, so that's a really nice feeling.
Speaker 2: How did the actual museum itself come to be?
Speaker 0: Originally, I had a handful of machines in my home, and then I started getting more and more machines.
Speaker 0: I started acquiring more machines as time went on, and so I started renting storage space from indoor mini storage and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: I started with one locker and two lockers and three.
Speaker 0: Eventually, I had eight lockers, like almost a couple thousand square feet, and I couldn't get to any of the games.
Speaker 0: I couldn't play anything.
Speaker 0: Even though I had electricity there, it was such a hassle.
Speaker 0: I couldn't show anybody anything.
Speaker 0: It's not very interesting to bring someone to a storage facility and just show them games, and for the most part, they were still wrapped or boxed or whatnot.
Speaker 0: I hadn't had a chance to work on them, except for the very few that I had in my home, so I decided that I needed to get them out.
Speaker 0: I started looking around for commercial real estate space.
Speaker 0: Originally, I was looking for a big warehouse, and then I would have people come into the warehouse and play them.
Speaker 0: Somehow, this came along.
Speaker 0: I had been to Beacon several times with my wife and my family, and I really loved the town.
Speaker 0: I like the fact that it feels like the cross between an artist community and a little bit of Soho.
Speaker 0: I lived in Soho for a while, so it's got a little bit of everything, and that great diner.
Speaker 0: It brings back so many nice memories, and I just decided that this place just happened to come along at the right time.
Speaker 0: It cost me about as much to store as to have a storefront, although there are a lot of other expenses, but this is a dream come true.
Speaker 0: For anybody who's a gaming enthusiast to have their own arcade, a real arcade, it's a dream come true.
Speaker 0: I can't compare it to anything else.
Speaker 0: I guess it's like a musician having their own recording studio, or if you're an athlete, if you have a real regulation basketball court or a tennis court, I get to experience this.
Speaker 0: Hopefully when my daughter is old enough to really appreciate it, and she's six, seven years old, she'll really start getting those feelings that I had for the machines and the games.
Speaker 2: We have to ask, what was your first computer?
Speaker 0: Wow, my first computer.
Speaker 0: Boy, oh boy, you really did.
Speaker 0: I think it was a VIC.
Speaker 0: I think my first computer was a Commodore 64 or a VIC.
Speaker 0: They came out about the same time.
Speaker 0: I had a Commodore 64, I had a VIC.
Speaker 0: I took computers in high school, and we had a Wang Olivetti, and we had a PET.
Speaker 0: I remember that.
Speaker 0: I was terrible in computers.
Speaker 0: The irony is I ended up spending a good portion of my life developing and designing software and applications, but I nearly failed at computers in high school.
Speaker 0: The extent of my computer experience in college was shoeboxes full of punch cards.
Speaker 0: That was not for me.
Speaker 0: I had to wait until things got a little more advanced.
Speaker 0: I always wondered how things worked.
Speaker 0: From the time I was a little boy, I would take things apart.
Speaker 0: I didn't necessarily know how to put them back together, but I would always manage to get them apart and get all the pieces separated.
Speaker 0: Now I take a Polaroid before I take it apart.
Speaker 0: It's funny because I have always tried to be on the forefront, and now that I'm in this whole retro world, it's almost like being on the forefront of the retro world.
Speaker 0: The really exciting part is the expression that I use is that when I get something that's 40 or 50 years old, they say, "Oh, you got another old
Speaker 0: game?".
Speaker 0: I said, "Well, it's new to me," and I get to learn about it.
Speaker 0: I get to read the schematics.
Speaker 0: I get to figure out how it worked.
Speaker 0: I take it apart, and I'll sit there with a light and stare at it for like a half an hour or 45 minutes or an hour before I even touch it so I can try and figure out, "Okay, what's going
Speaker 0: on?".
Speaker 0: Eventually, you become more adept at these things, and you know how to hunt things down and how things work, but there's always some new twists.
Speaker 0: There's always something that you can't figure out, but being on the forefront of technology makes me appreciate this stuff even more because I don't know if people today are creative enough to have built something like this because this doesn't involve just sitting down and writing code.
Speaker 0: This involves something physical.
Speaker 0: This involves something tactile.
Speaker 0: Now the big thing is creating haptic feedback and haptic controllers.
Speaker 0: For instance, when I was working at the medical school, we were doing virtual surgery.
Speaker 0: In other words, we would set up a computer and a haptic controller like it could be anything from a scalpel to a forcep or any type of minimally invasive operating device, and that would be connected to a computer, and then via the internet, we'd run fiber through AT&T or whomever was the provider to Europe.
Speaker 0: This is true.
Speaker 0: This is happening right now that you could actually operate on a patient, and you could force feedback what it feels like.
Speaker 0: Now, I'm not a physician, so I never actually cut flesh, but I know what the physician needed to feel in order to be able to do that, so these are the types of things that we tried to simulate for them.
Speaker 0: The drawback to an experience like that is that it wasn't immediate.
Speaker 0: The force feedback didn't happen right away.
Speaker 0: There was always a millisecond or two or three millisecond delay.
Speaker 0: Well, that may not seem like a lot, a thousandth of a second, but if somebody's artery starts bleeding, you may only have a second or two to clamp it and move on to the next thing, so there really was this kind of crossover, this melding of the computers and these physical devices.
Speaker 0: I like to say that we're all analog.
Speaker 0: As we sit here and as we breathe, as we look at each other, no matter how many times our brains are firing, no matter how many times our neurons are firing, you wouldn't see me if there wasn't light reflecting into our eyes and we didn't have a lens in front of our eyes, and that's analog, so no matter how much people talk about digital, digital, digital, that we live in a digital world, we really physically live in an analog world and we just like to store things digitally or we like to manipulate things digitally.
Speaker 0: These machines are pure analog.
Speaker 0: They rub against one another.
Speaker 0: There are parts that move and they rub and they count and they're very simple, but then they show you that part of the brain before there was integrated circuits to do the calculating for you.
Speaker 0: It's almost like if you go back to Roman culture.
Speaker 0: when they created these pedometers, they were able to actually count the kilometers when they built this incredible road system.
Speaker 0: Even today, people have a hard time figuring out how these devices worked, and that's amazing to me, so just having an appreciation of those kinds of things, that's a whole other world that we get to explore in these games.
Speaker 2: Could you tell us a little bit about yourself?
Speaker 2: What came before?
Speaker 0: I've always worked from the time I was 13 years old, and I started out working, doing retail.
Speaker 0: I worked in Sam Goody.
Speaker 0: It always had something to do with something creative back when Sam Goody was still around, but I worked for a wedding photographer.
Speaker 0: Back in the days before there was videotape, and what we did was we shot on film.
Speaker 0: There wasn't even Super 8 film.
Speaker 0: We shot on 16, and then we sliced the film in half to make 8-millimeter film, and then people would take those 8-millimeter films.
Speaker 0: That was my start, and that inspired me to go to film school.
Speaker 0: Originally, I started out going to the film school at Brooklyn College, which at that time was a very prestigious film school.
Speaker 0: We had George Roy Hill and Paul Newman and all these wonderful guest visitors.
Speaker 0: The best part about Brooklyn College film school was the equipment room.
Speaker 0: We had all the gear we could ever want and take it out anytime we wanted.
Speaker 0: I remember the guy's names.
Speaker 0: It was Lenny and Steve, these two guys in there.
Speaker 0: Here I was, and I was very young when I went to school.
Speaker 0: I was 16 when I started college.
Speaker 0: Here I am, a 16-year-old kid.
Speaker 0: I wanted to make a movie.
Speaker 0: I'd go in and say, "Yeah, I'd like an Arri CP-16 and give me a set of three Schneider
Speaker 0: Primes.".
Speaker 0: I'd walk out, and I'd be so ... I mean, I couldn't believe it.
Speaker 0: They'd give me light kits.
Speaker 0: They'd give me everything.
Speaker 0: I really got the feel of being in school, when I was in school, of being in the film industry.
Speaker 0: Something happened where I wasn't able to continue in film school.
Speaker 0: I actually developed a problem with my eyes, and I had corneal transplants back in 1981 and '84.
Speaker 0: Fortunately, I got my vision back, but it took years for me to get my vision back, so I figured if I can't use my eyes, I'll use my ears.
Speaker 0: I'd always been a musician, so I went into the music business.
Speaker 0: I was in bands all through high school and everything else.
Speaker 0: One of my bands got signed to an indie label.
Speaker 0: The next thing I know, we were renting a house in Woodstock.
Speaker 0: I built a recording studio in the house.
Speaker 0: Back then, it was a big deal to have a 16-track recording studio, and I spent about a year just recording music.
Speaker 0: The band took a turn from what we originally signed for, so I came back to New York as a recording engineer.
Speaker 0: That kicked off about a 15-year career in the music industry.
Speaker 0: I worked for all the majors at the time, when there were a lot of labels.
Speaker 0: I worked for MCA and EMI and Sony and Columbia and just down the list.
Speaker 0: If I mention the artists, most people look at me, stare blankly.
Speaker 0: Some of the names will ring familiar, like almost as old as these acts.
Speaker 0: I worked with Biz Markie and Brenda K. Starr.
Speaker 0: I worked on movies like the Lombato movies and all sorts of things like that.
Speaker 0: It's all very quaint now, but it was a really fun, exciting career.
Speaker 0: I got to meet my heroes.
Speaker 0: I got to work with my heroes.
Speaker 0: I spent two years working with a man named Amir Diodato.
Speaker 0: Diodato was the arranger for Roberta Flack for Killing Me Softly.
Speaker 0: He did all of the Cool and the Gang albums, like Ladies Night and Too Hot.
Speaker 0: He wrote and recorded all those records.
Speaker 0: I got to meet all these incredible people.
Speaker 0: I got to meet all these producers who I had admired.
Speaker 0: I have a lot of autographed CDs.
Speaker 0: Ironically, it's not the artists, but it's the producers who autographed it for me.
Speaker 0: I got to be in all these wonderful sessions and meet from the hard rock guys and hanging out with Aerosmith and being backstage to the coolest jazz guys like Peter Erskine and recording them and doing sessions with them.
Speaker 0: It was just so exciting.
Speaker 0: Then, I guess, I was probably in my mid-30s, and I decided that there was a point where I actually saw my ... There's that expression, "Jumping the
Speaker 0: shark.".
Speaker 0: I saw a lot of my heroes jump the shark.
Speaker 0: You're familiar with that expression, right?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Unfortunately, these guys, when they get to a certain age, there's an expression.
Speaker 0: It's like every other business.
Speaker 0: I don't care whether you're a coder, a computer coder, or you're as good as your last game, or you're as good as your last record, or you're as good as your last movie.
Speaker 0: If you have two flops in a row, good luck getting hired for the next one.
Speaker 0: The music business is changing dramatically.
Speaker 0: One of the main reasons that I got ... I got a foothold in.
Speaker 0: why I was successful in the music industry is because I was one of the very first people in computer music.
Speaker 0: Before there were computers in computer music, there were sequencers that you had to take patch cords and plug things in.
Speaker 0: We used those sequencers.
Speaker 0: I was one of the geeks who knew how to do all that stuff.
Speaker 0: Plus, I was like a hard rock guy.
Speaker 0: Back then, when I had hair, more of it, I had hair down to my waist.
Speaker 0: I was in a heavy metal band, but I knew how to do all the MIDI stuff.
Speaker 0: Even before MIDI was a standard, I knew how to do all that.
Speaker 0: I was able to get a foothold.
Speaker 0: That launched me into the music business in a big way.
Speaker 0: I went from doing my hard rock band to doing this MIDI thing.
Speaker 0: Then I wanted something a little more serious in my life.
Speaker 0: I decided that I would do a complete change and I would go more into a corporate thing.
Speaker 0: I had been running a major recording studio at the time.
Speaker 0: I was, at that time, more in the business end of the music business and not doing as much creative stuff.
Speaker 0: An opportunity came along for me to be a multimedia producer at the Mount Sinai School of Medicine in New York.
Speaker 0: That was in about '95 or '96.
Speaker 0: I said, "Well, it's steady work.
Speaker 0: It's a full-time job.
Speaker 0: I get benefits.
Speaker 0: I get to be around a whole different environment.
Speaker 0: It's very academic, very
Speaker 0: institutional.".
Speaker 0: I started out there working for the hospital as a kind of a multimedia guy.
Speaker 0: Eventually, I built that up into my own department.
Speaker 0: We called it Educational Technology Group.
Speaker 0: I ended up patenting and designing and building all these different applications for medical education.
Speaker 0: It was a total experience.
Speaker 0: It was an amazing experience because I was fortunate enough to be given all of these opportunities.
Speaker 0: The joke that I had was I'm not a doctor.
Speaker 0: I just play when I work.
Speaker 0: I spent three years going through fellowship rotations with surgical fellows.
Speaker 0: Here I am, 5 o'clock in the morning in the operating room, dressed in scrubs and watching what these guys do.
Speaker 0: I literally lived my life with these guys and women.
Speaker 0: I would produce their educational training programs on how to do a bowel resection or how to do a thyroidectomy or whatever it was.
Speaker 0: These guys were really into technology.
Speaker 0: They were really into multimedia.
Speaker 0: A lot of guys programmed their own surgical games.
Speaker 0: They did their own videos.
Speaker 0: They did all this stuff.
Speaker 0: It was a great experience.
Speaker 0: I've seen things that most people never had an opportunity to see.
Speaker 0: I've seen it all.
Speaker 0: Everything that takes place in a hospital, from the heartbreaking to the miraculous.
Speaker 0: It was a great experience.
Speaker 0: Running my own department was a lot of fun for a long time, but then something called the business of medicine got too big.
Speaker 0: It became overwhelming because I had about eight people that worked for me, up to about 45 people.
Speaker 0: I was producing symposia and traveling around the country and lecturing and all that business.
Speaker 0: I just said, "I have to be responsible for the bottom
Speaker 0: line.".
Speaker 0: We were a cost recoupment department.
Speaker 0: The business of medicine is a rough business.
Speaker 0: Medical schools are not designed to make money.
Speaker 0: I had to make money.
Speaker 0: I had about 80 pharmaceutical companies that were clients of ours.
Speaker 0: We would produce multimedia projects for them, everything from games to CD-ROMs to DVDs to web streaming.
Speaker 0: I was probably one of the first people in on the web streaming industry.
Speaker 0: I started streaming back in 1998-99.
Speaker 0: Back then, the only game in town was real producer and real media.
Speaker 0: I got a grant.
Speaker 0: I used the money to buy a server.
Speaker 0: I spent $10,000 for a real enterprise license.
Speaker 0: Of course, now you get everything for free.
Speaker 0: You go out and you can buy, not buy, you can get Helix or you can buy the Adobe, the Flash communication server and all these newfangled things.
Speaker 0: Now, it's a whole different world.
Speaker 0: I was in on the beginning of that.
Speaker 0: We built up a library of, I don't know, maybe thousands, in the many thousands of materials.
Speaker 0: I ended up doing that for a lot of different industries and the medical center and for other hospitals and pharmaceutical companies.
Speaker 0: It got to be a real drag because then suddenly I was the bookkeeper.
Speaker 0: I was responsible for all this money and that was not, I always wanted to be in the creative side of it.
Speaker 0: I formed a company with my cousin and his college buddy.
Speaker 0: They're both Wharton graduates.
Speaker 0: My cousin was in sports and sports entertainment.
Speaker 0: He worked for Spectacor and he bought and sold baseball teams and all this sort of thing.
Speaker 0: My other partner, and he built sports bars and so he was in on the whole retail end of it.
Speaker 0: My other partner, and his name is Scott Barbara.
Speaker 0: We had the same last name.
Speaker 0: Our dads are brothers.
Speaker 0: My other partner, Greg O'Connor, is a movie producer, a real life Hollywood movie producer.
Speaker 0: He's also, the thing that gets me about working with both of them is they're both self-made.
Speaker 0: Greg put some money together after building up a business with his father, who is a retired police officer.
Speaker 0: They built up a security business together and Greg used that money to finance his first film and that film was Tumbleweeds.
Speaker 0: They won a Golden Globe for Tumbleweeds and then they used that money to get a deal with Disney and do their second film, which was Miracle about the Olympic ice hockey team.
Speaker 0: They built up this thing, so now Greg's a movie producer and we're all guys from the neighborhood.
Speaker 0: We're all like local kids, but we've got to travel all over the world and we've got to consult and do all this different stuff.
Speaker 0: In between, there are a bunch of different careers, but this thing that I'm doing with Scott and Greg is called Media Lab.
Speaker 0: We invent, I create different products for the entertainment in the industry and the crossovers between entertainment and technology.
Speaker 0: What I do is I try and create virtual reality situations for people to experience and tie that into monetizing it for the entertainment industry and I create applications for the entertainment industry.
Speaker 0: That's a lot of fun.
Speaker 0: Media Lab's been around for about two and a half years, so I transitioned out of Mount Sinai into Media Lab and then I found that since I didn't have the medical center to go to every day and I occasionally do consulting gigs for clients and I work for companies like Stella Productions who do these production projects, I decided that this is the ideal opportunity for me to do this.
Speaker 0: I may not have another opportunity in my life.
Speaker 0: I'm in my couple of months, I built the place.
Speaker 0: A lot of sweat equity went into it and just a lot of moral support from family and from my folks who are really good to me and very supportive.
Speaker 0: It's been an amazing experience and then getting to know the whole gaming community has been an amazing experience.
Speaker 0: There are websites like KLOV, which is Coin Lovers and there's a website called Tafa, which is T-A-F-A, which is just brochures and then there's so many of these different websites.
Speaker 0: I couldn't even go into all of them.
Speaker 0: There's Retroland and there's ... I can't even remember them off the side of my head, but there's so many wonderful places to go and you meet so many people.
Speaker 0: It's funny because you find doing the same thing in different ways in life.
Speaker 0: I used to travel around the world doing consulting about streaming media and digital video and now I get to travel around the world meeting collectors and doing this.
Speaker 0: This is infinitely more fun.
Speaker 0: Although the only difference is that this is on my dime, so that's the big difference.
Speaker 0: Somebody would pay me to go to China 10 years or 15 years ago.
Speaker 0: Now, I have to pay to go on my own, but the first thing is, is the feeling of acquiring a machine.
Speaker 0: It's not so much a selfish feeling.
Speaker 0: It's more of ... I feel like I've almost rescued these things from the dumpster or from the ax or from a fire, literally.
Speaker 0: The old game operators, they get tired of these things.
Speaker 0: They take them out in the back or they throw them off the back of a truck.
Speaker 0: They'd set them on fire.
Speaker 0: They destroy them.
Speaker 0: It was funny to them.
Speaker 0: This was landfill for them, but these are obviously objects of art.
Speaker 0: They really are.
Speaker 0: They're living, breathing, working machinery.
Speaker 0: I guess the same way people are addicted to old cars.
Speaker 0: People are into cars and they can appreciate every aspect of the car, appreciate this.
Speaker 0: The main difference is that even though I collected cars for a while, that was a hobby of mine, I wouldn't let anyone drive my cars.
Speaker 0: These I let people drive.
Speaker 0: These were meant to be driven.
Speaker 0: That was a big hurdle to get over, by the way.
Speaker 0: It was very difficult to reconcile letting people touch these things because you're afraid that somebody will abuse it or mishandle it.
Speaker 0: Finally, you come to the conclusion that these were designed for one purpose, to entertain.
Speaker 0: Now, that's what they're here for.
Speaker 0: I keep an eye on them.
Speaker 0: They're still my babies, but if people can get a kick out of them, that's the best feeling in the world, to hear the noises of the machines.
Speaker 0: I know that everybody is just having a great time when you hear the noises.
Speaker 0: Some people get hooked on one machine.
Speaker 0: There are different kinds of people.
Speaker 0: There are people that go from machine to machine and they want a little taste of everything, like the buffet, but then there are the people who get stuck on one thing, like the guy who wants to take all the shrimp.
Speaker 0: They have to play Ninja Gun for practically the whole time.
Speaker 0: Then the oddest thing is, here are all these wonderful games and all these toys and everything, and there'll be one person who'll just be stuck at the jukebox for an hour, and they'll just want to pick songs.
Speaker 0: It's been an hour out of two-and-a-half hours just looking for songs and doing that.
Speaker 2: What makes a good game?
Speaker 0: Storytelling, whether it's film or whether it's video, it's all storytelling.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter how you get there.
Speaker 0: It's if you get there, what you do.
Speaker 0: It's storytelling.
Speaker 0: I'd say probably the highest on the list for me is lighting.
Speaker 0: That's the single most important thing of making any kind of image that people see.
Speaker 0: Lighting is everything.
Speaker 0: That's followed by sound.
Speaker 0: When you're watching a film, it could have good sound or bad sound, and that'll make or break it.
Speaker 0: The funny part is it doesn't have to be technically good, the sound.
Speaker 0: That's analogous to these games.
Speaker 0: They don't have to be technically good to draw you in.
Speaker 0: Some of my favorite albums, some of my favorite performers and some of my favorite recordings have the worst sounds.
Speaker 0: They were intentionally over-modulated.
Speaker 0: The sound is so distorted.
Speaker 0: That was part of the charm of it.
Speaker 0: You listen to these old Zeppelin records or you listen to the old Beatles stuff that was recorded with a couple of microphones on an eight-track.
Speaker 0: It sounds better.
Speaker 0: It sounds richer.
Speaker 0: It sounds fuller because the performance is there.
Speaker 0: That's the big thing.
Speaker 0: Being in film school helps a lot too because these games have a story to them too.
Speaker 0: They all have some kind of theme to them.
Speaker 0: Once you master the theme, you sort of master the game.
Speaker 0: There's a certain amount of randomness to them, which makes them different from today's games.
Speaker 0: Today's games are funny because modern video games, you play on a console even though the graphics are amazing and the experience is amazing.
Speaker 0: They're almost surrealistic in their accuracy.
Speaker 0: It's scary.
Speaker 0: I really think there's going to be a point where people live in a virtual reality world.
Speaker 0: I don't think we're quite there yet, but it's very close.
Speaker 0: I'd say maybe 10, 15 years it'll be at that quality.
Speaker 0: The only thing that they're lacking is there's the television screen, in my opinion, that creates this impediment or this kind of barrier between you becoming immersed in the game.
Speaker 0: One day when we wear helmets or headsets or whatever that is, when you're really immersed in the game, I think that'll make a big difference.
Speaker 0: I think Wii was a big breakthrough.
Speaker 0: I have a Wii.
Speaker 0: I also have a lot of game consoles.
Speaker 0: Of course I have the old two-dimensional Atari and television and ColecoVision and Telstar and all that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: There was a charm in the two-dimensional and the repetitiveness in that.
Speaker 0: Something about it goes back to comfort foods and everything like that.
Speaker 0: There was a certain comfort in playing those games.
Speaker 0: I'll still enjoy them almost as much as I enjoy something new, but now when I play a Wii, that breaks down one of the barriers.
Speaker 0: Now suddenly I'm in another dimension.
Speaker 0: It's different from playing against the screen.
Speaker 0: Now suddenly I'm moving my body and I'm having an effect on it.
Speaker 0: I still kind of feel that screen in the way.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it is.
Speaker 0: As the games get more developed and I don't see my surroundings around me, I think that's the point in which I can say I've abandoned the analog and I've moved into the digital world.
Speaker 0: You can go back to a movie like Tron.
Speaker 0: And that was the penultimate in somebody being absorbed into the worlds of video games.
Speaker 0: I think that at some point we'll actually be absorbed into video games.
Speaker 0: But if you listen to music on headphones and you really get into an album and nothing else matters and the whole world just goes away and you're connecting with that artist, the same thing can happen with games where for those few moments or for however long it is, there's a connection between you and the machine.
Speaker 0: Even though you may not feel the connection and that connection goes as far as either the artist that you're listening to on the music or the person that designed and created the artwork for this thing.
Speaker 0: Suddenly you become part of it and it's three dimensional.
Speaker 0: That's the best part.
Speaker 0: Living in three dimensions, maybe one day we'll have four.
Speaker 0: That's some of the new technology that I developed with Media Lab is that we've created these interactive experiences, these three dimensional experiences where you're not just interacting with the computer but you're interacting with people inside the computer.
Speaker 0: I think it affects the way people respond and the way people interact and the way people let down their guard because suddenly you feel that it's okay to expose yourself because you're communicating with another being somehow, whether it's electronically or in reality.
Speaker 0: It's probably a lot easier to communicate with people electronically though, I will say.
Speaker 2: This has been Geek Nights with Rem and Scott.
Speaker 2: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 2: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 2: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 2: Tuesdays we have video games, board games and RPGs.
Speaker 2: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Speaker 2: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 2: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial Share-A-Like 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.