Speaker 1: It's Monday, August 24th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Night.
Speaker 1: Tonight, what if it was open-sourced?
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Nothing beats a weekend at the beach.
Speaker 1: Uh... two weekends at the beach.
Speaker 0: I had a good weekend in Wildwood.
Speaker 0: It was just me and Emily and uh...
Speaker 1: Wasn't it a little bit rainy?
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't really.
Speaker 0: Not at all.
Speaker 1: It was pretty rainy elsewhere.
Speaker 0: The only problem was that we couldn't really swim so much when the lifeguards were on duty.
Speaker 1: Because they kept kicking you out?
Speaker 0: They wouldn't let anyone into the water because there were like crazy waves.
Speaker 1: So basically the lifeguards job was to keep everyone out of the water?
Speaker 0: But the thing is, when the lifeguards weren't on duty, you could swim.
Speaker 0: So we'd get there before the lifeguards came out and go swimming.
Speaker 0: And it was awesome.
Speaker 0: Lifeguards come and make us stop.
Speaker 0: But then at five, the lifeguards leave.
Speaker 0: We go swimming again.
Speaker 0: But Saturday, we go swimming for a while after the lifeguards leave.
Speaker 1: And then the beach patrol comes?
Speaker 0: Well no, then a lifeguard comes along and they start yelling at everyone to get out of the water.
Speaker 0: And the guy is announcing, "The ocean is closed for the evening.
Speaker 0: Do not swim in the
Speaker 0: ocean.".
Speaker 0: So we get out of the water.
Speaker 1: And you wait until he leaves and go back in the water?
Speaker 0: Yes, and everyone does.
Speaker 0: So all along the beach you see this wave of people coming out of the water as he yells at them.
Speaker 0: And going right back in as soon as he drives ten feet further down the beach.
Speaker 0: He went back and forth for a while.
Speaker 0: And eventually we gave up and went home to get dinner.
Speaker 1: Well, you can't stay in the water forever.
Speaker 1: Especially when it gets dark and cold.
Speaker 0: It wasn't dark yet.
Speaker 0: It never got cold.
Speaker 0: It was so hot, Scott Johnson's dad turned on the AC.
Speaker 1: Holy shit!
Speaker 0: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: I got in and I was like, "Why are all the windows
Speaker 0: shut?".
Speaker 1: That was a mad powerful Eric.
Speaker 1: He has this crazy, it obviously looks crazy powerful.
Speaker 1: Is it crazy powerful?
Speaker 0: Well, he turned it on at the bare minimum.
Speaker 0: And inside he didn't notice.
Speaker 0: He's like, "It doesn't feel like the AC is
Speaker 0: on.".
Speaker 0: Then you walk outside and realize it's 25 degrees warmer out there.
Speaker 1: The front porch was even intolerable.
Speaker 0: The front porch was a little too hot to hang out on.
Speaker 1: Damn, that front porch even has a ceiling fan.
Speaker 1: It's such a great front porch.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: There were some surfers out there.
Speaker 0: It was good times.
Speaker 1: Alright, so I got a little thing that is not personal.
Speaker 1: But then I have a large personal revelation that was saved for the show.
Speaker 0: A person?
Speaker 0: Yeah, Scott wouldn't tell me.
Speaker 0: All he kept telling me was he's got something to say.
Speaker 1: Well, first of all, so I walk out.
Speaker 1: There's a new guy at work.
Speaker 1: Whatever, he's a new guy at work.
Speaker 1: So, I walk out of the office and I work like a few blocks north of Times Square.
Speaker 1: Basically, traffic is stopped.
Speaker 1: And it's just people everywhere going, "Oh, no, no, no,
Speaker 1: no.".
Speaker 1: Obviously, there's a famous person in the street.
Speaker 1: So, I'm just like, "Oh, fuck.
Speaker 1: Tourists.
Speaker 1: Get out of my way.
Speaker 1: God damn
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 0: Did it end up being someone cool?
Speaker 1: No, someone said that later.
Speaker 1: I was told on the tweets that Britney Spears is on the top of one of the tourist buses.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So, I'm just like,
Speaker 1: "Oh.".
Speaker 1: I looked and there were some people on top of one of the tourist buses.
Speaker 1: Is she still even famous?
Speaker 1: I don't fucking know.
Speaker 1: All I know is I'm like, "Whatever.
Speaker 1: These stupid, all these tourists.
Speaker 1: Everyone's just going
Speaker 1: woo.".
Speaker 1: I'm like, "Do you even like Britney Spears?
Speaker 1: Why are you going
Speaker 1: woo?".
Speaker 1: I mean, if I would have known it was her, I would have been like, "Bitch, you can't sing.
Speaker 1: Everyone go home.
Speaker 0: Bitch can't
Speaker 0: sing.".
Speaker 0: Scott, I would wager that the majority of people in the crowd didn't know who was there either.
Speaker 0: They were just going woo because other people were going woo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was just really, it was incredibly annoying.
Speaker 0: It's the real world woo game.
Speaker 1: So, here's the revelation.
Speaker 1: Are you ready for this?
Speaker 1: This is a killer.
Speaker 0: Is this, on the scale of, let's see, zero to ten, zero being, I don't know, Mars attacks, and ten being Steppenwolf, how much of a revelation was this?
Speaker 1: I know, it's maybe nine.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you ready for this?
Speaker 0: I'm ready.
Speaker 0: This is it.
Speaker 1: So, Emily will enjoy this as well.
Speaker 0: So, Rim- Is this like when you realized what the Beatles stood for?
Speaker 1: No, this is more than that.
Speaker 1: This is personal and not otherwise, right?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So, why does Scott not do any exercising?
Speaker 0: Because it hurts.
Speaker 1: Because it hurts.
Speaker 1: But there are some exercises I can do like- I don't know.
Speaker 0: I've never seen you exert yourself.
Speaker 1: Well, swimming.
Speaker 0: You can kind of swim.
Speaker 1: And also, remember I said I could bicycle forever as long as it's flat?
Speaker 0: At like one mile an hour, but yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay, anyway.
Speaker 1: So, I parked my car up on top of the hill on the street where I don't have to pay.
Speaker 1: Well, you technically do have to pay, but I haven't been able to pay.
Speaker 1: But the train was coming, so I ran down the hill.
Speaker 1: And you know, I don't have any asthma, right?
Speaker 1: And I don't have any other sorts of problems in that department, right?
Speaker 1: But, you know, it hurts when I do any sort of exertions, right?
Speaker 1: And no doctor has been able to tell me why forever.
Speaker 1: Even though I think they probably would have if they would have put me on the treadmill with the sticky bits and such.
Speaker 0: Because I did the treadmill sticky bit once in my childhood.
Speaker 1: I wanted to do it, but they never let me do it.
Speaker 1: And I think they would have figured out why I could not do any exercising.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I'm really curious to hear.
Speaker 1: It took me 27 years to figure it out.
Speaker 0: Because I'll point out that a lot of exercises, especially early on, does hurt a lot.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: And it turns into not hurting.
Speaker 1: You know why?
Speaker 1: I have a involuntary reflex when I exert myself, I hold my breath.
Speaker 1: And I went online to see if this was...
Speaker 0: A lot of people have that.
Speaker 1: I went online to see what it was called and I couldn't find what it was called.
Speaker 1: I just saw that people have it.
Speaker 1: And basically I saw like, you know, martial arts people mostly saying, "Hey, don't hold your
Speaker 1: breath.".
Speaker 1: And it's like, "Well, that's not really helping
Speaker 1: me.".
Speaker 1: Because then I'm like,
Speaker 1: "Okay.".
Speaker 1: So as soon as I realized it, I was like, "Oh my
Speaker 1: God.".
Speaker 1: Because that totally, like, I can swim.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: Because when you swim, you're supposed to hold your breath.
Speaker 0: Well, because I think you have the weird instinct, like the broken instinct of hold breath.
Speaker 0: But in the water, there's the contrary instinct of don't drown.
Speaker 1: That's the thing.
Speaker 1: Like if I run a long way, like when he ran with James and that little around the RIT thing.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, the Chase corporate challenge.
Speaker 1: The Chase corporate challenge, right?
Speaker 1: I hold my breath, but you know, because, you know, and then eventually when I'm going to die, it's just your body makes you breathe, right?
Speaker 1: But basically because you held your breath and then ran a bunch, you're now wrecked and you can't do anything and you fall over.
Speaker 1: And that's why, you know, if I'm biking flat, I'm not exerting.
Speaker 1: It's not, I'm not stressing, right?
Speaker 1: But if I go up the hill, then I just fall over and die.
Speaker 1: Because as soon as I start going up the hill and I have to push hard, I start holding my breath.
Speaker 0: See, because the thing is there are points where you hold your breath when you're exercising.
Speaker 0: Like when you're lifting weights, there's points where you hold, points where you breathe out, breathe in.
Speaker 1: I can't do a pushup.
Speaker 1: That's just because my arms are weak.
Speaker 1: But I can only try like once or twice before.
Speaker 1: I'm just like lying on the floor because while I'm pushing, I'm not breathing.
Speaker 0: So I tried to... You want to take some weights and while you're lifting, I'll just keep yelling,
Speaker 0: "Breathe!".
Speaker 1: I tried to consciously like breathe.
Speaker 0: Don't breathe.
Speaker 1: No more.
Speaker 1: I was like, OK, I stopped on the hill on the way down and I'm like, OK, consciously breathe now that you've realized this, right?
Speaker 1: So I'm like, OK, I can.
Speaker 1: So I breathe in.
Speaker 1: I start running.
Speaker 1: I didn't breathe out.
Speaker 1: I was like, fuck!
Speaker 1: So I don't, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I need some like... Here's what you need.
Speaker 1: A doctor couldn't diagnose me, but I need a doctor solution.
Speaker 1: I think that there has not been enough study in this area.
Speaker 0: I think there's a fairly simple solution, but it would hurt at first.
Speaker 0: You should take a martial art because in kung fu, you realize he would basically make us punch ourselves in the stomach and do all these hard exercises.
Speaker 0: And the whole time he would yell at us...
Speaker 1: I can't punch myself in the stomach.
Speaker 1: I'll get like an appendix explosion.
Speaker 0: Well, that comes after you make the muscle a little stronger than nothing.
Speaker 1: That's like halfway through the class.
Speaker 1: I also have stomach problems.
Speaker 1: I need a non-stomach exercise.
Speaker 0: But half of what he would do is force you.
Speaker 0: He'd make you do exercises where you breathe in and breathe out in very specific rhythms based on what you're doing.
Speaker 0: And he would hit you if you weren't breathing in or breathing out at the right time.
Speaker 1: I need, I need to hire the non-breather hitter.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, you want me to hit you?
Speaker 0: I'll hit you.
Speaker 1: I also read, this is also very dangerous apparently because when I was searching for it, I didn't know what to search for.
Speaker 1: I couldn't find any scientific word to describe it.
Speaker 1: I'm searching for like not breathing while exerting or not breathing while exercising or not breathing while running.
Speaker 1: And I couldn't, I found some people and I found people who had it and people who told you just basically the only advice is fucking breathe.
Speaker 1: There wasn't any other helpful advice.
Speaker 1: And it's like, I tried that already.
Speaker 1: It didn't work.
Speaker 1: So I need something else.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Or a word, you know, some, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Well, there's definitely an instinct when you're not terribly, or you're doing something that's more exertion than your body's ready for to hold your breath during the exertion.
Speaker 0: So if you're continually exerting and you're not used to it.
Speaker 1: Basically, if I try to do any exercise at all, I involuntarily hold my breath, use up all the oxygen in my body and then fall over and then breathe the whole bunch.
Speaker 0: So you should come around.
Speaker 0: I'll pace you will run.
Speaker 0: And every 10 seconds I'll say, Scott, breathe.
Speaker 1: That's I need more than like 10 seconds.
Speaker 1: I need to like, you know, consciously breathe before I start moving.
Speaker 0: Do you want me to make you an audio file?
Speaker 0: Just I need you to say, breathe in, breathe out.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It didn't work because I told myself to breathe in and out.
Speaker 1: I didn't.
Speaker 0: What if you have an audio tape telling you that?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I had to try it.
Speaker 0: I could follow you.
Speaker 0: I could follow you with like a 10 foot stick.
Speaker 0: I just want to know why.
Speaker 1: I want to know why a doctor couldn't tell me this right.
Speaker 1: You know, the doctor was like checking for like, you know, what's it called when your nose is bent out of shape?
Speaker 1: Deviated septum?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: He's checking for that.
Speaker 1: And he's checking for all this other stuff.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: No, they're checking for the asthma.
Speaker 1: I don't have any of that shit.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And he's like, I don't know.
Speaker 1: But apparently this is common enough that I could find it on the Internet that a bunch of people have it.
Speaker 1: But there's no word for it.
Speaker 1: A doctor can't tell you when it's you have the problem, I guess, without really investigating.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I don't think there's been enough study in this area at all.
Speaker 1: It could be a neurological thing.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: But it's apparently really dangerous because I was reading an article came up about like deep sea diver people and how they get wicked brain damage because they, you know, exert themselves like swimming while holding their breath for far too long.
Speaker 0: Well, part of that is because of it's very different breathing scuba.
Speaker 1: They also.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, well, no, no, no.
Speaker 1: I mean, deep sea divers like pearl diver types, not scuba.
Speaker 1: scuba is fine.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing about here's the thing.
Speaker 0: When your body passes out or you hold your breath for too long, the body forces you to breathe.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If you're deep sea diving, you can breathe in.
Speaker 1: So you're talking about like deep sea divers like to hold their breath for like really long.
Speaker 1: And it's, you know, getting Dane Brahmage.
Speaker 1: So I don't I don't think that's that's me.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is, sir, if you hold your breath for too long, your body will start breathing unless you're underwater.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The key is to not go underwater until you figure this out.
Speaker 1: I like swimming more than anyway.
Speaker 1: But I have to.
Speaker 1: I now I have to go and experiment and see what I can do.
Speaker 1: But I would I think I don't know how much I can do because I tried that and it didn't work now.
Speaker 1: So I have to get some sort of help now that I at least think I know what the problem is.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: No, I did at work at least.
Speaker 0: I finally got knocked out of the ping pong tournament.
Speaker 1: And you've got back into the winner's bracket or you're losing the loser's bracket.
Speaker 0: I made it a little bit further.
Speaker 0: And then I eventually lost in the loser's bracket to to someone who was really good, who was knocked out by the guy who knocked me out right away.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 0: And those two was a close match in the loser's bracket, though the loser's bracket finals, at least I got pretty far in the loser's bracket.
Speaker 0: But then the one I finally fought was basically like the second best person.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 0: So I lost by.
Speaker 1: you're not you're not the second best or the first.
Speaker 0: No, but I'm definitely in the top 10.
Speaker 0: And there are like 30 people who play ping pong regularly in the company.
Speaker 0: Oh, OK.
Speaker 0: I'm doing OK.
Speaker 1: But I played again as a friend.
Speaker 1: It's pretty big.
Speaker 1: Thirty people.
Speaker 1: I mean, I played against my floor.
Speaker 0: Boss's boss and I beat him.
Speaker 1: Was that the boss of all bosses?
Speaker 0: No, he's just the boss's boss.
Speaker 1: So there's a boss's boss's boss.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, he's a V.P.
Speaker 0: So there's only one level above the V.P So you're so you played one.
Speaker 1: You played someone who was one level below the top boss.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 0: And I beat him by using tricky English.
Speaker 0: He was trash talking up a motherfucking storm.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you, that's how that's how he gets to be.
Speaker 0: where he comes in.
Speaker 0: He puts on a headband.
Speaker 0: He starts swearing.
Speaker 1: He's ready to go.
Speaker 1: It's like, fuck you.
Speaker 1: I'm going to fuck you up.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And so all I did was just backspin, backspin, backspin, backspin, backspin, backspin.
Speaker 0: And I won.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's good stuff.
Speaker 1: You know, that's a good boss when he's back.
Speaker 0: Trash talk is pretty much one of the few indicators of a solid human being.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Or an asshole.
Speaker 1: Same thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's already gotten the news.
Speaker 1: Oh, shit.
Speaker 1: What was it?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Is actually, believe it or not, they're going to exert some editorial control on Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Well, they've done a few things like that in the past.
Speaker 1: So what they're doing basically is if there is any modification to a page of a famous person on the English site.
Speaker 0: Oh, they've already had policies like that.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 1: The change has to be approved by a certain change will not show up on the site at all.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Until it'll until a like Wikipedia approved person goes and like puts the OK on.
Speaker 1: It's like if you go to a famous person's page and put in like, you know, this person, I don't know, raves baby was in Times Square today making Scott's life slightly difficult.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Same as raping baby.
Speaker 1: Then that won't appear on Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: Everyone will see the old unedited page and then a good Wikipedia approved person will come in, see that and sort of click the green checkbox if it's good or click the red checkbox or the red X. About time, you know, no good.
Speaker 0: I was thinking in general Wikipedia should have for certain kinds of scientific articles and things that are pretty objective, have a way to have the kind of certified version of the page and then updates, updates, updates, updates.
Speaker 0: But you can look at the current version or the certified version.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Like the dev and the stable.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Like certified by some expert in the field, maybe a consortium, something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Something long.
Speaker 1: You know, it's not it's not the worst.
Speaker 1: The thing is, I wonder, I wonder if trade ideals for pragmatism.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I wonder if the the people who, though, are doing the green check in the red X flags, you know, know enough for this.
Speaker 1: Like, are they going to pay these people?
Speaker 1: What if, you know, I make a change to a famous person's page, but they're not that famous.
Speaker 1: And no one ever comes to give me the green check, even though it's true.
Speaker 0: There was another article a while ago about how the Wikipedia community, now that all the trivial additions are done, has really slowed down.
Speaker 0: And there is a very small core of very dedicated professionals and almost no one else contributes anymore.
Speaker 1: Because it's very difficult to find something to contribute.
Speaker 1: I mean, if there's a news art, if there's a news item, it gets immediately like immediately someone dies book page updated.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: So it's like, what can you possibly do unless, you know, talk about stuff that you're like the expert on or do what I do, which more people need to do, which is just go through every time you find a grammar or like typo mistake, anything like that.
Speaker 0: Just fix it anonymously.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That's what I most.
Speaker 1: the only big changes I ever make to Wikipedia are like when I go read an article about something and I see something blatantly wrong.
Speaker 1: And I just go and, you know, fix do the little fixes.
Speaker 1: I can't write a whole article.
Speaker 1: There's no whole article for me to write.
Speaker 0: I used to go out and attack certain pseudoscientific articles and basically it's not worth the effort.
Speaker 0: I won.
Speaker 0: I won some of my battles.
Speaker 0: But the baby one last I checked the Indigo Children article was OK.
Speaker 0: Thanks largely to me.
Speaker 0: Good job.
Speaker 0: Basically, I went in to save some indigo.
Speaker 0: I went in every couple of weeks and added the word allegedly in front of almost every sentence.
Speaker 1: OK, so any news over there?
Speaker 0: Of course, I want to point out that part of the reason they're probably doing this and they used to have a similar policy, not with the holding back the.
Speaker 1: Because you can get slandered, liable for this kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: They have a very strong policy about articles about individual people who are still alive.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But I want to talk a little bit about parking meters in Chicago because this is a really bad story.
Speaker 0: Basically, the city of Chicago purchased a 75 year lease on so-called smart, user friendly parking machine.
Speaker 1: Same kind of have in New York City.
Speaker 0: Kind of from Morgan Stanley.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Morgan Stanley.
Speaker 1: Isn't that a financial.
Speaker 0: Well, a Morgan Stanley consortium.
Speaker 1: OK, so basically they bought this to be a better choice.
Speaker 0: They bought the 75 year lease on these parking machines that everyone.
Speaker 1: they leased the machines.
Speaker 0: That's common.
Speaker 0: OK, but basically the machines suck and everyone agrees that they're terrible and they're a waste of money.
Speaker 0: They're like there's a gigantic scandal.
Speaker 0: They didn't check out.
Speaker 1: So that probably it was probably a lowest bidder situation where they didn't check the, you know, the quality.
Speaker 1: Well, no.
Speaker 0: Part of the problem is that the machines get this.
Speaker 0: So now if you want to park in these areas where they use these machines in Chicago, you have to park on the street.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: Walk like four blocks over to these little boxes.
Speaker 0: That's too far.
Speaker 1: You need one in every block.
Speaker 0: There aren't that many of them.
Speaker 1: That's not enough.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 0: Some of them are only a half a block away.
Speaker 0: It's still a ways though.
Speaker 1: It depends where you park.
Speaker 1: I mean, you could park right next to it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: And then you've got to, you know, type in your stuff and put your money in, get a receipt, put it in your window, go back to your car and put it in the window.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That's what the New York City knew.
Speaker 1: the ones in New York City.
Speaker 1: They do the same thing.
Speaker 1: The thing is, this box is all over the place.
Speaker 0: The ones you want on the same block, the ones in New York City are a lot older.
Speaker 0: And I note that in smart cities that old, there are old compared to these brand new ones.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 0: Plus, New York's had the system for a while, a little while.
Speaker 1: But I mean, New York had just plain old quarter in the meter for like fucking ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: A long time ago, they moved into those boxes less than like a decade ago.
Speaker 0: That's a long time in this sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, what a lot of smart cities do is just have machines where you type in the space number.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That's how the train station here does it.
Speaker 1: But I think that what they should do is not the space number.
Speaker 1: You should type in your license plate.
Speaker 0: Actually, that is what every other civilized country does on your cell phone.
Speaker 0: You text in you make an account and you text in like your license plate.
Speaker 1: What if I don't have a cell phone?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Screw you.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: We need to start.
Speaker 1: You know, we need to start if we want people to adapt to modern technology, that is that will help them.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like people have this thing where they won't get a technology until they need it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, they don't need it until they have it.
Speaker 1: Like, for example, you know, I always use the same example.
Speaker 1: Someone lives in a small town and they say, I don't need a car.
Speaker 1: Everything is in the walking distance.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But if they had a car, they would leave town.
Speaker 1: And if they left town, then after seeing what was outside the town that they never left before, they would want to leave the town.
Speaker 1: And thus now they only need the car after they've had the car.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like you only need the cell phone after you've had it.
Speaker 1: You have to have it first before you realize that you need it.
Speaker 1: And so I think we need to find any way possible to make people need technology that they don't think they need.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, if their lives are working fine, do we need to change them?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 1: Because it's better for them and they just don't know better is bad medicine.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, by having these magic wizard powers that not everyone has, we're basically in this separate, wonderful world.
Speaker 0: And by keeping people out of it, we just maintain our lives.
Speaker 1: You don't want to help the people.
Speaker 1: You just want to dominate the people.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm just putting this difference in you and me.
Speaker 0: I'm putting forward.
Speaker 1: I want to empower all the peoples because that makes it you know, the more people using it.
Speaker 0: The more fundamental problem here with these parking to reach the critical mass in general is that there is a huge problem in like upstate New York.
Speaker 0: And by upstate, I mean like the 30 miles north of Yonkers where these all these little small towns along the Hudson and they don't have enough parking.
Speaker 0: And a lot of small towns don't have enough parking.
Speaker 1: A lot of places.
Speaker 1: Boston doesn't have enough parking.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm not only talking about small towns right now, but they have.
Speaker 0: they don't have enough parking and they want to like.
Speaker 0: the root problem is not enough parking.
Speaker 0: And they want to encourage people from out of town to come in, park for like a couple hours, shop, put money in the community and then leave.
Speaker 0: They don't want residents parking there.
Speaker 0: They don't want anyone in the town parking there.
Speaker 0: And they don't want anyone parking there because they have an apartment nearby or parking long term.
Speaker 0: So they make they're making ever increasingly technological hurdles to using the parking spaces, things like pressure plates that determine.
Speaker 0: All right, I've parked here.
Speaker 0: I pay for like my four hours, which is the minimum I can pay for.
Speaker 0: I'm not allowed to put more money in without moving my car.
Speaker 0: And if I move my car for hours and it will.
Speaker 0: But if I move my car, the meter resets to zero.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So if I park for 15 minutes just to go to the dry cleaner, I got to pay for four hours.
Speaker 0: The person who comes after me can't use the rest of my time.
Speaker 0: It's gone.
Speaker 0: And the city gets the money.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And there are a ton of small towns that are basically using technology with parking meters and more and more advanced technology to solve the wrong problem or to generate revenue streams.
Speaker 0: And only in the end make things worse for everyone living in.
Speaker 1: this is this is true.
Speaker 1: However, I recently read this article.
Speaker 1: I got to read more.
Speaker 0: You bring this article up all the time.
Speaker 0: I can actually read it.
Speaker 1: What do you mean all the time?
Speaker 0: You've brought this up a lot.
Speaker 0: The article about how parking if we actually took into account what parking spaces cost.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think there's actually a book about it called like parking isn't?
Speaker 1: I forget what?
Speaker 1: I'm going to find the link and show it to you.
Speaker 1: But basically this guy, he said his whole thesis is that the actual cost of parking is like ludicrous.
Speaker 0: It depends on where you are.
Speaker 0: You realize, of course, it depends where you are in the Midwest or in towns that are made new recently.
Speaker 0: Parking is effectively free because that line wouldn't be used for anything anyway.
Speaker 1: But he just talks about the actual cost of a parking space, you know, and I'm sure it's very detailed if you wrote a whole book about it.
Speaker 1: And you know how even when people charge for parking, they're not charging anywhere even remotely close to the actual cost of the space.
Speaker 1: And it's actually, it turns out that when you look at the math, there's actually this gigantic government subsidy on parking because of the way it works out.
Speaker 0: Well, Scott, here's the question though.
Speaker 0: If they're not charging enough, how come parking garages make crazy tons of money?
Speaker 1: I'm just saying is that that's what this guy says.
Speaker 0: But how do they make so much money?
Speaker 1: He says it's effectively a government subsidy on parking.
Speaker 1: I'm curious how though because- I'm just saying what he says.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying I agree with it.
Speaker 1: What are you asking me?
Speaker 1: I just read like a synopsis of his thing.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: I didn't read the whole thing.
Speaker 1: You're attacking me like I'm the guy.
Speaker 0: Well, because you brought this article up more than once.
Speaker 1: I'm just bringing it up.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying I agree with it or that I know about it.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying that this guy's out there and this is what he says.
Speaker 0: I'm just pointing out that the fact that I can come up with a couple of I think pretty smart refutations immediately and out of nothing means that- I'm not disagreeing with your refutations.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying there's a whole book and I'm sure that there are things in that book because I didn't read it.
Speaker 1: that said probably answer your questions.
Speaker 1: Or at least are bad answers to your questions.
Speaker 0: The point I wanted to really bring up with this article is that, and we see this a lot, that people will seek technological solutions to the wrong problems.
Speaker 0: And when those solutions do not solve what they're actually trying to solve and they solve some other problem, they will continue to invest in the sunk cost of the wrong solution to the wrong problem trying to fix the root problem they could never possibly fix.
Speaker 0: It's like trying to make a line, like a wire between two poles, be perfectly horizontal.
Speaker 0: It is 100% mathematically and physically impossible.
Speaker 0: But yet they keep pulling harder and harder and harder on those poles.
Speaker 0: And I don't know what to do about it.
Speaker 1: Well, you know how you could do it though.
Speaker 1: You could have a third, taller pole that sort of lifts the wire up- But then it's not horizontal.
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: Alright, Scott.
Speaker 0: So now you've got two horizontal wires that are each bowing slightly in the center.
Speaker 0: Ah.
Speaker 1: You know what you could do though?
Speaker 0: Ten poles.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, no.
Speaker 1: You could have just, you know, you could do like a suspension bridge and basically the wire that you want to be horizontal will be like the suspension bridge.
Speaker 1: You want to have a- You'd have all these cables just suspending tiny segments of the actual cable itself.
Speaker 0: Scott, you know what the real answer is?
Speaker 0: It's okay to let it dip in the middle.
Speaker 0: It doesn't hurt anything.
Speaker 1: Here's another solution.
Speaker 1: Don't use a cable.
Speaker 1: Use like a steel beam.
Speaker 1: that's straight.
Speaker 0: Those dip a little bit in the center.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they do.
Speaker 1: You got a big old I-beam and just lay it down across two poles.
Speaker 0: Some minuscule amount.
Speaker 1: Oh, come on.
Speaker 0: Technically, yeah?
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay, whatever.
Speaker 0: Tiny bit.
Speaker 0: Microns.
Speaker 0: Sub-microns.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay, yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: You want to play that game?
Speaker 1: Poop just went in your mouth.
Speaker 0: Well, no.
Speaker 0: You see, there were two XK CDs about that and two wonder marks about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: So let's continue with this show.
Speaker 0: But it's more that people will engage in futile behavior and they'll blame the technology as opposed to their poor use of the technology.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: And aside from that, the only reason we can't have nice parking meters is because not everyone has nice phones in America.
Speaker 0: And even people who do don't know how to use their phones.
Speaker 0: And it's kind of like how we can assume that any adult who is a productive member of society has a credit card and a bank account.
Speaker 0: You can just assume that.
Speaker 0: And anyone who doesn't have both of those things kind of exists in this pseudo-economy that's underneath the main economy and usually doesn't interact with it directly.
Speaker 1: Funny story, my brother's car, he was driving, he got hit.
Speaker 1: You know what it was?
Speaker 1: A guy with no license, not a U.S.
Speaker 1: citizen, no insurance.
Speaker 0: It happens a lot.
Speaker 1: And the guy's brother who spoke English offered to just fix it and make it go away, but my brother just called the police.
Speaker 0: That's what I would do.
Speaker 1: Just had to take care, you know.
Speaker 0: That's why I pay for supplemental, you know, I don't even have collision on my car.
Speaker 1: Oh, collision's like the one that you're probably going to use.
Speaker 0: No, but I don't pay for it because I'm not going to hit anyone and I'll assume.
Speaker 1: You don't care about your piece of shit car.
Speaker 1: If you had a new car, you'd get the collision.
Speaker 0: What I do pay for is supplementary uninsured motorists.
Speaker 1: That's the most important.
Speaker 0: If anyone uninsured hits my car, they're fucked and I'm covered.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: But there's this whole problem where...
Speaker 1: You're saying the same thing over and over again.
Speaker 0: No, the whole bank account thing.
Speaker 0: Because we can assume the majority of people who are productive and in the economy have bank accounts or credit cards, things like that.
Speaker 0: Every business can just make these assumptions and we can have this higher level of business, this higher level of economic discourse.
Speaker 0: But with technology, you can't assume that any given person has an email address yet.
Speaker 0: Sad but true, you just can't.
Speaker 0: Businesses, if they need an email address, they're going to run into a lot of people who just don't have one.
Speaker 1: Well, people also, the email addresses change frequently and they're unreliable and people don't check them.
Speaker 0: Exactly, but technological people don't have these problems.
Speaker 0: Or with cell phones, I mean, you can't assume that everyone has a cell phone.
Speaker 0: There are still pay phones all over the place and there are a lot of people who rely on them in the case of emergency because they just don't have cell phones.
Speaker 0: So we can't make large civil structures reliant upon cell phones.
Speaker 0: We still need this back port technology.
Speaker 0: But in economics, we've gotten to the point to where...
Speaker 1: I think it's easy to solve it.
Speaker 1: We can do is we can just say, "Alright, listen up.
Speaker 1: This is what's going to
Speaker 1: happen.".
Speaker 1: Anyone who has a plain old telephone line, anyone who doesn't have a plain old telephone line or a cell phone, neither one.
Speaker 0: The people who don't have a cell phone, a number of some kind, landline or whatever, are in the same class of people who don't have bank accounts.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: So anyone who has a landline telephone will just give them a free piece of shit cell phone that doesn't do anything but make calls and be like, "Here you go.
Speaker 1: This comes with your local telephone
Speaker 1: line.".
Speaker 0: And what do you do when they never charge it because they don't know they have to?
Speaker 1: Well, that's just tough shit, but at least when you ask them for their cell phone number on a form, they'll have something that they can type in and complete the form.
Speaker 1: You can make it a required field because they have one.
Speaker 0: It's annoying to me in general that I...
Speaker 1: And if they don't bring it with them and then it causes them trouble because they don't have it, that's tough shit.
Speaker 1: because they can't say, "I didn't have
Speaker 1: one.".
Speaker 1: You can say, "Yes, you did have one.
Speaker 1: You didn't bring
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 0: There are a lot of things I could be doing that would make my life a lot better like at RIT when I could order all my pizza online just like that.
Speaker 1: I could order Chipotle online.
Speaker 1: It's in the same block as my office.
Speaker 1: I don't have to cross any streets to get to it.
Speaker 0: But at RIT, it was all integrated.
Speaker 0: You could go to the same site to order them all those places.
Speaker 1: Like at 2 a.m.
Speaker 1: when the pita pit would just walk up to the door.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: I miss that so much.
Speaker 1: Imagine if we could punch some numbers while we're doing the show and pita pit shows up at the door when the show is done.
Speaker 1: That is like... Who needs a mansion or a Ferrari?
Speaker 1: I want pita pit online delivery.
Speaker 0: But no, instead, if I want to order pizza, I got to call the guy on the phone and the pizza places around here suck.
Speaker 0: Some of them just don't even answer.
Speaker 0: The last time I called the guy, I didn't have the menu.
Speaker 0: As for Hawaiian pizza... He didn't know what Hawaiian pizza was.
Speaker 0: So I was like, fine, how about a margarita pizza?
Speaker 0: He didn't know what that was.
Speaker 0: So I told him what it was and then he made it.
Speaker 0: He was like, so what, you want pepperoni?
Speaker 1: You should have just said yes, pepperoni.
Speaker 1: Fine.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: So I'm sure many of you already read XKCD, but just in case, it's just too relevant.
Speaker 0: It's not even a joke.
Speaker 0: This isn't actually funny because it is 100 percent true.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like when I read some Dilberts from back in the day and I look at my job at IBM and all I can think is, you know what?
Speaker 0: That is in no way an exaggeration.
Speaker 0: That's exactly what my job is like.
Speaker 1: There is one thing that was recently modified on this chart, though, is you got to add... In addition to the Google aspect of the flow chart, you need to add the Stack Overflow trilogy is right past the Google part.
Speaker 1: It's like Google doesn't work.
Speaker 1: Stack Overflow trilogy.
Speaker 1: That doesn't work.
Speaker 1: Then go back.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: Stack Overflow is when you're looking for an answer and you're going to ask it.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't ask it in this situation because I wouldn't care.
Speaker 1: I guess.
Speaker 1: But yeah.
Speaker 0: And also Google, if the answer was already on Stack Overflow, it would find it.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: But it is the flow chart of literally how to be the local computer expert pretty much anywhere in the world.
Speaker 0: And I am so...
Speaker 1: It's how to be the anything expert.
Speaker 0: I am so dead serious when I say...
Speaker 1: Almost anything expert.
Speaker 0: When I say that this is all that... This is literally all that I do when anyone asks me a computer question.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: There is no other thing I do.
Speaker 0: I have no special knowledge.
Speaker 0: I don't know... I don't even know a lot about consumer computers anymore.
Speaker 0: This is how we learn the computer.
Speaker 1: shit is we just did this so many times that eventually we remember some of them.
Speaker 0: But even then, like my work is so divorced from normal computers that if someone asks me like an Outlook question or like a Microsoft Word question or even a Windows question.
Speaker 1: You have no idea.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what to do.
Speaker 1: I don't know how to use Outlook or telephones, but I know how to like make websites.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I learned how to use some stupid...
Speaker 1: I know how to do like some crazy embedded Linux shit, but I don't know anything about fucking, you know, like Microsoft PowerPoint.
Speaker 1: How to get a video to actually fucking work if it's possible.
Speaker 0: But this is 100% straight up absolutely literally exactly what computer people do when you ask them a stupid question.
Speaker 0: So you could use this flowchart and do it yourself.
Speaker 0: And I'm not kidding.
Speaker 0: It'll work every time.
Speaker 1: Unless you're moron.
Speaker 1: OK, so this is actually pretty cool.
Speaker 1: You know, when people are programming things right there, often the hacky last minute solutions, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know, often, you know, the hacky last minute solution is something that the programmer dreads.
Speaker 1: It's like, do I really want to do this?
Speaker 1: It's sort of painful to do it.
Speaker 1: But often it is humorous, especially when it is related to video games.
Speaker 1: So there here are 10 actual real world examples of hacky bullshit that was put into video games.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So my favorite example is one where basically they were playing.
Speaker 1: They're making this game right.
Speaker 1: And in like level 10, like one of the objects needed to be invisible, but they couldn't make it.
Speaker 1: They wanted it to be hidden, but it just wouldn't work like in the map editor.
Speaker 1: So rather than redo the whole map, they went into the game engine and they basically put in like, if level equals 10 and object ID equals 58, object ID 58 is hidden.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: And what happened was is they, you know, they later had other people using the game engine to make other games.
Speaker 1: You know, they sold it out like unreal.
Speaker 0: No one can figure out how to make something hidden.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 1: It's somebody was making a game and they're like, they made in level 10, the 58th object they made, and they called them up with like, you know, cause with this for the support and they're like, Hey, I'll come to this object keeps disappearing.
Speaker 1: What do we do?
Speaker 1: Uh, just make a 59th object.
Speaker 1: You know, but yeah, that was a, you know, that's just one of the examples in this funny, funny, uh, website.
Speaker 0: That is very close to why I enjoy negative worlds and things so much in video games.
Speaker 1: So you should, you should read this for more similar humorous anecdotes and that particular humorous anecdote as well.
Speaker 0: So we were debating some sort of what if show tonight, we won't go super long on this, but I think it's a good concept.
Speaker 0: We could explore in much more detail, but we were thinking about what if something crazy happened?
Speaker 0: Like what if windows went open source?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, it's, I started thinking of like, you know, the, the question of like, what would you do if you were in charge of Apple?
Speaker 1: Well, the answer is always I'd open source everything and be the good guy.
Speaker 1: I don't, you know, and I'd live a life of luxury with all the monies, you know, and it's the same situations.
Speaker 1: Like what if you were in charge of the phone companies?
Speaker 1: I'd stop being a Dick.
Speaker 1: I'd give everyone unlimited everything for a low, low price and I'd make the network not suck.
Speaker 1: And I'd let you use any phone with any app and you know, and it's like, okay, there's nothing really exciting to talk about in that question.
Speaker 1: So I was like, the more interesting question is like, if the shit was open source, what awesome thing would you do?
Speaker 1: You know, it's, it's like, you know, cause what would you do?
Speaker 1: You know, like if the iPhone, it's like, okay, sure.
Speaker 1: The iPhone's open source now.
Speaker 1: What are you going to do?
Speaker 1: That's so awesome.
Speaker 1: Now, uh, podcasts sinking over the airwaves.
Speaker 0: That's a good one.
Speaker 0: And Google voice.
Speaker 1: That's a good one too.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: That and multitasking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, I would do, um, wifi, Bluetooth, uh, uh, exchanging of, of, uh, music and video that was completely uninhibited in any way whatsoever.
Speaker 1: So like you could just go to your, you know, connect from your iPhone to your friend's iPhone.
Speaker 1: You're just like, here's my MP3.
Speaker 1: Just sends it to him.
Speaker 1: And now it's on his iPod.
Speaker 1: No problem.
Speaker 1: Why doesn't the zoom fricking do this?
Speaker 1: Why doesn't anyone do this?
Speaker 1: It's no, there's no technological problem preventing this.
Speaker 0: Well, the media companies might sue them.
Speaker 1: It's tough shit.
Speaker 1: We didn't do it.
Speaker 1: It's not illegal to do that.
Speaker 1: People are exchanging their files that they, that they, you know, they have legitimately.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So the thing is all the companies who are in a position to do it are too enmeshed in the media companies and all the stuff to do it.
Speaker 1: I would totally do that so quickly.
Speaker 0: Um, so Scott, the question on the show that is, what would you do if Linux were open source?
Speaker 1: Ah, everything I'm already notice.
Speaker 1: Isn't it so weird, right?
Speaker 1: It's like if Linux are open source, which it is, what would you do?
Speaker 1: And it's like, well, I don't really do anything because you know, part of it is because a Linux is an operating system kernel and I'm not really a kernel kind of programming guys.
Speaker 1: There's not much I can do in that area without lots of work, but it's also be sort of because it's been done.
Speaker 1: It's like everyone's fucking doing it.
Speaker 1: They jump on it before you can even get.
Speaker 0: well, except for media support and sound.
Speaker 1: People are working on it.
Speaker 1: There's actually some big head.
Speaker 1: Did you see?
Speaker 1: Oh my God, there's a thing.
Speaker 1: Uh, you're going to love this.
Speaker 1: Uh, Ubuntu is coming out with this thing called quickly.
Speaker 0: I was looking at that.
Speaker 1: Did you see that?
Speaker 1: I sent you the link.
Speaker 0: My coworker was looking at it actually.
Speaker 0: He's more developer than I am.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's basically what they did.
Speaker 1: is we come up with all these web frameworks to help you like rails and Django that, you know, to make web pages, you know, with a nice, you know, model and everything, right?
Speaker 1: Jenga Ubuntu just basically came out with the same thing for desktop apps.
Speaker 1: So it's like, yeah, just use this.
Speaker 1: And it's real easy to make Ubuntu desktop applications.
Speaker 1: I'm like, holy shit.
Speaker 1: That's like way ahead of Microsoft right there.
Speaker 1: Way ahead.
Speaker 1: It's like, it's like XNA for like desktop applications.
Speaker 1: That's like, that's a big deal.
Speaker 1: And I think it's gonna, I think I might actually, I might learn it and make something.
Speaker 1: I mean, who knows?
Speaker 0: Make me a, uh, a resound that doesn't crash.
Speaker 1: Well, the joke kosher was sorta gonna be that.
Speaker 0: Do anything and audacity.
Speaker 0: They keep talking.
Speaker 0: The thing is he's going to go somewhere, but it's not.
Speaker 1: If you get me, I need to get like a book of like audio algorithms and then I need to get a book about like wave files.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then I can just get all the open source decoders and encoders.
Speaker 1: And I can convert everything to wave format.
Speaker 0: thing is lads.
Speaker 1: And then I can get an open source fast for your transform.
Speaker 1: And then once I have all those pieces that I don't have to reinvent those wheels, I just have to implement the algorithms as they are in the.
Speaker 0: The thing is with lads, but there are a lot of plugins that do all those things.
Speaker 0: All I really need is the good interface.
Speaker 1: Oh, you just need the interface.
Speaker 0: The interface is all you can do.
Speaker 1: the interface because it uses Glade, which basically is just a drag and drop, draw your interface.
Speaker 1: And then it makes an XML file that defines the interface.
Speaker 1: You can do all that.
Speaker 1: Then you just bind the interface to the methods in the, in the thing.
Speaker 0: The thing is what I need is all the rest of the code under the interface.
Speaker 1: It comes with, you can just steal it from, you know, reusable libraries and such like and such and such.
Speaker 0: It's already too much work.
Speaker 0: I don't have time.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, it would take you longer than it would take me.
Speaker 0: What would I do if anything was open source?
Speaker 0: The answer is nothing because I'm too busy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But I guess it's more about, I mean, like I would do all that kind of shit for the iPhone if I didn't have to do it in like Objective C with, and they didn't, you know, there's no app approval process crap.
Speaker 1: You know, I do the same shit for like, you know, any portable device, you know, just freely transfer files between the devices, you know, run any app, you know, do all that stuff.
Speaker 1: Maybe it had like a video edit.
Speaker 1: They need some video editing on there.
Speaker 1: There's just, there's.
Speaker 1: no, you know, it's like nothing.
Speaker 1: A lot of them let you take videos, but they don't let you edit the videos.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, even like, like the iPhone, actually, I took some pictures with the iPhone like yesterday, but again, and when I pushed the picture button, it looked fine.
Speaker 1: And then later when I uploaded to Flickr, they're blurry.
Speaker 1: I was like, what the hell?
Speaker 1: It didn't give me like this usable picture preview and get like lied to me.
Speaker 1: It told me the picture was fine.
Speaker 0: The pre is like perfect.
Speaker 1: The pre is a lot better with the pictures.
Speaker 1: There's no doubt about that.
Speaker 1: What would you do if like the windows were open source?
Speaker 1: That's like the notorious one.
Speaker 0: The thing is, I think there's the, you know, like.
Speaker 0: what would I do personally if I were, if I had the time to code and everything?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're assuming that you can do it and you have time to do it.
Speaker 0: Because I would look more at Apple.
Speaker 0: Apple is what I really want to be open source.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's mad close.
Speaker 0: Because what I would do is I would add goddamn refresh buttons to every single window and dialogue and all of fucking OS X.
Speaker 1: All the finder.
Speaker 0: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: Everything would refresh.
Speaker 0: I could refresh it manually.
Speaker 1: I'd fix all the stupid keyboard shortcuts.
Speaker 1: That's what I would do.
Speaker 0: I would remove the Apple key entirely and use the windows key.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, the command key is the windows key, right?
Speaker 1: That's the secret that people don't realize.
Speaker 0: But I would make it act like the windows key.
Speaker 0: There'd be no like Apple key.
Speaker 1: Everything would be control and all and not, you know, command.
Speaker 1: Command would not be used for keyboard shortcuts unless the windows key were also used for those keys.
Speaker 0: I would also figure out all the contexts of all the different things in OS X. And I would then make a banner added to the bottom of every window and every program telling you what context you were in.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I would also make it so that you could like, you know, maximize a window and it would actually perfectly and nicely maximize.
Speaker 1: It wouldn't be like, yeah, we'll sort of stretch out a bit here.
Speaker 1: We won't really, you know.
Speaker 0: It always bothers me.
Speaker 0: I hit maximize the window that gets like 10 pixels bigger.
Speaker 0: I'm like, what the fuck?
Speaker 1: It's like I want to actually, you know, let me lay out these windows in a nice grid.
Speaker 1: You know, why are you making me sort of, you know, waste all this desktop space just so I can, you know, force me to be fast and loose.
Speaker 1: Screw that shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: With windows is tough because there's not a lot.
Speaker 1: Because I think the problem with windows is that, you know, even though it's closed source, everything already exists for windows.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like maybe what I would do for windows, right, is I would sort of rewrite like, you know, the front ends of it.
Speaker 1: Like I would take the windows kernel and so that it could run any windows application.
Speaker 1: You know, I'd get all the libraries and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: All the under the hood parts.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess, you know, you could do if windows is open source.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It would be really like wine would basically be gangbusters.
Speaker 1: So what you could do is you could basically take it and fork it and make a perfect implementation of the windows API such that you could run any windows application on a machine that's not running windows.
Speaker 1: And it would work perfectly, you know, as if it was windows.
Speaker 1: And I guess you could do the same thing with Mac.
Speaker 1: Like if OS X was completely open source, every part of it, then you could just re implement the entire API.
Speaker 1: You know, you could just take the code and, you know, just use it, reuse it.
Speaker 1: And you can make like this wicked crazy fast, you know, machine that could run any Linux, windows or Mac application just natively with no virtual machines whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Well, if I'm going wish list wise, I would just make the windows kernel para virtualized.
Speaker 0: Well, isn't it able to be virtualized?
Speaker 1: You can use Microsoft's virtually that they bought.
Speaker 1: What's it called?
Speaker 0: But you can't use it just like straight up with VMware or Zen yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's true.
Speaker 1: It's true.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: And it only works with mixes.
Speaker 1: It doesn't work with OS X or.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's something else, right?
Speaker 1: Is like if you're on a Mac and you use a virtual machine thing like virtual box or parallels, you can run Linux's, of course, in any virtual environment.
Speaker 1: But you can also run Windows's on Windows.
Speaker 1: You can run Windows's and Linux's in your VMware, but you can't run OS X in your VMware on Windows.
Speaker 1: You can't run OS X on anything but a Mac.
Speaker 1: But it was open source.
Speaker 1: You could run your OS X, you know, on your PC that you bought built from Newegg.
Speaker 1: You could run it in your virtual machine on your Linux box.
Speaker 1: You could run it just freaking anywhere.
Speaker 1: So I think I really think if OS X is open source, there would be a lot less Mac purchasing.
Speaker 1: I think there'll be a lot of people running OS X and all sorts of other devices.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, I feel like Apple could still make money in that world in the long run with with their good industrial design.
Speaker 0: They'd have to cut their profit margins.
Speaker 0: But if they just made different styles of embedded or small purpose specific, like, you know, think about the wonderful industrial design of the Mac Mini right now.
Speaker 0: That thing is a beauty to behold.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing.
Speaker 0: What if they made like 10 different computers that were like that for different purposes, like the car computer and the house computer?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, the car computer you don't see.
Speaker 1: But I think Apple's big thing is that their business model is cell hardware and everything else.
Speaker 1: iTunes, you know, OS X, whatever.
Speaker 1: All those things are just there because they sell hardware.
Speaker 1: That's why the Snow Leopard is only thirty dollars.
Speaker 1: It's coming out Friday, by the way, is because they're not trying to sell you Snow Leopard.
Speaker 1: Snow Leopard only exists because it's so awesome and it only runs on the Mac hardware.
Speaker 1: So it makes you buy the Mac hardware, which they overcharge you for.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And they make all their money.
Speaker 1: If you could get all the Apple shinies on other platforms besides Apple hardware, they would actually have to make their money on non hardware or they'd have to make their or they would basically lose all their profit margin because their hardware would not have to compete with the other hardware on a level playing field.
Speaker 1: And Apple would basically just go, well, they have no business.
Speaker 1: They'd have to.
Speaker 1: What would they do?
Speaker 1: What would their business model be?
Speaker 0: The thing is, right now, for certain kinds of industrial design, no one even comes close to Apple.
Speaker 1: Some have this better industrial design, but they can only charge so much more for it if OS X runs on other devices.
Speaker 0: But if they dropped all of their development teams, except for the iPhone stuff, they'd probably be fine.
Speaker 1: No, because then no one would because then the no one would use the OS X, everyone use Windows, and then no one would use a Mac.
Speaker 1: Now, because they'd have to start selling Macs with Windows on.
Speaker 1: They'd probably just let the open source community make OS OS, whatever, because if they don't control the whole experience, the whole thing falls apart because Apple.
Speaker 1: The reason that Apple stuff get gives you the experience it does is because they unify the hardware in the.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like look at Android.
Speaker 1: Android is designed for any sort of phone.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So what do you get?
Speaker 1: You get these funky ass devices that don't have like a headphone hole and shit like that.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But the iPhone software is built assuming you have an iPhone with this one button.
Speaker 1: And right.
Speaker 1: It's the hardware software unity that makes the stuff work that way.
Speaker 1: And if the saw if the OS X is done in an open source way just to make it as good as possible, it would be awesome.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But you wouldn't have that crate that, you know, Apple unified experience where the hardware and the software go together.
Speaker 1: Like you have that eject button in the top right of the keyboard and the OS, you know, ejects when you hold it down.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, there would probably be among all the forks of OS X and OS 11.
Speaker 1: You wouldn't have like the multi finger gestures and the giant touch pad.
Speaker 0: But it's got all the different force and things that the craziness that would happen.
Speaker 0: I am sure I expect that there would be one fork that was predominantly controlled by Apple fanboys.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But Apple fanboys are much, you know, the problem with that right is.
Speaker 1: I know that sounds good.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying it sounds good.
Speaker 0: I'm saying that they might keep the spirit alive.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Something I've learned is that fanboys ruin the spirit.
Speaker 1: I mean, think about this.
Speaker 1: That's like letting people in the tribes forums write tribes.
Speaker 1: It's not going to work.
Speaker 1: Not at all.
Speaker 1: It's you can't let the people who play the game write the game.
Speaker 1: It's just a mess.
Speaker 1: Or Scott letting Magic the Gathering players write Magic the Gathering cards.
Speaker 0: I guess let me put it in this perspective.
Speaker 0: What if it was open source and Steve Jobs and over the Steve Jobs fork, just like there's the whoever he delegated.
Speaker 0: You know, he would bless one fork and he would like approve different releases of that fork.
Speaker 0: as you know, you can use whatever one you want.
Speaker 0: It's all open source.
Speaker 0: But this is the one that Apple says is the good one.
Speaker 1: Somehow, I don't think he would like any of them as soon as he got open source.
Speaker 1: And he'd like start saying, do this, do that.
Speaker 1: And people who said is, you know, he'd have to start dealing with this kind of shit.
Speaker 1: Linus Torvalds deals with where people actually tell him he's wrong.
Speaker 0: But the thing is, I love the man, but he's an asshole.
Speaker 1: I didn't say he wasn't an asshole.
Speaker 1: I'm saying, you know, people can't.
Speaker 1: people in the open source world have to deal with, you know, people arguing with them and telling them they're wrong and actually having debates over decisions.
Speaker 1: Steve Jobs just says it's my way or the highway, and I don't think he could deal with someone telling him no.
Speaker 1: And if it's open source, even if there's the Steve Jobs blessed version and maybe he has some fanboys who do his bidding.
Speaker 0: Enough people would do his bidding, sadly.
Speaker 1: The thing is someone would eventually come and be like, Steve Jobs, this is a bad, dumb ass idea.
Speaker 1: You should do it this way instead.
Speaker 1: And he'd be like, no, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, you get forks.
Speaker 0: But Scott, that wouldn't be any different than it is now.
Speaker 1: Steve Jobs would basically have a heart attack to go with his liver action.
Speaker 0: The thing is, none of that's going to happen.
Speaker 0: And the more interesting question is what would like, what would be the actual ramifications of if like Microsoft, just like Bill Gates, like, you know what?
Speaker 0: It's over.
Speaker 0: And everything was just like Windows is open source.
Speaker 0: And that was it.
Speaker 1: Well, Microsoft make a lot less money.
Speaker 1: I mean, Microsoft really doesn't have a way to make money.
Speaker 1: They're not like Apple selling hardware.
Speaker 1: They sell Windows.
Speaker 1: Windows is open source, right?
Speaker 1: Because think about this.
Speaker 1: This has been a hot topic lately.
Speaker 1: When you're a Linux guy, right?
Speaker 1: Linux is free.
Speaker 1: You can install it a billion times.
Speaker 1: No problem.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So when you say you want to set up like a cluster, it's no big deal.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, we'll get a bunch of hardware, a bunch of machines.
Speaker 1: It was all Linux on all of them.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: When you're a Windows guy, setting up one gigantic, crazy, powerful computer instead of a cluster is a good idea.
Speaker 1: And it's like, what are you crazy?
Speaker 1: No one does the one giant machine anymore.
Speaker 1: Everyone does the bunch of cheap machines.
Speaker 1: That's the way to do it.
Speaker 1: But with Windows, a bunch of cheap machines, you have to buy a copy of Windows for each machine.
Speaker 1: Now, the machines aren't cheap anymore because you're buying a two hundred dollar copy of Windows for all the machines.
Speaker 1: You got five machines.
Speaker 1: That's an extra thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: You're paying six machines worth of money for five machines.
Speaker 1: If you need 10 machines, it's a two thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: It's crazy.
Speaker 1: So Windows people, it's actually sort of good idea to get the one big machine and install Windows on it once.
Speaker 1: You know, and think about it.
Speaker 1: That's only Windows.
Speaker 1: If you're doing a Microsoft platform, you've got to buy SQL Server.
Speaker 1: You've got to buy maybe Office.
Speaker 1: You've got to buy Exchange Server.
Speaker 1: Who knows what you're putting on there.
Speaker 1: All the Microsoft server stuff costs money, lots of money, tons of money, you know.
Speaker 1: So one big machine is a good idea with Microsoft.
Speaker 1: If it was open source and people would just get, there was no Windows licenses and no, you know, licenses for any of the Microsoft software.
Speaker 1: People would start installing Windows and everything, tons, you know, machines.
Speaker 1: And Microsoft wouldn't get any money from that and they wouldn't get money from anything.
Speaker 1: And that's it.
Speaker 1: They would get money for supporting like Red Hat.
Speaker 1: They'd be in the poorhouse.
Speaker 1: Microsoft would turn from like this giant world conquering company into like a one building situation.
Speaker 0: But that's pretty much expected.
Speaker 0: What would happen in the community?
Speaker 0: I mean, there would be.
Speaker 1: there would be.
Speaker 1: there would be crazy action with Windows.
Speaker 0: I think with Windows specifically, just because of the way the architecture is and the way people, it would take at least a couple of years for the community to grasp the code enough to make meaningful and safe changes to it.
Speaker 1: No, I don't think it would be about making safety.
Speaker 0: No, I think what it would be is people would.
Speaker 0: what would really happen.
Speaker 0: People would go in and find the good, like the specific bits that they needed to know how they work, like different APIs or different functions under the covers and port them elsewhere.
Speaker 0: Absolutely.
Speaker 1: It would be a raid.
Speaker 1: It'd be like, holy shit.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like.
Speaker 1: what if Photoshop was open source, right?
Speaker 0: Like we just get any of this on Linux like that.
Speaker 1: And I think if Photoshop.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty solid.
Speaker 1: I mean, if Photoshop was open source, people might modify it.
Speaker 1: But I think mostly the GIMP would just have a field day and raid it for all the filtering algorithms and stuff.
Speaker 1: They'd be like, well, Photoshop plugins work in the GIMP now.
Speaker 1: You know, they just be raiding it, stealing all the good out.
Speaker 1: What if the Nvidia driver was open source?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They would be a raid.
Speaker 1: They would take that shit and put it right in the kernel.
Speaker 1: Like it would take a day, if not less.
Speaker 1: You know, they just like, here's all those algorithms that we didn't know.
Speaker 1: You know, here's all the secrets of how that hardware works.
Speaker 1: Let's steal all that shit.
Speaker 1: Well, it wouldn't be stealing because we open source, but you just take all the good stuff and they would use it elsewhere as opposed to fixing it in its, you know, its current place.
Speaker 1: You get like, you know, the GIMP would be doing like all this stuff that Photoshop does that everyone complains about.
Speaker 1: You'd get like support for, you know, all those weird webcams and stuff and Linux just suddenly, you know, all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: It wouldn't be there wouldn't be that much modifying of windows to do other things, because if you start doing that, you'd actually break more than you fixed.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Because I mean, windows, all these things are built to work on windows in a certain way.
Speaker 1: You know what someone might do?
Speaker 1: They might do the no registry windows fork.
Speaker 1: I can see that someone make a fork of windows that doesn't have a registry that has like a couch DB instead.
Speaker 0: The thing is, it would serve the same purpose.
Speaker 1: No, but a couch DB would outperform.
Speaker 1: Well, the real problem with the registry is a file system situation.
Speaker 0: The real problem with the registry is partly that windows has no real capability to refresh without rebooting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that someone making no reboot windows unless you update the windows kernel.
Speaker 1: You get all sorts of stuff like that, maybe, but mostly if stuff became open source, like if apples, if OS X became open source, the next day, Linux and gnome would have like the most beautiful font rendering in the universe.
Speaker 1: You know, they would just steal OS X font rendering in the drop shadows.
Speaker 1: Like, thank you.
Speaker 0: So the moral here is that OS 10 and Microsoft windows will never, ever, ever be open source because it would destroy both companies.
Speaker 1: Probably not.
Speaker 1: No, I mean, it might happen if like someone with a ton of money just buys them out.
Speaker 1: It might happen if say, see, it's something I don't understand, right?
Speaker 1: They should, what they should do to sort of get the most because they're not, they're not maximizing their, what they're doing, right?
Speaker 1: What they should do is they should follow in.
Speaker 1: software model is when, like when windows seven comes out, open source XP, you don't need to open source Vista, but open source the XP, right?
Speaker 1: No one's for, you know, I mean, or at least open source, like windows 2000 or NT or 3.1 is so old.
Speaker 1: There's nothing.
Speaker 1: What is in there?
Speaker 0: Well, well, you need to, I mean, maybe something in there, but, but I can say there's two reasons.
Speaker 0: One, there's probably some code in there.
Speaker 0: They don't want out.
Speaker 0: They're worried that people might find exploits that made their way into more modern versions.
Speaker 1: I mean, oh no.
Speaker 1: I mean, the wine can already run any windows 3.1.
Speaker 0: More importantly, there are probably patent and cross.
Speaker 1: That's a legal situation.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about business.
Speaker 0: I'm ignoring the legal, the legal situation is the primary reason.
Speaker 0: I mean, uh, was to warp.
Speaker 0: We finished using it.
Speaker 0: We had version 4.5 at IBM.
Speaker 0: We used it.
Speaker 0: And yet we know it'll never be open source.
Speaker 0: And I have, uh, uh, OS two warp for my first computer.
Speaker 1: There are so many owned in my house that I was to work.
Speaker 0: There's so many IP owned by all these different companies and so many patents and so much stuff on the inside.
Speaker 0: That'll never be open source.
Speaker 0: Now it's lost to the world.
Speaker 1: But I mean, like why doesn't Apple open source like, Oh, S nine, you know, cause then people could do all this awesome OS nine shit and it would be cool.
Speaker 1: And you know, who need, you know, OS 10, you know, keep it your closed source obviously, but you know, open source, the OS nine, it would be awesome.
Speaker 1: And everyone would do all this, you know, you'd be able to run OS nine apps, you know, or one through nine apps on, uh, Linux.
Speaker 1: It would be totally cool.
Speaker 1: And everyone would get all like these old Mac games and it'd be sweet and you wouldn't need to get like a Mac plus like I have in my closet.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I think we're done.
Speaker 1: We are done.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.
Speaker 1: dot front road crew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.