Speaker 2: It's Wednesday, March 11th, and this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 2: Tonight, Urasawa's Pluto.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 2: So I'm walking back to our work from Brian Park.
Speaker 2: I was outside taking a long lunch, enjoying myself, and taking a break, and I suddenly hear a noise so distinct and so full of memories from earlier in my life that I had to stop.
Speaker 2: Now, there was no tribes 2 turret coming out of the ground to get me.
Speaker 2: But what happened?
Speaker 2: I'm walking and I hear this sound and I had to stop.
Speaker 2: I stopped dead in my tracks because I knew at that moment that an angel was descending to destroy the earth.
Speaker 2: You know that industrial like from Ava that they play in like every episode.
Speaker 2: It's that periodic like tamping.
Speaker 2: It's like this generic industrial noise, but Ava had a very specific one.
Speaker 2: I heard that exact noise, and I'm like alright, and I look around because maybe I'll find out what that sound was like what pulley they did or what they recorded.
Speaker 1: Someone was watching Ava on a laptop with a little speaker.
Speaker 2: It looks like they had guys hammering something into an I-beam about ten stories up on the skyscraper.
Speaker 2: I was walking by.
Speaker 2: So I heard the Ava noise, but that's I don't know.
Speaker 2: That's the most relevant anime related anecdote I've got.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what noise you're talking about.
Speaker 2: You really don't?
Speaker 1: I mean, maybe if it was cicadas.
Speaker 1: I'd be like ah.
Speaker 2: No, it wasn't the cicadas.
Speaker 2: It was like the generic banging industrial noise from Ava.
Speaker 2: They use it.
Speaker 2: It seems like they use that noise a lot more later in the series.
Speaker 1: The thing is right.
Speaker 1: whenever I watch like an anime, and they have the cicada noise.
Speaker 1: I'm like okay, but like my grandma lived in Queens.
Speaker 1: You know if I would like sleep over there in the summer.
Speaker 1: I would hear the cicadas in the morning.
Speaker 1: They didn't sound like that at all.
Speaker 1: So I don't know if it's a Japanese cicadas sound different.
Speaker 1: That's what I was going to say.
Speaker 1: It's probably a different kind.
Speaker 2: In fact the cicadas where I grew up don't sound like the cicadas here.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 2: I mean, maybe it wasn't cicadas, but yeah.
Speaker 1: I don't know if there's any right here.
Speaker 1: I know there's some in Queens.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I haven't really heard them in Beacon that much now that I think about it.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I guess the room of goth is empty.
Speaker 1: Instead here I hear I hear thought birds.
Speaker 2: You know if you ever climb Breakneck Ridge, there's a lot of them out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, thought bird what you gonna do?
Speaker 2: All right, so it's anime day, manga day, comic day, news day.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's some good news going down.
Speaker 2: Good as in interesting or good as in actually good.
Speaker 2: Because the anime industry has not been, shall we say, replete with good news.
Speaker 1: This is pretty good news if you're smart.
Speaker 1: This is excellent news.
Speaker 1: I don't know if you're gonna be able to handle this news.
Speaker 2: Well, it can't be that Sanctuary, Eagle and every manga I've ever liked is being re-released and I'm getting a copy for free.
Speaker 1: But close.
Speaker 1: Oh, yes.
Speaker 1: Pokemon is originally...
Speaker 2: Oh, snap!
Speaker 2: I'm gonna get to read about red again and yellow.
Speaker 1: So Pokemon was originally a Game Boy game.
Speaker 1: That was the first Pokemon thing ever, right?
Speaker 1: Because there's a lot of Pokemon stuff.
Speaker 1: There's an anime, there's toys, there's video games, right?
Speaker 1: The Game Boy games, Red and Blue or Red and Green or whatever, were the original.
Speaker 1: That was the first Pokemon thing there ever was.
Speaker 2: Now what's scary is that one, that was both a long time ago and at the same time, not that long ago.
Speaker 1: I know, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I was already sort of too old for Pokemon when it appeared and yet it's still around.
Speaker 2: Well, the other thing that amazes me is that if you ask people how long they've been fans of Pokemon, especially people in our age group, people feel like it's hard to remember when Pokemon appeared.
Speaker 2: You feel as though it's always been there.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, think about it, right?
Speaker 1: There have been all these sort of like, you know, there are always fads for kids, right?
Speaker 1: You know, like, "Oh, we're all into, you know, micro-machines.
Speaker 1: Our micro-machines are gone
Speaker 1: now.".
Speaker 2: Or Centurions.
Speaker 1: "He-mans are gone.
Speaker 1: Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles and things like that.
Speaker 1: Transformers are only for nerds.
Speaker 1: Regular kids don't like those anymore.
Speaker 1: so much,
Speaker 1: right?".
Speaker 1: But Barbie and Hot Wheels are sort of the always there since like the '50s or even earlier than that, right?
Speaker 2: I think Pokemon is going to be there.
Speaker 1: Wasn't Barbie's anniversary just like somewhat recently?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But Pokemon has sort of beat them all.
Speaker 1: It's Barbie, Hot Wheels, and Pokemon I think is the other one that's just going to last forever.
Speaker 2: I mean, I remember- Like infinity.
Speaker 1: Like your great, great grandchildren will still have Barbie, Hot Wheels, and Pokemon.
Speaker 1: They may be Sesame Street also, but everything else, well, you know, He-Man, Ninja Turtles, Transformers, you know, I guess Lego, but Lego is not really- Yeah.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much it.
Speaker 2: It's real easy to hold 10 Lego.
Speaker 1: But anyway.
Speaker 2: Alright, so we're going to get to read about red and yellow and- So, yes.
Speaker 1: The original Pokemon was a Game Boy game.
Speaker 1: However, there was a Pokemon manga.
Speaker 1: Well, actually, there were many Pokemon mangas, but there was one Pokemon manga in particular.
Speaker 1: It was called Pokemon, well, Pocket to Monster Special in Japan, but in the United States, it's Pokemon Adventures.
Speaker 1: Now, Pokemon Adventures was released in English a long time ago by Viz, and it was sort of like in these comic book sized books, but they had cardboard covers as opposed to sort of flimsy covers, and they were flat bound as opposed to staple bound.
Speaker 2: Well, Luke had them back at RIT.
Speaker 2: That's the only reason I was able to read them was that he owned like all of these things.
Speaker 1: There were a whole bunch of them, and it was a little bit expensive to get them.
Speaker 1: They really felt like kids coloring books more than like manga.
Speaker 1: But you could get them, and they're hard to get now, that particular format, but this manga was released in English.
Speaker 1: Viz, in like two or three months, is going to re-release this manga under the Viz kids line in sort of the normal format.
Speaker 1: This is going to be like $7 cover price for a volume.
Speaker 1: This is some serious business.
Speaker 1: So I'm going to pay like $5.
Speaker 2: Because, I mean, you know about Ash Ketchum and the Pokemon rap?
Speaker 2: Who?
Speaker 2: What are you talking about?
Speaker 2: And Team Rocket blast away again.
Speaker 2: That is like this bastard child of Pokemon.
Speaker 1: I want to read to you a quote.
Speaker 1: This is a quote from Satoshi Tajiri, who is the original creator of all Pokemon, right?
Speaker 1: And he says about this, this is what he has to say about this manga, quote, "This is the comic that most resembles the world I was trying to
Speaker 1: convey.".
Speaker 1: End quote.
Speaker 2: Now, it's actually a pretty good, I mean, it's a kid's manga, but it's good.
Speaker 1: Even if you don't like Pokemon, you don't care about Pokemon at all, you think it's kid's crap, you know, whatever.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: This manga, this is the serious business.
Speaker 1: This is the real deal.
Speaker 1: This is not, you know, about catching them all, all right?
Speaker 1: This is not about cutesy monsters and, you know, battles of powering up and shit.
Speaker 2: Granted, it's still not Shadow Star.
Speaker 1: No, it's not Shadow Star either.
Speaker 1: But, I mean, look, there is stuff that happens in this manga.
Speaker 1: I mean, there was a scene where someone's hand got chopped off by a dangerous Pokemon, you know?
Speaker 1: I think that was the most hardcore moment in the whole thing.
Speaker 1: But, yeah, ignore all those other Pokemon things, like Mystery Dungeon manga, fuck that shit.
Speaker 1: You know, Diamond and Pearl manga, fuck that shit, right?
Speaker 1: Pokemon Adventures, when this hits, you gotta pick that up.
Speaker 1: And it's mad, mad cheap, so you have no excuse.
Speaker 2: It's just, Ash is such a pale imitation of Red, and then they, I mean, I'm not gonna spoil this, but they pull a big change-up up when you're reading this, and stuff happens that you might not have expected.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know, it nominally is the same story as the original Pokemon, you know, game.
Speaker 1: You know, Pokemon Red, you know, the very, very original one.
Speaker 1: It's nominally that story, but it's also not that story.
Speaker 1: So don't think that you already know everything that's gonna go down, because you do not.
Speaker 2: But, moving right along, as you all know, we're gonna be attending Anime Boston for the first time this year.
Speaker 2: May 22nd through 24th, I think, yeah, that sounds about right.
Speaker 2: We're gonna be there, doing a bunch of panels, being guests, hanging out.
Speaker 2: We'll be around, I'll be hanging out in bars in Boston the whole weekend, so.
Speaker 2: If you wanna see us, come to Anime Boston, it's a good con, it'll be our first time there, but they just announced the musical guest of Anime Boston.
Speaker 2: And this is the kind of thing where, had we not been going to Anime Boston in a geek night's capacity, I might have been tempted to just go.
Speaker 2: The musical guest is going to be Kalafina and Yuki Kajira.
Speaker 2: If you don't know who that is, Noir, Dot Hack Sign, the music to those animes.
Speaker 1: Basically all the terrible animes with amazing music.
Speaker 2: Yeah, so if you wanna hear amazing music without having to deal with the terrible anime that they were associated with.
Speaker 1: Does it actually mean performance?
Speaker 1: It's not just an appearance?
Speaker 2: Actually, let me read this whole article, cause I got home kinda late.
Speaker 2: But yeah, the singing trio's gonna be there, and the composer.
Speaker 1: Uh huh.
Speaker 2: I'm pretty excited about this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that could be pretty hot right there.
Speaker 2: Especially since I didn't get to go to the concert at Otacon, because we were doing a panel during it.
Speaker 1: Well, we went to one of the concerts, but not the other one.
Speaker 2: Yeah, but we went to THE concert at Otacon.
Speaker 2: You know, Lark, way back, so I guess it's all good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we went to a bunch of those THE concerts.
Speaker 2: Yeah, but nothing's really topped Lark yet.
Speaker 1: No, we missed those Eurobeat girls.
Speaker 1: In '02.
Speaker 2: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Seven years ago.
Speaker 2: We've been going- SEVEN YEARS!
Speaker 2: Okay.
Speaker 2: But that aside, I just wanna point out, this is kind of a mini news, but it looks like... I don't know what's going on on Cartoon Network, but Naruto... Looks like they're dropping it, as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: Didn't they drop Toonami?
Speaker 2: It looks like things are really changing up, and it looks like anime is getting shorter and shorter of a shrift.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, Naruto, you can watch for free on the internets, legitimately, at all these places.
Speaker 1: Like, you know, the day after it's out in Japan.
Speaker 2: Yup, and subtitled, no less.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I don't know why Cartoon Network could even bother to continue to show it.
Speaker 1: I mean, really, they should only put Naruto on, unlike, you know, the kids' afternoon cartoon pro- Oh wait, everyone eliminated.
Speaker 1: the kids got home from school afternoon cartoon block.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and now instead they keep trying to put shows like- They don't even have Saturday morning or Sunday morning cartoons anymore.
Speaker 2: They keep trying to put shows like this on, like, Adult Swim, where anyone who's gonna be watching Adult Swim is just gonna go online anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think what really happened to Adult Swim is that you sort of had this competition between bringing awesome shows, you know, from around the world to, you know, to people, you know, regardless of who made them.
Speaker 1: With the simultaneous Cartoon Network's own productions sort of having to compete with that.
Speaker 1: And they had to sort of pick, are they gonna go with these animes, are they gonna go with, you know, the stuff they make?
Speaker 1: And they decided to go with the stuff they make, rather than, you know, like the robot chickens and that sort of stuff.
Speaker 2: For a lot of reasons, and I don't want to get into it, but it's interesting how this fight is, it's all just kind of falling apart.
Speaker 2: I think anime- Remember when Nickelodeon used to be awesome?
Speaker 1: Well, I think Nickelodeon had sort of the same problem MTV did, in which it just completely lost its identity, right?
Speaker 1: MTV used to be music videos.
Speaker 1: Now it's like game shows all day, isn't it?
Speaker 1: I think.
Speaker 1: Game shows and reality shows.
Speaker 1: That's what I hear, right?
Speaker 1: So, Nickelodeon was originally, like, you know, awesome, just like kids crazy shit all day.
Speaker 1: I mean, remember.
Speaker 1: Remember.
Speaker 1: Then they had the Nicktoons and they were rocking the house.
Speaker 2: You can't do that on television.
Speaker 1: Well, actually, Nickelodeon, I don't think, man, I think that was originally a Canadian show.
Speaker 2: No, but they got it, and they put it on, and that's the same thing as anime.
Speaker 1: No, but Nick Nickelodeon also made lots of good stuff, too, like Clarissa Explains It All, and Snick was alright, remember that?
Speaker 1: I remember that.
Speaker 1: And, you know, all the other Nicktoons, the Ren & Stimpies and all that stuff, and Doug and Rugrats, they made all those.
Speaker 2: Of course, we definitely have to clarify the old Nickelodeon Ren & Stimpy, because as we learned later- It's still good.
Speaker 2: It wasn't a great show, but it had its moments.
Speaker 1: It had a lot of moments.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, because you turn the page, and then you wash your hands, and then you turn the page, and then you wash your hands.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, but, you know, it's like these networks lost their identities, and Cartoon Network also seems to be losing its identity, right?
Speaker 1: It used to be about cartoons all day long, and now I heard that they were, like, showed this, like, a live-action Spider-Man movie instead of Toonami when Toonami was over.
Speaker 1: It's like, "Whoa,
Speaker 1: really?".
Speaker 1: And now they have, like, Boomerang.
Speaker 1: That's all these networks are doing.
Speaker 1: Like, MTV made MTV2, where they put the music videos, right?
Speaker 2: But then watch, MTV2 is gonna start having the reality shows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then Nickelodeon makes, like, another channel to put the cartoons on, and then, you know, Disney Channel makes another channel where they stick all the cartoons, and Cartoon Network makes Boomerang, where they put all the cartoons.
Speaker 1: It's like, "Yeah, we lost our identity on our main network.
Speaker 1: Let's make another network where we put the stuff that the original network was supposed to be," you know?
Speaker 1: And it's like, I really think that there's room now for someone to come out with an actual, a new TV network that actually has good kids programming, you know?
Speaker 1: And you sort of follow the same Nickelodeon formula, right?
Speaker 1: You need to have, like, two good shows, like, at, like, six in the morning before the kids go to school, right?
Speaker 1: You can watch them while you eat breakfast.
Speaker 1: Then you show shows for preschoolers, like, all day, right?
Speaker 1: And the kids who set to stay home from school watch it anyway.
Speaker 2: Yep, then you got the two-hour block, right, when the kids get home.
Speaker 1: No, you need the four-hour block when you get home before dinner, right?
Speaker 2: Well, demographic-wise, I mean, look, usually there's the staggered thing where elementary school kids get home first, then middle school, so you start with the show.
Speaker 2: Like, remember Cartoon Network, like, you'd start with Sailor Moon, and then the Dragon Ball.
Speaker 1: And then they went into Sailor Moon, and then they went into Voltron, and then, you know, and then it was, like, by four o'clock, you were in Batman.
Speaker 1: But then, like, from five to something, right, when people are eating dinner, you show Looney Tunes.
Speaker 1: That way, you know, it's, like, Looney Tunes stops to eat dinner.
Speaker 1: You come back, another one started.
Speaker 1: You're somewhere in there, right?
Speaker 2: And then, Nick at Night.
Speaker 2: Nick at Night was a brilliant idea.
Speaker 2: I don't know if they still do it.
Speaker 2: Do they still show it?
Speaker 1: It has its own network, I think, again.
Speaker 2: But that doesn't work.
Speaker 2: No shit.
Speaker 2: I don't know.
Speaker 2: There's something wrong.
Speaker 2: If you're watching Dragnet, and the sun is still up.
Speaker 1: I know, right?
Speaker 1: That is a show for 4 a.m But what I would do is I would probably put, like, you know, the old cartoons on all night, you know, or I would just put, like, the hardcore shit on all night.
Speaker 2: Or both.
Speaker 1: Like, Mazinger and shit.
Speaker 2: Late at night, yeah.
Speaker 1: Fist of the North Star, Bustin' Off Heads.
Speaker 2: Have the original Astro Boy, and then, like, Mazinger, and then, like, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it'd be like, going to Guy would be all night long.
Speaker 1: That would be my network.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should do that.
Speaker 1: Be like, what would be on your, you know, schedule your TV network.
Speaker 1: You can choose any show that has ever existed, you know, from all the shows in the history of television in any country in the world that have ever existed, you know, schedule, you know, your programming day.
Speaker 1: Let's make a game about it.
Speaker 2: I'll make a thread in the forum, and we'll pick a winner next Wednesday.
Speaker 2: You're not winning a prize.
Speaker 2: I've given up on that.
Speaker 1: Actually, what we have to do here, you have to invent, like, a whole TV network, give it a name, you know, the whole, you have to just do the whole thing.
Speaker 2: Yep, we'll put the details.
Speaker 1: Maybe you even have to do the whole week.
Speaker 1: Why not the whole, you know, or I guess weekday, Saturday, and Sunday.
Speaker 1: You need three schedules.
Speaker 2: Yep, we'll put the details in the forum.
Speaker 2: Check it out.
Speaker 2: So, things of the day.
Speaker 2: I'm trying to avoid doing an anime thing, because I feel like I gotta break from the routine and have stuff that's cross-interest on the things of the day, so there's always something for you.
Speaker 2: Otherwise... Well, I have three saved up, but the problem is two of them are good AMVs that people forgot about, and I feel like I gotta really save those for, like, bottom of the barrel.
Speaker 2: And the third one, I just want to save, so... A while ago, I think I talked about this, I didn't make it a thing of the day, but there's something about the lyrics to songs from the 80s and 90s.
Speaker 1: They're really bad?
Speaker 2: Yeah, like, really good songs, but if you actually listen to the lyrics, it's not even that they're bad or asinine.
Speaker 0: They're terrible!
Speaker 2: Like, they're painful!
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 2: But imagine if you took old songs like "White Wedding" or "Take On Me" and just changed the lyrics.
Speaker 2: Do the song exactly the same, but change the lyrics to just say, literally, what is going on in the associated music video to the song.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, if you did that, what if you did that, like, sledgehammer?
Speaker 1: You'd be like, "Bunch of shit movin' around!
Speaker 1: Bunch of shit movin'
Speaker 1: around!".
Speaker 1: "Oh, weird imagery!
Speaker 1: Weird imagery!
Speaker 1: Playing with the special effects on the video machine!
Speaker 1: Playing with the special
Speaker 1: effects!".
Speaker 2: Of all these, pretty much the best one, 'cause there's a guy doing a ton of this stuff, the best one is "White
Speaker 2: Wedding.".
Speaker 2: I found this so hilarious, it was painful.
Speaker 2: Because it's time for a cool glove, and that room is dangerous.
Speaker 1: Cool glove.
Speaker 2: Seriously, check this out.
Speaker 1: Did you know that there is some sort of Blue Mountain Dew now?
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: There's an ad for it on the webpage.
Speaker 1: that is my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Well, there's a Red Bull Cola that actually- It's like Mountain Dew Voltage, it's like a bright blue.
Speaker 2: That can't be good.
Speaker 1: It's kinda scary looking, anyway.
Speaker 2: Well, there's a Red Bull Cola.
Speaker 1: The thing of the day, which just happens to be on this page with the Mountain Dew ad that's not blocked, 'cause it's like the background of the site, it's one of those.
Speaker 2: Ah, I hate those.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so what this is, is, I don't know, do you remember?
Speaker 1: a while back, someone drew, like, the sort of the Watchmen Peanuts character mashup?
Speaker 2: Oh, I know what you're using.
Speaker 2: Yeah, that was pretty good.
Speaker 1: Oh, you saw this?
Speaker 2: I saw this.
Speaker 2: Somebody basically drew two pages of Sin City, but it's- Oh, I thought you were gonna do, someone animated the Watchmen as though it were a 90s cartoon.
Speaker 1: No, screw that.
Speaker 1: That was stupid, heck.
Speaker 1: I don't like that, heck.
Speaker 1: I liked it.
Speaker 1: No, I thought it was dumb.
Speaker 1: This, someone drew, was basically two pages of Sin City, but it's Schulz City.
Speaker 1: That yellow shirt, it's such and such.
Speaker 2: Not bad.
Speaker 2: But tonight, surprisingly, we're actually talking about something relatively new, as in we only have one volume of it, so it's kind of a preview, as opposed to the usual review.
Speaker 0: It's actually- It's new, and it's old.
Speaker 0: It's that dichotomy there.
Speaker 1: It's old, and it's super, it's old, because it was only released here recently, even though it came out in Japan a while ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's based on something- It's based on something even older.
Speaker 0: Old, old, incredibly old television show and manga.
Speaker 2: We've also got an Emily here, but it is Takashi, oops, sorry, I was reading the co-authored line.
Speaker 2: Anyway, it's Pluto, Urasawa's Pluto, which is based on two episodes, well, a story arc from Astro Boy.
Speaker 1: Right, I'm pretty sure it was a story arc in the original manga, and I'm pretty sure it was a story arc that was in the original 60s anime, and I definitely know that the story arc was re-.
Speaker 1: You know, it's basically every time they make a new iteration of Astro Boy, right, the 80s anime, and I don't know about the 2004 anime, but they retold this story, right?
Speaker 0: Wasn't there a blurb in the back of the manga about, like, written by the guy who's saying they were doing that series of episodes for the most recent Astro Boy television show when he was reading this manga?
Speaker 1: Maybe, I don't know, I didn't read it.
Speaker 2: Oh, Scott, there's a long interview in the back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's got a lot of stuff about the authors and, you know, notes by the translators and stuff, kind of giving some backstory.
Speaker 0: So, the interesting thing about this is they have both seen these episodes, but I haven't watched the Astro Boy episodes that it makes reference to, so we're kind of coming at it from different angles here.
Speaker 1: Well, I think that was sort of the point, is that, like, I saw those two episodes of Astro Boy, like, coincidentally, because we just happened to be watching the show, right?
Speaker 1: And it was, like, this two-part story, so I knew it was a big deal, and so we watched those, and then, coincidentally, Pluto just happened to show up, and I didn't even know.
Speaker 1: I knew Pluto was a retelling of some Astro Boy stuff, but I didn't realize it was that until I realized the robot's name was Pluto, because in the '80s, any dub of the '80s anime, they call him Bluton.
Speaker 0: Oh!
Speaker 2: Or Bruton, or something.
Speaker 1: Bruton, like he's a brute.
Speaker 1: But I'm like, "Huh, that must be
Speaker 1: Pluto.".
Speaker 1: And then, when the manga, like, happened to show up, like, a week later, I was like, "Oh,
Speaker 1: shit!".
Speaker 0: But I don't know why they call them Bruton, because in the manga, they're talking about, like, Pluto, god of death, and it makes so much more sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, the dub is very, very simplifying.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it was because the anime was much more simplified, or if the original... You know, I mean, this is odd, the Naoki Urasawa interpretation is obviously a lot more complicated and deep than the original.
Speaker 2: Well, the original...
Speaker 1: Tezuka, as great as he was, you know, Astro Boy was not... Well, it was just a substory, you know?
Speaker 2: If you put out that much manga, not everything's a winner.
Speaker 1: Well, no.
Speaker 1: I mean, I have some bad Tezuka, if you want.
Speaker 2: Yes, but, like, episodes of Astro Boy, or story arcs of Astro Boy, come and go.
Speaker 0: You cannot blame that fan-fiction, blackjack, everybody-shows-up, cross-universes episode on Tezuka.
Speaker 2: I can't blame that on Tezuka.
Speaker 2: Here's why.
Speaker 2: No, I can't blame that.
Speaker 2: He was alive.
Speaker 2: No, I blame it on him, because Princess Knight never really ended.
Speaker 2: So, that was the end.
Speaker 2: Someone had to do it.
Speaker 1: Oh, oh, that's, like, the worst ending ever, though.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: No, but actually, you know, I have read a lot of older Tezuka.
Speaker 1: Like, some of the stuff Dark Horse has put out, like, Lost World, or even Tezuka's Metropolis, right?
Speaker 1: Or Next World.
Speaker 1: Next World is pretty bad.
Speaker 1: It's not good.
Speaker 1: They could have chosen a lot better Tezukas to bring over than Next World, all right?
Speaker 1: And I guess it was an early work, and it has historical significance, but, you know, it's not... I mean, and Astro Boy, the original manga, like, some of it's good.
Speaker 1: Like, the one with, you know, the X-shaped aliens holding the lasers, you know, that one's good, but...
Speaker 2: Well, that's, like, the best episode of the '80s Astro Boy.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but, I mean, some of them, not so good.
Speaker 0: Well, you figure, especially prolific geniuses, they have really, really strong work, and some of their work, in comparison, is a little weaker.
Speaker 1: Well, I think with Tezuka, it's mostly the early work is no good, you know?
Speaker 1: It's like, he just happened to get published before he was God.
Speaker 1: It was like he was still demigod, but they started publishing.
Speaker 1: They didn't wait till it was hatched.
Speaker 0: Then you should look at it.
Speaker 0: See, you have this thing where, like, you just want to do stuff perfectly right away, and this is, like, a perfect example of why that theory never works, because even Tezuka had to start somewhere.
Speaker 0: Like, he was obviously very talented, even at the get-go, but you do see a maturation in any artist's work, and so you should look to him for guidance when you're all like, "I want to make videos perfect,".
Speaker 0: right, from the first day.
Speaker 0: So, anyway, I really enjoyed the manga, even without the background information there.
Speaker 2: Well, it definitely had a lot of -- I guess I had more impact, because Scott knew what it was, and he gave it to me.
Speaker 2: He walks in, and he's like, "Rim, read this," and I'm like, "Okay," and I add it to my pile of things I've got to read.
Speaker 2: He's like, "No, read
Speaker 2: it.".
Speaker 2: So I'm like, "All right, all right," and I flip through it, and page six, I see Mont Blanc, the word.
Speaker 2: I think, "Huh, Mont Blanc, yeah, that was that robot in that
Speaker 2: S-word.".
Speaker 0: Oh, that was sad.
Speaker 2: And then I read page seven, "All right, there's a murder
Speaker 2: mystery.".
Speaker 2: Page eight, "Oh, Mont Blanc.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's what that
Speaker 1: is.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I thought it was kind of interesting, because it's really -- the artist who draws it, the guy who did this adaptation, is the same guy who did Monster and Master Keaton and everything.
Speaker 1: Did he draw it?
Speaker 1: I mean, I know he drew Monster.
Speaker 0: It's obvious.
Speaker 0: Look at the style.
Speaker 1: The style's really, really -- Isn't there someone else's name on the cover?
Speaker 2: Takashi Nagasaki is the co-author, and there's also Makoto Tezuka supervised.
Speaker 0: Okay, so it's kind of a collaboration.
Speaker 0: I assume that he was the primary creative force behind this retelling.
Speaker 1: I'm also pretty sure he is the primary creative force.
Speaker 2: In the back, there's a little timeline.
Speaker 2: It's like, "1928, Osamu Tezuka, the genius who would eventually become known as the god of manga, is
Speaker 2: born.".
Speaker 2: "1951, Tezuka creates a narrative set in a futurist society about a boy robot whose machine body houses a
Speaker 2: soul.".
Speaker 1: You don't need to read the whole thing.
Speaker 2: You sound so angry.
Speaker 2: There's only three items in this timeline.
Speaker 2: Oh, okay.
Speaker 2: "Children throughout Japan go wild over the story.
Speaker 2: 2003, Naoki Urasawa challenges himself to create the ultimate tribute to the god of
Speaker 2: manga.".
Speaker 0: You did trailer voice there.
Speaker 0: It was kind of silly.
Speaker 1: I've only read one volume of it.
Speaker 1: How many volumes are there?
Speaker 1: Is it going to be three or four or something like that?
Speaker 0: We can check at the Kinokuniya.
Speaker 2: Considering the burn rate of characters, there can't be that many.
Speaker 1: I think it's seven volumes.
Speaker 1: It says right here.
Speaker 1: At least there's seven volumes, I guess, according to Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: That seems about right.
Speaker 0: It's so sad.
Speaker 0: The interesting thing is there's a lot of secondary references.
Speaker 0: There was the one where he makes the... What was the robot who played piano's name?
Speaker 1: The one with all the arms.
Speaker 0: The guy who composed the music.
Speaker 2: North number two.
Speaker 0: He composed for the movie The Moon is a Harsh Mistress.
Speaker 0: Isn't that a Heinlein story?
Speaker 0: I was like, dude.
Speaker 0: There was a lot of stuff like that.
Speaker 0: The funny thing is, I know you're going to laugh at me for this, but I couldn't help seeing Robby's wife as anything other than a really dark depiction of the maid from the Jetsons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I did actually.
Speaker 0: I remember.
Speaker 1: She definitely reminded me of Rosie the Robot.
Speaker 0: There was a boy, and they adopted a dog before he was born, and one day the dog died, and the boy cried, and I was like, oh my god, it's the Jetsons.
Speaker 1: And the dog was Rastro?
Speaker 0: I couldn't stop thinking about that.
Speaker 0: I would be like, that would be so horrible.
Speaker 2: Actually, what got me the most was that because of that robot's mechanical design, she always has this smile on her face, but because of the context, it was really jarring.
Speaker 2: It really stood out, and it made that scene a thousand times sadder.
Speaker 0: When you see her standing, it's like her face betrays no emotion, but her posture, and that scene where they're both standing, the detective comes to tell her her husband's passed away.
Speaker 0: Her husband's also a robot, and he was a patrolman with the police force, and they're standing silently in the kitchen, and she's making him a pot of tea, and it's the way it's framed, and also the way they're standing.
Speaker 0: You can just see the sadness, like no expression, no anything on her face, but it's very sad, very touching scene.
Speaker 2: Sadly, having watched the Astro Boy episodes, this is really good, but at the same time, there's a little bit of... I keep thinking back and either laughing or having extra insights into it, because I guess most people in Japan who would read this already know the story of Pluto, because they've seen Astro Boy.
Speaker 2: I guess Mickey Mouse didn't have some dark story arc, so we don't have anything to compare it to.
Speaker 2: But we watched the 80s Astro Boy, and it's pretty much very simple.
Speaker 2: It's just a two-parter where there's a robot named Bruton or Pluto, and he's a jerk, and he's going to go around and kill all the strongest robots in the world because he's a jerk.
Speaker 1: Well, it's mostly because his creator wants to prove that Pluto is the strongest robot in the world.
Speaker 1: In order to do that, he has to go and destroy all the other strongest robots in the world thereby.
Speaker 2: I mean, the name of this two-part story is called "The Greatest Robot on
Speaker 2: Earth."
Speaker 2: And it starts with this long, open-y bit where they're basically showing you all the best robots in the world, and it's like, "Number one, Montblanc, he's awesome and helps kids.
Speaker 2: Number two, Astro
Speaker 2: Boy!".
Speaker 2: And it just goes through, and it's kind of like the Dune board game where they give you every one, and it's like, there's no way anyone could beat that robot.
Speaker 2: It's like the most powerful robot in the world.
Speaker 1: Especially the wrestling robot.
Speaker 2: Ah, the wrestling robot.
Speaker 1: The wrestling robot is just so big and so powerful.
Speaker 1: It's like, well, there's no trouble with that one.
Speaker 2: So, Pluto or Bluton or Bruton goes around murdering all of them, and the thing is, they gave him the most disdainful voice I have ever heard.
Speaker 1: At least in the '80s dub.
Speaker 1: He's just like, he's almost like...
Speaker 2: "I don't want to fight you, Astro, but I have to because I'm going to be the strongest robot in the world, and I was built this way, and what's it to
Speaker 2: you?".
Speaker 0: So he kind of scoffs at everybody?
Speaker 0: That's it?
Speaker 1: He's like, "Oh, oh, oh,
Speaker 1: whatever.".
Speaker 1: It's weird because he's not, he doesn't come across, you know, it's Astro Boy, right?
Speaker 1: So the guy isn't blatantly evil, like, "I'm going to kill you all," right?
Speaker 1: He's just sort of like, you know, "This is what I have to do.
Speaker 1: He's a tragic
Speaker 1: villain.".
Speaker 1: You sort of feel for him, even though he's doing all these terrible things, basically killing everybody.
Speaker 2: There's actually this really funny scene where he kidnaps Uran, and they're like together, and he's holding on to her to like, "Astro, if you want her to be okay, you'll have to fight
Speaker 2: me.".
Speaker 2: And Astro's like, "I don't want to fight
Speaker 2: you.".
Speaker 2: He's like, "Well, you're going to have
Speaker 2: to.".
Speaker 2: And Uran looks him in the eye, and he looks at her, and they're both like,
Speaker 2: "Eh.".
Speaker 0: I like Uran.
Speaker 0: She's pretty tough.
Speaker 0: She's precocious.
Speaker 0: She gets really cranky.
Speaker 0: It's like, Astro Boy is always really, you know, sometimes he'll get angry, and sometimes he'll get sad, but for the most part, he's a very well-behaved, like, he's very good.
Speaker 0: Whereas Uran is very naughty, a lot.
Speaker 0: She'll misbehave.
Speaker 1: Uran isn't in the manga yet.
Speaker 1: I don't know if she will be.
Speaker 0: Oh, I assume so, right?
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: She was in those two episodes.
Speaker 2: And her and Bruton formed this kind of slightly-like, slightly-dislike relationship.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was sort of weird in that way.
Speaker 0: But the thing with the manga, like I said, I haven't had a chance to see, like, how the anime portrays Mont Blanc, and, like, all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: It barely portrays him at all.
Speaker 0: I know, it's like, it probably shows a picture, it's like, "He's really strong and tough, and he works in the mountains of
Speaker 0: Switzerland.".
Speaker 0: That's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: You know?
Speaker 0: But here, it's like, when he dies, it's like a huge thing.
Speaker 0: Imagine if your national hero, like, somebody who had saved people from avalanches and helped children and composed poems, and just really part of your national identity, not just as an individual, but, like, as a greater-than-life, like, Paul Bunyan hero kind of person, I guess.
Speaker 2: And they really milk it.
Speaker 1: They really, really make it into an emotional scene.
Speaker 2: Not only did he do all these things, but he also stopped the terrorists.
Speaker 1: The manga is pretty much all about milking it, right?
Speaker 1: He basically, you know, Tezuka's original story, you know, is a whole story in and of itself, and it's all right, but if you treat that as, like, a framework, right, and you just fill in all the blanks, you know, just, like, flesh everything out as much as it can be fleshed out, you know?
Speaker 1: If there was a character who was in there for, like, a minute, you know, tell their whole story like they're a whole big deal, and then, you know, like, if there's just, like, a fight, you know, just, like, stretch that out, you know, so much.
Speaker 1: And that's, I think, what Pluto does, is he takes, you know, this original, you know, Tezuka story of Astro Boy, and he stretches it all out, and he moves the perspective from Astro Boy over to the detective, and you just, you get, like, all these details filled in, and he just pretty much, it seems so far, at least in Volume 1, the story goes in the exact same direction, I don't know if he's gonna, you know, he could change it up, I haven't read the later volumes, he might do something different with the ending or whatever, but...
Speaker 2: Yeah, but there's just so much more here, I mean, the whole bit with Brau 1589...
Speaker 0: I was gonna ask, do they have that Robo-Hannibal Lecter in the... If that's what he is, he's scaring himself!
Speaker 0: The Robo-Hannibal Lecter!
Speaker 0: Shall we exchange memory chips?
Speaker 0: I killed a human once, would you like to know what's going through my mind?
Speaker 1: The Robo-Hannibal Lecter is not in the 80s anime, at least, but the robot with all the arms definitely is in the 80s anime.
Speaker 0: The one who plays piano?
Speaker 2: Yeah, you don't get anything about the piano, you pretty much just find out he gets killed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you find out he's, like, the servant of a rich old guy, and then he goes to fight with his crazy arms and such, and that's it.
Speaker 1: That's all you get.
Speaker 0: But it takes all these robots who are basically, like, cameos and just there for cannon fodder for Bruton or whatever they call them.
Speaker 1: It's called Pluto.
Speaker 0: We'll call him Pluto.
Speaker 0: How about Bluto?
Speaker 0: And they basically make them...
Speaker 1: I am what I am.
Speaker 0: Grounded characters with, like, a story of their own.
Speaker 0: Each robot has their own story and has their own sad things and happy things.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, really, if you think about it, you could do this sort of thing with, like, a lot of different... You know, how many anime out there are just literally, like, you know, "Haha, you are, you know, I am the robot that is
Speaker 1: red.".
Speaker 2: I am the fifth strongest robot on Robot Island.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I've always wanted to do, like, a show where it's like a giant robot show, right?
Speaker 0: Where there's huge mega robots fighting each other, but it's not told from the perspective of the pilot.
Speaker 0: It's told from the perspective of a civilian during the war.
Speaker 0: And, like, you know, 'cause there's, like, you see these robots fighting with each other and they get thrown into an apartment building.
Speaker 0: I'm like, "There are people in that apartment building, sitting on somebody's grandma
Speaker 0: there.".
Speaker 1: You know, this is terrible.
Speaker 1: Well, Macross did that a lot, actually.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, there are some... And, actually, Gundam does it a little bit, but the main characters...
Speaker 1: Well, it depends on the Gundam.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was gonna mention that one, really.
Speaker 1: That was, like, gave it the most human parts.
Speaker 2: God, that's one of my favorite Gundams.
Speaker 1: That's a really good one.
Speaker 1: But, like, a G-Gundam, right?
Speaker 0: Well, G-Gundam is a... There's no human story in G-Gundam.
Speaker 1: But imagine, like, if you took G-Gundam...
Speaker 0: It's not about the horror of war.
Speaker 1: Well, imagine, though, you could do the same thing Pluto does to this Astro Boy story and do it to G-Gundam, right?
Speaker 1: You could, like, tell, like, the horrible story of, like, you know, the pilot of the Windmill Gundam and, like, this whole... You could make up something, you know, and fill in all those blanks.
Speaker 0: He's from the Netherlands.
Speaker 1: And, you know, they could have you really care about that Windmill Gundam pilot, you know?
Speaker 0: Well, you know, Wicked and stuff like that, that's essentially the same idea.
Speaker 0: It's, like, take an antagonist or take a side character and make the story about them instead.
Speaker 0: Just completely reverse the perspective on it.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, you know, really, if any shallow story, right?
Speaker 1: It's just the deep story.
Speaker 1: He has a lot more flesh in between.
Speaker 2: Well, you can do the "just the facts" treatment.
Speaker 2: I mean, look at Pluto.
Speaker 2: He takes just the facts, lays them out in a line, and then writes a whole story that just hits all the facts and doesn't mess with them.
Speaker 0: Man, I like the big reveal in the beginning.
Speaker 0: 'Cause you don't know in the beginning about the Inspector.
Speaker 0: And then there's a reveal, and you're like...
Speaker 1: Oh, the fact that he's a robot?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually, that was even more powerful having seen the anime.
Speaker 1: 'Cause it's like, I'm just reading, and I think this guy's just a detective.
Speaker 1: And then as soon as you find out that he's a robot and he's made of a special alloy, having seen the anime, I'm like, "Oh, shit!
Speaker 1: Oh,
Speaker 1: shit!".
Speaker 0: It's that guy?
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's not just some detective.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But the way they reveal he's a robot actually surprised me, 'cause I wasn't expecting it to go down like that.
Speaker 0: I was like, "What?
Speaker 0: What?".
Speaker 0: But it's kinda neat.
Speaker 0: What was the other thing I wanted to talk about?
Speaker 0: Oh, talk about how they portray Astro Boy for like two seconds.
Speaker 1: Well, he's only on the last page.
Speaker 2: Well, this is definitely the Urasawa touch, because you build up and build up, and everyone reading this would know this is an Astro Boy story.
Speaker 2: And of course, that means that you know things about the main character and how this is gonna go already.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, I was wondering if Astro Boy was even going to appear.
Speaker 1: Like, would he even be in the manga, actually?
Speaker 1: Or would it be just one of those things where, like, you know, he's off in the distance?
Speaker 1: 'Cause, you know, Pluto was in it, but he was always off in the distance.
Speaker 1: You never saw him.
Speaker 1: You only, you know, he was like a force of nature as opposed to a character.
Speaker 2: You know anyone in Japan, anyone who knows the story of reading this is thinking, "Where's Astro Boy?
Speaker 2: Where's Astro Boy?
Speaker 2: Where's Astro
Speaker 2: Boy?".
Speaker 2: And the fact that he reveals Astro Boy like, "Oh, Astro Boy at the
Speaker 2: end.".
Speaker 1: Well, it's just, you know, the volume one.
Speaker 1: I think they could have chosen any number of chapters.
Speaker 2: Yes, but that unit still ends.
Speaker 2: I'm pretty sure that unit ends with, "Astro Boy, oh my
Speaker 2: god.".
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, but I mean, imagine if you were reading this serialized and, you know, big shounen, whatever it was, right?
Speaker 2: Yep, so one of those big shounen things.
Speaker 1: You get it one week, you read it.
Speaker 1: You get another week, you read it.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's a monthly, I don't know.
Speaker 1: And then suddenly, one of the months on the final page, it's like, "Astro
Speaker 1: Boy."
Speaker 1: That would be pretty sweet.
Speaker 1: It's like, "Aren't you,
Speaker 1: Adam?".
Speaker 1: Yeah, the end.
Speaker 2: One thing I've noticed, though, I've been reading, I'm reading two Urasauas at the same time.
Speaker 0: Which other one?
Speaker 2: Well, I'm actually reading Monster.
Speaker 0: Is it better than the anime?
Speaker 0: Because I know you like the anime, but you were a little bit, like, I don't know.
Speaker 0: You kind of soured on it after a while.
Speaker 2: I felt like the anime had some pacing issues, and the manga does not seem to have them.
Speaker 2: But it's weird, but he draws women's eyes the same way, and all of his women look vaguely evil.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the way they have, they sort of...
Speaker 2: They're either evil or tired.
Speaker 2: There's no middle ground.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're right.
Speaker 1: I see exactly what you're saying.
Speaker 1: It seems like all the old ladies are always tired, and all the sort of, you know, younger ladies are always, like, evil.
Speaker 1: Because their eyes are sort of, like, pointed.
Speaker 1: Slanted a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like they got points on one side, but they're sort of round on the other side.
Speaker 1: They're always at an angle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they have, like, these triangle mouths.
Speaker 1: They're like, "Oh, oh, oh,
Speaker 1: oh.".
Speaker 0: That's weird, because I totally didn't see that.
Speaker 0: I'll have to look at it again.
Speaker 2: Yeah, well, look at this.
Speaker 1: I'll show it to you after the show.
Speaker 0: And the men have really big noses.
Speaker 0: Like, I was describing this to Alex as we were walking home from work.
Speaker 0: And I was like, "Yeah, Scott lent me this really cool
Speaker 0: comic.".
Speaker 0: And I was describing the idea to him, and he said, "Okay, who's the artist
Speaker 0: again?".
Speaker 0: And I said, "Oh, you know, the guy who did Master Keaton.
Speaker 0: Really big
Speaker 0: noses.".
Speaker 0: He was like, "I know exactly who you're talking
Speaker 0: about.".
Speaker 2: Oh, Master Keaton.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But it's all over the world.
Speaker 1: It's weird, because his style, like, isn't a very, sort of, stereotypical anime style.
Speaker 0: No, I like it a lot.
Speaker 1: But it's much more closer to, like, the sanctuary kind of style.
Speaker 1: Well, he does faces.
Speaker 2: There'll be these iconic shots throughout of really good faces.
Speaker 2: And every character has a very distinct face.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: It's also nice to see a manga.
Speaker 0: Like, I've got to critique, not every shoujo manga, but a lot of shoujo manga, just have generic old man and generic old lady.
Speaker 0: And also generic teenagers.
Speaker 0: But, like, since they're focused on the teenagers, at least there's a little more variation.
Speaker 0: The work of this artist is really nice because he draws caricatures.
Speaker 0: And it's kind of something that is a mark of a good artist when he's got, you know, you can recognize the different people by their faces.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he always, you know, that's the thing.
Speaker 1: He has lots of different hairstyles, lots of different body types.
Speaker 0: But like the nose and the facial features and the eyes and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like all, you know, you always recognize someone when they reappear.
Speaker 1: Because in Monster, there's a lot of characters that come and go and people are dying and entering the story, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like you'll see someone and you'll see them again like a couple chapters later on, like, a couple pages, but you'll know who they are.
Speaker 1: You've seen them before, you know?
Speaker 1: And that actually, that helps out the storytelling a lot because, you know, if it was more poorly drawn and it was harder to tell the characters apart, right?
Speaker 1: There are scenes in Monster, right, where it's like they'll introduce a character and they'll introduce them as a bad guy, right?
Speaker 1: And then later, like that bad guy would be pretending to be a good guy somewhere, you know?
Speaker 1: And like all he'll do is have a panel of like that person opening a door.
Speaker 1: It's like you'll see their face.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, shit, it's that guy.
Speaker 1: You know?
Speaker 1: And that wouldn't work if you couldn't tell it was that guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know, so it helps out a lot to be able to draw that.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 1: You know, you couldn't, XKCD couldn't tell that story.
Speaker 1: XKCD would need, you know, a narration or a bubble saying, "I am that guy," or something, you know, Stan Lee-like.
Speaker 0: Remember that it was a pretty good comic, but it suffered from that problem, was that spy comic?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: I had such trouble telling the different people apart.
Speaker 0: And it's like, you know, it really was important to the narrative, like who's doing what.
Speaker 0: But then if you, the art would make you very confused on that point.
Speaker 0: So, um, well.
Speaker 1: Do you think you want to like read all the manga and then like see what the original story was?
Speaker 1: Or do you want to like see the original story?
Speaker 2: The thing is, because we're talking about it, like the way we talk about it, I think if you're smart, it's pretty obvious how this is going to end.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: Pretty much straight up.
Speaker 1: I was just, you know, I was just really interested in what their, you know, because, you know, my enjoyment of it was like incredibly, you know, usually when you see something and then you see an adaptation of it, obviously your experience of the adaptation is colored by what you experienced with, you know, the original or whatever order you happen to consume them in.
Speaker 1: You know, that's why people are asking like, "Oh, I've never read Watchmen.
Speaker 1: Should I watch the movie
Speaker 1: first?".
Speaker 1: Or, you know, "I've never read Akira.
Speaker 1: Should I watch it
Speaker 1: first?".
Speaker 0: It's different in this case because it's not a straight up adaptation.
Speaker 0: It's like Wicked or like those books where he is not telling the direct story.
Speaker 0: He's making a new story with references to the old story.
Speaker 2: And in this case especially because it's something that, I mean, Astro Boy was so iconic and so loved and so known that I feel like in the end, you should probably watch the 80s Astro Boy take or just enough to know what the story already is before you read it.
Speaker 2: because I feel like the majority of people who have read this, up until the American release at least, would have already known how it was going to end and already knew the story, remembered it from their childhood, and now are reading it going, "Oh, I remember Mont
Speaker 2: Blanc.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, I agree with you on that point.
Speaker 0: I think I'll probably watch the episodes before I read it anymore.
Speaker 2: It's on Netflix on demand.
Speaker 0: Still, I didn't watch and I still thought it was a damn good comic.
Speaker 0: Very, very good.
Speaker 1: I mean, while it's not a straight up adaptation, though, the knowledge of what happened in the original story heavily colored my enjoyment of it.
Speaker 1: So I was unsure if I would have-- because a lot of the thrills came, like the moment where I knew the detective was a robot and remembered him from the anime was huge.
Speaker 1: And it's like if I hadn't remembered him from the anime, would it have been as huge?
Speaker 1: Yeah, because there were the two revelations.
Speaker 2: There was the, "Oh, it's that guy.
Speaker 2: Oh.".
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it was tough.
Speaker 2: I think pretty much we can safely say this is one of those-- if you're a manga fan or an anime fan, just buy it.
Speaker 2: Don't even worry about it.
Speaker 2: You'll like it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got to buy this stuff.
Speaker 1: I mean, come on.
Speaker 1: If there's going to be a manga you're going to buy, it's going to be this, and I guess 20th Century Boys just started coming out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have yet to read that.
Speaker 0: Scott lent it to me, but I haven't gotten around to it.
Speaker 0: Scott's talking it up.
Speaker 0: Still beating Chrono Trigger.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, Urasawa, right?
Speaker 1: He did this.
Speaker 0: So 20th Century Boys is as good or better, so what are you going to-- I remember like six years ago going into Kinokunya and seeing that there, and I was like I had no idea what it was about.
Speaker 0: I was like, "Is it historical?
Speaker 0: Is it science fiction?
Speaker 0: Is it
Speaker 0: this?".
Speaker 0: You know, and it intrigued me.
Speaker 1: I didn't really know who it was either until I read it.
Speaker 0: I wanted to buy it really badly, and so now almost a decade after-- Plus, the horns.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you don't know.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: The horns have not appeared in Pluto at all.
Speaker 2: Well, they're referenced constantly.
Speaker 1: They're on the cover.
Speaker 2: He sticks horns in that guy's head.
Speaker 1: He leaves horns on Mont Blanc's head, but-- But the horns are big in the anime, real big.
Speaker 0: Do you think he's going to be like crazier because the way he killed them was kind of crazy?
Speaker 0: It was more like a serial killer than like, "Oh, well, it's my duty.
Speaker 0: Gotta go beat this
Speaker 0: guy.".
Speaker 2: Of course, I wonder more importantly if the volcano is going to erupt.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I don't know.
Speaker 1: The thing is I don't know if it will go that far.
Speaker 1: Will the manga end before that point, or will it keep going?
Speaker 2: Yeah, this manga could end before Pluto gets beaten.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because I mean, this is not a spoiler.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's an Astro Boy story, right?
Speaker 1: In the original Astro Boy story, the finale, of course, is Astro Boy fighting Pluto to the end, right?
Speaker 1: So I wonder if the manga will go all that way and show you this Astro Boy fight, or if it's going to end sometime before or after that even.
Speaker 1: How far is he going to take it?
Speaker 1: Is he going to do a prologue?
Speaker 1: Is he going to cut it short?
Speaker 1: It's up in the air, and I'm going to be interested.
Speaker 1: Seven volumes, he's got to go somewhere because he's already through two of the seven strongest robots in the world in volume one.
Speaker 2: I'll definitely be reading all of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, me too.
Speaker 2: This has been Geek Nights with Rem and Scott.
Speaker 2: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 2: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 2: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 2: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Speaker 2: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says "Send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Speaker 2: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 2: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share-alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.