Speaker 0: It's Thursday January 15th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: It's a Thursday.
Speaker 0: We talk about faking one's death.
Speaker 1: Let's do this Now.
Speaker 0: longtime listeners might have expected me to or Scott to open with the classic woman Because it's a little cold up here in beacon.
Speaker 1: It is like the coldest day.
Speaker 1: I think it might have been colder like today and yesterday than like any Rochester day I can remember.
Speaker 0: no no no no no no you know.
Speaker 1: granted My memory is not you know like in Rochester all the cold days sort of blur together into one.
Speaker 0: When we lived in Rochester we were becoming Lichened unto the gods in terms of the ability we had like I was thinking more lichened unto the abominable snowmen.
Speaker 0: We had like plus 15 cold resistance.
Speaker 0: you needed at least a fifth level spell of cold to get us.
Speaker 1: I mean there was that wizard on the quarter mile.
Speaker 1: He cast Kona cold at everyone, but no one noticed.
Speaker 1: I Was the only one who saw him there.
Speaker 1: like does anyone notice this guy, but people are like hey It doesn't hurt anybody in fact if you miss the saving throw.
Speaker 0: It's kind of balmy.
Speaker 0: But now I think today warrants the bringing back of a Terminology that I haven't really used since I was at RIT because it only ever really applied at RIT and once we left Rochester Until today I had not encountered Temperatures worthy of it, but you see at RIT like every student when we got there It's fucking cold.
Speaker 0: It was it was real cold.
Speaker 1: We had not yet learned about the coldness of space And how woman it is.
Speaker 0: I mean I'd grown up in Michigan.
Speaker 0: I was used to cold, but what I wasn't used to is walking long distances in said cold.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm Connecticut is not a warm place in the winter either.
Speaker 1: But it was not like part of it that Rochester.
Speaker 0: when you're a freshman all right you get to class.
Speaker 0: Even if you take like the scary frat tunnels and every tunnel you can get to get as close to the academic side as possible.
Speaker 0: even if you use buses You've still got to walk a long way in the cold.
Speaker 0: even if you drive You have like I had to park further from my classes when I drove to campus.
Speaker 0: Then like I had to drive to get to work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if I drew I would drive sometimes the other side of campus.
Speaker 1: But because I didn't have a fancy permit I had to park in this faraway lot and in that faraway lot
Speaker 0: I
Speaker 1: had to walk to the building and that walk to the building Was just as far almost as far as the walk like across campus You know using tunnels.
Speaker 0: it was.
Speaker 0: it was like two minutes less far, which is the only reason we drove all the time.
Speaker 0: yeah, right, but I I remember very specifically that when I would walk outside and when any of us would walk outside in these cold winter mornings Only one syllable could be uttered and that syllable was fuck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because you wouldn't expect it.
Speaker 0: you walk outside and You start to go and suddenly you realize how cold it is that warmth that you built up from being inside and the coat is Gone and all you can do is stop and say fuck
Speaker 1: even if you got the fancy coat where you tie it down low to keep the wind air from getting in and you got the fancy gloves that seal around with the wrist velcro like I have and The whole rubber bands around the legs.
Speaker 1: even the hot air just as soon as you walk out through it escapes.
Speaker 1: I don't know where it escapes.
Speaker 1: It just gets right out.
Speaker 0: now We used to say and by we I mean everyone at RIT when it was cold out you'd walk out you go It's fucking cold.
Speaker 0: Fuck this fuck.
Speaker 0: we would say fuck a lot But it doesn't.
Speaker 0: it got to the point to where we had our own language where the word fuck Meant very specifically cold.
Speaker 0: if it was cold out you didn't say woman it is cold out there.
Speaker 0: That's who we didn't.
Speaker 1: we didn't learn that yet.
Speaker 0: No, we didn't learn woman until I got to IVM.
Speaker 0: But you would say good friend who was a sophomore at RIT.
Speaker 0: It is fuck outside today.
Speaker 1: Why not only is it fuck outside today?
Speaker 0: It is also fucking now fucking.
Speaker 0: it was equivalent to snowing.
Speaker 1: Yes, you like the Eskimos we develop new words for snow because the Rochester snow was never that nice like snowball snow.
Speaker 0: It was always that like it would come down and freeze on things to where you had to spend about 10 minutes chipping your car Out there.
Speaker 1: also those two ice storms.
Speaker 0: Oh my god I was driving back to RIT from IVM for an anime music night When that second ice storm came.
Speaker 1: I mean the first time there's an ice storm.
Speaker 1: I'd never seen an ice storm like that.
Speaker 0: I did a 180 on the freeway in that ice at like 60 miles an hour.
Speaker 0: I mean you're going down you're walking right and then 180 was followed by another 180 so I didn't die.
Speaker 1: there there are trees right and The trees have no leaves because winter obviously.
Speaker 1: but every single branch down to the tiniest tiniest branch on every tree is Covered in ice.
Speaker 1: it's like it's like someone made an ice sculpture of a tree and then put a tree in it And it matched that's.
Speaker 1: it was like there would be literally like you would have a branch That was like the tiniest branch like we're talking like millimeter diameter branch With that with like a two centimeter thick cylinder of ice just perfectly around it like a candle With a wick in it.
Speaker 1: You know where the ice is the wax and the wick is the tree.
Speaker 1: Of course remember and that's every single branch and every single tree.
Speaker 0: remember I think it was two katsu kansa go driving down to DC Over that Delaware bridge when there was like an inch and a half of ice covering every piece of that bridge.
Speaker 1: Oh, that was there.
Speaker 0: It was like falling down in sheets into the two side lanes.
Speaker 0: We had to like hide in the middle lane.
Speaker 1: That's pretty scary shit.
Speaker 0: That was awesome Yeah, but I think where these words came from specifically might I don't think it was just the fact that the only word the only syllable you could utter when stepping out into this cold was Fuck and the fuck wasn't so much.
Speaker 0: It wasn't just the surprise It was also the fact that you were resigned to the fact that you had to walk through it.
Speaker 0: You couldn't give up.
Speaker 0: You couldn't say fuck.
Speaker 0: It's cold.
Speaker 0: Never mind.
Speaker 0: It was fuck.
Speaker 0: I got to keep walking.
Speaker 0: my journey has just begun and it is nowhere near completion.
Speaker 1: So needless to say It's really cold here in New York, yeah, we're talking.
Speaker 1: I'd like to move you know to a tropical island.
Speaker 1: Don't be nice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but all the jobs are here and all the like.
Speaker 0: anime screening.
Speaker 1: Well, there actually is a job that is not here on a tropical island.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: I applied for that along with everyone else in the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's cold.
Speaker 0: just for perspective for anyone out there.
Speaker 0: When we say cold in the fuck or woman perspective We mean below zero Fahrenheit saltwater freezing people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I took a photo and like my car has a thermometer that tells you the temperature outside the car.
Speaker 1: I took a little picture of it this morning.
Speaker 1: It's a negative 11 C. That's cold.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but see who uses C. We're in America.
Speaker 1: I See, you know, in fact, it's like I use C to the point where I have.
Speaker 1: I have actually a little difficult time like it's weird as the temperatures get higher Right, like we're talking like, you know, 60, you know 50 60 70.
Speaker 1: It's like I understand Fahrenheit more, but when you get colder near the zeros like the freezing area I like I understand see more, you know,
Speaker 0: I think part of it is When you're going up hot a hundred degrees as is the point at which it moves from it's hot to it's unbearable
Speaker 1: Hundred degrees.
Speaker 1: C is you're boiling like a lobster, but it's not good.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about Fahrenheit.
Speaker 0: The magic number is a hundred but in Celsius the magic number where it starts getting kind of cold is zero Even though I think it depends on where you grow up because you know growing up in Michigan the number we worried about was zero Fahrenheit.
Speaker 0: because when saltwater freezes is when frostbite goes from That distant concern.
Speaker 0: if you go off hiking - I hope I don't get frostbite on my way to school today Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: because saltwater freezes at that temperature and saltwater is yeah The ferry to a Newberg like what isn't running because there's so much ice in the Hudson River now.
Speaker 1: Usually the river doesn't get ice because the water is moving so it doesn't like to freeze But it's so cold that the ferry can't even bust the ice up.
Speaker 1: you
Speaker 0: know what though because this happened a couple times last year and the year before with that ferry but that I Beacon must be coming up in the world because they actually were announcing in Grand Central over the loudspeakers continuously before like whenever there was a train going up north at all saying the Beacon Newberg ferry is currently down due to ice conditions.
Speaker 0: Please go to the bus go to whatever and use the bus.
Speaker 1: Well, it's you just take the train as usual But instead of getting on the ferry you take a bus and they drive over the bridge.
Speaker 1: The bridge is just fine.
Speaker 0: Hey, it's better than what I used to live in poquoi.
Speaker 0: They were doing all that track work back in the day.
Speaker 0: So I would take the train to Southeast get off get on a school bus But then stop and all the different stations and basically go up the rest of the route.
Speaker 1: That's the worst thing I ever heard.
Speaker 0: the thing is it was always me and a bunch of like really hoity-toity Like older upper middle-class liberals because that's who lives in that area in a school But I mean the last time I say it would be me, right?
Speaker 0: I was off like visiting Emily or seeing like a movie or a show in the city and all these like very well-dressed Older couples who are in the city for a day of shopping.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I was on a school bus recently, you know, I went to earlier in the year.
Speaker 1: I was I went to a giant six the Giants 49ers game, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, we took one of these before.
Speaker 0: when you mean Emily went to that baseball game - yeah Yeah, but I mean you you know the.
Speaker 1: all the stadiums in the New York area are like they're building new ones.
Speaker 1: There's like a new new stadium in the Meadowlands new Met Stadium new Yankee Stadium, right?
Speaker 0: Yankee Stadium has its own train station.
Speaker 1: Yeah so they build these stadiums in the parking lots of the old stadiums and then they take the old stadiums down and make a new Parking lot.
Speaker 1: that's how this works, right?
Speaker 1: But you know, they need to play in the old stadium while the new ones being built result less parking during that time.
Speaker 1: So, you know all the sporting events have gone to in the past year or two, right?
Speaker 1: Unless you're the lucky guy who has a parking permit You got a park way far away and take a little shuttly bus, right which sucks Well and to use the vernacular.
Speaker 0: Well, it's rare that I'm in a school bus but I'm sure you've had the similar experience where you get into a school bus and suddenly all your brain can think is Shit is small Exactly.
Speaker 1: I mean like you look at the outside of a school bus.
Speaker 1: Shit is big right.
Speaker 1: and You remember when you were a kid on the school bus.
Speaker 1: there was you know, pretty roomy.
Speaker 1: I got in a school bus like all these Giants fans and like Like what you was a three-seater when I was a kid is like a one-seater For like me a normal-sized person and legroom.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess they assume people don't have legs.
Speaker 1: It's a bus for for.
Speaker 1: you know paraplegics.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: but And then I accidentally sat on the hump.
Speaker 1: I sat on the hump.
Speaker 1: that was a bad move.
Speaker 0: Why did you sit on?
Speaker 0: I didn't realize?
Speaker 1: Cuz I I was still stunned at how close and small the seats were.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I remember as a kid the back of the bus was so far away from the front.
Speaker 0: It was like its own world Like you'd be hanging out in the back of the bus like it was this private little apartment in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I sit in the back of a school bus now and it's like.
Speaker 0: I feel like I can reach out and grab the bus driver.
Speaker 1: Maybe not that close but if it's a guess if it's the the tiny but the short bus.
Speaker 0: mostly I feel Exposed because I think when you're little like remember you're a kid in the school bus you're sitting there and You're shorter than the seat in front of you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're hiding.
Speaker 0: you feel like you're like you're invincible.
Speaker 1: No one can see what you're done made a lot of mischief in the school bus.
Speaker 0: that way No one can see what you're writing on the seat Or the fact that you're eating and drinking even though you're not supposed to be or that you're playing punch for punch Or mercy.
Speaker 0: ah Mercy, I never played mercy because I knew better and I had more than one friend.
Speaker 1: get broken fingers Fingers, you're supposed to break wrists.
Speaker 1: You're doing it wrong.
Speaker 1: Broken wrist is probably you know, you're playing properly if it's broken fingers.
Speaker 1: Someone is just not playing it correctly.
Speaker 0: So, uh There was some other interesting news today.
Speaker 0: It's not really breaking news anymore, but it has a personal connection to you.
Speaker 1: I think oh Yeah, well that also involves the cold.
Speaker 1: yeah the cold Basically, there was.
Speaker 1: it was all over the crazy news like OMG plane crashes in river right which is right where we work.
Speaker 1: And apparently on that, you know, my company was recently bought by another company.
Speaker 1: That is well relatively recently as in before.
Speaker 1: Well, the economy was bad, but we didn't know it.
Speaker 1: yet when this happened And as CEO of that company right was on that plane, that's it.
Speaker 0: Didn't he like call you from the plane like hey, yeah, I didn't call us.
Speaker 1: He called you know, I guess his person or whatever.
Speaker 1: Oh, and then there was like a company email That's a CEO.
Speaker 0: So I guess he has a person he was in.
Speaker 1: basically it was like, you know You know, it's like hey, you know, he was in our office yesterday and then some and then it's like playing from New York to Charlotte.
Speaker 1: It was like huh?
Speaker 1: Wasn't he flying out today?
Speaker 1: How many planes to Charlotte could there be in one day?
Speaker 1: And that was that is I don't know, you know I have only like talked to the guy once and that was to say hey fucker Why didn't couldn't you wait until after Thanksgiving to lay people off?
Speaker 0: Did you say the word fucker?
Speaker 1: No, no No, that's the only thing I've said to this guy besides.
Speaker 1: Hey, what's up?
Speaker 1: So yeah, but yeah, that's it.
Speaker 1: It's kind of weird though.
Speaker 1: It's like usually you see a plane crash.
Speaker 1: You don't know anyone.
Speaker 1: Then suddenly there's a plane crash and you know someone.
Speaker 1: it's like ooh weird But no one died.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well the cool thing is they floated the plane down to Jersey.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean basically takes off right?
Speaker 1: And the planes not doing so well so you sort of just Give it as much go as it's got left in it and then figure out a way to.
Speaker 1: you know Take as much energy out of it as you can on the way down you know and then land somewhere where you're not gonna crash and explode.
Speaker 1: and then You know use all the life rafts and shit and you know, usually a lot of that stuff on the plane You know, it's like hey, is this shit gonna work?
Speaker 1: Well, you know, I guess they told the people in the emergency exit rows and they did what they're supposed to do.
Speaker 1: So I guess the shit does work.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean they you saw they were like photos.
Speaker 1: everyone's standing on the wing Plane floated for a while, you know, I think is the funniest part is on the on the radio.
Speaker 1: They were like the plane is now tied up in Battery Park.
Speaker 1: So, I guess it's like a plane just like tied up on the on the shore Which is but I think that'd be a funny thing to go see.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there'll be a picture of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we should turn it into a little I don't know.
Speaker 0: sculpture or something.
Speaker 1: Make a plushie.
Speaker 0: Yeah plushie.
Speaker 1: the Hudson River crash.
Speaker 1: So in sort of a an unavoidable thing that you know to not talk about, you know, Steve Jobs health How could we not discuss this right?
Speaker 1: So Steve Jobs is a Pretty important person even if you know Apple is doing some things that are not so cool like they still have DRM on their movies and the iPhone is really locked down and Macs are overpriced and they only have one mouse button, etc.
Speaker 1: Etc.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: See jobs is pretty important.
Speaker 1: I mean without Steve Jobs Probably wouldn't have computers so much.
Speaker 1: Heck we might not even have gooeys, you know.
Speaker 1: I mean the GUI might have been invented but it would not have been like, you know This thing that everyone had on their computers everywhere, you know Probably would have kept with the DOS the Mac wouldn't have pushed on Windows to come out etc.
Speaker 1: Etc.
Speaker 1: We'd be in a different place.
Speaker 1: So it's sort of significant that he's ill in and could be dying.
Speaker 1: We don't know.
Speaker 0: Well, it raises a lot of.
Speaker 0: I mean Thursday is usually the fun days.
Speaker 0: I don't want to get into all this.
Speaker 0: I was kind of saving this for Monday now because it's not really technology Talking about more that there are other ramifications like very cold calculated ramifications that like investors because Steve Jobs is such a that's not what I want to talk about I know.
Speaker 0: but because he is such a like Demigod for Apple like he is he is like this face this avatar of the company that His personal life and his health and who he is and what he does Have an undue effect on the health of the company itself because so much of the company Either really internally or superficially.
Speaker 0: I mean obviously we can't know Relies on him and things that he doesn't do directly in the course of his work.
Speaker 1: Yep, but anyway, the thing I want to draw attention to is not so much the Apple end of things You know.
Speaker 1: it is that if you don't know the story, right and I think in 2003 or 4 Steve does you can find out all this info online.
Speaker 1: um he had pancreatic cancer, right?
Speaker 1: Which is not lucky, but he was lucky to have.
Speaker 1: is it sort of weird that he was lucky I guess to have a rare type of pancreatic cancer?
Speaker 1: I guess he would have been luckier to have none.
Speaker 1: But the thing is the most common kind of pancreatic cancer is pretty much you're gonna die And it's not it's not looking too good.
Speaker 1: this rare kind of pancreatic cancer that he had was actually Resurvivable.
Speaker 1: if you just go to the doctor and get a little surgery It's not pleasant But you're.
Speaker 1: you got good chances much better chances than if you have regular more common pancreatic cancer.
Speaker 1: So he found out he had this.
Speaker 1: But because you know despite all those things I just said about him He's sort of a hippie vegan kind of guy you know.
Speaker 1: so he was like.
Speaker 1: you know be in his hippie ways was like you.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna do this real medicine surgery.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna go on a diet now and that'll cure my cancer.
Speaker 0: my question to you is how Verified is this?
Speaker 0: I mean do you have?
Speaker 1: it's ours technica reports?
Speaker 1: alright, so I'm.
Speaker 1: there's multiple other places that report this as well I know.
Speaker 0: I'm just doing my due diligence to avoid a libel.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: There's no libel It's it's.
Speaker 1: plenty of places are reporting this.
Speaker 0: I didn't make it up because I do also see that he required no Chemotherapy or radiation therapy of any kind because they can know he just needed a surgery.
Speaker 0: yes the whipple procedure Which I'm reading about now, and it's actually kind of interest.
Speaker 1: It is very interesting.
Speaker 1: all he needed was his surgery, but he refused to get it.
Speaker 0: You know what it involves the duodenum which came up in conversation like three times with me yesterday.
Speaker 1: duodenum is a good word It's funny duodenum duodenum All right, so he doesn't want to get this surgery and he said goes on a diet thinking that I'll care it right and of It doesn't.
Speaker 1: so like six months or so later of course it gets a lot worse And he's forced to have the surgery right after he has the surgery.
Speaker 1: He's better.
Speaker 1: Oh my god real medicine works.
Speaker 1: It's a miracle right.
Speaker 1: actually it's not anything close to a miracle.
Speaker 1: It's perfectly ordinary real medicine working.
Speaker 1: So now of course he is illin again and his illin appears to be more serious than the I guess hormone imbalance that he said it was like a week ago or so and You know he hasn't given enough details for anyone to really know.
Speaker 1: But you know many doctors are taking the evidence that you know the information We do have and sort of you know saying what is common?
Speaker 1: What is likely you know etc?
Speaker 1: What is probable probably wrong with him?
Speaker 1: You know because we know the symptoms.
Speaker 1: He's getting real thin.
Speaker 1: We know some of his medical history had pancreatic cancer waited too long to get the surgery right.
Speaker 1: so based on that a lot of Doctors you know I've said it.
Speaker 1: It's probable that because he waited to get the surgery and tried the phony You know it's not so much phony medicine, but you know it is not real medicine That that you know that waiting could have you know?
Speaker 1: Contributed to his current health woes and perhaps if he would have had the surgery right away He probably would have been a lot better off right now than he is right now.
Speaker 0: all I really have to say to that is That it's really really sad.
Speaker 1: it is pretty sad and the thing is right is that I mean we look at famous people who have tried to do phony medicine and Either suffered needlessly or died too early because of it like Martin Luther King's wife.
Speaker 1: right she could have you know gotten better But instead of going to get treatment at the hospital.
Speaker 1: She went to a like alternative clinic in Mexico And then died.
Speaker 1: you know Andy Kaufman went to get psychic surgery in the Philippines died right and those are just famous People that I happen to know about doing this shit right.
Speaker 1: there are millions and probably you know thousands maybe millions of non-famous people who have turned to fake medicine or have at least turned away from real medicine and needlessly suffered and or died because of it when real medicine could have just helped him out.
Speaker 1: just fine, so Learn from Steve Jobs.
Speaker 1: Do not be like him.
Speaker 1: if there is something wrong with you right go get real medicine.
Speaker 1: I don't care if insurance sucks.
Speaker 1: I don't care if you know the health care is.
Speaker 1: the pharmaceutical companies are evil.
Speaker 0: There is a caveat of if you can't afford real medicine or don't have access to it What do you do?
Speaker 1: you go to the emergency room in the u.s.. You go to the emergency room where they have to treat you?
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right, but whatever you know do not go do The fake man.
Speaker 0: don't do what Donnie.
Speaker 0: don't die.
Speaker 1: all those other problems.
Speaker 1: You know insurance companies suck.
Speaker 1: pharmaceutical companies Are evil whether those are true or not right those things are not as important as you not dying.
Speaker 1: so For now you have to deal with that bullshit.
Speaker 1: You can worry about that later.
Speaker 1: if there is something wrong with you or something wrong with someone you care about or anyone you know Make sure real medicine only no fake medicine if you actually care about any.
Speaker 1: I guess if you want someone to die And they're sick tell them to go try fake medicine.
Speaker 1: That that's a good idea, but I guess if you're even.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day on a somewhat lighter note.
Speaker 0: now It's a lighter note and that it's not sad, but at the same time It's a serious note because I worry as to how many people will do well on this test.
Speaker 0: oh I found this little quiz out there on the internet, and it's a very simple very short quiz and all it does is test your ability to think Logically and it will.
Speaker 0: it is designed in such a way that certain questions particularly question 12 for anyone who's paying attention They will lead you in a certain direction in order to point out the differences between say Inductive or deductive logic and all those sorts of things.
Speaker 0: I just thought this was neat.
Speaker 0: I'll point out I got a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: I got 93 percent, but the last question I did.
Speaker 1: I was rules lawyer on it because I was rules lawyer II on the rest of it and but being rules lawyer II on the final question You know sort of backfired But actually I'll give it to him the answers.
Speaker 1: the answer sheet admits that the final question is up for philosophical debate and Actually if there was a philosophical debate I would have debated on the side of my answer which they said was incorrect.
Speaker 1: so what I get?
Speaker 1: the rest of them, right?
Speaker 1: That's what really counts.
Speaker 1: yes, but so if you get the last one wrong It's okay.
Speaker 0: if you get less than 93 percent That's not okay you suck, but I mean part of the thing to keep in mind here Is that this kind of reveals the difference between?
Speaker 0: Like you look in law you have the preponderance of evidence kind of argument, and then you have the beyond a reasonable doubt argument Mm-hmm, but then you have the beyond a shadow of a doubt argument.
Speaker 1: see the thing is is that?
Speaker 1: Because it's sort of like.
Speaker 1: what this is is a like what you do in math problems, right?
Speaker 1: There's always the word problems.
Speaker 1: You know it's basically the same as all the other problems.
Speaker 1: only instead of saying What's 24 divided by 6 right.
Speaker 1: they say I have 24 apples and six friends.
Speaker 1: We want to share the apples evenly.
Speaker 1: how many apples do I give to each friend?
Speaker 1: right and it?
Speaker 1: It's the same exact answer, but you have to think about it differently.
Speaker 0: Clearly you give everyone one, and you throw the rest away, that's right, so what this does?
Speaker 1: what this?
Speaker 1: Test does is actually it's a discrete mathematics Twizz.
Speaker 1: that's what they're really asking you.
Speaker 1: you know you've got transitive relationships and all that business going on.
Speaker 0: Well actually the way in layman's terms.
Speaker 0: really simply when you when you think about logic.
Speaker 0: They're different.
Speaker 0: There is basically practical logic and Philosophical logic kind of like with you know real-life free will solipsism all that stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean Philosophically and physically.
Speaker 0: I can't prove that I have consciousness or any of those things, and I'm forced to admit that Solipsistically.
Speaker 0: the only thing I can prove that exists is myself, but practically Scott's sitting right there And I got a computer in front of me.
Speaker 0: so my practical logic has to get past the philosophical logic in that you have to.
Speaker 0: You can use fuzzy logic to live your real life Because things are not black and white in the real world because you don't have all the information.
Speaker 0: But if you use pure philosophical logic.
Speaker 0: And as and your precepts are correct like the.
Speaker 0: if A is true and B is true Then C is true.
Speaker 0: logic is used and you know for sure that A and B are true.
Speaker 0: Then you know one hundred percent sure that C is true.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I said it's discrete mathematics.
Speaker 1: You know A and A you know A and B therefore C.
Speaker 0: You know it also for a the fundamental Paradox of existence that the more sure you are about something or the more Close to a hundred percent veracity a statement is the less applicable or globally useful such statement is so kind of.
Speaker 0: the more right you are on a philosophical level the less Applicability you have.
Speaker 0: and if you're a hundred percent, right you have zero applicability.
Speaker 0: Mmm-hmm It's interesting stuff, and if you're not well versed in the true ideas of philosophical and mathematical logic this test If you're intelligent you will be able to learn almost all of it simply by taking and passing or failing this test.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're a computer scientist you need you can't pass this.
Speaker 0: you got problems find a new job You have a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: yeah kind of okay all right.
Speaker 1: so this this article It's more it's mostly an editorial and it's not full of a lot of evidence really and it's sort of written in a silly Fashion.
Speaker 1: so don't don't take it to be like you know.
Speaker 1: This is true for reals.
Speaker 1: There's a scientific study.
Speaker 1: OMG right even though I think it does reference a study you know as a little citation for it.
Speaker 1: But basically what this guy is saying is he saying?
Speaker 1: he's suggesting in a somewhat humorous manner That peanut allergies are an invention of yuppies.
Speaker 1: and While I don't know if it's a hundred percent true, and I'm very dubious and skeptical of the actual You know veracity of this suggestion it is.
Speaker 0: So I use the word veracity because I just used it a bunch of times a little while ago to got stuck in your head.
Speaker 1: I don't know I use that word.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: just it seems I feel like that word.
Speaker 1: am I supposed to use truthiness?
Speaker 1: no All right, but basically what he's suggesting here right is that basically there was a There are only four percent of kids with food allergies yet 25% of parents believe their kids have food allergies.
Speaker 1: It's a mismatch here, right?
Speaker 0: It's kind of like the the old mean-world syndrome where you know their X percentage of people are subject to violent crimes.
Speaker 0: But if you ask people Themselves the perception of how much violent crime is out there.
Speaker 0: every individual person perceives a lot more than there really is Mm-hmm like how every person in the like if you quiz people Far more than 50% of drivers think that they are an average or better driver.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right so You know he's talking about things like how you know these crazy overprotective yuppie parents You know well think their kids have food allergies and their kids like no I get the peanut butter away from me But they don't really have a food allergy.
Speaker 1: you know and maybe you know in some cases I mean, there's there's evidence of this in other things where you know maybe you're not actually allergic to something.
Speaker 1: But if you have this like extreme Psychological aversion to something that it can sort of cause a reaction like if I sort of you know really instill in you the fact That you know.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: I keep telling you you stay the fuck away from peanut butter.
Speaker 1: Oh my god You'll die you know and you actually believe this.
Speaker 1: and then peanut butter comes along Even if you don't have an actual allergy just because you're gonna freak out You're gonna have these other.
Speaker 1: you know whenever you see or smell peanut butter that they're freaking out in your in your mind Cause you know results in these other problems.
Speaker 1: You know the stress now.
Speaker 0: This is very true.
Speaker 0: I've seen a lot of studies, and this has been pretty verified that if someone believes they have sensitivity to something they can Generate psychosomatic responses that will actually cause hives to appear and physical symptoms of a minor nature to appear.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can.
Speaker 1: actually you know this happens a lot.
Speaker 1: This is where you get those people who say like you know that cell phone towers You know give them headaches
Speaker 0: or in like a school where like a girl smells something and then like she feels sick And then like all the other kids in the class start feeling sick - it's like this mass hysteria thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like you know.
Speaker 1: they like they've done like studies.
Speaker 1: basically you find someone who says that they're you know sensitive to.
Speaker 1: You know electromagnetic waves and basically whenever this person this person says that whenever they're near a cell tower They start to get headaches, and it sucks right, so what do you do?
Speaker 1: you put the person in a room right and?
Speaker 1: You go around and behind the wall where they can't see you have an antenna right and basically you turn it on and off But they don't know whether it's on or off.
Speaker 1: and then you ask them like you know is it on or off right now?
Speaker 1: and Basically if they decide that it's on they will actually have headaches, and they will tell you they have headaches.
Speaker 1: And they'll tell you they think it's on.
Speaker 1: and if they think it's off they won't have headaches.
Speaker 1: And they'll tell you they think it's off.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile it doesn't actually matter whether it's on or off.
Speaker 1: it only matters whether they think it's on or off which shows that the electromagnetic Waves from the radio are not actually the cause of their headaches But just their own.
Speaker 1: psychology is the cause of the headaches and and it's like it's very it is possible that a large amount of these you know reports of allergies and increase.
Speaker 1: I mean there's definitely been a. he says here that there has been a What percent?
Speaker 1: 18% increase in childhood food allergies between 97 and 2007.
Speaker 1: That definitely seems.
Speaker 1: I mean it's possible that that could be you know a genetic thing.
Speaker 1: You know just that the gene has emerged due to the way things have gone.
Speaker 0: There's also the option that it might be environmental.
Speaker 1: it could be endemic because there is possible.
Speaker 0: there is other evidence pointing to Allergies in general being in a higher rate of occurrence when cleanliness is above a certain standard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, too much antibacterial soaps and things are you.
Speaker 0: but the thing is these are all very loose correlations right now.
Speaker 0: There's no there's all of you.
Speaker 1: causation all of these are possible explanations all this But mass hysteria is just as plausible an explanation as the others cats and dogs living together.
Speaker 1: Yes, and it's you know.
Speaker 1: this little article is funny and interesting.
Speaker 1: Especially you know if you're like one of those if you're trying to send your kid to school with a peanut butter and jelly sandwich And they won't let you and you're pissed off.
Speaker 1: You know you'll like this article.
Speaker 0: Well the the real answer is peanut butter with a baseball bat Peanut butter jelly.
Speaker 0: peanut butter jelly.
Speaker 1: peanut butter jelly baseball bat.
Speaker 0: That's one thing.
Speaker 0: we were ahead of the curve.
Speaker 0: We were.
Speaker 0: we were all about that song.
Speaker 1: You know when I was about that song.
Speaker 1: I was about that song.
Speaker 1: I first heard it in Summer camp I guess I was a counselor and after the it was between my first and second years at RIT.
Speaker 1: so 2001 I had peanut butter jelly with a baseball bat beat up.
Speaker 1: that was way ahead.
Speaker 1: That was before the dancing banana at that point.
Speaker 1: It was just a song by the buckwheat boys and nothing more.
Speaker 1: Right not many people can come close to that except the other people at the summer camp.
Speaker 0: so What I have learned from the news recently is that one if you are going to fake your own death You should at least make sure there's enough fuel in your planes that it will actually crash over the ocean without your body in it instead of Nearby without your body in it with the door open.
Speaker 1: well You know well, I guess you got closing the doors key.
Speaker 0: first of all - if you're gonna fake your own death liquidate your assets Before you disappear not after.
Speaker 1: yeah, that's also a very good idea.
Speaker 1: the Swiss banks exist for a reason.
Speaker 0: so to the you know tiny islands in the Caribbean three if you jumped out of your plane and landed in a swamp and needed help and Go find the police.
Speaker 0: Have a better story than I was in a canoeing accident And don't give them your real driver's license.
Speaker 0: say you lost it in the canoeing accident.
Speaker 1: Did the guy really yes?
Speaker 1: Yes, Wow yes that just either.
Speaker 1: I mean that tells me like I didn't realize that he was that stupid this guy That he wasn't really trying that hard that he really didn't want it.
Speaker 1: He wasn't committed He didn't really want it to go.
Speaker 0: all the way people try to do too much with it.
Speaker 0: You did not try.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think he really wanted it.
Speaker 1: that badly enough either.
Speaker 1: that or is it?
Speaker 1: he couldn't have been that stupid.
Speaker 0: It might have been a cockamamie plan like maybe he's on the plane, and he's like oh crap I just suddenly realized how screwed I am.
Speaker 0: time to fake my own death.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he probably.
Speaker 1: yeah, it could have been a spontaneous thing in which case.
Speaker 1: There's no way it's gonna succeed I don't know.
Speaker 0: I it seems like running away in that capacity like faking your own death or disappearing or even being a willful bum if You're smart would be really easy and could probably be very cool.
Speaker 1: Faking your own death is significantly more different difficult than just running away right away.
Speaker 1: It's kind of easy I think faking your least.
Speaker 1: in a free country faking your death can be difficult if you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not like South Park.
Speaker 0: You just need to have a pig in butters clothing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean to fake your death.
Speaker 1: right you need to do one of two things basically at least in a country like the US right one.
Speaker 1: you either need to fake a corpse.
Speaker 1: That's really hard.
Speaker 1: I mean something that like uh you know what's what's the guy at the morgue's name the mortician or the corner?
Speaker 1: Yeah, something that a corner or a mortician is gonna be fooled by.
Speaker 1: Good luck.
Speaker 1: I mean maybe you could get an actual corpse But even then they're gonna DNA and they're gonna dental record.
Speaker 1: and what are you gonna do about that?
Speaker 1: It is fucking hard.
Speaker 1: It would cost you the amount of money It would cost to fake the corpse and fool even like the lazy corner really hard.
Speaker 1: I mean, maybe you could bribe the coroner that would might do it.
Speaker 1: But even then that is not a guaranteed thing.
Speaker 1: You're the fewer people you have to trust the better, right?
Speaker 1: So the other way to do it is to die in some way Where there is no corpse.
Speaker 1: for example your plane crashed a lot of times.
Speaker 1: planes crash and there's no corpse.
Speaker 1: You get eaten by sharks in the ocean.
Speaker 1: There's or piranhas.
Speaker 1: There's nothing left that that the piranhas come, right?
Speaker 1: What
Speaker 0: about in that movie where all you have to do is have a dentist friend find a hobo corpse somewhere Get him to dental I'm gonna use that as a verb or dentify the teeth to where upon an examination Especially it just they'll think it's you like they already think it's you because they found your wallet and you burn the body or something And they find the skull in the teeth and they do their quick x-ray in their tests and it matches up with your dental records.
Speaker 1: They say well unless there's it as long as there's no suspicion of like murder and it's not part of like a big case They're not gonna dedicate resources to investigate further.
Speaker 1: So that probably would work.
Speaker 1: but if they do investigate further like they think there might be some foul play and it gets all on the news and they got to do bringing the Real forensic experts and not just like the local cop schmucks then they're gonna look and say hey these teeth were doctored.
Speaker 1: See, this is a fuck.
Speaker 0: This is one of the problems with their CSI bullshit.
Speaker 0: see more Reason you have to fake your death the harder it becomes because more people are looking for you.
Speaker 0: if I fake my death People would go.
Speaker 0: well rim had a good run.
Speaker 0: I mean, it'd be really easy to all I do is say I'm going to breakneck Ridge hiking or something And then just I would leave town.
Speaker 0: I would just like drive.
Speaker 0: I'd like ditch my car I'd like walk real far away and then I'd start hitchhiking and once I got far enough away, I just like Lay down outside a hospital at night and fall asleep.
Speaker 0: Wait till someone finds me and claim amnesia.
Speaker 0: Eventually, they'd assume I was dead in the wilderness.
Speaker 1: Hmm get to be really good at acting though because they'll check for that brain damage.
Speaker 1: those Neurologists will come and you might get caught.
Speaker 1: You had to be Really good with the acting to claim amnesia or just act like you're stupid.
Speaker 1: I guess that work.
Speaker 1: you gotta be really good at acting.
Speaker 1: So the other ways you got it.
Speaker 1: you got to die where there's.
Speaker 1: the Already said that where no one expects to find a body you got drop in a vat of acid.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Now the thing is dropping a vat of acid.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: I was that vat of acid there - what were you doing?
Speaker 1: Hanging out.
Speaker 1: Oh think about this though.
Speaker 1: It's not just that it's.
Speaker 1: how do you fall and create the impression?
Speaker 1: That you have fallen in the vat of acid?
Speaker 1: yet You did not actually fall in the vat of acid because then you didn't fake your death.
Speaker 1: you committed suicide.
Speaker 1: You had to.
Speaker 1: so you have to like take a fake you toss it in the acid and then somehow escape.
Speaker 1: That's it's a little harder than I mean.
Speaker 1: jumping in the vat of acid is easy.
Speaker 1: now try surviving that but having people believe you didn't That's hard.
Speaker 0: Maybe one way to go is just cut yourself and get a bunch of blood like in your bedroom or something.
Speaker 0: Here it is make it look like you were murdered and then just disappear.
Speaker 0: Like drive your car out somewhere.
Speaker 0: cut yourself cover your car in your own blood.
Speaker 0: Maybe someone else's blood - if you've got someone else's blood handy, of course.
Speaker 0: if you do You're probably a bad person in the police.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like you're trying to just escape.
Speaker 1: You're not trying to be bad It's just you're trying.
Speaker 0: I'm saying what if you have like you work in a hospital.
Speaker 0: All right, you've got access to like blood.
Speaker 0: All right, put some other blood there too just to make it weird and suspicious and then like that's not good.
Speaker 1: But if it's weird and suspicious living a lot more investigating.
Speaker 1: But then just push the car off a cliff Then they'll go and pick the car off off the bottom of the cliff and there's no bodies in it.
Speaker 1: This is a lot of blood.
Speaker 1: Yeah where the bodies go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they're gonna look for bodies.
Speaker 0: They're not gonna look for you alive and well in Albuquerque working as like a busker.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's gonna be one of those things.
Speaker 1: They do the manhunt on the news and they're looking with Are you a pretty young white woman?
Speaker 0: You are well pretty and young.
Speaker 1: yes mostly the white woman.
Speaker 0: Anyway Yeah, yeah See, but it's kind of like the same thing with being a bum.
Speaker 0: I mean Or a lot of situations like if I personally became homeless or became a bum or needed to fake my own death.
Speaker 0: I feel like I could get away with it.
Speaker 1: But I think Scott - and I think a lot of smart people could kind of like how well running it see the thing is I don't know if I get faked my own death because it's actually kind of hard.
Speaker 1: But I mean, I guess I could have really tried.
Speaker 0: I think if you were to turn running away You spent like a month planning it as opposed to I don't know 10 minutes on a radio show off the cuff.
Speaker 1: running away is actually really easy because Right.
Speaker 1: I am over the age of 18 years old, right?
Speaker 1: I'm just you know, if I just get up and leave and you just don't see me I don't come back tomorrow.
Speaker 1: You can't really file and like a you know, a missing person's report or anything.
Speaker 0: I'm allowed to go.
Speaker 0: I can file a missing person's report But the police won't act on it for X days or X weeks or whatever.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna really.
Speaker 1: I'm just allowed to go Wherever I want.
Speaker 1: I can't know.
Speaker 1: as long as my like taxes end up getting paid and stuff like that You know, no one's gonna come looking for me.
Speaker 1: And as long as I can get a new identity.
Speaker 0: But that's the tricky part in the u.s.
Speaker 0: They're making that more and more difficult.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm more difficult.
Speaker 0: have the amnesia.
Speaker 0: you show up in a hospital and You just like you don't remember who you are or anything and eventually hope that they give you something.
Speaker 1: I think a better idea is just go to a small town and live a small town life Maybe like marry someone in the small town where how you gonna get the marriage license?
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: You don't have any ID?
Speaker 1: It's a small town.
Speaker 1: They don't freakin.
Speaker 0: Yes, they do they.
Speaker 0: they they'll check.
Speaker 1: Just a stranger comes to town.
Speaker 0: things are getting increasingly interlink idly data vase.
Speaker 0: if I'd They like that term interlink idly data vase.
Speaker 1: if I'd that is you know Whether you fake your own death or try to run away, right if you do try really want to do it go to Mexico.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you do try to create a new identity in a civilized, you know developed fancy high-tech society It is very difficult because like okay, so you either a get real papers or be forged some papers, right?
Speaker 1: Well, if you forge some papers that's harder and harder to do.
Speaker 1: but if they're forged papers remember Someone eventually is gonna take those papers and then look them up in a database.
Speaker 1: Like maybe a cop will pull you over and take your fake driver's license Even if the driver's license is really you made it at the DMV with a corrupt DMV person.
Speaker 1: Okay, so you can get into bars and drink easily, right?
Speaker 1: But when a cop takes it and types in your driver's license number into his computer and it says not valid you are Fucked.
Speaker 1: so you got a hack the DMV database to get that info in there.
Speaker 0: That is really hard as I am bordering on the thing is it's really hard and it's also really easy because People like us have technological skills and contacts.
Speaker 0: I Don't think it would be that hard for me.
Speaker 1: Well, are you even here's where it gets interesting problem Is that when you you can pull that off?
Speaker 1: But it requires either a you to be in a position say you work at the DMV or something like that or the social Security office or be you're trusting someone who does and remember.
Speaker 1: Well, even if you can have someone you can trust and it is probably gonna work but a loose lip will sink the ship.
Speaker 0: Well, one option is how is the age-old tradition of hacking by leaving USB keys with auto-inject Trojans just like on the street outside of the DMV?
Speaker 0: Mmm, so you got to be clever.
Speaker 1: if you can pull off a move like that Then then the winner is you.
Speaker 1: but but remember DMV computer is not likely to be on the Internet's.
Speaker 0: The point I really want to make is that a lot of these things and this applies broadly crime running away faking your death being a terrorist all those things are Trivial in many ways for people who are smart.
Speaker 0: But the reason we don't see this happening is because if you're smart You can do something more worthwhile with your life and sad people do that's the same thing.
Speaker 1: We always talk about with terrorism, right?
Speaker 1: It's like look at the real.
Speaker 1: to the terrorists the people who actively hate the u.s Don't mind killing people in fact want to kill people right as much as there's a lot of fear-mongering And it's the problem of terrorism is very inflated in the media and sensationalized.
Speaker 1: those people do exist.
Speaker 1: They're out there, right?
Speaker 1: They they they would really like it if bombs exploded in New York City and every other major city and such.
Speaker 1: They are people who would like that.
Speaker 0: luckily luckily do he died.
Speaker 1: They are luckily they're all stupid Very very stupid and not smart, but it's the same thing like look at our homeless.
Speaker 0: people are a good example.
Speaker 0: A lot of studies show that many many people who become homeless Who don't have mental problems and are otherwise, okay But had a run of bad luck will become non homeless within a relatively short span of time Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And now obviously there are exceptions to this and homelessness is a huge problem in the u.s.
Speaker 0: But a lot of the people you see who are homeless I would especially.
Speaker 1: the thing is the homeless people that you see are the like the street wandering type.
Speaker 0: I was about to say they're taking the begging type.
Speaker 0: There are the willful homeless who refuse to like.
Speaker 0: they know about the shelters they know about the help and they refuse to do it because they prefer to be homeless or they're crazy and they're the people who Have mental problems that really should be in institutions getting help.
Speaker 0: but because of the way the US systems work There's nowhere for these people to go.
Speaker 0: and it's it's really this freedom conundrum where.
Speaker 0: think about it.
Speaker 0: You have the freedom to do whatever you want.
Speaker 0: These people they're not Stabbing themselves or like doing the things that would get them arrested and sent to Not showering collecting nasty shit doing little dances and pooping occasionally.
Speaker 0: now, here's the problem.
Speaker 0: What's the line between someone who just doesn't want to make better of themselves?
Speaker 0: versus someone who has a mental problem?
Speaker 0: and they can't and they need help?
Speaker 0: because in one case you have to Forcibly intervene in their lives to help them But in another case is that intervention justified?
Speaker 0: if the person is a rational thinking adult who has chosen this lifestyle?
Speaker 0: yep, and You either are going to infringe on someone's freedom or let someone who really does need help not get help And I don't know what to do about that.
Speaker 0: but if someone like me or one of us or a lot of you out there were homeless suddenly like your house blew up and You got fired from your job and someone stole all your money and the government wouldn't help you You had no insurance.
Speaker 1: you could probably Figure something out like I mean at the worst right.
Speaker 1: you can get a job at the McDonald's.
Speaker 1: live with a friend You know.
Speaker 1: live with your parents You know.
Speaker 1: find you somewhere to crash.
Speaker 0: or even if you're completely alone in the world Especially at our age and your age like what would I do right now if I had no friends in the world?
Speaker 1: Go to Europe.
Speaker 0: I suddenly lost everything I owned.
Speaker 0: I had no assets whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Go to Europe.
Speaker 0: No go to a college campus.
Speaker 0: hang out.
Speaker 0: make friends with people especially stoners and drunk frat guys.
Speaker 0: They will totally hook you up and give you places to stay as long as you're cool And then you can get yourself on your feet that way.
Speaker 0: hmm.
Speaker 0: I mean that.
Speaker 0: Do that?
Speaker 1: I mean especially like if someone if you find a college campus find some college kids living around there Right and you go to work at say like Home Depot all day while they're in college Doing their college thing and you're hanging with them
Speaker 0: You have more money than they do.
Speaker 1: you are bringing in so much money And if you pay a significant portion of the rent they're totally helping you out, and they got mad monies.
Speaker 0: You know weed.
Speaker 0: they got weed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: you can really you know and work in Home Depot ain't so bad?
Speaker 1: It's better than nothing.
Speaker 0: yep, right, so It you know well like all right like.
Speaker 0: How many people did I convince to feed me when I had no money and no food in college?
Speaker 0: I think I could seduce my way across the country getting people to feed me if I needed to.
Speaker 0: I Don't know.
Speaker 0: I tell stories like I do.
Speaker 0: geek nights live for people.
Speaker 0: I just hang out and be cool and get people to give me stuff.
Speaker 0: mmm Maybe I should do that.
Speaker 0: that might be a more fun life.
Speaker 0: I should give up the glamour of the stock market and all the money and all this stuff and just Wander around being one of those traveling troubadours.
Speaker 1: No, not bad idea.
Speaker 0: No, why not?
Speaker 0: why not?
Speaker 1: no it's not good see.
Speaker 0: the only problem with those plans Is that the seduce your way across the country or hang out with the college kids thing?
Speaker 0: Really tapers off as age increases.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's.
Speaker 0: I mean when you're 45 and you're hanging out at the frat house That is when people start looking at you as a borderline pedophile Borderline.
Speaker 0: well, they're college people so they're above the age anyway.
Speaker 0: It's just it's creepy.
Speaker 1: well I mean, you know it's not any more creepy than like Hugh Hefner.
Speaker 0: right yeah, but society Vindicate.
Speaker 0: not doesn't vindicate, but society rationalizes him because he has money.
Speaker 0: yeah But there's a lot of situations of you know young girls really old guys But you don't have anything to bring to the equation you're a bum.
Speaker 1: Hey, you know there are bums.
Speaker 1: They get like mad booty.
Speaker 1: it happens.
Speaker 1: Usually though it's like they're not bums, but like hobos.
Speaker 1: like there was a hobo I heard about who ran a pirate radio station and that in like a little shack.
Speaker 0: well There is a big distinction between hobo bum and all those different.
Speaker 1: But he had mad ladies like hot college ladies because his radio station was apparently really hip and cool yeah, and they'd come out to his shack and It was part Radio Shack part.
Speaker 0: Love Shack See at this point.
Speaker 0: I'd say hey well What would we do right now if we had to do a couple of one of those scenarios, but?
Speaker 0: They're so specific like what would I do if X happened?
Speaker 0: I have like a thousand Pretty much.
Speaker 1: what it boils down to is I'm smart.
Speaker 1: I have skills.
Speaker 1: I would be okay Unless it was you know unless it was a situation that was sort of Unrecoverable like hey a nuke dropped real close to me, and I have nasty radiation or all right I'm locked or airtight stone room.
Speaker 0: Yeah naked with no tools.
Speaker 1: Oh shit It's Mad Max, and I'm not on top.
Speaker 1: You know someone else's.
Speaker 1: I know you know I'm not Ken Shiro.
Speaker 1: I'm some guy who's like you know asking Ken Shiro to punch a hole in the ground to get water.
Speaker 0: You're one of those farmers.
Speaker 0: You know what it's not good to be a farmer in the Mad Max world.
Speaker 1: No, no, it is very good to know.
Speaker 1: hooked on a Ken too bad.
Speaker 1: I do not know it.
Speaker 0: All right this show is privately petering out.
Speaker 0: I think we're done all right.
Speaker 0: sure This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.