Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, March 3rd, I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Sky.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, a little bit of Mouseguard and then Quake Live.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: As I said this morning about the weather, I tire of this bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I just, uh... It is so cold.
Speaker 0: I mean, I did the Rochester walk this morning.
Speaker 0: I have not done the Rochester walk in a while.
Speaker 0: And I do not want to have to do it again.
Speaker 1: I see the thermometer in my car every morning, and this morning it only said -11C.
Speaker 1: And there was another time this year where it was less than that.
Speaker 1: It was like -13 or 14C.
Speaker 1: So it wasn't the cold as it's been all year, but it was starting to get warm.
Speaker 1: It was like 40-something degrees for a little while.
Speaker 1: So the fact that it got cold again is just like... I'm really not too happy, and I just feel like total shit.
Speaker 1: And if it doesn't get spring-sued, I'm just gonna quit and get in a plane, and I'm gonna go buy like a $5,000 house in the desert.
Speaker 1: Because, you know, houses are cheap, deserts are warm.
Speaker 1: Why would I stay here?
Speaker 0: Just quit your job, live off your savings.
Speaker 1: I could just take all my money and I could afford to live in the desert and pay for only an internet connection and electricity and food and own a little desert house and live there for like quite a few years.
Speaker 1: I feel like maybe I should.
Speaker 0: You could go one step further and just squat somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I want to live in a nice desert house.
Speaker 0: No, buy a really nice Winnebago.
Speaker 1: Winnebago costs more than a desert shack.
Speaker 0: Fine, buy a really crappy Winnebago.
Speaker 1: Rather, a desert shack is nice.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It wouldn't be that nice.
Speaker 0: Depends.
Speaker 1: I'd make it myself.
Speaker 1: It'd be very nice.
Speaker 0: So you're gonna play Quake on that high-latency satellite internet connection?
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: Because a desert shack is so cheap, I could afford to have a T1 brought out.
Speaker 1: There's telephone pretty much anywhere, so why not?
Speaker 1: I'm not talking about the middle of Death Valley.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about that tiny little Nevada town or something.
Speaker 1: Somewhere between Vegas and Reno.
Speaker 0: But not that long ago, we were at the New York Comic-Con and we did a bunch of stuff there and we have a few things still pending from that, but one thing I did was I talked to Luke Crane a bit about the mouse card role-playing game.
Speaker 0: Now, Mouse Guard, we played it a little bit.
Speaker 0: We're gonna do a show on it once we've fully grokked all that it is and really pushed it to its limits.
Speaker 0: So we're really trying to avoid our commentary on it just yet.
Speaker 1: But yeah, basically, Mouse Guard is a comic book made by David Peterson that I was a huge fan of and had been reading for a very long time.
Speaker 1: Luke Crane, you probably know, is the creator of Burning Wheel and I like his RPGs.
Speaker 1: And way back, when we did that first Luke Crane interview, right before that interview, like literally one minute before we started that interview, I was sitting in the lobby of, what was that hotel?
Speaker 0: Wherever UberCon was.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was near the Meadowlands in some hotel at UberCon, whatever number it was.
Speaker 1: And it was me, Luke Crane, Drunken Rim, right?
Speaker 0: I wasn't drunk yet.
Speaker 1: No, Tor Olavsrud and these guys from Arcana Studio Press.
Speaker 1: And we were sitting there and they were talking.
Speaker 1: And once I realized who they were, I was like, oh, because Mouse Guard was brand new back then.
Speaker 1: And Scott and I were not... Makes you realize how old Mouse Guard is.
Speaker 1: It's only in its second series.
Speaker 0: We were not yet the epic podcasters that we are.
Speaker 1: No, we're not.
Speaker 0: Basically, we had badgered Luke Crane.
Speaker 1: That's where we left the power supply to the compressor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the old compressor.
Speaker 0: But we had badgered Luke Crane, this whole con.
Speaker 0: Like, can we interview?
Speaker 0: Can we interview?
Speaker 0: And finally, he was like, all right, after the con, you can interview me before I go home.
Speaker 1: No, I think he liked being able to.
Speaker 1: He did.
Speaker 0: He did.
Speaker 0: But he was definitely...
Speaker 1: And that interview is definitely, you know, he's definitely very pleased with the attention that we have managed to attract for him.
Speaker 0: But it was definitely a, we're some punk kids who bothered him to get an interview for something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but, you know, so that was like the burning empires had just come out.
Speaker 1: then, you know.
Speaker 1: And he was talking to the Arcana Studio Press guys and he was like, hey, Mouse Guard RPG, you know, if, you know, if you guys want me to do it, I'll do it.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, sure enough, here it is.
Speaker 1: How many years later?
Speaker 1: There it is.
Speaker 1: Mouse Guard RPG.
Speaker 0: But Luke Crane had quite a bit to say about it.
Speaker 0: I recorded this just at the New York Comic Con.
Speaker 0: So there's some background noise, but I'm pretty sure you can understand what he's got to say.
Speaker 2: Hey, Mouse fans.
Speaker 2: Mouse Guard Role Playing Game is a, it's meant to be a simple, instructive role playing game that does not ignore complexity and fighting.
Speaker 2: And the things that we liked about D&D were the things that we ignored about D&D when we played it when we were kids.
Speaker 2: The mechanic for the game, I mean, aside from all the color about, you know, what your fur color is and your cloak color and all that cool stuff, the mechanic for the game that really locks it in nice and tight is called nature.
Speaker 2: And your nature determines how mousy you are or how not mousy you are.
Speaker 2: And your nature ranges from zero to seven.
Speaker 2: And the higher your nature is, the better off you are.
Speaker 2: You can power your nature into doing all sorts of things.
Speaker 2: A normal mouse could not.
Speaker 2: But if your nature gets too high, you become too mousy, too mouse-like.
Speaker 2: You embody the animal too much, right?
Speaker 2: So you can, you know, the wolf will never catch you.
Speaker 2: You'll always outrun the wolf.
Speaker 2: You know, you'll always dig your burrow better, but you become too mouse-like.
Speaker 2: And so that gets you a trait.
Speaker 2: Basically, your nature hits seven.
Speaker 2: That gets you a crazy mousy trait.
Speaker 2: When your nature hits zero, you become too un-mouse-like and you get a trait.
Speaker 2: Like, Kelina is the best example, the old dude, you know, the black axe, whatever.
Speaker 2: He, at some point in that character's past, he hit nature zero and he retired.
Speaker 2: He became un-mouse-like and became kind of, he got the old fur trait, basically, when he hit zero.
Speaker 2: Because he's just like, "Ah, forget it.
Speaker 2: I don't want to do this
Speaker 2: anymore.".
Speaker 2: And that's how he's introduced.
Speaker 2: He's like, "I don't want to be in the mouse guard anymore.
Speaker 2: I'm something else
Speaker 2: now.".
Speaker 2: And we were like, "Wait, how do we make that into a mechanic in the
Speaker 2: game?".
Speaker 2: And Kelina, interestingly enough, isn't a sample character because he's the guy you have to play toward.
Speaker 2: You can't make him at the start.
Speaker 2: You have to gun toward playing him and make that history in play.
Speaker 2: Character creation is questionnaire-based.
Speaker 2: You answer questions about your mouse, you know, where he was born, who his parents were, what they did, what his mentor did in the guard, what skills he picked up in the guard, what skills he picked up on the road in the guard, and any kind of natural talents he has.
Speaker 2: And that's pretty much it.
Speaker 2: So that's for your skills.
Speaker 2: And then you do the same thing.
Speaker 2: What traits did your parents have?
Speaker 2: What did you inherit from them?
Speaker 2: What didn't you inherit from them?
Speaker 2: What did you get on your own?
Speaker 2: So it's a questionnaire.
Speaker 2: We try to, like all Burning Wheel games, we try to give you a sense of the history of the character in character creation.
Speaker 2: We worked really hard to make sure that the mouse guard game, out of the box, without any effort from the players, plays out the comics.
Speaker 2: Fall and winter, right?
Speaker 2: Where you're scraping and scrapping to survive, you're fighting against insane animals, owls and snakes and badgers.
Speaker 2: You're, you know, you're the representatives of this organization on which the safety of all mousekind, you know, rests, right?
Speaker 2: And so there's a lot of pressure and, you know, your missions are all high stakes.
Speaker 2: Your life is always on the line.
Speaker 2: When you open that book and you start reading that book, you are going to play a mouse guard story, period.
Speaker 2: So one of the ways, one of the mechanics that we built into the game, rather, to reinforce the mousiness of it was something called the natural order.
Speaker 2: And we have this beautiful little chart that David Peterson, the artist and author, designed for us.
Speaker 2: that shows, you know, all the way from insects and, you know, and mice and snakes and bats and birds and badgers and wolves and foxes and bears and moose, like this great scale chart, which honestly is an homage to Call of Cthulhu.
Speaker 2: Anybody who knows what I'm talking about knows what I'm talking about.
Speaker 2: And there's that great chart of, like, you go all the way from, like, Bayaki to men all the way up to Cthulhu and they show you the size comparison.
Speaker 2: Well, one of the problems in that, for me, is that Cthulhu just has a set number of hit points.
Speaker 2: Yeah, he's got special powers, blah, blah, blah, but he's got hit points, which means he can be dealt with.
Speaker 2: Not in mouse guard.
Speaker 2: So you can only affect, like, you can only fight with creatures that are, like, one higher step than you or lower.
Speaker 2: On the natural order.
Speaker 2: So mice can fight with snakes and weasels, right?
Speaker 2: And, you know, and have a chance.
Speaker 2: But beyond that, you know, foxes and wolves and bears, mice run.
Speaker 2: That's what you do.
Speaker 2: when you fight a fox or a weasel or whatever, or a fox or rather a wolverine, you run.
Speaker 2: And if you want to confront those creatures, you have to use science.
Speaker 2: You have to use warfare, right?
Speaker 2: No stabby stabby for them.
Speaker 2: You have to use your smarts.
Speaker 2: So by doing this, by creating this natural order and saying this is how it is and these rules are immutable and unbreakable, you know, we've given shape to the universe.
Speaker 2: You know, we've planted the poles of the mouse guard world and said, like, okay, this is how they live and this is what they can deal with and this is what they can.
Speaker 2: And it just, it immediately sets players' wheels spinning.
Speaker 2: It's really, really effective.
Speaker 2: Animals in mouse guard are animals.
Speaker 2: Mice are special, right?
Speaker 2: They have their foil, right?
Speaker 2: You know, mice are special and they have their darker cousin.
Speaker 2: They have weasels, which they're not really cousins, but mostelids and rodents are two different things.
Speaker 2: I researched all this.
Speaker 2: Anyway, but so, but you basically have your, you know, you have your protagonist peoples and then you have your antagonist peoples.
Speaker 2: You have your orcs, right?
Speaker 2: Weasels are the orcs.
Speaker 2: So they're also smart, but they're smart for evil.
Speaker 2: But everything else in the mouse guard world are animals.
Speaker 2: They don't have any intelligence.
Speaker 2: They don't have any goals, any aims.
Speaker 2: They have no civilization, no society.
Speaker 2: And this creates a great sense of horror when you realize that the raccoon doesn't want to talk to you, it wants to eat you.
Speaker 2: And there's like no amount of negotiation or communication.
Speaker 2: Like, you know, a lot of players want to talk to the raccoons and you can, there's a little talk to animal skill.
Speaker 2: And that's fine because, you know, we're all animals, whatever.
Speaker 2: But the raccoons pretty much going like, I talked to David Peterson about this.
Speaker 2: He was like, I was like, all right, if Liam and the snake from fall, if they could talk, what would the snake be saying?
Speaker 2: And Dave was like, yeah, pretty much be saying, I'm going to eat you.
Speaker 2: So you're like right in the game, the animals don't have stats for negotiation or anything like that.
Speaker 2: Animals have their nature and they obey the laws of their nature period.
Speaker 2: And that's that's because they're animals.
Speaker 2: And it's great.
Speaker 2: Weasels are David Peterson's orcs, essentially, for this setting.
Speaker 2: They're the generic bad guys.
Speaker 2: But the cool thing is, is that one weasel versus one mouse.
Speaker 2: It's no contest.
Speaker 2: The weasel is a mouse killer, you know.
Speaker 2: And there there's lots of weasels, not as many weasels as mice.
Speaker 2: But there are, you know, they're a genocidal threat to all of mouse kind.
Speaker 2: And so I was OK with them as villains.
Speaker 2: I'm like, OK, these guys are kind of badass.
Speaker 2: So we did a whole like, you know, we started out just about every like weasel we could think of.
Speaker 2: So I think comes to like eight different weasels.
Speaker 2: So but they have stats and skills like mice have stats and skills.
Speaker 2: So unlike animals, animals don't have skills, stat skills.
Speaker 2: They just have nature.
Speaker 2: If I if I had my druthers, I would want gamer families to play mouse card.
Speaker 2: I want mom or dad to come home to their seven, eight, nine year old kids and be like, all right, we've been waiting.
Speaker 2: We wait for you to get old enough.
Speaker 2: We've been waiting for a game to be good enough.
Speaker 2: And here we go.
Speaker 2: You are going to be role playing gamers.
Speaker 2: That would be my ideal.
Speaker 2: As far as I've played, you know, with kids, burning wheel and mouse guard and whatnot, they've never had any trouble rocking the rules.
Speaker 2: Only people have trouble rocking the rules for mouse guard or hardcore gamers.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: We play games a lot.
Speaker 0: And the one problem with playing games a lot, like really being into gaming, is that you'll often demystify games for yourself.
Speaker 0: Like I used to be like I used to be very excited when I found glitchy parts of like Simon's Quest.
Speaker 0: Like I find a weird area and I'd be all excited and exploring it.
Speaker 0: It was this crazy thing.
Speaker 0: But now I know exactly why that happens.
Speaker 0: And it's no longer interesting to me.
Speaker 1: I remember one time I think there was a babysitter at my house and I was playing Mega Man two and I was fighting Bubble Man.
Speaker 0: Oh, I remember the Bubble Man story.
Speaker 1: And then the door that, you know, I was jumping up to shoot Bubble Man and the door opened and I went backwards and the game totally fucked up.
Speaker 1: So I went back through the door and I was in Bubble Man's room, but everything was screwed up and invisible.
Speaker 1: And I basically messed around in that room to figure out what the fuck.
Speaker 1: I thought I had found some amazing secret for like, you know, a long time.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Didn't you find like every invisible block?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It was just, you know, basically it was just a glitch.
Speaker 1: It wasn't actually some crazy secret.
Speaker 1: But, you know, it was a glitch that happened to appear like a secret, sort of like Metroid only in Metroid.
Speaker 1: The glitches become secrets because you glitch them so much that you actually get from one place in the map to another place in the map.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Of course, more often than not, you just end up somewhere unsavable and then you die.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Pretty, you know, but people who are good at doing the, you know, the secret, you know, Metroid, you know, glitch jump wall jump tricks, they can pretty much get anywhere they want.
Speaker 1: They know where all the spots are and they can like go right to the end of the game and all sorts of shit.
Speaker 1: So.
Speaker 0: But anyway, if you want to talk about demystification to the absolute extreme, right here is a website that diagrams everything you could possibly want to know, not just that.
Speaker 0: It diagrams everything about Pac-Man, the exact logic the ghosts use, exactly how they move every single thing.
Speaker 1: Well, that only applies to the original arcade Pac-Man, right?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: That doesn't apply to like Pac-Man verse or, you know, any other releases.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, we don't know.
Speaker 0: We'd have to analyze them in similar detail to find out.
Speaker 1: But he's just analyzing the original real deal arcade one, right?
Speaker 0: But this is right down to like the speed of Pac-Man and the ghosts and how it changes over time based on how many pellets you've taken.
Speaker 0: The logic the ghosts use to figure out where to go is pretty cool.
Speaker 0: And in case you were a gamer who always suspected but could never prove it.
Speaker 0: Yes, the ghosts did have different personalities.
Speaker 0: They all had completely different logic.
Speaker 0: And because it made sense that the red guy was always coming after you and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: But you can see their paths.
Speaker 0: And the cool thing is what they would always do is every second they would be calculating a spot and they're trying to get to that spot.
Speaker 0: But the spot they're trying to get to is changing all the time based on where Pac-Man is.
Speaker 0: So someone made him out of the game where you can see the dots that show where the ghosts are trying to get to.
Speaker 1: That must make it really easy to win because you just...
Speaker 0: But remember they're reacting to you in real time so you know where they're trying to get but that dot is jumping all over the place as you move.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean it still would make it a lot easier to win because you'd know like you'd be going one way and you'd realize you were going to be trapped.
Speaker 1: You know sometimes you'd be going down a hallway and like a ghost will look like he's going to hit you.
Speaker 1: So you turn around and you end up dying but actually that ghost turned a different way.
Speaker 1: You know and you could have made it if you would have gone that way.
Speaker 0: If you read this you can figure out which ghost is almost always going to turn away.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's good stuff.
Speaker 1: It is good stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah the thing is even so.
Speaker 1: you'd have to think fast.
Speaker 1: You'd have to be like orange ghost keep going or blue ghost turn around and you know that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: But it's interesting that a game that appears so simple when you play it.
Speaker 0: And a lot of times people will think it's very random because they don't understand how games work.
Speaker 0: or they're not good at them or they're a kid or something.
Speaker 0: But the game as simple as it is had a lot of really interesting emergent behavior that appeared.
Speaker 0: But if you actually analyze it fully it's all still completely 100 percent deterministic.
Speaker 1: No, well it's a computer.
Speaker 1: It can't be non-deterministic unless it's broken.
Speaker 0: Well I mean you could use random numbers to see behavior and that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Yes but the random numbers are deterministic.
Speaker 1: They're not real random numbers.
Speaker 0: Well Scott what if you used a true...
Speaker 1: Especially not in a weak ass old arcade machine.
Speaker 0: What if you used a true or semi-true random number generator like say a thermal delta switch.
Speaker 1: Well you know that's a different story.
Speaker 1: But that would create possibly... You could actually... That would be really interesting if you had a true random number generator or something like that and you used it in some sort of game.
Speaker 1: You could perhaps make a game that is unwinnable.
Speaker 0: Well it's not that hard to make a game that's unwinnable.
Speaker 0: Mario starts, there's no floor.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: I mean you know an interesting unwinnable game.
Speaker 0: So it's like that cat Mario mod game.
Speaker 1: Basically it would be a game where there is no optimal strategy because you're going against true randomness.
Speaker 1: but you know...
Speaker 0: But Scott you can effectively get true randomness.
Speaker 0: I say effectively with dice.
Speaker 0: We have that.
Speaker 1: Yeah dice are pretty random.
Speaker 0: Actually you know in World War II how they generated one-time pads in Britain for the military to use?
Speaker 0: Old ladies rolling bingo things basically.
Speaker 1: Oh bingo balls?
Speaker 1: No that's not bad.
Speaker 0: They'd roll something, pull out a number, write the number down, roll something, pull out another number, write the number down.
Speaker 1: Uh huh.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That works.
Speaker 0: So do you have a thing of the day?
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: So I was poking around looking at you know game engines right?
Speaker 1: Because you know I was talking like water is poison.
Speaker 1: We're like hey let's make like a Half-Life mod.
Speaker 1: All these punk kids do it.
Speaker 1: We can do it too right?
Speaker 1: We're professionals.
Speaker 1: And of course there's a long story behind that but that wasn't going to work out.
Speaker 1: So I started poking around and I'm like there has to be some sort of open source game engine.
Speaker 1: that's all awesome like.
Speaker 0: Well see I was about to say there are plenty but then you just said awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So every game engine out there seems to either be limited, not awesome.
Speaker 1: I mean there's zillions of them out there right?
Speaker 1: But they're either crap, limited, cost money.
Speaker 1: Pretty much all of them are flawed in some way.
Speaker 1: They're in a bad language that no one wants to use.
Speaker 1: You know?
Speaker 1: Like there's one that's actually kind of okay called Joker, J Ogre.
Speaker 1: It's a Java thing that like gives you a pretty standard.
Speaker 0: Java.
Speaker 1: Yeah it gives you a pretty standard MVC framework for you know making sort of simple multiplayer games.
Speaker 1: Like if you want to make board games like this handles like already you don't have to do any work.
Speaker 1: It does like.
Speaker 1: you know the lobbies and the joining and the whole thing and it just works.
Speaker 1: I tried it.
Speaker 1: It totally works.
Speaker 1: But the thing is you can't make anything that looks nice because it's all swing gooeys.
Speaker 1: So you'd have to basically do a whole shit ton of work to make anything that looks cool or it just looks like you know Java gooeys.
Speaker 1: But anyway in the course of that I found this thing called love right?
Speaker 0: And that.
Speaker 0: You found love.
Speaker 1: Not love as in the emotion but love as in the game engine called love.
Speaker 1: And love the game engine isn't really.
Speaker 1: it's pretty limited right?
Speaker 1: It falls into the limited category.
Speaker 1: You can't make a multiplayer game with this right?
Speaker 1: You can't make.
Speaker 1: you know a lot of you can't make like really fancy games with this.
Speaker 1: But what it is is you can make games using a language called Lua.
Speaker 1: L-U-A.
Speaker 1: And for people who don't know Lua is like this really sort of simple programming language.
Speaker 1: And a lot of like a lot of things will use it as the configuration.
Speaker 1: Like if you use lighty the web server like all the configuration files are written in Lua.
Speaker 1: So it's it's meant to be very human readable and very easy to do.
Speaker 1: And if you use love you can very easily make sort of simple 2D games.
Speaker 1: You know like.
Speaker 1: if you want to make you know something like you know just something one of those like little indie demo kind of things like something like passage.
Speaker 1: you can make passage in love.
Speaker 1: You could make what's the one with the chandelier and the.
Speaker 0: I have no idea what you're talking about.
Speaker 1: Remember the one where you drop the chandelier and the monster.
Speaker 1: It's just it's just to fight the boss.
Speaker 1: There was like the little quirky little indie game.
Speaker 0: I remember it vaguely.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But anyway you can make that.
Speaker 1: you know anything like that.
Speaker 1: you know a cute small game you can make in love really really easy.
Speaker 0: So when are we going to see the first Scott production.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: But the point is is that if you have a get an idea for some like sort of cute little 2D game you could crack you could smack that thing out in love and like you know less than a day like pretty easily depending on how you know real quick.
Speaker 1: So you know if someone wants to make like a platform game that's like you know just one screen something like line right or you could probably make you know anything along those lines.
Speaker 1: You can probably make a tower defense but it'd be it'd be a little difficult.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Tower Defense right.
Speaker 0: It seems like it had this high rise and I feel like it's a dying genre already.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean I played like the last 10 that I've seen just briefly and they were all like exactly the same if not worse.
Speaker 1: Well you know it's pretty much.
Speaker 1: they sort of try to differentiate themselves by changing superficial things without changing any fundamental things.
Speaker 0: Yeah so you shoot like a zombie or you shoot.
Speaker 1: Well it's like that.
Speaker 1: some of them are like OK you can upgrade these things with gems and another one is like OK you can combine the gems together and another one is like all right you don't actually upgrade anything you just put towers next to each other and which towers are adjacent to each other determines changes the towers themselves and they do stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Maybe I think that's part of the reason why I like the old desktop tower defense so much was that it kind of did away with scanning and theme really and it was just a tower defense.
Speaker 1: The theme was it's your desk.
Speaker 0: But none of the things made much sense in that regard.
Speaker 1: There were things you were drawing on your desk with a pencil.
Speaker 0: That was the theme?
Speaker 1: You can see it's desktop tower defense.
Speaker 1: The background is a desk.
Speaker 0: But the structures were basically just little blobs.
Speaker 1: Well that's what you're doodling.
Speaker 0: OK yeah that's kind of weak.
Speaker 1: Well that's that's the theme of desktop tower defense.
Speaker 1: it's literally desktop tower defense.
Speaker 0: But what I'm saying is that the theme was like barely there and didn't affect the game.
Speaker 1: You're talking about.
Speaker 1: the theme was incredibly strong.
Speaker 1: It's everything's drawn all pencil-y right.
Speaker 1: The background is a picture of the top of a desk.
Speaker 0: OK so it had a background.
Speaker 0: the rest it wasn't really drawn sketchily.
Speaker 0: Do I have to pull up screenshots of it again?
Speaker 1: Go look at it.
Speaker 1: You'll see it.
Speaker 1: I can't believe you didn't know this.
Speaker 1: This is like it was obvious for the moment.
Speaker 1: I first played it.
Speaker 1: The theme is very strong anyway.
Speaker 0: Alright I argue that the theme is weak but we digress.
Speaker 1: Anyway so yeah if you want to make a little tiny game you can you can get some love.
Speaker 1: It's free and open source and all that and whatnot.
Speaker 0: So for the last many years there's been this kind of FPS's event in a state.
Speaker 0: You hear us complain about FPS's all the time but just recently this gigantic monolith has been dropped amidst the Halo players.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean basically what happened is you know there were FPS's were pretty much all in software.
Speaker 1: you know is Wolfenstein, Doom, Doom, Quake, Quake, Quake, Quake right.
Speaker 1: And that was what the FPS was.
Speaker 1: And then you know other FPS's came around.
Speaker 1: You had the GoldenEye, Half-Life, and Halo were pretty much like the big three.
Speaker 1: That sort of an unreal tournament not so much.
Speaker 1: It was sort of off to the side.
Speaker 1: It was always like a second fiddle.
Speaker 1: But those three came along and sort of changed FPS's.
Speaker 1: You know Counter-Strike especially.
Speaker 1: You know it's like okay no more of the.
Speaker 1: you know deathmatch.
Speaker 1: No more of the really fast Twitch gameplay.
Speaker 1: Now we're going to have a slow game.
Speaker 1: You know it's all about being slow and crafty and it's all you got to reload your weapons.
Speaker 1: You know and it's not about Twitch.
Speaker 1: It's about which path you're taking and can you aim and all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: Well I would argue more that it's much simpler than that.
Speaker 0: It was just that consoles became the primary means of gameplay.
Speaker 1: Well that was later though.
Speaker 1: I mean I think that the old school FPS died before the console.
Speaker 1: You know because Counter-Strike was there for a few years.
Speaker 1: You know killing off Quake before Halo came along.
Speaker 0: But at the same time Counter-Strike is still pretty old school.
Speaker 0: I mean it's still a difficult awesome FPS.
Speaker 0: If you don't have the raw aiming and maneuvering FPS skills you can't play Counter-Strike.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: But I guess Counter-Strike is sort of the in between.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like you know but it's definitely not.
Speaker 1: It's not Quake.
Speaker 1: It's not the same.
Speaker 1: It's not old school.
Speaker 1: It's semi old school.
Speaker 0: I don't know it's not that.
Speaker 0: I mean the only difference between it and say like action Quake team play was that action Quake team play was well I don't know three or four times faster.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: The speed makes it.
Speaker 1: you know it's just what you think.
Speaker 1: it's just one factor the speed.
Speaker 1: But no that one factor makes like this entire world of difference.
Speaker 0: But just to simplify there was this combination of one consoles which have very weak controls compared to a PC for FPS's and two this drive toward realism and trying to make games FPS's at least very realistic and gritty.
Speaker 0: and the more realistic you make an FPS it's kind of like the difference between Soul Calibur and Bushido Blade.
Speaker 0: Bushido Blade's a lot more realistic in one regard but it makes it a completely different game as a result.
Speaker 1: Bad game.
Speaker 0: And for a long time we really wanted to bring back the old school FPS's.
Speaker 0: I mean I love natural selection and it's doing okay.
Speaker 0: I mean the community is still pretty strong.
Speaker 0: And I love tribes too but there's just no way to make the tribes 2 community come back again.
Speaker 0: It's just impossible.
Speaker 1: I mean they they're trying recently.
Speaker 1: they do it like the tribes revival or whatever but it's not.
Speaker 1: it's not coming on as strong as it needs to.
Speaker 1: And the major problem there is that tribes is a game that needs you know servers that have like 40 people on them and you know it's just a game that doesn't work unless a shit ton of people are playing it.
Speaker 1: So basically we're sitting here and we got some FPS's to play but we're missing the old school flavor and it's sort of like.
Speaker 1: you know you have this genre FPS and within the genre there are flavors.
Speaker 1: you know the slow tactical and the the military and the the team based one with vehicles right and you got all these you know sub-genres but the sub-genre of really fast twitch just fucking kill.
Speaker 1: everyone sort of died out.
Speaker 1: I mean there was Quake 4 but no one who plays Quake 4.
Speaker 0: No one plays Quake 4.
Speaker 1: No one plays Quake 4 right.
Speaker 1: So much to our surprise right Quake Live comes.
Speaker 1: you know it's been.
Speaker 1: it's been around for you know a while but the beta opened up like a week ago.
Speaker 1: I think something like that.
Speaker 1: not too long ago.
Speaker 1: the Quake Live beta opened up and I was you know I was curious.
Speaker 1: so we go in and it's like okay Quake in the web browser.
Speaker 1: what's you know?
Speaker 1: what are they?
Speaker 1: what are they going to do here.
Speaker 0: And it's not even.
Speaker 0: I mean you can't say it's a web plug.
Speaker 0: it's basically just you download Quake and then it interfaces through the web browser to like set up your game.
Speaker 1: Yeah basically instead of installing Quake as its own application it's just installs as a browser plug-in but you're still just installing Quake it's not you know?
Speaker 1: I mean you can if you want to keep the quake window inside your browser window thus making it really hard to see instead of playing full screen.
Speaker 0: Now the end result is that this is brilliant.
Speaker 0: I mean it's Quake 3. it's an old game and they brought it back in this capacity but all they've really done is solved the problem I've been having for years of.
Speaker 0: I like old school FPSs.
Speaker 0: I like difficult FPSs.
Speaker 0: I want other people to play these FPSs but those games are so inaccessible and even if they are accessible as a game on the meta perspective there's no way to get a game of it going.
Speaker 0: do you know how hard it is to like get a bunch of Halo kids to download Quake 3 install it connect to my server with an IP address and then play a deathmatch.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean people.
Speaker 1: you know you're used to playing Halo and you're used to playing games on Steam right where you have sort of easy it's.
Speaker 1: you know there's a list of servers and you just click on one and you're playing and they handle that for you.
Speaker 1: you don't realize that Quake 1, 2, 3 all those old games even Quake 3 there was no really good server match up thing.
Speaker 1: there was no list of servers.
Speaker 0: I used to have literally this text file I saved to my desktop and it listed all the.
Speaker 1: Yeah people would use things like you know GameSpy and Kali in order to you know get server lists.
Speaker 1: it was sort of like they would have separate programs to list the servers.
Speaker 1: then they would double click on one in the list and I would launch the game separately.
Speaker 0: Well if you were smart you just use the CLQ.
Speaker 1: Yes but you know you get.
Speaker 1: my point is that it wasn't easy to get a game of these things going.
Speaker 1: you know you had to find a server you had to be in the know it was and normal people couldn't do it.
Speaker 1: I mean normal people could go to the store buy Quake 3 install it and play.
Speaker 1: they get a LAN game going on pretty easily.
Speaker 1: but to play an internet game required you know effort now extra effort.
Speaker 0: For a long time up to this point there have been a lot of arguments all over the internet I won't say our forums because it's everywhere people like us who play these old FPS's.
Speaker 0: and then kids who say yeah they're not so different they're not so hard.
Speaker 0: my games are fine Halo's great and I mean those games are good games but they never really seem to understand just how difficult these old games are and how difficult it is to be good at them and not even good how difficult it is to kill a single person.
Speaker 1: How difficult it is to get a weapon even though they're lying around all over the place and how difficult it is to not get killed.
Speaker 0: Let alone how fast they go.
Speaker 0: and Quake 3 is not even the fastest.
Speaker 0: Quake 3 is slow it's just.
Speaker 0: we're never gonna get Quake 2 back.
Speaker 0: I've given up on playing like Mega TF with people again.
Speaker 0: yeah I think those games they're dinosaurs they're extinct.
Speaker 0: I admit that.
Speaker 1: When you kids go to play Quake Live and you see how fast it is right remember that that was actually when Quake 3 came out everyone who had played Quake 1 and 2 was like wow why is Quake 3 all slow?
Speaker 1: and so Quake Live is Quake 3 it's slow.
Speaker 1: Quake 1 and 2 are crazy fast like well correct speed.
Speaker 1: Quake 3 is slow but yeah.
Speaker 0: This has finally been solved because all over the internet now we have seen people Halo kids modern FPSers posting in forums and saying things to the effect of what the fuck I can't get any kills what's going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah and the thing I sort of realized you know because I haven't played you know Quake like for more than five minutes in a very long time is that you know how simple the game is compared to a lot of other FPS is.
Speaker 1: I mean not even tribes 2 or NS but say Counter Strike.
Speaker 1: right and Counter Strike you've got buy menus you've got reload you've got crouch right.
Speaker 1: you know what Quake has.
Speaker 1: it's got change weapon shoot jump move and zoom in.
Speaker 1: that's pretty much all it has.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean those are all the controls.
Speaker 1: there are a couple of items but yeah there's a use button that you that you push.
Speaker 0: maybe like once a century you don't even have to click anything to open doors doors just open.
Speaker 1: yeah there is literally like the controls are so primitive.
Speaker 1: I mean I guess oh you move the mouse to aim.
Speaker 1: of course right but that's it.
Speaker 1: that's all the controls of Quake 3. yet the game is so incredibly difficult compared to games with other controls.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 1: you can learn how to play in like a minute you know because the controls are so few but if you play against anyone who knows what they're doing at all you're just going to get killed instantly because the game is so fast and requires such reflexes and such.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: I guess this is a little bit of learning curve and learning what all the weapons do and learning what all the items do.
Speaker 1: you know like you got to know that green health lets you go above a hundred and yellow health doesn't and red armor is better than yellow armor.
Speaker 0: yeah the thing is you don't even need to know that stuff too well.
Speaker 0: you're pretty much just have to be able to move shoot and react quickly to things.
Speaker 1: yeah that'll that'll get you you know far enough to actually pick up some of these items.
Speaker 0: yeah but I mean I think like it.
Speaker 0: this made me though playing this again because I'd played Quake 3 and Quake 2 and all these games recently a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: but now that I'm playing them for real with other people on a regular basis I mean I have played Quake almost every day for the past week for like hours and I'm starting to remember all the things about all these old FPS.
Speaker 0: is that just don't happen anymore?
Speaker 0: like the?
Speaker 0: the precision required to aim is ludicrous for most kids.
Speaker 1: now I mean this is the railgun.
Speaker 1: right the railgun pretty much kills most people in one hit.
Speaker 1: if you hit them in the head yeah I mean it's it's really dangerous.
Speaker 1: I mean and the thing is most of the people you're fighting are you know it's rare that you come across someone with full health right.
Speaker 1: so if you hit them with it they're probably gonna die right and it actually goes through people.
Speaker 1: so if everyone lines up and you shoot it you can shoot it straight through them and kill like three or four people in one shot.
Speaker 1: you have to pretty much aim exactly on them you know.
Speaker 1: or it's a laser that pretty much as soon as you push the button it fires and that one spot and that's it.
Speaker 1: it's a railgun yeah and it's really really hard to hit anyone with it.
Speaker 0: if they're unless they're standing still like a doofus plus if you're playing a duel I mean these guys are moving three or four times faster than like Team Fortress and they're further away and the spaces are bigger.
Speaker 0: and if it's a full health like duel you've got to hit him in the head yeah his tiny little head.
Speaker 1: and if it's a duel right and there's less people on the map right.
Speaker 1: so if it's like a 16 player deathmatch all right everyone's running around getting shot at constantly.
Speaker 1: if it's a duel one-on-one people have time to go around and get armor and get all kinds of weapons before you bump into them.
Speaker 0: right unless you play one of the old school duel maps but none of those seem to be in here yet.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 1: so if they got time to go run around and grab all this stuff by the time you meet them you're gonna need to hit them a whole lot before they hit you a whole lot.
Speaker 0: of course you should have picked all this stuff up too.
Speaker 1: yeah but you know there's only one red arm.
Speaker 1: so if one guy gets the red you're probably only gonna get the yellow now.
Speaker 0: you can avoid him until it comes and you can grab it too.
Speaker 0: I guess you know depending on the map and such plus if you're playing one-on-one you should be playing on a duel map where that's all taken care of.
Speaker 1: yeah that's true.
Speaker 1: also you know if it's a good duel map.
Speaker 1: I haven't actually played any duels.
Speaker 1: I've been mostly playing deathmatches.
Speaker 0: yeah there's.
Speaker 0: there's just some sort of visceral fun about a death.
Speaker 0: I mean I forgot almost actually won one.
Speaker 0: it was crazy about this time in my life.
Speaker 0: I've won like 10. it's not that of course I've played more than you.
Speaker 1: I only won.
Speaker 1: I almost won one just now.
Speaker 1: I was down by like two.
Speaker 0: it's amazing.
Speaker 0: you see the skill cab difference in a game like team fortress where once you get good enough like no one can be better than you because everyone's pretty much at this equal level.
Speaker 0: but in quake you'll see someone where five minutes have gone by.
Speaker 0: they've got 40 frags the next person out of them has 39 person out of them has seven then there's a whole bunch of sevens and then everyone else has like negative two.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean you can always sort of tell if someone's really good.
Speaker 1: I mean like if there's someone on the server who's really good.
Speaker 1: right they're just gonna win because they'll get the rail gunning and hit everyone with every single shot.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: but if everyone's sort of equal I remember the game really comes down to the fight over the quad damage.
Speaker 1: because you get the quad damage then that gives you the the upper hand you know for like about 30 seconds to hose enough people down to get like five or six frags and that's what's gonna give you the win.
Speaker 0: but I'm just.
Speaker 0: I'm having such visceral simple fun from playing an FPS.
Speaker 0: we're all.
Speaker 0: it's a it's a deathmatch.
Speaker 0: deathmatch is almost gone and now it's back a straight-up deathmatch.
Speaker 1: yeah all they had to do right was they took the same exact game.
Speaker 1: they barely changed it.
Speaker 1: they sort of it's just pure quake right and they made it so that you can get at it easily.
Speaker 1: you don't need IP addresses you don't need any sort of funky user interface right.
Speaker 1: they put all the server matchups and all the you know user profiles and all the friend system and the whole thing in the web browser.
Speaker 1: and then as soon as you click you know join game it opens up and goes full screen or whatever with the plug-in and that's that's it.
Speaker 0: it's a game where you're trying to get frags and not get gibbed.
Speaker 0: yep though honestly the best thing I haven't been able to play FPS is like this for a long time but you know back in the day like playing in clans and being really like into this sort of thing and like practicing and these are FPS is where if you want to be good you've got to sit down with people and practice.
Speaker 0: let me do like shooting drill.
Speaker 1: yeah well look at a dude like fatality right that dude freaking practiced like almost all day every day.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: he like he like trained like he was an athlete.
Speaker 1: that's how.
Speaker 1: that's why he was as good as he is.
Speaker 0: but this is I mean.
Speaker 0: I used to do anything I could that was within the rules to get an edge.
Speaker 0: and back in the quake two days I always played with an FOV of 120. so in a normal FPS by default you have a field of view of 90 degrees.
Speaker 0: so you see this 90 degree chunk out from the eyes of your model and that's what you see.
Speaker 0: now you don't have any peripheral vision or anything and that's just kind of the way FPS is were.
Speaker 0: but a lot of really hardcore people in the quake two days would turn off all the textures or weaken all the textures or change the textures.
Speaker 0: everything was kind of bland.
Speaker 0: you get a higher frame rate and then they'd widen the FOV to like 110 120 130 hmm this basically if you watch someone play like that or now with quake live you can just do it and see the whole world looks like a fishbowl and it's incredibly disorienting if you're not used to it.
Speaker 0: but if you can get used to it it gives you this gigantic edge over everyone else you can see people behind you and turn and shoot them.
Speaker 0: it becomes a game of click on all the heads that are floating around the screen before they click on yours.
Speaker 1: yeah well if you've you know got a railgun I mean if you don't you can't just click on the heads.
Speaker 1: you got it.
Speaker 1: yeah you got to maybe shoot a rocket at the feet you know.
Speaker 1: maybe throw some you know lead them with the plasma rifle a bit huh.
Speaker 0: the only thing that I'm missing that I feel like I should have are my offhand grenades but I can live without that.
Speaker 1: yeah well I mean you know you can get the grenade launcher if you really want to say there's.
Speaker 0: there was something about throwing a grenade at a guy's feet shooting a rocket throwing another grenade bouncing him off of the second grenade into the rocket.
Speaker 1: yeah I think you know.
Speaker 1: I guess they could put grenades in it.
Speaker 1: but yeah I guess there were grenades in quake 3 right so why should that?
Speaker 0: I feel like they should leave it as is.
Speaker 1: I could foresee I'll bet that we that sort of gets rid of the the fact that it's this pure and simple game.
Speaker 1: you know in terms of you know the act the game itself.
Speaker 0: well what they could do?
Speaker 0: I it'd be really interesting if they open this platform up to more games than just quite three.
Speaker 0: like what if they put quite you and quick one on there?
Speaker 0: there's no reason not to.
Speaker 1: well I think this technically isn't quake 3 it's quake live.
Speaker 1: right they don't want to call it quake 3.
Speaker 0: well yeah but it's quite 3.
Speaker 1: yeah I there was an interview with Carmack and he talked about.
Speaker 1: you know stuff like.
Speaker 1: you know if there were gonna be mods on there and stuff like that and I think they were talking about like.
Speaker 1: you know if they found maps from people that were really awesome they would put them in there and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: so there's there's definitely gonna be more content in there.
Speaker 1: at the very least.
Speaker 1: you know maybe more game modes because right now they got a few game modes and then they got CTF they got clan arena.
Speaker 0: yeah but they're all the like quake 3 modes and I'll admit I don't like any of those modes.
Speaker 0: back when they came out everyone hated him.
Speaker 0: they were terrible.
Speaker 1: yeah yeah well I mean that's the thing is you know it's like they're keeping it simple right.
Speaker 1: this isn't about you know revolutionizing FPS even though I think it will in a small way because well because it's taking the pure FPS and making it accessible to the masses.
Speaker 0: they took an FPS that I played in high school and just re-released it without doing much to it and it's already really popular.
Speaker 0: it's in beta and it's in many ways it feels fresher than a lot of new FPS is because it's so different from most games that people play today even though it's a game from when I was in high school.
Speaker 0: I know right I bought quake 3 when I was in high school.
Speaker 1: I mean you could do the same thing.
Speaker 1: I mean think about right if you want to look for originality in video games right the old PC games is where you know there were no genres in those olden days.
Speaker 1: you know things like.
Speaker 1: you know mule and Starcraft and you know all these sorts of things totally defy genre completely like there's.
Speaker 1: no those are the only games like those.
Speaker 1: that's it right.
Speaker 1: so if you get games like those from the early PC days and bring them back it's totally you know.
Speaker 1: it's.
Speaker 1: it's super fresh because this.
Speaker 1: you haven't played anything like that since the olden days and it's the same you know even though FPS is as a whole are not fresh right this style of FPS is fresh.
Speaker 1: I mean I could come out with like a Wolfenstein like game today right which is an FPS that primarily concentrates on you know mazes and secrets and that sort of thing as opposed to you know and down plays the shooting element and it would be totally fresh if you like that sort of thing you know.
Speaker 0: so maybe we should get the forum together and play some games.
Speaker 0: find one of those empty servers on there.
Speaker 1: well you know the.
Speaker 1: it's got a friend system right.
Speaker 1: so just find out.
Speaker 1: you know who everyone else's name is.
Speaker 0: my name is rim.
Speaker 1: yeah you can guess what my name is.
Speaker 1: and then you know add people to your friends list.
Speaker 1: it's pretty easy.
Speaker 1: and then when you're online fight look in their friends for you know who's playing.
Speaker 1: enjoy.
Speaker 1: now the thing is is a skill matching system and the skill matching system is pretty good.
Speaker 1: you know it's not like super perfect but it's in the beginning.
Speaker 0: it pretty much puts you in and says like get as far as you can get and then enter the and it doesn't even tell you anything.
Speaker 1: it's just like get as far as you can get in this room and then it when you can't get any further go in the door.
Speaker 0: it's great cuz.
Speaker 0: first is like you know jump over this thing and then rocket jump over this thing and then bunny hop.
Speaker 0: now bunny hopping again is something that has been like it's been taken out of.
Speaker 0: a lot of FPS is and all that kind of jumping fiddly almost glitchy stuff was taken out of.
Speaker 0: modern FPS is for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 0: but you know in quake one it was clearly a glitch but people used it was part of the game.
Speaker 0: quake two it was less of a glitch but it was still there.
Speaker 0: quake three they coded it in because they knew people wanted it.
Speaker 0: it was there on purpose.
Speaker 0: yep that think.
Speaker 0: think about how much the culture of FPS thing has changed from the glitch that was popular is coded into the game to the sterile ultra realistic games we have today.
Speaker 1: yeah I did the rocket jump.
Speaker 1: I didn't I couldn't I didn't do the be hop.
Speaker 0: well the thing is I think to fully do the be hop you got to start with a rocket.
Speaker 1: yeah I try to do the Rockets right and what happened was is I actually ran out of rocket and then I also kill.
Speaker 1: you know you're invincible so you couldn't kill yourself but you know I just ran out of rockets and I said fuck it and I went in the door.
Speaker 1: so yeah.
Speaker 1: and then you sort of fight this bot and I guess they sort of gauge how well you do against the bot.
Speaker 1: you know based on the bots difficulty which I think also changes a lot of people can't beat the bot.
Speaker 1: yeah it's it's weird that people didn't beat the bot.
Speaker 1: I mean like.
Speaker 1: I started fighting the bot and it killed me a little bit and I was like oh crap.
Speaker 1: and then I came back and beat it.
Speaker 1: but it was weird that people were like yeah the bot kicked my ass and I was like oh that's that's too bad.
Speaker 0: but pretty much anyone out there if you have a Windows PC quake 3 came out when I was in high school.
Speaker 0: you can probably run quake 3.
Speaker 1: you can definitely run quake 3. you could probably run this on a netbook most.
Speaker 1: so if it has any sort of 3d at all like an integrated cheap ass you know graphics chip an Intel even an Intel integrated thing will play quake 3.
Speaker 0: there is absolutely no reason not to download quake live and play it.
Speaker 0: at least try even if you don't like FPS is or even if you don't like this kind of twitchy deathmatch gibbon FPS.
Speaker 0: you should play it at least once to to see where we're coming from.
Speaker 0: this is this game is like the midpoint between my perfect FPS and a modern Halo FPS mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: and I'm just.
Speaker 1: I'm just glad that you know there is a type of game that was that was lost and now is found.
Speaker 1: and you know people can.
Speaker 1: actually you know when when I say oh man you don't know old-school FPS is I can't say oh well yeah you're not actually gonna be able to play any of them.
Speaker 1: to find out.
Speaker 1: now I can say here you can at least go play quake live and then you'll know what I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: yeah because nothing was worse than nah man quick - was so much better.
Speaker 0: yeah well how do I play it all right?
Speaker 0: well first you got a pirate a copy of quake - I already got that.
Speaker 1: no it's open source.
Speaker 1: but even so you got a pirate that the now the data file.
Speaker 0: now edit this text file.
Speaker 1: yeah it's like already.
Speaker 1: they're not gonna do it you know you know even if you did it for them it they think you know when they I want to configure their controls.
Speaker 1: and there were controls that configure that weren't in the control configuration menu.
Speaker 1: yeah that'd be the end of it.
Speaker 1: so but now you know it's accessible and it's gonna be eventually out on the Mac.
Speaker 1: and you know the Linux supposedly and it's it people everywhere are gonna be able to play quick together and happy times.
Speaker 0: this has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays we have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: you can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: if you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.