Speaker 0: Hey, it's Monday, June 1st, I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Sky.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights Tonight.
Speaker 1: Documentation... Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So the other day, I slipped out of work for a long lunch.
Speaker 0: Now, I often take a short lunch, but I decided time for a long lunch.
Speaker 0: So I walk over to Bryant Park, and I get myself a baguette of some kind.
Speaker 1: Bryant Park, where most people are not eating lunch, they're working.
Speaker 0: Ah, Bryant Park.
Speaker 0: You know, it's true.
Speaker 0: I mean, I go to Bryant Park, and there's just people with laptops, like half of them from my office.
Speaker 1: Right, there are many parks in New York City, right?
Speaker 1: But Bryant Park has, A, an incredible abundance of chairs and tables.
Speaker 0: It is on 42nd Street, well, near 42nd Street, at Midtown.
Speaker 1: It's near a whole bunch of office buildings, and Google has covered the whole thing in Wi-Fi that is free and easily accessible without any bullshit.
Speaker 0: That Wi-Fi is so overloaded, I use my Verizon card when I'm there.
Speaker 1: I know, right?
Speaker 1: But, as a result of the excessive number of tables and chairs, and also the Google Wi-Fi, a lot of people just go work there.
Speaker 1: Freelancers, people who just want to get out of the office, tons of people.
Speaker 0: If I lived in Manhattan,
Speaker 1: old guys who play chess,
Speaker 0: if I lived in Manhattan, and I were a gigger, or a freelancer, or worked for myself,
Speaker 1: or even if you're just a telecommuter who also lived in the city,
Speaker 0: Bryant Park would be my office nine months out of the year.
Speaker 1: Well, it does get cold.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't.
Speaker 0: Woman.
Speaker 0: Never gets cold.
Speaker 0: It gets cold.
Speaker 0: It'll never get cold again.
Speaker 1: The thing is, once it's cold, they build an ice rink there, so you know to stop working.
Speaker 0: But then I can ice skate.
Speaker 1: Yes, but you will not get any monies.
Speaker 0: I made a critical mistake.
Speaker 0: I walked out, and I didn't bring any entertainment with me like I usually do.
Speaker 0: I just forgot my bag, so I didn't have my idea.
Speaker 1: Well, you could buy some entertainment very easily.
Speaker 0: Well, no, I decided- I decided to just sit there and enjoy my lunch and think.
Speaker 1: Uh-oh.
Speaker 0: And, of course, because I'm unoccupied by- Wait, you don't have an iPod or a laptop.
Speaker 0: I'm just sitting there in a comfortable chair, staring out over the park going, "Ahh," and eating my hummus and ham baguette.
Speaker 1: That means that if there are people's about, they can see that you do not have headphones, which means you can hear what they are saying.
Speaker 0: These two kids, they were like 19, made a beeline for me.
Speaker 0: I can see them from across the park.
Speaker 1: Oh, shit.
Speaker 0: And they're walking directly at me and talking to each other and kind of looking at me.
Speaker 0: It's like, "All right, what's this?
Speaker 0: Are these listeners?
Speaker 0: Do they recognize me?
Speaker 0: Am I about to get mugged?
Speaker 0: What's going
Speaker 0: on?".
Speaker 1: This trouble's brewing.
Speaker 0: And they come up, and they're real, real friendly.
Speaker 0: And right about now is when my missionary alert goes off.
Speaker 1: "Anyone who's too friendly must be
Speaker 1: religious.".
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: That has never been not the case with the possible exception of some mentally not-so-there people who are friendly for other reasons.
Speaker 0: I've had that situation.
Speaker 0: "Join me.
Speaker 1: We will start a new
Speaker 1: kingdom.".
Speaker 0: "I, too, have lost a
Speaker 0: kingdom.".
Speaker 1: It's actually, it's sort of scary.
Speaker 1: Just in general, anyone who's too friendly, it's usually bad news.
Speaker 1: When I was in summer camp, when I was a counselor, they had this sort of mandatory training where they taught you, because pedophiles like to become summer camp counselors, right?
Speaker 1: So they trained all the counselors.
Speaker 1: They basically said, "This is how to identify a pedophile," short of actually seeing them being a pedophile, right?
Speaker 1: And they said, "Watch out for people who are scarily
Speaker 1: friendly.".
Speaker 0: Well, "scarily" is the point, because I've noticed.
Speaker 1: They also said that if you are a pedophile, just leave now, and we won't say anything.
Speaker 1: Just get up and go.
Speaker 1: Not at the meeting, but you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Joey Jojo doesn't show up to the next meeting after that.
Speaker 1: Well, no, it's just, they said, "After this meeting, just leave camp, and we won't, that'll be
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: And no one left.
Speaker 0: Is it that much of a problem?
Speaker 1: It's a significant thing.
Speaker 1: I think that's sort of law, actually, that makes it mandatory at all the summer camps.
Speaker 0: What, mandatory pedophiles?
Speaker 1: No, mandatory pedophile avoidance training.
Speaker 0: But "scarily" is the key, because some people are just really friendly, and those people never set off any alarms for me.
Speaker 0: But there are people who are friendly in the uncanny valley of friendliness.
Speaker 0: It is either too far beyond what is reasonable for friendly, or just short of actually friendly.
Speaker 0: And these people reeked of that, the "too far," to a frightening degree.
Speaker 0: And they're being really friendly, and they're like, "Hey, so what are you up
Speaker 0: to?".
Speaker 0: I was like, "I'm sitting here enjoying my baguette.
Speaker 0: I'm being real friendly, too.
Speaker 0: I've got the smile that... You've seen this smile
Speaker 0: before.".
Speaker 1: "I did not bring entertainment!
Speaker 1: Look!
Speaker 1: Lo, there must be a God!
Speaker 1: He has brought entertainment unto
Speaker 1: me!".
Speaker 0: This was the smile of that guy at the anime con who was arguing with the crazy Jesus guy outside of anime Boston.
Speaker 1: That guy at the anime con wasn't smiling.
Speaker 1: I think he was a stupid teenager who still thought that he was gonna, you know...
Speaker 0: I don't know, when he walked up, he had the smile.
Speaker 0: It's hard to say.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: The smile might have gone away, I don't know.
Speaker 0: So I'm humoring them.
Speaker 0: I'm enjoying this conversation.
Speaker 0: They haven't brought up religion yet.
Speaker 0: At all.
Speaker 0: For like five minutes, no religion.
Speaker 0: But I know it's coming.
Speaker 0: I'm so sure it's coming.
Speaker 0: And then they're like, "Yeah, so we're new to the city.
Speaker 0: We're
Speaker 0: missionaries.".
Speaker 0: And we're conducting... Really?
Speaker 1: I'm on a mission, too.
Speaker 1: To Mars.
Speaker 0: We're conducting a survey.
Speaker 0: We're just trying to ask people about their lives and about what they're up to to kind of get a feel for New York.
Speaker 0: You know, we're not from around here.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: I haven't noticed.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, "Oh, where are you
Speaker 0: from?".
Speaker 1: You're friendly.
Speaker 0: I just engaged them straight up because I got about 48 minutes to kill.
Speaker 1: Oh, shit.
Speaker 1: That's a lot of time to fuck them up.
Speaker 0: I was willing to entertain anything they had to say for the next 48 minutes, and they were not going to get away from me politely.
Speaker 0: And they're like, "Oh, I'm from
Speaker 0: Michigan."
Speaker 0: And, "Oh, I know
Speaker 0: Michigan.".
Speaker 0: And I had a lot of anecdotes back and forth, and I kept them talking for a while.
Speaker 0: And then their first question is like, "So how do you feel about our mission that we should all be one family under God with no prejudice against anyone and everyone's just cool with
Speaker 0: everyone?".
Speaker 0: And I was like, "I'm for all of that, but there's no
Speaker 0: God.".
Speaker 0: And the guy's like, "Oh, really?
Speaker 0: Well, how did you come to that?
Speaker 0: Like, why do you believe that there's no
Speaker 0: God?".
Speaker 0: And I was like, "You know what?
Speaker 0: To be honest, for the last 8,000 years of human history, there's never been a single recorded instance of anything supernatural of any kind in any capacity
Speaker 0: ever.".
Speaker 0: And then I started explaining the James Randi Foundation.
Speaker 0: And at this point I realized that one of these people is the seasoned missionary who is training the other one how to do this.
Speaker 0: And the one who was being trained was fucked because everything I said, I would get him to agree with it because logic always wins.
Speaker 0: So at one point I was like, "How do you feel about
Speaker 0: homosexuals?".
Speaker 0: And he's like, "Well, they're people too.
Speaker 0: And while I don't agree with what they do, they should be
Speaker 0: afraid.".
Speaker 0: He's really backpedaling here.
Speaker 0: But in the end, I pushed him into agreeing that they should have equal rights.
Speaker 0: So then I'm like, "So how about the right to
Speaker 0: marry?".
Speaker 0: And he's like, "Well...".
Speaker 0: And I'm like, "Because you really can't deny that and still say that it's equal and still say...".
Speaker 0: And he basically, after a lot of hemming and hawing, is like, "You know what?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're right.
Speaker 0: We really should let him get married.
Speaker 0: We can't really justifiably...".
Speaker 0: And that's when the other guy interrupts him.
Speaker 0: He's like, "Uh, we got to
Speaker 0: go.".
Speaker 0: And he just wraps this up and drags the kid away.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I opened someone's mind, but it was somewhat hilarious.
Speaker 0: And then I had another half hour to eat because they left.
Speaker 1: I wanted him to stay.
Speaker 0: I wanted to convince both of them.
Speaker 0: I wanted to talk to them.
Speaker 1: Well, that proves that, A, there was a God, and he was coming to check on you.
Speaker 1: And he found out, right?
Speaker 1: He was giving you a chance.
Speaker 1: He gave you some entertainment, but then he found out that you were still against him.
Speaker 1: So he took your entertainment away.
Speaker 0: Luckily, a chipmunk came out.
Speaker 0: I was good for the rest of lunch.
Speaker 1: It was a chipmunk in Bryant Park, really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a lot of chipmunks in Bryant Park.
Speaker 1: Wow, where do they live?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: They come and they run around and kids feed them.
Speaker 1: Uh, the pigeons don't, uh, dominate?
Speaker 0: Chipmunks are faster than pigeons.
Speaker 1: I don't know, but a chicken can peck the chipmunk in the... Chicken?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I had a tiny, quick experience on the train this morning.
Speaker 1: I'm sitting in one of the four-seaters, and in the four-seater across from me is a fat lady.
Speaker 1: Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Speaker 0: Now, much like how my "these people are missionaries" sense went off, was this person in...
Speaker 1: I didn't even notice them, right?
Speaker 1: Some guy basically comes, some guy walks up and he starts, like, he looks at me and he asks me something, and I got my etymotics in, so I'm just like, "Uhhh," you know, sleeping.
Speaker 1: But then he, like, he asks the fat lady something, so I'm looking at him because suddenly there's something to pay attention to, right?
Speaker 1: And I pull one of the headphones out and he's like, "Something, something, beeping something, something,".
Speaker 1: and I see that one of the fat ladies has a cell phone, and I sort of figured out pretty quickly.
Speaker 1: she was playing a video game on her cell phone that was making lots of beeping noises, and she wasn't turning the sound off.
Speaker 1: So then another guy, right, this guy goes to sit down.
Speaker 1: Someone else comes up and asks her to, like, you know, "Hey, turn it off," right?
Speaker 1: "Indignancy!
Speaker 1: Activate!".
Speaker 1: And the indignancy passed, the indignancy of the fat lady playing the video game passed to the other fat lady, so it's like they double activated the indignancy.
Speaker 0: Wait, so the person who wasn't playing the game was indignant?
Speaker 0: now?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: Were they friends?
Speaker 1: No, she just, you know, she got indignant and she just started talking and talking and talking in indignant talk while everyone else is sitting, right?
Speaker 1: And she eventually activated, she just activated the indignant talk in the other fat lady after a time.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: Maybe there must be some sort of API for this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the conductor eventually came and he's like, "What's the
Speaker 1: problem?".
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I gotta say, this is why I love New York and why I love Metro North, because if someone is annoying on the train, the conductor will come and make them shut the fuck up.
Speaker 1: And the conductor, he was basically just like, "Fuck this shit," and he just left.
Speaker 1: He's like, "I don't give a fuck
Speaker 1: this.".
Speaker 1: Luckily, the original indignant lady got off a Croton Harmon.
Speaker 1: Oh.
Speaker 1: The other indignant lady remained indignant for maybe a minute or two and just talked to herself indignantly.
Speaker 0: What do you say?
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is, I know exactly what they said.
Speaker 1: I don't know what they said because I had my etymotics and all I heard was...
Speaker 0: Well, first they'll huff.
Speaker 0: They'll be like... And then they'll be like, "I don't know why you people are so rude.
Speaker 0: Why do people have to be so rude?
Speaker 1: Why can't people just think
Speaker 1: up?".
Speaker 1: And then they shut up for the rest of the ride.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: I've noticed a trend lately, though.
Speaker 0: A lot of people, if I take a later train home...
Speaker 1: I wanted to see someone try to hit the conductor and go to jail for seven years.
Speaker 0: I've seen people get close.
Speaker 1: Over a cell phone video game.
Speaker 0: This old, old guy, when I used to take the train from the Bronx...
Speaker 1: Man, that's a death sentence for an old guy.
Speaker 0: This guy was like 90, and he had a cane, and he's sitting there, and the conductor is like, "You gotta pay more.
Speaker 0: The senior citizen's discount doesn't count on peak trains through rush
Speaker 0: hour.".
Speaker 1: "That's right, old man.
Speaker 1: Pay the full
Speaker 1: price.".
Speaker 0: And the old man's like, "I'm not paying, and you can't make
Speaker 0: me.".
Speaker 0: And the conductor's like, "I'll call the
Speaker 0: police.".
Speaker 1: "You're going to
Speaker 1: jail.".
Speaker 0: And the guy raises his cane, and the conductor just says, "Go for
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 1: He said, "Go for
Speaker 1: it?".
Speaker 0: He said, "Go for
Speaker 0: it.".
Speaker 1: "All right!
Speaker 1: Yeah!".
Speaker 1: "That's awesome.
Speaker 1: Go for
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 0: That's second only to, "And they're
Speaker 0: off.".
Speaker 1: "Okay.".
Speaker 0: So, it's Monday.
Speaker 0: It's Tech Day.
Speaker 0: Welcome to all you new people from anime Boston.
Speaker 0: I'm sure some of you accidentally listened to this show.
Speaker 1: By the way, I'm going to say this.
Speaker 1: On this weekend, Saturday and Sunday, June 1, 2, 3, 5, and
Speaker 1: 6? 4, 5, 6. 5
Speaker 1: and 6.
Speaker 1: MOCA Arts Festival, New York City, something or other armory.
Speaker 1: It moved.
Speaker 1: It's not in the Puck Building anymore.
Speaker 0: We'll link to it again.
Speaker 0: We'll probably be there Saturday.
Speaker 1: If you go to Google and you search for MOCA Arts Festival, you will find it.
Speaker 0: We will probably be there Saturday.
Speaker 0: We have stuff going on that weekend.
Speaker 0: If that fails, we'll be there Sunday no matter what.
Speaker 1: What are we going on this weekend?
Speaker 0: A bunch of people might be coming over and then going to the MOCA with us.
Speaker 1: That's Saturday then.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: Really, it's two days, Saturday and Sunday.
Speaker 1: You only need to go one day.
Speaker 1: There's so few panels that unless you really want to go to a panel one day and a panel the other day, there's not much of a reason to go both days.
Speaker 0: Well, my plan though is I was thinking I want to do karaoke with the group, but I also want to go see the World of Darkness before they shut it down.
Speaker 0: Which is already closed.
Speaker 1: It's been apparently, they didn't even give you a lead.
Speaker 1: They were just like, yes, closing closed.
Speaker 0: Ah, ah, ah.
Speaker 1: Plus, you wouldn't have time to see the World of Darkness and do the MOCA in one day.
Speaker 0: I would.
Speaker 1: Unless you went to like way early.
Speaker 1: Depends what time the MOCA opens because the MOCA opens.
Speaker 1: You could go to it early enough, then go to the World of Darkness.
Speaker 1: And depending on when the zoo closes, stay late.
Speaker 0: But it doesn't matter when you go to the MOCA because I never go to panels.
Speaker 0: I just walk to every single table and look at every single thing.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: And then I leave.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And if someone cool like Jason is there, I stand in line to giggle like a schoolgirl while he draws something for me.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 0: That was basically what we did.
Speaker 0: So I had the microphone on.
Speaker 1: It's just like a million tech news is, but we're not doing a tech news round up.
Speaker 1: So we had to choose just to talk about Bing.
Speaker 1: No, not OK.
Speaker 1: Ready here real quick.
Speaker 1: Bing is a Google clone and it's not significantly better than Google.
Speaker 1: So it has no use.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: If people are going to use it for a little bit because it's new and it's in the news, then they're going to forget about it.
Speaker 0: The only thing I want to say right now is AOL Time Warner finally.
Speaker 0: And well, I actually want to talk about the Palm trees.
Speaker 1: OK, it's the real news.
Speaker 1: Google way.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So I was at work.
Speaker 0: You know, we were all at work when the news of disappeared.
Speaker 0: And I saw the Slashdot article and I was like, all right, Google wave.
Speaker 0: That's probably something stupid I don't care about.
Speaker 0: And like an hour later, I you know, I have some time before I go to lunch.
Speaker 0: I click on the article and then I click on the thing and I start watching the video and suddenly it's like, wait a minute.
Speaker 0: What is this?
Speaker 0: So I go back and actually read what it is.
Speaker 1: So Google Wave, basically, I am really you know, I usually am so the cynical say that's going to be poop.
Speaker 1: I ain't going to do shit.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Google Wave, I think, is going to change everything.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the main reason why it unlike other things that have high potential that never reach it.
Speaker 0: This is something that has potential that I alone can force it to reach even if no one else does.
Speaker 0: This is make it reach that potential for me.
Speaker 1: So I have, you know, I have a vision.
Speaker 1: You have a vision, a vision.
Speaker 0: We haven't had a vision in over a year.
Speaker 1: Here's my vision.
Speaker 1: So right now, the way the Internet and the Web's work right is where you put things up and they sort of stay there and then people get them.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But I think it's going to happen with the wave.
Speaker 1: Is everyone is going to like make this like stream of shit like it's all these faucets.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So it's like basically it's the Web, but with kinetic energy, everything is moving all the time, you know, and then you'll sort of everyone will also be sort of in addition to, you know, spitting out materials constantly, you know, streaming such there will also be many, many ways of filtering and funneling and sifting said, you know, you know, waterfalls into, you know, different streams for the viewing.
Speaker 1: And I think that is where we are headed from where we are now.
Speaker 1: So it's going to be like, you know, like Twitter.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's just one hundred and forty characters of text.
Speaker 1: Think like Twitter times a billion and also not just text, also video and everything in the world.
Speaker 1: Well, audio and pictures and everything.
Speaker 0: There's so much potential.
Speaker 0: And like, if nothing else, like I could see using this for collaboration on like role playing games, geek nights, collaboration, us planning episodes.
Speaker 0: I could even see sharing a wave if we were doing teleconferencing.
Speaker 0: Say we do like three different people do a geek nights episode and we share a wave while we're doing it.
Speaker 1: Imagine if there was like that.
Speaker 1: somehow integrate like the wave and some Skype or maybe some go to meeting or maybe some WebEx.
Speaker 0: This is the end of WebEx.
Speaker 0: If I get this thing going the way I expect, I can get it going.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, I can just keep thinking of I think what's going to happen.
Speaker 1: also right is that people a lot of there are a lot of protocols out there.
Speaker 1: Twitter API, XMPP, Jabber, email, you know, YouTube, right.
Speaker 1: A lot of these protocols underlying things.
Speaker 1: I think a lot of existing applications are going to be able to use wave as the back end protocol.
Speaker 1: And as a result, it's going to, you know, sort of achieve what XMPP was supposed to achieve.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's just not enough.
Speaker 1: people are using it.
Speaker 1: Like imagine, you know, it's I am you can have an IM client.
Speaker 1: It works exactly like every other IM client does today.
Speaker 1: You don't even notice.
Speaker 1: But instead of all the messages going over XMPP or AOL or whatever, they're going through some wave somewhere, you know, and that, you know, from your point of view, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: You're just using your IM client.
Speaker 1: But because it's wave powered, all this shit is going on in the back and it's totally awesome and apply that to like anything and everything.
Speaker 0: It allows this kind of constant sideband communication that is so much more full feature than anything we have now.
Speaker 1: It's it I'm going to like.
Speaker 1: totally make so many JPEGs for wave things.
Speaker 1: You have no idea.
Speaker 0: We didn't even tell that story.
Speaker 0: We should say we're going to save that story to save that.
Speaker 0: But there's always it to say you can you can solve any problem with a JPEG.
Speaker 1: But I want to reiterate, actually, the tweet this weekend was like the best tweet I think possibly ever.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, really listen to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They talk about the wave.
Speaker 1: They talk about the wave.
Speaker 1: Some hey, by the way, one thing that they pointed out that I thought was like the most insightful thing.
Speaker 1: It's sort of something, you know, but you don't know it until someone says it right is you?
Speaker 1: look look at right now.
Speaker 1: I got the Bing we just talked about.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: What does Microsoft do?
Speaker 1: They make being a product for you to use.
Speaker 1: What is Google?
Speaker 1: They make a platform upon for which you to build.
Speaker 0: That was quite a sentence.
Speaker 1: I know, wasn't it?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So and look right.
Speaker 1: I mean, the wave is made by the Google Maps guys.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Perhaps Google's second most successful, third most successful thing after search and Gmail.
Speaker 0: I was about to say Gmail.
Speaker 1: It's of course, they're actually maps is sort of equal to Gmail.
Speaker 1: Maybe it even beats it.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But well, the thing is, the only reason I don't rank Google Maps as high as it could be is that it still doesn't have good driving directions compared to MapQuest.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: But the actual rest of it is perfect.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: I use the Google Maps guys.
Speaker 1: They made they made the wave and they talked about how the best time in their lives was like an 05 when everyone was making Google Maps mashups.
Speaker 1: So now they're just.
Speaker 1: they're going to be so thrilled that everyone's making the wave mashups.
Speaker 1: It's going to be like the new best time in their lives.
Speaker 1: One other thing I want to say, I think it's kind of scary.
Speaker 1: They called it the wave because not only is wave a good metaphor.
Speaker 0: It's also the name of a great movie.
Speaker 1: It's also the movie.
Speaker 0: I was going to make a which is very relevant.
Speaker 0: I can't believe you beat me to the wave joke.
Speaker 1: It's obvious.
Speaker 0: Maybe I should use the book for that as the book club.
Speaker 1: I didn't know there was a book for that.
Speaker 1: It was based on their TV movie.
Speaker 0: That was that's the movie you're thinking of.
Speaker 1: But I think I went on IMDB looking for it, actually.
Speaker 0: And they remade it in 2008.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: What the fuck's up with that?
Speaker 0: I didn't watch it.
Speaker 0: Let's let's look out the remake.
Speaker 0: I'm curious what the deal is with that.
Speaker 1: I will have to do some more research on the wave, but watch out.
Speaker 1: Watch out for the wave.
Speaker 1: It's going to blow you over.
Speaker 1: You'll drown if you don't swim.
Speaker 1: Maybe get a surfboard.
Speaker 1: I'm getting a surfboard in advance.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm doing.
Speaker 0: So speaking of surfboards, the Palm Pre, which we talked about.
Speaker 0: how this is?
Speaker 0: this is make or break for spring.
Speaker 0: This is make or break for Paul.
Speaker 1: Actually, Verizon made a dick move.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Basically, they're exclusive to Sprint for six months.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So Verizon is pretty much like, yeah, we have that shit in six months.
Speaker 1: Basically, in January, you know, there's going to be a Verizon Pre.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: Guaranteed.
Speaker 1: So it's sort of like this dick move because like, sure.
Speaker 1: OK, dick over Sprint.
Speaker 1: I don't really care.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But basically, Palm just needs to sell as many pre's as they can.
Speaker 1: See, at the same time, people are holding out until January.
Speaker 1: That's going to hurt Palm big time.
Speaker 0: At the same time, if they if they do it this way, here's my guess.
Speaker 0: Paul.
Speaker 0: Paul might be brilliant.
Speaker 0: They might have let Sprint pay out of its asshole for the rights to the six month exclusive.
Speaker 0: And simultaneously, they didn't make that many.
Speaker 0: And they pushed the schedule and just, you know, they put it as early as they could.
Speaker 0: And they only made enough.
Speaker 1: Palm wants to sell as many as they can.
Speaker 1: They don't care who the fucking carrier.
Speaker 0: But here's the thing.
Speaker 0: You only make enough now so you can have the release early.
Speaker 0: But when you're actually going to have enough to sell is six months later and you now get to release hypes at six month intervals.
Speaker 0: Maybe so it'll get the hype when it comes out the height.
Speaker 1: The second hype will probably just be when there's a big software update that makes significant change.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is, the second hype could be the Verizon hype.
Speaker 1: if because remember, they're time the firmware update with the Verizon release, that would be big.
Speaker 0: They're leaving out one feature that they could.
Speaker 0: They have probably already got this feature and they're leaving it out only to add it at the six month interval.
Speaker 0: This is my totally, you know, pulling out of nowhere guess.
Speaker 0: Visual voicemail is not part of the initial release.
Speaker 1: Oh, they're going to add that in.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: But that's not.
Speaker 1: that's not a huge deal, though.
Speaker 1: That's not.
Speaker 1: it's not like a game changer.
Speaker 1: It's it's cool, but it's not a game changer for me.
Speaker 0: It is like visual voicemail is something that's pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: Because I don't listen to my voicemail ever.
Speaker 1: I know, right.
Speaker 1: Like I hate I love the visual voicemail.
Speaker 1: I'm not knocking it, but it's like, you know, it's not.
Speaker 1: No, but it's big, but it's not super big.
Speaker 0: If I were Palm, I would have done this and I would I would release the firmware update for a visual voicemail the same day that it is available for Verizon.
Speaker 1: It's a good idea.
Speaker 1: Maybe two days before I say, hey, you got to have some other features in that firmware update, though, to get the big hype.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's got to be features that no one else has.
Speaker 0: But there is a lot of new.
Speaker 0: I mean, normally I would talk about the pre after.
Speaker 0: And the only reason I care is that I didn't buy the Android or the iPhone.
Speaker 0: This is this is the third one.
Speaker 0: If I don't buy this one, I'm going to have to buy one of the other two because I need a smartphone.
Speaker 0: It is I can't go any longer without a smartphone.
Speaker 0: I need it now.
Speaker 1: You're not going to continue your plan of waiting for the perfect thing.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: I might still wait, but the pre is almost there because the news that came out a little while ago is that supposedly it will synchronize with iTunes and not just synchronize because you can use other MP3 players with iTunes.
Speaker 0: Supposedly, I will be able to synchronize it with iTunes as though it were an iPod with all the features.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it'll have all the features, because, see, the thing is, yeah, it might not have one.
Speaker 0: It won't have the old DRM.
Speaker 1: That's for sure.
Speaker 0: I don't care about that.
Speaker 1: No, who cares?
Speaker 0: And it might not have the play pause play again between all my devices.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: But it might, because supposedly the story is they got old Apple engineers.
Speaker 1: Well, I'll tell you what, the guy who the guy who made it was in charge of the pre was the guy who pretty much, quote, invented the iPod.
Speaker 1: He was like that the hardware lead at Apple.
Speaker 0: But Paul basically came out and said, yeah, we pretty much reverse engineered it.
Speaker 0: And as far as anyone can tell, it pretends to be like a generation four iPod in all respect.
Speaker 1: Let me steal from another podcast.
Speaker 1: I'll steal from the GDGT podcast this time, which I also listen to today.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Basically, what's going to happen here is Palm stole all these Apple people.
Speaker 1: They come out with this phone that synchronizes with iTunes.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So obviously there's some sort of legal thing going on here, right?
Speaker 0: Well, here's well, two things.
Speaker 0: My reading of this is that one palm probably has a patent portfolio, the likes of which Apple also has a patent portfolio.
Speaker 0: Two companies have equally deadly patent portfolios.
Speaker 0: The only thing that comes out of that is an automatic license.
Speaker 1: Here's the thinking that the GDGT guys came up with a second thinking.
Speaker 1: Their thinking is that Apple's like, we're going to get you.
Speaker 1: And Palm is like, bring it.
Speaker 1: Because what's going to happen, right, is if Apple brings it, Palm is going to be like, you know, oh, look, you know, they're afraid of competition.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They got to bring us down with the law because they can't beat us by making something better.
Speaker 1: And it's going to be a big.
Speaker 1: it's going to be a big searing bond.
Speaker 0: If Palm were if Palm and Sprint were really brilliant, like and there's no way this is true.
Speaker 0: This is my.
Speaker 0: if I were them, what I would have done is set this up to fail.
Speaker 0: And as soon as Apple goes after me and I'd even make it to where Apple can trivially go after me, what I would do is then say, all right, have a big press release.
Speaker 0: Be like, look, Apple won't let us sing to the iTunes store.
Speaker 1: Like what Amazon did to the book people?
Speaker 0: Well, I would say here is our store and anyone can sell on it and set any prices they want.
Speaker 0: And I would I mean, there are all the details.
Speaker 1: That's a little bit out there.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is, you wouldn't.
Speaker 1: And it's not see what it is, really.
Speaker 1: It's not about the store, really.
Speaker 1: What it is, is that people manage their media.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Mostly with iTunes is the most popular one.
Speaker 1: And the problem with selling anyone a new portable music device like a Zune or something is that it's a pain in the ass to switch what desktop program using to manage your media library.
Speaker 1: So allowing people to continue to use iTunes to manage their media library is a huge boost.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's just the difficulty of switching to something else is what keeps a lot of people from switching away from iPod, partially myself included.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I mean, there's more here.
Speaker 0: I don't think Apple is going to go after him in the end.
Speaker 1: Oh, you don't think so?
Speaker 0: Well, here's the reasons.
Speaker 0: One patent portfolio, Palm and Apple can fuck each other to death with their patents.
Speaker 0: And while Apple could take Palm down, they would take a serious beating, I think, in the patent.
Speaker 0: I think that basically to Apple, while they make a ton of money with their markups on their hardware, they also make money on the iTunes store.
Speaker 0: And if this thing can buy stuff from the iTunes store.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: You can buy stuff from the iTunes store and put it on.
Speaker 0: Apple's going to make its money.
Speaker 1: It's not DRM free.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's true.
Speaker 1: Apple should be sort of happy with that.
Speaker 1: That's maybe that's what Palm will come back.
Speaker 1: Yes, because the other day, you know, music people, Apple is like, you know, we made a device that's very popular and people are buying music from you to put on our.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And that's that's a good one.
Speaker 0: That is what brings me to my third reason Apple is not going to attack them.
Speaker 0: If Apple brings them down, everyone else now has a lot more standing for antitrust against Apple.
Speaker 1: Well, it's always like.
Speaker 1: I think what basically what's going to happen is you're going to see lawyers on all the three sides.
Speaker 1: Basically, they're going to mill for a whole bunch of months, maybe six to 12 months.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Until each set of lawyers figures out the perfect attack plan and then they're going to execute.
Speaker 0: I don't think Apple is going to attack.
Speaker 1: I think they will if their lawyers figure out something that they know is a lock.
Speaker 1: You know, they're not going to go into it.
Speaker 1: They're not going to rush in.
Speaker 1: They're going to wait to the perfect legal strategy.
Speaker 0: It is my guess that Apple's lawyers are going to realize that Palm's portfolio, because Palm was making PDAs when PDAs mattered.
Speaker 0: Palm is just like this.
Speaker 0: They have so many crazy patents for obvious things that they're just keeping.
Speaker 0: I'm sure they've got this gigantic secret portfolio of doom.
Speaker 0: Just right.
Speaker 1: There's a big chess game going on.
Speaker 1: It's it's.
Speaker 1: it's just fun for us.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And but the PRI, I can't talk a lot about it other than that.
Speaker 1: All because we've never seen one, nor does barely anyone.
Speaker 0: All of the initial reviews I see are that the multi touch screen is as good or so close that it doesn't matter to being as good as the iPhone and it has gestures at the bottom separate from the screen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's that's really cool.
Speaker 0: Like I saw a video of how that works.
Speaker 1: I saw that it's pretty good.
Speaker 0: Leaves like that trail where you move your fingers.
Speaker 0: I really like that.
Speaker 0: It's got a real keyboard.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: That is like killer for me.
Speaker 0: And while people who have touched it said the keyboard sucks, those people qualify that by saying that it's about as good as a Blackberry keyboard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I mean, it's like very fine.
Speaker 1: A keyboard, you know, no mobile keyboard is great.
Speaker 1: You know, like maybe some of them are, you know, but a keyboard is better than no keyboard.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: Because I looked at the kind of keyboard they use and I went to a Verizon store and found a keyboard that has a similar keyboard, a similar phone.
Speaker 0: It's not the same.
Speaker 0: It was bigger and it wasn't the same thing.
Speaker 0: But I tried it and I realized everyone who has problems with the with this keyboard either has really, really fat thumbs.
Speaker 1: A lot of people.
Speaker 0: Or they cut their fingernails too short because I realized that I type with my fingernails on phones.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: Because this is a givey plastic thing instead of a solid plastic thing, I think I'll be able to type lightning fast.
Speaker 1: No, it's definitely better than the onscreen keyboard, that's for sure.
Speaker 0: I guess my my guess is that maybe the new iPhone will have the keyboard.
Speaker 0: Maybe the only other complaint I see people saying is that this thing is way too light, which that's not a complaint.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: So I am probably going to buy one unless the thing is what you could do is just get one, right?
Speaker 1: And if it sucks, you can just you have 30 days to just bail.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's usually how that thing works.
Speaker 0: The thing is, I looked by Verizon contract ends on the 20th of this month.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So I got to wait until the end of the month.
Speaker 1: Waiting is fun.
Speaker 0: Which is fine, because that'll give me enough time for the Internet to point out, like, oh, you'll also want to do any stupid lines, probably.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: However, I have some secret radio checks.
Speaker 0: Remember, you have to.
Speaker 0: it's not two hundred dollars.
Speaker 0: It's like four hundred dollars or five hundred.
Speaker 0: And then you got a rebate.
Speaker 0: Best Buy and Radio Shack will give you the rebate at the store right then.
Speaker 1: Oh, and I know that in New York City that those Best Buy mobile stores.
Speaker 1: Yes, those are good.
Speaker 0: And there are like five places within walking distance of my work that will have it.
Speaker 0: So I might just get it and get a new phone number.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't do that.
Speaker 1: I would wait it out.
Speaker 0: I might.
Speaker 1: It's a lie.
Speaker 1: It's, you know, a pain in the ass to changing a phone number versus what most a month.
Speaker 0: The other option is waiting for the Verizon plan.
Speaker 1: Not a bad idea either.
Speaker 0: But I kind of want to switch to the Sprint plan because for what I would get, it looks like it's a lot cheaper.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you if you're not going if you're only in place, you know, Sprint, you know, is that is not the greatest.
Speaker 0: I would argue having had a Sprint phone forever until relatively recently when I switched to Verizon, Sprint had a great network and good prices and terrible customer service.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but their network, you know, is fast.
Speaker 0: And I mean, this thing is, you know, it's 3G.
Speaker 0: It's Avdo Revision A.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not it's not bad.
Speaker 1: And it works.
Speaker 0: And the coverage is good enough in places where we are and never run into a problem with Sprint coverage in my entire life.
Speaker 1: You know, and they have one hundred dollars for the unlimited everything.
Speaker 0: It's 70 bucks for effectively the unlimited everything, because the only thing you lose there is you only get like 400 minutes of talking.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, I used that's like.
Speaker 1: that's like what I have my iPhone.
Speaker 1: The thing is, it actually comes out to ninety dollars after all the bullshit fees I used.
Speaker 0: I think 19 minutes last month.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't use any minutes.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Plus multitasking.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, OK, that's there's a whole million more tech news that we don't have time to discuss.
Speaker 0: We'll save them for later, because it is time for things of the day.
Speaker 0: What do you got for me, Scott?
Speaker 1: This isn't an awesome thing like most people would be expecting, like a funny video or some such as a piece of software called DNS mask, DNS, M.A.S.
Speaker 1: Q. Right.
Speaker 1: And what this is is I wish I would have discovered it earlier.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's a DNS server, but it's also a DHCP server and it's also a TFTP server.
Speaker 1: So, you know, if you've got, say, a small home network.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And you want to like, you know, give your computers names like so that you can do stuff like SSH space name of computer in the living room or as our paying space name of computer in the bedroom of situations of I.T.
Speaker 0: person versus C.S.
Speaker 0: person solving a problem or expert in a field versus expert in another field who just wants to make the field.
Speaker 0: They're not an expert in work as they can do their real work.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Or if you want to like, you know, have some local DNS caching, you know, because the other DNS servers are not trustworthy.
Speaker 0: Scott comes to me and he's like, how do I do this?
Speaker 0: How do I just have like a local DNS?
Speaker 0: That was like just run bind locally and make a config.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Run the gigantic DNS server of full power with one hundred configuration files.
Speaker 0: Thing is bind as one tiny configuration file and it's actually tiny.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, this is pretty much your answer here.
Speaker 0: C.S.
Speaker 0: guy just wrote something that does what bind does.
Speaker 1: the best thing about the DNS mask is that, you know, it's mainly designed for a small home network with Nat, you know, to run everything on the inside of the net in terms of DNS, DTP and such.
Speaker 1: But it is also very good to just install it on your computer and then you can use it to sort of give you DNS for all the virtual machines you're running.
Speaker 1: So if you're like a developer like me and you've got all these virtual machines, you can use this to sort of DNS all of them and you can do cool stuff like, you know, basically it's basically gives you a host file on cracks.
Speaker 1: You can do stuff like star dot whatever and point every possible sub domain at the same IP address, which is very, very helpful.
Speaker 1: If you're doing like a virtual machine with virtual hosts, you know, if you understand what I'm saying, then you will understand why this is useful to you.
Speaker 1: If you don't understand what I'm talking about, then you have no interest in this.
Speaker 1: Then there's no point in you figuring what I will say, though, because it's already not useful to you if you don't know what I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: If you were in college and you think that you can use this instead of buying for DNS, you're wrong.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: it's not a real DNS server replacement.
Speaker 1: It's meant for, you know, a small home network or an individual computer.
Speaker 0: Just, you know, this is a tool that fixes an IT problem for a developer.
Speaker 0: This is not.
Speaker 0: this is not solve your DNS problem.
Speaker 1: If you have a home network, it's good.
Speaker 1: It does not.
Speaker 1: it's not good if you have a real network is very bad.
Speaker 0: So the wrong door, as far as I can tell, do these skits, you know, funny humor sketches that involve a lot of CG.
Speaker 0: And I found this one pretty amusing and it reminded me of Dave and Joel because it involves dinosaurs.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: I think they're parodying some either some generic show or maybe there's a specific show in Britain.
Speaker 0: They're parodying Albion.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry, I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: But it is just a typical, you know, guy and girl.
Speaker 0: The girl is breaking up with the guy in the short term and then has a flashback montage of all the good times they had together.
Speaker 0: But it's a velociraptor or a baby T-Rex or something like that.
Speaker 0: And I found this incredibly funny.
Speaker 1: I didn't think it was that funny.
Speaker 0: Scott doesn't find anything funny that is not immediately blisteringly funny.
Speaker 0: Like if a YouTube video is 20 seconds long, he's skipping to the end to see what happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I found this wasn't funny in any part.
Speaker 0: I think it was.
Speaker 1: I don't think it was.
Speaker 0: Listeners, what do you think?
Speaker 0: Was that funny?
Speaker 1: Oh, they're easily amused.
Speaker 1: They think we're funny.
Speaker 0: I see you've taken a page from the pendulate self-deprecating humor at all turns.
Speaker 1: I learned from.
Speaker 1: I steal from the forgotten masters.
Speaker 0: Penn's forgotten?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: So how do you document things?
Speaker 0: This is not a trivial question, sadly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically I want to do a little.
Speaker 1: see we're going to do a series of shows here because there is sort of like this suite of applications that businesses need these days, especially businesses with tech people.
Speaker 1: And they sort of all they're all these separate tools that need some amount of integration with each other.
Speaker 1: And they're all related, but they're all so distinct.
Speaker 1: And those tools are the ticketing system, the project and task management system, the version control type systems.
Speaker 1: If you have some sort of code going on.
Speaker 0: Well, that's easy to get.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But, you know, so you've got all these these sort of things going on.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: And we want to sort of spend a show on each one of these to talk about because basically they all so time tracking is also sort of in there with the project management bit.
Speaker 0: They all suck.
Speaker 1: There are no good ones out there.
Speaker 1: And we are constantly in our jobs dealing with bad ones, good ones, picking ones out, making ones.
Speaker 1: And it's just it's never perfect.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So we want to we want to dedicate some show time to these these pieces of software.
Speaker 0: I have four use cases, I guess, or four scenarios of me as an IT professional trying to have things be documented in any capacity.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, the first thing you got to talk about, though, is the difference between like software documentation from the developer side.
Speaker 0: Oh, crap.
Speaker 0: I had a discussion like this with the developer not that long ago where I basically said, yeah, we need a system to document things.
Speaker 0: And you guys got to write documentation.
Speaker 0: You could probably put it in our Twiki.
Speaker 0: And the guys like for documentation, we use Doxygen.
Speaker 0: And I was like, that does not solve the problem I'm right.
Speaker 0: So any capacity.
Speaker 1: So for people who don't know.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And when you're writing software, right, you'll put comments in the code, which is just like notes that don't actually do anything like this for loop doesn't do anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You just write in the middle of your code words that explain the code and help you understand it.
Speaker 1: So what people will do is they'll sort of have these documentation systems where in front of every function, in front of every class, you will put comments in some particular format and then you'll run some program that will generate sort of websites that, you know, document the code.
Speaker 1: So, you know, if I have a class, you know, and I can I write what the class does and I wrote the arguments to all the functions are.
Speaker 1: And then I put the comments in the file and I push a button.
Speaker 1: And then there's a website.
Speaker 1: So someone else who wants to say work on my source code or integrate with it right can just go to that website and it explains the code so that they don't accept to look at the code.
Speaker 1: All the information they need is sort of like the interface, the API parts.
Speaker 1: So that is what that's one kind of documentation.
Speaker 1: But systems for that kind of documentation are actually very prevalent.
Speaker 1: And there's quite a few good ones out there.
Speaker 1: And it varies by language and such.
Speaker 1: The thing is, a lot of people don't you know, it takes a really good people actually use them.
Speaker 1: I mean, I haven't actually gotten into a place that uses it fully and properly since I was in college and we used it in college.
Speaker 1: So, you know, it's one of those things where it's like on paper, you know, you should do it.
Speaker 1: Some people do do it.
Speaker 1: I've never done it just because, you know, you never do things that you know that you only know there's a right way to do things, but you never actually end up doing it that way.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Just because the realities of the world, 99 percent of these scripts I've written in the course of my professional career to do something on a server for me.
Speaker 0: They if you put the wrong argument in, it'll just crash and there's no error handling.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: But my four cases are first at RIT doing IT projects with other students for grades.
Speaker 0: We took notes on pieces of paper and we handed these scribbled documents into professors.
Speaker 0: We never referred to them.
Speaker 0: We didn't document anything.
Speaker 0: IBM.
Speaker 0: Everyone there was actually pretty smart.
Speaker 0: They had a documentation server.
Speaker 0: It was just a Windows box running IIS.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: And you just made documentation in HTML or text and you put it up there and then you added it to this hierarchy.
Speaker 0: It was basically the equivalent of a file server.
Speaker 0: It was a file server, but it served the purpose of a wiki.
Speaker 0: It wasn't a good way to go about it, but it kind of encouraged this sort of.
Speaker 0: you put up complete awesome documentation as opposed to half as barely finished documentation.
Speaker 0: Then I worked at Emerging Health, the hospital thing.
Speaker 0: There was no documentation for anything anywhere.
Speaker 1: So how did you know how things worked?
Speaker 0: I would have to ask people.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: And then I would write documentation for myself, which became one of the most sought after commodities in the history of that company.
Speaker 0: And the problem there, though, was that I kept saying, we need a wiki, we need a wiki, we need a wiki, we need a documentation server, we need something.
Speaker 0: And they always said, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: And then I quit.
Speaker 0: And then where I work now, we had a Twiki wiki, which media wiki seems to be the popular wiki among people who want to set up a wiki.
Speaker 1: The fact is that all wikis suck.
Speaker 0: They all suck.
Speaker 0: Good God, every wiki sucks.
Speaker 0: Google's is probably the least shitty, but it still has its problems.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they're all terrible.
Speaker 0: Most people seem to know media wiki and use it because it has a lot of extensions and features.
Speaker 0: Twiki seems to be used primarily by enterprise people.
Speaker 0: I think Twiki is better in the ways that matter.
Speaker 0: But media wiki is still good.
Speaker 0: I think they're equal, but different.
Speaker 0: And theoretically, a wiki seems to solve the documentation problem because people just write all of their documentation and the structure of the wiki just emerges if everyone's smart.
Speaker 1: I mean, in my last company, you know, we knew documentation was the way to go and we wanted it.
Speaker 1: We just we never actually wrote enough of it, but we did set up a docu wiki.
Speaker 1: It was actually a wiki for documentation called docu wiki.
Speaker 1: It wasn't amazing by any means.
Speaker 1: You know, it was sort of an average wiki, but it was meant for documentation.
Speaker 1: And it had, you know, some good versioning type features and such like that, which is good, you know, and we wrote some documentation in it, but, you know, we didn't write enough and now they're out of business.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess the problem I really found is that it's really easy to get technical people to write documentation as long as you give them time to do it.
Speaker 0: Project managers seem to always forget that they need to allocate like 10 percent of a project to documentation and knowledge.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, I could never write documentation because I always had to do work, you know.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So if any of you are ever in a position to manage tech people did whatever your project is, give them 10 percent of the time for documentation and knowledge transfer.
Speaker 0: You will you will make the best projects ever.
Speaker 1: You'll also be easier to fire people and hire new people with more skills, but don't tell them that now because then they won't document.
Speaker 1: Oh, they will.
Speaker 1: Maybe if they have the skills and they're and they're going to write if they have this, if they're writing good documentation.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Because they don't write good documentation is used.
Speaker 0: I knew a guy at IBM who purposefully did not write documentation so that he could not be fired.
Speaker 1: Ah, bad.
Speaker 0: That was his stated goal.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: I mean, I think that that's what he said to sound sort of smart and witty and clever.
Speaker 0: But really, that was really.
Speaker 1: he was lazy and didn't want to write.
Speaker 0: that was his goal.
Speaker 0: He he he would refuse to give me the answers I needed to write the program that was going to replace his job.
Speaker 0: And then I quit.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 0: But the problem I've run into is that you need like it's not just tech stuff.
Speaker 0: If you just look at tech stuff, the documentation problem is pretty easy to handle.
Speaker 0: If it's just tech people writing tech documentation, you set up like a Twicky Wiki.
Speaker 0: You make a good skeleton structure of some kind.
Speaker 1: Like you make a hierarchy and tech people will be smart enough to make it work, even if it's the system is not perfect.
Speaker 0: But you need other people or documentation.
Speaker 1: You also need other people to read the documentation and be able to understand and such and such.
Speaker 0: And I don't want to like.
Speaker 0: basically I just want to point out that there's no good way to do this.
Speaker 0: that exists in any capacity as far as I can see.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Remember, you know, let's for a minute.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: This documentation we're talking about, you know, it's not the software documentation.
Speaker 1: This is like.
Speaker 1: it's the business documentation.
Speaker 1: Like, you know, for example, like this is the process for doing this.
Speaker 1: You know, that's like.
Speaker 1: these are the steps you take.
Speaker 0: I want to get a new fixed connection for a customer.
Speaker 0: What are the processes?
Speaker 0: Or I want to get a new customer on our platform.
Speaker 0: What are all the steps?
Speaker 1: And it's sort of like, you know, the user manuals for things to think about when you have a company, right?
Speaker 1: Let's you go to the store and you buy something.
Speaker 1: It comes with an instruction manual.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, companies have a lot of things that are specific to them.
Speaker 1: You some guy makes a piece of software that is for internal use at your company.
Speaker 1: The only place that software ever be used is your company using it for itself.
Speaker 1: That needs an instruction manual.
Speaker 1: So that's the kind of documentation we're talking about.
Speaker 1: is how do you use the systems and what's the network look like?
Speaker 1: You know what IP addresses are these things on?
Speaker 0: All that kind of thing that I really find interesting is that different groups seem to all across every company.
Speaker 0: I've seen document things the same wrong way.
Speaker 0: And it's always the scenario of if all you have is a hammer, you're you're nailing every goddamn thing into whatever you're trying to put it in that screw.
Speaker 1: Hit that screw real hard.
Speaker 0: Hit that carburetor.
Speaker 0: Make it go.
Speaker 1: You broke it.
Speaker 0: I mean, every HR department I've ever seen has a Samba share on some Windows server somewhere.
Speaker 0: And on that Samba share are all these word documents and PDFs explaining like or like scans of physical documents.
Speaker 1: That's better than a physical document.
Speaker 0: Yes, but they tell people, yeah, go to the D drive and on the D drive you will find a directory full of files that are named.
Speaker 1: And maybe if you use something like Google desktop or SharePoint, SharePoint is actually pretty good.
Speaker 1: SharePoint is getting better, but it's still not great.
Speaker 0: But the thing SharePoint does is you can have versioning of documents that is transparent in the file system, but only if you set it up right.
Speaker 1: Just people know SharePoint is Microsoft's solution to many of the things we are going to discuss in this series, but not enough of them for it to be the solution.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: It's like it does some things.
Speaker 1: I've used it a couple of times.
Speaker 1: Some of the things it does are kind of slick and it's starting to go somewhere, but it's not complete.
Speaker 1: It leaves a lot of gaps.
Speaker 1: So you still need to accommodate it with other things.
Speaker 1: And when those things don't integrate, so it's like, fuck, there's also other popular solutions out there.
Speaker 1: Like Basecamp is a very popular solution to many of the things we're talking about here.
Speaker 1: But, you know, it's documentation is like these write boards and it's pretty sad.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But what?
Speaker 0: HR departments always seem to have slightly better documentation than everyone else.
Speaker 0: And I've noticed this because HR people tend to have been trained in so-called Microsoft Office Suite power usage.
Speaker 0: So they're the ones who make the crazy Excel spreadsheet that like auto calculates everything when you should have just hired someone to make a web app.
Speaker 1: Also, HR people, a lot of their job is procedures like how do you sign someone up for the health care?
Speaker 1: How do you hire a new employee?
Speaker 1: How do you fire a new employee?
Speaker 1: What do you do if someone quits?
Speaker 1: What do you do?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So all those procedures, they need to make sure they do those things fucking right now.
Speaker 1: And so they have, you know, procedural documents explaining every single step they need to take and every single form that needs to be.
Speaker 1: It's a lot of bureaucracy.
Speaker 0: Bureaucracy is always well documented the way tech people do that.
Speaker 0: Imagine if you used a ticketing system that had pre-created ticket types.
Speaker 0: So the HR person says, you know, or someone in the company makes a ticket saying, yeah, we hired this person.
Speaker 0: And that automatically creates these work orders to all the HR people to do, you know, work order to do all the business processes.
Speaker 1: and that's ticket system.
Speaker 1: But yeah, yes.
Speaker 0: But the ticket system in sets up the workflow.
Speaker 0: And then there is documentation that was that is managed in an intelligent wiki style way version with like certified versions, like people collaborate.
Speaker 0: And then this is the current official version of the process for onboarding.
Speaker 1: That's the kind of feature that not a lot of the documentation that, you know, even if setting up a wiki is a great start.
Speaker 0: Well, the reason I say the two, the real problem is that there are solutions to all of these tiny problems, but none of the solutions integrate with each other.
Speaker 0: If the ticketing system made the work order to the HR person and linked to the most recent certified version of the procedure, you know, and when they finished it, it closed it out.
Speaker 0: And then at the same time, like that, the process that you followed created all the secret documents about that person, like it updated the database of all the HR, like all the HR stuff.
Speaker 1: Well, you're going even beyond just the integration of the systems.
Speaker 1: You're actually going to the to the point where, you know, the systems enact some of the the documented procedures.
Speaker 0: because no one is me.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's the pie in the sky.
Speaker 0: dream of information management, as it should be, that you have technology that manages all of your information between all of your sources intelligently, regardless of the technical skills of the people involved, purely based on their knowledge skills in their relevant fields of expertise.
Speaker 0: We are currently nowhere near that now.
Speaker 0: Instead, we have problems like, all right, get the HR people to use Twiggy.
Speaker 0: They know how to use word.
Speaker 0: They can't use an HTML WYSIWYG editor because HTML WYSIWYG editors, as everyone technological knows, require a lot of fiddling with the stupid HTML.
Speaker 1: I think that is a major hurdle to wiki usage is that no one can do any of the wiki languages or the WYSIWYG editors.
Speaker 0: Don't try to teach them.
Speaker 0: I have tried.
Speaker 0: I've given class.
Speaker 1: I mean, you can maybe try to use like one of the Markdown languages, you know, one of the ones is simpler syntax.
Speaker 0: No, that doesn't work.
Speaker 1: Doesn't work.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: I tried to teach people TML, which is simple as shit.
Speaker 1: It's just like use a bunch of equals is under the header, you know?
Speaker 0: Can't even do that.
Speaker 1: Can't even do that.
Speaker 0: So WYSIWYG.
Speaker 0: But you all know you're all tech people.
Speaker 0: You're listening to Geek Next Mondays.
Speaker 0: Half the time you use WYSIWYG, but there's always like that extra bullet point.
Speaker 0: And then you hit the HTML button and you get rid of the extra bullet point.
Speaker 0: That is already beyond 99 percent of people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can't.
Speaker 0: WYSIWYG is not a solution because it does not work.
Speaker 1: If you had one that worked, we could talk.
Speaker 0: But there are ones that work.
Speaker 0: They're all for proprietary crappy wikis or they're for things that aren't wikis.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: That is.
Speaker 1: And the other thing, right, is that, you know, a wiki is good, but sometimes the documentation you don't want a wiki necessarily.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Well, look, wiki is the problem with wiki, especially Twiki.
Speaker 0: The philosophy is it's open.
Speaker 0: It is hard to lock stuff down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's meant to be like Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: Like, oh, we assume that every user is going to be able to edit anything.
Speaker 0: Say for
Speaker 0: H.R.,
Speaker 0: you know, you have people collaborating in the wiki on, say, you know, this is the procedure for setting up the health care and you keep changing it like the H.R people will rewrite it and things change.
Speaker 0: But you need an official certified version that someone signed off on and a way to verify that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And then you have like the development version, not edited in a business.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Even with a wiki, with collaboration and nice things like that, not all users are created equal.
Speaker 1: You don't want, you know, the normal employees to be able to see the employee handbook that's still being worked on.
Speaker 1: You want them to only be able to see the newest version and that's it.
Speaker 1: You don't want them to be able to see old versions.
Speaker 1: You don't have to be able to see working versions.
Speaker 1: You only want certain people to be able to look at the working version and then even fewer people to actually be able to edit the working version and only maybe one or two people to certify and make it the new version and get rid of the old one.
Speaker 1: And wikis just don't have the features for that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: You can do that with Twiki like I'd set up.
Speaker 1: You also like don't want like, you know, you want everyone in the business to have the access they need to the same one system.
Speaker 1: But you don't want the secretary to see the tech documentation and like the IP addresses of all the network machines and shit.
Speaker 1: They can't be knowing that, you know, and that no wiki takes care of that.
Speaker 1: That that that I've heard of.
Speaker 0: Well, you can do it with a lot of wikis if you know about technology.
Speaker 0: I mean, I made a secure Twiki.
Speaker 0: It's people cannot read certain parts of the Twiki unless they have root access on the server with Apache, which is me.
Speaker 0: So that's not a concern.
Speaker 0: Or they're evil geniuses and they find some crazy cross-eyed scripting attack, which will be hard to do because it's behind a VPN anyway.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 0: And like I made secret webs and I made certifications where you can certify a document.
Speaker 0: You can make all these workflows into a key to all.
Speaker 1: you did plugins for all this stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The thing is, they're all not robust, not intuitive.
Speaker 0: And good God, if I ever am going to teach a non-technical person to use any of this shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, I mean, you know, you could you could.
Speaker 1: the setup doesn't necessarily need to be so easy for a normal person, but using has to be easy for a normal person.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, you know, if you can't get every person in the company to use it, you're not, you know, it doesn't matter even if it's perfect by what we say, if not, everyone's using it.
Speaker 1: It's it's not working.
Speaker 0: So what do we do?
Speaker 0: How do we document stuff?
Speaker 0: There's the problem.
Speaker 0: There is no answer.
Speaker 1: We ask the question, even if everyone in the company is well-meaning and wants to document and knows it's for the best and agrees on an awesome wiki solution that's perfect and has all these features and, you know, you got to do it too.
Speaker 1: It's it's like there's so many barriers to making it happen and all of those things sort of while they're good in the long run for awesomeness and having, you know, such any business people always see you doing this and like, that's working.
Speaker 1: You're not making me money right now.
Speaker 0: I think what we need to outline is for documentation alone.
Speaker 0: Forget my pie in the sky.
Speaker 0: A documentation system that I would say solves this problem.
Speaker 0: One needs to involve for the average for the majority of users, no code or markup of any kind.
Speaker 1: It has to be Microsoft Word at or or just notepad.
Speaker 0: It has to be Microsoft Word because people need to be able to format.
Speaker 1: It could be word pad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that level.
Speaker 0: It has to be that level, but it has to be that level that works perfectly.
Speaker 1: You could use RTF maybe.
Speaker 0: You know how shitty RTF is under the covers?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean, if people are just uploading and editing, you know, RTFs like RTFs in the background, people are editing.
Speaker 1: So what's this?
Speaker 0: I use to share these collaboratively?
Speaker 1: Well, you'll have a JavaScript RTF editor right in the browser.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So I'm just shooting the shit.
Speaker 1: I don't fucking know.
Speaker 0: So I think one way around this, if someone could come up with a sort of simple subset of HTML and make a WYSIWYG editor that only does that subset, that is actually perfect.
Speaker 0: There aren't any.
Speaker 1: Well, you just have bold, italic, underlined, big font, small font.
Speaker 0: You need six heading levels.
Speaker 1: Do you really need six heading levels?
Speaker 0: Good God.
Speaker 0: Looking at you at least five.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So you have all the heading levels and then links.
Speaker 0: But here's the thing.
Speaker 0: You need to be able to make colors.
Speaker 0: You need to be able to quote boxes.
Speaker 0: You need to be able to indent without bullet points, which nothing freaking does, because there is no good way to do that in HTML for good reason.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But you need it for a document management system.
Speaker 0: You need it for documentation.
Speaker 0: If you can.
Speaker 1: Well, what you could do is you could just have the CSS automatically set up such that, you know, you have an H, a header, and then it'll indent.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: And then you could do that.
Speaker 1: So the headers will automatically indent based on the header level.
Speaker 0: But here's the thing.
Speaker 0: That implementation, we need something that does that.
Speaker 0: We don't need.
Speaker 0: I mean, I could make a system that does that for my company, that serves all my purposes, but it won't get out there anywhere.
Speaker 0: We we need someone to make something that just does.
Speaker 1: There are HTML WYSIWYG editors, but they're, you know, that have that limited subset.
Speaker 1: And, you know, they're used in forums and such.
Speaker 1: But, you know, they don't they don't work.
Speaker 0: Like they the thing that works the least are bullet points.
Speaker 0: The thing that people need the most works the least.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, well.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And linking documents to other documents or categorizing documents needs to be intuitive.
Speaker 1: That's the thing is that even the simplest methods of linking like camel case linking, people can't even write the thing in camel case.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: So I don't know how to make it easier.
Speaker 1: I give up.
Speaker 0: Maybe just highlight it, click link, and then it gives you a gooey of find the document you want to link to.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I just.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've gone lately with the root of creating like basically I will get people who are non-technical who I want to document stuff.
Speaker 0: I will make all the framework and all the links and I'll just make all the empty documents with sections that say write a section on this here, write a section on this here, and then they fill it in.
Speaker 0: And that works really well.
Speaker 0: The other solution I have is that one department is getting an intern and they gave the interns do it.
Speaker 0: They gave me the intern and they said, make this intern right.
Speaker 0: Documentation for every business process my department has.
Speaker 0: He knows HTML.
Speaker 1: Oh, shit.
Speaker 0: That kid is a good idea is going to have a miserable summer.
Speaker 1: He's going to get some monies.
Speaker 0: He's going to get some money and he's going to learn some stuff.
Speaker 1: He's got some resumes.
Speaker 0: He's not going to have fun.
Speaker 1: No, he's not.
Speaker 1: It's all right.
Speaker 1: He'll be in.
Speaker 1: Maybe he'll become an HTML documentation Wiki master and then he'll get a job making a better one.
Speaker 1: just that we want.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But listeners, what do you think?
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: How do you document stuff?
Speaker 0: I know the answer is unknown.
Speaker 1: I know that most of the people out there don't really care about all this business process shit, but we're giving you like three or four shows on it.
Speaker 1: So shove it.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I think we're done partly because I really want some pizza.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's get some pizza.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share-alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.