Speaker 0: Hey, it's Monday October 19th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I got a scratchy voice, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We're back with problem solving my morons.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Wow, we haven't done a show in like forever.
Speaker 1: What are you talking about?
Speaker 1: We did show yesterday.
Speaker 0: Did we?
Speaker 0: yeah on what?
Speaker 1: It just wasn't a public.
Speaker 1: You know I mean, it's like you know you can.
Speaker 1: we do shows all the time.
Speaker 1: We just don't publish all of them.
Speaker 1: Put on a private performance.
Speaker 0: Yes a private performance.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: I've part of the Limited engagement.
Speaker 0: yes, we did a live show at a wedding.
Speaker 1: there's someone else's wedding.
Speaker 0: You know the funny thing is a lot.
Speaker 1: We didn't actually do a show there.
Speaker 0: in case anyone is stupid a lot of our listeners were I don't know you guys were all Like oh my god room.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like buying houses and moving and stuff.
Speaker 0: geek nights is gonna disappear, and then obviously that's not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: We'll talk about all that.
Speaker 0: you know when we do our state of the podcast whatever on Halloween, but What's funny is that right after that we ended up having to miss a week of shows for completely unrelated reasons?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like out of nowhere.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: so Monday, and we're did the show on that but Didn't get home from work at any reasonable time because what was it?
Speaker 0: Amtrak hit some dude?
Speaker 1: Yeah, train the other.
Speaker 1: see we'd ride the Metro North trains But there's occasionally a few times a day Amtrak trains lose the second.
Speaker 1: I was like occasionally a few times the day Amtrak hits someone they use the same tracks So the basically all the Metro North trains just move out of the way.
Speaker 1: the Amtrak goes whoosh real fast And then the Metro North's move again.
Speaker 1: the Amtrak train hit somebody.
Speaker 0: now the worst thing It's so bad is bad.
Speaker 1: someone actually got hit and it's serious and we're making hockey jokes.
Speaker 0: the worst thing is though.
Speaker 0: I was on my train and trains don't back up but my trained like came to a stop suddenly and Then backed up to another station and the conductor the whole time they wouldn't tell anyone what was going on.
Speaker 1: our conductor was like Yeah, an Amtrak train hit a car or something.
Speaker 1: We don't know how long I'm gonna be here.
Speaker 0: Yeah But we'll tell that story because it's kind of the point of the show, but that aside all right.
Speaker 0: It's Tuesday.
Speaker 0: We decide I'll do a show anyway.
Speaker 0: No Scott does late getting home cuz car battery was dead.
Speaker 1: Ah Someone left my reading.
Speaker 1: Someone.
Speaker 0: the passenger side reading lamp was left on except that you hadn't driven anyone around in like forever.
Speaker 1: It's all I'll say.
Speaker 0: Yeah, someone did it.
Speaker 1: That's all I'll say.
Speaker 0: Of course Scott was incapable of dealing with this on his own.
Speaker 1: no not really.
Speaker 0: So I actually had a rollerblade all the way home the next day to get a car.
Speaker 1: You've been rolling home anyway your car head doesn't even work, and then you even try to fix it.
Speaker 0: There's a difference between rollerblading with like a backpack with like a suit in it and rollerblading with a car battery.
Speaker 1: It's all it's.
Speaker 1: it's like a little motorcycle.
Speaker 0: You try rollerblading with that thing that things heavy.
Speaker 1: I can't rollerblade naked so It's not gonna help.
Speaker 0: so it took two.
Speaker 1: actually it might help because it helped me balance a little bit.
Speaker 1: I go all slow and sort of shuffle with it and use it to you know move the center of gravity about.
Speaker 0: so it took Two days for Scott to sort that out, but yeah, that's done, and you know all these other things happen all weeks.
Speaker 0: moving Moving didn't actually interrupt geek nights at all.
Speaker 1: yeah even though You know it is sort of occupying all of my free time.
Speaker 1: just now I was calculating my moving expenses, which are greatly inflated Scott.
Speaker 0: it cost us like four grand to move out of Rochester.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 1: You know how much fucking like curtains cost goddamn.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yes, I do.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking about making my own curtains.
Speaker 1: I might have to because the cost of them is just too much and the size is that they don't sell the size I need and the custom size ones are like fuck all bajillion dollars, so Like they can't.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna have to delay on like the couch and the TV for like a month or two because just forget the curtains.
Speaker 1: for now It's like I don't care there's no one.
Speaker 1: I'm not worried.
Speaker 1: Looking in it's mostly an issue of if I don't want the Sun in my eyes I can't make it go away cuz the other day You know I was walking home from like the fancy part of the like.
Speaker 1: it'd be hard to sleep if like this lights of the City are blasting into my window.
Speaker 0: I was walking home through like the Washington Square like super fancy brownstones in Manhattan And I realized none of the rich people there have curtains their blinds No Nothing.
Speaker 0: all those super rich people like with those giant like dude lives in a whole brownstone by himself like all floors of it.
Speaker 0: They just have their windows open to show off.
Speaker 0: and as I walk by you know at night I could see all the op lii opulence in there and all the rich people sitting around being rich Man, this one guy's brown on the third floor.
Speaker 1: No one can see my shit.
Speaker 0: I could see up into other like third fourth floor even.
Speaker 0: but there's one guy like.
Speaker 0: he had a living room.
Speaker 0: He our entire house would fit inside of his brownstone, and he had like Opulent decadent like mirror candle things everywhere all these fancy antiques all over the place.
Speaker 1: you sure that wasn't like You know a clubhouse as opposed.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I'm absolutely sure it was just some guy's house in the front of the window.
Speaker 0: Like to top it all off that this old-school looking wrought-iron kind of birdcage like you see in movies and in it the fanciest Most like.
Speaker 0: I'm richer than you looking bird.
Speaker 0: I have ever seen Faberge bird.
Speaker 1: Faberge bird All right desire reminds me of this article I read today's.
Speaker 1: you know just one of those internet things people write.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know some blog post or whatever.
Speaker 1: But the guy in his blog post he was basically talking about how like when you make a business you have to decide at the beginning If your goal is rich or king.
Speaker 1: and rich means you're going for the money And you don't give a shit about anything else.
Speaker 1: and king means you're gonna be like the king of X You know.
Speaker 1: like for example like Facebook is king.
Speaker 1: right king of social networking You Know but you can tell because like you know the founder of Facebook He stayed on.
Speaker 1: if he was about rich He would have bailed as soon as he got mad money.
Speaker 1: so right He says you have to decide from the beginning whether you're going for Richard King.
Speaker 0: I'm going for rich King or out.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: He says if you go for King You know riches is definitely a possibility.
Speaker 1: But he talks about he unabashedly went for rich and got it and how.
Speaker 1: when he sold his company people gave him all this shit.
Speaker 1: But the thing is in this article he had his graph and the graph was pretty much like at.
Speaker 1: the x-axis Was how much money you make and the y-axis is like effect on your life, right?
Speaker 1: So basically the graph was like, you know, it was going up towards a million dollars.
Speaker 1: And as it went towards a million dollars, it was like, you know, you can eat you can buy a house You can you know own a car, you know, and then somewhere past like 1 million dollars It shot up right and then it crossed this line and the line was never need to worry about money again.
Speaker 1: And then the line sort of got towards the top and tapered off again, and then it reached the final point which is private jet.
Speaker 0: So you've been on and on with these private jets lately.
Speaker 1: I know right It's the private basically shows you.
Speaker 1: it's like, you know, it's like money, you know as you get more money It doesn't really change your lifestyle.
Speaker 1: that significantly just changes how fancy your shit is.
Speaker 1: And then at a certain point you never have to worry about money again And then more money beyond that doesn't really change anything either, you know It's like is it is like this one spot where having more money like it's holy shit.
Speaker 1: And then after that, it's like, you know, so that's why he's like.
Speaker 1: I sold my business I got so many millions whatever and he's like.
Speaker 1: I never had to worry about money again.
Speaker 1: So why would I hold out for more?
Speaker 1: It's like I had it there any more than that wouldn't have made a real difference.
Speaker 1: You know, I was going for rich I wasn't going for King.
Speaker 0: So what are we going for with geek nights?
Speaker 1: He ignites his King.
Speaker 1: something else has got to be rich.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Could settle for Duke Duke.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think we look for his.
Speaker 1: beat us to the kingdom.
Speaker 1: I think he's actually got like the Emperor dumb of podcasting.
Speaker 1: podcasting today at least nerdy Podcasting I mean someone else is probably the winner of.
Speaker 0: you know, dude Michael one of my co-workers He's got.
Speaker 0: you know, I guess who lose.
Speaker 0: the champion I don't know out of the blue comes into work the other day.
Speaker 0: He's like, so I found out that Kevin Smith does a podcast.
Speaker 0: really that I was like welcome to the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah He's like.
Speaker 0: it's the funniest thing I've ever encountered in my life.
Speaker 0: It's not that great and all I could think was wow You're not.
Speaker 0: you haven't really made it to the internet yet.
Speaker 0: Have you know?
Speaker 1: Let me show you this fortune.
Speaker 0: so I At least got to tell the story Briefly because I don't know if I should save it for like a separate Thursday show of how I got my bike back.
Speaker 1: I didn't actually hear this whole story.
Speaker 0: So should I wait though?
Speaker 0: Cuz this could be a whole Thursday show.
Speaker 0: It's quite a story.
Speaker 1: How could it be so much of a story?
Speaker 0: It's like the bamboo and the vision.
Speaker 0: It's one of those kind of.
Speaker 1: is that big?
Speaker 1: How long is this confrontation?
Speaker 0: I have a lot to say Around like I have this cycle out like analysis of the dude cuz I got to encounter the dude who stole my bike.
Speaker 1: Kind of dude was he?
Speaker 0: I'll tell you this my analysis of him is he is a kind of thuggish 28 to 30 year old African American loser guy going nowhere who is a habitual thief of opportunity.
Speaker 0: He's also a coward Of course, but that wasn't a coward.
Speaker 1: He wouldn't be a thief of opportunity.
Speaker 1: He'd be thief of initiative.
Speaker 0: but at the same time I will say that him being a coward and Not calling my bluff is the only way I avoided having to fight with this guy who was almost a foot taller than me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you were gonna use your kung fu.
Speaker 1: What happened to that big exercise?
Speaker 1: weightlifting kung fu man?
Speaker 0: I was totally set to fight him.
Speaker 0: you realize my bluff because I bluff.
Speaker 0: I had this huge bluff which is the only reason I really got the bike back, but The blood he bent your handlebars Actually didn't know but he put electrical tape all over the bike to try to disguise it so I wouldn't notice it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, never mind the fact that he parked it right next to where he fucking stole it from.
Speaker 1: I kind of like it when the bike has electrical tape all over it though that I took the electrical tape off.
Speaker 1: Jesus I like the electrical tape styling.
Speaker 0: That's the styling of either one hipster guy who thinks it's cool to be a bike messenger even though it's kind of a dying Career or to dude what fucking stole my bike.
Speaker 1: There's also the third style of like delivery, dude That's the hipster, dude.
Speaker 1: Yeah Like messenger whatever.
Speaker 0: But basically my bluff was not.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna get the bike with this bluff.
Speaker 0: My bluff was.
Speaker 0: I need to distract him long enough to be ready to punch a motherfucker in the face.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was ready to fight him, but I didn't have to because I bluffed.
Speaker 0: moral of the story always blow.
Speaker 1: The thing is fighting is probably a really bad idea because like even if he stole your shit if you fight him That's probably gonna get you in trouble.
Speaker 0: I was not worried about that at all because one I probably could have taken him and two there's no one around.
Speaker 0: So as long as I take him, I just take the bike and that's the end of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess yeah What's he gonna do?
Speaker 1: call the police?
Speaker 1: I stole this dude's bike and he beat me up.
Speaker 0: Yeah Plus self-defense because basically my whole plan.
Speaker 0: every anytime I encounter Like this level of person the kind of person who I might have to fight.
Speaker 1: I Always go for the mean bean machine.
Speaker 0: Not only that but it's always the situation where I definitely will put myself in the situation where I am Defending myself.
Speaker 0: the other person attacked me.
Speaker 1: That's obviously a good idea.
Speaker 0: My whole kung fu strategy because you know, I learned enough kung fu I know like stuff My whole strategy is to wait for them to throw the first punch and do that crane spreads its wings things to basically knock Them out with their first punch.
Speaker 0: That's it It'll.
Speaker 0: but you want to try it on me try to punch me.
Speaker 0: We'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll punch you with my gun.
Speaker 0: Yes I bet you will lose your thief of opportunity who steals a 15 year old busted-ass bike from the train station and Isn't smart enough to sell it or to at least not park it from at the place where he stole it.
Speaker 0: I'm not too worried about him having a gun.
Speaker 1: He could have stolen it in an opportunistic fashion.
Speaker 0: But Scott in close quarters like that if you don't or anyone if you don't already have a gun out and pointed at the person You're fighting with.
Speaker 0: that gun is not a factor in the fight.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's why you run away like you're a coward.
Speaker 0: then you turn around and start walking in And then the other guy's got to run away, yeah Thing is my bluff pretty much Obviated that but I'm gonna save the story for Thursday cuz I got pictures and everything.
Speaker 1: You took pictures dude while he was the head and
Speaker 0: now I didn't because but I took pictures of the bike and like all the stuff he did to it because it's it's pretty sad how he disguised the bike like all the Everything about this dude reeks of sad, dude.
Speaker 0: His life is never gonna go anywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah But at least he didn't have to fight me.
Speaker 1: So let's talk about some news.
Speaker 1: Monday tech news is is a pretty obvious news.
Speaker 1: is the droid coming to the horizon?
Speaker 0: Is it not the drugs you're looking for?
Speaker 1: one thing?
Speaker 1: I thought was weird and that my co-worker agreed.
Speaker 1: was they put out this commercial right and I watched the commercial and it was like iPhone doesn't do this.
Speaker 1: iPhone doesn't have a real keyboard iPhone.
Speaker 1: You can't replace the battery iPhone and it's all true, right?
Speaker 1: And it was actually cut kind of good that people were actually doing this sort of like direct Point out the flaws and Apple's shit to the general public.
Speaker 1: I like that because you know that stuff that normal people can understand and that they don't really think about.
Speaker 1: but tech people all know And we need you know companies.
Speaker 1: if you're gonna fight Apple.
Speaker 1: That's what you got to do.
Speaker 1: You got to do the same shit Apple does to Microsoft.
Speaker 1: where they're like Windows gets all kinds of viruses.
Speaker 1: You gotta be like hey MacBook, you know iPhone battery life not so good.
Speaker 1: You got to do the same shit to them because there are plenty of flaws in Apple products that just no one talks about.
Speaker 0: But no everyone tries to ape.
Speaker 0: Apple is kind of like all the MMOs.
Speaker 0: They try to be World of Warcraft instead of just saying wow sucks.
Speaker 0: We're different.
Speaker 0: play this exactly.
Speaker 0: They're like, we're almost like wow, we're cheaper.
Speaker 1: All right, so you got a point, you know This is the right kind of marketing.
Speaker 1: but the thing is they didn't show the fucking phone in the ad.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: not only do you have to bash Apple right you also have to come and say yeah Well, we got this we got this.
Speaker 1: if you go watch the Steve Jobs keynote.
Speaker 1: He says like amazing and fantastic like, you know a hundred times.
Speaker 1: He's like check out our amazing this and our fantastic that you got to both.
Speaker 1: Right, you got to ape them and smash them because smashing them is aping them you see because they smash Microsoft and Windows.
Speaker 1: So if you want to you have to ape their style and smile anyway, so yeah I'm not getting another phone until like the middle of next year, but if I had to get one now, it's looking pretty good.
Speaker 1: I mean the Verizon data network.
Speaker 1: I think technically according to benchmarks isn't as fast as the Sprint one but just overall the Verizon network is about a bajillion times more reliable than everyone else's network and It's an Android phone.
Speaker 1: It looks like it's gonna you know be pretty Good as far as Android phones go.
Speaker 1: I mean the other Android phones.
Speaker 1: I'll have like these arm CPUs But this one has the same CPU that the iPhone and the prehab.
Speaker 1: So it's gonna be a lot faster than the other Android phones.
Speaker 1: It's gonna have the new Android OS.
Speaker 1: It's got a real keyboard You know, it's got a nice touchscreen.
Speaker 1: People who've used it say it's pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: I'm really thinking that Android's gonna gonna be the way to go.
Speaker 1: just cuz Google's coming on so strong.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's hard to say though.
Speaker 0: I mean really.
Speaker 1: I mean like really when I'm sitting at a computer.
Speaker 1: I mean like Google.
Speaker 1: they determined what it's like.
Speaker 1: six percent of all internet traffic period is Google.
Speaker 1: So having a phone That's Google.
Speaker 1: That's fucking useful as all hell.
Speaker 1: Yeah, especially since it looks like Google is integrating less and less with the iPhone.
Speaker 0: It's like considering like outside of work.
Speaker 0: the vast majority of the work I do for geek nights is basically through Google tools.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as I plan conventions and email people.
Speaker 0: Yep so the thing is what we.
Speaker 0: what will really be the factor aside from this coming out is When the next web OS phone comes out.
Speaker 0: cuz web OS is not a player yet.
Speaker 0: It's just on one phone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I wonder what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wonder if it's gonna.
Speaker 0: I think in the end we're gonna see a huge huge drop-off of Apple iPhone and a big Well, you know, it's.
Speaker 1: it's actually kind of interesting like where people are, you know There's like a lot of different angles on it, right?
Speaker 1: There's the angle of you know, like, okay So which which persons are gonna buy which phones and you think about it?
Speaker 1: The most smartphones are actually probably sold to people who are like becoming 18 or like leaving college.
Speaker 1: right because it's like okay you're you're 18. now It's like so.
Speaker 1: you're probably gonna get some presents you're gonna go to college something like that, right?
Speaker 1: You've probably just had a phone phone for the you know, just texting and calling.
Speaker 1: you didn't have a smartphone yet Cuz you're a poor kid.
Speaker 1: now you're gonna get you know a phone for college or whatever iPhone is probably gonna win them over.
Speaker 0: see except there's growing like normal.
Speaker 0: people that I talk to More and more are very cognizant of the AT&T is shitty problem.
Speaker 1: It is and that's why everything hinges on the iPhone being on non AT&T.
Speaker 0: I hear people saying things now constantly like I would get an a phone but iPhone a phone But AT&T.
Speaker 0: I can't deal with them.
Speaker 1: I know right and the thing is you and more and more like.
Speaker 0: as a secondary part of that.
Speaker 0: those same people will then say Things like you know Sprint isn't looking so bad anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like Sprint was looking really terrible.
Speaker 1: The thing with Sprint is like their data networks looking really good.
Speaker 1: Their pricing is looking All right, the customer service is well, no one has good customer service.
Speaker 0: So I've given up on.
Speaker 0: the thing is I don't need customer service.
Speaker 0: I've decided yeah, really like I want to do a show on this.
Speaker 0: I've realized that I do not require customer service anymore and it is not something I'm willing to pay for.
Speaker 1: No, not really.
Speaker 1: I mean so in some situations it's nice, but it's like I don't need it.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna make my decision based on it.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: The only customer service I need is that if there is a service They are legally obligated to provide me like the phone had a flaw replace it.
Speaker 0: I can sue them if they won't do that.
Speaker 0: So I had everything I meant Sue about.
Speaker 1: so I got a new checking account online at chase calm.
Speaker 1: I didn't have to actually talk to anyone and they sent me the ATM card and I went to the ATM today with it for The first time and I realized they had never told me the pin and I had never been given the option to set a pin.
Speaker 0: They usually mail that in a separate envelope.
Speaker 1: it was I never got it.
Speaker 0: So are you sure you didn't throw it away as junk mail?
Speaker 0: They usually look really shady.
Speaker 1: No, cuz the eight the ATM card came in a really shady envelope But in the piece of paper in it didn't have any pin.
Speaker 0: Yes, cuz they always mail the pin separately obviously for a good reason.
Speaker 0: Think about it.
Speaker 1: Well, no, cuz it was I had to activate it anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you can't.
Speaker 0: they're not gonna give you the pin over the phone.
Speaker 0: That's not secure either.
Speaker 0: Regardless get a new ATM card.
Speaker 1: Let me activate it and they didn't have me set a pin.
Speaker 0: So that that's either you missed a mail or something.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 1: I didn't miss any males.
Speaker 1: I didn't screw anything.
Speaker 0: I doubt it.
Speaker 0: cuz every time I get a new debit card, they mail me the card in a separate envelope.
Speaker 1: Envelope.
Speaker 1: I checked.
Speaker 1: I don't know they fucked up or something.
Speaker 1: I went to The chase like, you know, there are.
Speaker 1: there are bajillion chase branches and they'll have people in them.
Speaker 0: I want a midtown.
Speaker 1: I could have gone to any one of them to get to handle this situation.
Speaker 1: But it just so happened that you know my co-worker he's got this thing now where he loves going to like the food trucks Right, but not just the regular old street meat.
Speaker 1: He's got to find like the stylish Street, you know.
Speaker 1: so there's this Street Suites and he follows it on Twitter and it's basically a bakery in a truck and He's he goes to that like freaking every time he comes to the city and next to the street suites.
Speaker 1: today was the schnitzel and Things truck which had a line so long we couldn't wait in it.
Speaker 1: But when he attempted to wait in the line I went to the chase like The entire building was chased and I went to the branch in the bottom of that and got the shit taken care of.
Speaker 1: It was pretty weird because I went and I sat you know in the back of the bank where you almost never go.
Speaker 0: So did you ask them how you're supposed to get the pin?
Speaker 0: Like did you ask them what happened?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they said there should have been a pin number in the envelope with it with the card.
Speaker 0: That's weird.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, I'm just you know customer service situation.
Speaker 0: So there's that whole situation about the LHC and I do want to talk about this briefly because I think it's really cool and there's an anime called Boca Rado that you could probably watch.
Speaker 0: if you wanted to watch anime, that would be Related.
Speaker 0: but this crazy crackpot sounding theory came out and it was on slash out about how you're pretty much like.
Speaker 1: This theory is totally real and now Timo the physicist is like, yeah, that's a crack of shit.
Speaker 1: Well, no,
Speaker 0: no, no, no, he pointed out that the guy who said it is kind of a crack of shit Because there's the same guy who has all these other crazy similar theories about what if we flip it on and off and on and Off and then we'll find out if God exists.
Speaker 1: How does that work?
Speaker 0: I have the paper.
Speaker 0: I didn't read it yet.
Speaker 0: Okay, but the whole idea and this is what I'm fascinated with because it's an idea that while probably is not true is Because of the way quantum mechanics are more plausible than you'd think.
Speaker 0: but I think it's more.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's necessarily plausible for the LHC because I don't think the LHC has a good chance of destroying the world.
Speaker 0: But the theory more is that if we could destroy the world in some quantum way We might as well keep trying because we didn't.
Speaker 0: because if we were able to do it and did it we wouldn't exist already.
Speaker 0: So it wouldn't matter.
Speaker 0: the fact that we still exist means we can't destroy the world that way.
Speaker 1: it is an interesting concept to think about like, you know, if You were going it's like the you know, the universe usually think of it being destroyed, you know at a moment Like the earth explodes, right?
Speaker 1: So it's like, okay So that means we live like the dinosaurs you live and then you don't live.
Speaker 0: but if it's one of those quantum things, right?
Speaker 0: quantum causality You know buzzword.
Speaker 1: whatever the situation where you know, the universe spawns multiple universes like imagine There's a black hole, but the black hole didn't just suck in all energy and all matter But it also sucked in time and it sucked you in.
Speaker 1: then not only would you cease to exist at that point?
Speaker 1: But you never would have existed because that time would be getting sucked in and then.
Speaker 1: so it's like you wouldn't even exist now If in the future you got sucked in.
Speaker 0: his actually was The analogy I used with someone else I was talking to at work who's as I was a PhD in this stuff Mm-hmm, and he said it was a pretty good analogy.
Speaker 0: Is that if you destroy the world in that way?
Speaker 0: It gets destroyed both directions in time simultaneously forward and backward.
Speaker 1: Here's is an interesting thing.
Speaker 1: I was reading up on it.
Speaker 1: So imagine this right?
Speaker 1: So let's say take a laser and you shoot the laser, right and you split it two ways.
Speaker 1: Okay, so now I'm on those left split and you're on the right split and we entangle them.
Speaker 1: Whoo, right?
Speaker 1: So then I twiddle my part of the laser and you're a part of the laser twiddles at the exact same time I twiddle.
Speaker 1: so if I twiddle the one Your side turns into one and if I twiddle zero your side twiddles to zero, right?
Speaker 1: So now we can communicate with this entangled laser.
Speaker 1: right now.
Speaker 1: This brings up two very interesting things to think about.
Speaker 1: number one Let's pretend we do the same exact thing with the laser.
Speaker 1: only I'm an andromeda and you're on earth.
Speaker 1: I twiddle to zero.
Speaker 1: it twiddles to zero by you at the same exact time.
Speaker 1: We are now somehow communicating faster than the speed of light.
Speaker 0: Well, because either causality or locality are broken.
Speaker 0: right then right?
Speaker 0: Well not broken, but that maybe they never really existed Right, so now here's interesting thought.
Speaker 1: number two, right?
Speaker 1: Okay, so, you know, we're assuming now that the laser split is like halfway between us.
Speaker 1: Let's say the laser splitter is right next to you.
Speaker 1: So you're like a foot away from it, but I'm an andromeda.
Speaker 0: Okay, I twiddle my.
Speaker 1: you twiddle your bit or I twiddle my bit and I forget which way it goes.
Speaker 1: But basically your bit would twiddle before I twiddled.
Speaker 1: so basically I'd be communicating with the past Because they would.
Speaker 1: you know the amount of it takes so long to get to the split from me But it only takes you so long much less time to get to the splitting.
Speaker 0: Well, there's also the trouble that while you know, there's the entanglement aside.
Speaker 0: You still can't transfer the in for actual information Really faster than the speed of light.
Speaker 0: This was explained to me and I don't really understand it.
Speaker 1: I'm starting to understand that part.
Speaker 0: I'm well that party was the idea that alright, so you can twiddle bits and they you know in real time in both places change or whatever.
Speaker 0: but Despite that you have to impart structure on that information which then takes more time and more to Italy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, here's here's the most I've been able to understand about the information part, right?
Speaker 1: So let's pretend you have a box.
Speaker 1: Okay, and the box has one particle in it, right?
Speaker 1: And if you know that the particle is in the right half of the box, then you could Partition the box right stick a plunger into the left half.
Speaker 1: You know that the half that doesn't have the particle.
Speaker 1: then remove the partition and you would get free energy Right just by knowing which half of the box the particle was in.
Speaker 1: But if you don't know Right, which half it's in then you're not going to be able to get the free energy because you don't know which side to go on right, so That's sort of like hey if you have information then you can cheat and obviously free energy ain't gonna happen.
Speaker 1: So that means there has to be something inherent in the information that is gonna somehow prevent you from getting the free energy.
Speaker 0: Well, it was like Timo pointed out on the farm information is energy and that's it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: it's like.
Speaker 1: well if I do this then I get free energy.
Speaker 1: Well, no you didn't because you spent the energy on the information itself of the knowing.
Speaker 0: but this whole LHC bokurato theory It's just really cool because it's so Plausible just in terms of the way we understand this quantum physics and the way the universe actually works that it it makes sense.
Speaker 1: It's just good to know that if somehow we don't know right, but if it is possible to destroy the universe in both directions in time That did not happen.
Speaker 1: Yes will not happen.
Speaker 1: That is that is comforting.
Speaker 0: So the argument there as I make is that we can only destroy the universe forward.
Speaker 0: We must continue to strive to destroy the universe in both directions.
Speaker 0: Then we'll find interesting stuff and we know we're safe.
Speaker 1: Yes But the thing is we have to act.
Speaker 1: we have to not accidentally destroy the universe forwards only.
Speaker 0: that would be bad Yep, or at least not destroy just the part of the universe.
Speaker 0: We're in that's also.
Speaker 0: that's probably easy to do.
Speaker 1: That's very easy to do.
Speaker 1: In fact, we can already do that.
Speaker 1: It's called the nuclear missile.
Speaker 0: But while you know, the theory is cool and I think pretty solid from a conceptual standpoint.
Speaker 0: But I don't think the LHC has anything.
Speaker 0: I don't think the LHC is causing that.
Speaker 0: I don't think this is the magnets failing and everything has anything to do with this theory.
Speaker 0: No And the quote from Teemo in the forum says it best.
Speaker 0: I could take it seriously if I hadn't personally met Holger Beck.
Speaker 1: Nielsen Is but I can imagine that this I've met Teemo so I know that he is a good judge of the This kind of person.
Speaker 1: I will trust his.
Speaker 1: you know that that's a crazy dude.
Speaker 0: So things of the day.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell this is an ad for the Karlsruhe Institute of Technology.
Speaker 1: Yes, Karlsruhe from 13 Texas.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: It's a jury.
Speaker 1: It's a city in Germany.
Speaker 1: Is that our state?
Speaker 1: I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: Yes yeah, so anyway, this is an ad for that.
Speaker 0: and they go around Germany asking people to pronounce Karlsruhe and Maha who shats?
Speaker 0: The Maha who shats Institute of Technology?
Speaker 0: by and large German people can't say the word, Massachusetts.
Speaker 1: Well, I can't say Karlsruhe German people.
Speaker 1: Tell me how to say it properly My Karlsruhe just like I'm laughing at their message.
Speaker 1: who was?
Speaker 1: I love nothing more than hearing people in foreign languages pronounce words in my Language, I also like hearing people like, you know, it's like if you you know You always do that.
Speaker 1: Like if you don't know Chinese or something, you can always be like, you know The French.
Speaker 1: Right, you can always you know do that right but it's great, you know It's like.
Speaker 1: I don't feel bad being racist or stereotypical doing that because I love it.
Speaker 1: when other people do that to you know English.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm sure that they love it.
Speaker 1: when I do it to their language.
Speaker 0: that Australian dude at Otacon was it was Doing what Americans do and he's like ah Welcome to America.
Speaker 0: Ah He's like you guys just really say your.
Speaker 1: obviously he's never been to Boston or New York.
Speaker 1: What do you got for me, oh so basically I Saw a link on the Internet's.
Speaker 1: that was like dude.
Speaker 1: So I was like drunk dude going to get more beer and I was like, alright, let me see.
Speaker 1: I Seen drunk dudes on the Internet.
Speaker 1: What's that famous guy from FARC?
Speaker 0: Oh, I forget his name.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the guy who's?
Speaker 1: there's a. there's a Firefox extension.
Speaker 0: Henry Earl See what he's up to.
Speaker 0: you keep talking.
Speaker 0: I'll see if he's been arrested again.
Speaker 1: this dude in this video Is that it's like.
Speaker 1: he's not so drunk.
Speaker 1: He's vomiting or as alcohol poisoning in the hospital, but that's the next step, right?
Speaker 1: He is like basically like at the maximum of the stumbling aspect of drunkenness.
Speaker 1: He is so stumble rific.
Speaker 1: It's like you can't even buy more beer and I think that's actually that's probably a good evolutionary Defense against drunkenness is that you know you get drunk?
Speaker 1: I think your body might be intentionally making you stumble about just so that you can't possibly get more drunk.
Speaker 1: It's like your body's defending itself from alcohol poisoning by making you so uncoordinated that you can't get more alcohol in your mouth Because this guy can't even walk through the convenience store.
Speaker 0: that has been the argument I've always used for why you put drinks in those upright glasses, you know, the fancy martini glass the triangle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because if you're drunk limiting glass it sure is Alright Henry Earl.
Speaker 1: Hey, why do they have like?
Speaker 1: don't they drink like sake out of a bowl?
Speaker 1: Isn't that sort of?
Speaker 1: uh, you know sometimes at least that's like but the you see the businessman.
Speaker 0: eventually They just grab the bottle.
Speaker 0: So Henry Earl as of October 6th 2009 he has been arrested five times in 2009. he has spent 276 days of this year in jail for alcohol.
Speaker 1: only for alcohol.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the only thing.
Speaker 0: he's ever been arrested only nine times this year man.
Speaker 1: I've spent pretty much the whole day in year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that sucks for four thousand four hundred and forty seven days in jail since 1992.
Speaker 0: Henry Earl, I salute you downtown James Brown.
Speaker 0: That's what he calls himself.
Speaker 1: really yeah, I guess that's the sort of kind of thing a drunk dude says, you know that All right, so the Amtrak story, you know, it's very sad.
Speaker 0: This elderly gentleman was hit by an Amtrak train and my commute and everyone was delayed for a long time.
Speaker 0: There are all these troubles and as far as I can tell Every police officer in the tri-county area arrived to deal with the situation.
Speaker 0: There were like a hundred police cars blocking like the entire train station at peak skill But what amazed me was that on the train, you know on my train the first train that was stopped by it No one would say what was happening.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: I even asked the conductor like hey, what's going on?
Speaker 0: He's like can't tell you like.
Speaker 1: no our conductor was just like yeah cargo hit by trade.
Speaker 0: No one would tell us what happened at any capacity at all.
Speaker 0: They just said there's a delay at peak skill.
Speaker 0: We will be sitting here for an indeterminate amount of time.
Speaker 0: They opened the doors on the train and let us get out at Cortland.
Speaker 0: and you know, they didn't know what was going on.
Speaker 0: I almost got off the train cuz there's an Indian restaurant.
Speaker 0: I found on Google Maps like an hour away an hour.
Speaker 1: You're gonna walk it out.
Speaker 0: Sorry, I'll buy a mile away.
Speaker 0: Oh I'm real tired because I'm working the night shift this week.
Speaker 0: I'm going straight from this to work.
Speaker 1: Geek morning, sir.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh my god Plus my throat's kind of scratchy from yelling and talking at the party all night at the wedding over the weekend.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so, you know, I'm on this train and no one knows what's going on.
Speaker 0: So I pull out the smartphone and I find out what's going on.
Speaker 0: I found out exactly what's going on and it took me like five minutes of Twitter and SMS to find out exactly what was going On.
Speaker 0: Yep, so I kind of say out loud cuz you know, it's a there's a weird situation going on.
Speaker 0: Everyone's kind of friendly on the train and talking to each other about.
Speaker 0: you know, like man what's going on?
Speaker 0: I don't know man.
Speaker 0: Maybe we should just skip and go to a bar.
Speaker 0: Are there even bars around here?
Speaker 0: Are there restaurants?
Speaker 0: I don't know and I just too bad.
Speaker 1: You couldn't be in Cold Spring.
Speaker 1: There's like that our peak skills like a bar right next to the train set up.
Speaker 0: So I just say out loud Do get it by Amtrak.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and everyone on the train gets silent.
Speaker 0: They're like, really?
Speaker 0: How'd you figure that out?
Speaker 0: Oh my god, like how do you know?
Speaker 0: And I held up my phone and I was like I have the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have a smartphone.
Speaker 0: and then I realized that almost every other person in that car Also had a smartphone but they they did not have a smart user.
Speaker 0: Not only that most of them were using their smartphones at that moment and none of them could figure out How I had found this information.
Speaker 0: and I was like smartphone.
Speaker 0: and they're like, you know, I held it up.
Speaker 0: I'm like, yeah, I just looked and found out and they're like, how'd you find out Google?
Speaker 0: I'm like Google News Twitter SMSing the people in other trains on the train line Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It did not cross any of their minds to do this and then I realized step back a little bit.
Speaker 0: All those guys are like man.
Speaker 0: Are there any restaurants around here?
Speaker 0: Is it worth it to get off the train?
Speaker 0: Is there anywhere we could even go?
Speaker 1: you already use Google Maps?
Speaker 0: I already knew.
Speaker 0: I already looked up.
Speaker 0: There was a couple in the restaurant like a mile away.
Speaker 0: There was like a bar a half mile away.
Speaker 0: There were plenty of places.
Speaker 1: It's not just mobile things either, you know, how many times you know?
Speaker 1: There's a reason that there's that.
Speaker 1: let me google that for you website.
Speaker 1: It's because someone will go on like a disguise.
Speaker 1: isn't that weird?
Speaker 1: like someone let's say someone's in like, I don't know.
Speaker 1: They're.
Speaker 1: they're a big fan of a football team, right?
Speaker 1: So they hang out on some communal PHP BB forum for their particular football team.
Speaker 1: they talk to all these other football fans and maybe they'll have a problem with their home theater or Their computer or their car, right?
Speaker 1: And that's the only internet community that they're in.
Speaker 1: So what they'll do is they'll post like some off-topic thread like hey, what should I do about my car?
Speaker 1: It's like it's a football forum.
Speaker 1: What the fuck is wrong with you?
Speaker 1: You know, it's because they don't you know, it's it's that old situation of when you have a have a hammer Everything looks like nails, you know.
Speaker 1: people don't you know, they use what they got, you know, and they don't branch out.
Speaker 1: I can't tell you how many.
Speaker 1: like tech help questions I see and like comic book forums It's like what is wrong with you?
Speaker 1: people here are comic book people.
Speaker 1: They don't know shit about computers.
Speaker 1: Go ask your question on super user stack overflow or something, but they don't even know those places exist.
Speaker 0: and this now I realized on the train and we were gonna do a show on this if we hadn't been distracted by unrelated issues for the whole last week and a half and change.
Speaker 0: but People have these crazy technology tool.
Speaker 0: It's not just like the internet like this is going beyond.
Speaker 0: just people don't know how to use the internet.
Speaker 0: No, yeah Like.
Speaker 1: I think it's just like people.
Speaker 1: it's like driving a car don't know how to use the cruise control Got a VCR didn't know that you could program it to do certain things.
Speaker 0: You you think Scott's joking?
Speaker 0: I've met people who don't know what cruise control does.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like seriously like.
Speaker 0: they're like.
Speaker 0: They're like, oh, yeah I never use the management Superman How to get it to work.
Speaker 1: Imagine if Superman didn't know he had like the freeze breath, which he has.
Speaker 1: that's what's going on here Right.
Speaker 1: It's like people have all these things.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, and they have all these abilities.
Speaker 1: Oh, I didn't know that I could set my air conditioner to turn on like eight hours after I leave the house.
Speaker 1: Oh, I didn't know that I could you know set my crock-pot to turn on, you know, four hours or something something.
Speaker 0: But it's starting to be a not really a problem for me because it makes me a wizard in the real world.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it's great because I have a smartphone.
Speaker 0: It used to be you know when when if one person in a group of geeks had a smartphone they were the wizard because you'd all be arguing like Man, what are the word barbecue come from?
Speaker 0: I think it's this.
Speaker 0: I think it's that and then Wizard goes smartphone Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Here's the answer.
Speaker 0: I did that on the way to the wedding.
Speaker 0: We looked up the etymology of barbecue.
Speaker 1: Oh, what was it?
Speaker 0: It's really cool.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I also learned about thug and buccaneer comes from the same kind of root as barbecue real.
Speaker 0: Yeah Get some ribs All right, but I thought all right once everyone has smartphones No one can be wizards anymore.
Speaker 0: and in geek communities among smart people.
Speaker 0: That was true.
Speaker 1: That's absolutely true.
Speaker 1: You'll say everyone will go to the Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: It'll be a race.
Speaker 0: Yes, we have the separate thing.
Speaker 0: We race to see who is the fastest wizard.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's it's a Harry Potter wizard battles.
Speaker 1: I never even read that much Harry Potter.
Speaker 1: They even have wizard battles.
Speaker 1: They must have wizard bezel.
Speaker 0: They have to try wizard.
Speaker 0: Well anyway, yeah, so Among normal people.
Speaker 0: I'm still a wizard.
Speaker 0: cuz no one in any way that everyone has a smartphone.
Speaker 0: No one even realizes they can look stuff up on the internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's you know, I think what it is.
Speaker 1: it's like People only you know, like they only know how to use what they got.
Speaker 1: It's the same situation where you know, I people like putting a database in excels because they got excel They know how to use it.
Speaker 0: I think it's beyond that.
Speaker 0: I think it's a cultural almost zebra storyteller situation to where They think they have a problem like I need to know X and they may know a solution.
Speaker 0: like I could look it up online.
Speaker 0: But they don't at any point connect.
Speaker 0: I can look it up online On my phone like they don't even think of their phone as the tool to solve that problem because they the first thought they have.
Speaker 1: People don't even know to look it up online.
Speaker 1: Normally, I have to be like google.
Speaker 1: it buy it online.
Speaker 1: How many times do I tell people that like just google it just buy it on Amazon?
Speaker 1: people come to me Where should I buy this?
Speaker 1: amazon.com where you could buy absolutely anything that exists in the entire universe, you know.
Speaker 1: That's why it's a to z.
Speaker 0: Look stuff up on cars and houses.
Speaker 0: They don't think like it's like their brain has a checklist of.
Speaker 0: it goes through the list of I need to know X. How do I achieve this?
Speaker 0: it goes like down the list?
Speaker 0: Like if this maybe I'll do this.
Speaker 0: try this try this try.
Speaker 0: this phone is not anywhere on that list.
Speaker 0: It just isn't there.
Speaker 0: They just they never even conceive of using the phone to solve the problem.
Speaker 0: And the weird thing is I see them using the phones but like on the train I've lately whenever I walk on the train I walk all I get on the train at the first car and I walk all the way down and I look at what everyone Is doing with their technology?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm starting to do this.
Speaker 1: laptops usually watching DVDs.
Speaker 1: People some people, you know playing some video games.
Speaker 1: a lot of people with blackberries playing brick breaker check an email.
Speaker 0: Here's what bothers me.
Speaker 0: I would say the majority of people I see with technology are playing solitaire.
Speaker 0: Yes, a lot of people playing solid see people with gigantic laptops like a super powerful laptop And they open it up and they're playing solitaire on the laptop.
Speaker 0: like really Honestly, that's what you're doing.
Speaker 0: You have all this.
Speaker 0: you have technology.
Speaker 0: 90 minutes on a train Technology to never be bored ever in your life anywhere again forever.
Speaker 0: But I was a kid.
Speaker 1: I've thing is I've never seen anyone with with a evdu card, you know or some internet connectivity Playing solitaire.
Speaker 1: They're usually out looking and such.
Speaker 0: Yes Well, that's because it's mostly business people whose companies pay for them.
Speaker 0: or exactly they're surfing the internet doing nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I don't see that many evdu cards to be honest on the train and a handful kind of suck.
Speaker 0: I like one per car.
Speaker 0: They stop working a croton harm.
Speaker 1: They do it sucks.
Speaker 0: I Don't get like any service a croton Harmon who the hell lives there?
Speaker 1: Well, there's that big cell tower that they put up right next to it.
Speaker 1: But it's like because you're under the tower It doesn't help you.
Speaker 1: you need to be a little bit far away from it in order for it.
Speaker 1: You know because it aims, you know line of sight ish So if you're directly under it, it's like well, it's not aiming straight at the ground You know, that would be sort of a waste of the energy Because most of you get service, I guess if you're a mole man, it's it's.
Speaker 1: yeah They don't want the mole men to get service.
Speaker 1: They don't aim it at the ground right under it.
Speaker 0: But I just it amazes me and I don't know what to do.
Speaker 0: I don't have any idea for this show beyond pointing out that people are stupid.
Speaker 0: They don't use the technology.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what it is.
Speaker 1: I think just you know, if you ever have any problem whatsoever Right, you need to really put in a strong effort You know to think the technology solves all problems like not all problems But like 99% of problems every day mundane issues that people have can be solved with the existing Technology Google that can do 75% of it.
Speaker 1: Amazon can do like another five to ten percent, right?
Speaker 1: and you just have to get in the habit of Always just look for a technological solution always don't like and you know Don't like fall onto things, you know, just you know, go and maximize find and you know, they you know There's an app for that, you know, there's a website for that.
Speaker 1: go out and find it.
Speaker 1: Don't just go to the website.
Speaker 1: You already know, you know, don't just keep doing things.
Speaker 0: You know, what if you already know Google?
Speaker 1: Then you're all set.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think it's a more fundamental thing.
Speaker 1: The thing is even people who do know Google have really shitty Google skills, like they can't find shit on Google.
Speaker 1: I find it with like one query.
Speaker 1: In fact rim really sucks at Google.
Speaker 1: How so you always take like a whole bunch of searches to find something.
Speaker 1: I find it like two seconds mean example.
Speaker 1: I'm an example.
Speaker 1: It's mostly I think what it is that I'll be like rim.
Speaker 1: Just look this up and you're like god takes so long.
Speaker 1: It's so much effort and I'm like boom two seconds I find it.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's just because I'm a jerk and I'm annoyed at the fact that you rather than giving me a link you tell me to Google it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz googling it should take two seconds.
Speaker 1: Googling is easier than finding a link, but you're the one.
Speaker 1: you have Google skills You wouldn't you know, it's it's like up there it is But it's something.
Speaker 0: if you go to someone you're like, hey check out this video.
Speaker 0: I saw Google for it.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: well, you won't even put forward the effort to give me a link.
Speaker 0: I don't care about what you're trying to show me.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 1: The thing is giving you a link is a lot more effort than googling.
Speaker 1: Yeah, are you that shitty at googling that you can't just boom get it on the first query?
Speaker 0: No, it's more than if you aren't willing to put for it.
Speaker 0: It's like a barrier to entry to get my attention.
Speaker 0: That's the way I look at it.
Speaker 1: I just You suck at googling and it's so much, you know, it shouldn't be that much work for you to just get it Boom done.
Speaker 0: I don't even do it.
Speaker 0: I mean bother.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know It's cuz you suck.
Speaker 0: But the I think it's a more fundamental problem even beyond technology.
Speaker 0: I think people just don't have basic troubleshooting skills.
Speaker 1: Well troubleshooting skills is a separate problem entirely.
Speaker 0: when I say troubleshooting I mean life like problem solving like I have four matches and a duck and a boat and I have to solve this problem.
Speaker 0: and it's like people don't even like.
Speaker 0: and the problem is like Get across the river and like they won't think to use the boat.
Speaker 0: They're like try to make a raft out of the matchsticks and drown Like that is what's happening and I don't know what to do.
Speaker 1: I think see I don't even think it's.
Speaker 1: yeah I think it's actually two sort of separate problems.
Speaker 1: you put them together.
Speaker 1: is troubleshooting skills is like, you know It's like there's a you don't even try to solve.
Speaker 1: the problem is is what we're talking about here, right?
Speaker 1: It's like thing doesn't work.
Speaker 1: Don't even try, you know, they don't even consider that solving the problem is an option.
Speaker 1: That is the problem.
Speaker 1: troubleshooting skills is okay.
Speaker 1: now you're forced to try to solve the problem and They don't know to use the process of elimination.
Speaker 1: that's a lack of troubleshooting skills.
Speaker 1: We have to get to the troubleshooting part first.
Speaker 1: They don't even try to solve the problem to begin with, you know, they don't even activate their shitty troubleshooting mechanism There's.
Speaker 1: so they don't even know they have the troubleshooting mechanism to begin with just like Superman doesn't know he has freeze breath.
Speaker 0: So, how do we foster this in people?
Speaker 0: how do we teach people to solve problems?
Speaker 0: It's not that hard It's like let's see.
Speaker 0: I want a sandwich.
Speaker 0: Do I go get a sandwich or not?
Speaker 0: How do you get someone to that level of realizing they can go get a sandwich?
Speaker 1: I actually think that if you look at something like the you know scribble knots, which is not a good game, right?
Speaker 1: But actually it has a very good model for teaching people this sort of thing, which is you know Give someone a problem to solve right then However, they solved it take away the tool and then force them to do it again and force them to do it again.
Speaker 1: And if people solve problems even the same problem over and over again with different tools Instead of you know people tend to learn like tools and they don't learn too many tools because they don't like learning or they Don't feel like they like learning at least I don't know or they're adverse to learning things even if for whatever reason They will try to do as much as possible as they can with the few tools that they are very comfortable with and very learned With and I think forcing people to just learn more tools even just have cursory level knowledge of a wider variety of tools.
Speaker 1: Eventually you reach some sort of point where you actually choose tools when you have a problem to solve rather than just Picking up the tool that you already know immediately and then stretching it as far as you can possibly stretch it, you know We should apply this education.
Speaker 1: though How much people try to do with Excel Excel should really really only be used if you have numbers and you need graphs and charts or accounting or something like that.
Speaker 1: Otherwise No Excel.
Speaker 0: No, I Just said they don't even get to the point of using the tools So they don't even realize they have a problem or they don't realize the problem is solved.
Speaker 1: a lot of people just you know They don't even realize they have problems and if they do they don't even try to solve them.
Speaker 1: They just go.
Speaker 1: They just.
Speaker 1: it's just something they'll always complain about, you know, it's like doesn't it suck, you know?
Speaker 0: I just think of that Gervais comedy on Thought.
Speaker 1: yeah, right It's like people just have these things and they just sort of take it as a complaint with life like oh man It doesn't it suck?
Speaker 1: how you know?
Speaker 1: VCRs are so hard to program.
Speaker 1: They always go 12 and you know, just like everyone would be like, yeah, doesn't that suck?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: you can program the VCR.
Speaker 1: damn it You can do it.
Speaker 1: or it's like oh man, doesn't it suck?
Speaker 1: how you can't do this?
Speaker 1: It's like yes you can.
Speaker 1: you didn't even think about trying to fix it.
Speaker 0: Option is to not bother trying to help our fellow man in this situation and just be Wizards.
Speaker 0: the thing is it doesn't it doesn't Train and these people are all like I need food blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: and I was like There's a restaurant here and there's a restaurant here and there's restaurant here.
Speaker 0: and they had no idea how I got this magic information.
Speaker 0: It was kind of a powerful cool feeling to be a wizard to be able to just Lord this over people like that to be Like look I have power that you will never achieve.
Speaker 0: Look at my technology that you also have in your pocket, but you don't know to use.
Speaker 1: I know right?
Speaker 1: It's like and we're so worried.
Speaker 1: This is why I think it's sort of silly to sort of regulate things in a in a commercial way.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, oh we can't let anyone have you know CD burners because then they'll all pirate music or whatever It's like people aren't smart enough to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, why aren't?
Speaker 1: why isn't everyone in the world downloading music from the Pirate Bay?
Speaker 1: It's not because people don't want free music or they have some moral qualms so they're worried about the law.
Speaker 1: It's cuz they're too dumb.
Speaker 1: You know Why is everyone buying games on the virtual console?
Speaker 1: because they are too dumb to even know that an emulator is something that could possibly Exist.
Speaker 0: we own a lot of virtual console games.
Speaker 1: I know but I'm just saying right It's it's cuz.
Speaker 1: people just they you know, I mean, I'm surprised It's so many people have like those deep the DSR for cards, you know that amazes me Yeah, but yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I think we're done cuz I gotta go to work.
Speaker 1: Yeah Think about any time you have a complaint or anything is making you unhappy.
Speaker 1: Look for a technology that will solve it.
Speaker 1: It's probably a technology you don't already know and it's probably worth it to learn.
Speaker 1: and Google is your friend Don't if you ask me anything?
Speaker 1: people know this.
Speaker 1: if you ask me anything that is answered by Google I'm just gonna you know, go ha ha ha you suck.
Speaker 1: So don't do that.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Speaker 1: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.