Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, May 6th.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, we review Naoki Urasawa's Monster.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So, I think we've mentioned it a couple times, but we haven't actually done a big deal about it, but just in case, we're gonna be at Anime Boston for the first time ever this year.
Speaker 1: Oh my gosh, Boston.
Speaker 1: We got all these people we know in Boston, but it's like, we've never gone to see them because we never go to Boston.
Speaker 0: I know, I've never even been to Boston.
Speaker 1: I've been to Boston like a hundred times, you know, in the first 18 years of my life, and zero times in the past nine years of my life.
Speaker 0: This is gonna be interesting though, because one, it's a new anime con, and even if you're jaded...
Speaker 1: Well, it's not new, but it's new to us.
Speaker 0: It's new to us, but going to a con you've never been to before, even if you've been to a million anime cons and you're jaded, there's something about the new con.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, yeah, it's like there's a lot of, you know, stuff that you haven't seen before, you know, hopefully, and at the very least you're learning a new building, you know, learn new restaurants.
Speaker 0: Yeah, hang out in Boston.
Speaker 1: Plus friends that we don't see too often.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we're doing a whole bunch of panels at Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: Now, if you've seen us at all of the other cons that we go to, we're doing a lot of the same name panels, but we've upped the ante.
Speaker 0: So, if you think you saw Anime You Should See, you should probably see Anime You Should See at Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: Uh-oh.
Speaker 0: We've upped it.
Speaker 0: We've put it over 9,000 or so.
Speaker 1: Oh, shit.
Speaker 0: And out of the blue, we're also going to do Beyond Dungeons and Dragons again.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: See, I don't mind doing a repeat panel, as long as it's not a repeat at the same convention.
Speaker 0: Now, that's not necessarily a bad thing.
Speaker 0: What if it's a con that's so big and the room just wasn't big enough?
Speaker 1: I have to have, like, some sort of guarantee that there's no one seeing it twice.
Speaker 1: Especially if someone who hasn't seen it wants to see it.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe we'll have to do something like that for PAX.
Speaker 0: At the beginning, if anyone is in the room who's already seen the panel, we'll kick them out.
Speaker 0: I think that's the only way to go about it.
Speaker 0: Of course, we might have a bigger room for that, but Anime Boston, Memorial Day weekend, May 22nd to 24th at the Heinz Convention Center and Sheraton Boston Hotel in Boston?
Speaker 0: Anime Boston?
Speaker 1: Boston, Massachusetts.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I don't think there are many other Bostons.
Speaker 0: If you end up at another Boston, I'm sorry, but we're not going to do a panel there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sorry.
Speaker 0: I think it'll be fun.
Speaker 0: We're not doing that many panels.
Speaker 0: We're doing enough to where we'll, you know, have a presence at the con and all that stuff, but we'll actually be able to hang out.
Speaker 0: So, if you tried to talk to us at Otacon and we blew you off and disappeared, we can actually talk to you at Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: This will be a big change for us.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So, if people did not know, last Saturday was Free Comic Book Day.
Speaker 1: And for every year of Geek Nights, we've always done a Free Comic Book Day episode, every time.
Speaker 1: I don't know if we're going to do one this year.
Speaker 1: Let me, let me do, this will be your replacement for a Free Comic Book Day episode.
Speaker 1: First of all, right, a lot of the comics on Free Comic Book Day are more of the same.
Speaker 1: For example, every year there is a free Bongo Comics for All, that is basically the Simpsons, Futurama, Matt Groening property comic, right?
Speaker 1: And it's the same quality stuff every year.
Speaker 1: It's no different.
Speaker 1: And it's sort of, you know, there are very few, I mean, there's an Atomic Robo comic this year.
Speaker 1: There was one last year.
Speaker 1: There's an Owly this year.
Speaker 1: There was an Owly last year.
Speaker 1: And there's so few that are new from year to year that there's not much use in, you know, going over them again.
Speaker 0: So what about the new ones?
Speaker 0: I'm sure they're all amazing.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is, right, I went down to the Dragon's Den.
Speaker 1: And the Dragon's Den, you know, for what problems the store may have, is awesome on Free Comic Book Day, because they allow you to take one of each, and they usually get some of each.
Speaker 0: I feel, though, like every good comic shop will let you do that.
Speaker 1: No, the vast majority of comic shops are like, take, pick two.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and hence, I said, every good comic shop.
Speaker 1: Right, so the Dragon's Den lets you take one of each, which is why I always go there, so I can get one of each.
Speaker 1: And that's the only reason we're able to do these Free Comic Book Day episodes that cover all these comics, because I can go and get one of each for us.
Speaker 1: Now, I did go there, and I did get one of each and got a bunch.
Speaker 0: Well, I actually haven't been to the Dragon's Den in like...
Speaker 1: There's no reason to go there.
Speaker 0: Almost a year.
Speaker 1: There's nothing there for you.
Speaker 1: Now, what was awesome is I sort of always feel bad going in there every year and getting all these comics and not buying anything.
Speaker 1: But they had a huge sale simultaneously on comics.
Speaker 1: It was 40% off, everything.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what this means to me?
Speaker 0: The cynic reading into this is that...
Speaker 1: They're getting rid of comics.
Speaker 0: They're giving up on comics because they're not profitable, they don't bring anyone into the store, and they've had the kind of weak selection in the back for a long time anyway.
Speaker 1: It did look like they were sort of, like the trade selection was mad weak.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they're buying any more trades there, but I think they might keep the single-issue business going.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: Just, you know, for the people who come in every week.
Speaker 0: I feel like they make all their money off of Microsoft.
Speaker 1: Because they don't have any local comic shop competition, you know?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, what other comic shops?
Speaker 0: There's that one down here in New Bern.
Speaker 1: I don't know if that one's still open.
Speaker 1: That one was so shady.
Speaker 0: That was like, I mean, I've been to shady...
Speaker 1: That was the stereotypical bad comic shop taken to the extreme.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's the kind of place where the owner is surly and like, "You're not buying
Speaker 0: anything?".
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So anyway, apparently... They had the mind to shelf.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the guy at the Dragon's Den, right?
Speaker 1: The guy I always see there?
Speaker 1: He said, you know, "Yeah, we're always, you know, we like to give one of
Speaker 1: each.".
Speaker 1: But he's like, "People came in here at 10 o'clock and I had two tables
Speaker 1: covered.".
Speaker 1: Because he had every single free comic book day comic.
Speaker 1: He bought some of everything.
Speaker 1: Of course, he bought more of the Marvel and DC ones and less of the other ones, of course, right?
Speaker 1: But he got some of everything.
Speaker 1: And at 10 o'clock, people busted in and they like took one of everything.
Speaker 1: Like some lady took one of everything and he was like, "Are you going to read all
Speaker 1: those?".
Speaker 1: She's like, "No, but why not?
Speaker 1: They're all free,
Speaker 1: right?".
Speaker 1: So the thing was, I would have read them all.
Speaker 1: So as a result of that, you know, I wasn't able to get many of the less popular, better ones.
Speaker 1: The only one I really wanted, I think there was like a Ninja Turtles 25th anniversary one.
Speaker 1: You know, there were some other good ones, but I didn't want them too badly.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so I don't think we're going to do a free comic book day episode this year.
Speaker 1: But that's the free comic book day news for you.
Speaker 1: What I do want to do is, you know, I do the Scott's box off and on, mostly off, right?
Speaker 0: I found a bunch of them when I was cleaning off the video on the tape recorder.
Speaker 1: See, the question is, you know, those are just sort of, you know, they're sort of like one and done, right?
Speaker 1: Turn on the camera.
Speaker 1: I do it and I turn the camera off and they're not really edited.
Speaker 1: So I was like, should I edit them or should I just upload them the way they are?
Speaker 1: Anyway, so, yeah, so so I want to discuss because people don't seem to realize this.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You order comics two months in advance.
Speaker 1: So you think, OK, if you order comics two months in advance, what month is the big order going to be in?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You think, well, when do people buy the most comics?
Speaker 1: And you might think, well, maybe they buy them on the holidays.
Speaker 1: So the big order comes in December, November, October, October must be the big month.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: No, it's not October.
Speaker 1: Well, free comic days, a big month in May.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So maybe, you know, April, March, March must be the big month.
Speaker 1: No, it's not March.
Speaker 1: The big month is May because in June, July is the San Diego Comic Con.
Speaker 0: Ah, there's a good chance.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure you go in and out there heading down there.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: OK, I'd like to go there one day, but it's just too much.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what?
Speaker 1: I was actually with limited vacations.
Speaker 0: Well, I got plenty of vacation.
Speaker 0: I would if I weren't going to, you know, both taxes instead.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: OK, so anyway, in honor of the big order month, I'm going to.
Speaker 1: I'm going to tell you the goods I'm buying here, some of which is very notable.
Speaker 1: Are you ready?
Speaker 1: I'm just going to.
Speaker 1: I'm going to try to do it quickly and not dwell.
Speaker 1: The much delayed Gunsmith Cat's Burst Volume four.
Speaker 1: Uncle Scrooge statue number two, which is Donald Duck.
Speaker 0: Oh, so so you went for it.
Speaker 0: You couldn't pass that up.
Speaker 1: I have a job now.
Speaker 0: So you're going to have these big busts.
Speaker 1: They're not busting a full statue.
Speaker 1: If it was a bust, I wouldn't have bought it.
Speaker 1: I don't like busts.
Speaker 1: They're kind of stupid.
Speaker 0: What if it was a bust of Scrooge McDuck?
Speaker 1: No, it's not good.
Speaker 0: A high quality bronze one.
Speaker 1: You mean like a full like a big one, like the kind that you can tilt the head back and push a button and then a door opens?
Speaker 0: Yes, I'm talking a proper and full bust of Scrooge McDuck.
Speaker 1: This is a series of small statues and metal cases, so that's whatever.
Speaker 1: There is a new comic from Vertigo.
Speaker 1: And whenever they have a new comic, the first issue is always cheap.
Speaker 1: I think it's a dollar.
Speaker 1: And with my discount, it's twenty five cents called Greek Street.
Speaker 1: So we'll see what that's about.
Speaker 0: Greek Street.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Look that up.
Speaker 0: You you keep talking.
Speaker 1: That's the new comic from vertical, not vertical vertigo that's coming out.
Speaker 1: Fables Volume twelve.
Speaker 1: Spider-Man number six hundred, which is five dollars, but it's supposed to be like one hundred something pages.
Speaker 1: So why the fuck not?
Speaker 1: Incredible Hulk.
Speaker 1: Six hundred people said you're going to find out who the Red Hulk is or whatever.
Speaker 0: What about the Blue Hulk?
Speaker 0: The Orange Hulk?
Speaker 1: No, this is a red one.
Speaker 1: It's been a story for a while.
Speaker 1: I got the first issue of the Red Hulk and I thought it was stupid, so I didn't get any more.
Speaker 1: And it's pretty much just like I only care who the Red Hulk is.
Speaker 1: The story is stupid.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh, oh.
Speaker 0: Do you know what Greek Street is about?
Speaker 1: What's it about?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I'm stealing this from someone else who stole it from someone else.
Speaker 0: So I'm quoting someone, but I'm not even going to try to figure out who originally said this.
Speaker 0: It's it's nothing like anything you've ever read before, according to some guy who are the artists and the writer, Peter Milligan.
Speaker 0: OK, I don't know who that is, to be honest.
Speaker 0: Now, I mean, the Greek Street is a street in London that runs through Soho.
Speaker 0: And Soho is kind of like our red light district.
Speaker 0: It's all the low lives and gangsters.
Speaker 0: This story is a reimagining and retelling of those fantastic and brutal and visceral Greek legends played out on these modern streets.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: I'm looking forward to this.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we got Marvel 1985.
Speaker 1: Remember, 1602.
Speaker 1: Well, this is sort of like 1985.
Speaker 0: Sixteen or two was good, but it didn't really need to be Marvel.
Speaker 1: No, not really.
Speaker 1: But I mean, the Thor reveal was just awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But spoiler.
Speaker 1: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: I mean, that Thor reveals one of the best reveals ever.
Speaker 1: I'd say top 10, at least primarily because it's Thor.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, if anyone else, there's no other superhero that could be revealed in any way that I would care about at all.
Speaker 1: But Thor is mainly that I didn't see it come.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: Annihilation classic and trade paperback.
Speaker 1: This was released in hardcover before and I was pissed.
Speaker 1: Now it's in trade.
Speaker 1: The boys trade paperback.
Speaker 1: Number four, Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles 25th anniversary.
Speaker 1: This is what there was a free comic day comic for.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So fuck, I'll just buy it if they're good.
Speaker 1: Dick Tracy, volume eight, Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles collected book volume one.
Speaker 1: So if people don't realize this, it was it's common knowledge that Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles was originally a comic book by Eastman and Laird a long time ago.
Speaker 1: And that, you know, the cartoon and what you know, is nothing like the original comic book.
Speaker 1: And the original comic book has been hard to get, you know, for normal people for a very long time.
Speaker 0: Even now with the Internet.
Speaker 0: I mean, I remember when I was a kid, you know, watching the old cartoon and having the toys and everything, we're all into turtles.
Speaker 0: We're all playing the games.
Speaker 0: But there was kind of this underground legend among the kids that there was some previous Ninja Turtles.
Speaker 0: that was all cool.
Speaker 1: And I was in high school.
Speaker 1: The Akira Mongo is like this legend.
Speaker 1: And now I have it all.
Speaker 1: So this is going to be the sort of the same thing.
Speaker 1: We're like, you know, yes, I know that Ninja Turtles is originally this awesome indie comic.
Speaker 1: Well, now normal people can finally get it in trade paperback.
Speaker 1: Cursed Pirate Girl number three of three member who told us to buy?
Speaker 1: Dave Peterson told us to buy that atomic robo shadow from beyond time for five surrogates.
Speaker 1: Volume two flesh and bone.
Speaker 0: I'm still waiting for a surrogates movie.
Speaker 1: 20th Century Boys, volume four, Pokemon Adventures, volume two.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And there's one more thing I want to talk about a little bit more.
Speaker 1: It's called Wednesday Comics, right?
Speaker 1: Let me let me explain this to you.
Speaker 1: Wednesday Comics is coming from
Speaker 1: D.C.,
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: Now, back in the day, way back in the day, you would get things like when you bought a newspaper, you would get a comics insert like the spirit was like this section in the newspaper.
Speaker 1: That's what the spirit was.
Speaker 1: It wasn't like a comic book on the shelf.
Speaker 1: You know, the spirit was this insert into the newspaper.
Speaker 1: It was big like newspaper bag in full color.
Speaker 1: It was crazy.
Speaker 1: And that would just come in the newspaper.
Speaker 1: You didn't buy it on its own.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So what D.C.
Speaker 1: is doing, it says here, let me read this little story here.
Speaker 1: I'm going to put a link to this in the show at a time when many newspapers are cutting back or dying, cutting back in the comic sections.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: D.C.
Speaker 1: is trying to remind people of the fun and excitement of full Sunday size comic section, even at a time like this, even at a time like this, except they're going to do it on Wednesday, because that's the day that new comic books are at the comic book store.
Speaker 1: That's why it's called Wednesday Comics as opposed to Sunday Comics.
Speaker 1: This is a 12 part series.
Speaker 1: So there's going to be 12 issues, right?
Speaker 1: It's going to be weekly.
Speaker 1: So that means four issues a month.
Speaker 1: So three months, right?
Speaker 1: July, August, September.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So you preorder in May, June, July to get all of them.
Speaker 1: So I'm buying all four of these.
Speaker 1: And you might say, wait, Scott, why are you buying these normal issues?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: What is wrong with you?
Speaker 1: Don't you wait for the trade?
Speaker 1: I would indeed wait for the trade.
Speaker 1: In fact, I considered waiting for the trade until I read this part.
Speaker 1: That is next.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 1: The 12 part series launching this summer.
Speaker 1: that will be presented in a 14 inch by 20 inch broadsheet format.
Speaker 1: It will have to be unfolded and open to be read now for let's see, like four dollars an issue.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, it's only what, 16 pages an issue.
Speaker 1: It's not many pages, but 16 times four because you're folding it out into being four times the size.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So what's that?
Speaker 1: Like sixty four because forty and then twenty four is sixty four.
Speaker 0: So all I need to do to get you to buy stuff is to make it bigger.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, it's more for your money, right?
Speaker 1: That's the whole point.
Speaker 0: Is that all that matters?
Speaker 0: Well, that's all to be good.
Speaker 1: Right now.
Speaker 1: Wait, here is.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So if that alone doesn't sell you, allow me to read the creator list.
Speaker 1: Are you ready for the creators?
Speaker 0: Are you ready?
Speaker 0: No, not at all.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: Kyle Baker, Neil Gaiman, all red.
Speaker 1: As are
Speaker 1: L.O.,
Speaker 1: Paul Pope, Walt Simonson, Dave Bullock, Dave Givens, Ryan Sook, Jonna Crudy, Lee Bermejo, Joe Kubert, Ben Caldwell, Kurt Busiek, basically all huge names.
Speaker 0: See, this is interesting because I really feel like now is the time, especially, you know, people are saying the economy may have hit the bottom and it might start recovering in the industry, all the industries, every industry is in flux right now.
Speaker 0: Now is the time to hit the market and hit the ground running with something different.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Now is the time to hit.
Speaker 1: And that was just something different.
Speaker 1: But to go for quality as opposed to quantity.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Because if people.
Speaker 1: If people are spending less.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They're not going to be looking, you know, to get more.
Speaker 1: You know, people are trying to get rid of stuff.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They're selling their gold.
Speaker 1: They're selling stuff, giving stuff away.
Speaker 1: People want less stuff right now.
Speaker 1: They want to get rid of stuff and have more money, which means if they buy things, they they're going to be looking for fewer quality things, not a bunch of cheap crap they don't need.
Speaker 0: Well, the smart people, at least.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: So now is the time to make, you know, quality things, things that stand out from the you know, the crowd, things that are more interesting, not something that someone, you know, is looking at and compares it to the stuff they're selling on Craigslist and said, I'm not going to buy that.
Speaker 1: I'm selling something just like that.
Speaker 1: So this is a good road to go down.
Speaker 1: And I mean, they got me to order for comics sight unseen for four dollars each, given there's a major discount on them because I go to DCV service.
Speaker 1: But, you know, regardless.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So this is is something special here.
Speaker 1: You should look out and, you know, even if you don't preorder in July, go to the comic store once a week on Wednesday and buy the copy of Wednesday comics and watch out.
Speaker 0: It's coming.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's good.
Speaker 1: You probably won't be able to miss it.
Speaker 1: It's it'll look like a comic book, but it'll fold out.
Speaker 1: You know, it'll stand out on the shelf.
Speaker 0: The Internet will be all the Twitter about it.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It's already a Twitter ring.
Speaker 0: So much more expected and at the same time, sad news.
Speaker 0: If you missed it, CPM is actually gone.
Speaker 0: They're declaring full on Chapter seven bankruptcy.
Speaker 0: That's the end.
Speaker 1: It's kind of weird because it's like there's a lot of anime companies out there and other companies in various niche areas.
Speaker 1: that sort of.
Speaker 1: they don't go out of business.
Speaker 1: They just sort of enter this holding pattern where, like, they're not bringing in big revenues, but they just don't spend anything.
Speaker 1: They just stop doing business.
Speaker 1: They just sort of sit there.
Speaker 1: And, you know, the revenue, as long as the revenue isn't zero, the money sort of trickles in, you know, and they just sort of let it sit and they don't have to go bankrupt or anything.
Speaker 1: They just sort of stay still.
Speaker 1: And that's what CPM has been doing.
Speaker 1: You know, they would go to conventions, sell all their extra DVDs on the cheap.
Speaker 1: You know, they would, you know, continue, you know, making some DVDs available to, you know, write stuff or wherever Amazon, who knows?
Speaker 0: Well, they were enacted.
Speaker 0: I mean, they didn't pick up a title in over a year.
Speaker 1: No, they just in a holding pattern.
Speaker 0: But I never.
Speaker 0: you know, the anime industry is so opaque.
Speaker 0: There's no way to know if they actually had plans to come back or if this was just the long, slow burnout.
Speaker 1: I don't think it was a slow burnout.
Speaker 1: I think they did.
Speaker 1: They were just in a holding pattern.
Speaker 0: But a holding pattern has to end with either the plane landing or the plane crashing.
Speaker 1: It could just be a perpetual holding.
Speaker 0: No, it can't.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: This is don't really work that way.
Speaker 0: Wouldn't if they weren't ever going to do anything.
Speaker 1: I think they might have done something eventually, you know, but I wonder.
Speaker 1: I think what the thing is, when you're at when you're in a holding pattern, you have to.
Speaker 1: if you're going to make a move, you have to be 100 percent sure it's the right move.
Speaker 1: So you're going to stay in that holding pattern as long as you can.
Speaker 1: And so you're sure that you're making the right move because if that move is the wrong move, you're at the same time.
Speaker 0: I don't think there was any way for CPM to get themselves out of the situation they were in.
Speaker 1: If they could have licensed one show and got it on TV or something.
Speaker 0: But there's no way they could do that because it's almost impossible to get anime on actual television.
Speaker 0: You can only get it on the kind of.
Speaker 1: I think what they also could have done is they could have found some way to, you know, they already had a bunch of licenses and they could have found, you know, new ways to get money off of them.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean, like if you if they were to put their stuff on Crunchyroll, you get money from that people.
Speaker 1: People pay for Crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: What rights did they really have?
Speaker 0: The industry is so opaque and you didn't always get absolute rights to a show when you license it from Japan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: it might have had the right.
Speaker 0: We don't know what's going on DVDs, but not to digital distribution or licenses might have expired secretly.
Speaker 0: It's there's no way for us to know.
Speaker 1: No, but CPM actually filed for actual bankruptcy.
Speaker 1: Bankruptcy.
Speaker 1: What is the difference in Chapter seven and the others?
Speaker 1: Do we know?
Speaker 1: Do we care?
Speaker 0: Chapter seven means they're gone, completely gone.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The other chapters mean that they'll come back, possibly.
Speaker 1: OK, so what does it mean for the things that they owned?
Speaker 0: Everything's liquidated.
Speaker 0: Creditors get paid.
Speaker 0: OK, well, creditors, they can get paid.
Speaker 0: as I as Animators Network so helpfully points out they have about one hundred thousand dollars in assets and about one point two million dollars in debts.
Speaker 1: Wait, one hundred thousand dollars in total assets.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Hundred and twenty six.
Speaker 1: That means that the licenses for those properties, including things like Utena, Grave of the Fireflies, a judge, a psychic
Speaker 0: one before we go, I got to point they
Speaker 1: were eleven and up to less than one hundred thousand dollars
Speaker 0: in CPM was such a big deal is that they brought out a lot of the anime that was huge back in the day, like CPM was the shit.
Speaker 1: Oh, they were definitely the shit.
Speaker 0: They were also had lots of shit, but they also had all the good stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean, look at this list, you know, the so-called prominent works noted on Anime News Network.
Speaker 0: This is just a fraction.
Speaker 0: Grave of the Fireflies, Utena, Patlabor, Lotus Wars, Slayers, Nod of the Galactic Railroad, Project Echo, Dominion Tank Police, Descendants of Darkness, Demon City, Shinjuku, Urochikidoji, Blue Girl.
Speaker 1: Keep going.
Speaker 0: I like how the list kind of.
Speaker 1: Didn't they have?
Speaker 1: they were eleven?
Speaker 0: Ah, probably.
Speaker 1: Let's get the freaking.
Speaker 1: they were eleven license.
Speaker 0: Jesus, we may not be able to.
Speaker 1: Someone's liquidating it.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: I have it's less than one hundred thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: We don't know.
Speaker 0: if they only if ICV to reports that they only had those assets, then maybe the assets or the licenses weren't transferable.
Speaker 1: No, because there's another news story that says ADV picked up some of them.
Speaker 0: Yes, but not all of them.
Speaker 0: We don't know what's happening to all of them or if the licenses were transferable.
Speaker 0: Maybe their licenses from Japan that expire in the near future.
Speaker 0: They could not for redistribution.
Speaker 0: or maybe they have the right to the anime, but not for the dub.
Speaker 0: But no one wants to make a new dub.
Speaker 1: I want the right.
Speaker 1: So they were eleven because I could do some awesome shit with that.
Speaker 0: Plus, Scott, quote, no specific value or an unknown value was assigned to the company's intellectual property rights and master tapes.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, there you go.
Speaker 0: So the answer to that is we have no idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So the hundred thousand does not include the intellectual property.
Speaker 1: is that was the key part there that I did not know.
Speaker 0: But to get a sense of this, I mean, CVM basically put up the Big Apple Anime Festival, which I realize how old I was when I realized that that died almost a decade ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that ran from like 2000 to 2003.
Speaker 0: And then the Republicans killed it.
Speaker 0: Mm hmm.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't know if the I mean, the Republicans killed one and then they just never did any more after that.
Speaker 1: Well, I think the mistake of the Big Apple Anime Festival was not being in the Javits.
Speaker 1: And while the Javits sucks, you know, that's obviously how to do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Plus, I mean, being in New York City in general, better a convention center that sucks than not a convention center.
Speaker 0: If you're not a professional con running your and you're going to be a big con.
Speaker 0: I mean, the above got, you know, seven, eight thousand people.
Speaker 0: And I think it peaked at like eleven or twelve thousand.
Speaker 0: But having that many people in New York City for a con, unless you were professionals, there is no way it is going to be a good con.
Speaker 0: And everyone I know who went to these generally didn't have a good time.
Speaker 0: There wasn't much to do.
Speaker 0: And you kind of walk between all these buildings where nothing was going on.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: That's what I heard back in the day.
Speaker 0: CPM gone.
Speaker 0: A.D.V.
Speaker 0: meanwhile, picking up everything they possibly can.
Speaker 1: A.D.V.s meanwhile, is is there.
Speaker 1: They're also in a holding pattern.
Speaker 1: They're not doing too well.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I mean, like their manga all evacuated.
Speaker 1: Yen Press has Yotsuba.
Speaker 1: We're waiting for them to make a move on that.
Speaker 1: You know, it's A.D.V.
Speaker 1: still is apparently doing, you know, anime stuff.
Speaker 1: But when was the last time they actually put anything out?
Speaker 1: Really, it's the game.
Speaker 1: The only games left in town are pretty much Viz and Funimation.
Speaker 1: And I guess Tokyo Pop kind of is in the manga town.
Speaker 0: But it's A.D.V.
Speaker 0: is doing fine because you realize they got possibly the most important license, maybe the most dangerous license that's ever that ever has been available in the United States.
Speaker 1: No more need be said.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I feel like in the end, this consolidation is going to be good for the industry because it's really going to force the anime industry in the U.S.
Speaker 0: to trim the fat and kind of what it.
Speaker 1: what did you read?
Speaker 0: On good properties that will actually sell or in some way be marketable in the modern world with visual distribution and fan subs and crunchy roll.
Speaker 1: There is sort of one thing I realized the other day, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, we always say to the anime companies, you know, it's it's because there's too much crap, right?
Speaker 1: You license all this crap and you wonder why you're not making any money.
Speaker 1: If you only license the good stuff, you'll you'll make money.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Well, if you really think about it right.
Speaker 1: We simultaneously complain that no one buys the good stuff.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So and it's true, right?
Speaker 1: The stuff that's really good, right?
Speaker 1: The stuff we love doesn't make the huge sales figures, you know, vertical with their awesome mangas, not so much sales.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean, you know, they were 11, not so very these.
Speaker 1: the really good stuff doesn't get the big sales.
Speaker 1: And I think what it is, I think the people at the anime companies know what's good and what isn't, just like we know what's good and what isn't right.
Speaker 1: But they know that what's good doesn't sell.
Speaker 1: So the thing is, imagine if I gave you a pile of anime, you took out all the good stuff, the stuff that you like, that you knew was awesome.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And you said this will never sell.
Speaker 1: And you put it aside and you look at this pile of crap that's left over.
Speaker 1: You have to figure out which of that crap is going to sell and which isn't.
Speaker 0: So, you know, I think I don't think that's the way to look at it.
Speaker 0: I mean, look at the way the rest of the American media factory machine works in the US.
Speaker 0: I use the word America and US in the same sentence.
Speaker 0: I'm very proud of that anyway.
Speaker 0: But it's not what will sell and what won't.
Speaker 0: It's what do we promote, therefore causing it to sell?
Speaker 0: And what do we don't?
Speaker 0: And I think the anime industry was always kind of niche.
Speaker 0: And they did.
Speaker 0: I think they did a much better job marketing back in the day when they sold anime as check out this ultra violent crap from Japan.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: I feel like that got more attention than, you know, they kind of like.
Speaker 0: there was the anime network, but it was this kind of on demand, half assed effort.
Speaker 0: And Cartoon Network has a lot of action.
Speaker 0: Like Cartoon Network is straying so far from what it used to be.
Speaker 0: that I mean, to not even show anime practically.
Speaker 1: Well, I think part of it was that original marketing, while all the marketing they've done is sort of bad in design wise.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That original marketing was like you had these people who wanted something and it didn't really exist.
Speaker 1: And it's like, here is that awesome thing you've been looking for.
Speaker 1: Come and get it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Whereas the more recent marketing has been like the kids already know the Naruto is out there and they're like, hey, kids, Naruto.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, we know.
Speaker 0: But all the mainstream like the people who got into anime and became hardcore were punk kids, but they found anime by seeing it on TV.
Speaker 0: I mean, I wouldn't have gone searching for anime on the Internet if I hadn't seen Vampire Hunter D on the TV first and gone.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Wouldn't I go into the anime club?
Speaker 1: That's for sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Plus, I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's really I still really don't know what to do with the anime industry.
Speaker 0: And sadly, I just want to point out neither does Japan.
Speaker 0: The big industry group, the Association of Japanese Animations, basically said that anime was, quote, a bubble several years ago that burst.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: So this is in Japan.
Speaker 0: Remember, not just in America.
Speaker 0: The marketplace is on a falling curve due to declining birth rates and the recession.
Speaker 1: So I guess even in Japan, they think that anime is for kids and the fact that there's less kids is hurting anime sales.
Speaker 0: Well, there's an interesting quote in this article.
Speaker 0: near the end, an unnamed producer told them, quote, It's because fans realized that more and more of the releases are the same kinds of titles with the shoujo and mecha elements added just because they are said to sell.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, that's something I mean, anime was originally awesome because you had like all these, you know, interesting plots, or at least even if, you know, now I see that many of them were, you know, formulaic, but there were new formulas.
Speaker 1: to someone who is not from Japan, you know, at being, you know, growing up in the United States and seeing Looney Tunes my whole life.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Seeing, you know, an anime was like, oh, my God, it's something new.
Speaker 1: And that's why it was exciting because it was new and different.
Speaker 0: And they were very much.
Speaker 0: I mean, they couldn't bring everything out and it was difficult to get the licenses back then.
Speaker 0: They would they would pick and choose like for Shiggy Yugi is a pretty mediocre show, all things considered.
Speaker 0: And if a show like that came out now, people would just like ignore it.
Speaker 0: But it was super popular in the US.
Speaker 0: And I think the reason was they picked a show like that for Shiggy Yugi.
Speaker 0: They decided this is the show like that, what we are going to push.
Speaker 0: And it did really well as a result.
Speaker 0: And it became like the biggest freaking show in the world for a while.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And, you know, it's just that it's an animation.
Speaker 1: It is definitely possible to make things that are new and different even today.
Speaker 1: I mean, look at like the awesome anime that does still come out like doing.
Speaker 1: we just saw Skycrawlers.
Speaker 1: We see Satoshi Kann stuff, sort of the samurai Miyazaki still doing shit.
Speaker 1: You know, we see some cool Tezuka remakes of the recent Phoenix series.
Speaker 0: I still just feel like the the main thing that needs to be done is you've got to just market anime differently and actually just go after.
Speaker 1: But it's on the production side, you know, Studio 4C, right?
Speaker 1: They need to, you know, pretty much make a lot more of the different and interesting, you know, animes and, you know, stop doing so many Mowei shows and so many typical crap robot shows.
Speaker 1: You got to go at the same time.
Speaker 0: It was like that back then, too.
Speaker 0: I mean, we'd watch the most dangerous show.
Speaker 0: There were like a hundred other shows that were just like it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But that was because we didn't know that.
Speaker 0: That was new to us.
Speaker 0: Still, it all comes down to picking and choosing what you market.
Speaker 0: Because remember, there was an old saying that the TV networks pushed a lot.
Speaker 0: It's new to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The thing is, we need nothing's new to us now.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: But we need more stuff that's new to us.
Speaker 0: Anime doesn't need to market to people like us because whatever we like, that's good.
Speaker 0: We'll just go out and get.
Speaker 0: And that's not even a question.
Speaker 0: What they need to do is take things like Cowboy Bebop or They Were Eleven or Sort of Samurai or whatever.
Speaker 0: Find people who don't know that this sort of thing exists, but would probably like it and go after them.
Speaker 0: Because even if you take a formulaic show, I mean, sort of the samurai was pretty derivative and just show it to people who don't know that that sort of thing exists.
Speaker 1: Then I think you need both directions.
Speaker 1: You need to have, you know, because if you do that right, if you just keep showing the same old formulas to new people, right, what's going to happen is those new people will eventually also, you know, see that there's now.
Speaker 1: there's nothing new and different for them.
Speaker 1: You continue providing the new and different things constantly.
Speaker 0: Scott, that's a silly argument because every media is like that.
Speaker 0: And every other media is fine.
Speaker 0: I think anime is only different because of the way it's treated by the American.
Speaker 0: Just the American consumer thinks that cartoons by default are for kids.
Speaker 0: They don't get it and they ignore them.
Speaker 0: And the industry just kind of ignores it.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: I feel like it's just a matter of marketing.
Speaker 0: I think that's the only thing standing between a successful anime industry in the U.S.
Speaker 0: and a failed one.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I don't think there's any other factor at this point.
Speaker 1: It's good.
Speaker 1: We definitely agree that anime was a bubble a few years ago.
Speaker 1: that is burst.
Speaker 1: There's no question about that one.
Speaker 0: Well, it's interesting that Japan's having the same trouble, at least because they're the ones making it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But America all goes back to them in America.
Speaker 0: We need to look at it from a different perspective.
Speaker 0: All this stuff already exists.
Speaker 0: And especially if the anime industry is not doing so well over there, you've got to get the licenses and take the risk and go for the marketing and go crazy.
Speaker 0: That was the time to do something just crazy.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: What do you got for me?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I remember now.
Speaker 1: So this video as Adam West outside of a cave.
Speaker 1: Supposedly the Batcave and he's selling all his Batman stuff, you know, and it's pretty funny.
Speaker 0: I got a really, really big soft spot in my heart for Adam West because he, just like the Rick Roll, the Rick man, gets it.
Speaker 0: He gets it.
Speaker 0: People who get it when the Internet focuses its horrible, withering gaze upon them are my heroes.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, really what it is, it's like, you know, there there are some people right who become, you know, you know, they're famous for something.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And sometimes someone is famous for something that is not so glamorous, you know, like Numa Numa, like Tiger Woods.
Speaker 1: He's famous for something glamorous.
Speaker 1: He's the best golfer probably ever.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But, you know, Numa Numa guy, he's famous, but it's not a glamorous thing to be famous for.
Speaker 0: Watch his name.
Speaker 0: I already forgot his name.
Speaker 0: The guy who was arrested at Star Wars.
Speaker 1: Kid is the probably the extreme example of being famous for something and then not handling it properly.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So when you see people like Rick Astley or Adam West.
Speaker 1: It's like they're famous for something.
Speaker 1: They know that what they're famous for is kind of.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: it's not cool.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But their attitude makes it awesome.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like if you have the right attitude about it, then you're sort of laughing at yourself with everyone.
Speaker 1: It's like as opposed to being laughed at and being a turd.
Speaker 0: Well, more importantly, they have both realized that they can make money off of it just by going with it.
Speaker 0: I mean, because I mean, what Adam West does, he voice acts himself on Family Guy in possibly the most self-deprecating way.
Speaker 0: I've ever seen someone do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And also, you know, think about it in this way.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Why is, you know, Adam West or whatever, you know, why is it humorous and entertaining?
Speaker 1: It's because you're laughing at the corniness.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: When you watch that Batman movie, you're laughing at the shark repellent.
Speaker 1: Now, if, you know, Adam West was all like, you know, depressed and unhappy and had this bad attitude about it, then that even that corny movie would have a different, you know, aspect of you know, it wouldn't be the same right for the viewer.
Speaker 1: So because he has that attitude, it actually enhances the entertainment value of the corny things.
Speaker 1: he that he's got the good attitude about, you know, like Rick Astley's song, if Rick Astley like didn't get it and was sort of a jerk, you know, then there's three rolling wouldn't work so well, it would depower the.
Speaker 0: really though, because Rick rolling went for a long time before Rick Astley found out.
Speaker 1: I'll give you I'll give you an example of depowering.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Snakes on a plane.
Speaker 0: Well, they totally had the wrong attitude about it.
Speaker 1: They went for commercialization and they weren't taking it in jest.
Speaker 1: They were taking it like this serious sort of business thing.
Speaker 1: And with that wrong attitude, as soon as that movie came out, snakes on a plane was gone.
Speaker 0: See, the thing is, God, I don't know if that was so much the attitude.
Speaker 0: I think it's just that they actually thought they could make something funny and they just didn't get it.
Speaker 1: Well, I think that it was.
Speaker 1: See, it wasn't a. it wasn't the same bad attitude that, say, the Star Wars kid has, but it was a different bad.
Speaker 0: That's what I was about to say.
Speaker 0: There are three ways to go.
Speaker 0: There's the you get it and you go with it.
Speaker 0: There's the you don't get it and you're sad or angry about it.
Speaker 0: And then there's the big old Venn diagram here, but the third one, the important one, the one that is sad, but also kind of funny.
Speaker 0: The people who don't understand and think that they're having a resurgence of popularity.
Speaker 0: I mean, what if Rick Astley had been mad?
Speaker 0: My career is coming back and he made a new album.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: See, there are some people that, you know, I think the saddest right is the people who just don't even realize anything at all.
Speaker 1: Like, I don't know, sort of like like the Carmel dancing people.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Or I don't know, the Lloyd to my people.
Speaker 1: They they know what's up.
Speaker 0: I think they figured it out.
Speaker 0: I think someone actually showed it to them.
Speaker 0: I found there's an article talking about did I do the Carmel dance people?
Speaker 1: They don't know.
Speaker 1: They might.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: But it's like, you know, those kind of things.
Speaker 1: where it's like, you know, they have this opportunity to make a big move.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But they don't make any move.
Speaker 1: And you worry.
Speaker 1: You wonder if they even know Adam West knows.
Speaker 0: So YouTube Poop is not funny, by and large, is don't don't even consider.
Speaker 1: It has nothing to do with feces, as far as I know.
Speaker 0: Don't even consider looking for YouTube Poops trying to find a good one.
Speaker 0: But randomly and by randomly, I mean, because Wyatt told us to search for poop on YouTube because he was bored, because he promised we would find something funny, which we did, which was not this.
Speaker 0: But this is actually a pretty funny YouTube Poop.
Speaker 0: But really, only if you know something about Pokemon.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There were some jokes in this one.
Speaker 1: I think the only really funny part was in the Pokedex was talking to him.
Speaker 0: There were a couple other good bits.
Speaker 0: But if you're ever going to watch a YouTube Poop or you wonder what YouTube Poop is, watch this one, because it's it's funny enough to where you won't have wasted your five minutes.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, it shows you exactly what a YouTube Poop is.
Speaker 0: And you'll never have to wonder.
Speaker 0: You'll never have to try to watch one.
Speaker 0: You'll never have to hurt yourself.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: This is all I have to say about YouTube Poop is that I've known about them for a while and I sort of I knew what they were, but I never really bothered because stupid, you
Speaker 0: know, like they're kind of like, so
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure this one that we think is fun that we think is good is really old.
Speaker 1: It probably is really, very likely.
Speaker 0: But very few people I know know about, care about or watch YouTube Poop.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The I feel like these are actually very similar to AMV Hell.
Speaker 0: They're like the Internet 4chan kid who may or may not necessarily even know anything about anime, who is making the same kind of joke that an AMV Hell is making.
Speaker 1: The only thing about these is that I look at them.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And while it's not sort of well done in a production sense, it actually takes quite a bit of, you know, labor to make something like this.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean, it's not.
Speaker 1: you know, it's not like, you know, incredibly hard, like making a good video is.
Speaker 1: But it's not like just trivial, like someone just clicks a few buttons and it comes out, you know, some some work went into this poop.
Speaker 1: It was effortful poop, which is sort of, you know, when you think about like what the person must have done in their video editor to make this, it's like, huh, it took him like a few hours, possibly even more.
Speaker 1: It's like, hey, there's something there's something new to that.
Speaker 0: So well, tonight we're going to talk about a somewhat old manga that I hope many of you have already read.
Speaker 0: And we're going to do a final thought to some point in the future.
Speaker 1: But if you have not read Monster by Naoki Urasawa, it's just Naoki Urasawa like we might as well just change Wednesday to Naoki Urasawa.
Speaker 0: You realize right now I'm reading three manga.
Speaker 0: I'm reading Monster, Pluto and 20th Century Boys.
Speaker 1: The reason for this is that Monster has been coming out from Viz and the Signature Series for a long time now.
Speaker 1: And the final volume, the 18th volume, was released in December.
Speaker 1: So once I saw that, I just said, you know what, fuck it.
Speaker 1: And I ordered all the volumes.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then in January, Pluto one and 20th Century Boys one came out and every month in the year of 2009, at least one volume of one of those two is going to come out every month.
Speaker 1: So when you go to the comic store to get Wednesday comics, look for, you know, the Naoki Urasawa shelf and you'll probably get like three or four volumes of each over there.
Speaker 0: But Monster, well, pretty much everything he does.
Speaker 1: This is the year of Naoki Urasawa.
Speaker 0: If you want psychological thrillers or detective manga, he's the master.
Speaker 0: He's pretty much got this down.
Speaker 0: He's the grand master.
Speaker 0: And the cool thing is I'd recommend just for roller coaster syndrome, read Monster first and then read Pluto and 20th Century Boys, because I think you can really see him progressing as a manga artist.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, and there are older manga than Monster also, you know, that we just don't have in the US.
Speaker 1: Like we don't have the master Keaton manga.
Speaker 1: We have the anime, though, right?
Speaker 0: The anime is pretty bad ass.
Speaker 1: We don't have like a Yawara fashionable Judo girl, which I always kind of wanted to see.
Speaker 1: You know, that's that was like his first really big popular thing.
Speaker 1: There was like even, I think, a long running anime based on it, too.
Speaker 0: What about Dancing Policeman?
Speaker 1: I never heard of that.
Speaker 0: There's only one volume.
Speaker 1: Didn't he also make something like Pineapple Army?
Speaker 0: Yeah, yes.
Speaker 0: Pineapple Army.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we don't have that either.
Speaker 0: Jigoro.
Speaker 1: Well, what's the thing he's making now?
Speaker 0: Billy Bat.
Speaker 1: Is that what he's making now?
Speaker 0: Started in October 2008 and I don't know anything else about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're probably not going to get that until Pluto and 20th Century Boys are done.
Speaker 0: Which is fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but, you know, you see what's going on here.
Speaker 1: We're basically we're on a no Kiyorasawa delay.
Speaker 1: We're getting a delayed feed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is probably fine because Monster in and of itself is great.
Speaker 0: But if you've seen if you've seen the Monster anime, just kind of a forward here, a preface, you you can read the manga and you probably should read the manga because the manga is what it's based on.
Speaker 0: But the anime is literally just that.
Speaker 0: they use the manga as storyboards and made the anime like frame for frame.
Speaker 0: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: Well, the other thing is that, you know, I never watched much of the anime.
Speaker 1: I think I watched an episode two at the most way back in the day.
Speaker 1: So I barely remember.
Speaker 1: But I do what I you know, and back then I wasn't as intelligent as I am now.
Speaker 1: I didn't know the name Nyoka or Asawa.
Speaker 1: I didn't know anything.
Speaker 1: All I knew is that there's some new anime called Monster.
Speaker 1: It's about doctors.
Speaker 1: That's what I knew.
Speaker 1: And, you know, I watched that, you know, first episode or two back in the day.
Speaker 1: And apparently they weren't exciting enough for me to watch any more back in the day.
Speaker 0: Well, I was watching Monster as well while I was living in the mountains bored out of my mind.
Speaker 0: And I got about 13 episodes in and it just wasn't doing it for me.
Speaker 0: But then I pick up the manga, you know, years later and I just read through the first one and I burned through about three and a half to four of these things the day on the.
Speaker 1: Well, I think there's something about it where it's like it just it's so quick to read.
Speaker 1: I mean, manga is generally quick to read compared to, say, Stanley, you know, just about comics from anywhere else.
Speaker 1: Manga is made to be a quick read.
Speaker 1: You know, these read real fast.
Speaker 1: You can literally like the pages like on fire.
Speaker 1: I'm turning so fast.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it doesn't help.
Speaker 1: Or Asawa that he's doing a suspense thriller.
Speaker 1: So basically, imagine if you're watching like this incredibly suspenseful mystery movie and you could fast forward it without it getting all squealy.
Speaker 1: You could still get the full experience and you can turn the pages real quick.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, my God, you're like turning the pages as fast as humanly possible.
Speaker 0: This is the interesting part with Monster.
Speaker 0: We just have it all.
Speaker 0: We can just read it just that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because I bought every volume or like Eska Flonie did that with the cliffhanger at the end of every freaking episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, well, cliffhanger.
Speaker 1: Got to watch the next one.
Speaker 1: Oh, God, watch next.
Speaker 0: You just keep watching with Pluto and 20th Century Boys.
Speaker 1: I have to wait because we don't have all the volumes at once.
Speaker 0: Of course, I point out enough because he hasn't read Monster yet, but he read all of 20th Century Boys because he read the first one and he couldn't deal with it.
Speaker 0: So he just got a cancellation.
Speaker 0: He got the rest of it immediately.
Speaker 1: So I think what I'm going to do is I'm going to read it as it comes out.
Speaker 1: And then when the last volume shows up, I'm not going to read it.
Speaker 1: I'm going to reread all the other volumes and then read the last one.
Speaker 1: You like that?
Speaker 1: That's my strategy.
Speaker 0: That's a pretty good strategy.
Speaker 1: to see that strategy.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You sort of you got because you don't really remember what you read.
Speaker 0: God, you know what you're doing?
Speaker 0: You're doing to yourself a Gundam where the two episodes before the final story arc are just the recap episode.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, when it's an anime, I hate the recap because I marathon the anime.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if I didn't marathon the anime, the recap would be helpful.
Speaker 0: Except in Gundam shows.
Speaker 0: Well, Gundam seed at least.
Speaker 0: I love the recap because it was just counting how many times the names of different people who had died were yelled.
Speaker 1: Yeah, rusty, rusty, Miguel.
Speaker 1: You were never even on screen.
Speaker 0: Miguel Rossi died in one episode one.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, you never even saw his face.
Speaker 1: You just saw him wearing a suit now.
Speaker 1: I think they had a photograph of him later.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like hanging in someone's locker.
Speaker 0: Like I would swear people yelled his name.
Speaker 0: Didn't even know who he was.
Speaker 1: So one star monster is.
Speaker 0: this is the story.
Speaker 0: Obviously, no spoilers here.
Speaker 0: We're reviewing this to convince you to read it.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Monster is the story of a doctor, a brilliant doctor from Japan who has moved to Germany.
Speaker 1: Ah, the Germans.
Speaker 0: He is dating the daughter of the director of a big hospital.
Speaker 0: He's a neurosurgeon.
Speaker 0: He's a rising star.
Speaker 0: He's like everything is going right for him.
Speaker 0: He's like the biggest, baddest neurosurgeon ever.
Speaker 0: And the director of the hospital is kind of propping him up and pushing him forward.
Speaker 0: He's destined for great things.
Speaker 1: And one day he's got nepotism, but he's also got skills and he's got everything's awesome.
Speaker 1: And he's also a really nice dude.
Speaker 0: He's wealthy.
Speaker 0: He's got a beautiful wife.
Speaker 0: Everything's going great.
Speaker 0: And one day he operate.
Speaker 0: He is going to operate on a man who came in some poor Turkish immigrant who had an accident.
Speaker 0: But he is told by the hospital to operate on an important political figure instead.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Basically, the mayor gets hurt and the mayor is like brought into the hospital.
Speaker 1: So they say, oh, you go work on the mayor.
Speaker 1: He just came in.
Speaker 1: Oh, shit.
Speaker 1: And they put someone else will take care of the Turkish guy who you were scheduled to take care of.
Speaker 0: And that doctor is not that good.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Another doctor.
Speaker 1: I mean, that other doctor is a really nice, great guy.
Speaker 1: He's a he's a character and he's in throughout the whole story, you know.
Speaker 1: But, you know, he is, you know, the main character is the best doctor there is.
Speaker 0: Well, the best neurosurgeon, of course.
Speaker 0: He basically later in the manga is blackjack.
Speaker 1: Well, he's he was blackjack from the beginning, right?
Speaker 1: Because the beginning of this story, this first volume or so is the is sort of like this typical hospital drama story.
Speaker 1: And I see this particular hospital drama with the evil hospital administration.
Speaker 1: I see that in a lot of places.
Speaker 1: You know, I see it in blackjack.
Speaker 1: I see it in Ray, which was also sort of a blackjack.
Speaker 0: Ray is just blackjack, too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's not by Tessa Gray.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Still blackjack, too.
Speaker 1: I see it in pretty much any manga involving hospitals.
Speaker 1: I see sort of like a trauma center a little bit.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's the same story of the administration of the hospital is evil.
Speaker 1: And the doctors who are awesome just want to save lives.
Speaker 1: And the evil business of the hospital, you know, which is trying to run it as a business is ruining it.
Speaker 1: And, you know, this all comes from the fact that Tezuka himself went to medical school, became a doctor and then was a manga artist.
Speaker 1: Instead of being a doctor because of evil hospital administration, as he saw it.
Speaker 0: And if anyone draws heavily from Tezuka, it is Ursa.
Speaker 1: Oh, you read Monster.
Speaker 1: And it's the reason that he's the one who's doing Pluto.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: If you have read like most of Tezuka's work in English and you read Monster, you see scenes from Tezuka straight up, just kind of reimagined characters like Mr.
Speaker 1: Mustachios.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: Daddy Walrus.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you see, it's like, you know, it's like all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: It's just Tezuka all over the place.
Speaker 1: The blackjack's coming in, everything's coming in.
Speaker 0: But that's not the interesting thing about Monster.
Speaker 0: I mean, that in and of itself, that setup would make for a great manga series.
Speaker 0: But basically what Ursa does with Monster is pull a Hitchcock.
Speaker 1: It's a total Hitchcock.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess we'll have to spoil the first volume to spoil Psycho, because I hope you have all seen Alfred Hitchcock's Psycho.
Speaker 0: But in Psycho, the story starts, if you recall, as a woman who has robbed all this money and she's on the run on the car, she stops at this motel and it starts off like it's going to be this kind of robber money mystery kind of thing.
Speaker 0: The police are after her and she stopped at this hotel and this nice man gives her room and she goes into the room.
Speaker 0: And you're expecting this one kind of movie.
Speaker 0: And then the stabbings happen and it's a completely different movie.
Speaker 0: Monster is the exact same thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like I expected reading Monster for it to be the same hospital drama story, you know, from beginning to end, you know, because it started off as like a hospital drama kind of thing.
Speaker 1: And the doctor is his main character.
Speaker 1: So it's going to be that awesome manga hospital drama.
Speaker 1: And that's what Monster is.
Speaker 0: But no, the story is, you know, it sets up that that kind of moral dilemma.
Speaker 0: And later, Tenma, the doctor, he comes out of a surgery and he sees the wife of the Turkish person he didn't operate on.
Speaker 0: And he died and she's crying.
Speaker 0: And he's really bothered by this.
Speaker 0: And you can see this kind of plot fomenting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because he realized that if he had operated on the Turkish guy, he would have lived.
Speaker 1: And that's who he was scheduled to operate on.
Speaker 0: And the Turkish guy, he saved the mayor instead.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And the Turkish guy came in first.
Speaker 0: He's kind of disillusioned, but everyone's kind of telling him, oh, don't worry about it.
Speaker 0: That's the way the world is.
Speaker 0: Just deal with it.
Speaker 0: And then the same thing happens again.
Speaker 0: But this time there's a there's a crazy murder, suicide, like something happens at this mansion.
Speaker 0: And a young boy is found shot through the head, but still breathing.
Speaker 0: And a young girl is found comatose and everyone else in the family is dead.
Speaker 1: So he immediately, you know, he's basically their siblings and their their children of two important people who escaped from East Germany.
Speaker 0: But they don't even know that right away.
Speaker 0: All Tenma knows is that this boy was shot in the head, but he's alive and he thinks he can save him.
Speaker 1: Mm hmm.
Speaker 0: So he does.
Speaker 0: He's about to operate.
Speaker 1: Then a very important political person comes in and he needs to operate on him instead.
Speaker 0: And Tenma is, you know, he's going to go along with it.
Speaker 0: But then he he has this kind of internal crisis and he decides, no, I'm doing the right thing.
Speaker 0: I'm going to save this boy.
Speaker 0: Damn the consequences.
Speaker 0: And he does.
Speaker 0: He saves this boy's life.
Speaker 0: The political figure dies and he is now persona non gratis with everyone in the hospital.
Speaker 0: Basically now his his, you know, fiance, the daughter of the hospital, leaves of the director of the hospital, leaves him.
Speaker 0: The director passes him over.
Speaker 0: He's no longer the head of neurosurgery.
Speaker 1: He doesn't get any promotions.
Speaker 1: He does.
Speaker 1: He gets basically to stick.
Speaker 1: They work him to death.
Speaker 1: They give him like the worst hours.
Speaker 1: He has to work like all day and all night doing like the lowest end level surgeries.
Speaker 0: Some other doctor now is dating his fiance.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he basically gets the complete total shaft.
Speaker 1: And now he's hanging out with the other surgeon who's like, yeah, I got the shaft to welcome to my world.
Speaker 1: So I like that guy.
Speaker 1: That's like one of my favorite characters, that other doctor.
Speaker 0: I like him, too.
Speaker 0: He's what we'll talk about.
Speaker 0: Why is so great?
Speaker 0: because but suffice it to say his side characters are brilliant.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, what he does all throughout Monster, right, is pretty much every volume or two.
Speaker 1: He brings in these brand new characters, right?
Speaker 1: It's like brand new.
Speaker 1: And usually when someone brings in a brand new character, multi volumes in, you're like, who the fuck is this?
Speaker 1: You know, you just want to see the characters you already love and see what happens to them.
Speaker 0: Of course, a lot of people bring it.
Speaker 0: Well, remember, Trigun, you didn't give a shit about Brado at the beginning.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: You were crying your eyes out by the end.
Speaker 1: Brado master.
Speaker 1: He brings in Brado's like every fucking volume and then within 10 pages, you care about them just as much as you care about.
Speaker 1: Tenma.
Speaker 1: So he basically keeps adding more people to care about with occasional deaths, of course.
Speaker 0: But what happens with Monster is that he's kind of his life is falling apart and he's in the room with this boy who he saved.
Speaker 0: And he basically says to the boy, you know, I gave up everything to say the boy's comatose.
Speaker 1: He's sort of just talking to himself and he's, you know, sort of having this soliloquy in the room of, you know, the comatose boy.
Speaker 0: But he's at peace.
Speaker 0: He's given he's lost everything, but he feels like he did the right thing.
Speaker 0: He saved this boy's life.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, he you know, he wishes that this hadn't happened and that all the people who had wronged him were dead or not around or just, you know, the anger of someone who has been wronged unduly.
Speaker 0: All of those people, well, not all of those people, but many of the people die mysteriously and one thing leads to another.
Speaker 0: And then the boy and the girl disappear.
Speaker 0: And I'm obviously I'm being vague here because this is where it all takes off.
Speaker 0: But the story goes in a direction so unlike where it began and so out there and just so beyond what you would have expected from this disappearance monster is just this powerful psychological thriller that keeps you on the edge of your seat at every single freaking panel all the way until the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: And just constantly like I said, you're lighting the pages on fire, you know, and obviously, you know, it goes away from the hospital, but Tenma is occasionally forced to blackjack it up here and there.
Speaker 0: Tenma is just blackjack plus Master Keaton.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty much he's better Keaton with the blackjack skills instead of the fighting skills.
Speaker 1: But actually, at one point, he goes to fighting school and learns the fighting skills.
Speaker 0: That's actually pretty good.
Speaker 0: He starts looking more and more like Master Keaton, too.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, you know, Urasawa sort of does that thing where, you know, his main characters all look very similar.
Speaker 1: They're all look like Master Keaton.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let me look at sanctuary.
Speaker 1: You see the same thing.
Speaker 1: Like the guy in 20th Century Boys looks a little bit like he's a little different, but he's, you know.
Speaker 0: Well, plus there's the friend in both of them, right?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So, you know, but yeah, it's like all, you know, Tenma goes on this journey, basically, of awesomeness and epicness.
Speaker 1: And you're not always following him directly, though.
Speaker 1: You know, sometimes you're sort of floating near him, like, you know, you'll be like following some other characters and like Tenma will walk by and it's like, oh, shit, oh, shit.
Speaker 1: Oh, shit.
Speaker 0: Pretty much the way I will tell this to you is that, you know, all this happens.
Speaker 0: The boy and the sister disappear and a bunch of people die.
Speaker 0: Fast forward many, many years later, like it skips a big period of time and then the plot begins.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So the kind of the entire whole first set up is just the preface.
Speaker 0: It's like here is what happened in the past and now our feature presentation.
Speaker 1: But and that that what happened in the past is volume one.
Speaker 1: So it's 17 volumes of feature presentation.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: And the quote from the beginning of the manga actually really sums it up best.
Speaker 0: You may recognize what it is from, but this might give you an idea of where this is going.
Speaker 0: And I saw the beast rise up out of the sea, having seven heads and 10 horns and upon his horns, 10 crowns and upon his heads, the names of blasphemy.
Speaker 0: And they worshiped the dragon, which gave power unto the beast.
Speaker 0: And they worshiped the beast, saying, who is like unto the beast?
Speaker 0: Who is able to make war with him?
Speaker 0: That's our revelations.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but what does it say on the back?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the first volume over there.
Speaker 0: No, because we can read the text on the back, actually, because I've been reading this so quickly.
Speaker 0: I have like four volumes of Monster in my car.
Speaker 0: I have another three in my desk at work because I'm just carrying them around and reading them everywhere.
Speaker 0: I have to make sure I have enough with me to get through a train ride.
Speaker 0: I'm going to be.
Speaker 0: you realize I am like three volumes away from the end at this point.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: Well, so on Amazon.com, actually, I checked right now.
Speaker 1: There's actually no discount on Monster whatsoever.
Speaker 1: So it would cost you about one hundred and eighty dollars to get all of it.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: It's definitely worth.
Speaker 1: Well, what I'm going to tell you to do is I'm looking at some other websites to try to find a lower price right now.
Speaker 1: I guess I can't find a lower price.
Speaker 1: I bought them from in stock trades dot com, but apparently I bought all of them and they're no longer in stock.
Speaker 1: So you get I got a discount over there.
Speaker 0: So I guess I would.
Speaker 0: this is one of those things where I would.
Speaker 1: Maybe try to buy, you know, used on Amazon, try to find it at a convention.
Speaker 0: Try to mention is probably your best bet.
Speaker 0: We'll find one of those, you know, buy four, get five.
Speaker 1: This isn't.
Speaker 1: this isn't something that's going to be hard to find, you know, because it was you know, it's a recent vis release.
Speaker 1: The last volume came out December.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: Like just a few months ago.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So you can definitely find this at a convention or, you know, borders or whatever.
Speaker 1: Just, you know, do something that you discount because one hundred eighty dollars is a lot of monies and, you know, monies is tight.
Speaker 1: I paid, you know, five bucks per volume.
Speaker 1: So there's no reason you should pay ten.
Speaker 0: But at least this isn't going to be a sanctuary.
Speaker 0: You're not going to have to like scrounge for years to find the one or two volumes you're missing or anything.
Speaker 1: No, I mean, the only thing you might have to worry about is if it gets stupid popular, there might not be enough of them out there already.
Speaker 0: You know, for everybody, of course, that might be good.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll get a reprint now.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Plus, you know, I'm pretty sure like number 18 is like still in print.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, at least some many of them are priced still in print.
Speaker 0: But what makes Monster Urusawa stuff.
Speaker 0: good primarily is just that his faces are great.
Speaker 0: Like he, while he uses this kind of cast of characters approach that Tezuka used and other people use, all of his side character, like every character is so absolutely distinctive and so unique.
Speaker 1: And it's like he's.
Speaker 1: the faces have a little bit of the stereotypical anime look like some people got a pointy chin or a big eye kind of thing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But like they have like these really human faces.
Speaker 1: Most of the characters.
Speaker 1: And you can always recognize people, you know, it's like and a lot of them are like really unique, like not everyone is like, you know, a freakin like, you know, a teenager or college student.
Speaker 1: You know, he's got lots of like old people and like old ladies and old dudes and sort of weird looking people, tall, skinny people, short, fat people, even a completely throwaway, you know, bartender at a bar who has two lines in two panels.
Speaker 0: And that's it will have character and be unique from any other bartender you see.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it's like there's lots of characters that are like their side characters and they'll make you care about them a little bit.
Speaker 1: They're sort of like on the third or fourth tier down from the main characters, you know, but he'll still draw them like all recognizably.
Speaker 1: Like there are characters that are like only in the last volume, but they you know, they're there and they mean something.
Speaker 1: They're important.
Speaker 1: They take a part in the story and he'll give them you know, he'll design them like full on and they're totally unique and you remember them.
Speaker 1: And it's it's pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: Also, I think part of why he's able to pull out so much suspense is that there's this cinematic timing to the way he draws panels to where the panels are arranged and put together.
Speaker 0: Just they draw your eye along like you're watching a movie in the comic.
Speaker 0: And I know a lot of good manga do that, but I think Urasawa is particularly good at it.
Speaker 0: And especially looking at Pluto or stuff after this, he's just getting better.
Speaker 0: And I think he's got a long way to go.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, that's the key to comics right above all else, right?
Speaker 1: The number one most important thing in comic art is the control of time, right?
Speaker 1: Because in a movie or if you're making a movie, you don't really control time, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, you can have more frames per second, but people are watching action at a rate of one second per second.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So, you know, you can make it sort of seem long and drawn out by like, you know, having someone watch like, you know, an empty room for a minute or two and they'll get kind of bored.
Speaker 1: But in a comic, right, a person is turning the pages.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And you might want them to turn the pages real quick in one part and slow in another part.
Speaker 1: And you have to with your art, with the way you lay out the panels, with the way you move the eye around, with how many words, whenever you put a lot of words in one place, someone's going to be stuck there for a while.
Speaker 0: When you put no words or even if you don't, I think his brilliance is that I'll be like, I want to read it so fast because I'm desperately trying to see what's going to happen.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, you'll kind of read, you'll look at panels.
Speaker 0: There'll be a bunch of panels in a row and you'll kind of pause on one or two at the appropriate moment.
Speaker 0: He draws you into this rhythm of reading to where even though, you know, you get to the panel and you know, on the next page, there's going to be the big reveal, but you don't turn the page right away.
Speaker 0: You kind of build up your own anticipation.
Speaker 0: And I think he subconsciously causes you to do that just by the way he arranges panels and what he's showing you.
Speaker 1: Well, that's that's what comics are.
Speaker 1: You know, all good comics, you know, he also definitely this is an urasawa thing.
Speaker 0: He loves to have one party in a conversation, not be known.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that's always.
Speaker 0: you always get the over the shoulder view, a little bit of the hair.
Speaker 0: And then the last panel before, like the title, like every chapter, you know, turn around and show you the other view.
Speaker 1: You do the 180 and you'll see the person who was on the other side of the conversation.
Speaker 0: It's like every volume will begin with this kind of preface where it's always two characters having a conversation and you don't know who the second one is.
Speaker 0: And then the last panel that the last page that has the title of that volume will then show you who the person was talking to.
Speaker 1: And it's always like also sometimes what he'll do is if if there's a character by themselves, it'll either give you what they're saying or what to themselves or what they're thinking or some sort of narration as the character is performing some actions.
Speaker 1: And then once that, you know, it's sort of coming to a head that he'll draw and reveal, like the secret thing about what the character was doing, you know, like, oh, snap, you know, like someone will be looking for something and, you know, like maybe trying to find a secret.
Speaker 1: And then he'll you'll turn the page, Bani hits you with the secret, just as if he was, you know, showing you the other character in a conversation.
Speaker 1: Same technique.
Speaker 0: Plus, I got to say, well, the side characters are great, but I like all the main characters except Detective Sook.
Speaker 1: Except Detective Sook.
Speaker 0: He's just kind of lame.
Speaker 1: My favorite guys are.
Speaker 1: well, number one, my favorite guy is lunch.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: He is just the thing with lunch is like he starts out one way and then he sort of gets crazy for a while.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, what they do with him is like totally not what you would expect that character to do.
Speaker 0: It's hard to tell what he's doing because you can't get into his head more so than on purpose.
Speaker 1: They don't.
Speaker 1: He doesn't bring you into his head.
Speaker 0: But it's interesting because the whole time you're wondering, there are a couple of times where I thought he was on one side and then he just does the exact opposite of what I expect.
Speaker 1: And he's like.
Speaker 1: he's just, you know, they betray him as such like this fucked up, hard to understand guy.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like, you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: it's like kids and wife leave him and whatever.
Speaker 1: And it's like, you know, and he just sort of doesn't have any sort of emotional reaction whatsoever.
Speaker 1: And you can't figure out like, you know, well, is he upset and hiding it or does he not care?
Speaker 1: You don't know.
Speaker 1: You can't tell.
Speaker 1: And he's a crazy dude.
Speaker 1: And out the other doctor, I already said I like him a lot.
Speaker 1: I actually like the girl a lot.
Speaker 0: Oh, she's bad.
Speaker 0: She's awesome.
Speaker 0: This is I feel like he's better about this now, but at least in Monster and some.
Speaker 0: He seems to have this kind of a few faces.
Speaker 0: He draws women with.
Speaker 0: women are either sad, evil or the main character.
Speaker 1: Well, no, see that there was the girl who is the untrained doctor.
Speaker 1: She was there for like a little bit.
Speaker 0: She's awesome.
Speaker 0: I didn't see much of her.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she's not.
Speaker 1: she's not like.
Speaker 1: she's like.
Speaker 1: it's weird because like he actually bothers to develop her character a little bit and like gives her a whole chapter or two like to, you know, talk about her and whatever.
Speaker 1: But like and I think she's in it for like a couple more panels and like.
Speaker 1: she's not there that much and she doesn't matter that much.
Speaker 1: But he puts her in there, you know, and it's that sort of character.
Speaker 1: It's like you bother to make a character, you fill them with so much life and then they don't get a lot of screen time.
Speaker 1: And you just have so many of those.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: This quantity of really strong, you know, life filled characters just all over the place.
Speaker 1: It's like a menagerie of characters.
Speaker 1: It's like a zoo.
Speaker 1: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: I like it.
Speaker 0: I don't really want to say too much more because you've really got to do some final thoughts when you're done.
Speaker 0: You have all got to read Monster.
Speaker 0: This is an amazing manga.
Speaker 1: I was going to say it would be monstrous.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays we have video games, board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights and Thursdays are the catch alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an Odeo on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.