Speaker 1: Hey, it's Monday, August 10th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: SSH Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So this week sucks ass.
Speaker 0: How much ass does it suck?
Speaker 1: This is like the one week where I got to work the night shift like the European midnight to 9 a.m To train the guy who's gonna be actually working that shift.
Speaker 1: and let me tell you New York is the city that never sleeps Except at 4 in the morning.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, it's only sleeps at 4.
Speaker 0: See the thing about New York City is that it's true that it doesn't sleep.
Speaker 0: However, the thing is in New York City, there are many different neighborhood.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, it's got no that I wandered around even took the subway down to other more half plate like happen in places.
Speaker 1: There's basically nothing going on except if you go far enough away from Midtown.
Speaker 1: There are one or two bodegas open.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's about it.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: Midtown is an area where it's got.
Speaker 1: I'm saying even if you leave Midtown There's nothing going on.
Speaker 0: a for gotta go to the residential places.
Speaker 0: I live.
Speaker 1: even if you go to those places.
Speaker 1: There's not that much going on except a couple of bodegas.
Speaker 1: one McDonald's this 24/7, but I learned something else.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm McDonald's doesn't even serve breakfast at 4 a.m Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: They don't start that until 530.
Speaker 0: You got to go.
Speaker 0: There are places just got to know where they are, but it is true that most shit closes.
Speaker 1: people got to sleep, man I guess there are bars that might be open Yeah, but it was amazing to walk around the city and there were a lot of people walking around But nothing was open but at 4 in the morning.
Speaker 1: Yeah when I went to lunch Wow, I just wandered outside.
Speaker 1: I wanted to see what it was, you know, I never get to hang out in Midtown that late.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's that's like a lot of people, huh?
Speaker 0: 4 a.m.
Speaker 1: Well, the weird thing is a lot of people took the train in in the more like a midnight yesterday And a lot of people took the train out at 9 a.m.
Speaker 0: But it was a must be a lot of night workers.
Speaker 1: No, it wasn't workers.
Speaker 1: It was all like families.
Speaker 1: It was all like mom and kids but not that many guys and there were a lot of weird people on the train going in the Opposite direction a lot of loud people having weird conversations.
Speaker 0: Very strange.
Speaker 1: This whole experience is just surreal.
Speaker 0: Well, you're only gonna have to suffer it for a week It'd be.
Speaker 0: it'd be weird if it was surreal every day.
Speaker 0: Eventually, the surreal would become non surreal.
Speaker 0: and then when you had to like the city in a normal hour you'd be like what the fuck?
Speaker 1: It's just crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, it's always stuff like that's always cool in small doses though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is I I'm tired partly, you know, I was gonna get some sleep this morning.
Speaker 1: You know, I come home at like 10 a.m.
Speaker 1: And then go to sleep except that the power went out like three times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I came home.
Speaker 0: I saw that immediately all the clocks were off by like four hours.
Speaker 0: Yeah computer was off The hallway computer was off.
Speaker 1: I'm asleep and the power goes out.
Speaker 1: So I get woken up by the UPS streaking and no AC Nothing to do and it's hot.
Speaker 1: So I open the windows and I turn on my fan.
Speaker 0: It's hot as hell.
Speaker 1: I turn on my fan.
Speaker 1: Yeah still well fan didn't do anything cuz there's no power.
Speaker 0: Oh fuck Spritz yourself with some water.
Speaker 1: I just stood in the shower.
Speaker 1: I Did that way back?
Speaker 1: I was water.
Speaker 1: I was at the University of Michigan at this like marching band thing and I went by myself because it was sort of this like honors thing.
Speaker 1: We had to apply for it and Stupidly I listened to knitter by instructor and I applied for this thing and I got in and then I learned that no one Else applied for it because it sucks.
Speaker 1: So I get there and it's super hard and everyone's a jerk and I'm like the only person from my school and it's like a million degrees.
Speaker 1: Wow, as I was walking out of the showers to go to bed in this on air-conditioned alcohol I see a guy who has pulled a chair into the shower Set it on a low cold trickle and it's just sleeping under it and you copied him.
Speaker 1: I did the same thing.
Speaker 1: I didn't stay there all night, but I laid there for a while.
Speaker 0: You said they're all night.
Speaker 0: You might in sick.
Speaker 0: Well, it'll be interesting.
Speaker 0: We'll see what happens and we'll definitely learn.
Speaker 1: they die.
Speaker 0: You'll learn lots of things and I will learn them by proxy hurray.
Speaker 1: for me What I've learned pretty much is that no amount of money no amount of money could make me do this shift.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's nothing in the world that could make me work midnight tonight I think is you there's?
Speaker 0: that's not true because what if someone gave you like a billion dollars for like a week?
Speaker 0: you would Do it for a week and then you'd be like, so Well, let me put it this way.
Speaker 1: No reason.
Speaker 1: you quit and you'd you know I know reasonable amount of money and - I would not do it for more than about a week.
Speaker 1: half a million dollars a year I don't know wouldn't be worth it.
Speaker 0: a million dollars a year.
Speaker 1: Give me one million dollars a year of my life is not worth that.
Speaker 0: two million dollars worth it.
Speaker 0: million now Really five million.
Speaker 0: I would not basically work one year and never have to work again.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't do it.
Speaker 0: That's like baseball player.
Speaker 1: You you try this shift.
Speaker 1: It's not fun.
Speaker 0: I know but for five million dollars I do it for one year and then the rest of my life do it ever the hell I want it.
Speaker 0: It'd be totally worth.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: one entire year of kind of when I'm still at by one of my.
Speaker 1: you know The physical prime of my life is not worth five million dollars because I can't get that back.
Speaker 0: I can make five million dollars some other way Maybe but I could live in the luxury Manhattan apartment dirty if I got paid that much money while I and I'd basically just walk Down there at night and oh man.
Speaker 1: But then you wouldn't have that much money left at the end of the thing to show for it.
Speaker 0: I would cuz I would I wouldn't spend the money like a dumbass.
Speaker 0: The luxury Manhattan apartment is only could only be like three thousand a month.
Speaker 1: So that's why it's a lot more than that.
Speaker 0: Well for a small yet luxury apartment.
Speaker 0: I saw some that were only three thousand.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I don't know about luxury.
Speaker 1: You're you're thinking luxury in the.
Speaker 0: I'm not talking.
Speaker 1: I'm not talking Person luxury.
Speaker 0: I'm talking luxury as in.
Speaker 0: it's actually new and has a parking space.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, you're talking luxury.
Speaker 1: Like when they say luxury apartments in the Bronx, they basically mean these aren't shit holes.
Speaker 1: exactly.
Speaker 0: Exactly, you know, it's nice.
Speaker 0: It's clean, you know, it's got a modern appliances.
Speaker 0: It's got a parking space.
Speaker 0: It's got you know a little enough room to sit and such.
Speaker 1: so that aside We should get right into this because I want to go to work.
Speaker 0: So his is my news.
Speaker 0: I'll make it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what do you got?
Speaker 0: So check this out?
Speaker 0: I have this problem where I have a bank in Connecticut where I grew up and I spent you know 16 years of my life 17 years of my life, right and I just never changed banks and why should I?
Speaker 0: it's just a lot of Work and there's not much benefit to it and I can use pretty much in any ATM I want.
Speaker 0: I have really good online banking all my direct deposits already set up.
Speaker 0: So why should I change the bank?
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: The only time I ever actually need to go to my bank is if I need to deposit a Check.
Speaker 0: on a rare rare rare occasion.
Speaker 0: Someone gives me a check and it's sort of annoying but I can just mail it home to my parents who still live in Connecticut and they deposit it.
Speaker 0: but this one bank Came up with a solution and the solution is very so simple and so obvious.
Speaker 0: I hope my bank does it.
Speaker 0: you take a picture of your check with your phone, right?
Speaker 0: I guess both sides of the check I assume and then you void the check and then they take care of it and Of course, they won't let just anyone do this, right?
Speaker 0: You have to be like not a schmuck You know, like if you got lots of debts and shit and you're not don't have good credit They won't let you do this because you'll probably fraud them and whatnot.
Speaker 0: But you know if you're not defrauding anyone and you check out and you've got you know money.
Speaker 0: they let you do it.
Speaker 0: It's totally cool.
Speaker 1: I just wish I didn't have to use checks at all.
Speaker 0: I know checks are so old and like they're totally that there's no reason to have them anymore.
Speaker 0: People should be able to exchange money directly with each other and a card slash PayPal fashion without fees.
Speaker 1: It's partly the bank's problems in that You know my bank just won't wire money to people without all this hassle.
Speaker 1: like wiring money is such a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I should be able to go to a website type in my friend's number that he gives me some public You know a secure number right and then give him an arbitrary amount of money at no cost Directly from my checking account to his checking account.
Speaker 0: and I shouldn't need to pay PayPal a fee.
Speaker 0: I shouldn't need to pay the bank a fee.
Speaker 0: I'm just giving someone money.
Speaker 0: It's basically just some bits have to move.
Speaker 0: It's like a text message.
Speaker 1: It doesn't cost anything Right, so no, it does actually cost something in terms of you know, but there one.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of regulatory stuff about tracking where money goes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's in a database one record in a database.
Speaker 1: No, it costs money to have people to kind of maintain all that and watch it and to file all the paperwork.
Speaker 0: That's the cost I pay just having a bank account.
Speaker 1: in general You don't pay anything to have a bank account, huh?
Speaker 0: But it cost something to have a bank account, doesn't it?
Speaker 1: No, it doesn't see.
Speaker 0: the bank makes its money because they're holding on to my money investing it and reaping rewards from it.
Speaker 0: That's where they get paid.
Speaker 0: So they shouldn't pay me.
Speaker 0: They should.
Speaker 0: I shouldn't have to pay them fees to do stuff.
Speaker 0: I think the real getting paid by having my money.
Speaker 1: I think the real problem is that the vast majority of people don't even like they would never even care about us or something like That.
Speaker 1: so it'll never happen.
Speaker 0: I think a lot of people would like it a lot not enough people for to matter.
Speaker 1: I mean no bank is going to do it and then all the other banks are gonna follow suit or that's true.
Speaker 0: But I think this bank is doing it and if it helps, you know I think slowly but surely banks will be sort of just.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be slow but more stuff like this will happen and then eventually what I just said will Happen and then it'll be a good day.
Speaker 1: I don't think it'll be anytime soon though, really It's gonna take a while maybe 10 years because remember we still have to interface with people who just don't get it.
Speaker 1: I mean, I still have to write checks to my stupid landlord.
Speaker 0: I know right.
Speaker 0: Hopefully in the city, I'll find a landlord who can just like directly take the money.
Speaker 1: That's the what.
Speaker 1: the biggest thing I'm looking forward to more and more about buying a house Is that I can just have that taken care of because I can.
Speaker 0: Why is the bank in the bank and just take care of itself?
Speaker 1: Well, I also you know have an escrow account set up for all the taxes and everything else.
Speaker 1: I basically won't have to ever do anything unless I've run out of money.
Speaker 0: No, that's yeah, but I mean if you just run out of money, you still won't have to do anything.
Speaker 1: It's a runaway All right, so I'd like to talk at least a little bit about prank net.
Speaker 1: now you could argue if this is a Monday or A Thursday is some sort of 4chan derivative.
Speaker 1: No, okay Prank net is that thing where basically people were calling other people and convincing to do dangerous stupid destructive things.
Speaker 1: Hey, you're in a hotel, right?
Speaker 1: Well, there's snakes and if you don't break the windows blah blah blah you might die.
Speaker 0: See I heard about this right the other day and I thought about it for a little while and the first thing you think Of course is wow.
Speaker 0: These people are stupid doing what they're told over the phone.
Speaker 1: No, I'd actually go one step further.
Speaker 1: I blame society for instilling in people this kind of immediate and Automatic trust of anything that sounds like an authority, right?
Speaker 0: So my the thing is, you know My first instinct here is to blame the people who are on the receiving end of the prank, right?
Speaker 0: But I thought about it a little bit more and you know what.
Speaker 0: actually Even though I am NOT going to disagree that those people are morons and it's society's fault, etc, etc.
Speaker 0: I do think the people pulling the prank should go to jail.
Speaker 0: You know, why Al Capone?
Speaker 1: No, not Al Capone That's.
Speaker 1: that's how they're gonna get him though.
Speaker 0: That's probably how they're gonna get him.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I think is the problem here Some of it?
Speaker 0: look at the descriptions of some of the pranks.
Speaker 0: they're pulling right like they called someone up on the phone and they're Like yeah, there's a toxic gas leak.
Speaker 0: You need to jump out the window of your hotel room, right?
Speaker 0: You know what that is?
Speaker 0: That's shouting fire in the crowded theater the thing that you're not allowed to do that Even the free speech crazies like us say you're not allowed to do.
Speaker 0: and here's the thing I mean.
Speaker 0: therefore I think the pranking people are definitely definitely bad.
Speaker 0: These are yelling fire in the crowded.
Speaker 1: these tire iron pranks were across like they're all over the place.
Speaker 1: And what is the line between shouting fire and simply, you know, convincing someone stupid to do something stupid?
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: think you would have to definitely judge that based on the individual phone call because some of not all the phone calls were oh My god, there's a toxic gas leak, you know, some of the phone calls were like something else And depending on what they actually said on the call, I'm sure hotels record the calls I don't know what they do, but you know, depending on the evidence and all that you'd have to make a decision.
Speaker 0: I'm sure some of the pranks were shouting fire in a crowded theater and some of them were probably not and That's up to the court and the jury and such to decide.
Speaker 1: not what I find interesting is that one these were some relatively unsophisticated people and all the reports are that the guy who was kind of running this is literally some loser who lives in his mom's basement and Kind of a loner no job.
Speaker 0: Just like he's such a stereotype of that kind of loser I think that we could actually Probably help society out a lot if we had some sort of law that just gets people out of their mom's Basements.
Speaker 0: like you can't live with your mom.
Speaker 0: You got to get your ass out.
Speaker 1: Why not though?
Speaker 1: because a lot of people use that to a great advantage, you know Just out of college got a lot of student loans.
Speaker 1: live with mom for a couple
Speaker 0: years You know, but maybe we need some sort of you know System to like find these, you know If we find out that someone's living with their mom after X years
Speaker 1: and they shouldn't have the freedom to live that kind of life No,
Speaker 0: but we should actually, you know We should check them out to make sure it's not a crazy.
Speaker 1: and so you're gonna you want to spend more money on some sort Of social services program to find the 25 year old living in his mom's basement.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they probably need some help those people and they're very dangerous Scott are we?
Speaker 1: our child services can't even help.
Speaker 1: actual kids are getting beaten that well We need to help them - you're gonna help the 28 year old while playing basement dweller get away from Wow And orders my.
Speaker 0: ideally we would help them all but you know, we suck is?
Speaker 0: it's the reality versus the ideal.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying ideally we should help them.
Speaker 0: Well, that's saying realistically we can.
Speaker 1: I do feel that the culpability is about 50/50 between the People inducing these people to do the crimes and the people doing the crimes.
Speaker 1: but the thing about prank net that's interesting Is that this was basically just some piece some very?
Speaker 1: Unsophisticated people pulling pranks.
Speaker 1: I'm very surprised that something like this has not happened on a more organized scale because smart people You know the 4chan II anonymous types or even people like us could basically pull this off on a global scale without any Think about gloom and doom right lately.
Speaker 0: I mean this has been the week of stuff happening.
Speaker 0: There was all those DDoS is that were real big on Twitter and everybody, right?
Speaker 0: There's all this stuff that can totally.
Speaker 0: we're so vulnerable.
Speaker 0: It's basically like you're just a duck sort of flying slowly across the marsh.
Speaker 0: It's like a hundred Elmer Fudd's and that ducks just ain't shot yet, right?
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: it's that there are always Elmer Fudd's and there were always guns laying around.
Speaker 1: but it just recently We're having the ratio of Elmer Fudd's two guns is getting to a dangerous level.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's just it's still.
Speaker 0: I'm so surprised that like oh the worst we've had is a DDoS in this prank net.
Speaker 0: We haven't had like, you know, just like fires and riots in the streets coinciding with well the thing, you know Everyone's hard drive getting erased.
Speaker 1: The lucky thing is that most of the people who are smart and sophisticated enough to do these things the way smart people would do them Either are not evil people or there aren't enough of those people with a common goal to organize anything that big.
Speaker 1: I mean There's one crazy who wants eggs and one crazy or wants why the two of them will not be able to easily Coordinate to get to.
Speaker 1: you know Do they're crazy in pursuit of both of their?
Speaker 0: so Marvel Comics is right and the supervillains can ever actually work together.
Speaker 1: I think they were in a degree except if you watch x-men the new one The supervillains were a lot of a lot smarter than the x-men were.
Speaker 0: yeah Heroes are never smart.
Speaker 1: They were just could have just called Magneto and said hey is professor X there.
Speaker 1: He would have been like yeah found him naked and passed out.
Speaker 0: You guys want to pick him up, but no Right, why didn't Magneto call the x-men?
Speaker 0: should it be like hey, I just found Professor X all naked.
Speaker 0: you want to come Right, you should have called the other.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: He probably did and Wolverine just didn't check the fucking voicemail.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, you know, it's hard to check voice from all the danger and we can't really hear them.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so things of the day.
Speaker 1: I'll admit that I very much like to watch computers masturbate and this is another example of that and it's very well done.
Speaker 0: So someone made a flash game that generates in real-time or semi real-time Super Mario World levels and so basically it just makes Super Mario World levels that are brand-new like totally You know not made by humans and you play them.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So cool.
Speaker 1: Someone else made a beat Super Mario World's AI Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: So this video beat any Super Mario World no matter what any beatable one at least.
Speaker 1: Wow, so someone put the two of these together and you can see the logic of kind of the thing charts out like all The pads and all the pads that are gonna die and the ones that aren't gonna die with red lines.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 0: uh, can it do scrolling levels or only still love?
Speaker 1: I have.
Speaker 0: no I did not scrolling levels means it just has to be real fast.
Speaker 1: I did not do any research whatsoever beyond watching this video.
Speaker 0: Okay, is that it?
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: So, you know Conway's game of life, of course.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Somebody made a complete Computer constructor in Conway's game of life.
Speaker 0: Wow, that's all I got to say.
Speaker 1: I remember like trying to make and gates and stuff like that in the game.
Speaker 0: They made a complete computer.
Speaker 0: So this can make basically process any program.
Speaker 0: So you might take a while might take a real long time, but you know, it's still.
Speaker 0: it's a complete computer as complete.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's Turing complete.
Speaker 0: I had to investigate further But you know, it's a computer in Conway's game alive.
Speaker 0: You can write programs for it and it will run them.
Speaker 1: people seem to really like taking like look at the little big plant or anything like that.
Speaker 1: people like to take the machines or the physics of a made-up world and make Less efficient versions of real machines in them and it seems to be this huge hobby among geeks.
Speaker 0: It's it's definitely cool.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, I totally love making computers out of anything that a computer can be made out of.
Speaker 1: So tonight we won't talk about this too long because there's not that much to say and we're not going to do a here Is how to do the things with this.
Speaker 0: but now you can read the man page.
Speaker 1: Yes, so SSH is possibly the most used most important and most useful tool that any computer person will ever use.
Speaker 0: Yes, it's so surprising that it doesn't come with Windows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's so surprising that SSH the secure shell as it is Is the thing that I probably use more than anything like of all the computer software in the world.
Speaker 0: Like I use Firefox and secure shell more than fucking anything else and I probably use secure shell more because I've been using it since before Fires Fox is around.
Speaker 0: I mean pretty much whenever I open a computer terminal The first thing I'm gonna type in is SSH something something and then get to work, right?
Speaker 0: So what is the secure shell?
Speaker 0: Basically back in the day you had telnet and you still have telnet.
Speaker 0: and what telnet does?
Speaker 0: is it basically just you open a connection to a computer on a port and It sends bits back and forth?
Speaker 1: now what does tell when I like to think about?
Speaker 1: I remember before I was being.
Speaker 1: before I was Very computer proficient, you know, I didn't know a lot about things, but I had my modem and a friend of mine had his modem Mm-hmm, and I remember being so excited about one day we got the modems to talk to each other and we both had a terminal open and I typed stuff on my screen and on his screen.
Speaker 1: He's like, I see everything you're typing.
Speaker 1: Oh my gosh Oh my gosh, and the fact that that the majority of my job goes funnels through what is effectively that?
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 0: So if you want to see how telnet works, right how it was done in the olden days Type go to your command line even in Windows and type something like telnet space google.com space 80 and that will make a TCP connection to google.com on port 80 and then type like get in capital letters space forward slash or press enter and You'll see the HTML of google.com will come by because all you did was make a TCP connection to the Google web server and Tell it get forward slash which is HTTP protocol, right?
Speaker 0: And then you'll see the what it get what you get back, which is the HTML of google.com.
Speaker 1: Well, I think people a lot of non-technical people don't seem to realize that Everything is other than X. pretty much everything in computing is pretty self consistent and simple.
Speaker 1: actually It's just a lot of simple things that are repeated very quickly.
Speaker 0: I mean a lot of layers.
Speaker 1: what I big onion something I often do when I'm working with systems is Telnet to a port that is not telnet because I can just send stuff to that port and it'll respond.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean like I have a fixed demon I can telnet to it And if I really want I can construct a message that it will accept as a fixed message and send it, you know When you go to your browser, you type google.com.
Speaker 0: What do you think it's doing?
Speaker 0: It's connecting to google.com.
Speaker 1: I was doing like it's going get and then it gets HTML and then it renders.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's what it's doing.
Speaker 0: We just can't see that part cuz and it would be really annoying to use that way.
Speaker 0: But that's the way the computers talk.
Speaker 1: That's the way real men use the internet.
Speaker 0: Oh, that was a big Thunder All right, so a way to break the fourth wall.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: We're real people in the real world and it's Thunder outside.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: So secure shell right.
Speaker 0: see one of the most popular uses of telnet was to actually connect to another computer, right?
Speaker 0: For example, I have in the olden days you'd have like a mainframe right and the mainframe would run say a terminal program a terminal emulator a TTY on Port 90 so I don't know.
Speaker 0: pick a port number right and you would go to your terminal right your VT 100 terminal Which is not actually a computer just a terminal a keyboard and a monitor and you would telnet Which is it did it in hardware to port whatever on the mainframe and then that terminal that was running on the mainframe terminal software would show up on your physical hardware.
Speaker 0: VT 100 terminal and Unix and Linux still work that way on the lowest level.
Speaker 0: when you go to your Linux machine If you got an Ubuntu line around press like control alt f1 and you'll see TTY 0 staring at you.
Speaker 0: It's not running on a network port.
Speaker 0: So you can't tell that into it, but it's running on.
Speaker 0: you know This local display.
Speaker 0: you can.
Speaker 0: you can look at it.
Speaker 0: So SSH is Basically a secure way of doing that secure shell.
Speaker 0: you're going to connect to Another computer right say from a terminal to a mainframe or nowadays usually a computer to a computer, right?
Speaker 0: And you're going to get a shell on that terminal and that other computer that you can use.
Speaker 0: So most of the time you would use this.
Speaker 0: say I have a web server.
Speaker 0: I have a computer in my house.
Speaker 0: I have to connect to the web server and edit some files on it to can fit reconfigure it.
Speaker 0: Well, I will SSH to the web server.
Speaker 0: now I am connected to it and the terminal from the web server shows up in a box on my screen and my computer and I Can control the web server even though I'm not sitting right next to it.
Speaker 0: but it's as if I'm sitting right next to it and I basically use that more than freaking anything in the entire universe.
Speaker 0: because you know I've said my desk and whatever desk I'm sitting at be my laptop my actual desk my work desk.
Speaker 0: Right the computers that I'm working on are not those computers.
Speaker 0: the computer that I'm sitting at is just a desktop that I'm using Like the browser.
Speaker 1: do we really need to explain what SSH is?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I want to make sure that people know because I hope the non tech people will learn to use SSH.
Speaker 1: I don't know more and more.
Speaker 1: I see like the non tech people don't listen.
Speaker 1: We got to figure out what to do with the Monday show because we always kind of reach this middle ground between you know This is what a keyboard is and the high-level stuff Alright, so so why is SSH cool and why do we replace telnet with it, right?
Speaker 0: It's mostly an issue of security because telnet is just totally plain.
Speaker 0: whatever you send out people can just look at it on the internet It's it's not encrypted or secure in any way.
Speaker 0: if you log into some system over telnet Everyone could just see your username and password floating over the internet, whatever SSH solves this problem with hardcore encryption Totally hardcore and badass.
Speaker 0: that was trivially broken in SSH one with man-in-the-middle attacks Yes, so it SSH to which is the only one you should be using and you're if you don't know what you're using You're probably using SSH to that.
Speaker 0: almost nothing uses sh1 anymore.
Speaker 0: And this is a wicked old piece of shit machine that no one updated like some HP x from a hundred years ago.
Speaker 0: so The way this works right is you just SSH to a machine and then by default it uses like password encryption But all the passwords are encrypted so no one can see them on the line.
Speaker 0: The thing is you don't want to use that because it's a pain in the ass every time you can.
Speaker 0: you're connecting the machines all The time all over the place and you're gonna keep typing in your passwords.
Speaker 0: and hopefully you have a good password So you're typing it in.
Speaker 0: typing it in typing in it sucks.
Speaker 1: Well, well now see I know where you're going with this But I have a much more secure and better solution that I use at work.
Speaker 0: really What's a better solution?
Speaker 1: basically because of the nature of my work?
Speaker 1: You know, we have to be able to have central account management trivially.
Speaker 1: So we use a pro.
Speaker 1: basically we have it integrated with the Active Directory.
Speaker 0: Aha, where now that?
Speaker 1: so if I will but higher level, we're actually using the AD because LDAP, you know Active Directory is just okay.
Speaker 1: Basically, if you're using LDAP directly you're doing it wrong.
Speaker 1: No LDAP is such an obsolete.
Speaker 1: just So what I do is I log into an X server that is in our corporate office hmm, and then from that X server I open I can open sessions to whatever other servers I want and I just Authenticate via Active Directory when that's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's interesting.
Speaker 1: I got to use keys because that would mean that if any computer along the chain is compromised that everything's compromised.
Speaker 1: So no, no keys at all.
Speaker 0: Hmm But then have so you're like when you log to the X when you're connect to the X server, right that centralized one Right, then isn't doesn't?
Speaker 0: isn't it using the keys to connect to the other servers along the line?
Speaker 1: No It's just a convenience so that I can say, you know connect to my accession there and then if I have to go home Or leave my computer or something happens.
Speaker 1: I can just connect to my accession again from somewhere.
Speaker 0: How do the other computers know that it's?
Speaker 0: it's valid when you're connecting to them.
Speaker 0: How do they know that?
Speaker 0: It's cool.
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: How do they know this is cool that I is there some sort of like Active Directory agent that keeps track Of it or what?
Speaker 1: Basically you I mean not getting into the technical details because they're very boring.
Speaker 1: But yeah, basically whatever Active Directory users Permissions are there for a server or just there on that server.
Speaker 1: So, you know this Active Directory account has this shell on the server and the shell on the server and the shell on the server And these accesses to these things.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: That's interesting.
Speaker 0: See I use the keys right and the way the keys work is you basically put your public key on the machine You want to connect to right and you have your private key on your local machine that you never share with anyone Of course as is private.
Speaker 0: and when you connect to the faraway machine, right?
Speaker 0: You basically sign something and send it over the line and the other machine can tell if you signed it.
Speaker 0: So it's basically proving who you are just because you have this key.
Speaker 1: It amazes me How many people just are incapable of setting this up?
Speaker 1: It's not that hard to do.
Speaker 0: It's really easy to set up.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of how-tos online and the best thing about it right is it's one of the rare instances where something can be a more Secure but be more convenient at the same time.
Speaker 1: Well, well unless it there's always the problem of if your computer is compromised and you've got the keys there.
Speaker 0: Well That is true.
Speaker 0: However your keys, you know You should keep them close to your chest and also you should have a passphrase on your keys Right so that even if someone gets your key, they don't they can't use it because they don't have the passphrase.
Speaker 1: Oh, so then I just have to type my password every time I log in.
Speaker 0: That's not true because there is the SSH agent that you should be using.
Speaker 0: See the way the SS ever happy if you use like Ubuntu or Mac.
Speaker 0: now They have a key ring and the way this works basically is you let you log into your local machine.
Speaker 0: You activate your SSH private keys.
Speaker 0: you sort of you know by typing in your passphrase You're like key activate and then so it knows it's you and your key is now good.
Speaker 0: And then you can use the key without typing your password in.
Speaker 0: but then once you log out or the agent dies or anything like That you're gonna have to reactivate the key.
Speaker 0: So basically, you know if someone steals your keys somehow They say they log into your computer remotely and copy the keys or they steal your computer And they turn it on and somehow log into your account, right?
Speaker 0: They need to know the passphrase to unlock those keys to make them work.
Speaker 0: So just having the key is not enough.
Speaker 0: It's a something.
Speaker 0: you have something, you know Situation but you only have to type into something, you know Once each time you sit at the computer so that you know, it's not inconvenient Yeah, where you typing it every time you're logging in
Speaker 1: the problems with this So that one most people use Windows at work, even if they're doing Linux II stuff
Speaker 0: I know it's like yet.
Speaker 0: He's the putty and the the pageant and the whole set up body is just so useless I don't.
Speaker 0: I actually really putty it just I've been rocking the putty lately.
Speaker 0: I totally figured out how to get all that putty Jen pageant.
Speaker 0: I got it all to work.
Speaker 0: It's totally awesome.
Speaker 1: I just use you know, we pay for X win 32.
Speaker 0: Oh if you're paying for it.
Speaker 1: Well, it's a different story It's just it's like night and day.
Speaker 0: yeah, well actually, you know, I use the the Ning X server on Windows with putty and it just frickin works great.
Speaker 0: now that I Know because I know how to do it I could see easily though how someone who is not an expert at this sort of thing would have a very very difficult time Making it work.
Speaker 1: Well X 1 32 does a good job with their so-called quote like live things.
Speaker 1: so I have this you know whole set of terminal sessions together and then I Can basically close it and reopen on different computers in real time and it take it just kind of takes care of a lot Of these basic things on the back end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can't do anything like that.
Speaker 0: All I do is SSH to machines and I can also X forward from the machine.
Speaker 1: I've got a terminal side to.
Speaker 1: that has been running.
Speaker 1: basically I ran something as myself in the foreground.
Speaker 1: So I have this output that I can see and this little GUI that pops up.
Speaker 1: It's been running continuously on that X server for like a year.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow See if I wanted to do something like that I would just use new screen and then when I SSH back in I would use screen X to Get back in the screen session.
Speaker 0: the screen would run for the whole year.
Speaker 0: But yeah, the thing is I'm also using X a lot less lately like on all my servers.
Speaker 0: I'm just using server edition of Ubuntu with no X whatsoever Like.
Speaker 0: the only X I actually use anymore is the X. that's on my Ubuntu laptop.
Speaker 1: I only use X for debugging stuff Like.
Speaker 1: I'm using this product to make like these fixed protocol gateways.
Speaker 1: We're like fixed.
Speaker 1: I just come in product and they go out.
Speaker 1: Well, no it.
Speaker 1: when I say product, you know But I come we bought this product and it was given to me and they were like here This is a product that will do this thing that you need to do.
Speaker 1: It should take you like 10 minutes to set up.
Speaker 1: It's not a product.
Speaker 1: It is a Java development framework.
Speaker 1: Fuck you Ah, it's.
Speaker 1: so yeah, I've been running all this Java code, but it's but it's in X.
Speaker 0: It needs X.
Speaker 1: Well, no, no, it doesn't.
Speaker 1: it's.
Speaker 1: basically it's just a Java.
Speaker 1: Okay The thing is for debugging purposes.
Speaker 1: the Java has a nice GUI built in that I can pop up.
Speaker 1: So when I run this fix router I can have it pop up a GUI that shows me all the connections on both sides.
Speaker 1: Ah, that's nice.
Speaker 1: And the statuses of all of them.
Speaker 1: while I'm setting it up and then when it's done and I know it's working I turn off the GUI and then I you know, make it a Java like Linux service and then I'm done Hmm.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, I learned something because I forgot.
Speaker 1: basically, you know If you want to run something in the background Independent of your user to where you can even log off you you like the no hop and all that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like the best way to do it.
Speaker 1: I did the no hop and all that on this thing.
Speaker 1: Just not thinking and Suddenly var was full.
Speaker 1: Yeah lot.
Speaker 1: No var filled up like 80 gigs were full.
Speaker 0: Standard out was queuing up.
Speaker 1: well the standard out was queuing up and there was a loop with the standard in because the program but you I have to specify no Hop in the thing and specify no up on the command line.
Speaker 0: I just put an ampersand at the end and then do use FG and PS to get them back.
Speaker 0: Well, I do the foreground F G BG.
Speaker 1: some of this Java stuff though doesn't handle that so gracefully Is it?
Speaker 0: you should theoretically be Developing it locally because it's multi flat It's cross-platform and then you can just deploy it to the other server.
Speaker 1: now But the thing is setting up.
Speaker 1: the Java environment is 90% of the battle in Java Environments plus it's also an eclipse deal.
Speaker 1: Nah, it's also the environment of the network.
Speaker 1: Remember, this is a network thing, basically.
Speaker 1: So the environment of the network and the firewalls at all different chains.
Speaker 1: It makes sense to develop it on the server where it's gonna be running one One.
Speaker 0: other thing to talk about.
Speaker 0: SSH tried to bring it back here right is people don't know about the secret feature of SSH?
Speaker 0: Well, there's many secret features But the number one port forwarding one is the SSH secure tunnel port forwarding and tunnels are like They'll solve.
Speaker 1: Oh anytime you have a problem.
Speaker 1: It is probably solved by that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so let's say for example I don't know.
Speaker 0: So I've got a computer and it's got a web server on port 80 where it belongs right and I want to connect to that port 80 Securely right from far away.
Speaker 0: What I can do is I can SSH to that machine and I can make an SSH tunnel Right, which would connect port 80 to say port 80 80. then I can SSH to port 80 80 and Connect that to the port on my local machine and then I can open up my web browser and be like localhost Something something and it's actually making this big tunnel across the internet all the way to some other machine.
Speaker 0: That whole tunnel is totally secure.
Speaker 0: But what happens is there's a port on my local machine that's now securely attached to some port on some other machine across who knows where and I can just securely connect to anything Over SSH and it's it's super super freakin useful in ways that like you won't even realize Like, you know, I try to think of like a really good example.
Speaker 0: Here's a good example, right we had We couldn't get into our home network when we were away on vacation, right and we needed to reconfigure the router.
Speaker 0: But the only way to connect to the router was the routers web server and you can't connect to the routers web server Remotely, you have to be in the house to do it.
Speaker 0: But I had hamachi running on one of the machines in the house.
Speaker 0: so SSH to the machine in the house over hamachi, right and then I Made an SSH tunnel to the routers web server and then on my laptop out while I was on vacation I was able to bring up the routers configuration interface over this is double SSH tunnel and reconfigure the router.
Speaker 0: Well, I wasn't even at home.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of awesomeness and it was totally secure.
Speaker 0: every part of that transaction was totally encrypted and totally safe and nobody's broken it.
Speaker 0: I mean SSH is it a lot of problems, but it's one of those things that it's so ludicrously important that Like pretty much they're constantly ahead of the hackers Like they're just always they're finding things in SSH that are like might be security problems and fixing them Even though no one's taking advantage of them yet or even thought about taking advantage of them.
Speaker 0: It's you know.
Speaker 0: So the day when SSH is broken is a very bad day and you'll see that that'll be a lot worse than like some you Know ie windows vulnerability, you know all real things are gonna start breaking if SSH has a vulnerability in it.
Speaker 0: So, yeah SSH is a tool that people should learn how to use.
Speaker 0: it's totally this.
Speaker 0: open SSH is the most popular implementation of it But there are many non free implementations But as far as I've been experiencing they pretty much all work together.
Speaker 0: just just fine that you know.
Speaker 0: They have no problem.
Speaker 0: putty is the client you want to use if you're on Windows.
Speaker 0: if you're on anything else You just have actual open SSH, but on Windows you need to use weird stuff because Windows side
Speaker 1: It still just really amazes me that to this day like Windows almost is in this ghetto when it like it Windows works fine For just about everything you want to do Except interacting with real development environments.
Speaker 1: You basically just can't SSH or SCP or do anything by default I think.
Speaker 0: well not by default.
Speaker 0: No, not at all.
Speaker 0: But putty I think is a great client, but in terms of servers I mean there are Windows SSH servers, but they're all shit except for the ones that cost a ton of money, right?
Speaker 0: There's like.
Speaker 0: there are ones that actually are very expensive and I've gotten like demos of them and they're great once they work but They're you know, all the free ones on Windows suck.
Speaker 0: theoretically you can use open SSH on Windows the server.
Speaker 0: I've never gotten that to work ever.
Speaker 0: and even if it does work, I can't imagine it's very good.
Speaker 0: But every other machine every Unix Mac Linux just open SSH just works amazingly and perfectly every time Especially if you have a newer version of it.
Speaker 0: It's just great fantastic.
Speaker 0: and and Ubuntu and OS X both have GUI key management utilities that just work.
Speaker 0: No problem, they handle the agent.
Speaker 0: they handle everything for you in Windows.
Speaker 0: If you want to do that stuff, you need to use putty Jen and pageant, you know P You know the putty agent and I've gotten those things to work.
Speaker 0: It's not difficult, but it does require some doing.
Speaker 0: it's not just you know, push a button like it is in Mac and Linux.
Speaker 1: One thing I've really it seems strange to me that even a lot of technical people I know don't know any like they really don't know any of the advanced stuff around SSH and terminals.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean, it's usually because most especially IT people are mostly Windows people, you know.
Speaker 0: And they Windows people just don't use SSH.
Speaker 0: They always use like even remote desktop or go to my PC or any of those sorts of things.
Speaker 1: Oh my god any.
Speaker 1: pretty much whenever I work, you know, I interview people I one of the things I always ask them is like yeah go to my PC and all that stuff because I know they don't Know what they're doing.
Speaker 0: Pretty readily by asking them those sorts of go to my PC is actually a good product But it is.
Speaker 0: maybe use it as an IT tool.
Speaker 0: That's a problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, that should not be no same thing.
Speaker 0: VNC.
Speaker 0: like you go to those companies.
Speaker 0: It was like a VNC server running at every desktop.
Speaker 1: bad And the way they teach people and I remember that the first year of our IT is a freshman It was every class basically forced you to use all of these Unix tools and they weren't taught to you.
Speaker 1: It was just assumed that you either knew them or you'd figure them out And you could tell the people who didn't figure them out because they didn't graduate.
Speaker 0: Here's another example of why SSH is awesome, right?
Speaker 0: I was at our IT.
Speaker 0: I was a computer science student, right?
Speaker 0: even if you could work on your projects at home you needed to go to the computer science lab and you had to submit it On their computer science computers and had to work on those computers, right?
Speaker 0: You couldn't submit it from your computer.
Speaker 0: The thing is you could SSH to the computer science lab and use one of those computers Even though you weren't sitting in front of it, which is very nice.
Speaker 0: You can just do all your computer science work from your dorm or your apartment.
Speaker 0: Smart people did that.
Speaker 0: Stupid people went into the CS labs and had to go all the way across campus or commute or whatever else the hell they did To get over there, right?
Speaker 0: So That's that's the kind of power that something like SSH has and that's what I started using.
Speaker 0: It was when I decided I was gonna save myself a trip across campus because SSH is just that powerful.
Speaker 0: It's as powerful as a two-mile walk.
Speaker 1: Alright, I gotta go to work soon.
Speaker 0: Oh man, night work.
Speaker 1: And there's a crazy thunderstorm, so I think we'll just leave it at that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's done.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our crapper map, and links to all the We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology, Tuesdays We have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: For the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.