Speaker 1: Hey, it's Wednesday August 12th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We ramble a little bit about the anime and comics We're watching and reading right now.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess anime con seasons finally over for us for a while.
Speaker 0: How over is it?
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, what do we have to do?
Speaker 1: Let me have the New York anime festival, which is usually pretty easy.
Speaker 1: We're doing like two panels at it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just bang bang.
Speaker 1: and then what anime?
Speaker 1: Boston?
Speaker 0: Anyway, Boston's next year.
Speaker 0: It's not this year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so don't have much to do.
Speaker 0: I guess finally relax I guess not that's that's kind of interesting.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: Oh con season But wait Pax is coming, isn't it?
Speaker 1: Yeah, Pax is coming.
Speaker 1: the schedule for Pax West was just put online and you can see our three panels.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna talk about it much.
Speaker 1: But obviously we're doing three panels at Pax.
Speaker 1: We talked about it a lot in the last couple of shows and we'll talk about it before Pax.
Speaker 0: The thing is funny.
Speaker 0: Django con which I probably won't go to but I might if work takes care of it for me is You know because Pax is Friday Saturday Sunday, then Monday is Labor Day.
Speaker 0: Django con is Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday Nah in Portland, so it's like I go to the west coast of Seattle then have to get.
Speaker 0: if I did it I have to go to Portland from Seattle and then stay there for into and then come home like Friday.
Speaker 1: So one thing that's interesting though.
Speaker 1: Pax is starting at like 10 a.m.
Speaker 1: On Friday this year.
Speaker 0: Start early on Friday instead of starting super late like they usually do.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, I don't know if it was usually.
Speaker 1: I never really looked at the time schedule until the year we went last year.
Speaker 0: So I also I want to make a note that just an interesting note of something I discovered.
Speaker 0: right you discover Pax mails out the badges But I found out they don't mail them to Canada, huh?
Speaker 0: I don't think they.
Speaker 0: I think they only mail them to US people.
Speaker 1: Well, they don't mail them to people like us either.
Speaker 1: Remember we have to go to that special like register.
Speaker 0: The thing is going to.
Speaker 0: that special place is gonna be cool because all the other special people are gonna be there.
Speaker 1: It still amazes me that I mean the fact that I have like the same badge as MC front a lot.
Speaker 1: It's like I could walk up to him be like hey, man We're peers and he could laugh at me and then we could go about our lives.
Speaker 0: He's ten times our talent I know.
Speaker 1: All right, so it's definitely one of those people who was put in his 10,000 hours, right?
Speaker 0: So Let's you got to go to work because this is your night work week.
Speaker 1: Yep this week I've been supporting like the European environment.
Speaker 1: So I've been working midnight to nine and let me tell you It sucks, right?
Speaker 1: So let's let's get this episode on a roll here on a roll.
Speaker 0: Yes on a roll.
Speaker 0: Here's my news.
Speaker 0: ready is a quick news.
Speaker 0: Okay, I decided to get all comic stuff cuz I know rims gonna lay it down Heavy with the animes.
Speaker 1: Well, I'll tell you this.
Speaker 1: I will talk about every piece of anime news from the last four months.
Speaker 1: That is in any way interesting.
Speaker 0: Okay, so check this out right a while back.
Speaker 0: You know, there's a. What's his name?
Speaker 0: Oh Todd McFarlane, you know Todd McFarlane, right?
Speaker 0: Yes the spawn guy, right?
Speaker 0: The thing is he hasn't actually made comics in since 2000 forever, right?
Speaker 0: So Robert Kirkman, who's the walking dead?
Speaker 0: Guy, right?
Speaker 0: He went to at some convention.
Speaker 0: It was it was like a famous thing.
Speaker 0: He went up and he was like Todd McFarlane, you know, I'm making you all this money with my walking dead image comics, right?
Speaker 0: He's like you haven't made a comic in forever.
Speaker 0: I'll write a comic and you draw it and the guy was like, okay, right?
Speaker 0: So just in this, you know, most recent previews catalog.
Speaker 0: So I guess coming out in two months from now.
Speaker 0: So what's?
Speaker 0: it's August.
Speaker 0: so in October, you know, what's coming out?
Speaker 1: Haunt number one on number one.
Speaker 0: So haunt is if you don't know it's basically a spider-man ripoff of Todd McFarlane's from back in the day.
Speaker 0: It's basically spider-man with sort of a black costume with jizz all over it, right?
Speaker 0: It's not even drawn by Todd McFarlane.
Speaker 0: He only inked it.
Speaker 0: He didn't do the rest of the art not the colors of the page only doing the inking and it's written by Kirkman.
Speaker 0: So everyone pretty much saw it and was like really we had that big he'd be stood up and he challenged him at a convention Like draw comic again.
Speaker 0: See what you can do and that's what he wrote.
Speaker 0: and then he comes up with this piece of shit.
Speaker 0: So it's just sort of funny how things work out that way.
Speaker 0: I think you know.
Speaker 0: I think it's pretty obvious by now that Todd McFarlane is the guy who.
Speaker 0: I don't think he just cares about Comics that much.
Speaker 0: I think he just cares about, you know business and money more so but you know, that's who he is whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess I won't read it.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'll show you the cover.
Speaker 0: those you can lol at it.
Speaker 0: If you yeah go online and search for like haunt comic or like go to image comics website and look for haunt It's.
Speaker 0: uh, hi Larry is when you see this cover It's basically the same cover Todd McFarlane's drawn a thousand times before in his life.
Speaker 1: So Kagoshima to get tourism and that sort of thing and also probably for respect and nostalgia is having a new Galaxy Express 999 short made but the short is 999 seconds long and will premiere on September 9th 2009.
Speaker 0: I Mean that's cool and all.
Speaker 0: but I mean, is it really gonna be good?
Speaker 0: I mean, it's probably gonna be much better.
Speaker 0: Well more well animated because it's only a short and it's made in modern times But it's just a short and it's made for advertising purposes.
Speaker 0: I don't think this is something I really need to run out and see.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 1: at the same time though It looks like they've got all the right ducks in line.
Speaker 1: I mean, obviously there is some love here because one you know wrote it the same guy did hakaba ki taro.
Speaker 0: I like that guy.
Speaker 1: I trust that guy Yoshimi not finish that freakin show.
Speaker 0: Yeah Why don't they bring that manga out here?
Speaker 0: That's a manga.
Speaker 0: I'll buy Are you?
Speaker 0: are you listening Viz or whoever?
Speaker 1: But also to celebrate the 30th anniversary of Galaxy Express 3 9 They're going to be showing a remastered version of it in Japan.
Speaker 0: Are you the tea of the movie?
Speaker 1: I'd love a TV show.
Speaker 1: I guess the whole TV show 100 and it just says Galaxy Express 3 9 anime to mark the film's 30th anniversary.
Speaker 0: I assume that's the movie.
Speaker 0: They said film is the movie.
Speaker 1: Okay, but they're getting the original voice cast and everything for this thing.
Speaker 0: Maybe we should get that.
Speaker 0: I want to know I got it.
Speaker 0: We got to get like that remastered DVD when it comes out.
Speaker 1: I'm sure we'll be able to get it in some capacity.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that'd be awesome.
Speaker 1: It is scary though.
Speaker 1: looking at this picture I don't know if it's from the short or not but Tetsuro is pretty on model in the first episode of Galaxy Express and pretty much gets more and more and more off model as the
Speaker 0: Tetsuro is drawn differently in all these in all the like in the movies.
Speaker 0: He's drawn very normal.
Speaker 1: He's not like a potato head or but in this picture here is definitely potato head, but the eyes are lined up.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, they're almost the same size.
Speaker 0: the TV show He's a potato head, but he's sort of even still normal and like in some of the series like That I've seen like he's drawn.
Speaker 0: He's like missing a lump like they don't Properly at all and and he's totally acts like.
Speaker 0: so, you know, it's like there's all these multiple different characters.
Speaker 0: They all call them all Tetsuro But you know only some of them are good and some of them are.
Speaker 1: see while his character is consistent in the actual anime He definitely gets more and more off model throughout the show and then kind of comes back on model at the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, it's just weird to see how him having two reasonably similarly sized eyes that are almost lined up with each other Wait, wait, do you see him in the movie?
Speaker 1: I've seen him in the movie.
Speaker 0: He's completely different.
Speaker 1: It's not Tetsuro at some other guy.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but as far as I can tell that's all the anime news.
Speaker 1: I mean, I didn't really want to talk about the fact that for kids is losing money hand over fist But it's not news.
Speaker 1: anime is not really on TV.
Speaker 0: So what are they gonna do?
Speaker 0: Yeah, thanks to the three-year-old news Okay.
Speaker 1: Anyway, well the fact that they lost money is actually new news.
Speaker 1: They weren't losing money before.
Speaker 0: It's not a surprise.
Speaker 0: It's like if you didn't if you didn't know that was coming then I don't know what to say.
Speaker 1: No It's more that it's sad that anime is just not like.
Speaker 1: no one's pushing it anymore in the US and the whole industry is just Collapsing.
Speaker 0: what what's new about that?
Speaker 0: Nothing.
Speaker 0: It's it's been around.
Speaker 1: It's like okay, but I thought geek nights was commentary not news.
Speaker 1: You can always get the news a lot sooner than you'll get it from us Especially before.
Speaker 0: but everyone has already said everything there is to say about the collapsing anime industry.
Speaker 0: Not only is it not new there is nothing new to say.
Speaker 0: It's all been said anime dead end of story.
Speaker 0: What you gonna do?
Speaker 1: All right, you got a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Oh, I do have a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: So, you know Rob Liefeld the guy everyone likes to make fun of for not being able to draw feeder hands and making people who are entirely too muscly and Putting lots and lots of pouches and belts on all the x-men and such.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess it was also Jim Lee doing that.
Speaker 0: but regardless that Rob Liefeld, right?
Speaker 0: You know, he's you know, despite you know, what you whether you think of his arts good or bad, right?
Speaker 0: And obviously he can't draw feet.
Speaker 0: There's no question about that, right?
Speaker 0: You know, he still goes to conventions.
Speaker 0: He still has fans.
Speaker 0: He still makes stuff, you know, and from what I hear I've never met him.
Speaker 0: He's not really a bad person.
Speaker 0: He's just you know, he is who he is.
Speaker 0: So some kids, you know thought they would be all cool and they went and they were at.
Speaker 0: you know They saw that Rob Liefeld was there and they you know were like, you know, but they were all wussy fanboys, right?
Speaker 0: They didn't have the balls to like.
Speaker 0: just go up to him.
Speaker 0: be like you suck, right?
Speaker 0: So they were just sort of like hey, what's going on?
Speaker 0: right, but then they were they were around the comic convention and they saw for sale an old copy of How to draw comics the Marvel Way, oh man, that's that's semi infamous, right?
Speaker 0: so they bought it for like five or ten bucks and They because you know, it's not an expensive book and they basically wrote like instead of you know Handing it to him be like hey, man I think you could really use this, you know, like I'm like someone with balls would do right?
Speaker 0: They basically wrote a note in the back.
Speaker 0: They like set it down in his table and like tapped it with their hand a few times and ran away like little girlies Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, you know a lot of people on the internet were like, you know Even though they might you know, not be be Liefeld fans and make fun of them all the time on the Internet's.
Speaker 0: They were all like hey, that's not cool man, right?
Speaker 0: You know, like you shouldn't be going insulted and people like that blah blah blah, but I was like, hey That was cool.
Speaker 0: But the part there wasn't cool was not that they were insulting him.
Speaker 0: It was that they insulted him like pussies, right?
Speaker 0: If you want to insult the man you got to go up and you know do it, right?
Speaker 0: I mean like imagine if you are at a convention, I got to do it cleverly.
Speaker 1: You've got to have like the the one-two punch the exactly the punch it has to be and it has to be the insult That is given with a little bit of love
Speaker 0: exactly like if I'm sitting there at the geek night's table at some convention right and someone comes up and like puts Podcasting for dummies on the table like taps it a few times and run and walks away like a wuss.
Speaker 0: I'll just be like what the fuck they just give me a free book.
Speaker 0: What are they trying to advertise?
Speaker 0: I'm just like what the fuck is going on, right?
Speaker 0: But if they come up and they'd be like, you know, hey, I really think you could use this.
Speaker 0: I'd be like, oh man laws that I'd you know I'd be shaking their hand to get a picture with them and you know, I'd sign the book for whatever, you know It'd be.
Speaker 0: it'd be a good times if they had balls, right?
Speaker 0: Because I wouldn't take it all You know angrily as some people might but you know, this is a is an example of how not to be right.
Speaker 0: This is why this is my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Don't be this guy.
Speaker 1: Don't do what Donny don't doesn't do exactly either.
Speaker 0: Don't insult people or insult them with you know balls, even if you're a girl, you know, not necessarily balls.
Speaker 1: I think panache is what you really need.
Speaker 1: that too and a little bit of hutzpah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's those are all related to the testicle The virtual testicles not the physical ones.
Speaker 1: So I think this is really cool And hopefully you will too.
Speaker 1: and if you think this is not cool watch it before you pass judgment.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: if you think if you don't think this is cool, then you're not qualified to be geek nights listener.
Speaker 1: very simply Cars have something called a differential gear.
Speaker 1: It's how they can turn.
Speaker 1: and if you don't understand why?
Speaker 1: This video explains better and in more concisely and more directly than anything I've ever seen in my life.
Speaker 1: It is just they take the concept and they boil it down to its fundamental in a way that anyone anyone could understand.
Speaker 1: And this is from the 30s, I I don't know.
Speaker 1: it's kind of weird to watch this kind of explanation of something and then I look at all the kind of like how-to's and Explanations of things you see on YouTube and on how stuff works today, and they're just not nearly as elegant.
Speaker 0: Maybe we should make a series of how-to videos about modern ultra modern things But make them in this style with that narration and a black and white video.
Speaker 1: Of course part of the problem is that a differential gear, you know You know.
Speaker 1: once you know the concept the engineering part of it's pretty straightforward, but now Many things are not conceptually simple let alone Engineering Lee simple and the yeah like the fundamental concept of a lot of engineering feats today Alone would take an entire lifetime to understand fully.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's just the way of the world, but you know, I think this is actually you know.
Speaker 0: The coolest thing about this video I think is you by watching it you see how much effort they put into it.
Speaker 0: Like look how many different gears they made to show you the progression from the concept like Lincoln log tinker toy Differential up to the real deal, you know, it was.
Speaker 0: you know, it's like wow, they could have made like three But they made like ten Whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we need more videos like this.
Speaker 1: So if anyone knows of any let me know because I got to point out that there are a bunch of related videos that are all just terrible Simulations our explanation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I almost feel like if I had a video like this for every part of the car I could be a mechanic just watching them all I'd be done.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't have to go to mechanic school or anything.
Speaker 1: The thing is it's one thing to know how a differential works.
Speaker 1: It's another thing to unlock a locked differential.
Speaker 0: This is true.
Speaker 0: All right, so let's You decided that because you're working nights and such and because we didn't really read or watch much in common.
Speaker 1: Yep, basically Scott's reading a lot of comics.
Speaker 1: I'm watching a lot of anime and we're not linking up.
Speaker 0: Not really not linking up very much at all.
Speaker 0: So maybe we are gonna do a show that consists entirely of geek bites.
Speaker 1: one thing I got to say though that while I'm watching and doing a lot of stuff right now What I want to be watching is basically ghost in the shell standalone complex, but I've already seen that.
Speaker 0: I have already seen that Yes, but I keep it like every time I watch anime.
Speaker 1: I just think I want some sort of sci-fi Procedural every time there's a new anime season, right?
Speaker 0: I look at all the shows that are listed and I'm like man Like I don't like.
Speaker 0: I don't really want to watch any of them Right, or at least I don't have a strong feeling for any of them I'm.
Speaker 0: the only show that I'm really looking for is like standalone complex third gig.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm looking for.
Speaker 0: It's like where is that?
Speaker 0: That's what I want to see.
Speaker 0: more shit like that.
Speaker 1: Well thing is I mean Michio and Hachin and I guess Gurren Lagann's him already going back.
Speaker 0: Yeah What?
Speaker 1: yeah, how can you not be except both of those shows are fantastic.
Speaker 1: Yeah Alright, so what are you doing?
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Never watches anime.
Speaker 0: I finished watching all a hundred and thirteen episodes of the galaxy express 3 9 TV show Which I think puts me in a very exclusive club of people have seen all 113 episodes.
Speaker 0: I've seen a little under half.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now how many people in the entire history of the world?
Speaker 0: Do you think I've seen all 113?
Speaker 0: Well good for you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it's on crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: It's free.
Speaker 0: You should probably watch that but no I have also Let's see if I watched any other a nimes at all.
Speaker 1: No you haven't.
Speaker 1: you don't do anything.
Speaker 0: No, I didn't watch any a Not any nimes that I can remember.
Speaker 0: I've you know, but I'm about to watch Boca rata which is a show that I put off.
Speaker 1: Ah, you're putting that off for so long.
Speaker 1: I've see.
Speaker 1: I watched that show like over a year ago.
Speaker 0: It was in the queue and now it came up in the queue.
Speaker 0: people are always like oh, you know I'm just like a year ago.
Speaker 0: You were like, you know some months ago.
Speaker 0: You're like.
Speaker 0: watch Boca Rana.
Speaker 1: See the thing is I'm watching by having your cue.
Speaker 1: the way you are You're basically in that XKCD situation.
Speaker 1: We're a year or two after it's done.
Speaker 1: You'll be that guy going like hey, man The cake is a lie.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not cuz I don't do stupid shit like that.
Speaker 1: Well, though that's conceptually Scott not literally.
Speaker 1: good God.
Speaker 1: as in you're the one who reads the prince of nothing the fourth book like two years after everyone else already read it talked About it is done with it.
Speaker 0: So what's the difference?
Speaker 1: So then you don't get to talk to anyone about it.
Speaker 0: What do I need to talk to him?
Speaker 0: I enjoy just the same.
Speaker 0: What's the?
Speaker 0: what's the problem?
Speaker 1: I'd say a good half the enjoyment I get from media is Discussing the media with other people who have also experienced it.
Speaker 0: If I wanted to discuss the media and that was where the enjoyment came from that I probably would just read CliffsNotes and shit, you know, the enjoyment of media is the media in and of itself.
Speaker 1: Well, that's part of it.
Speaker 1: But I get very I get equal enjoyment from discussing and you know Seeing other people experience and that sort of thing that I do from actually watching the media.
Speaker 0: My enjoyment is from the the art itself and all right, I really have this need to discuss it with people.
Speaker 0: I mean plus if I see it a year later and Someone might still want to discuss it.
Speaker 0: If not, if not, whatever.
Speaker 0: It's not a big deal.
Speaker 0: but anyway I'm gonna watch the Bocorano soon and I does anyone out there know if The Bocorano manga is scans lated or is gonna be published or something?
Speaker 0: because you know I heard long ago that you know, the the TV show was toned down from the manga.
Speaker 0: I don't know how true that is But I think we didn't news about it once and I really really want to read the original Bocorano manga to compare and contrast with the TV show which is only 24 episodes which now feels measly compared to the Galaxy Express 3913.
Speaker 0: I think that I think was actually sort of good for me to watch the Galaxy Express.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like when a baseball player gets on deck and he swings the bat with a big heavy weight on it.
Speaker 1: Scott Did you look at all?
Speaker 1: all the scans are online?
Speaker 0: Are they really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it took two seconds on Google.
Speaker 1: here They are.
Speaker 0: I don't know how to find scans.
Speaker 0: Really.
Speaker 0: I'm not googled for it.
Speaker 0: I'm not a big scans person.
Speaker 0: So I don't really and I haven't read scans since Death Note and I own all that.
Speaker 0: so So, okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, send me that link and I will I'll check it out.
Speaker 1: man.
Speaker 1: They're watching Bocorano.
Speaker 1: No, that was Scott Johnson of all.
Speaker 1: people finally watch Boca.
Speaker 0: That's his kind of show.
Speaker 1: if a show has ever been up his alley more so than now and then here and there it is Bocorano.
Speaker 0: It's definitely a Scott Johnson show.
Speaker 1: He just likes tragedy in space.
Speaker 0: Well, this is tragedy on earth and a robot which is close to space.
Speaker 1: Well, wait Bocorano is a show that pulls a switch up a little bit.
Speaker 0: It goes to space.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't want to say what it's really about but it's a show in space.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's a show that has a lot of change ups and it addresses.
Speaker 1: it addresses issues in a manner that usually shows.
Speaker 0: You know I did watch a handful of episodes of it.
Speaker 0: I watched like four or five if I remember.
Speaker 1: it's a show that gets a lot of points for the fact that and all all the Characters react in believable and intelligent manners.
Speaker 1: There's a space robot.
Speaker 1: I go straight to the military.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the show did progress really quickly from the few episodes I watched.
Speaker 0: so it would have to pull some change-ups in order to have somewhere to go for 24 episodes.
Speaker 0: They'd run out of ground real quick.
Speaker 1: They couldn't really run out of ground because all they have to do is kill one child per episode and then when they're out of Thing is is 24 episodes, but there aren't 24 children so it has to be at a slower rate than that.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe they get some more children.
Speaker 0: Maybe that's possible.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: the room of golf is empty.
Speaker 0: No, no room.
Speaker 0: go know whoever you get that joke.
Speaker 0: You're a hundred million times awesome and you win a prize.
Speaker 0: The prize is this golf clap.
Speaker 0: I Don't know if you heard that or not.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure the noise suppression will get rid of that.
Speaker 0: Okay, but you you there was a golf clap there.
Speaker 0: whether you heard or not.
Speaker 0: All right, so well you've been watching a bunch of animes.
Speaker 0: I watched oh my god.
Speaker 1: So I recently I think I mentioned this before finally watched giant robo and that show is like.
Speaker 0: that was a while ago.
Speaker 1: It wasn't that long ago.
Speaker 1: That show is like so great.
Speaker 1: I cannot express to you how great giant robo is But you really can't enjoy it unless you're an anime fan who has seen a lot of anime.
Speaker 1: It is it's like the I think I said the uncanny valley of highbrow.
Speaker 1: lowbrow Where it seems lowbrow Unless you've gotten past this point and once you get past that point you realize that it's actually highbrow secret highbrow But it's almost faux highbrow.
Speaker 1: Oh That's what I would say.
Speaker 1: faux highbrow is what I would call giant robo.
Speaker 0: guys like lifting up one eyebrow But then you get to get a closer look and it was a false brow.
Speaker 1: It's just there's so much.
Speaker 1: oh my it's got.
Speaker 1: It's got homage to all these like great And other anime and all that but it's got this kind of symphonic classy character That it very much reeks of.
Speaker 1: read or die of you take as absurd concepts But you animate it really well with good music and good characters and you make it take itself 100% dead serious.
Speaker 1: There is never a moment where the show doubts itself in any way.
Speaker 0: I think that is.
Speaker 0: that is something that a lot of animes have in common.
Speaker 0: when like this is like visual like Lunacy going on right, but it's taken completely seriously.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, that's really, you know, if you look at something like, you know Gundam it's like the almost the same exact thing, right?
Speaker 0: They have these like ludicrous robots that they just.
Speaker 0: they really are completely nuts But everyone just takes them at face value and and thus they are at face value.
Speaker 0: and it's all about you know the attitude of The believable human characters in a show towards the nutty unrealistic things that happen in the show.
Speaker 0: You know Like this, you know Galaxy Express in 113 episodes.
Speaker 0: Some episodes are better than others and the ones that are better are usually not necessarily the ones where you know There aren't crazy things.
Speaker 0: cuz I mean there are crazy episodes with like freaking dinosaurs and shit, right?
Speaker 0: But it's the episodes where they don't treat the crazy things as being crazy.
Speaker 0: Like there's an episode with like weird aliens, but the weird aliens that were totally goofy were you know treated as totally normal aliens.
Speaker 0: You know, there's an episode of like the butterfly people but they treated the butterfly people as people so it worked out Well, but then there were some other episodes.
Speaker 0: were just normal people not nothing even crazy But they treated it as wacky.
Speaker 0: so it came off all and it wasn't, you know, the greatest episode ever.
Speaker 1: They just it all harkens back to read or die when they make that giant paper airplane and ride it off of the skyscraper Into a dogfight.
Speaker 0: Mmm, man, if you're on a go, but you know, but when you were watching giant Robo, I was watching like Goon saga, I never finished that.
Speaker 0: maybe after I finished bokurato.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go back and try to finish the goon side.
Speaker 1: I definitely want to watch some goon sighs.
Speaker 1: I saw the first I think three episodes.
Speaker 0: I was like, nah, I really dug it maybe four or five.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: You know how I want a ghost in the shell standalone complex to happen again.
Speaker 1: I want a serious fantasy anime to happen again when goon saga is a serious fan exactly so I gotta watch it.
Speaker 0: There was also watching the shin messenger which is directed by the giant robo guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, you know what they're.
Speaker 1: they having seen the first episode of that They're very very similar in the way They treat themselves.
Speaker 0: well.
Speaker 0: after that if you watch the second at the first episode is like, uh, and the second episode is like, ah the third episodes like oh Okay.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: It's like they did something that whole concept of you know start with something crazy and then Eventually get to the point of so how did it all come to this?
Speaker 1: I love that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: That's sort of like in media res but not really because there's no way you could have possibly known what was going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 0: So let me talk about some comics here.
Speaker 0: So I read I got the first trade paperback of all star Batman and Robin and the reason it's called all star Batman and Robin is because the creators are all stars.
Speaker 0: It's written by a Frank Miller and drawn by Jim Lee's the all-star Batman and Robin, right?
Speaker 0: And it doesn't really have much to do with any other Batman or Robin.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, you know, it's the it's you know, same story of you know, the origin of Robin, right?
Speaker 0: But it's you know, it's.
Speaker 0: it's not like, you know It has anything to do with like.
Speaker 0: it's not like.
Speaker 0: it's a read the actual Batman comic to know what's going on.
Speaker 0: It's not tied in with anything else.
Speaker 0: In fact, you know someone suggested that this is in like the Dark Knight universe.
Speaker 0: But so it's like the pre prequel, you know, like way back.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I'm not worrying about DC continuity, right?
Speaker 0: Exactly You know, this is the sort of the it's.
Speaker 0: it's sort of infamous on the Internet's, you know.
Speaker 0: You've probably seen like pictures of Batman Painting the whole like apartment yellow for when the Green Lantern shows up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's this comic, right?
Speaker 0: Also, the thing is that the thing that this comic is most infamous for that You might not realize.
Speaker 0: is you've heard people talk about the goddamn Batman, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's where this comes from.
Speaker 0: They basically say goddamn Batman like a thousand times.
Speaker 0: There's even one panel where he's like, you know What this girl's insulting him for calling it the Batmobile like.
Speaker 0: that's one of the jokes is like the Batmobile is a stupid name.
Speaker 0: He's like.
Speaker 0: I'm the goddamn Batman.
Speaker 0: I'll call my goddamn car.
Speaker 0: Whatever I goddamn feel like You know, it's like that.
Speaker 1: that is very juggernaut.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly, right?
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: you know, it's not the best Batman comic in the universe.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: if you want a Batman comic to read and you already read Dark Knight Returns Why the hell not right?
Speaker 0: I mean, it's Batman.
Speaker 0: But give me that same feeling of when I read Dark Knight Returns the right, you know, I don't read Dark Knight Returns.
Speaker 0: I feel like I'm watching a Batman movie, right?
Speaker 0: This feels more like I Don't know.
Speaker 1: Well Scott.
Speaker 1: We're in the minority where we like the Michael Keaton Batman above all other Batman movies, correct?
Speaker 1: I mean, I'll admit I thought Batman begins with shit.
Speaker 0: I also thought Batman begins with shit.
Speaker 1: It was just too unrelated movie.
Speaker 0: It was like a kung-fu movie coupled with a cheesy Batman movie with no real I didn't see the newest one that everyone likes so much but is Directed by the same guy who like who made the Batman, you know begins or whatever, which I thought was poop.
Speaker 0: and You know everyone who liked the one that I thought was poop also like the new one the Dark Knight.
Speaker 1: So what the new one had goods?
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna prejudge was the Joker but I watched on YouTube every scene that the Joker's in Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: I feel like that's all I needed to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see I can't pass a judgment because I haven't seen it.
Speaker 1: Wait, so then to this day, you don't know what the pencil trick is.
Speaker 0: I don't really care.
Speaker 1: Joker does a really good magic trick with a pencil.
Speaker 0: I know that everyone makes a joke about a pencil trick and I really just don't give a shit what it is It's really man.
Speaker 1: You're all like soon.
Speaker 0: today today, whatever movie new cares.
Speaker 0: It's like Joke about the pencil trick whatever.
Speaker 1: I don't care about the anime industry.
Speaker 1: I don't watch anime and I don't care about anything.
Speaker 0: Anyone else cares about this crap.
Speaker 1: So you ever get excited about anything?
Speaker 0: I'm good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm getting excited about all these other things I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: All right, you're being all you're not?
Speaker 0: I watch 113 episodes of Galaxy Express.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It's one of the greatest anime ever I'd like.
Speaker 1: I'm so pumped about watching the end because I haven't seen the movie in like Almost 10 years.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I saw the movie maybe a year or so ago when I downloaded it But that was only the second time I watched it.
Speaker 0: No only the first time I watched it unedited.
Speaker 1: I'm real excited because Emily has like she's.
Speaker 1: she has not seen the movie and she has not seen the anime.
Speaker 1: So well, she saw random episodes of the anime, but she does not know like what it really is.
Speaker 0: I remember sitting there once and she's like, so what's may tells deal and I'm like, you don't know.
Speaker 1: Holy shit Really, but imagine being a kid in the 70s in Japan where you didn't know.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is you were spoiled as soon as you saw the movie if you saw the movie.
Speaker 0: So anyway, yeah, there's that Batman book is out there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: you can get it in a trade.
Speaker 0: now The trade isn't all of it though.
Speaker 0: There's like another trade coming But apparently it just takes them so long to come out with issues of this.
Speaker 0: So who knows when that second trade is coming probably years from now?
Speaker 1: actually what I'm watching right now that I'm really excited about is I Finally own irresponsible captain Tyler, which is weird because you know, whenever we do that anime you should see panel.
Speaker 1: I talk about anime.
Speaker 1: I always talk about how like utenna is my favorite anime and cowboy bebop is the best anime and I have all these things.
Speaker 1: but Really Irresponsible captain Tyler is in many ways my personal favorite anime.
Speaker 1: The show was just is one of the first anime that I really watched and really got into.
Speaker 1: I mean I bought VHS tapes of this thing back in the day.
Speaker 0: It's a real crowd-pleaser That's for sure.
Speaker 1: One thing I can say though is I watched it like I didn't even see all of it.
Speaker 1: You know, I never had money.
Speaker 1: I got like the first couple of VHS tapes.
Speaker 0: So I saw like the first maybe nine episodes, but I only really paid attention to the first two or three.
Speaker 1: I saw the first I don't know seven episodes back in the day.
Speaker 1: legitimately I saw like eight more episodes in shit like terrible fan subs and then I saw the last three episodes and then this like 100 by 100 pixel RM file of the movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I saw that hundred by hundred RM file the movie, but I don't remember anything I will.
Speaker 1: basically it's just Roman holiday.
Speaker 0: Oh, I like Roman holiday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well then you would really like the responsible captain Tyler movie.
Speaker 0: I can go back and watch that wreck show.
Speaker 0: That wasn't too many.
Speaker 1: Oh my god That show was great.
Speaker 1: At least the one episode ever.
Speaker 1: We watched was good Roman holiday episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, but every episode of that was like an Audrey Hepburn movie.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm All right, I'll take a little break in the middle of the episode here.
Speaker 0: break.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I gotta talk about something.
Speaker 1: I was in the middle of talking about something.
Speaker 1: Come on irresponsible captain Tyler.
Speaker 1: The thing is it's like it's my favorite show, but I really like.
Speaker 1: I watched it Mostly once a long time ago and it says a lot that it influenced me so much to where I hold it in such high esteem.
Speaker 1: and Like when Scott watch Ava again or when I watch eska flown a again or a lot of these older anime that you know I always thought it was like the greatest things ever.
Speaker 1: I finally bought the box set because it was republished in a thin pack and it wasn't like $100 and I started watching it again I'm about halfway through.
Speaker 1: I've seen the first like 14 episodes now on a DVD for reals and Any time I worry that some show that I thought was great a long time ago is gonna he-man me.
Speaker 1: Anime always proves me wrong.
Speaker 1: This show is just so fantastic I know right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, I saw he-man when I was a kid and I thought it was great And I watch it now not so great But like Ava, you know you just said it's like I watched Ava right like a couple times back in the day and I didn't watch it for a long Time and all I you know, just people kept talking about it.
Speaker 0: All the show fucks with your head.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's got a crazy ending.
Speaker 0: Oh, it sucks and I sorta, you know forgot that it was great.
Speaker 0: And then I watched it again and it was better than it had ever been.
Speaker 0: and I'm like, wow All these years these people have been saying it's you know hard this and that and like they were all completely wrong.
Speaker 0: And I think captain Tyler is you know the same way.
Speaker 0: It's like I haven't seen it in forever.
Speaker 0: I remember it was kind of silly, you know above average.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling when I watch it again It's gonna be like oh shit.
Speaker 1: one thing I I hadn't seen a lot of anime when I saw irresponsible captain Tyler the first time.
Speaker 1: But now and I'm noticed that's the same thing with giant robo.
Speaker 1: I've seen a lot of anime now.
Speaker 1: I remember that list of you know, like the hundred must see anime and I'll.
Speaker 1: Basically, we've seen like 98 of them.
Speaker 0: Most of them or we at least know of or you know are very familiar with them if we haven't actually seen them.
Speaker 1: so watching it now and Having all this context the show is even better.
Speaker 1: like just there's so many legend of the galactic heroes jokes Because it's kind of.
Speaker 1: you know young wendy like it's kind of based on that in a way and that it's almost a parody of it, but not really it.
Speaker 1: Plus the animation is Surprisingly good.
Speaker 1: I mean the show feels almost if you start to watch it again at first like one of those kind of low-budget anime, but you look at it and the cell animation is just Surprisingly beautiful and well done.
Speaker 1: It just really stands out and there's such attention to detail and I think a Lot of people.
Speaker 1: this has made me realize, you know, Dave and Joel when they talk about Akira they talked a lot about cell animation and how everything after cell animation wasn't as good and how great that is and I Realized exactly what the issue is with cell animation.
Speaker 1: There was a lot of crap but for people who were dedicated to the shows They were making they put in like.
Speaker 1: there was this attention to detail that was unsurpassed and there are so many Tiny little throwaway jokes that are animated in the background of this show Like the guy with the chainsaw doing something silly or a guy just making dumb faces at someone when he turns his back.
Speaker 0: It's not just the cell versus digital that causes stuff like that.
Speaker 0: It's the fact that all of the the grunt work is outsourced.
Speaker 0: now that is a major contributor to the lot You didn't let me finish.
Speaker 1: What I was saying is that in a lot of newer anime at least a lot of the bad worst anime because you know You can do all this stuff with digital animation the same way you can do with cells.
Speaker 1: But a lot of anime kind of cop out and they just they do the scene to make it work Rather than putting that extra little bit to do something funny in the background that most people won't even notice.
Speaker 1: And I think it's really just a matter of the culture of making the shows and the money in the industry and everything because it's the Same as CDs.
Speaker 1: people are nostalgic for records because a lot of records had much greater dynamic contrast and that sort of thing and they felt like there was more attention put into the mastering.
Speaker 1: and While it's true that there probably was more attention put into the mastering a CD has so much more potential to be good than a record and so much more room to make an awesome work.
Speaker 1: But most people who put stuff on CDs nowadays are lazy and just normalize the hell out of their music and clip it and just Get it on there as loud as possible.
Speaker 1: They could make music that was just as dynamically awesome as a record on a CD.
Speaker 1: They just don't.
Speaker 1: so as a result, there's this conflation between kind of good stuff and vinyl Mmm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I think it's the same thing with sound animation.
Speaker 0: Well, I think what it is is it's not.
Speaker 0: you know The it's not just.
Speaker 0: we're.
Speaker 0: look we see from our end being consumers of the entertainment, right?
Speaker 0: We're looking at the change in the you know, the the delivery medium.
Speaker 0: right you're talking about CDs and records, right?
Speaker 0: But really what it is is a change in the tools of production, right?
Speaker 0: I mean someone's sitting there drawing things by hand, you know to doodle in a little funny thing in the back.
Speaker 0: You know you think about.
Speaker 0: you know Physicality of that, you know doodling something in the corner right now think about someone sitting at a computer Even if they've got like a Wacom or something, you know It's like to doodle something in the in the background of like a scene is a completely different thing when you're doing it digitally.
Speaker 1: You know and it's not well, it's got doodling something in the background of a scene with cells forever You've got to put it in the keyframes then you got to get it to the in-betweens and that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: It's not quite so simple I don't know.
Speaker 0: I didn't say I didn't say it's simple.
Speaker 0: But you think about the physicality of doodling in the corner versus the physicality.
Speaker 0: You know doing it on the computer, right?
Speaker 0: And that's that's the reason that something like that would happen, you know with one.
Speaker 0: That
Speaker 1: stuff does happen with great anime that's made now with the modern tools and I think what it really comes down to is the filter of quality and Shows like Tyler are just so high quality you know, I get a lot of flack for people saying that I only like the old anime and that's not true.
Speaker 1: Mitch stone hotchine and Forgot the name of that other show that I like.
Speaker 0: You keep saying it's so great.
Speaker 1: I saw three episodes and it's fantastic and I really want to watch the rest of it.
Speaker 1: I just have to get it all and watch it.
Speaker 1: But I'm watching Tyler right now, but you know watching a show like Ava or eska flown a or Tyler again now They're just so.
Speaker 1: I don't know transcendent of all the other stuff that was coming out even at the time That they hold up today more so than a lot of stuff coming out now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean this, you know, even stuff that comes out now that I watch, you know What is still gonna hold up, you know?
Speaker 0: I mean look Galaxy Express is watch the show from like the late 70s.
Speaker 0: What show from now is still gonna be good in 30 years?
Speaker 1: I think Baccano will hold up.
Speaker 0: Hey, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Baccano has such just a fun style to it and it's different.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I like it You know what?
Speaker 0: I've watched maybe five or six episodes and I'll finish it, you know in some time five years from now We'll be doing the show and it's gotta be like man.
Speaker 1: So I just watched Baccano.
Speaker 0: That show was awesome Yeah, but I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't feel like Baccano will hold up over a long period of time.
Speaker 0: I Can't see myself like, you know watching it again after I finish it.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: Are you kidding that that is definitely a rewashable show just for it's got a lot of those kind of just epic scenes?
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, you're about everything.
Speaker 1: No except a couple of comics, I guess.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I've got to make this thing that I forgot to say at the beginning of the show We've I'm redoing the website, but I'm not redoing it in any way that you're gonna notice Most likely right?
Speaker 0: Um, basically it's gonna be 2.0 of the site that's already there.
Speaker 0: So it's gonna look 99% the same right?
Speaker 0: I'm just basically, you know polishing it and doing all kinds of stuff and I've already made a humongous progress in.
Speaker 0: But it's not, you know, it's not live yet.
Speaker 0: It's on my laptop, you know, and once it's all ready I'm gonna put it out there and we're gonna add a bunch of nice features for you.
Speaker 0: Like automatically, you know posting episodes to Twitter and Automatically, you know linking the forum and the website, you know an interesting way And you know when Google Wave is out, we're gonna integrate Google Wave in some nice ways, whatever.
Speaker 0: But one thing that I decided to do is we have these ads in the forum.
Speaker 0: You may have noticed them, right?
Speaker 0: We don't really make money off them.
Speaker 1: You couldn't wait till the end of the show for this.
Speaker 0: Well, no, because I wanted to you know, I figure people would start, you know The I forgot to do at the beginning of the show and I figured doing it in the middle of the show Right.
Speaker 0: people would be like, ah and you know They wouldn't like turn off the the episode when I started talking about it because we're still gonna talk about more awesome stuff after this.
Speaker 1: Actually, we're going on pretty long.
Speaker 1: I don't think we will.
Speaker 0: No, you don't think we will.
Speaker 0: now Bob I got stuff to talk about.
Speaker 1: Anyway, cuz I want to go to.
Speaker 1: I got to go to work soon.
Speaker 0: Oh shits All right, well actually leaves us with more materials for the future, which is good.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the long and short of it is that we haven't made that much money off ads and that's fine Cuz we didn't really expect you anyway, but where you can use that money instead to buy ads.
Speaker 0: You know, we said we would never have advertising in geek nights the show.
Speaker 0: that is true That's true.
Speaker 0: That'll never happen.
Speaker 0: nor will there be advertising on for a crew.
Speaker 0: calm But there may be advertising in other things that we may make, you know, but anyway You know, we never said he wouldn't buy ads that say hey listen to geek nights, right and I want it.
Speaker 0: You know mostly I'm not really.
Speaker 0: you know, it would be a nice bonus if they worked and got us a bunch of listeners.
Speaker 0: But mostly I'm just want to see.
Speaker 0: you know I want to experience buying ads something that I have not done.
Speaker 0: I want to see how the whole thing works and you know learn about it and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: So the thing is to buy ads.
Speaker 0: we need ads, right?
Speaker 0: We mean I could do a text ad if I wanted to but we know we need images arts to you know That are the correct shape and size to purchase, you know in place on other sites.
Speaker 0: So I made a little contest.
Speaker 0: It's in the forum.
Speaker 0: It's also on the website to you know, basically You make ads and we'll pick some out that we think are the winners and then there will be a prize.
Speaker 0: and the thing is I actually have a prize.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: This isn't where you know, the classic rim.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll give some sort of prize for that.
Speaker 1: He's got.
Speaker 1: we have a prize and not really.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll think of something.
Speaker 1: We actually there is a prize.
Speaker 0: there is a prize.
Speaker 1: What do you see?
Speaker 1: It is there it is a real prize.
Speaker 0: now this is a little story right?
Speaker 0: is?
Speaker 0: The Akira manga right has been out in English for a while now But you know it came out while I was in college and I bought all six volumes in Dark Horse.
Speaker 0: They're very expensive six gigantic volumes.
Speaker 0: they're exactly the same as the Japanese volumes except they're flipped over from.
Speaker 0: you know, so they're you know, English direction left to right and They're translated.
Speaker 0: obviously The thing about these volumes that they've been out of print and not so easy to get and not cheap to get either.
Speaker 0: Now you might be wondering Scott.
Speaker 0: You're gonna give those volumes away.
Speaker 0: Holy shit Akira's like, you know, this is the most amazing manga, you know, one of your favorites.
Speaker 0: you gonna give it away?
Speaker 0: Well, not exactly.
Speaker 0: you see Kodansha see Dark Horse lost the license for a cure.
Speaker 0: They also lost the license for Ghost in the Shell.
Speaker 0: I guess I don't know why but they're I guess they it expired.
Speaker 0: So Kodansha the actual Japanese publisher of these things is going to directly publish them in the United States.
Speaker 0: so in two months for now or I assume the.
Speaker 0: You know cuz I'm ordering it this month the first volume of the Akira manga is coming out in the u.s From Kodansha.
Speaker 0: now, I don't know if it's printed from right to left, but I have to assume it's gonna be the same size.
Speaker 0: I mean the.
Speaker 0: the image they showed of it is the same exact cover image.
Speaker 0: So, you know I have to without this information about if it's gonna be flipped or if it has a different translation or whatever.
Speaker 0: I gotta buy it to compare and contrast it with what I got right, you know, I can't just let it go like that.
Speaker 0: so the result is that I'm gonna have two sets of the Akira manga the Kodansha and the Dark Horse.
Speaker 0: and You know, I don't imagine that either one of them will be bad, but I'm going to.
Speaker 0: probably once I have both sets I won't need both of them.
Speaker 0: I'll pick whichever one I like better and the other one will be the prize.
Speaker 0: So you will get the entire set of Akira manga either Dark Horse or Kodansha editions It's up to me, which is you know manufacturers retail price of at least like $180 worth of comics.
Speaker 0: It's six gigantic volumes.
Speaker 0: So if you make us awesome ads that are worthy of us putting them on other websites and paying money for that Then you can win all of Akira the manga, which is totally awesome.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Yes So make us ads and post them in the forum or email them to us or I point out that while we won't use them I would very much appreciate ironic entries in addition to real entries.
Speaker 0: Yes Humor will be rewarded with golf claps.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is if someone submits and a biting enough ironic ad I could see us using that There also I posted some details in the forum of this contest.
Speaker 0: obviously, I don't know contest laws, I don't have a lawyer I'm probably breaking laws in every state, but whatever.
Speaker 0: and also You know the shapes and sizes of the ads are posted in the forum.
Speaker 0: and also By submitting an ad to the contest you all you automatically release it into the Creative Commons license Which means we could use it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, even if you don't win Creative Commons attribution, that's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's it.
Speaker 0: Do you get credit for it?
Speaker 1: No matter what one version of the Creative Commons?
Speaker 0: Well, I think we're on 3.0 now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever newest Creative Commons attribution license, you know, you don't really have a choice.
Speaker 0: So and that's that's all we're gonna say about that.
Speaker 1: All right, but you know stuff we're watching.
Speaker 1: I'm watching irresponsible captain Tyler again.
Speaker 1: It's the fucking business.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I can't express to you how great it is.
Speaker 1: I'm finally watching Gurren Lagann, which is also pretty damn great.
Speaker 1: However, I know the show takes it like the show is okay and then hits a point where suddenly it's great.
Speaker 1: I do not believe I've hit that point yet and I'll tell you this Gurren Lagann fans If I have already hit that point and I don't think I have fuck that show.
Speaker 1: But if the point is not yet come then that show might still be one of the better anime to come out ever.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh it.
Speaker 1: the show has so much style going for it that that can make up for almost any problem that might occur.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Should I talk about something else?
Speaker 0: Actually, I do want to talk about one more thing.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm also reading Steppenwolf.
Speaker 0: Well, that's a.
Speaker 1: that's a book that's not Anime that we're supposed to do a book club episode on someone else reads.
Speaker 0: You know what I'm doing.
Speaker 0: I'm fixing the website.
Speaker 0: Well, how was your e-commerce coming along over there?
Speaker 1: What I'm doing instead of the e-commerce?
Speaker 1: Watching anime and reading Steppenwolf.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay, so and working nights I have to get ready for work in like an hour.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah working nights for one week.
Speaker 0: How long has it been since the e-commerce is supposed to be ready?
Speaker 0: like months and months is April.
Speaker 1: I've been busy.
Speaker 1: I basically haven't been working on it.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So yeah, you act like you don't believe me.
Speaker 1: No, I really haven't been working on it.
Speaker 0: Who's doing work and who's watching animes?
Speaker 1: I believe if Scott Johnson pointed out in the forums because one of us has stuff to do outside I do stuff.
Speaker 0: What do I have?
Speaker 0: we both do the same amount of stuff?
Speaker 1: I think I do more.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Okay anyway, so Actually, you know vertigo comics, right?
Speaker 0: You know, they it's vertigo is DC if you don't realize this but you know They do the fables and the wide last man and you know the Sandman and all that stuff, right?
Speaker 0: They're basically the way they sell comics.
Speaker 0: is they put out issues and they put out trades But the trades are always cheap and the first issue is always cheap Like the first issue of any vertigo series would be like a dollar and the first trade will always be like five dollars or seven Dollars.
Speaker 0: we could cheap.
Speaker 0: so they get you hooked and then you'll buy the rest of the trades at you know Regular prices.
Speaker 0: now the thing is, you know a new.
Speaker 0: whenever new vertigo series comes along I always get the first issue for like 25 cents cuz.
Speaker 0: why the hell not, you know I'll go see what it's about.
Speaker 0: and I read two new vertigo series recently.
Speaker 0: the first issues.
Speaker 0: one of them was Greek Street.
Speaker 0: This was just terrible.
Speaker 0: I don't know why anyone would like this.
Speaker 0: It was basically the first story was about a guy who accidentally has sex with his mom And then there was a sorry edifice and then there was a story about some strippers.
Speaker 0: Just I don't know what the hell was going on.
Speaker 1: Are you sure that these aren't all modern retellings of old Greek tragedies?
Speaker 1: It's possible that that sounds like that's what that's doing.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 1: You probably just don't know.
Speaker 0: Probably from something maybe but it was bad like it wasn't entertaining in and of itself.
Speaker 0: and the third one then it was like some story with like some mafia dudes and I couldn't.
Speaker 0: it was just complete trash and I was not interested.
Speaker 0: but The the other series I read unwritten, right?
Speaker 0: Unwritten.
Speaker 0: it was a really weird experience reading this thing because it was simultaneously so Cliche, but at the same time it was so unique and amazing, right?
Speaker 0: It's like it starts off.
Speaker 0: you have this like guy at a convention and he's doing all like these autographs for people and he's famous And you slowly learn that what he's famous for is basically that his dad who's the lady who wrote Harry Potter.
Speaker 0: What's her name?
Speaker 1: I don't even know her name.
Speaker 0: I forgot her name.
Speaker 0: I could if you told it to me I'd be like that's the name but I can't come up with it right now.
Speaker 0: But anyway, this dude's dad is the Harry Potter author, right?
Speaker 0: But his dad basically abandoned him and disappeared, right?
Speaker 0: He is right, but the Harry Potter character was supposedly modeled after him.
Speaker 0: So as far as you know, people are concerned this guy, even though he's sort of like a grown-up 20-30 something year old dude.
Speaker 0: He is the Harry Potter of this universe, right?
Speaker 0: Even though they don't use the words Harry Potter It's Harry Potter, right?
Speaker 0: It's obvious They're.
Speaker 0: it's intentionally right referenced and such.
Speaker 0: now The thing is right.
Speaker 0: you're like, okay What kind of story is there to tell about this guy whose dad is the famous author who sold the most popular book?
Speaker 1: Well missing dad is the premise of every Final Fantasy legend.
Speaker 0: Now you're getting close to it.
Speaker 0: basically, he's at the.
Speaker 0: he's at.
Speaker 0: he's on a panel at a convention right where all these fans are and One person stands up and is like, hey your birth certificate something something conspiracy, you know, who are you?
Speaker 0: You're not you know, actually the son of the author something something.
Speaker 0: and then you know his agents like got to go to today, right and You find out that no He's probably not the son of this guy and his weird shit going on.
Speaker 0: and you know What the wizard Harry Potter shit might be real.
Speaker 0: and it's it gets.
Speaker 0: it gets sort of crazy fucked up And there's only in the first issue, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like 20 30 something pages.
Speaker 0: This isn't even the first trade paperback.
Speaker 0: and I was like, whoa, what the hell is going on here?
Speaker 0: What is this?
Speaker 0: So even though I'm like, you know, not a not interested in Harry Potter at all, right this Unwritten from vertigo is looking pretty interesting.
Speaker 0: I'm going to be getting some first trade paperback action, which is why it's very awesome that they have one dollar issue number ones.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, yep, so one other thing before it and this so I can you know go to work.
Speaker 1: now I've got the box set and after I finish captain Tyler, I think I'm finally gonna sit down and watch it.
Speaker 1: Well, I am also, you know watching Legend of the Galactic Heroes.
Speaker 0: Good God.
Speaker 1: That show is pretty great.
Speaker 0: How many episodes is that?
Speaker 1: Infinity.
Speaker 1: it's like a hundred hits a lot.
Speaker 1: I don't even have all of it.
Speaker 1: I only have like the first ten.
Speaker 1: I'll have to get the rest somewhere.
Speaker 1: but Nadesha co is like the one Show from the era that it came out that I did not watch, you know, I started, you know back a while I saw like the first D evil the first VHS worth of it dubbed.
Speaker 1: I never saw any more.
Speaker 0: Yeah I converted it all to iPod for iPhone format and I started watching it.
Speaker 0: and I just I just never like.
Speaker 0: I watched a few episodes and I was like And I just stopped side, you know It didn't it didn't grab me.
Speaker 1: and like the first four or five I'm going to watch solely because it was fairly enduringly popular from the time.
Speaker 1: so there's got to be something to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean even for Shiggy Yugi was very popular when it came out and while it faded I can see why it was worth watching The first season of that.
Speaker 1: so I got to see what the deal is.
Speaker 0: I also will eventually see what the deal is.
Speaker 1: The thing is if it.
Speaker 1: if it is what I think it is Gurren Lagann just did it better.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't like I died.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen either of the two.
Speaker 0: So how would I even know if they were you really gonna watch?
Speaker 1: I mean, this is a show that has the.
Speaker 1: if you ever hear people quoting the line Don't believe in yourself believe in the me that believes in you.
Speaker 1: Yeah Stuff like that is from Gurren Lagann.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that doesn't excite me.
Speaker 1: How can that not excite you?
Speaker 0: because every time someone says that it's just.
Speaker 0: it's just like what the fuck is wrong with you.
Speaker 1: What are you talking about?
Speaker 1: That's that is perhaps the most inspirational thing you can say to anyone ever.
Speaker 0: It's just really corny.
Speaker 1: If you ask me, it's supposed the whole show is corny.
Speaker 1: It's epically corny.
Speaker 0: It's corny.
Speaker 0: So you like that.
Speaker 1: if you don't like Stan Lee cuz it's corny in the read or die way Uh-huh, or in the giant orobo way.
Speaker 1: if they don't and characters don't say what they're doing as they do it.
Speaker 1: Well, they kind of do.
Speaker 0: Well, it's okay if it's rocket punch.
Speaker 0: if someone else at the narrator says rocket punch You know if or if you say rocket punch like after it hits like fuck Got you in the face you piece of shit, right?
Speaker 1: What if you're in the robot?
Speaker 1: you'll rock it's a pod and then the rocket punch comes out.
Speaker 0: That's not as good All right.
Speaker 1: At any rate the show is kind of rambling.
Speaker 1: I'm tired.
Speaker 1: I gotta go to work.
Speaker 0: How'd it go to bed?
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front road crew comm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.