Speaker 0: Hey, it's Tuesday September 1st.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight the last geek nights before packs 2009 in Seattle.
Speaker 1: fuck yeah Let's do this.
Speaker 0: It's coming.
Speaker 1: What's coming?
Speaker 0: something's coming?
Speaker 1: Is it Godzilla?
Speaker 1: Oh?
Speaker 0: Maybe Washington, Washington.
Speaker 0: It's packs.
Speaker 0: packs is coming all week.
Speaker 0: I'm just not doing anything to work.
Speaker 0: I'm just thinking about packs.
Speaker 1: It's so weird like other conventions.
Speaker 1: It's like you know a kind of excited about him leading up to it.
Speaker 1: It's like packs.
Speaker 1: I've been like yeah, fuck their packs is coming like weeks ago, and I think it's a different.
Speaker 0: like two three days.
Speaker 0: I'm excited about packs the way I used to be excited about things like Otakon you know in the early days of cons when Like every like being an attendee and nothing more was just crazy and amazing and like walk into a dealer's room and oh my god There's 26,000 nerds, but you know anime cons for us are about 75% work.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 1: Well packs is work too, but you know what packs is just so great.
Speaker 1: I would the greatest of the greats.
Speaker 0: One of the only regrets and now we have two in my entire life Is that I did not go to a pack sooner?
Speaker 1: I would have had to suffer to go to those packs as we we considered it is when they announced that first packs We're like let's go no matter what.
Speaker 1: but we didn't yeah because we didn't have enough money, and then the next year We're like let's go no matter what and eventually we went no matter what.
Speaker 1: last year far too late.
Speaker 1: We should have gone no matter what much much earlier.
Speaker 0: It's very few things.
Speaker 1: how things have turned out then.
Speaker 1: Otakon might be mailing badges already.
Speaker 0: Yep Just imagine going to that early packs is only what like 3,000 feet.
Speaker 1: yeah the early packs is.
Speaker 1: people don't realize We're not that large, but this packs Sold the fuck out.
Speaker 1: Zero back no badges for sale at the door game over.
Speaker 1: You're either going or you're not.
Speaker 1: if you're not going you suck.
Speaker 0: you do need those stinking badges.
Speaker 0: of course you know I'm not to make fun of people but If you don't know Jared emailed us today, and he's like yeah, I forgot to pre-reg.
Speaker 0: he sucks.
Speaker 1: I mean if you edge if you wanted to go you're planning on going and now you're not going because you don't have a badge You suck.
Speaker 0: In
Speaker 1: a situation like you live in the middle of Kansas, and you wanted to go if you have no money well You know that you don't suck, but if you wanted to go and the only reason you're not going is cuz you waited too long To pre-reg hope you learn your lesson.
Speaker 1: What do you edge the day the badges go on sale.
Speaker 1: do not hesitate?
Speaker 1: Well unless you're like us we will save money And you won't be a chump like how many people go.
Speaker 1: look on Twitter see how many chumps there are.
Speaker 1: go to the packs forums For like Want badges.
Speaker 0: then there are badges.
Speaker 0: They're going to be jumps no matter what.
Speaker 0: people could have all registered on day one and then hour to day one It'd be the same number of jumps.
Speaker 1: That's right You got it.
Speaker 1: if you don't want to be a chump if someone told me that they were there as soon as the announcement was made Constantly refreshing the page and trying to buy a badge immediately And they sold out and they weren't able to get one then they are not a chump.
Speaker 0: the thing is it's funny How it.
Speaker 0: other cons like on the artist alley registration is like that.
Speaker 0: there are people who refresh that thing Register within like a minute, and you know what it's like.
Speaker 1: It's like back in the day.
Speaker 1: try two things I can.
Speaker 1: I can equate it to number one registering for classes at RIT.
Speaker 0: When you're a measly freshman, you know I never had to go through that.
Speaker 0: That's one of the few other than my first.
Speaker 0: I only had to do it like a couple times at RIT when I didn't know better.
Speaker 0: Remember I I was.
Speaker 0: I was like uh-huh.
Speaker 1: anyway the number two thing I can relate it to.
Speaker 1: the number two thing is Trying to get the newest version to counter-strike the day it comes out.
Speaker 0: You know what.
Speaker 0: I never had to deal with that either.
Speaker 0: You just waited till the next day because you would always get it And then I would just take it off like your windows share.
Speaker 1: I don't remember ever giving it to you, and I didn't have a windows share.
Speaker 0: I would get it from you.
Speaker 0: I don't usually because you'd be like hey you want to play counter-strike, and I'd be like I didn't download the patch.
Speaker 0: yet.
Speaker 1: I don't remember ever giving you a counter-strike.
Speaker 1: I remember everyone waiting in line, okay?
Speaker 1: I think in random mirrors until it worked.
Speaker 0: I usually wait until someone else got it then just so people.
Speaker 1: people don't appreciate how great steam is just automatically updating your shit.
Speaker 1: You know with no bullshit.
Speaker 1: You don't remember the days of counter-strike updates like you know trying to get beta 9 and when beta 8 was your current version.
Speaker 1: You know what.
Speaker 0: that wasn't the problem.
Speaker 0: that wasn't the part that bothered me because like I said I never waited those stupid lines.
Speaker 0: I just waited for some other chump to get it for me.
Speaker 1: I didn't you wasn't me Greg.
Speaker 0: I always got someone to do it anyway.
Speaker 0: But the plus RIT you could get it off a direct connect.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like within an hour not freshman year directing.
Speaker 1: that came later.
Speaker 1: The problem was by that time steam was out.
Speaker 0: the problem was that RIT that once they release an update like half the servers be running different versions and half the servers wouldn't work in the server side would be A mess for like a week after the update.
Speaker 1: that was true.
Speaker 0: Everyone would jump on to like the three servers that I had At the right very but at the same time as it moved you'd see the servers that didn't move getting more and more full as People who didn't have the update yet had to move to them.
Speaker 1: Yeah As they had to play while they're waiting the update to download plus half the servers.
Speaker 0: then like the admin mods wouldn't work anymore And you couldn't kick people.
Speaker 0: you'd have admins like breaking into patches.
Speaker 0: It was it was crazy.
Speaker 1: Alright, so check out some video game news.
Speaker 0: you ready for this, and I'm ready alright.
Speaker 1: So rim when you go to the arcade right and you're playing the what there's no such thing as arcades.
Speaker 1: when you go to fun Spot or the the you mean when I go to a video or you go to video topia.
Speaker 1: Yes, it is video.
Speaker 1: topia by the way is in the Rochester strong music?
Speaker 1: I think is it the strong museum of fun?
Speaker 0: so like I was about to say if I go to a museum Fun spots not a museum anyway effectively it is anyway.
Speaker 1: if you go to an arcade with the old-school games What are your old-school games that you play?
Speaker 1: I?
Speaker 0: Don't know all of them.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: No like the games that are rims games like root beer tappers.
Speaker 1: And you know cinestar is not your game.
Speaker 0: I like cinestar.
Speaker 1: You know, but it's not your game root beer.
Speaker 1: I think your games are root beer tapper.
Speaker 0: Here's the difference.
Speaker 0: Do you mean my game as in the games that I was transcendently good at?
Speaker 0: yeah somehow?
Speaker 1: Yes, root beer tapper root beer tapper miss pac-man.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much it right.
Speaker 0: well ramparts later.
Speaker 0: I don't even consider that old-school.
Speaker 1: I consider rampart old-school.
Speaker 0: I don't know what to consider it.
Speaker 0: It's so middle school Horton to my life.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so what are my games?
Speaker 0: Uh, what are your games?
Speaker 1: mega man to Arcade games of the old-school flavor.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I consider my game to be Galaga even though I'm not a master of Scott likes.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, so there's that the new champion of Galaga.
Speaker 1: That's correct Yeah.
Speaker 1: So previously the champion of Galaga was Andrew Laidlaw from the United States with 2.7 million points.
Speaker 1: Some dude in Australia named Phil day has three point forty four million points Holy craps, and basically all he did.
Speaker 1: he's been playing it since he was seven years old.
Speaker 1: He had a machine He trained like intensely for six months out in the you know who knows middle of nowhere and the outback right and then He put up the video camera because people don't know right.
Speaker 1: Twin galaxies is the like official video game high score keeping organization And you can either register your high score in the presence of a twin galaxies referee or You can do it via video tape where you basically videotape your machine to prove that it's the real deal.
Speaker 1: Then videotape your entire play session and you know the whole and then mail your videotape to twin galaxies for them to verify that You didn't like photoshop it and such and so he chose the videotape method and he did it like just all on his own and his house with his machine and You know.
Speaker 0: basically I wonder how many attempts that took.
Speaker 0: like you wonder you know eight hours into his fourth session Fuck the.
Speaker 1: the interesting thing that they said about it was that you know when he crossed the high score point He just kept going and he was just sort of in a daze and he was real exhausted so that you didn't have he didn't Like celebrate or go like yeah when he passed the point He just kept going until he died and then he was like who?
Speaker 1: I haven't seen the video though But that's what they.
Speaker 0: that's what there's something about that zone and every gamer has it.
Speaker 0: I mean even playing DDR.
Speaker 0: You know you'll be playing and you get to a point to where you realize that you're not even looking at the arrows.
Speaker 0: your feet Are just kind of moving yep, and you're getting them all.
Speaker 1: one thing that really interested me though is like you know You know what a Galaga machine looks like.
Speaker 1: right apparently if you want to register a high score for Galaga You can only do it on an unaltered 1981 Japanese Galaga machine.
Speaker 1: with this you can't like if you use like you know the new Galaga pack miss pac-man combo machine.
Speaker 1: that don't.
Speaker 0: Why is there that different?
Speaker 1: that's what they said.
Speaker 1: you have to play it on the original Japanese 1981 Galaga tournament machine.
Speaker 1: that's the only machine.
Speaker 1: you get the high score this.
Speaker 0: so this raises some very important questions.
Speaker 0: For example it raises the.
Speaker 1: I've never played I've never even I saw a picture of that machine online today, and I'm like.
Speaker 1: I've never seen a Galaga like that before.
Speaker 1: That's the original Galaga.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem.
Speaker 0: this raises the ship of Theseus question How what percentage of the components can I have replaced over the years as they broke to have it still count as an original Machine?
Speaker 1: I think it just has to be.
Speaker 1: you know the the exact same.
Speaker 1: You know I'm sure if you like Manufactured the exact same thing with the exact same code with the exact same parts even if it wasn't all original parts You know they would be okay.
Speaker 0: that might be unfair though because you have an advantage of all new workings all new perfect controller.
Speaker 1: But I mean you know they just have to be the same exact.
Speaker 1: It would be the same as if you had scored the high score in 1981, and what's the difference.
Speaker 1: that's legitimate?
Speaker 1: You know when all the parts of the machines were brand.
Speaker 0: but at the same time that limits the scope of people have access to The best technology and it over time it'll be harder and harder to get these machines.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know it is.
Speaker 1: it is a question.
Speaker 1: I thought it was interesting and the question is are some of the questions that I was also raised?
Speaker 1: I'm also very supposed to score a high scoring Galaga.
Speaker 1: I've never even fucking seen that machine.
Speaker 1: I'm also only ever seen normal.
Speaker 0: I'm also curious as to why I mean it sounds like this is just I'm gonna go straight up petty fanboy rules, and I think partially.
Speaker 1: But also I do know for a fact that some other Galaga machines especially newer ones have various like difficulty setting switches And there's like some Galaga's let you shoot two bullets at a time and some let you shoot like infinity bullets as fast as you Can push the button and some let you know.
Speaker 1: so there's many different settings plus Hardware.
Speaker 0: hack my original machine.
Speaker 1: They would then you wouldn't be valid because they yet to when you see if you send in your videotape.
Speaker 1: Yet to video the like the whole machine so they can see it and inspect it And then they know what it's supposed to be all right.
Speaker 1: And if you have a referee the referee inspects the machine And they know what the fuck's going on.
Speaker 0: so if I don't have a referee when does the video start?
Speaker 0: when I start playing it?
Speaker 0: Shows me and the machine and my screen.
Speaker 1: you have to.
Speaker 1: if you if they're not satisfied with your videotape They just reject it and don't count your score, so it's completely up to twin galaxies whether your video counts or not.
Speaker 0: Yeah so I'm curious.
Speaker 0: I I think it would be fairly easy to hack the machine with a couple of Subtle bits here and there that wouldn't be noticed by someone watching or eight-hour video you are.
Speaker 1: But I mean if they're they're they're real experts And they're examining every detail like if they notice like your ship like skip to the left ones You know which you know or something like that to be like.
Speaker 1: hey he died and then re-edited the video.
Speaker 1: That's bullshit and fail.
Speaker 0: while that is true I Very much doubt the competence of humans to detect very subtle changes in a long and tedious Video of someone playing an arcade game.
Speaker 1: I agree, but they they they're the experts on it I don't.
Speaker 1: I'd be very interested to hear what their actual method for you know verifying videos submissions is but you know I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm just.
Speaker 0: I'm less and less impressed with these sort of things as time goes on especially after having watched the King of Kong.
Speaker 1: yeah, I didn't watch the King of Kong.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wouldn't.
Speaker 0: it wasn't that good.
Speaker 1: I'll be honest I thought it was just about like some jerks playing Donkey Kong.
Speaker 0: it basically was.
Speaker 0: it was kind of tedious And it just.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: the games like this where the difficulty does not necessarily Grow beyond a certain point But at the same like a good example is WarioWare the difficulty keeps going up until it's effectively impossible So that it's going to eliminate people fairly quickly.
Speaker 0: these old-school arcade games if you're the expert at it.
Speaker 0: You're the world champion.
Speaker 0: It's just a test of endurance.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's pretty much what it is especially these sorts of high score games.
Speaker 1: It's endurance.
Speaker 1: a game like Pitfall though is I think is the much more interesting game for the high score because it's not about right.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of guys out there who can get perfect scores on Atari Pitfall on the 2600 But they're basically racing for the best possible time, and it's like some guys go left some guys go right some guys get.
Speaker 1: you know It's it's totally.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: they mix it up all the time And it's like you know.
Speaker 1: there's actual competition there.
Speaker 0: well to a degree that remember that is still just a memorization game.
Speaker 1: Endurance.
Speaker 1: it's perfect.
Speaker 1: It's about perfection.
Speaker 0: It is well.
Speaker 0: It's a performance art kind of like those Mario 1 racing guys exactly.
Speaker 1: Oh my god High score is a lot better than the you know say the pac-man's.
Speaker 0: what about doggy car?
Speaker 0: what about super pitfall?
Speaker 1: Super pitfall just sucks All right, what's your news there?
Speaker 1: So you a punk kid who wants to make games and you're probably in college or don't otherwise have a job Don't do what I did and spend your college doing nothing and then regret later not making something while you're in college.
Speaker 0: You mustn't kill time boys.
Speaker 0: He was cherished.
Speaker 1: Yeah Be like.
Speaker 1: you know all those other guys who made some awesome Software while they were in college and then didn't have to get jobs when they got out because their software was their job.
Speaker 0: It's it feels almost very old to be saying this but looking back at college.
Speaker 0: I wasted 99% of the time I had in college.
Speaker 0: now at the same time It's tricky because I enjoyed that wasting.
Speaker 0: and could I have been the person I am today had I not wasted all that time Playing counter-strike and taking around.
Speaker 1: the thing is I would have be happier now if I had done something differently But I would not have been happier then if I had done something differently.
Speaker 1: So it's just you know, it's it evens out.
Speaker 0: Yes, because remember had we done something in college We would not have had quote those days Exactly.
Speaker 0: So kids either do something or cherish those days and by those days I mean days where you're in college in your little dorm or apartment and You don't have any homework to do and you don't have any classes to go to and you don't have a job yet And you have like three days of nothing.
Speaker 0: Those are the best days you will ever have and the weather's nice and the weather's not.
Speaker 1: Or college guys if you're a girl Or if you're you know, if you swing that way, you know, whatever doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo.
Speaker 1: Let's continue.
Speaker 0: So if you don't want to have those days and you want to do something You can win.
Speaker 0: actually the company Emily and Alex work for muse games is doing a $10,000 contest and all you have to do a lot of monies.
Speaker 0: all you have to do is make a Prototype of the game you want to make with the unity engine which is this 3d browser based platform.
Speaker 0: That's actually Surprisingly slick.
Speaker 1: So you how do you how do you enter this contest?
Speaker 0: Well, we're gonna link to it.
Speaker 0: basically check out this link and you'll see all the rules.
Speaker 0: But you have to make a very simple prototype of your game and tell them you know This is what I want the game to be.
Speaker 0: Here's the working super simple basic prototype and they're gonna go through all these rounds and everything and eventually they're gonna pick a winner.
Speaker 0: The winner gets 10 grand and help from them to make the game and then they'll help you publish it straight up Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So if you're in college and you want to make games This is pretty much what you should be doing 10 grand in college.
Speaker 0: That would have changed my entire life.
Speaker 1: and you know what if you make a game and it doesn't win?
Speaker 1: I know that the unity engine allows you to make iPhone things.
Speaker 1: So if you're gave you spend time making a game and it doesn't win Turn it into an iPhone game and you'll make some bank.
Speaker 1: I guarantee it.
Speaker 0: now remember I mean think about this.
Speaker 0: What do we always see?
Speaker 0: you're not wasting your time, especially on the Monday shows?
Speaker 0: You can't learn something by trying to learn it.
Speaker 0: You can only learn something by doing it.
Speaker 0: So if you think you want to be a game programmer, you're thinking I should learn game programming.
Speaker 0: No, just do it.
Speaker 0: Just enter this contest.
Speaker 1: exactly Like if you want to learn how to like use a table saw You can't be like I want to learn how to use a table saw.
Speaker 1: just get some wood.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you have to be like I want to make a birdhouse or I want to make a cabinet and then in the course of Making cabinet you're gonna need that table saw and once you need the table saw You're gonna use it and learn how to use it.
Speaker 0: aside if you're using a bandsaw Don't think that you can sand wood with the flat side of the blade.
Speaker 1: Yeah That'll.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna point that out because I've seen people do this and I've seen fingers get cut the fuck off.
Speaker 1: Always use proper safety.
Speaker 0: when in a wood or metal shop any sort of workshop scenario also a game shop I did not actually see the finger get cut off.
Speaker 1: make and remember.
Speaker 0: I heard ah And it's funny and there was a finger cut.
Speaker 1: funny as it is in that kind of situation.
Speaker 1: The goggles do not do nothing.
Speaker 1: You need the goggles Okay, but you can.
Speaker 1: they will stop the flying splinter of wood from stabbing you in the eye.
Speaker 0: submissions go until October 15.
Speaker 1: that's a lot of time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's only.
Speaker 1: it's a beginning of September.
Speaker 1: That's like a whole month Man, if you got a whole month and you're a college kid and all you need to do is make a prototype of a game You know I think back to college you crank that shit out.
Speaker 1: a month was Especially with like an easy engine that helps you out.
Speaker 0: a month was effectively forever Like I think back and the time between like April and May was infinity time.
Speaker 0: That was the entire life I.
Speaker 1: now months are like yet.
Speaker 1: Just another rent.
Speaker 1: check out the door My god all the time, but they'll announce.
Speaker 0: the winners are the winner at the unite unity conference in San Francisco at the end of October.
Speaker 1: ooh, they're gonna go to San Francisco our friends.
Speaker 0: I think so.
Speaker 1: Oh shits quote.
Speaker 0: as indie developers ourselves We strongly believe that the Indian in the Indian community.
Speaker 0: We want to reward developers for making great games.
Speaker 0: Hopefully we're gonna make this a model of successful one for the future and ultimately raise the stakes on browser-based indie development.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: We'll have a link.
Speaker 0: check it out.
Speaker 0: ten grand.
Speaker 1: I Contest be like ten grand Rupel's.
Speaker 0: So anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: I thought this was cute.
Speaker 0: I just straight-up.
Speaker 0: there's nothing else I can say.
Speaker 0: this is a Venn diagram of mystical beasts.
Speaker 0: So it's not like these human Eagle horse Narwhal dog and bull.
Speaker 0: and every intersection of all these circles is One or other various mythical beasts.
Speaker 0: for example horse and narwhal Unicorn yeah snake and eagle cockatrice lion and man trees cockatrice magic.
Speaker 1: are I like a manticore bull and mermaid?
Speaker 1: What's a bull in a room it gets up there, but I like a hippo canvas.
Speaker 0: I think my favorite part is there's dog dog and dog and in the middle of these three is Cerberus.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's about right.
Speaker 0: This thing's just cute and funny.
Speaker 0: I don't know what's like.
Speaker 1: is there human and goat?
Speaker 0: They didn't add goat because if they had added goat along with lion they could have gotten like Samara.
Speaker 1: They could have had Seder and chimera, and yeah, they didn't have any of that, but those are magical beasts.
Speaker 1: What the fuck they've got.
Speaker 0: centaur Pegasus unicorn echidna harpy manticore sound.
Speaker 1: I don't know what's up with this echidna.
Speaker 1: I thought echidna was like knuckles from Sonic the head clearly knuckles.
Speaker 1: the echidna know anything about Greek myth.
Speaker 1: It should be a Lamia.
Speaker 0: Lamia is a type of monster Action is a specific monster.
Speaker 0: Scott is very into hot Lamia action as I discovered during final Action is a huge inside joke.
Speaker 0: There's the thing about hot Lamia action.
Speaker 0: It is difficult to deny the hotness of that Lamia as we all could agree.
Speaker 1: actually that Lamia was not that hot.
Speaker 0: I don't know it for it was actually sort of a bitch Lamia.
Speaker 0: well It's really big do she wasn't that much of a bitch considering that we murdered all of her chefs and then her husband.
Speaker 1: We murdered her before we murdered her as we murdered them both at about the same time.
Speaker 0: in fact We tried to murder him first until she started healing him.
Speaker 0: we had to back up and kill her, but yeah, that's anyway poor mr.
Speaker 1: Mashant for Lamia's.
Speaker 1: okay, so what do you got for me?
Speaker 1: Oh right thing of the day, so The the old Lucasarts adventure games are getting popular again.
Speaker 1: What be it by scum VM or re-release or whatever right and I've actually noticed on the Internet's recently.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of people out there who are just making adventure games on these engines scum VM or whatever right and You know in the style of monkey island or Indiana Jones and Atlantis or whatever.
Speaker 1: they're making adventure games in these styles.
Speaker 0: That are not actually I know what you're talking about.
Speaker 0: I want to play this.
Speaker 1: so there is out there someone made another Indiana Jones adventure game.
Speaker 1: That's just another Indiana Jones adventure game But that's not what you're talking about.
Speaker 1: somebody else so is in the process of making Han Solo adventures.
Speaker 0: I watch the video.
Speaker 0: that was basically the the guy clicked on shoot first.
Speaker 0: It was.
Speaker 0: it was just so.
Speaker 1: check out this video is the thing of the day.
Speaker 1: but eventually this game will be released and playable supposedly.
Speaker 1: and Yeah, you check it out.
Speaker 0: If you're an adventure game type person so if you are going or Star Wars type person if you're going to go to PAX Which hopefully you are then you should do certain things at PAX like go to our panels.
Speaker 1: That's right, so if you're not going to PAX, and you don't have a badge already your SOL Just stay home.
Speaker 0: So on Friday in the Raven Theatre at 1130 in the morning We're doing beyond Candyland.
Speaker 0: that is the OMG German board games are the shit.
Speaker 0: you should play them panel yep on Saturday morning.
Speaker 0: We're doing on Saturday at 1030 a.m.. In the Wolfman theater.
Speaker 0: oh I wondered if you were going to make a sound effect or not We are going to be doing.
Speaker 0: losing should be fun.
Speaker 0: Which is the panel about how losing should be fun.
Speaker 1: Also, I just want to point out that packs.
Speaker 1: I don't think they like looked at their whole panel list.
Speaker 0: We already talked about this.
Speaker 1: I'll talk about it again.
Speaker 1: Just quickly.
Speaker 1: on Friday I think night someone's doing a panel winning sucks Which is basically someone who seems to at least by judging by the panel description completely agree with us.
Speaker 1: So they have basically two redundant panels, and I want to go to that other guy's panel.
Speaker 1: so we can you know heckle Yeah, you know make nice.
Speaker 0: Hopefully we agree.
Speaker 1: I mean maybe you know I'm pretty sure he's like winning sucks And he's like losing sucks even worse, and we're like losing should be fun and winning should be even more fun.
Speaker 1: No, but I think he agrees.
Speaker 1: it's someone who agrees with us, and they have the same panel twice.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, so I don't think it's a popular idea.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's the same panel twice necessarily because remember It's not like they're trying to get like.
Speaker 0: we need a panel on this and a panel on this.
Speaker 1: No, no, but I mean they didn't notice that two panels had basically the same exact.
Speaker 1: I don't area.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's a matter of not noticing at all because talking to them They seem to have vetted the panels out very well.
Speaker 0: I think it's that They picked people who they think have interesting things to say and just put them in rooms.
Speaker 0: And I think that's it.
Speaker 1: and we have the.
Speaker 1: we happen to have the same thing to say someone else.
Speaker 0: I don't think that's that far out there.
Speaker 0: I mean look Luke Crane and Jared Sorenson also have this thing to say and if they were more together They would probably have done a panel like this.
Speaker 1: And on Sunday morning if you didn't notice all our panels are basically morning panels one panel Friday morning one panel Saturday morning one panel Sunday morning at 10 a.m We are doing yet again a reprise at PAX Beyond Dungeons & Dragons last time ever at PAX West.
Speaker 0: most likely however We are going to be doing it at PAX East.
Speaker 0: we're going to be doing it possibly at the New York Comic Con.
Speaker 0: This panel will never die because people it's gonna die by 2011. see maybe what.
Speaker 0: what if PAX just keeps wanting us to do it every year?
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: I'll say no We're doing something different.
Speaker 0: I'll do it.
Speaker 1: Let's come up with something different.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll do something different and I'll do it.
Speaker 1: No, we should replace it.
Speaker 0: why if new people keep wanting to see it until we have a definitive films at least remix it With what it's perfect.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: It's we could do sudden.
Speaker 1: That's you know Crook slightly, so why?
Speaker 0: why bother?
Speaker 0: Megato Megatie until we just film it and put the definitive version online we might have to keep doing it.
Speaker 0: But Sunday 10 a.m.. In the Raven theater Beyond Dungeons & Dragons Yes beyond that don't come to see that.
Speaker 1: if you've seen it already like at the last bags.
Speaker 0: Don't do go to the keynote.
Speaker 0: do go to the ass gave and Tycho.
Speaker 0: do go to all the concerts.
Speaker 1: Do go to the tabletop gaming area on Saturday and play a game with Luke crane.
Speaker 0: go to the Tabletop gaming area on Sunday and possibly play a game with Luke crane.
Speaker 1: Oh, I forget last year right?
Speaker 1: remember There are handheld lounges where they a B and C. right.
Speaker 1: yep, right B. Handheld lounge B is awesome.
Speaker 1: a and C are for losers.
Speaker 1: So if it's a time when we're going ah look at handheld lounge B For awesome.
Speaker 1: B stands for awesome and a stand And C is for crab Handheld lounge B, and if for some reason they change in numbers and tell lounge - and if they change into colors handheld lounge green.
Speaker 0: Oh, good.
Speaker 0: God.
Speaker 0: There's a settlers of Catan tournament.
Speaker 0: That's all you.
Speaker 0: I got nothing to do with that.
Speaker 1: I can see there in a curricula tournament.
Speaker 0: There's a Robo rally tournament.
Speaker 1: I don't know how to play.
Speaker 0: Robo rally left for dead.
Speaker 0: tournament from 7 p.m.. To 1 a.m.. On Friday.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: could we all our good players are in New York.
Speaker 1: We'd have to get them together.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah Card tournament, there's a Tetris tournament.
Speaker 1: That's all you do.
Speaker 0: well You can't.
Speaker 1: is there anything that I tournament that I would win?
Speaker 0: you can't deal with Tetris.
Speaker 0: I do okay at Tetris Tournament oh shit, but there's a Puerto Rico tournament.
Speaker 1: there you go.
Speaker 1: I mean that shit.
Speaker 0: It's on Saturday.
Speaker 0: This is anything else going on during it.
Speaker 1: Let's do it.
Speaker 1: It's 3 p.m..
Speaker 0: To 9 p.m..
Speaker 1: All right Maybe we should Spend six hours of our time in Seattle playing Puerto Rico.
Speaker 0: Well, I imagine you think about if we're playing.
Speaker 0: we could ring it.
Speaker 0: We could both join the tournament get in the same games and pick a winner.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but how many people are gonna be in the tournament?
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: I don't know how this is gonna work.
Speaker 1: well We'll check it out at con.
Speaker 0: We'll check out the details.
Speaker 0: if it is not too much of a hassle I might just enter that because I think I can win.
Speaker 0: I can win.
Speaker 0: I think I'm a pretty optimal.
Speaker 1: maybe maybe we'll play against each other in the first round and then one of us will just be Out and it'll be real easy.
Speaker 0: You know maybe it'll be a round-robin situation I might have to brush up because I don't remember the exact method to get the factory going well.
Speaker 1: Let's play when.
Speaker 1: Okay, so yeah if you're going to PAX do all those things also the game works outside of.
Speaker 1: PAX is a good place to Play some games and PAX is closed.
Speaker 0: I was thinking about renting the whole place out and having a party, but then I don't have the.
Speaker 0: yeah I just couldn't deal with that this year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I called them.
Speaker 0: I had it all set up.
Speaker 0: I just had to like give them money, and I just didn't.
Speaker 1: so last year at PAX We ate at a bunch of different restaurants.
Speaker 1: Von's was the best restaurant.
Speaker 0: No, this is a terrible restaurant.
Speaker 1: You shouldn't eat that If you've never been to Seattle before.
Speaker 1: the sci-fi museum is worth like an hour of your time.
Speaker 0: the Space Needle is mini But it's worth seeing.
Speaker 0: just don't ride the monorail.
Speaker 0: It's not worth it.
Speaker 1: But actually I found out there's a monorail that goes from the airport to the the city.
Speaker 1: yes But it was not built yet, but now it is built so we can use it to get to the city.
Speaker 1: Is it built yeah?
Speaker 0: Oh cuz I went as we could use it.
Speaker 0: I went to a website and it didn't say it worked yet, and I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: well if we if it's not working if we get There it's not working.
Speaker 1: We'll take a car so it's not a big deal, but yeah There's a. we use the monorail to get from the airport to Seattle on a rail.
Speaker 1: I didn't check to see if there's any Football or baseball game, so I don't know about that.
Speaker 0: However, do not ride the monorail in Seattle it goes.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's lame.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you this it goes about 15 feet.
Speaker 1: do try to find the secret donut place.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna tell you where it is.
Speaker 0: however It is between The ma isn't in a tree in between packs and the Space Needle.
Speaker 0: it is somewhere in a triangle between the two monorail stops And packs.
Speaker 1: there is also this music festival.
Speaker 1: You know Woodstock style Yeah, the bumper chute.
Speaker 1: That's going all weekend including Monday and Pat Monday is Labor Day and packs is not going on Monday.
Speaker 1: This is Friday Saturday Sunday.
Speaker 1: So you could go to the bumper chute Monday if you're still in Seattle you know and if you are Loser none of a packs badge you can just go to the bumper chute all weekend.
Speaker 0: I think next year I'm just gonna take like Tuesday off or Wednesday off and stay in Seattle longer and go to the bumper chute.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean we walked around it last year.
Speaker 1: We didn't go into it.
Speaker 0: also guys Just let us know because you know I really seriously considered just renting out game works for like Sunday night after packs Because last year it was like some girls about Mitzvah.
Speaker 0: So if you guys will attend and you guys want me to do that just email us and for next facts I'll just do it because it wasn't that much money like I could have just paid for it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm In the exhibition hall.
Speaker 1: there are two things You know.
Speaker 1: of course there's gonna be a million awesome things in there for you to check out.
Speaker 0: unknown worlds.
Speaker 1: Yes, the two things that you should check out just go and give them money.
Speaker 0: Don't even just throw it at them.
Speaker 1: unknown worlds creators of natural selection will be there with natural selection to Most likely almost definitely.
Speaker 1: just go there and just give them your wallet and take you know whatever they're giving out Unknown worlds.
Speaker 1: and number two in the exhibition hall Our friend Eric Marshak the guy who does all of the chalks at the conventions.
Speaker 1: He didn't say what chalk he's doing.
Speaker 1: He's being paid by a company to do a chalk a spot He's.
Speaker 1: so it's a paid advertising chalks at PAX, and he didn't say what it was.
Speaker 1: He has an NDA but on his website He posted a section of an image that included a pointy drill.
Speaker 1: So I would wager it is either a Gurren Lagann not likely.
Speaker 1: it's probably a Bioshock to chalk.
Speaker 1: that is my guess.
Speaker 1: I guess only so.
Speaker 1: don't sue him Whoever makes Bioshock.
Speaker 1: - so yeah, but there's gonna be awesome chalk going on.
Speaker 1: say hi to him.
Speaker 1: he likes to be interrupted and so he has you know time to stand up and stretch and Such man.
Speaker 0: I didn't look at like anything that's going on.
Speaker 0: in terms of the like omega-thon Yeah, it's an omega-thon.
Speaker 1: You'll watch the final round.
Speaker 0: I found that the best way to deal with the omega-thon
Speaker 1: is to do music videos at an anime convention If you
Speaker 0: happen to wander into an area where a contest is going on watch it because it's usually great
Speaker 1: most definitely
Speaker 0: But it's really doesn't seem to be worth it to stand in line to wait And you'll see the end at the end, and I don't know if they're gonna be able to top What they did last year.
Speaker 1: Excitebike - yep also at PAX our Amazing listener row she has printed up There's this PAX button near thing that goes on.
Speaker 1: or basically People print a bunch of buttons and they go to PAX and they trade buttons with.
Speaker 1: other.
Speaker 1: people have buttons.
Speaker 1: So she printed out all these packs geek nights buttons.
Speaker 1: So if you are at PAX and you're a geek nights listener You should definitely make sure you get one of those buttons.
Speaker 1: we will be sure to meet her probably on Thursday and get some so you can get them from us probably as well and You know it'll be awesome.
Speaker 1: and make sure to give you know the buttons to lots of you know non geek nights Button ear type people and exchange with them and turn them into geek nights.
Speaker 0: listen Oh, that reminds me.
Speaker 0: you know what I'm gonna bring in my care in my luggage, but my working Atari 2600 paddle controllers Oh snap because last year Last year Scott was like they have every game here, and I was like no they don't they don't have fucking kaboom.
Speaker 0: It's guys like let's see.
Speaker 0: so we go into the open gaming area, and I'm like look There kaboom.
Speaker 0: They're like three guys experts.
Speaker 0: these guys are like like like.
Speaker 0: yeah We want to play with the things bad.
Speaker 0: I'm like yeah kaboom is great, and they're like well.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: we're real good.
Speaker 0: I'm like I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm real good.
Speaker 0: We're comparing scores, and we're like oh, we got a fight.
Speaker 0: We got a fight we got a fight and the controllers just didn't work.
Speaker 0: and oh my god.
Speaker 1: If you are those dudes who were playing kaboom last year Meet up with us.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: You were not hard to find at PAX.
Speaker 1: also I want to play Tron games at PAX.
Speaker 1: I want to see some ricochet going down in the PC LAN area And I want to see some snafu going down to the console area.
Speaker 1: all right Oh my god If it's the year of Tron.
Speaker 0: if they have an Intellivision I will play snafu with people.
Speaker 1: it's time for Tron games everybody.
Speaker 1: So make sure it packs even if it's for just five minutes.
Speaker 1: play one either disc throwing or bike riding game.
Speaker 0: Honestly because I've you know Scott And I can get into the exhibit hall on Friday like an hour and a half before everyone else.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna take care of that.
Speaker 0: other than the concerts and our panels and the few like really big panels I want to go to I think I'm just gonna play games with people.
Speaker 1: I think that's what I'm gonna do to mostly tabletop games probably cuz I mean that is the it's like Goddamn, just gotta play some fucking games.
Speaker 0: I mean this is a con where I can walk into the tabletop gaming area.
Speaker 0: There's a copy of Dune and like four people ready to play it at the drop of a hat We got to just play.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna spend a lot of time playing fucking games.
Speaker 1: now To transition into the next part of this show What we're gonna do is we're in the second part of the show.
Speaker 1: We're gonna talk about what you should do if you're a loser and you're not at PAX one.
Speaker 0: You should enter that unity game contest.
Speaker 1: answer, but I want to transition.
Speaker 1: There is a game that you should play and buy Whether you're at PAX or not.
Speaker 1: Leighton Leighton.
Speaker 1: I just got Professor Leighton to Diabolical box.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna play it on the plane.
Speaker 1: You know what I'm gonna play it on the train.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna play it in handheld lounge B To fucking pre-order Think over lunch tomorrow.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna have to go to like game spot.
Speaker 1: You want me to go.
Speaker 1: I walk past the Nintendo store every day.
Speaker 1: Do you want me to just get you one?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll pay you in cash.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be full retail price.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 0: I need it.
Speaker 1: All right, but yeah I'm already.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna say something.
Speaker 1: well into like chapter two I think add packs or three.
Speaker 1: I don't even know.
Speaker 0: do not play Leighton.
Speaker 0: play Leighton outside of packs.
Speaker 0: packs is the time to play games with other people?
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, but I'm saying you got it, you know lanes for when you're relaxing in handheld lounge B?
Speaker 1: No It's also for when you're in your hotel or in a car on the way to packs.
Speaker 0: You best be playing worms with me.
Speaker 1: Oh, I should bring all my worms worms.
Speaker 0: That's one of the few games that I just really want to play with a bunch of strangers.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So anyway, if you're not at packs, what other games should you be playing?
Speaker 0: should you really be playing games?
Speaker 0: Because clearly you did not want packs enough.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, it's Labor Day weekend.
Speaker 1: So the first game you should play is barbecue.
Speaker 1: Otherwise Will Smith's gonna say I could have been at a barbecue I could have been at packs.
Speaker 1: Drag your ass to the burden desert.
Speaker 1: who's a man?
Speaker 1: So be sure to barbecue.
Speaker 1: if you're not a pack Weekend go out in the United States and it's not Labor Day where you are Barbecue anyway, it's still Saturday and Sunday.
Speaker 0: You could barbecue You know what as I've learned.
Speaker 1: and if you're in the southern hemisphere where it's cold Barbecue anyway, if you ever have a design in your house to barbecue just do it.
Speaker 1: just do it.
Speaker 1: Don't ever hesitate its barbecue weekend around the world.
Speaker 0: But anyway, you know you should be doing.
Speaker 0: if you're not a packs watch some TED Talks and enter this game contest.
Speaker 0: And I don't know edify yourself.
Speaker 1: well one game you should play is a free game.
Speaker 1: This Warsaw is basically is basically this open-source FPS But it got really polished and it's a lot like quake.
Speaker 1: Only you have this special movement button that makes it really basically it's like quake but bunny hopping is really easy Jumping off of walls is really easy And it's slick and polished and open-source and free for Mac Linux Windows and you can just get it.
Speaker 1: It's WARS.
Speaker 1: Oh W just search for it on Google and it's not the greatest game in the universe, but you know what?
Speaker 1: It's real fast.
Speaker 1: It's an FPS.
Speaker 1: It's a lot like quake.
Speaker 1: It's real colorful.
Speaker 1: It looks good.
Speaker 1: I played it a little bit.
Speaker 1: It's nice.
Speaker 1: Just get it and it's free.
Speaker 1: What the hell?
Speaker 1: Another game you should be playing Because you're not gonna be able to see unknown worlds in the exhibition hall at PAX.
Speaker 1: You're just going to play NS one like a sad sack, but you know NS one.
Speaker 1: I've been playing it lately.
Speaker 0: One is still one of my favorite.
Speaker 0: I pretty much play natural selection Civ for quake live.
Speaker 1: so make this.
Speaker 1: if you're not going to PAX make this your weekend to play NS one and if You don't know how to play NS one Make this your weekend to learn how to play NS one in preparation for NS to.
Speaker 0: you want to know how to learn to play?
Speaker 0: NS one.
Speaker 0: read the dot read the documentation on the website, which is out of date But still mostly accurate.
Speaker 0: and then because that you know back in the day, you know with FPS is I?
Speaker 0: Used to like read the website and it would tell me how to play and then I would play and I'd know what to do And people today don't seem to read the website.
Speaker 1: Well, a lot of times the website doesn't have an instruction counter strike, especially for obscure mods.
Speaker 0: They don't have the instructions on the site and as does however But as does just join any NS game that isn't combat join a team and then ask the team in the chat What do I do?
Speaker 0: and someone will tell you to do something and just do it?
Speaker 1: Make sure you join Marines.
Speaker 1: if you join aliens You're probably just gonna.
Speaker 1: you have a lot more potential to hurt your team very badly and also You're just gonna be a lot harder to be aliens because it requires a lot more FPS skills.
Speaker 0: Yeah, one bad marine is basically just gonna die alone crying and scared in the dark But he's not gonna bring his team down with it.
Speaker 1: Yeah one Die one shitty alien is gonna basically get a whole bunch of res and not use them for shit and then die.
Speaker 1: and it's gonna Be.
Speaker 1: it's gonna suck.
Speaker 0: Hey guys, don't worry.
Speaker 0: I know you need die defense towers, but I built.
Speaker 1: no see we're okay See Yeah, yeah that guy's still playing.
Speaker 1: I ran into him alien commander.
Speaker 0: well, he's he's marine dude now Yeah, yeah, dude, I next time I'm online I just got to talk to that guy because I want to interview him.
Speaker 1: You go on.
Speaker 1: guns are back to school.
Speaker 1: He's on there.
Speaker 0: I know I just got to bother him.
Speaker 1: Yeah Get him.
Speaker 0: go G.
Speaker 1: Got him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right best guy ever.
Speaker 1: All right, what are the games other than NS?
Speaker 0: - you know You should play ricochet.
Speaker 0: There are only like four ricochet servers in the world, but I Found people playing on him.
Speaker 0: I played real ricochet with real people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, play the Tron games whether you're at PAX or not.
Speaker 1: So, you know ricochet.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, we should play some ricochet to the show.
Speaker 1: Maybe maybe I don't.
Speaker 1: I might just play NS.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I gotta print out all my stuff like hotel reservation and Jet blue itinerary and all that business.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I'm like the train schedule.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna figure everything out tonight.
Speaker 1: Let's see here here One old-school game that you should revisit if you're staying home earthbound earth.
Speaker 1: That's a good one.
Speaker 0: That's a great one, man.
Speaker 1: I you know, I played it more recently, but I didn't get to the end.
Speaker 1: I got to like I was in a desert.
Speaker 0: I think it was you the giant robot.
Speaker 0: I think it was you put in the forums who was playing mother 3 and it just reminded me how much I like mother - yeah I go play.
Speaker 1: so if you never played earthbound This is the weekend of going to play earthbound.
Speaker 1: get the an SNES emulator.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: If you never played portal beat it on Saturday.
Speaker 0: just but get it and beat it.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 0: It takes at most one day of gaming to beat it no matter how bad at FPS as you are.
Speaker 1: Yep Are we gonna?
Speaker 1: um, unless you're just really dumb.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, are we gonna do a show Thursday?
Speaker 1: Probably not.
Speaker 1: probably not so and we're not gonna do a show Labor Day.
Speaker 1: No so the next Pat the next geek nights is probably gonna be like in a Wednesday and then the week after that will be a Tuesday show and We will review packs.
Speaker 0: We might just do a special episode or something.
Speaker 0: We'll figure it out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: But yeah, so the next night's after this one is gonna be a week from tomorrow.
Speaker 0: We're gonna try to get a lot more video and audio recordings from packs this year because now we know the way I mean when I get here, here's something that people should know.
Speaker 1: We're gonna go into the exhibition hall 90 minutes before the general public on Friday.
Speaker 1: I'm basically gonna take a billion pictures and videos and it's when I get out of there while we're Preparing for our panel.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna try to upload them to the internet on flickr and/or YouTube.
Speaker 0: You follow me on Twitter.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna have a constant stream of pictures and tweets coming out of that room for 90 minutes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're gonna be you know, just tweeting and flickr in and crazy go not so watch our Twitter.
Speaker 0: You're gonna see pictures of us taking pictures of things We're not supposed to take pictures of followed by pictures of the police escorting us out, right?
Speaker 1: So pay attention to our feeds to get the latest packs goody goodies from the packs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what else?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: if you're you know, you're listening to this cuz you're into some other type of game or you don't play at play.
Speaker 0: FPS is just go on Steam right now.
Speaker 0: Buy half-life 1. put it on easy mode half-life 1 source.
Speaker 1: It's a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a little bit doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Just put it on easy mode and just play it.
Speaker 0: You will realize that FPS is can be fun If you've never played a real FPS multiplayer deathmatch.
Speaker 0: and or you think that team fortress 2 is an awesome game play some quake live.
Speaker 1: Quake live is available now for Linux Mac Windows.
Speaker 0: So if you haven't played it yet Any time you think we're too harsh on modern FPS is or you think that we're you know, we're not.
Speaker 0: just go play quake live You'll see what we mean.
Speaker 0: and here Warsaw if you don't set your FOV to at least 120 You're not hardcore Warsaw.
Speaker 1: Let's change the FOV.
Speaker 0: You know, what's bad?
Speaker 1: There's an option in the options menu to just change FOV and worse NS.
Speaker 0: it works because NS is a special kind of game but ricochet.
Speaker 0: I had a lot of trouble playing ricochet because I'm so used to an FOV of 129.
Speaker 1: Yeah, ricochet cannot change the FOV.
Speaker 1: I it's not gonna work.
Speaker 0: 129 was necessary and I've gotten to the point You gotta be 90 degrees in ricochet.
Speaker 1: I figure out the angles properly.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, I don't know if I can change it.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I'm allowed to.
Speaker 0: oh But I can't play with a 90 anymore.
Speaker 1: I forgot that when I play goes and I'll chop your head off with my you will.
Speaker 0: Chainsaw blade is back in the day Like.
Speaker 0: it took me over a year when I started playing counter-strike to learn to play with a low FOV again.
Speaker 0: Well, because I used to play like with all the dynamic lighting, you know last year's packs We didn't actually go into the the.
Speaker 1: bring your own PC area.
Speaker 1: The thing is we can't bring our PCs obviously because you need to register to do that.
Speaker 1: But half the room was just filled with Dells that were already set up and it was a big room.
Speaker 1: So this year I want to.
Speaker 1: I want to definitely go in that room a little bit more than last year Maybe get some PC game and go.
Speaker 0: I have very fond memories.
Speaker 0: I forget what con it was but me and Scott Johnson were doing like the anime programming for some gaming con in Rochester Mm-hmm as we did very often and they had a land gaming area.
Speaker 0: So we wandered over there late at night and kind of drunk and played games.
Speaker 1: tax.
Speaker 1: I wish packs was just overnight because I would go to that land gaming area Friday night after the concerts and I would go to The tabletop gaming area Saturday night after the concerts.
Speaker 1: Well funny.
Speaker 1: You should say that I just wouldn't go to bed.
Speaker 0: Funny you should say that.
Speaker 0: let me get back to the packs website Because there was a news.
Speaker 0: our item of interest.
Speaker 0: blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: Okay from 830.
Speaker 0: I First want to clear up a common question.
Speaker 0: We've been getting this week.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: We are sold out three-day Friday and Saturday badges.
Speaker 0: Yes, this includes walk-up purchases given that we will sell out of Sunday badges in the next day or two.
Speaker 1: They're sold out of Sunday badges already.
Speaker 0: If you have not purchased a badge online, you will not get into packs.
Speaker 0: Please do not try to buy a badge on site.
Speaker 0: We have no badges to sell again.
Speaker 0: We have no valid badges to sell.
Speaker 0: we apologize.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: Here's the quote.
Speaker 0: that's interesting Quote.
Speaker 0: we are trying to secure more space for 2010 Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I don't know what they're gonna get.
Speaker 1: Well another interesting remember last year.
Speaker 1: The tabletop was in the annex.
Speaker 1: this year.
Speaker 1: They got the top floor of the main building.
Speaker 1: They don't have the annex.
Speaker 1: So what happened is they're moving all of the console gaming up top and all the a lot of the panel rooms up top and The tabletop is going down where the console and the panel rooms used to be down low.
Speaker 1: So that's gonna be.
Speaker 1: it's gonna be a lot more like, you know The other kind of tabletop gaming cons we go to where there's like lots of small rooms.
Speaker 0: I think Connecticut I think the tabletop is gonna get a lot more walk-in traffic as a result, which I think will do very well for Luke Crane.
Speaker 1: I think you'll do very well for Luke Crane who is again Saturday in tabletop areas.
Speaker 1: look for Luke Crane to play the burning wheels and such.
Speaker 0: Yes We will tweet his exact location.
Speaker 0: Once we sort all that business follow the tweets in memory.
Speaker 1: There's a it's.
Speaker 1: it's hard to do a Search on Twitter for packs because you'll basically find a bunch of searches about peace not anymore.
Speaker 0: You're basically just gonna find packs.
Speaker 1: Well, I searched for pound Pax and that is how you will find the good.
Speaker 0: Well, that's how Twitter works.
Speaker 1: Well, some people just search for you know, just packs on its own.
Speaker 0: I only do that if I'm searching for something obscure like I don't know geek night.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's all good.
Speaker 1: It's real hard to search for so it's really hard to like.
Speaker 1: have I search?
Speaker 1: I do a Twitter search like Python.
Speaker 1: It's like you see all these snakes posts.
Speaker 0: How much can people be posting about herpetology on a regular basis?
Speaker 0: be surprised Anyway, but I wonder what they're gonna do and maybe I think the solution for packs would be to either move out of Seattle But that wouldn't really work.
Speaker 1: now It's not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: packs East has a better proposition is if they fill up Boston Which they're definitely gonna do in a few years pretty quickly.
Speaker 0: They could just move it to Baltimore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, it's not the best place.
Speaker 0: I think the BCC can handle packs.
Speaker 1: East Building is fine.
Speaker 1: The city is no.
Speaker 1: I think they'd be better off.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There aren't enough hotels in Boston.
Speaker 1: I don't think in the what I would do if I was packs though if he needed to expand as I basically get a Ballroom in every hotel because you know like one inches that you know CES right the consumer electronics show in Vegas the way it works Right.
Speaker 1: Is this the main floor in the Convention Center?
Speaker 1: But then in all the hotels all like the companies get rooms and stuff.
Speaker 1: So it's like yes come to this hotel to check out I don't know.
Speaker 1: like company X's TV lineup and they'll have like a you know They'll bring all like reporters over there showing their TVs and stuff.
Speaker 1: If Pax is more like that where suddenly you get like companies or people like getting all the ballrooms and all the hotels to basically Effectively expand packs so that like there's a route everyone in your hotel.
Speaker 1: The ballroom has game and go hood on, you know.
Speaker 1: Oh also a Pax badge pickup is at the Hyatt.
Speaker 1: It's not at the Convention Center.
Speaker 1: It's at the Hyatt.
Speaker 1: Don't mess that up.
Speaker 1: I Think that's it.
Speaker 0: Yep, pretty much but I Feel like Pax is gonna have in the long run Hopefully 24/7 content.
Speaker 0: if they don't maybe we'll try to make that happen.
Speaker 1: Maybe we will but Pax Whoa, whoa, that's an idea.
Speaker 0: But you know we keep saying we want to make the geek nights like a gaming con like a little thing and be just make It.
Speaker 1: just make it night at Pax instead geeky nights.
Speaker 1: It just be night at Pax.
Speaker 0: It's so trivial to do.
Speaker 0: All we have to do is rent a hotel ballroom after between the hours of Pax closing and tax opening Just pick one of the hotels in Seattle and rent the rooms and sort it all out.
Speaker 1: and then we got to promote it big Time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that wouldn't be hard to do.
Speaker 0: I'm sure we could work something out.
Speaker 0: That's geek nights.
Speaker 0: that that might happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that that's gonna be worked on.
Speaker 1: we could do that at Otacon too Like hey Otacon after the doors closed everyone come to this hotel ballroom.
Speaker 0: I would rather do it for Pax.
Speaker 1: Yeah, me too.
Speaker 1: And basically if you have a Pax badge, we'll let you in and that'll be our policy, huh?
Speaker 0: This is Going to.
Speaker 0: you will hear news on this fairly quickly.
Speaker 0: after pack We get some sponsors as I sort.
Speaker 1: hopefully sumo will sponsor us so we can fill the room with bean bags And won't have to pay to rent tables and chairs.
Speaker 0: All they have to do is pay me in bean bags.
Speaker 1: I know right.
Speaker 1: I'll say they got a. sumo has a green bean bag.
Speaker 1: now when I move a green bag Yes, when I move them getting one, I'm getting probably getting like three.
Speaker 1: I think I might get red green blue Even though they're expensive.
Speaker 1: It's worth it.
Speaker 0: All right I think we're done because I want to pack for packs and play games and packs Fuck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if you're not going Fuck you.
Speaker 1: Thank you.
Speaker 0: What what did you say?
Speaker 1: sucks for you?
Speaker 0: What did you actually say?
Speaker 0: I forgot to say the word for You know this harkens back to when I was a little kid and I got in more trouble than Ida.
Speaker 0: I was really young and I meant I Honestly meant to call my little brother a name, and I did not mean to call him a scum fucker But I was gonna call him a scum bucket and I was gonna call him a scum sucker and I kind of didn't decide which one and I ended up calling him a scum bucker and I got in trouble.
Speaker 0: Scum bucker it was too close to scum fucker.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 0: I was like six.
Speaker 1: What's wrong with fucking scum?
Speaker 0: Because they take like one damage for a round.
Speaker 0: it takes forever.
Speaker 0: all right This has been geek nights with rim and scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front road crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: if you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.