Speaker 1: -Warm today.
Speaker 0: -It wasn't that warm today.
Speaker 1: -It was pretty warm.
Speaker 0: -No, it wasn't.
Speaker 0: It was a little bit cold.
Speaker 0: I had to open the window, then I had to close the window.
Speaker 0: When did you open the window?
Speaker 1: It was cold in the morning.
Speaker 0: I opened the window at various times in the day.
Speaker 0: I tried to reopen it, but I always had to close it again.
Speaker 1: I think you're a wuss.
Speaker 1: It was real warm.
Speaker 0: It wasn't warm enough.
Speaker 1: It wasn't as warm yesterday.
Speaker 0: -That's for sure.
Speaker 1: -But it was warmer today.
Speaker 0: I'm wearing shorts, but it's still... it's not... I mean, it's warm.
Speaker 0: It's not cold.
Speaker 0: It's definitely not cold, but it's not... it's not warm enough.
Speaker 0: It's not... we're not quite to where I can go outside and be like,
Speaker 0: "Yes!".
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a good feeling.
Speaker 1: But for anyone who's new to this whole Geek Nights thing, you know, maybe you found the website or something.
Speaker 0: Like yesterday.
Speaker 1: Or maybe you're one of those people who was in the Ustream doing your thing.
Speaker 0: Lol.
Speaker 1: But this... what you're about to hear is not a normal episode of Geek Nights, so if you're looking to find out what this is all about, I recommend you just pick any other episode.
Speaker 1: Except for any other episode that starts like this.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, when was this supposed to go online, Aaron?
Speaker 1: Well, originally we were gonna do it, Rob, on the Thursday.
Speaker 1: Two weeks ago?
Speaker 1: -Yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 0: -Yeah, what took two weeks?
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: One, originally, we were gonna do it right away.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, we're hurting for Thursdays, so we're gonna save it for a Thursday.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: We were gonna do it right away, and then you didn't get it done.
Speaker 0: Just like, there are still promises we made in this very episode that you did not fulfill.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what?
Speaker 1: Unlike someone in this room, I have a job that I'm working at.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but even if you had the job, you should not have made the promise that you could not keep.
Speaker 1: Well, which promises?
Speaker 1: All I said on the e-commerce was, "I'll try to get it
Speaker 1: done.".
Speaker 0: No, you said you would get it done.
Speaker 0: You said, "I got
Speaker 0: that.".
Speaker 1: I said, "I got that," as in, "I'll handle
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: -Yeah.
Speaker 1: -And, "I'll
Speaker 1: try.".
Speaker 0: -Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: -Yeah?
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Cop here.
Speaker 0: Cop it out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah?
Speaker 1: Plus, this was actually done a week and a half ago.
Speaker 1: We just didn't put it up because I'm gonna be gone all next week, so we were trying to spread stuff out and have extra episodes.
Speaker 0: That's your post-hoc excuse.
Speaker 1: It was done a week and a half ago.
Speaker 1: We just didn't put it up.
Speaker 0: It still was not in time to be... Anyway.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, this is a live show that we recorded and you streamed a couple weeks ago.
Speaker 1: I gotta say, it's not that interesting to listen to without the video.
Speaker 0: -Really?
Speaker 1: -Nah, it's no good.
Speaker 0: Did we even do anything in the video?
Speaker 0: I mean, it was mostly just us sitting, looking at laptops, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the video still adds a lot.
Speaker 1: The audio just doesn't have the same snap or pizzazz.
Speaker 0: Well, even so, in this audio...
Speaker 1: -Ah.
Speaker 1: -What?
Speaker 1: -Uh.
Speaker 0: Even so, you can hear us share very important information about various announcements, as well as answering listener questions and things like that.
Speaker 1: It was a good time, but I'd recommend you should probably, if you want to experience this, just watch the video.
Speaker 0: I also think that without the context of the chat room and such, it might make less sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but no one could keep up with that chat room.
Speaker 0: I couldn't keep up with it.
Speaker 0: I just looked up every now and then when I needed something new to say and, you know, used it as a little seed material.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but this was fun, and once I get back from Costa Rica, we'll probably do these on a semi-regular basis in some fashion.
Speaker 0: Some sort of weekend fashion?
Speaker 1: Yeah, not a, you know, Wednesday night fashion.
Speaker 0: It was only Wednesday night because it was, um...
Speaker 1: -It was the day.
Speaker 0: -Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 0: -It was the day.
Speaker 1: those things happened.
Speaker 0: -Right, yeah.
Speaker 1: -Yep.
Speaker 0: -Okay, listen to it.
Speaker 1: Enjoy.
Speaker 1: The audio obviously won't be as great as normal Geek Nights because we used a different kind of microphone that you could actually see in the videos sitting kind of between us on the table.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that way we could, you know, be in the living room.
Speaker 0: We wouldn't have to have microphones in our face.
Speaker 0: We can get the video camera going, you know, the whole thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because the lavalier isn't so great, so...
Speaker 0: -Different setup.
Speaker 0: -Yep.
Speaker 1: That's all we really got.
Speaker 1: Just listen to this.
Speaker 1: No things of the day or anything.
Speaker 1: And, uh, again, if you've never listened to Geek Nights before, pick some other episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this one won't make very much sense at all.
Speaker 1: This one's a lot of inside baseball.
Speaker 1: Do you like a baseball?
Speaker 0: Wait, is it actually recording?
Speaker 0: I pushed the start record button.
Speaker 1: I think it's recording.
Speaker 0: -Okay, now it's recording.
Speaker 1: -Now it's recording.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So that's how we start our video.
Speaker 0: Yes, that's correct.
Speaker 1: No, without saying, "Oh, it's recording
Speaker 1: now.".
Speaker 0: That was inevitable.
Speaker 0: There was nothing we could do about that one.
Speaker 0: So I guess, um, we don't have intro musics with video and such.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's kind of weird to not have the microphone in front of my face.
Speaker 1: Like, I'm so used to that that I'm kind of hunched over, like, expecting it to be there, and I...
Speaker 0: I'm leaning back, but I'm gonna have to hunch over to use the computer.
Speaker 1: -But I can't...
Speaker 0: -You wanna try to bring this closer?
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe we should.
Speaker 1: Mainly, I can't hear my own voice coming back with a slight delay into my ears.
Speaker 0: -Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 1: -That's really, like, messing with me.
Speaker 1: Am I losing the ability to talk in the real world?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Uh, so the deal with this is today is April Fool's Day, and if you've listened to our show, you will know that, um, you know, over the past many years, we have sort of had a mostly hate, slightly love relationship with April Fool's Day.
Speaker 1: Mostly the fact that I'll go to Slashshot, and I can't believe anything on the site for 24 hours.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, it's like, there's no way to trust any news.
Speaker 0: You can't communicate for 24 hours.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, when April Fool's Day was before the internet, you could, you know, pranks were sort of, you could see them.
Speaker 1: -People mostly talk, walk and talk normally.
Speaker 1: -Yeah, I mean, granted, you had the situation where your, you know, father calls and says your uncle died, and you're like, "Ha ha
Speaker 1: ha!".
Speaker 0: Oh, uh, that could happen.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it has.
Speaker 1: But the internet is that times a million.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, every blog is just all fake.
Speaker 0: You know, last year, what was it?
Speaker 0: Rickrolls everywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everywhere I went was a Rickroll.
Speaker 1: I think that was the straw, was that everything was a Rickroll.
Speaker 1: See, at least if I were YouTube, I would have gone all the way, and I would have just turned every video into a Rickroll all day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the Rickrolls broke the, uh, the camels back there.
Speaker 0: So we decided that to sort of fix April Fool's Day, right, we're gonna do is we decided, and, you know, the live part of this was to draw a lot of attention to our movement, um, was to make it April Truth Day, and we're basically going to tell you the idea is that you save up amazing but true things, right?
Speaker 0: You don't tell them to anyone, you hold on to them, the amazing but true things, and then you come out and you tell them on April Fool's Day, because no one will believe it, but it's amazing but true, right?
Speaker 0: So, we have many amazing but true things to, to tell.
Speaker 1: Of course, I will point out, I did, I did do my own April Fool's joke in the forum, and I got a bunch of you, which is sad, because I didn't even do it, I just replied to the thread where I did it last year.
Speaker 0: Actually, here, before, did you actually see any good April Fool's today?
Speaker 1: Uh, no, I mean, Reddit, what, looked like Digg?
Speaker 0: That's it?
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: I mean, uh, Quake Live was a little bit funny, but it was in Fools.
Speaker 1: That's the thing, is?
Speaker 0: I hate things that don't fool, it's just, someone will put up a fake news story, but it's obviously fake, it's not fooling anyone.
Speaker 1: You have to fool someone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, nothing, like, last year, Fark and BoardGameGeek got us both.
Speaker 0: BoardGameGeek was, I think, before Fark did that.
Speaker 0: Was it?
Speaker 1: All I remember is I went to Fark one day, and I forgot it was April Fool's Day, and I'm sitting there, and I see the, you know, I'm
Speaker 0: chatting
Speaker 1: and responding to someone, then I see this, like, moderate button, and I'm like,
Speaker 1: "Huh?"
Speaker 1: And I click on it, and I see all these options, I'm like...
Speaker 0: And I start going to, like, action, like, I start banning people.
Speaker 1: I guess I'm one of those people who would abuse my power.
Speaker 0: So the one good April Fool's Day I saw was there's this Firefox, like, combo extension, and if you're, like, a family or something like that, where everyone uses the same computer, and everyone uses the same browser, doesn't have separate
Speaker 1: accounts,
Speaker 0: you know, or if you have access to someone's account because no one uses passwords and stuff, right, it's really easy to install a Firefox extension in someone else's, um, you know, Firefox.
Speaker 0: So this extension, it was actually a bunch of extensions that come in a combo pack, would, basically, it wouldn't do anything.
Speaker 0: But on April 1st, it would start doing stuff, and it would start doing more stuff as later in the day.
Speaker 0: So what it would do, like, it would just pick links in websites that were legitimate links, but turn them into Rick Roll links.
Speaker 0: So you wouldn't actually have to Rick Roll someone, right?
Speaker 0: And there were other extensions in there, like, one would do stuff, like, if you pushed back, it would actually go forward, you know?
Speaker 0: And as the day went on, it would do it more and more, and you wouldn't know what was causing it, because it was Firefox doing it, not, right?
Speaker 1: It's still not a fool, like, it's a prank, but it's not a fool, per se.
Speaker 0: It's true, it's not a fool.
Speaker 0: But I did kind of like, it was clever.
Speaker 0: And the fact that it only works on, um, you know, it only works on April Fool's Day, the extension actually looks at the date.
Speaker 1: Oh, it looks like one of the listeners installed that on someone's computer.
Speaker 0: You know, you just, uh, you know, I thought that was clever, you know, as opposed to many other things.
Speaker 0: Alright, so do you want to do our, um, our big announcements?
Speaker 1: Amazing but true, do you want to start, where do you want to start with?
Speaker 1: Well, we can build up, because the announcement's coming in.
Speaker 1: Building up is not so bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, we got a little thing here.
Speaker 1: I'm sure many of you have seen these, but not everyone has, but we have the wonderful Geek Nights t-shirts.
Speaker 0: Yes, these t-shirts do exist, you can see them for reals, bring closer.
Speaker 0: Hold it there for a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yes, that is the real Geek Nights t-shirt, okay.
Speaker 1: Now, sadly, we sold most of them that we bought at conventions, so we have to, uh, order some more before we can really sell them to you guys over the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, we have, like, 20-something up there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and, like, only, like, seven mediums and, like, seven extra larges.
Speaker 0: So, the shirts exist, you saw them there, right?
Speaker 1: We have a web store set up, but what, it was RIM's responsibility?
Speaker 1: And I didn't make it, I got all the, this is all we got left.
Speaker 0: And RIM, uh, didn't fully set up the web store.
Speaker 1: No, I didn't make it.
Speaker 1: So, we have an empty web store that is at shop.frontroadcrew.com.
Speaker 1: So, you guys know, the reason for all that is that e-commerce sucks.
Speaker 1: Every solution either doesn't work at all, is really crappy, or does everything but takes, like, a year to set up.
Speaker 1: So, we decided to go with the full-on solu- Well, I decided to go with the full-on solution, and I said, "Scott, I got plenty of time, I'll have this ready by April
Speaker 1: 1st.".
Speaker 1: And Scott said, "All right, RIM, do
Speaker 1: it.".
Speaker 1: And I said, "Okay,".
Speaker 1: and then I just didn't.
Speaker 0: I know it's a 403, it's going to be not 403 soon enough.
Speaker 1: Yep, because we're, uh, we got a couple other little things.
Speaker 1: Talk about packs.
Speaker 1: Uh, what about packs?
Speaker 0: Well, uh- We're going to, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're going, we said we're going, well, two years ago, we said, well, yeah, we said, "Next packs," which was this previous packs, "We're going no matter
Speaker 1: what.".
Speaker 1: So, packs, are we talking about packs 09 or packs 10?
Speaker 1: Packs 09.
Speaker 0: Well, packs, oh, packs, oh, packs.
Speaker 0: There's numbers in this year's, packs 09 or packs 10?
Speaker 1: Uh, the packs we went to.
Speaker 1: We'd said the year before, "We're going," and we went.
Speaker 1: There are no Geek Nights condoms, shut up.
Speaker 1: Why, see, you're supposed to ignore that stupid shit.
Speaker 1: I don't know, it stood out.
Speaker 1: I'm avoiding the other things.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so we're like, "We're going no matter
Speaker 1: what.".
Speaker 1: And then we decided, "All right, since we're going, let's try to get a
Speaker 1: panel.".
Speaker 1: Like, I didn't think we'd get one.
Speaker 1: I put in the application, they were real professional, and one thing led to another, and we did, Beyond Dungeons and Dragons.
Speaker 1: And for anyone who wasn't at, uh, packs, people lined up for like an hour and a half to see this thing.
Speaker 1: Like, it was crazy.
Speaker 0: It was very strange.
Speaker 1: And then the fact that afterward we got the whole crowd to come to this room, and we ran the panel with Luke Crane and, uh, Jared Sorensen and a bunch of other people for like another couple hours.
Speaker 1: Well, they ran it for a couple hours.
Speaker 1: We stayed for like an hour, and then we split and went to the concert.
Speaker 0: I wasn't gonna miss the concert.
Speaker 0: What do you think this is?
Speaker 1: So, uh, I was keeping in touch with the packs people, and deciding, you know, "Hey, I wanna do stuff at the next packs.
Speaker 1: Maybe we'll try to get another
Speaker 1: panel.".
Speaker 1: And, uh, we're already doing at least two panels at the next packs in Seattle.
Speaker 1: So, we're doing Beyond Dungeons and Dragons again.
Speaker 1: I don't know why we're doing it again.
Speaker 1: At the request of packs, we're going to do it for an hour, same as last time, in a much bigger room, since, you know, people couldn't get in.
Speaker 1: And after that, we're gonna have, I didn't confirm it with Luke yet, but we're probably gonna have Luke Crane and a bunch of other people running demos of Burning Wheel and all these games for like eight hours for the rest of the day on Friday.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be like packs keynote, Beyond D&D, demos all day until the concert.
Speaker 1: And maybe all night, too.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: And then, uh, we've got another panel.
Speaker 1: I don't wanna reveal it yet, but it's something pretty cool that we're gonna be doing Saturday at some point at packs.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna say what it is yet, because it's really cool, and I think it'll be a shock and a surprise.
Speaker 1: It's called "How Great is WoW and Why We Should All Play
Speaker 1: It.".
Speaker 0: I thought we weren't doing April Fools.
Speaker 1: No, no, April Fools.
Speaker 1: It's something to do with the idea that maybe losing games should be just as fun as winning them.
Speaker 1: It's one of those theoretical "there are no games like this, but what if" kind of deals.
Speaker 1: And the only other PAX thing I got for you is that we're gonna be doing a ton of stuff at PAX East in 2010.
Speaker 1: I can't say exactly what yet, but it's gonna be big.
Speaker 1: Like, there's going to be a lot of Geek Night stuff going on at PAX East.
Speaker 1: You will be surprised.
Speaker 0: PAX East is going to be... They might as well just call it Geek Night's time, right?
Speaker 1: I mean... Well, we're not going to run tabletop gaming, but we're going to be running a large section of tabletop gaming, possibly with Luke Crane and his whole crew and a bunch of other people.
Speaker 0: Hopefully.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: Oh, someone asked about... We already announced Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Alright, fine.
Speaker 1: We're going to be at Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: We're doing, like, eight panels there, including The Late Show.
Speaker 1: We're going to be at the New York Anime Festival.
Speaker 1: We're going to be at the New York Comic Con.
Speaker 1: We're going to be at Otacon.
Speaker 1: We're going to be at Kineticon if they ever email me back.
Speaker 1: And PAX's.
Speaker 1: Is that all the conventions?
Speaker 0: Uh... Katsu-Con?
Speaker 0: Yes, no?
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah, next Katsu-Con, but I can't announce anything about that yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we don't know about that.
Speaker 0: So that's the full convention awesomeness.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: PAX is, uh... For any of you who saw Beyond D&D, compared to all the other panels we've done, it was kind of a step up.
Speaker 1: And all of our panels are going to be on that level from now on.
Speaker 1: So we're going to do fewer, more awesome panels.
Speaker 1: You know, faster, more intense.
Speaker 0: So you want to talk about something local?
Speaker 1: Something local?
Speaker 0: So, you know, we live in Beacon, New York, right?
Speaker 0: Which is, you know, it's sort of, it's a city, but it's not, like, a big city like New York.
Speaker 0: You know, there aren't any tall buildings here.
Speaker 0: It's just got a long, sort of busy main street, surrounded by houses.
Speaker 0: And it's, you know, it's in upstate New York.
Speaker 0: It's not too far upstate, but it's not too far downstate.
Speaker 0: You know, it's far enough away from New York, not to cost a fortune to live in, but it's close enough that you can take the trains in New York City.
Speaker 0: You know, it's a nice in-between kind of place.
Speaker 0: We got trees, we got houses, we got a main street, we got the Hudson River, it's sort of everything in one place.
Speaker 0: And we're walking down the main street, and we see a sign on the main street, and the sign says, "Retro Arcade
Speaker 0: Museum."
Speaker 0: And it has a picture of an arcade cabinet on it.
Speaker 1: So we look in the window, and there's nothing.
Speaker 1: Like, there's nothing in this door.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't really have windows.
Speaker 0: The only window is on the front door, and the door has shades on the inside.
Speaker 1: So we're, like, peeking around, and we see, like, this kind of empty room.
Speaker 1: We can't really tell.
Speaker 1: There's H&R Block sharing the building.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it was, you know, it was very like, "Huh, why is there a Retro Arcade Museum in our town?
Speaker 0: Is it, you know, where are the geeks
Speaker 0: at?".
Speaker 0: Obviously, even if there's nothing in this building here, this sign exists.
Speaker 0: This sign was not here before.
Speaker 0: That means recent geekery has been in this place, and it is our duty as the geeks of this town to seek it out.
Speaker 1: So we're thinking, "All right, we gotta figure out what this
Speaker 1: is.".
Speaker 1: And I'm thinking, "It's probably something that failed.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna buy the sign from whoever that
Speaker 1: was.".
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, 'cause, you know, there was what?
Speaker 0: There was that really bad anime store that was in the mall, in the Poughkeepsie Mall.
Speaker 1: Oh, the guy selling bootlegs?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and he bought a retail space across from the baseball stadium, but never moved into it, or moved in and moved out, but his sign is still there.
Speaker 0: It's still empty.
Speaker 0: I drove by it the other day.
Speaker 0: So, you know, there's been geekery, and there have been instances of signs for things going up, but the business is never coming to actually exist.
Speaker 1: Or like, last year in the summer, I was riding my bike, and I sat on a bench in Beacon, and someone had, like, carved into this thing, "I heart Naruto
Speaker 1: OMG.".
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I went back.
Speaker 1: We were trying to eat dinner.
Speaker 1: Scott didn't come, but I was out, and we were walking toward a place to eat dinner, and the whole crew, like, we had the whole front row crew there almost.
Speaker 1: And we see that it's open.
Speaker 1: So we go in.
Speaker 1: And there is, in fact, a retro arcade museum there, and the guy who runs it is, like, the coolest guy in the world.
Speaker 1: And I'm not talking retro, like, Pac-Man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're not talking about... There is a Pac-Man machine is too new for this arcade, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, Pong is probably the newest thing he's got in there, right?
Speaker 0: You're thinking, "Wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Pong was the first arcade machine.
Speaker 0: How can there possibly be something older than
Speaker 0: Pong?".
Speaker 0: Is it just all pinball machines?
Speaker 1: These are, like, mechanical arcade games from the '50s and '60s made by, like, Sega.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, people don't really realize that, you know, pinball, you know, is a mechanical game, right?
Speaker 0: Modern pinball machines are digital.
Speaker 0: They have a few mechanical parts, like the ball and the flippers, right?
Speaker 0: But, you know, old pinball machines were 100% mechanical.
Speaker 0: You know, they had solenoids and gears and chains and... Yeah, just like an odometer.
Speaker 0: So people don't remember, you know, punk kids these days, that there were other, you know, mechanical arcade machines, analog arcade machines that were not pinball.
Speaker 0: You ever seen one of those, like, you know, target practice games that actually shoots little tiny things and hits little tiny targets?
Speaker 0: Like, it'll look like a Wild West scene and they'll shoot, like, the barrel and then, like, a hobo will come out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or Ninja Gun is the best one.
Speaker 1: You just have a rifle and you shoot ninjas.
Speaker 1: Yeah, physical ninjas flying across this thing.
Speaker 1: And the way these things work is, like, amazing.
Speaker 1: We interviewed the guy, actually.
Speaker 1: We interviewed him for quite some time.
Speaker 1: He's, like, the coolest guy in the world.
Speaker 1: And we're going to put that interview up for you.
Speaker 1: And we're going to make a series of videos about all these machines in this arcade.
Speaker 0: And apparently the guy has a lot more machines that are in his storage facility and not in his little arcade because the arcade is not big enough to hold them all.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: But he also does private parties.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much all he does is private parties.
Speaker 0: You can't just walk in.
Speaker 1: And his life, he had quite a life, too.
Speaker 0: He did have quite a life.
Speaker 1: He had some stories, so we'll be talking to him a lot.
Speaker 1: But the gist is the moral of the story.
Speaker 1: Suffice it to say, we're going to put up this interview and then we're going to make all these YouTube videos.
Speaker 1: You're going to see, one by one, a bunch of videos of all these different machines, one by one.
Speaker 1: And at the end of that series, we're going to have the first Geek Nights Con at this place.
Speaker 1: We're going to have a party.
Speaker 1: You'll be able to pre-register.
Speaker 0: Not too many people can come.
Speaker 1: You're going to have to pre-register through the e-commerce site that I'm building.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're going to sell tickets.
Speaker 1: You'll be able to buy tickets there.
Speaker 1: We'll probably give away some tickets to people who want to come.
Speaker 1: And this place is amazing.
Speaker 1: I can't express to you how crazy it is.
Speaker 0: Not only that, but the place is... What's it called?
Speaker 1: I forgot what I was going to say.
Speaker 1: What were you going to say?
Speaker 1: I forget.
Speaker 1: It's cheap.
Speaker 1: It's small.
Speaker 1: It's cool.
Speaker 1: He's got that kitchen in the back with the subway doors.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I forget.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so yeah, there's going to be awesome things going down at this retro arcade-y place.
Speaker 0: And that's pretty big, pretty big deal.
Speaker 0: Because you might not think it's a big deal now.
Speaker 0: You know, why are they announcing this, right?
Speaker 0: But when you see this place, it's going to be a big deal.
Speaker 0: Alright, so next up on our list of awesome but true things.
Speaker 0: Oh, so in terms of other videos we're doing, if you don't notice, since I have no job, I've been doing more video-type things.
Speaker 0: Mostly with this webcam.
Speaker 0: For some reason, I got for almost free a camcorder because of Sony points on my Sony card.
Speaker 1: It's pretty crappy.
Speaker 0: It's good for standard definition video recording.
Speaker 0: The lens is pretty good and it's got a big old hard drive in it.
Speaker 1: If I got another battery for it, I could record for hours and hours and hours with no problem.
Speaker 0: And I bought it because it actually has a hard drive in it.
Speaker 0: Not like a lot of these other ones that have an SD card and you can barely record anything.
Speaker 0: So, you know, I tried to do some video with that thing.
Speaker 0: But the problem is, A, I was lazy.
Speaker 0: And B, you can't use it as a webcam.
Speaker 0: You can only use it to record and then drag the files off and then edit them and then put them on YouTube or whatever.
Speaker 0: And I started doing that a little bit, but I sort of didn't stick with it.
Speaker 0: Now that I have no job, I could probably do a little more.
Speaker 0: And I probably am going to.
Speaker 0: I have a whole bunch of Scott's Boxes in the hopper.
Speaker 1: He's been doing them.
Speaker 0: I just got to cut up a bunch of them.
Speaker 0: I could probably upload a whole bunch to YouTube tomorrow.
Speaker 0: But I think I got this webcam here.
Speaker 0: And since we got the webcam, we've been using it like crazy.
Speaker 0: So I think really streaming is much better for us than recording and editing.
Speaker 1: At least for now.
Speaker 1: I mean, we've got a lot of recording, editing things in the hopper.
Speaker 1: But as you know, our hopper is longer than we can ever get to as long as either of us is working.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, only things that we promise are guaranteed to make it out of the hopper.
Speaker 0: Other things in the hopper might stay there forever.
Speaker 0: But I think what I'm going to do is, A, I'm going to put up a bunch of those Scott's Boxes that I've recorded already.
Speaker 0: But I'm also thinking about, like, you know, as long as I don't have a job, maybe I can, like, if I scheduled, like, Scott's Box with the webcam, maybe I could do something like that, you know, like be like, you know, at this time, every, you know, every day or two, you know, I'd have read a comic.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And I would, you know, I'll go.
Speaker 0: And not only will I, you know, tell you about it, but people will also.
Speaker 0: it'll be an interactive kind of show.
Speaker 0: You know, just like this one.
Speaker 1: Plus, you know, with the I mean, the idea here, like what we're doing here is we're doing this live.
Speaker 1: But then we're going to record the video and put it up somewhere.
Speaker 1: And we're recording the audio.
Speaker 1: And tomorrow we'll just put the audio up as a show.
Speaker 1: Obviously edited for the get rid of long silences that inevitably will occur.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So what else do you want?
Speaker 1: Well, you have them open there.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Do you want to talk about the?
Speaker 0: do you want to do this one?
Speaker 1: The second one?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we should.
Speaker 1: But that's something we kind of.
Speaker 1: I don't know if we will actually get to it.
Speaker 0: I worry.
Speaker 0: You worry.
Speaker 1: I think we'll get to it.
Speaker 0: You think.
Speaker 1: Should we set a date now?
Speaker 1: That's forcing ourselves.
Speaker 0: You want to set a date for it?
Speaker 1: Or set a time frame?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Let's hold on.
Speaker 0: No time frame, but we can still say we're going to do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's something that we talked about doing when we first started.
Speaker 1: We just never did it.
Speaker 0: So basically we thought for a long time ago, we had the idea to sort of, you know, have, I don't know, like an award or sort of an order.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: An order of knights, perhaps geek knights.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's the obvious joke, right?
Speaker 0: You know, and it's the obvious pun in our show title is geek knights, but you know, nighttime, but also knights of the round table.
Speaker 0: And we're thinking there should be some sort of, you know, we should be able to label certain people like you, you are a geek knight and you, you other people are not, you know.
Speaker 1: And we toyed with originally.
Speaker 1: we thought maybe we'll have people nominate and we'll give it to famous people.
Speaker 1: But then we decided that's lame.
Speaker 1: So we gave up on that.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So I think we should, um, you know, possibly like get an actual trophy and maybe annually or something like that.
Speaker 1: We'll do a bunch to start because there are four of you out there right now who deserve it already.
Speaker 0: And you know, so you should know who you are.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: A Kniggetz.
Speaker 0: And we, so, you know, we should give out awards to the people who are the geek knights and it's mostly, you know, it's a listener recognition kind of thing.
Speaker 0: So you can, uh, you can look forward to that.
Speaker 0: And, oh, we have one more.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah.
Speaker 1: I don't know if we need to bother with that one.
Speaker 1: Does anyone even care?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: We don't really need to.
Speaker 1: Well, we can move on then.
Speaker 0: No, I think we have to announce this though.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, someone found out about it early.
Speaker 0: They did.
Speaker 0: Someone did find out about it early, but that was, that was my bad for not being diligent.
Speaker 0: I was sort of doing security through obscurity a little bit.
Speaker 1: Who found it by the way?
Speaker 0: I was just in this chat room streaming and someone was like, Hey, and pasted the URL in there.
Speaker 1: So how do you silence them?
Speaker 1: I assume.
Speaker 0: Well, I was like, great.
Speaker 0: I was like, great.
Speaker 1: That is when you turn that into a Rick roll.
Speaker 0: I could have, but instead I just did so.
Speaker 0: Oh, it was Mike 2175.
Speaker 0: Thanks a lot.
Speaker 0: Um, yeah.
Speaker 0: So today we must announce that we have finished the new website of front recruit.com.
Speaker 1: It's up.
Speaker 0: It's not up.
Speaker 0: I have to, I have to type a bunch of things to make it up.
Speaker 0: I'm going to do it right now.
Speaker 1: It's up.
Speaker 1: You just can't see it yet.
Speaker 1: We can see it.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: So excuse me while I type.
Speaker 1: Well, scout does that.
Speaker 1: A lot of questions have been queuing up here actually in the Twitter, almost all of them about gaming and game theory and burning wheel.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Uh, Hey guys.
Speaker 1: So you can, you cover a little bit of beyond D and D sometime soon.
Speaker 1: Heard a lot about it.
Speaker 1: Would like to know more.
Speaker 1: Uh, for anyone who was at packs, you saw it obviously.
Speaker 1: And we did it at Connecticut too.
Speaker 1: And I think we actually did it better at Connecticut because we were, uh, it was so informal.
Speaker 1: Like we'd never done it before.
Speaker 1: That was the test run.
Speaker 1: So we literally, we show up to this panel.
Speaker 1: We've done seven other panels that day.
Speaker 1: We're exhausted, utterly wrecked.
Speaker 1: Emily got us Chinese food.
Speaker 1: We set it down in front of ourselves.
Speaker 1: We just eat this Chinese food and give this panel and it was like the best thing ever.
Speaker 1: But we talk about how Dungeons and Dragons, as good as it was for learning how to play role-playing games or all of us got into role-playing with it or all those sorts of things, it's a terrible role-playing game because it doesn't really have anything to do with role-playing and it's a combat game, but there's no other sort of conflict resolution.
Speaker 1: We, we basically talk for an hour about exactly what it is that Dungeons and Dragons is and what it isn't and what a role-playing game is and what role-playing game isn't.
Speaker 1: And then we kind of, we get the audience to agree to a definition of a role-playing game, which is basically a conflict resolution mechanism for collaborative storytelling.
Speaker 1: And then we talk about all the games that actually do that pretty well, like Burning Wheel, Inspectors.
Speaker 0: The games, there are a lot of games that do it very well.
Speaker 0: We don't know all of them.
Speaker 1: We talk about, we give like four examples in the panel and we kind of take people through them and it's like, it's our headlining panel right now and we're probably going to do it at like every con this year and then we're going to record some sort of video final version and then just can it.
Speaker 1: So that's what it's about.
Speaker 0: That basically it's about mechanism design and conflict resolution in tabletop role-playing games.
Speaker 1: Mechanism design, by the way, is the idea that if you think about, if you have a game, you can design the rules of a game to force someone to do something or you can design the rules of a game to encourage someone to do something without forcing them.
Speaker 1: Like mechanism design of a game like Burning Wheel is to create a story that keeps complicating itself and going in directions you wouldn't expect and always pushes people to like purposefully screw something up at the critical moment or lose as opposed to win.
Speaker 1: And it's just as awesome.
Speaker 1: And D&D kind of encourages this idea that you can always solve something by fighting with it.
Speaker 1: I guess we do need a geeky quilt.
Speaker 1: This is not a geeky quilt.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Does someone want to make one for us?
Speaker 0: That's probably a good idea.
Speaker 0: Actually, this couch, it is called the fucker.
Speaker 1: Pretty much like that.
Speaker 1: That is the name of this couch because we moved into this house.
Speaker 1: This house is actually pretty big.
Speaker 1: We found it.
Speaker 1: Did we ever tell the story of like how we got this house?
Speaker 0: You can just keep telling stories.
Speaker 1: It's going to take a little bit.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So we live in a pretty big house, actually, especially considering we pay almost nothing for this thing.
Speaker 1: It's gigantic.
Speaker 1: But we were looking for a place to live.
Speaker 1: I'd been living in the Mid-Hudson Valley for like two and a half years working for IBM, all this stuff.
Speaker 1: Scott was at RIT and they lived with his parents for a while and he moved around.
Speaker 1: I was like, Scott, just move to Beacon or Poughkeepsie or somewhere in this area.
Speaker 1: We can both work in the city.
Speaker 1: We can get everyone to move out here.
Speaker 1: It'll be awesome.
Speaker 1: So we're doing this.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to get him to move out.
Speaker 1: I'm looking at houses and apartments and everything.
Speaker 1: I don't have a lot of money yet.
Speaker 1: IBM was paying me like 45K a year, which just wasn't enough, especially for this area.
Speaker 1: So eventually I find like these five places and I look at them all and there's two that are... Well, there's one that's a really good candidate and I'm like, all right, this is it.
Speaker 1: We're definitely going to move into this place.
Speaker 1: I got to get Scott to look at it and we'll just do it.
Speaker 1: So he takes the train up and he stays in my crappy little apartment in Fishkill.
Speaker 1: I believe, didn't the heat stop working that night?
Speaker 1: It was rough.
Speaker 1: I fall asleep and Scott's on the floor.
Speaker 1: It's like a studio apartment in this French style.
Speaker 1: It's this really shady building I was living in, but I was paying like 400 bucks a month.
Speaker 1: And well, this story is just, I keep spawning all these tangents.
Speaker 1: So I wake up and I'm kind of chilly and I look over and I see Scott is curled into this like fetal position with the one tiny sheet I gave him, basically dead.
Speaker 1: And the room is like 35 degrees because the boiler failed overnight.
Speaker 1: So we go look at this apartment.
Speaker 1: It's in some lady's basement.
Speaker 1: It's beautiful, but it's like this basement apartment in someone's house and it's not that big.
Speaker 1: And we're like, you want to move in?
Speaker 1: Let's move in.
Speaker 1: Let's do it.
Speaker 1: We're like, all right, we just have to look at this one other house, this one other place.
Speaker 1: We're not going to move into it.
Speaker 1: We'll come back, sign the stuff, all set.
Speaker 1: I didn't even want to come see this place because I'd already found the perfect place.
Speaker 1: And this house, I tried to look at it two times before and one time like the scheduling messed up and the other time I couldn't find it.
Speaker 1: And like I gave up and I wasn't able to get in.
Speaker 0: Well, when we tried to come, we couldn't find it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then we couldn't find it again.
Speaker 0: So finally- That was your fault for not getting the name of the street right.
Speaker 1: Well, because I swore she said Coughlin Street, but it was Conklin Street.
Speaker 1: And there are two, both streets exist in Beacon and the same address exists on both streets.
Speaker 0: You thought it was like Christina Street.
Speaker 1: No, it was Coughlin Street.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So we went to Coughlin Street and there's a seven Coughlin Street and it's definitely not it.
Speaker 1: So we sorted out and we go and we're like, all right, let's just look at the stupid thing.
Speaker 1: Say no, be nice to this lady and then go.
Speaker 1: And she takes us into this gigantic house and I'm looking at it and it's gigantic.
Speaker 1: So finally I'm like, so who lives upstairs?
Speaker 1: So she's like, oh, you want to see the upstairs?
Speaker 1: The upstairs was part of it and it costs less than the other place.
Speaker 1: So we moved into it.
Speaker 1: So we had to move all our stuff out of Rochester.
Speaker 1: I rented a, I think 16 foot truck.
Speaker 1: They didn't have any 16 foot trucks when I showed up.
Speaker 1: They gave me a 24 foot semi truck.
Speaker 0: That was fun.
Speaker 1: It was like the worst thing ever.
Speaker 1: So Scott took like a little bit of stuff in his car and drove here.
Speaker 1: That was the tempo.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: You're like, it didn't, you lost the muffler, not that time, but some other time on the mid hustle bridge.
Speaker 0: So no, on the, uh, the Newberg beacon, the Hamilton fish bridge.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: So me and Pete in the front row crew load up this 24 foot fucking truck and we drive it through the mountains on route 17 all the way here listening to like NPR and just whatever we could find on the radio.
Speaker 1: It was this horrible drive.
Speaker 1: It took forever.
Speaker 1: I could barely drive this car.
Speaker 1: I was having so much trouble with this truck.
Speaker 0: Like I couldn't get it out.
Speaker 1: Exit ramps.
Speaker 1: I ran over stuff like on the sidewalk.
Speaker 0: It was gigantic.
Speaker 0: I couldn't drive it.
Speaker 1: Like when you drove down that residential street in Rochester trying to get it out of the place.
Speaker 1: Like I was running over things.
Speaker 1: It was horrible.
Speaker 1: Eventually I get the stupid truck here like, ah, and we start to unpack it and we thought it'd take like an hour.
Speaker 1: It took us like five hours.
Speaker 1: If Pete hadn't skipped work the next day and hadn't stayed and loved all this stuff for us because Pete is a beast of a man.
Speaker 1: We would have died.
Speaker 1: Like the police would have found me and Scott under this couch dead.
Speaker 1: So Pete helps us move this couch in.
Speaker 1: This thing weighs, I don't know, 400 pounds.
Speaker 0: That's pretty close.
Speaker 1: It's got a steel frame.
Speaker 1: There's a whole queen size bed in here, but the whole thing is the steel frame.
Speaker 1: We had no way.
Speaker 1: There was no possible way we could get this thing in.
Speaker 1: Pete can barely get it in.
Speaker 1: We put a hole in the wall, bringing it in.
Speaker 1: We got it here.
Speaker 1: That wasn't actually a hole.
Speaker 1: I fixed it.
Speaker 1: Well, it was like this.
Speaker 0: Mark on the wall.
Speaker 0: I think I fixed it.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, I fixed it.
Speaker 1: You don't need a license to drive a 24 foot truck.
Speaker 1: It is the biggest truck you can drive in New York without having a commercial license.
Speaker 1: So I could legally drive it.
Speaker 1: Plus back then I think I still had a Michigan driver's license.
Speaker 0: That's interesting.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Remember I didn't get a New York license until relatively recently.
Speaker 1: Remember I got pulled over with that expired Michigan plate from like four years ago.
Speaker 0: All right, let's see if this works.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: This is going to be hilarious.
Speaker 1: Well, do we have any way to tell?
Speaker 1: Because I think you only allowed.
Speaker 1: But didn't you only allow.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: Oh, you probably got rid of the access filter.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Just go to regular.
Speaker 1: I want to go to that.
Speaker 0: Remember, you're testing this website right now.
Speaker 0: I need, I need to know, Oh, by the way, feed burners probably going to stop working.
Speaker 0: We're going to need to sort something out with them.
Speaker 1: It'll start up again.
Speaker 1: Probably.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Loading.
Speaker 1: Waiting.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: Loading.
Speaker 1: Still loading.
Speaker 1: Nothing's happening.
Speaker 0: That's pretty great.
Speaker 0: How about the, I'll check the shop.
Speaker 1: If the shop's fine, then you know that the, uh, what'd you do?
Speaker 0: I knew it wasn't going to work.
Speaker 1: Well, you keep working on it, I guess.
Speaker 1: So we finally get this couch in and Pete plops down on it and he looks at us and he says, I hereby dubbed this couch, the fucker may I rest in peace.
Speaker 1: And he told us that he would never help us move again for the rest of our lives.
Speaker 0: People are seeing it.
Speaker 1: Oh, they're seeing the website.
Speaker 0: Is he going slow?
Speaker 1: I can't see it still.
Speaker 0: I can't see it either.
Speaker 1: Are they just lying to us?
Speaker 0: Could be lying.
Speaker 1: Wait, did you load it?
Speaker 1: Because you had that rule that we could only get to it from here.
Speaker 1: Then the beta.
Speaker 0: Oh, here it goes.
Speaker 0: No, I changed that up.
Speaker 1: Why won't it load for me?
Speaker 0: Oh, there it goes.
Speaker 0: I think it's just slow because we're sort of DDO S-ing it now.
Speaker 1: I'm going to, I'm going to spruce it up with, if only like a thousand people are hitting it.
Speaker 0: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: I'm going to, I'm going to, you know, I still can't get to it.
Speaker 0: I'm going to power it up.
Speaker 0: Some I, you just have to wait.
Speaker 0: Don't touch anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: We didn't write all the texts.
Speaker 1: A lot of that's in my court.
Speaker 0: There's a, there's a lot of things that rim a, I did all the work.
Speaker 1: Most of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The design is by our friend cat.
Speaker 0: She did all the photo shops.
Speaker 0: I did all the HTMLs and the CSS and all that other business.
Speaker 1: I worked at a job and got money unrelated to this the whole time.
Speaker 0: So, you know, anything that's, you know, it's not a hundred percent done.
Speaker 1: It's like 90% done, but it's, uh, you know, it's, uh, it's ready to roll because I'm sick of the fact.
Speaker 1: like what really, I hate to call out anime world order cause I love those guys, but what really like?
Speaker 1: the impetus for me to have this website and our e-commerce and everything was that, well, what do you mean?
Speaker 1: it's all web 2.0?
Speaker 1: I hate that term.
Speaker 0: Hate that term.
Speaker 1: It's not even really that web 2.0.
Speaker 1: Not really.
Speaker 1: Web 2.0 is, is not that, web 2.0 is like D.
Speaker 0: Oh wow, the forum is hurting too.
Speaker 0: Let me, uh, is there something going on with the, uh, let me check the CPU usage on the actual server.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we didn't, we never did a stress test or a regression test.
Speaker 0: We didn't do any sort of test.
Speaker 1: Well, you check that.
Speaker 0: I'm checking.
Speaker 1: But, uh, anime world order, you keep saying it's web 2.0.
Speaker 1: How is it web 2.0?
Speaker 1: Whoever just said that, I want you to post what web 2.0 means and then why you think this website is somehow web 2.0. because I don't think, you know, yes, interactivity, user generated content also, uh, not just interactivity, but interlinking between multiple things or it doesn't do any of that.
Speaker 1: It's just a blog.
Speaker 1: It just looks different from WordPress.
Speaker 0: It could look, WordPress could look like that.
Speaker 0: You can just make a theme for WordPress that looks like that.
Speaker 1: The only reason we didn't use WordPress was that it sucks to make WordPress do this and it was much better to use Django.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Plus with Django we can do lots of specialized things.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you a secret.
Speaker 0: There is a thing of the day RSS feed.
Speaker 0: If you go to slash feeds slash T O T D. Let me type that into the chat room there.
Speaker 1: Sexy font does not equal web 2.0.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, this font is not sexy.
Speaker 0: All these fonts and things are from Yahoo.
Speaker 0: I use the Yahoo.
Speaker 1: Suddenly the Twitter's exploding here.
Speaker 0: Is it really exploding now?
Speaker 1: I just suddenly got a whole bunch of, let me refresh this.
Speaker 0: That URL will take you to a feed of things today.
Speaker 1: It's not web 2.0.
Speaker 1: There are no reflections or lens flares.
Speaker 1: Two people made the same joke at the same time.
Speaker 0: I like how some people think about 2.0 is about graphic design and other people think it's about, you know, Ajax and doing HTTP requests without refreshing the page.
Speaker 1: I think there's the difference between people who know about the front end and people who know about the back end.
Speaker 1: I mean like you can always tell the people who don't know about the back end and I can't blame anyone for not knowing about the back ends of these things, but if someone asks you to design a website, you can tell in five seconds if they know how websites work or not.
Speaker 1: If they give you a Photoshop picture and they're like, yeah, make my website look like that, then clearly they don't know.
Speaker 0: Okay, here, let me, let me try something here.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Checking stuff out.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I think we spawned too many Apache processes.
Speaker 1: Is that?
Speaker 1: maybe you need to optimize the spawning of Apache processes?
Speaker 0: That's what I'm going to do.
Speaker 0: I'm going to turn the website off.
Speaker 0: That's off.
Speaker 0: Ah, see, there's still some there.
Speaker 1: They got to clean those up.
Speaker 1: Oh, Apache 2.0.
Speaker 0: Those are, they're getting out of control even though I turned that shit off.
Speaker 1: This dead air.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: This is what this is for.
Speaker 0: They're helping us out.
Speaker 1: They're helping us out.
Speaker 1: We probably should have done some sort of stress test.
Speaker 0: No, it's all right.
Speaker 1: All I do is write a w get script.
Speaker 1: All right, let's go through this Twitter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's start.
Speaker 0: All right, so now we're going to start taking any comments or questions from anyone while I finish this business here.
Speaker 1: If one of you were to die, would the show go on?
Speaker 1: What if one of you were to die during recording?
Speaker 1: Well, if we were to die during recording, probably you'd be called a 911 and- I'd probably leave the recording going, but I would stop editing or muting, coughing or anything.
Speaker 1: You'd probably hear a lot of scary stuff going on in the background.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you'd hear paramedics talking and- I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't have a funny answer for that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: What kind of question is that?
Speaker 1: If one of us died, if Scott died, I would keep doing Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: I would probably stop doing Geek Nights for a month or so while I sorted out Scott's affairs vis-a-vis me, because our affairs are actually pretty entwined at this point, what with Geek Nights and everything.
Speaker 1: But yeah, Geek Nights would continue.
Speaker 1: And honestly, I think Geek Nights will continue.
Speaker 1: Even if we moved, like I moved to Costa Rica, we would probably keep doing Geek Nights and Front Room Crew and all these things in some sort of form.
Speaker 1: Our internet presence will not die until both of us are dead.
Speaker 1: And if I can, I have this impression that if this stuff is continuing to the point where we're in our 70s, we will probably pass the mantle on to someone else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, there's just, you know, by the time we, you know, that's so far in the future, things won't even be the way they are now.
Speaker 1: Will you sell t-shirts on the store in the website?
Speaker 1: Yes!
Speaker 1: There's an e-commerce site.
Speaker 0: We haven't put them in yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, RIM failed to put them there.
Speaker 1: I didn't finish setting up the e-commerce yet, but yes, you will be able to buy.
Speaker 1: The impetus for all that.
Speaker 1: So Anime World Order, they were like, "Yeah, we got hoodies.
Speaker 1: If you want to buy one, send us an
Speaker 1: email.".
Speaker 1: And at that moment, I said, "We are never going to do something like that.
Speaker 1: So I'm making this e-commerce be totally
Speaker 1: awesome.".
Speaker 1: No, if Scott died, I would not have sex with his corpse.
Speaker 1: Thank you, you streamer83613.
Speaker 0: I told you not to recognize the stupid questions.
Speaker 1: It was a question.
Speaker 1: It's a stupid question.
Speaker 1: No, there were much stupider questions.
Speaker 1: I'm skipping.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: I haven't been looking.
Speaker 0: I'm still trying to get the website out there.
Speaker 1: I'm going to keep an eye on that.
Speaker 1: But seriously, this is something that the internet hasn't had to deal with yet in any big form, but some day the people who do Penny Arcade are going to die.
Speaker 1: Some day.
Speaker 1: All the people who do these things that we read and love are going to either stop doing them or die and thus stop doing them.
Speaker 1: And I have yet to see any internet thing deal with that effectively yet.
Speaker 1: I feel like we will deal with it.
Speaker 1: I don't know what Penny Arcade will do.
Speaker 1: I don't know what.
Speaker 1: I think Mega Tokyo will just stop.
Speaker 1: I think it will stop long before Fred Gallagher dies.
Speaker 1: Plus, 80 years from now, what was going on in the world, well, I guess 60 years ago because we're not zero, what was going on in the world 60 years ago?
Speaker 1: World War I was going on!
Speaker 0: The world is going to change a lot by then.
Speaker 0: Actually, World War I was more than 60 years ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but not that.
Speaker 0: Actually, World War II was more than 60 years ago.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: I guess you're right.
Speaker 0: Yes, I am right.
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: "Oh, you're yelling at me for not knowing histories, look who doesn't
Speaker 0: know.".
Speaker 0: I'm going to reboot the whole line node.
Speaker 1: Whole line node?
Speaker 1: Oh, snap.
Speaker 0: Rebooting the whole thing.
Speaker 1: But anyway, yes, we will try to keep, geek nights will be passed on to someone most likely.
Speaker 1: So it will probably go on forever and the front row crew will eventually have new people I guess.
Speaker 1: Maybe the children of all the people in the front row crew now.
Speaker 0: Who knows?
Speaker 0: There's got to be, you know.
Speaker 0: I mean, if we build a brand that has value, why would the brand ever, you know, stop being used?
Speaker 0: You know?
Speaker 0: If it's a valuable brand, why would people, you know?
Speaker 0: Henry Ford isn't there, but the Ford Motor Company is.
Speaker 0: So the only way that geek nights would go away is if the brand loses all value and no one wants to keep it around.
Speaker 1: So your mom just said, "Do you remember World War
Speaker 1: II?".
Speaker 1: And the Katsucon where I met Daryl Surratt, I hadn't been drunk at the time, but me and Scott Johnson and Lara and a bunch of other people got stinking drunk and we were hanging out at this con and we had one of those everyone's drunk conversations.
Speaker 1: And someone asked, "Do you remember World War
Speaker 1: II?".
Speaker 1: Like you know, that war?
Speaker 1: And the conversation that spawned from that was one of those, one of the most epic conversations ever, much like the Barry argument.
Speaker 1: Sadly, we never get drunk at cons anymore.
Speaker 1: Well, Scott never got drunk, but I'm always busy at conventions now doing geek nights.
Speaker 1: I haven't gotten drunk at a con in a long time, but I guess I never will again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you have a question that you actually want to get answered, you're going to have to tweet it to us because the chat room's scrolling by too fast for me to really see everything in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, tweet to @geeknights, you know, it doesn't matter if Geek Nights is following you or not.
Speaker 0: We'll see it.
Speaker 0: You can also suffice to say us.
Speaker 0: That's not a bad idea, you know, since we have suffice to say, oh wait, but it's not up.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: Forget about suffice to say.
Speaker 1: Forget about that.
Speaker 1: I guess you can send an email or a chat to geeknights@frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of watching that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: This will be ready in a second, I think.
Speaker 1: So beyond D&D, great minds think alike, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, the same few people keep tweeting over and over again here.
Speaker 1: No one else is.
Speaker 0: Probably because those are the Tweety people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not Tweety.
Speaker 1: I've never used TweetDeck until just now.
Speaker 1: So I'm kind of, I like it.
Speaker 1: I'll probably start using it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just, all right, now the website is working and fast.
Speaker 1: Not bad.
Speaker 1: Oh, I guess people can hear the new message alert that keeps popping up every now and then.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You're not hearing all of them because I'm kind of suppressing a lot of these.
Speaker 1: Once I got an email like Carl Horn, blah, blah, blah, that's not a question.
Speaker 1: That's not a question.
Speaker 0: That doesn't have to be a question, it could just be a comment that elicits a response.
Speaker 1: That has a question mark, but it is not a question, nor is it interesting.
Speaker 1: Oh, they're starting to chat me.
Speaker 1: Here we go.
Speaker 0: Is the website starting to be slow?
Speaker 1: Rym?
Speaker 1: Yes, I'm here.
Speaker 1: I will respond back, in fact.
Speaker 1: So someone asked the question, what is strategy?
Speaker 1: Because apparently, you know, on the show last night, we kept talking about games we wanted.
Speaker 1: And I think we mentioned, as we always do, strategy and tactics, that we want games that have these sorts of things.
Speaker 1: Strategy has different meanings depending on whether you're looking at the colloquial meaning, the game theory meaning, the military meaning.
Speaker 1: Like I remember Bruce and I had a long conversation over New Year's about how like, in the military, strategy or strategic means the theater, like you've got a war, like say World War Two, there was the Asian theater, or the Pacific theater, and there was the European theater.
Speaker 1: So strategy is the kind of overarching plan, or you know, how you're dealing with the entire theater of war, like the strategy of World War Two in Europe was all of Europe combined, like.
Speaker 1: that is strategy, or like, now strategic often means global thermonuclear war, those sorts of things, that level of strategic thought.
Speaker 1: In game theory, strategy means you are not making decisions anymore.
Speaker 1: A strategy is you have an expert system, you have a specific plan, you know for every situation that can occur in the game, what your reaction will be, and what your reaction will be to all the reactions to that action.
Speaker 1: So if you have a strategy in a game, that means that you don't need to be there anymore, you are no longer making decisions at this point.
Speaker 1: Colloquially,
Speaker 0: and
Speaker 1: what most board game people will say, a strategy is simply, this is my plan going forward, like I'm thinking, here are the next ten moves I'm going to make, as opposed to, you know, someone else makes a move, how do I react to that, I'm thinking about this right now, or someone surprised me, I don't know what to do.
Speaker 1: That is tactics.
Speaker 1: I don't want to go into more detail, I don't want to talk about math, I mean.
Speaker 0: Alright, the site seems to be working for me, and is relatively fast, so.
Speaker 1: I like our website to be honest, so poke it, try to break it, let us know what works and what doesn't.
Speaker 0: Yeah, find if there's something wrong with it, tell me if there's something missing, tell me if there's a missing episode, you know, anything like that.
Speaker 1: So I guess as long as Scott is not working 9-5, he can make updates to this pretty readily, so make your suggestions now, once Scott is working 9-5 again, then it's not going to happen anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but actually because the site isn't WordPress anymore, it's actually a lot easier to do things than it would have been, so awesomeness all around.
Speaker 0: So one thing, someone asked the question, I want to point out, how do you tweet someone?
Speaker 0: Go to Twitter.com, sign up, and then do @geeknights, and then whatever you want to say.
Speaker 1: I would say more honestly, it seems like there are people who use Twitter, and people who don't use Twitter.
Speaker 1: And the differentiation between these people is this crazy gulf, and I don't know which side is better to be on.
Speaker 1: But it amazes me how many people just like, I have no idea what Twitter is to this day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then there are other people who are like using it, but they don't get it.
Speaker 0: But then there are other people that get it and don't use it, and then there are other people that think they get it and don't use it.
Speaker 1: Then there are the people who just literally live on Twitter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know what's going on.
Speaker 1: So, I don't know if you want to say anything, but someone asked a really interesting question.
Speaker 1: Uh, considering your belief that the front row crew might continue through its children, would you call the front row crew a guild?
Speaker 1: Because a long time ago- A guild is specifically an economic construct.
Speaker 1: Well, again, you know, economic definition, colloquial definition.
Speaker 1: But Scott actually had a good answer for this.
Speaker 1: Remember when someone asked, "How can I join the front row
Speaker 1: crew?"
Speaker 1: Didn't you say that that's like asking, "How can I join the
Speaker 1: Rubins?".
Speaker 0: Eh, something like that.
Speaker 1: Uh, the front row crew is a family.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's at the point where literally we are a family.
Speaker 1: Like, we are closer than a lot of families I've seen are.
Speaker 0: Or what did Emily's mom say?
Speaker 0: A tribe?
Speaker 1: A tribe.
Speaker 1: Well, there was an article in the New Yorker about that, I think, about how there's this new-
Speaker 0: It's not
Speaker 1: new in the scheme of humanity, but it's new in America that people seem to be forming these kind of- Instead of, like, nuclear family or extended family or friend groups, there are these tribes of, like, twenty-something people who maybe went to college together or know each other in some sort of form and decided to- Like, they have a relationship that is well beyond friendship and is definitely on the level of family.
Speaker 1: But it's a self-selected family.
Speaker 1: It's literally a tribe.
Speaker 1: And this is really occurring more and more in urban culture.
Speaker 1: Like, in cities, there are tribes of twenty-something hit people getting together.
Speaker 1: And she pointed out that the front row crew basically is straight up a tribe.
Speaker 1: Like, by all the definitions that they have of tribe.
Speaker 1: And it's- I don't know what I can say.
Speaker 1: It's- We are a tribe.
Speaker 1: We are a family.
Speaker 1: Front row crew is almost a surname at this point.
Speaker 1: So a lot of you ask us all the time, "How can I join the front row
Speaker 1: crew?"
Speaker 1: And that is literally, like, asking, "How do I join the
Speaker 1: decosters?".
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can join the front row crew fan club.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You can join that.
Speaker 1: But to join the front row crew, short of marrying in- And even that is not a guarantee.
Speaker 1: If you marry someone in the front row crew, that's just not me.
Speaker 0: There have been many, uh- You know, there's been a lot of people who have, you know, sort of come and gone, you know?
Speaker 0: And some people have come and stayed for quite a long time, and they're still gone.
Speaker 0: I mean, there were people that were here for, like, years.
Speaker 1: And then they went, and we don't even talk to them anymore.
Speaker 1: There's really only one person who left the front row crew, though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there were, you know, there's people who become, you know- You know you have friends, and then you have acquaintances.
Speaker 0: They're just, like, people you know, but you don't really hang out with them, right?
Speaker 0: So there's a lot of people like that, you know?
Speaker 0: They sort of come in, and we hang out with them a bunch, and we know who they are.
Speaker 0: But we don't really, you know, we're not, like, you know, with them a whole bunch.
Speaker 1: But it's interesting how the crew has- It's, like, there are people who are friends of, or acquaintances of, the crew.
Speaker 1: As opposed to of any one of us in particular.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: It's also interesting to see when, like, there'd be people that were both really close- You know, were really close to, like, these two people, but they've never met each other.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we had a few people like that, like, out- Or also we had- Like, on New Year's, like, we had people coming.
Speaker 0: It was, like, best friend and other best friend both show up on New Year's.
Speaker 0: They never met each other in their whole lives.
Speaker 1: Well, part of that, for the longest time in the world, there was this kind of problem where Scott- Like, the original front row crew, the original, original, original core front row crew was, like, six or seven people.
Speaker 1: It was, like, me and Scott, and Alex, and Pete, and Katsu, and, like, all these people at RIT who, like, became friends at this club.
Speaker 1: And then we started spreading, and we had all these different people around, but Scott's typing someone up there, so I can't see the chat anymore, but that's fine.
Speaker 1: So, it, the, like, the crew, I forgot where I was going with this, to be honest, but the crew, like, founded itself as one thing, and then it grew into other things.
Speaker 1: I kept trying to talk, I forgot where I was going with it.
Speaker 0: Don't worry about it, let's see what people are saying here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm trying to avoid becoming just the show about the front row crew.
Speaker 0: Right here, well, you and Scott are going to split a pizza, what is on it?
Speaker 1: Scott hates everything I like on pizza.
Speaker 1: Well, that's 'cause you only like the really bad shit.
Speaker 1: You know what, I like Hawaiian pizza.
Speaker 1: I like sausage on a pizza.
Speaker 0: I don't like sausage.
Speaker 0: I like mushrooms, you like mushrooms?
Speaker 1: Mushrooms are fine.
Speaker 0: See, I only don't like fruits.
Speaker 1: I like fruits.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, like, a tomato, I guess, technically a fruit, but we're talking about, you know, like, pineapple, no good.
Speaker 1: I don't like ham.
Speaker 1: Pineapple is key, I agree.
Speaker 0: No, and I don't like sausage, right?
Speaker 0: But anything else, I mean, you could put the meatball, the chicken, the pepperoni, the mushrooms, the peppers, the onion, any, you know, ten kinds of cheese, right?
Speaker 0: As long as it's not pineapple, ham, or sausage, everything else is awesome.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess anchovies are a little bit eh.
Speaker 0: Honestly, I don't hate anchovies, but I don't seek them out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, you know, and I mean, the thing is, you know, depending, like, it's weird, because actually the sort of, like, the bad sausage actually tastes less like sausage, so it's a little more tolerable, right, for me?
Speaker 0: And I'll eat a pizza that has, like, the bad sausage, but if it has, like, like, awesome sausage, what other people would consider to be, like, awesome sausage, like, I would not eat it because it's too sausage.
Speaker 0: But then again, part of, like, you don't like ham either.
Speaker 1: It's not like you avoid it for religious reasons.
Speaker 0: No, are you kidding?
Speaker 0: I eat mad bacons.
Speaker 1: I eat mad, uh, I eat pork fried rice.
Speaker 1: You didn't grow up eating ham, so ham is a taste that, I guess, if you're not, I've noticed people who didn't eat ham when they were young don't like, like, a glazed ham.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, I mean, it's like anyone who didn't, you know, usually you develop taste when you're young and it's like, you know, people who don't eat a lot of fish when they're young don't like fish later, even if they're, you know, open to eating it.
Speaker 0: You know, they'll just like, oh, I'll try fish.
Speaker 0: I'm an adult now.
Speaker 0: I didn't eat it when I was a kid, right?
Speaker 0: Very rarely will they like it just because the connections in their brain have lined up to where it's, these taste good, these taste bad, right?
Speaker 0: So a new, if it's, you know, a fish taste comes in and it's lined up to bad, your brain has to rearrange to, you know, to make it taste good to you.
Speaker 1: Ah, but the issue we had, just so I can finish this thought before I lose it, people were, you know, with the front row crew, the problem we had was that Scott and I, because our apartment was the hangout apartment because we had furniture.
Speaker 1: That was really the only, it's weird how these small things like become like into these bigger things later, but literally Scott and I were the only people who had furniture in our apartment for a long time.
Speaker 1: So the whole front row crew would always hang out in our apartment.
Speaker 1: So like we were the center of the front row crew, like social scene at RIT for a long time.
Speaker 1: And then eventually James saved us because he started having parties at his place and then we had parties at Capstone.
Speaker 1: But as a result, there were a lot of people in the crew who only knew us and didn't know anyone else in the crew for a long time.
Speaker 0: It was really weird.
Speaker 0: It was, it was kind of weird.
Speaker 0: Someone asked if we're ever going to return or change the show.
Speaker 0: They said, we're going to, if we're going to change the show schedule again or change the show schedule format.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it's not a specific question of, are we going to go back to four shows?
Speaker 0: Is it, is it going to be two shows forever?
Speaker 0: And I think most likely it's not going to be two shows forever.
Speaker 0: We're going to, you know, geek nights has been, you know, it's the internets.
Speaker 0: We can do whatever we want.
Speaker 0: So, you know, uh, part of the plan is, you know, it's going to keep changing forever.
Speaker 0: It's going to change with the world.
Speaker 0: You know, if we suddenly, you know, I mean right now, video and audio or on the internets is, is what comes along.
Speaker 0: But you know, if people start getting like VR broadcasters or something, well, we're going to keep moving forward and changing things as our lives change and as technology change and as the world changes.
Speaker 0: So most likely geek nights is not going to stay the same forever.
Speaker 1: There's no way, but we're, we definitely plan to keep the radio show because I feel like audio only content needs to exist forever.
Speaker 1: And I want to, even if like it dies completely, I want to be one of those people who just like holds onto it and make sure it exists in some form forever.
Speaker 1: But I think there are other people like that too.
Speaker 1: I'm not too worried.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So someone asks, you know, why did we change it to two shows a week?
Speaker 0: I've noticed there've been a few questions that have come up in here.
Speaker 0: that were questions that are answered in episodes.
Speaker 0: And it's really strange because someone here says, why are PCFPS far superior to console FPS?
Speaker 0: We did a whole show on that, right?
Speaker 0: So wait a second though, by asking that question, that means this person knows we think PCFPS are superior.
Speaker 0: If they know that we think PCFPS are superior.
Speaker 1: Well it's not hard to know that.
Speaker 1: We say that like every episode.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Like I start every episode with, wow sucks.
Speaker 0: That means that they're, that means that they're listening.
Speaker 0: So shouldn't they have listened to the one where we said why?
Speaker 0: I mean, we said, you know, but someone over there is like, why did you change it to two episodes a week?
Speaker 0: Did you not listen to the episode where we talked about changing it to two shows a week?
Speaker 1: When we lived here, we watched like four movies a week.
Speaker 1: that just stopped happening with geek nights.
Speaker 1: But that wasn't the reason we switched.
Speaker 1: The reason was I loved Penn radio.
Speaker 1: It was like the best thing ever.
Speaker 0: And Scott loved Penn radio.
Speaker 0: And radio was good.
Speaker 1: And after when it started repeating itself, it was, yeah, but after like you get listener fatigue and I remember it got to the point where I listened to Penn radio every day and then it got like, I started not liking it even though the content was great.
Speaker 1: I just couldn't, it was like, it started grading on me.
Speaker 1: Kind of like if you listen to the same song over and over again, it starts grading to you.
Speaker 1: Geek nights has this kind of specific format.
Speaker 1: And if you listen to us every weeknight for a year, you're going to start getting rim and Scott fatigue and I would get rim and Scott fatigue.
Speaker 1: So we wanted to keep the show high energy, wanted to keep the show good.
Speaker 1: And I felt like if we kept doing four nights a week, the show was going to get tiresome and it would have died in the end.
Speaker 0: It also really helped that, you know, when we came, you know, when we were all tired doing the show after work, the show was, we didn't feel that the show was as great as it was.
Speaker 0: when, uh, you know, we were really excited about doing the show.
Speaker 0: And we also, you know, we sort of used up all our ideas and we're really, we're really scratching for ideas now even.
Speaker 1: Plus there were shows where we would be like so tired that we both had nothing and we'd argue for like an hour before the show about just stupid crap because we were so tired.
Speaker 1: Neither one of us actually wanted to do it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So yeah, so we're getting better shows.
Speaker 0: We're using up our ideas more slowly.
Speaker 1: Plus the website didn't come to fruition because Scott lost his job.
Speaker 0: It was pretty much like we were on our way.
Speaker 0: This website actually was designed a year ago at, uh, we, we started working on it.
Speaker 0: February of oh eight is when we actually really, really started working on it.
Speaker 0: So, you know, I just sort of had it done for quite a, you know, mostly done for quite a while and it still needs a little bit more polishing, you know?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: But a theory shadow, someone's a spamming in there.
Speaker 1: Check that out.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of people spamming.
Speaker 1: I've been, I've been not saying anything about it, but I'm, I'm proud that enough people have decided that they, they not only know about geek nights, but they want to come in and like just shit cock all over this.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of, I don't know, I'm more flattered by that than I am angry.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like, I don't care if they spam this stupid chat room.
Speaker 1: It doesn't bother me, but it's, it's sort of interesting that this is so important that it's, I want to give some props to a theory shadow in the forum.
Speaker 1: Because when I, you know, I moved out of colony at RIT for like six months to work at IBM and I just kept paying right at that time and Scott kind of lived there alone.
Speaker 1: And then I moved back and went to school for a year.
Speaker 1: Then I moved out for good and I lived out here working for IBM.
Speaker 0: But I was still at school for a few more, two more semesters, I think.
Speaker 1: Oh, geek nights live is apparently on the front page of Ustream right now.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: Way to go.
Speaker 0: Let's get some attention people.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so we had our friend Kevin who was like, he was one of the friends of the front row crew.
Speaker 1: Like we got with him a lot.
Speaker 1: He was, we met all these freshmen at RIT one year and they were all awesome.
Speaker 1: So we had like this cadre of awesome freshmen we were hanging out with.
Speaker 1: We were playing like D and D with them.
Speaker 1: We ran this awful D and D game.
Speaker 0: Remember that?
Speaker 0: That was like the worst D and D game.
Speaker 0: Which one was the awful one?
Speaker 1: The one where it was a pirate game.
Speaker 0: Oh, see that one, see that one could have actually been good.
Speaker 0: The problem is, is that we, we had so many players, right.
Speaker 0: That we sort of split up the GMing and like I would plan a little bit, but you were just sort of like, eh, off the cut, whatever.
Speaker 1: And it was totally conflicting.
Speaker 0: And when like, it was just like, uh, at a certain point and they're just like, oh, fuck.
Speaker 1: Plus we're always distracted by like Carla and all the people at our WAG.
Speaker 1: And we all, it was crazy, but Kevin was this cool guy and we lived with him.
Speaker 1: Well, Scott lived with him in a colony.
Speaker 1: He basically moved in with Scott, left all the furniture there and I moved away.
Speaker 1: And he pointed out that we, we have the loveseat from when we lived there.
Speaker 1: We left the couch because it was disgusting.
Speaker 1: It was white when we bought it.
Speaker 1: It was not white by the time we moved out.
Speaker 0: Kevin pointed out, there's the, so I can't, I'm going to move the camera cause it'll take a while to get it back in position.
Speaker 1: Kevin pointed out that they totally destroyed that couch with fire.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: That was the only solution to that couch.
Speaker 0: That was really, it was the only solution to that couch.
Speaker 0: That couch was awful.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's actually a somewhat serious question.
Speaker 0: He said with Easter fast approaching many atheists have families which celebrate it religiously.
Speaker 0: Would it be hypocritical for an atheist to join the festivities?
Speaker 0: I celebrate Christmas.
Speaker 1: I celebrate Hanukkah.
Speaker 0: I celebrate, you know, what's wrong with celebrating a holiday?
Speaker 0: I mean, it's just, you know, what's, I mean, are you Catholic if you celebrate, uh, St Patrick's day by, you know, I mean, what if someone is Irish and atheist and on St Patrick's day, they get drunk and eat the corn beef and cabbage and a green bagel.
Speaker 0: Is there something wrong with that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, that doesn't imply any irrational beliefs.
Speaker 0: It's not hurting anyone.
Speaker 0: So, you know, there's nothing wrong with, you know, ritualistic behavior as long as you recognize what you're doing and you know, you don't, uh, you know, let it become dogmatic and such, you know, I mean, it's, it's fun to do a lot of these things.
Speaker 0: That's why people do them, you know?
Speaker 1: Well, like Loganator pointed out, it's like being a Jew in culture only.
Speaker 1: I mean, you look at a lot of surveys and a lot of people who are Jewish ethnically or culturally, a lot of the younger ones at least, are not religiously Jewish, but they still keep the culture.
Speaker 1: And I know a lot of people who are atheists, but they keep the Catholic culture and they still are active in the church because they have friends there.
Speaker 0: And making share ornaments and you can all share and have a good time putting presents under the tree.
Speaker 0: Does that hurt anyone?
Speaker 0: Does that have any, you know, I mean, it's tied to a religious thing originally kind of, but who gets it?
Speaker 1: I guess the only as an atheist, you know, just the only thing that ever bothers me, the only thing hypocritical one is if you say you believe when you really don't.
Speaker 1: And I, that's the only thing that's hypocritical.
Speaker 1: What else can I say?
Speaker 0: Celebrate whatever holidays you want.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Do you make up your own?
Speaker 1: You can celebrate, you know, I mean, I've been, I've been to church several times in my life and the only thing I do is I don't kneel and stand and sit and pray because I don't believe any of that stuff, but I still attend and I'm polite.
Speaker 1: and I do, you know, actually I kind of like Catholic masses.
Speaker 1: I think they're cool because one, I went to a parochial school.
Speaker 1: It was all Latin mass.
Speaker 0: I mean, go to like a Reform Jewish temple, not an Orthodox one, go to Reform one.
Speaker 0: You going somewhere?
Speaker 1: I need a little more wine.
Speaker 0: And it's a fun time.
Speaker 0: They sing fun songs and do fun dances and all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: You know, it's good times.
Speaker 0: All right, let's, let's look for something else for people to talk to.
Speaker 1: You can handle this for a bit.
Speaker 1: I've been staring at these chats for a while.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: People are basically saying nothing.
Speaker 1: Well, there's been a lot of shit cockery going on in that forum.
Speaker 0: Oh, the stream is down.
Speaker 0: Internet's broke.
Speaker 0: Something, something people are saying.
Speaker 0: How is the stream down?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm going to take a look.
Speaker 0: I didn't do anything.
Speaker 0: I didn't do anything either.
Speaker 0: Oh, I guess it is down.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: Something happened.
Speaker 1: We'll bring it back up momentarily, even if we have to start a new one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it looks like a lot of people dropped the chat as soon as Easter came up.
Speaker 1: That's really interesting.
Speaker 0: Oh, I think it's working again.
Speaker 1: Might have been an internet blip on our end.
Speaker 1: I don't think it was on our end because we have a pretty sophisticated network in this house, actually.
Speaker 1: So how's it going?
Speaker 1: Is it working?
Speaker 1: No, no, it's not updating.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 1: Oh, now it's updating.
Speaker 0: OK, it's working again.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: It's interesting.
Speaker 0: You can see like these people coming in from like the front page of Ustream saying like these really horrible things.
Speaker 0: It's like what, you know.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 0: Look at that.
Speaker 1: It tells you a lot about the Internet.
Speaker 1: It's like as soon, well, kind of like.
Speaker 0: look at you.
Speaker 0: It's like you got 100 listeners, but then there's like this fluctuating number of...
Speaker 1: It's weird.
Speaker 1: I think what really illustrates it is YouTube comments.
Speaker 1: Like how come YouTube comments like they're... Who is posting YouTube comments?
Speaker 1: Oh, I guess I filled my wine glass while the stream was down, so it came back and my wine glass was full.
Speaker 0: Oh, we should have done it on purpose.
Speaker 1: That was... Oh, well.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: That's amazing, though, that... Who are all these people on the Internet who are just like...
Speaker 0: They really have nothing better to do?
Speaker 0: I mean, go play a video game.
Speaker 0: Seriously.
Speaker 0: That's... Instead of, you know, posting racial slurs in some random chat room.
Speaker 1: Not that I care.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're probably going to want to tweet us or chat us or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I'm looking at the chat.
Speaker 0: You can also... You can tweet Geek Nights or you can tweet APRECHE.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So someone asked what kind of wine I'm drinking.
Speaker 1: My favorite red wine is Chianti.
Speaker 1: I drink Chianti all the time.
Speaker 1: I don't know what else I can say other than that I really like Chianti.
Speaker 0: Someone says, "What animes are you
Speaker 0: watching?".
Speaker 1: We were trying to watch more Michio and Hachi.
Speaker 1: Well, we were trying to watch that, but there was a subtitle issue.
Speaker 0: I'm always trying to watch more Galaxy Express 3-9, but I found out they stopped Fansub me because Crunchyroll's got it.
Speaker 0: But I can't see enough of it on Crunchyroll without joining Crunchyroll.
Speaker 1: So it's like, what the hell?
Speaker 1: So apparently people really wanted me to be here without pants.
Speaker 1: You know, if we had the table taller, my idea was... Because this is what I wore to work today.
Speaker 1: My plan was just to take off the pants I wore to work and have boxers on.
Speaker 1: But you wouldn't be able to see because the table would have been covering it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I turned the sensor off, maybe I could turn it on.
Speaker 0: Maybe that'll help keep some of the spam down a little bit.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: How did the sensor work?
Speaker 0: Basically, you just turn it on and off like that.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it works or not, though.
Speaker 1: "What wines, liquors, mixed drinks do you recommend to a newbie at
Speaker 1: drinking?".
Speaker 1: So you're trying to get into drinking?
Speaker 1: Should we do a show on that, getting into being an alcoholic?
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't.
Speaker 1: Nah.
Speaker 1: Wow, look at everything censored now.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right?
Speaker 1: That's interesting.
Speaker 1: So now we just have a bunch of censored spam.
Speaker 1: Drink nights?
Speaker 1: If you want to try alcohol, try one of every classic, standard mixed drink.
Speaker 0: Yeah, go to the... I don't know enough about it, but I can tell you this is pretty much common sense.
Speaker 0: Go to a liquor store or the grocery store and buy wines or alcohols that have names you are familiar with.
Speaker 0: And then get one of everything, maybe in a small quantity at a low price.
Speaker 0: If there's something that you recognize the name of, you're never drinking any alcohol.
Speaker 1: Go drink a Budweiser.
Speaker 0: It probably doesn't taste good, but you try it and see what it tastes like.
Speaker 1: And then go and try...
Speaker 0: It's a Pilsner, I think, Budweiser?
Speaker 0: So I guess.
Speaker 0: then try another type of beer.
Speaker 0: Try... I don't know, what are the other names for them?
Speaker 1: I don't know, but you get my point, right?
Speaker 0: Try one of every type.
Speaker 0: See what they taste like.
Speaker 1: Try a whiskey, try a scotch, try a vodka.
Speaker 1: My real recommendation is find someone you know who drinks alcohol but does not get drunk.
Speaker 1: Like someone who actually enjoys alcohol.
Speaker 1: Like someone who has a cocktail at five o'clock.
Speaker 1: But not your friend who... Woo!
Speaker 1: With the red cups.
Speaker 1: And just tell them and ask them to make you a drink and they'll make you a drink and you'll find out if you like it or not.
Speaker 1: And tell them what you like or don't like about it and then they'll recommend something else.
Speaker 1: Like I give some to the Manhattan and they say, "Ah, it's too
Speaker 1: sweet.".
Speaker 1: Then I give them like a dry gin and tonic or a dry martini.
Speaker 1: That sort of thing.
Speaker 0: You can also... You probably want to go... If you're going to do stuff just like that comes in a can or a bottle, you can... You go to the grocery store, but if you want to try other stuff, you should probably go to a bar that has a good bartender with some friends and whatnot.
Speaker 1: Yes, go to a nice bar.
Speaker 1: Maybe either a...
Speaker 0: Not like a hotel bar.
Speaker 0: A place that actually is kind of crowded, which means it has a good quality bartender.
Speaker 0: If they do tricks, that also means they're good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it depends.
Speaker 0: It depends.
Speaker 1: You can tell if their tricks are... Just go to a bartender and say... Just tell them straight up, "I don't drink a lot.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: What would you recommend?
Speaker 1: Help me
Speaker 1: out.".
Speaker 1: Bartenders love nothing more than making a drink for you and telling you all about it.
Speaker 0: And if it tastes like rubbing alcohol, that means that they're trying to get you drunk as opposed to trying to make it taste good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, good drinks should taste good.
Speaker 1: If they don't taste good to you, you shouldn't be drinking alcohol unless you're trying to get drunk and then go nuts.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So people want to know when this is going to end.
Speaker 0: When do you want to end this?
Speaker 0: 8.30, 8.45, something like that?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: This is kind of fun.
Speaker 1: How long have we got to eat dinner?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, we're stopping at 9 at the latest.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you that.
Speaker 0: Alright, so before 9, this will be over.
Speaker 1: 9 Eastern Daylight Time.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 0: So yeah, just keep sending in comments and questions for us to answer and such.
Speaker 1: I'll answer one more alcohol question.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: My favorite mixed drink is a Manhattan on the Rocks with Jameson.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: You want to hit something?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: You got anything over there?
Speaker 1: Any thoughts on the Nintendo DSi?
Speaker 1: I don't care about it at all.
Speaker 0: The DSi is sort of a weird thing.
Speaker 0: It's a little bit thinner, I heard.
Speaker 0: The screen's a little bit bigger, I heard.
Speaker 0: It's got the SD slot and I guess you can download software, right?
Speaker 1: I think it's going to be big for homebrew.
Speaker 0: Well, they got to crack the slot.
Speaker 1: Someone's going to crack it.
Speaker 0: I mean, the homebrew cartridges, R4s and Cyclos and whatever, are actually a lot bigger than you think in the US.
Speaker 0: I saw just, you know, there's people in the city, when you go in the city on the subway and on the train, you see people who are not, they don't look like gamers and they have DSs or PSPs.
Speaker 0: They all have freaking, you know, crack pirate cards now.
Speaker 0: I hardly ever see anyone playing a real DS game.
Speaker 1: You know, it's weird how quickly it went from handheld games or unpiratable to all the pumpkins, pirate everything.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So I think that if they crack the SD slot on the DSi, I think that, you know, people who have no interest in GBA games are going to get DSIs and use the, just use SD cards instead of paying out for piracy cards, right?
Speaker 0: It's going to really hurt the piracy card business.
Speaker 0: I think you're going to see some people try to sell the piracy software, but someone's going to have one that's free and then no one's going to be able to sell it anymore.
Speaker 0: And so the whole business of selling Cyclos and selling R4s is going to go away because everyone's just going to put some software on an SD card and put it in that slot and that's going to be it, right?
Speaker 0: I also think that, you know, while buying and downloading software to the DS might be interesting at first and there might be a few really good things to get on there, I think that in the long run it's going to become
Speaker 1: more
Speaker 0: like what's on the Wii and hardly ever going to the Wii shop anymore because it's like, you know, the virtual console is overpriced and there's barely any good
Speaker 1: WiiWare games.
Speaker 1: They're not going to let you if you bought Mario 1 on the Wii.
Speaker 1: I don't think they're going to let you just also have it on your DS.
Speaker 1: That would be nice.
Speaker 1: That might be good.
Speaker 1: That would be the killer app, but they're not going to do it.
Speaker 1: They'll make more money by reselling again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're not cool.
Speaker 1: I feel like most of the features on the DSi are aimed at the Japanese market and not at the American market, to be honest.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is definitely aimed at the Japanese.
Speaker 0: I think that, you know, the lack of a GBA slot on it and the fact that it isn't significantly better.
Speaker 0: I mean, the DS Lite was a huge improvement over the DS, which is a huge improvement over the SP, which is a huge improvement over the GBA.
Speaker 0: Notice the GBA Micro didn't really do so well because it wasn't a huge improvement over the, you know, SP.
Speaker 0: I mean, it had a better screen, you know, but it was kind of small and it only had GBA games where the SP could play anything.
Speaker 1: It would have done a lot better if it had come out a lot earlier, I think.
Speaker 1: I might have bought one because I was still playing a ton of GBA games, like, all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think if the DSi had been the DS, it would have helped out a lot, but I really don't have a lot of interest in the, you know, DSi.
Speaker 1: I mean... All right, wow, there's a lot of questions here now.
Speaker 1: CycloDS works on the DSi.
Speaker 0: That's interesting.
Speaker 0: I guess that'll hold people over until there's a non-hard worker.
Speaker 1: I got a bunch of quickies.
Speaker 1: Any chance on the Seinfeld Thursday episode?
Speaker 1: That's an easy one.
Speaker 0: That's a good Thursday episode.
Speaker 0: We'll do a Thursday episode on Seinfeld.
Speaker 0: We're gonna watch a few more, just refresh our memories, watch some episodes, and we'll be good to go.
Speaker 1: Favorite grinding games.
Speaker 1: back when grinding games weren't an issue for us?
Speaker 1: I kind of always hated the grind, but I played The Realm, the first MMO.
Speaker 0: It's actually weird that back in the day, I didn't hate the grind.
Speaker 1: Don't hate the game, hate the player.
Speaker 0: Because I had so much free time that the grinding didn't bother me.
Speaker 0: What bothered me was random encounters, and what bothered me is an imbalanced grind.
Speaker 0: Like, I would play MUDs back in the day.
Speaker 0: There was one MUD I played, and it's like, as soon as I got to level 100-something, it was at this point where it was, like, too hard to kill the next hardest bad guy, but the bad guy that I could kill didn't give me enough experience to level up quickly.
Speaker 0: And World of Warcraft solves that problem.
Speaker 0: You level up nice and smooth, straight up, and you never have that frustration.
Speaker 0: So the thing is, now I have the problem of my time is limited.
Speaker 0: So now I'm frustrated by any grind, even if it's a smooth grind.
Speaker 0: But back in the day, any smooth grind was all good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know AKA.
Speaker 0: That's a crazy MUD.
Speaker 1: Plus, single player games, the grind... I guess there's the difference between leveling up in the course of a game versus being forced to grind through... Oh, that's a good question.
Speaker 1: Who designed the new Geek Nights logo?
Speaker 0: Oh, I should do this.
Speaker 0: That's not a new logo, first off.
Speaker 0: Okay, so the Geek Nights logo is not super new.
Speaker 0: There is a person named Brandon Kramer.
Speaker 0: His website...
Speaker 1: Brando K.
Speaker 0: Brando K. Yeah, if you search for that on Google, you should be able to find this guy.
Speaker 0: He's a man.
Speaker 0: He is the awesomest man.
Speaker 0: I think now, the last I heard from him, he's writing for AdultSwim.com, I think.
Speaker 0: I don't think he works on shows yet, but I think he was writing for the website or something like that.
Speaker 0: So he's a pretty awesome dude.
Speaker 0: We met at Otakon and some conventions.
Speaker 0: He's got awesome art skills, and he did some awesome arts that we bought off of him.
Speaker 0: Since we liked him so much, we asked him to design these logos for us, and he did so.
Speaker 0: We had our friend Kat Lee, who is a professional graphic designer, design the website around those logos.
Speaker 0: So she took the black thing and put the white and blue over it and did all that other stuff.
Speaker 1: This banner, I threw this together with a demo copy of Photoshop, just barely.
Speaker 1: I got it printed, and it worked.
Speaker 1: okay, but it's a little too big, and I just took the logo and put a shadow on it.
Speaker 1: We're making much better logos and banners and everything now.
Speaker 0: Someone says, "What do you think the ratio of girl-to-guy listeners
Speaker 0: is?".
Speaker 1: I feel like there are more girls than guys.
Speaker 0: I can't really tell, because I think the girls are less likely to interact.
Speaker 1: But I feel like the girls that do interact, they always have a lot more to contribute than the guys.
Speaker 0: If you just pick out the super hardcore Geek Nights fans, I think maybe half of them are female, and it's about half to half.
Speaker 0: When you look at the forum as a whole, like all registrations in the forum, it's more of maybe a 30-70 or a 40-60.
Speaker 1: But look at who has sent us awesome fan art or awesome things.
Speaker 1: It's all girls, like Ro and Vega and Mancun.
Speaker 0: The best fans are always girl fans.
Speaker 1: Mancun is so cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the guy fans are not as cool.
Speaker 0: Sorry guys.
Speaker 1: Yes, we know a lot of you contribute, but...
Speaker 0: There are plenty of girl geeks out there, and they are the awesome.
Speaker 1: More Final Thoughts?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we can do more Final Thoughts episodes.
Speaker 0: We can do more Final Thoughts.
Speaker 0: We have to watch some more shows.
Speaker 1: What is your opinion on Super Dolphy?
Speaker 1: Super Dolphy is a hobby.
Speaker 1: You can be into that.
Speaker 0: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: You're making little dolls.
Speaker 0: Usually you buy the dolls, but you do the hair and you do the clothing, and there's a craft to it.
Speaker 0: It's a very respectable and cool hobby.
Speaker 0: It's just as cool as any other arts and crafts kind of hobby.
Speaker 0: It's just sort of creepy.
Speaker 0: Some of the people in that community treat their doll-fies as if they are real people.
Speaker 0: Or they act in a very strange way.
Speaker 0: That is sort of kind of scary, and it turns people away.
Speaker 0: There's nothing wrong with the hobby itself.
Speaker 0: There's just a certain creepiness in that community.
Speaker 0: Sort of like the furries.
Speaker 0: I have nothing against someone who gets jollies from whatever they get.
Speaker 1: Or even more to the point, I'll admit I really like a lot of anthropomorphic art.
Speaker 0: Looney Tunes is anthropomorphic.
Speaker 0: Disney is anthropomorphic.
Speaker 0: Technically, right?
Speaker 0: There's nothing wrong with anthropomorphic art inherently.
Speaker 0: It's art.
Speaker 0: It's just that there's a particular community, and a portion of that community acts in a creepy way.
Speaker 0: So that turns people off of that hobby because they associate this creepy behavior with the hobby.
Speaker 0: If you're a smart person like us, you can learn to disassociate these things and recognize them for what they are.
Speaker 0: They're asking about Conficker.
Speaker 1: We could do a show on it.
Speaker 1: Honestly, no competent tech company or firm or person had any issue with Conficker.
Speaker 0: People saw it coming so far in advance that either the person who put it out there screwed up, or the person out there chickened out.
Speaker 0: It was a good example of, "Look, we can see this virus coming in advance, and we can take care of it, and now nothing happened, and everything's all
Speaker 0: cool.".
Speaker 0: For now, we're ahead of these people a little bit, and it's good stuff.
Speaker 1: There's an interesting question here.
Speaker 1: "Do you think the FRC was inevitable, or was it a product of RIT's
Speaker 1: environment?".
Speaker 1: Is a product inevitable?
Speaker 1: I don't know if it was RIT specifically, but I think there's a certain kind of environment that can foster the sort of relationship that the front-room crew formed that isn't necessarily possible in other environments.
Speaker 1: I think it was a combination of the fact that RIT is a self-selected set.
Speaker 1: The majority of the people there have very similar interests in a lot of ways.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's true about a lot of other colleges, but not everyone who goes to RIT has this kind of thing happen.
Speaker 1: True, but at the same time, notice how all the people in the front-room crew were all into gaming, all into anime.
Speaker 1: We all had very similar interests.
Speaker 0: I think what it was is you went to the gaming club, and you saw some people there.
Speaker 0: You went to the anime club, and you saw different people there.
Speaker 1: We had friends in the gaming club that didn't join the front-room crew, but we totally had the same gaming interests.
Speaker 0: The front-room crew.
Speaker 0: people were in both independently of each other.
Speaker 0: It was sort of like you had the self-selected sample of like-minded people, RIT students, and then you had a sample of people, people who went to the gaming club, and then you had people who went to the anime club, and then there were people who went to both.
Speaker 0: There was this even smaller group of people that saw each other a lot, and that set-up, anyone who is socially adaptable, didn't scare others away, was friendly and got along well and had discussions with each other, and saw each other frequently.
Speaker 0: There were people that I would just see while I was at RIT.
Speaker 0: I would see them every day.
Speaker 0: Like Mitch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you see someone every day, you're going to talk to them, you're going to get to know them, especially over the course of multiple years, it's going to happen.
Speaker 0: You just had to be the person who's in that situation.
Speaker 1: Plus, it was a self-selected sample at RIT, and then it's a self-selected sample from that of all these different hobbies, and everyone in the crew, like Scott said, kind of was in all of those groups.
Speaker 1: I mean, we had a lot of friends in the gaming club.
Speaker 1: They didn't watch really anime or anything, there weren't any other things, so they didn't really become a crew.
Speaker 0: Imagine this, what if you're a Geek Nights listener, supposedly, unless you're one of these YouTube stragglers, and let's say you're getting along in this community with other Geek Nights listeners.
Speaker 0: And then independently of that, you listen to some other podcast, and you find someone who you didn't recommend to them this other podcast, they just happen to also listen to that same other podcast as you.
Speaker 0: So now you're in the same community with this person, you're in two different communities with the same person, independently, you didn't tell them to go to this other one.
Speaker 0: So you're going to probably keep bumping into this person frequently, you're going to get together with them, and it's going to be, you know, it's going to happen.
Speaker 1: Plus, I think the isolation had something to do with the fact that RIT was this like self contained unit, it was like we were on a spaceship going somewhere, we were pretty much cut off from the world because we had one car among like 20 people.
Speaker 1: So we couldn't leave campus, we had to stay on campus or walk or like take the bus as a group.
Speaker 1: And we spent a lot of time like hanging out as a group together in the lounges just doing nothing.
Speaker 1: As a group, because there's nothing else to do, we had no money, we had nothing, we played games together.
Speaker 0: All right, some people are asking about what is the breakdown of the OS's the listeners use?
Speaker 0: They probably mostly use Windows, a bunch of Mac, and I know there's a bunch of Linux people out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know, there's no such thing as OS.
Speaker 1: I got all three in this room right now, all right.
Speaker 1: Windows, Linux, Mac.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you know, there's no OS bias here, and I really don't care.
Speaker 1: Whatever OS does what you need.
Speaker 1: That's the only question.
Speaker 0: It's like saying, oh, do you know more listeners use hammers or more use screwdrivers?
Speaker 0: It's like, when you got a nail, use the hammer.
Speaker 0: When you got a screw, use a screwdriver.
Speaker 1: Kind of like the browser question.
Speaker 1: I mean, everyone seems to use Firefox or Chrome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, oh, we need to do some arts.
Speaker 0: Well, let's get some Macs to make the artists happy.
Speaker 0: Oh, we need to do some programming.
Speaker 0: Let's get some Linuxes, you know.
Speaker 0: Oh, we need to play some games.
Speaker 0: Let's get some Windows.
Speaker 1: No, this banner is not always up here.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: We put this banner up here just now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't want to pan the camera, but the living room is pretty big, and there's like, over there is like the piano and the other loveseat and all this other stuff.
Speaker 1: And over there is all the board games, and over there is all the DVDs, and around the corner there is the table for snacks, and we have people over.
Speaker 1: And then there's the big window and the extra couch.
Speaker 0: They want us to talk about the James Randi YouTube thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically, they took all, Randi got banned from YouTube, all their videos, and the rumor is that it has something to do with Oprah Winfrey, but this rumor, I haven't seen any confirmation of it or anything like that.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing, though.
Speaker 1: I know that the JREF would not have taken these down.
Speaker 0: No, it was definitely YouTube pushed them out.
Speaker 1: I'm filled with righteous indignation, but what can I do?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, everyone go write a letter to YouTube or send an angry email.
Speaker 1: Actually, I'm sure this will be in news next time we do a Monday show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it'll almost definitely be in news once we have more reliable information about it.
Speaker 0: But right now, it's just a bunch of rumors and indignation, so what are you going to do about it?
Speaker 0: Alright, let's see, how many people in something, something?
Speaker 1: Have you ever tried a banana dipped in pizza sauce?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: That's a Douglas or a Dougwatcher.
Speaker 0: I like that.
Speaker 0: Mad props to the Dougwatcher.
Speaker 1: What, that guy?
Speaker 1: Yeah, whoever asked for that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that guy's been asking a lot of the good questions.
Speaker 0: Oh, has he?
Speaker 1: Oh, that's Kevin!
Speaker 1: That's the theory shadow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's a Dougwatcher, alright.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we kind of fell out of touch with you, Kevin.
Speaker 0: What's going on?
Speaker 1: I should probably make you into the secret for him, but you probably already are.
Speaker 1: Or you should have been and I forgot, so remind me.
Speaker 1: You're not looking for another question?
Speaker 0: GN has been around for so long, there's an old school, new school line now?
Speaker 1: I don't know about that.
Speaker 1: We've only been around, what, 2005 we started.
Speaker 0: We're not popular, really.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's only 100 people in this chat, Leo Laporta's thousands, so we're not popular enough.
Speaker 0: I mean, if you start listening now, right, if we ever do become popular, you're going to be old school stuff.
Speaker 1: We have between, statistically, one and five thousand regular listeners.
Speaker 1: And less than ten thousand, probably, at most, at absolute maximum, six or seven thousand occasional listeners.
Speaker 0: That's crazy.
Speaker 1: That's like the absolute, like, statistical, it's hard to tell, so.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was in before.
Speaker 0: it was cool.
Speaker 0: Guess what, it's still not cool.
Speaker 0: It's not cool yet.
Speaker 1: So you're all in before it's cool.
Speaker 1: Someone asked, do you get anything, quote, has Geek Nights fame brought you any significant benefits to your lives?
Speaker 1: E.g.,
Speaker 1: free stuff, gifts, girls, all of those.
Speaker 0: We've gotten, see the thing is, there are other podcasts out there that do a much better job of getting listener gifts.
Speaker 1: Well, we don't shoot for it, we don't try, other than...
Speaker 0: Well, they don't shoot for it either, but they behave in a way that gets it going on.
Speaker 0: For example, I listen to Comic Geek speak, and these guys get tons of stuff from listeners.
Speaker 0: And the reason they get tons of stuff from listeners is because they always give back to the listeners, big time.
Speaker 0: They constantly play voicemails on the show, read emails, they're constantly giving mad props to people.
Speaker 0: When their listeners do stuff, they always pimp them, even if the listeners are doing stuff that's not the greatest stuff in the world.
Speaker 0: And as a result, they get a lot back from the listeners, always giving them gifts and helping them out and all that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: We don't play voicemails, we don't do a lot of email reading.
Speaker 0: Geek facts are very, very rare.
Speaker 1: The only time I ever, I guess I feel like I took advantage of the listeners, not really, but I really wanted one of these, and I couldn't get one at PAX.
Speaker 1: I tried so hard, but I couldn't get one.
Speaker 1: And four listeners offered them to me, and two listeners sent them to me.
Speaker 1: I still owe the people who sent these to me a gift box that I kind of half put together and just never finished.
Speaker 1: But other than this, I don't know, I haven't paid for a convention since 2002.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not paying for conventions is very nice.
Speaker 0: But I mean, even without Geek Nights, we probably could have built up panels and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: I mean, we were doing panels since 2002 at anime conventions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we were doing panels long before Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: I get press stuff, like anytime I want press access to something, I just get it at this point, which is pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I would do another hate mail show, someone's asking about a hate mail show, but we haven't got any hate mail.
Speaker 0: Not in a while.
Speaker 0: I don't think we've ever, the only real hate mail we've gotten was
Speaker 0: V.I.V.,
Speaker 0: you know, what's his name?
Speaker 1: Beefy?
Speaker 0: Admiral Beefy, who had a voicemail on Anime World Order.
Speaker 0: that was to us.
Speaker 0: He was pissed off at us, and he was just a ranting lunatic.
Speaker 1: I was hard to tell.
Speaker 1: To this day, I can't tell if that was a joke or not.
Speaker 1: Either that's a scary guy or that guy's really good.
Speaker 1: Like, that guy should do a radio show.
Speaker 0: Someone wants to know what are the chances of a teething a geek talk?
Speaker 1: Geek talks, I just don't have time for, to be honest.
Speaker 1: Emily's in them off and on.
Speaker 1: The one time I was in one, Emily was in my room instead of being in her apartment, and I happened to walk into the room, so I stepped in for a bit, but I don't have time.
Speaker 1: I don't even talk to my own friends, let alone you guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, you know, we do, we communicate with you in the forums, we communicate with you with stuff like this, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, the geek talk is for listener solidarity.
Speaker 0: It's not, it's not for us.
Speaker 1: I read, we read every email we get, but we don't have time to respond to them all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, I mean, that's, that's how it's gonna be.
Speaker 0: Alright, let's see.
Speaker 1: I think it's winded up.
Speaker 1: Now, while the banner is not always up here, when we lived in Colony, we duct taped DDR pads to the floor.
Speaker 1: Those were there pretty much as long as we lived there, until we moved out at the end of that summer.
Speaker 0: That's a complicated question, I want to answer that.
Speaker 1: That's a really complicated question that would make a really good show.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 1: I mean, do a show on that.
Speaker 1: I'm sure everyone has seen it.
Speaker 0: Rims had his eyebrows trimmed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I had a unibrow forever, and eventually Emily convinced me to pluck this middle part.
Speaker 1: It hurts so much!
Speaker 1: Good God, I cry every time I do it.
Speaker 0: You should just go back to the unibrow.
Speaker 1: I should.
Speaker 1: I am so hot.
Speaker 1: On Hot or Not, back in the day, when that was the popular thing, I ended up with an average of, I think, 8.9.
Speaker 1: I haven't cut my hair in a year and a half.
Speaker 0: You should probably cut it soon, it's getting a little, uh...
Speaker 1: It's getting kind of raggedy in the end now.
Speaker 1: Uh, yes, I have piercings.
Speaker 0: We don't have tattoos, though, I don't think.
Speaker 1: Nah.
Speaker 1: I've considered tattoos often, the only reason I never got one was that they don't look good enough yet, in my opinion.
Speaker 1: Like, they're not there.
Speaker 1: The technology is not there fully.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Uh, I would, I would like tattoos.
Speaker 0: The main problem I have with a tattoo is that it's irreversible, right?
Speaker 0: And I just, I don't like to do anything that I can't undo, you know?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, I'm willing to try all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 0: But anything that has a permanent effect is sort of, like, probably a bad idea to do that so early in life.
Speaker 0: If I could get it...
Speaker 1: 'Cause then you're gonna have to live with that effect forever.
Speaker 1: If I could get a clear ink that I could just, like, plug a USB stick in my arm and change the picture.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: My whole body would be covered in tattoos.
Speaker 0: I would, I would just, uh, you know, if I could digitally load, like, JPEGs into my arm, I would do that all the time.
Speaker 0: I would, you know, I would turn it blank, you know, most of the time.
Speaker 0: But, like, if I would, you know, I would have, like, a default one, or maybe if my mood changed, I would change.
Speaker 0: I would do that, it would be awesome, you know?
Speaker 0: You know, putting art on your body is totally great, but...
Speaker 1: You're wrong, whoever said that's not gonna get that advanced.
Speaker 1: They have already designed tattoos that could be changed in real time.
Speaker 1: It's just the problem is that the technology's not there yet.
Speaker 1: Within ten years, we will have tattoos that you can just change with some sort of light device.
Speaker 1: Hopefully.
Speaker 1: I'm so sure.
Speaker 0: Some of us who play Resident Evil 5, what system do I have that can play Resident Evil 5?
Speaker 0: We have a Wii, and we have computers.
Speaker 1: What's under the TV?
Speaker 1: A Wii, a Switch, a Roku, an amplifier, and a Mac Mini?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we would need a 360 or a PS3 or something.
Speaker 0: Is Resident Evil 5 for the Wii?
Speaker 0: I don't think it is.
Speaker 1: Oh, there are a whole bunch of good questions that just passed by real quick.
Speaker 0: If I would lose a limb, would I have a weapon and a small computer built in?
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I lose a limb, I'm going all out.
Speaker 0: There's a great TED Talk with this lady who has no legs, and talking about how her prosthetics actually give her superpowers, because she can switch them up to ones that have different utilities, so she can be taller or shorter or whatever.
Speaker 0: I would totally be the same way.
Speaker 0: If I had to replace some part of my body with a prosthetic, it would be loaded with awesomeness.
Speaker 1: Kevin said, "You keep forgetting to add me to the secret forum.
Speaker 1: I'd be more in touch if I had travel
Speaker 1: money.".
Speaker 1: I'll add you to the secret forum.
Speaker 1: You deserve to be there.
Speaker 0: I just keep forgetting.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, Mega Man is fully robotic, but, you know, he's not a...
Speaker 1: He's like Tetsuan Adam.
Speaker 0: Stop asking the difficult question that requires an episode to answer.
Speaker 0: We want the short questions that we can answer in a few sentences.
Speaker 1: Favorite comedians?
Speaker 1: I always liked George Carlin because he, I think, had a big effect on American culture.
Speaker 0: I like Lewis Black.
Speaker 1: He makes me roll the most.
Speaker 1: I've met Lewis Black twice.
Speaker 0: We talked about OnLive on our show yesterday.
Speaker 1: I really like Eddie Izzard.
Speaker 1: Laser guitar?
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think we're petering out here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we are petering a little bit.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of good questions, but they're scrolling by too fast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's give, like, five or ten more minutes and then we'll meet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're gonna wind this down.
Speaker 1: I gotta eat dinner.
Speaker 1: I got work tomorrow, so...
Speaker 0: Yeah, I actually have to interview tomorrow in the city that I have to go to.
Speaker 1: I'll admit, I haven't found any new comedians that I like.
Speaker 0: There are a few, if you go to College Humor, you watch, they do stand-up videos on there, and most of them are bad, but once in a while, they're pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just, it's tough to be a good comedian.
Speaker 1: Like, maybe one out of a million comedians is worth listening to.
Speaker 1: Now, I'm not telling you about the secret forum.
Speaker 1: Someone asked here, "Will there ever be official Geek Nights parties at summer
Speaker 1: conventions?".
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: I'm done with that.
Speaker 1: My days of running parties at conventions are over.
Speaker 1: It is so much, Geek Nights takes a tenth of the work that convention parties take.
Speaker 1: I will never have time for that again.
Speaker 0: If you want more Geek Profiles episodes, I've seen that go by a few times.
Speaker 0: We've been trying, I wanted to do some more, but the thing is, Rim always goes, you know, it's usually the day of that we think to do it.
Speaker 1: And I gotta get up at like 4.30 the next morning and go to work, so...
Speaker 0: So we'd have to record it in advance or something like that, you know?
Speaker 0: We couldn't record it on the Thursday.
Speaker 1: If you presented the opportunity, who would you apprentice under?
Speaker 1: Robert Koo, I just want that man to tell me what to do.
Speaker 0: That's a good one, that's a good one.
Speaker 0: Who would I apprentice under?
Speaker 1: James Randi, I would love to take--.
Speaker 1: If my job could be to take over the JREF, I would do that without question or thought.
Speaker 0: That's a good one.
Speaker 1: I would dedicate my life to that.
Speaker 1: I might app--.
Speaker 0: See, the thing is, do I want to apprentice under someone who has skills in something I don't have?
Speaker 0: That way I can learn something new and be awesome at it?
Speaker 0: Or do I want to apprentice under a programmer and then explode my programming awesomeness all over the place?
Speaker 0: You know?
Speaker 0: I think that's the real decision.
Speaker 0: If I could pick a dead person, I would apprentice under DaVinci, because that would be the easiest.
Speaker 0: Maybe Imhotep.
Speaker 1: Depends if he really designed the pyramid or not.
Speaker 1: If he did, yes.
Speaker 1: If he didn't, no.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't say Alexander the Great, because he kind of just took over the stuff his daddy did.
Speaker 1: He didn't do anything interesting.
Speaker 1: What's for dinner?
Speaker 1: We don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we didn't eat dinner yet.
Speaker 0: Try to get a pizza somewhere?
Speaker 1: Actually, that pizza place down the road went out of business.
Speaker 1: There's a sign reopening again as a pizza place.
Speaker 1: And I was looking at it like,
Speaker 1: "Eh?".
Speaker 1: And this Mexican guy walked over and he had his daughter.
Speaker 1: And he was like, "Yeah, I bought this place.
Speaker 1: I'm opening a pizza
Speaker 1: place.".
Speaker 1: And I was like, "Good luck, man.
Speaker 1: I will try your pizza.
Speaker 0: Good
Speaker 0: luck.".
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: Let's try this place on Beacon Main Street.
Speaker 0: We should actually just drive over there and get slices, I think.
Speaker 1: I want to eat at Poppy's, but I don't think they're open this late.
Speaker 0: No, this is the Nova Roma place.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but Poppy's, it's just burgers.
Speaker 0: We could try there, too.
Speaker 0: Actually, isn't the sushi place open late?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it is.
Speaker 1: Well, we learned that the Charlie Brown's is open till one.
Speaker 0: Rym said he figured out how to do a Skype call-in.
Speaker 0: The big problem with doing a Skype call-in show, which we would really like to do, actually, is the screening.
Speaker 0: We would need a set-up for someone else off-camera to screen the call.
Speaker 1: I can do it.
Speaker 1: What we would probably do is do it on a Saturday morning sometime, and then we'd edit it and put it on the show.
Speaker 1: So you'd hear it not live, but there would be a live equivalent on Ustream, I guess.
Speaker 1: Kind of like this.
Speaker 0: It would basically be just like this, only we'd have some buttons where you'd be like, "Next caller," and you would hear the voice of the caller.
Speaker 1: And I'm not going to edit this too much for tomorrow.
Speaker 0: And we wouldn't be paying attention to the chat pretty much at all.
Speaker 0: We would only be paying attention to the caller.
Speaker 1: If we do a call-in show, I would heavily edit it.
Speaker 1: I don't listen to any podcasts anymore.
Speaker 0: I don't listen to any gaming podcasts anymore.
Speaker 1: I listen to It's All Politics from NPR.
Speaker 1: I listen to Dave and Joel every now and then.
Speaker 1: And I listen to...
Speaker 0: Actually, stop listening to Dave and Joel.
Speaker 1: Anime World Order, occasionally.
Speaker 0: Not that I didn't like them.
Speaker 0: I just didn't.
Speaker 0: I listen to Anime World Order, Twit, ESPN, Floss Weekly.
Speaker 0: And I'm watching, like, TED videos, right?
Speaker 0: It's a video podcast, technically.
Speaker 0: I got the Onion video podcast, not the audio one.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's really good.
Speaker 0: It is really good.
Speaker 1: Geek Profile of Dave Riley and Joel White.
Speaker 1: In the years we've been podcasting and been kind of internet friends with Dave Riley, I have had maybe 15 minutes of total contiguous conversation with that man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's actually surprisingly difficult to talk to for a significant amount of time.
Speaker 1: I mean, I love Dave Riley, but he is scatterbrained.
Speaker 1: I think he said he has ADHD.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I cannot have a consistent conversation with him for any period of time.
Speaker 1: I've tried.
Speaker 1: I like him, though.
Speaker 0: One day, I will go to the San Diego Comic-Con before I die.
Speaker 0: Most likely.
Speaker 1: As a sysadmin, are there any tools you rely upon heavily?
Speaker 0: SSH.
Speaker 1: V.I.?
Speaker 0: ?
Speaker 0: V.I.
Speaker 0: and SSH.
Speaker 1: Uh, tail-f?
Speaker 0: That's not a tool.
Speaker 1: Tail-f pipe grep something?
Speaker 0: Grep, I guess, maybe.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No, seriously.
Speaker 1: What I rely upon primarily is tail-f pipe grep some regular expression.
Speaker 0: Why don't you use, like, um... Oh, there's, like, a... Is it called, like, super tail or something?
Speaker 1: No, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 1: I say tail-f.
Speaker 1: We actually have our own proprietary tail that will... Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: We have all our system demons, and if you just type the name of our demon, it will tail whatever instance of that demon I want.
Speaker 0: That's a good one.
Speaker 1: And I can... It's all alias-powered, or... I can also do an equivalent of this.
Speaker 1: that will basically, on its own, go back through the logs an arbitrary amount of time and find certain... We have demon... We have log channels.
Speaker 1: So, like, channel three, like, every line that says 03 is for us.
Speaker 1: 10 is for, like, customer support, so I can see what everyone else is seeing.
Speaker 0: Okay, so someone's asking best Firefox add-on, right?
Speaker 0: I want to talk about this.
Speaker 0: This is something that keeps coming up, right?
Speaker 0: People will come up and they'll ask me, you know, "What are some good Firefox
Speaker 0: add-ons?".
Speaker 0: "I just got an iPhone.
Speaker 0: What apps should I
Speaker 0: install?".
Speaker 0: You know, these sorts of questions, right?
Speaker 0: You know, "What are some really good
Speaker 0: apps?".
Speaker 0: You know, "What are some really good widgets for OS X
Speaker 0: dashboard?"
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: This is the wrong question to ask, right?
Speaker 0: You do not think of things in this direction.
Speaker 0: "What apps do I
Speaker 0: install?".
Speaker 0: "Bad, wet...".
Speaker 0: No, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: What you should do is instead say, "What do I
Speaker 0: need?".
Speaker 0: That's the question you should ask.
Speaker 0: "What do I need that I do not
Speaker 0: have?"
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: As soon as you figure out what you need that you do not have, then you can go and find an app that satisfies the need.
Speaker 0: Don't go around just installing a whole bunch of apps just because they're cool or whatever, right?
Speaker 0: Think of what you need and then meet those needs with appropriate tools.
Speaker 0: Don't go get this giant toolbox full of tools you're never going to use and are just cluttering up your iPhone or your Firefox, right?
Speaker 1: Don't think in that direction.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I use three.
Speaker 1: Adblock, Delicious, and Farkit.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: I use Adblock, Delicious, and, like, you know, there's some... I use a lot of developer ones, like, you know, Web Development Toolbar and Firebug, but those are only for development, so most people don't need those.
Speaker 1: Someone's asking, "What language of
Speaker 1: choice?".
Speaker 1: Use whatever language fits whatever task you're doing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just like we said with operating systems.
Speaker 0: Programming languages are tools.
Speaker 1: A real programmer, it's not a matter of what languages you know.
Speaker 1: It's a matter of you know how to program.
Speaker 1: If you do, you can use any language.
Speaker 0: I can use any object-oriented programming language.
Speaker 0: If you came up with a new object-oriented programming language today and there was a book about it, a documentation that was good, I could read that documentation and write a program in that language just right away.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't have any problem with it whatsoever, you know?
Speaker 0: I don't have to learn a new language.
Speaker 0: The big differences are syntax, right, and libraries and those sorts of things.
Speaker 0: As long as I have documentation, it's all good.
Speaker 0: So figure out what your project is, what are you trying to make, and then find the best, you know, language or framework that does what you need to do, and you'll find.
Speaker 0: on different projects you're going to use a different language, you're going to use a different framework, a different library, and that's how it goes.
Speaker 0: So learn the fundamentals of programming, and then you should be able to use whatever tool you're going to need.
Speaker 0: You mean when you're a carpenter, you don't just say, "What tool do you learn how to use?
Speaker 0: I learned how to use the
Speaker 0: hammer.".
Speaker 0: Well, when it comes time to screw, right, it's not going to work out.
Speaker 0: Carpenters learn how to use any tool, right?
Speaker 0: If you gave a carpenter a brand new carpeting tool, he wouldn't have to, you know, learn how to use it.
Speaker 0: He can just sort of look at it and intuit, you know, what to do with it, because he's a carpenter.
Speaker 0: Unless it's the whole hog.
Speaker 0: He knows how to carpet.
Speaker 1: If it's the whole hog, you might have trouble.
Speaker 0: Maybe, but you see what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: We've said this many times before.
Speaker 1: Yep, someone has a good comment.
Speaker 1: You guys, it's not really a question.
Speaker 1: It's just, it's a thank you to us.
Speaker 1: So you guys gave me some really valuable and honest advice when I was stressing over exams.
Speaker 1: Just want to send my thanks.
Speaker 1: See?
Speaker 1: I guess people have noticed this.
Speaker 1: I brought it down.
Speaker 1: I thought I bought this at an Otakon a while ago, and I just, I think it's the cutest thing ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Rim has sort of this thing where when he knows he's going to be on camera, he sort of like intentionally does corny things.
Speaker 0: So he explicitly like intentionally brought that downstairs.
Speaker 1: I collect plushies.
Speaker 0: I have a bigger plushie collection than Rim does.
Speaker 0: See, now you've got him going.
Speaker 0: He's going to start a, I might do freelance work.
Speaker 0: I don't really know what I'm going to do at all.
Speaker 0: So if you have, if you want me to do freelance work, if you have some work for me, you know, call me up, and I'll, you know, we can see what goes on.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 0: Now we have a plushie fest.
Speaker 1: So these are not all of them, but these are the best ones.
Speaker 1: I got to, I got to bring these up.
Speaker 1: This is the, I have the Hachiroku from Initial D. I really like this.
Speaker 0: That's a pillow, I think, technically.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's also a stuffed thing.
Speaker 1: The story of how I got, this Cactuar was not easy to get.
Speaker 1: These are now common again, but there was a time when these were rare as fuck.
Speaker 1: And there was almost a fight, but I got it.
Speaker 1: The dragon from Brave Story.
Speaker 1: I cannot express how cute I think this is.
Speaker 1: This is possibly the cutest thing I've ever seen in my life.
Speaker 1: And the Tachiko.
Speaker 1: One more needs to be said.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I got a whole bunch upstairs.
Speaker 0: I got, I have a...
Speaker 1: Well, you have that poly wag.
Speaker 0: I have a poly wag.
Speaker 0: That was, oh god, I think it's a poly whirl technically.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, I guess it is.
Speaker 0: I've got a chicken from like Cow and Chicken.
Speaker 0: I've got a Charmander.
Speaker 0: I've got Cthulhu.
Speaker 0: I've got Calcifer.
Speaker 0: I've got... The Calcifer.
Speaker 0: Oh, right, that Kitaro with also his dad.
Speaker 0: Kitaro with his dad.
Speaker 0: Kitaro.
Speaker 0: I've got, I don't know, I've got, I have a, I have like a little manta, like a stingray.
Speaker 0: It's a little tiny stingray guy.
Speaker 0: I got from an aquarium once.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we've got a Cthulhu.
Speaker 1: It's upstairs.
Speaker 1: The 8086 plush was bought at a convention.
Speaker 1: I think it was Otakon 2003.
Speaker 0: I think it's Otakon 03.
Speaker 0: We've got that.
Speaker 1: I walked, I carried around the con for the entire con.
Speaker 1: I always had it on me for the rest of the con.
Speaker 1: I would like plop down in a panel room and just sleep on it for an hour.
Speaker 1: I don't find Cow and Chicken funny at all.
Speaker 0: It's not that good.
Speaker 0: Someone wants to know what our closing music is.
Speaker 1: Oh, should we reveal that?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: Nah.
Speaker 1: The only people who know, if you want to try to figure it out, the people who did a guest episode of Geek Nights a long time ago, uh, involving- I don't even, but they probably don't remember even.
Speaker 1: Yes, but I told them and I gave them the song because they kept asking about it.
Speaker 0: I think someone once guessed it.
Speaker 1: If anyone guesses it, you're awesome.
Speaker 0: The thing of the day music- I think someone once talked to me and knew what it was and I told them, I don't remember if I told them not to tell anyone.
Speaker 0: Alright, I'll give everyone a hint.
Speaker 1: The thing of the day music is from the same thing that the closing music is.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: Someone asked what the oldest computer hardware we have is.
Speaker 1: The Apple II?
Speaker 0: I got an Apple II GS.
Speaker 0: It's pretty old.
Speaker 0: I also have a Mac Plus that has one megabyte of RAM.
Speaker 1: Oh, they all know who it was at least.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they all know.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, people know what it was.
Speaker 0: Someone's smart.
Speaker 1: If you can tell me what album it was from.
Speaker 0: Alright, people are repeating themselves now.
Speaker 0: Alright, let's do-.
Speaker 0: when my clock here says 845, I'm gonna close it out.
Speaker 1: Alright, so we got four minutes.
Speaker 0: We got four minutes here.
Speaker 1: So, if you have a question you really want us to answer, now is the chance.
Speaker 1: This is it.
Speaker 0: Oldest board game.
Speaker 0: The one you've owned the longest.
Speaker 1: Not the one that is the oldest.
Speaker 1: Oh, I was about to go grab one.
Speaker 1: At risk is pretty old.
Speaker 0: I mean, I have some board games I've owned almost my whole life.
Speaker 1: I have an Uncle Wiggly.
Speaker 1: that was my mom's when she was a kid.
Speaker 0: Wow, that's a pretty old one.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I've got a game.
Speaker 0: It's basically- remember the Hangman game, Probe?
Speaker 0: That was my mom's.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a good game.
Speaker 0: It's basically just Hangman.
Speaker 0: It's versus Hangman.
Speaker 1: It's a good game, though.
Speaker 0: That's a good game to make on the computer for Probe.
Speaker 0: That game is probably- no one owns the rights to that shit.
Speaker 0: Will it be- no, the forums are staying the way they are.
Speaker 0: I mean, what are we gonna change on them?
Speaker 0: How they look?
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: The oldest game that we own, if you want to answer the broader question, probably chess or go.
Speaker 0: Best Beatles album is Rubber Soul.
Speaker 1: Favorite Final Fantasy?
Speaker 1: Not Crystal.
Speaker 1: Well, Crystal.
Speaker 0: Six.
Speaker 0: Yeah, six.
Speaker 1: Maybe four.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Also, Legend 3.
Speaker 1: Legend 2.
Speaker 0: Dad turns into a self bomber.
Speaker 1: My favorite thing at a convention, because people always go woo, is to call them out.
Speaker 1: Like, you guys go woo when I say anything you like or recognize.
Speaker 0: We don't have Shoki.
Speaker 0: Should we get it?
Speaker 0: I don't know how to play it.
Speaker 1: We could learn.
Speaker 1: I've heard- I've heard a lot of people say it's hyped.
Speaker 1: It's not that good.
Speaker 0: I thought it was very similar to chess.
Speaker 0: I'd much rather play the Star Wars table game.
Speaker 1: Yes, Celeste for the win.
Speaker 1: Moncola is not that great of a game, to be honest.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got Moncola- I had Moncola.
Speaker 0: I actually learned how to play it very recently on my iPhone because it was a free app.
Speaker 0: And then I was like, oh, that's how this game works?
Speaker 1: Eh.
Speaker 0: Okay, we got like two minutes here.
Speaker 1: Led Zeppelin or Deep Purple?
Speaker 0: Led Zeppelin.
Speaker 0: Not that Deep Purple isn't awesome.
Speaker 0: I didn't see the Watchmen movie.
Speaker 1: Do another live show.
Speaker 0: We'll do another live show someday.
Speaker 1: No, I'm not going to take my pants off.
Speaker 1: I like lolcats.
Speaker 1: Everyone likes lolcats.
Speaker 0: You may be running- we didn't- didn't we do an episode about running a panel?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm toying with the idea of doing a how to run a panel panel at some convention in the future.
Speaker 1: No, I'm not still watching Birdie Decode because my etymotic earphones, the filter's busted, so I'm waiting for the replacement to be sent.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to answer the question for Ro because I don't want anyone else to scoop me on it.
Speaker 1: I called them and they didn't answer.
Speaker 1: I'm still trying to do that thing.
Speaker 0: D&D 4th Dad is just World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: We played it at PAX.
Speaker 0: We talked about it on a show.
Speaker 1: It's great if you want to play a tabletop World of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, it's terrible.
Speaker 0: We can- we'd need to do something different if Emily was on the live show.
Speaker 1: Do the show.
Speaker 1: Drunk is All Hell?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: You realize me drunk is not that different from me sober.
Speaker 1: I just smile all the time.
Speaker 0: We haven't done a show on Princess Tutu, have we?
Speaker 0: I thought we did.
Speaker 0: But we watched- we both watched the whole show.
Speaker 1: No, we did a show where I had seen it all and you'd seen some of it.
Speaker 1: We did a review, not a final thoughts.
Speaker 1: We could do a final thoughts on Princess Tutu.
Speaker 1: I think Princess Tutu deserves a final thoughts.
Speaker 0: That's a good one, yes.
Speaker 1: That's a good show.
Speaker 0: Alright, I think we're running out of time here very, very quickly.
Speaker 0: I would get a 360 if I had an HDTV.
Speaker 0: The thing is, the 360 is kind of old, so I'd probably, if I did get an HDTV, would probably wait around until there was like a 460, right?
Speaker 1: Yes, we'll do a. there were 11 final thoughts.
Speaker 1: It needs to be done.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Anime Expo, I have no interest.
Speaker 0: Probably not going to Anime Expo unless it's just really convenient.
Speaker 1: Yes, Baccano is great.
Speaker 1: Yes, I love Emily too.
Speaker 1: Giant Robo, someone brought up Giant Robo.
Speaker 0: We have Giant Robo, we just haven't watched it.
Speaker 0: We have never done a Cowabeebop.
Speaker 0: final thoughts?
Speaker 0: We might not have.
Speaker 0: I never watched all of Area 88, but you can play the SNES game, and I think we're out of time.
Speaker 1: Wait, wait.
Speaker 1: Wait, wait, what?
Speaker 0: We're talking about Giant Robo, though.
Speaker 1: So we're going to play with this- No, I do have the- I bought this at Otacon for like 15 bucks.
Speaker 1: It's all Giant Robo in the Eye of Vogler.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you could have gotten- there's a better Slimcase box.
Speaker 0: That one is kind of poofy.
Speaker 1: The thing is, it was so cheap.
Speaker 1: Plus, the Eye of Vogler.
Speaker 0: I know, but it's, you know, you could have gotten cheaper at the Slimcase.
Speaker 1: Yes, any of you may groom me.
Speaker 0: Come to a convention.
Speaker 0: All right, I'm going to stop the recording part at least.
Speaker 0: We're done.
Speaker 0: This is it for the show.
Speaker 0: We will do this again someday.