Speaker 0: Hey, it's Wednesday October 28th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim God over Skype, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk about a comic packs Romana by the Hickman.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: That static you hear in the background can only mean one thing.
Speaker 0: It's fads karate for the geek nights.
Speaker 0: I have scott on Skype.
Speaker 0: Oh Shit, I feel like we don't clap, but we're not going to do that.
Speaker 0: That double record sinking just yet since this is kind of off the cuff.
Speaker 1: That's also because we have the skills to use the mixer to do the one-side record.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same time it sounds a lot better if you do the two-side record.
Speaker 0: But I'm lazy and basically my plan is you know I don't want to We're.
Speaker 0: we're still like you guys are lucky.
Speaker 0: We're doing shows at all for the next like two weeks because everything's just crazy as we're trying to like shuffle all these houses around And I got all this other stuff going on, but in moving moving you know I mean people are worried.
Speaker 1: Oh, no geek that will be no more.
Speaker 1: well That's not true, but what is true is that you know when people are moving they got a. you're constantly got shit to do.
Speaker 1: That's more important than a podcast.
Speaker 1: They are not paid for You know.
Speaker 0: so yeah, well partly that too is.
Speaker 0: I still don't have a car and Scott won't let me drive his car even though It's here.
Speaker 0: Oh good.
Speaker 1: You are not driving the car.
Speaker 0: I used a little like.
Speaker 0: I said I took it grocery shopping once and that was it.
Speaker 0: Okay, good, cuz I needed grocery shopping something fierce.
Speaker 0: I was out of food and so was Emily the car speaking of the car.
Speaker 1: Right I was going around the internet changing my address at various places And I changed it at Geico where I'm supposed to change it and they made your insurance go up hold on.
Speaker 1: They asked me in the end on the internet You know are you bringing the car with you, and I said no they said where are you leaving the car?
Speaker 1: I said in Beacon how long for a couple months.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they said how come you're not bringing it with you?
Speaker 1: And I'm like because there's nowhere to park and I can take the subway to work Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: so then they called me this morning, and it's a uh-huh.
Speaker 1: so why aren't you bringing the car with you?
Speaker 1: I'm like yeah, because there's no parking and right.
Speaker 1: so they asked me again.
Speaker 1: Why I'm not and they're like.
Speaker 1: They're like Well, no no no no so then they're like.
Speaker 1: well, you know Even whether you're bringing the car with you or not.
Speaker 1: we have to charge you as if you have the car with you.
Speaker 1: regardless I'm like.
Speaker 1: so why did you even ask me?
Speaker 1: Right like why ask me whether or not I'm bringing the car with me or why if it doesn't matter I don't even know.
Speaker 0: I used to just lie on that stupid thing.
Speaker 0: They made me fill out anyway cuz I was like if they're gonna drive to work.
Speaker 1: Hey funny as if the car is in Astoria Why even bother asking where the car is or the reasons for the car being where it is?
Speaker 0: There's some way where they don't have to turn cuz they don't have to.
Speaker 0: they can charge whatever they want.
Speaker 0: That's just him saying some you know Lady but you know whatever.
Speaker 0: yeah But I mean most likely if your answer had been like I'm leaving it in a garage upstate And I take a train up to take it whenever going a road trip.
Speaker 0: They would have been like.
Speaker 1: that's what I told them Really?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Oh Well, that's it.
Speaker 0: At least you can say, you know, you don't use the car to commute because that cut down on my insurance more Than anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 0: But now my $8 a month of car insurance my car is worth less than like the chair.
Speaker 0: I'm sitting in right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the insurance is now like $800 a year like four payments of 200 something each.
Speaker 0: that's not too bad Now.
Speaker 1: before it was four payments of like a hundred and forty each so it went up by six to like two hundred and forty Dollars a year.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow Yeah, we'll see what happens with that.
Speaker 1: You know, I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: you know I'm gonna keep the car and if you know we'll see how much I actually end up using it.
Speaker 1: Like if I don't use it for like months on end and don't have it, you know desire or need to use it.
Speaker 1: For you know Even though I really like the car and I've wanted to keep it for a long time and I completely own it If I sell it, I'll get a huge pile of money and I'll be able to just go.
Speaker 1: Ah, I don't need to worry about money.
Speaker 0: Ah, yep, but then you won't have a car.
Speaker 1: But if I'm not using it for months on end, what will it matter?
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 0: Well, then you'll have to do what I was doing for a while Where whenever you want to go on a trip and someone else isn't driving you got to rent the car and go pick it up and like, you know,
Speaker 1: or maybe I can you know Get the car or something
Speaker 0: that car is not worth the money.
Speaker 0: You're better off just renting an individual car every time you need it.
Speaker 1: I know it depends though.
Speaker 1: Like if I use the zipcar a lot or you know, it's it's it's you got to calculate.
Speaker 1: for some people It's worth it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but not I don't think I want to buy your car.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna buy a scojo super cheap car and I'm saying it's a better car to buy.
Speaker 0: Well, I only need a hold out until I got settled in house business cuz.
Speaker 0: once all that settled I was gonna buy like a fit And maybe a Miata and then I'll be set.
Speaker 1: you buy two cars.
Speaker 0: Well Emily's gonna get the fit and I'm gonna get like a Miata or a z4 Like this fit car.
Speaker 0: It's just a really it's like it's the same like kind of car as your Mazda 3 except it's smaller.
Speaker 0: It's a lot smaller and it's cute.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's also less speedy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you don't need speed so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my car is cool.
Speaker 0: Not for driving around town.
Speaker 0: Plus what I'm thinking about doing seriously is it will have for a while have like one maybe like the dumper car And the nice car I might just buy like a little vespa to go around upstating.
Speaker 1: It's not a bad idea.
Speaker 0: cuz I'm going to the train station and stuff like that I just parked it with the bikes.
Speaker 1: I could get one of those if I was in Manhattan, but I'm in Queens.
Speaker 1: So that's not.
Speaker 0: I guess if you're gonna drive you got to use a car in Queens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not gonna.
Speaker 1: thing is if I here's the other thing though, right?
Speaker 1: You know, it's like oh man the car.
Speaker 1: if I get like a raise of like $1,200 a year I don't think that's gonna happen very soon.
Speaker 1: I've haven't even been there a year yet.
Speaker 1: I've been there six months, right?
Speaker 0: That's that's a pretty standard raise.
Speaker 0: You should get that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I eventually get some sort of raise You know the parking spot behind my building is only a hundred and twelve dollars a month.
Speaker 1: So if after taxes I get a raise of a hundred and twelve dollars, that's the thing It's like by the parking space.
Speaker 0: Living in the city kind of like it sucks to have a car if you're not ultra wealthy because you got to deal with it.
Speaker 0: But if you have the money to just pay to park the car right next to your house in New York City It's like the best thing in the world.
Speaker 1: But here's the problem though, right if I drive say to Wildwood with it That's fine.
Speaker 1: That's totally awesome, right?
Speaker 1: But if I drive say, you know to I don't know somewhere like on the other side of Queens Where it's sort of far away from the subway or you know, I want to
Speaker 0: go and like yeah Well,
Speaker 1: no, for example, right if I wanted to drive to like Target to buy like an appliance That was big and I couldn't carry it on the subway right cuz I want to bring the car with me.
Speaker 1: Parking anywhere else sucks a big day.
Speaker 0: Hey, I used to work in the Bronx.
Speaker 1: We have to pay money.
Speaker 0: I'm well aware.
Speaker 0: more than once I would drive to like a work site and then an hour later I'd call back and be like I spent an hour.
Speaker 0: There's nowhere to park within like an hour's walk.
Speaker 0: I'm just coming back to the office.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so here let's see some other little bit before we go.
Speaker 1: It's a movie.
Speaker 0: I'm sure people are really fascinated with all this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: See it's a moving tidbits number one A tension rod really works kind of well in the bedroom didn't work.
Speaker 1: So well, I didn't get enough.
Speaker 1: I didn't get a second one, which I'm glad because they didn't have one wide enough for the living room.
Speaker 0: So let's get to inductive them together in the middle.
Speaker 1: They actually had a thing that lets you connect two tension rods together.
Speaker 1: It was like a special bit.
Speaker 1: The special bit required needs to be screwed into the wall.
Speaker 1: pretty much There's no way to avoid screwing something into the wall.
Speaker 0: They're gonna figure out what that metal was is like a doctor what can't tell what the hell it is.
Speaker 1: I'm basically gonna find the stupor and ask him to help me out because I don't know what to do with that situation at all.
Speaker 1: But I don't know it sucks.
Speaker 1: But you know the tension rod is doing pretty nice in the bedroom.
Speaker 1: So whatever What else do I get here?
Speaker 0: The real question Scott is if the curtains match the handbag in the shoes, right?
Speaker 1: Whatever the People don't have to look at me naked anymore.
Speaker 1: That's what the the answer is.
Speaker 1: Um, I finally got like a hanging file cabinet right, which I've always wanted and so now I was able to sort all my papers into it instead of them being in sort of a pile in the closet.
Speaker 1: and One thing about this file cabinet.
Speaker 1: it's from IKEA and it it was really narrow.
Speaker 1: so I was like, huh, I've never seen a hanging file so narrow.
Speaker 1: and So I went to Staples and about the.
Speaker 1: they only had two sizes of hanging file letter and legal.
Speaker 1: so I bought letter, right?
Speaker 1: And it wouldn't fit in the hanging file like it just would not fit in there.
Speaker 1: and I'm like what the fuck How am I supposed to use this hanging file?
Speaker 1: It makes no sense.
Speaker 1: apparently the way this thing works is You have to take out the bottom of the drawer like remove the bottom of the drawer And then there are these two metal sticks that you slide in and you actually hang the files Sideways on the metal sticks and they hang out the bottom of the drawer.
Speaker 0: That's nowhere.
Speaker 1: Nowhere in the instructions did it say that you had to do that?
Speaker 1: That's exactly what you have to do.
Speaker 1: I Had to find it online though.
Speaker 1: People are talking about it and it's actually.
Speaker 1: it's very nice.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh What about a TV that's not here yet.
Speaker 1: I bought it.
Speaker 1: I went to B&H which is sort of like this big fancy like pro electronics store in in behind Madison Square Garden, it's uber famous and such and It's very Jewish.
Speaker 1: They're closed on Saturday and everything.
Speaker 1: and I just went to look at the TVs and The people there the you know, the TV salesman.
Speaker 1: they weren't actually that knowledgeable, but they were you know or helpful.
Speaker 1: But at least they didn't give a shit.
Speaker 1: So there I was like, can I change the settings on the TV?
Speaker 1: They're like, yeah, whatever do whatever you want.
Speaker 1: So I changed the settings on the TVs to normal to figure out you know, whatever.
Speaker 1: And I pretty much decided well the TVs that look great are too expensive.
Speaker 1: So I would just get a normal TV.
Speaker 1: But the thing is so I look at the normal TV with $700 the one the Samsung I was looking at.
Speaker 1: I go on Amazon.
Speaker 1: It's 650.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, do you have a price guarantee?
Speaker 1: Do you have free delivery?
Speaker 1: and they didn't have a price guarantee, but they didn't have free delivery and Amazon also had free delivery.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, well, you know what?
Speaker 1: I'll just buy it on Amazon here.
Speaker 0: That's the way you go.
Speaker 0: I don't buy anything in the real world except I don't know food.
Speaker 1: So the Amazon the TV was 50 bucks less.
Speaker 1: So it's coming.
Speaker 0: I guess now my co-workers are buying TVs right now because they're they're all talking about the big rush as OLED becomes big.
Speaker 0: they're like, yeah buy all the old LCDs for super cheap.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the thing right is that they've got the LCDs which and then they've got the LED, right?
Speaker 1: And they're trying to trick people into thinking that LED is different from LCD like, you know But really all it is is the same TV with different lights behind it.
Speaker 1: and LED is better, you know It's gonna be darker.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be more in the black area.
Speaker 1: They're gonna be more evenly lit It's gonna use less energy.
Speaker 1: But they're charging ludicrous amounts of extra money for the LED backlit.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, you gotta wait on something like that.
Speaker 1: But I mean like I have an LED backlit monitors and LED backlit You know laptop screens and they were not.
Speaker 0: ludicrously more money Partly depends on the size and the form factor and all sorts of.
Speaker 1: I guess yeah more bigger LEDs might be more money It's true.
Speaker 0: but oh, well plus it's a different market different demagogue.
Speaker 0: Everything's different with TVs than with monitors.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna save any more talk about moving stuff for later.
Speaker 1: We don't have in minutes.
Speaker 1: There's low our whole load right away.
Speaker 0: and what a load it is.
Speaker 0: I got this whole house to myself.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's kind of quiet up here.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 0: I got and I felt like my day was a lot longer because I came home from work yesterday.
Speaker 0: I'm like hanging around the house and I did like all this stuff.
Speaker 0: No one came into our room and bothered me And eventually I went to bed.
Speaker 1: You know, I thought that my day would feel a lot longer.
Speaker 1: and the thing is right.
Speaker 1: number one I'm actually not saving that much time because I'm sleeping like an extra 90 minutes.
Speaker 0: But you're getting 90 minutes more sleep.
Speaker 1: I am but I don't.
Speaker 1: I'm not getting more time to do stuff Which is what I really wanted.
Speaker 1: and number two is after work every day I'm pretty much going around to like bed baths and beyond in other places to get house shit and sorting house stuff out.
Speaker 1: So I'm still don't really have any much extra time to like, you know do how you know to start coding or working on projects?
Speaker 0: Yeah, those days when I like I just stay in the city for some reasons I got some hours to kill I was like wandering around the city going like stupid just doing stupid stuff.
Speaker 1: Yep, but soon Do that Anime.
Speaker 1: So I've actually got it with that.
Speaker 1: what the show we're doing it.
Speaker 0: I've actually got a geek bite here because you know, I keep saying oh really I also have a geek bite.
Speaker 0: I keep saying there's no anime news.
Speaker 0: and then I think last time I said there's no anime news except the fact that there's no Anime news.
Speaker 0: All I gotta say is Jesus Christ.
Speaker 0: like nothing is happening in the anime industry anymore like nothing at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean there's no anime and stuff and I'm actually watching a ton of anime lately on the train But there's just there's nothing interesting happening anymore.
Speaker 0: Like there's no news other than X show came out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wouldn't get the giant robo that you gave me, but I don't have any Speakers on this computer now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm moving them over to the TV.
Speaker 0: Don't waste John.
Speaker 1: I moved the old TV speakers into the bedroom Which is so awesome like because I basically connected my iPod dock to the TM to those speakers in the bedroom.
Speaker 1: It's like the alarm uses them and I got you.
Speaker 1: it's it's.
Speaker 1: oh it's so great.
Speaker 0: It's the best move but you don't want to waste giant robo.
Speaker 0: without a good sound system giant robo you know, I watched the first episode again because I showed it to Judith and Natalie when they were visiting and Emily never seen it.
Speaker 0: and Jesus Christ, is that show awesome?
Speaker 0: Like I just it's.
Speaker 0: I almost forget until I watch it again.
Speaker 0: It was like, alright that show The first time we watched it.
Speaker 1: RIT was nuts.
Speaker 0: We were young we didn't get it.
Speaker 0: I know exactly what I was thinking when we saw that giant robo one.
Speaker 0: That was that era when we always left anime club early to go hang out somewhere like as a crew Only when the show was bad even often when the show was good.
Speaker 0: We'd be like, yeah, let's go hang out We go do stuff like we play card games or bard games or whatever.
Speaker 0: Anyway, or but I think back then like I remember I see why I wasn't at the time in my life when I could appreciate A show like that.
Speaker 0: I was like, yeah, it's some stupid robot fighting show.
Speaker 0: Fuck this.
Speaker 0: Why does everyone have superpowers?
Speaker 0: that doesn't make any sense?
Speaker 0: Now it's like.
Speaker 0: I mean, I guess I'm just a Hokuto.
Speaker 0: no Ken fix that everyone has super powers in that show.
Speaker 0: But I'm watching of all things right now and I said I was watching it before and then I stopped and I'm almost done with it.
Speaker 0: Tetsuwan birdie decode the Remake of the original Tetsuwan birdie aka.
Speaker 1: It's a remake.
Speaker 1: It's not a sequel It's dead.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I mean I've not seen more than like one episode of the original birdie the mighty.
Speaker 0: It definitely feels like a complete remake.
Speaker 1: so you can watch this show knowing nothing about Absolutely, nothing.
Speaker 0: The only thing you will not get are some clever homage to the original show.
Speaker 1: Okay, so it's not it's not it's not.
Speaker 1: there's no story connection.
Speaker 1: You find out on your own episode 174 of spider-man without reading one through 173.
Speaker 0: No, it's basically just oh shit It's birdie the mighty aka birdie the berserker killer and she punches some kid and then he dies and she has to die share the body and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: and I like this show a lot more than I expected.
Speaker 0: I thought it'd be so dumb, but I watched the first episode with Emily and it was just it.
Speaker 0: Harken back to a different era of anime.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: I felt like it was 1996 again In a good way like it was a dumb show, but it wasn't dumb like dumb anime I watch now.
Speaker 0: it was dumb like dumb 90s anime Like it was just kind of like high flying space comedy action and just I don't know.
Speaker 1: There's a lot going on in this show and watching the show on crunchyroll or somewhere else or what?
Speaker 0: I got a Pirated copy.
Speaker 0: I'm watching on the train.
Speaker 1: Maybe it leave you legally available.
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 0: At this point, I don't unless something's on crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: if it came out after like 2007 I don't have any faith that there's any legal way to get it.
Speaker 0: I just don't even know what's on DVD anymore.
Speaker 1: I think claim word is coming out on DVD right now.
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 0: I could.
Speaker 0: I was a show that was good enough to finish?
Speaker 0: I think I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's good enough to at least continue watching before I left off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I actually you know, it's that's one of those ones where it's like.
Speaker 1: should I go and finish watching that anime?
Speaker 0: If there's any show that manga if there's any show that we have the you know.
Speaker 0: We started watching it and we stopped for no reason other than we stopped.
Speaker 0: We got to watch the rest of ergo proxy because that was a show.
Speaker 1: That was the show that I was coming into my mind just as you were talking about stopping watching a show Because we didn't stop for any reason.
Speaker 0: In fact, the show is just getting to the point We're like, oh shit.
Speaker 0: This might be a good show.
Speaker 1: the one thing about the ergo proxy those I know what Darryl Surratt said about.
Speaker 1: you know the leader parts and such.
Speaker 1: but the thing is the show started with that cool cyberpunk city and then it switched to sort of Outside the city business, but then we was just getting back into the city.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, but I mean I like this.
Speaker 1: I wish it was the cyberpunk stuff the whole time.
Speaker 1: It would have been much closer to a ghost shell kind of thing.
Speaker 0: I think the weird thing about the show is that with the aesthetic and like the first couple episodes It looked really kind of I hate to use the word pretentious, but it seemed like this pretentious garbage.
Speaker 0: And then suddenly it's like oh wait, it's not doing that.
Speaker 0: It's using uh, and then it went outside.
Speaker 0: It's like oh it's doing something different entirely.
Speaker 0: and then having not seen the rest but having listened to Darryl Surratt's review Everything he said tells me that it's a show.
Speaker 0: I like Yeah, probably.
Speaker 0: so we got.
Speaker 0: we got to watch that and review it.
Speaker 1: Alright, so I'm gonna actually do a geek bite on a comic book.
Speaker 1: You know what kind of book it is Pax Romana?
Speaker 1: No, that's what we're doing the whole show.
Speaker 0: I know but you could totally steal all of our thunder with that.
Speaker 1: Steal my own thunder from myself.
Speaker 1: I stole a dollar from my own wallet.
Speaker 1: Ah, okay The only comic that I really since.
Speaker 1: you know I couldn't really bring my books with me yet because they are too heavy and such.
Speaker 1: I have to find some way to get them down here later Perhaps slowly and over time.
Speaker 1: I Brought down.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to read everything that I've borrowed from anybody, you know Because that way I can give them back and not have to move them.
Speaker 1: People give me back things I lent to them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, speaking of which you ever get Eagle back from the comic geek speed guys.
Speaker 1: No, I will probably get it back at like the New York Comic Con.
Speaker 0: All right, cuz I want it back.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I want to lend it to someone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we could have gotten it back at What's it called the if we went to their convention.
Speaker 1: the thing?
Speaker 0: Wanted to go to that.
Speaker 1: their convention is the same day as PAX East.
Speaker 0: so I can't happen.
Speaker 0: No So well at the New York Comic Con which I guess is see that the you own the vast majority of the comics and manga In the front row crew like right here though.
Speaker 0: Lara has pretty much all the manga that you don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much but I'm very happy that I am the owner of sanctuary at Eagle like I feel like those two are worth if it weren't for Urasawa.
Speaker 0: those two are worth more than like your entire collection, but Urasawa Damn, you know by it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Scott's boxes are being delivered here now, by the way, so Very nice.
Speaker 1: Anyway, no, so I was you know, I also I want to you know.
Speaker 1: Okay, if I'm moving I want to get stuff sorted out between who I lent what and who lent what to me and all that Kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: so so it doesn't get lost, you know in the moving process.
Speaker 0: So I started reading Alex's Alan Moore Swamp Thing volumes That was laying under the piano forever and I while I've kept forgetting whose it was.
Speaker 0: Yeah, who's is this now?
Speaker 0: It's like it's mine.
Speaker 0: I lent it to Scott.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've read.
Speaker 1: I've read like two volumes so far.
Speaker 1: Maybe three.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good.
Speaker 1: I mean the first.
Speaker 1: you know The first issue in the first volume has it's sort of like Sandman in a way in that You know in like the first volume of Sandman It was like a little superhero II, you know and the Swamp Thing like the first issue actually has like the Justice League in it You know, they don't really do anything but they're just they're there there they are, right?
Speaker 1: So it's a little bit super hero II and then it sort of gets away from that.
Speaker 1: and the thing is some of the issues It's you know has like this very heavy-handed Environmental message like this one issue that's like nuclear bad.
Speaker 1: It's all about like this guy nuke face who's like horribly deformed from drinking like radioactive materials and that he shouldn't have done that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's you know, it's it's.
Speaker 1: it's also has like people dumping toxic waste into the swamp, you know and stuff.
Speaker 1: And it's like, you know, obviously that's bad.
Speaker 1: But like, you know, it's a very anti nuclear power issue and you know I think it would have worked a lot better if I didn't know that nuclear power was totally awesome.
Speaker 1: But you know and other parts of it, you know, or you know, it's really interesting Like I didn't know like what Swamp Thing was like.
Speaker 1: I knew he was a green guy from the swamp and that was pretty much it.
Speaker 1: Like knowing what Swamp Thing actually is, you know And it actually Swamp Thing was something different and then Alan Moore changed what it was in this one issue.
Speaker 1: That's like the lauded great issue.
Speaker 1: I think it's called like Anatomy lesson and It was actually.
Speaker 1: it's pretty fantastic.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's you know, it's Alan Moore quality writing, you know And the art is actually really great.
Speaker 1: the colors actually you think like the whole thing will be like black and green But it's not.
Speaker 1: there's actually a whole ton of color like all over and it really like stands out.
Speaker 1: It's like the art is as good as the art that on fables right now.
Speaker 1: So even though this thing is wicked old on a scale of make it old I mean, I think it's 80s old on a scale of say Watchmen to Batman Dark Knight Returns.
Speaker 0: Where does it lie?
Speaker 1: Below both of them, but it's you know, it's still up there.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's.
Speaker 1: I say it's it's prime mouse guard.
Speaker 0: good You have to read it and then we can review it straight up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, probably
Speaker 0: I'll recommend conversely at some point It'd be worth your while to watch birdie the mighty at least a couple episodes to see Because the show would be dumb except that all the action in it is very like old-school anime action But not old old-school like old-school 90s old school.
Speaker 0: There are so many schools now.
Speaker 0: It's crazy.
Speaker 0: Like some people old-school is Star Blazers and some people old-school is like Giant robo or Tetsu on birdie, but giant robo is old-school homage to an older school Incredibly old-school.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but anyway moving this along it's time for things of the day.
Speaker 0: So according to FARC anvil shooting is a grand American tradition and it is literally.
Speaker 1: If you shoot at anvils or you shoot anvil you shoot anvils and anvils are the ammunition.
Speaker 0: you shoot anvils at anvils with anvils.
Speaker 1: Wait, you can't have three anvils in.
Speaker 0: so here's what you do.
Speaker 0: You take one anvil you put it on the ground Upside down you put gunpowder in the hole in the bottom of the anvil.
Speaker 1: you put a hole in the anvil.
Speaker 0: There's a hole on the bottom of an anvil.
Speaker 0: really that's like where you mount the anvil on something.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay I see what you're saying.
Speaker 0: It's like a big slot down there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then on top of that you put another identical anvil.
Speaker 0: Okay, and then you blow it up and that anvil goes higher.
Speaker 0: It's so high that you cannot see it and it comes back down Almost exactly where you shot it.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it'll hit the anvil from which you launched it and Then you have to freakin run the hell away.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: the video is basically he lights it and you expect you know watching myth busters or all the kind of Professional and semi-professional people doing stuff like this.
Speaker 0: I Expected there to be like this long fuse or something electronic.
Speaker 0: He likes the fuse.
Speaker 0: It's sticking like an inch out of that anvil.
Speaker 0: Motherfucker runs, let me tell you.
Speaker 1: Oh, he did run far away.
Speaker 0: No, he likes it and it's like a light light light light light run.
Speaker 1: So like if a guy ran like let's say you ran like you just didn't stop running and the landfill got him any lady.
Speaker 1: And then he ran immediately as soon as it was lit and never stopped and then the anvil happened to land on top of him Wherever you got to.
Speaker 0: the image of that is kind of funny.
Speaker 1: But apparently why the coyote moment right there?
Speaker 0: apparently the anvils tend to fall almost exactly where they went up.
Speaker 0: because you know Winds now pushing an anvil so much, you know, it'd be badass though.
Speaker 1: If you if you like could Calculate and be really precise with your anvil and hit an anvil in the air with another anvil No, but that's an even better idea.
Speaker 1: But no like if you got the if you knew the anvil was gonna land exactly where it took off from.
Speaker 0: have another anvil shoot Up just as that one lands.
Speaker 1: No You you lit it and you just stood right next to it and it landed like right in front of you and you were just like Yeah, fuck that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah I Just stood right here.
Speaker 1: this anvil could have landed on my head But it landed one foot in front of me and I was
Speaker 0: like the old physics thing where you take a bowling ball On a string hanging from the ceiling and you hold it next to your nose and you let go and you just stand there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, however, all that reminds me of is we were talking about electron microscopes and physics in like 10th grade And I remember he the professor part of the teacher.
Speaker 0: I guess it was high school pointed out You were talking about why electron microscopes work that a far more accurate Man microscope would be a bowling ball microscope that just fired millions of bowling balls at near the speed of light at an object.
Speaker 1: Too bad.
Speaker 1: We can't fire the bowling balls with the speed of light.
Speaker 0: Well near the speed of light not at the speed of light.
Speaker 1: and the other problem is the bowling balls will hit each other.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah electrons do the same thing.
Speaker 0: electrons electron microscopes many kinds of them basically destroy whatever they're looking at.
Speaker 1: I Know that.
Speaker 1: that's why you can't take pictures of like live things.
Speaker 1: They always die.
Speaker 1: There are some cool techniques to take usually kill them like when they're setting them up for it to go in the mega.
Speaker 0: There are some weird cool techniques to take images of living things with electron microscopes Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know much more about it than that has maybe a scientist and show will type in.
Speaker 1: but my thing of the Day is not the greatest thing of the day in the universe But it is following a long tradition of Soviet things of the day.
Speaker 0: Those were the days my friend We thought they'd never end.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: This is basically a bunch of anti u.s.
Speaker 1: Soviet propaganda.
Speaker 0: I love stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's you know, it's just a simple webpage.
Speaker 1: It's got pictures of you know fat cats with top hats being carried around by.
Speaker 0: The reason I like so much Soviet propaganda is that one.
Speaker 0: it uses this really cool style Like the very star and a lot of different styles going on here actually but to the message like the raw message independently of the kind of reality of communism is You know the workers rising up and taking back.
Speaker 0: What's theirs?
Speaker 0: You know the blood.
Speaker 1: actually most of these most of these images.
Speaker 1: I mean there's a little bit of that but most of these images are like Americans evil bombs Soviets good babies.
Speaker 1: Like one of these pictures right show the loaf of bread and then it shows like a combat knife and the combat knife is chopping the loaf of bread right and each slice of bread is sort of falling off and turning into bombs.
Speaker 1: and It's right.
Speaker 1: It's trying to say that the u.s.
Speaker 1: You know turns food into bombs.
Speaker 0: We kind of did back then.
Speaker 0: I know I mean not that communism was great But I can see the word rest of the world having that image of us and not feeling too unjustified.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the translation is humanitarian help to starving ones in American way.
Speaker 0: You see that.
Speaker 0: you know, that's what really does it the Communist stuff like that.
Speaker 0: That's kind of funny and clever and well thought out.
Speaker 0: I mean look at the propaganda We drop over like Afghanistan.
Speaker 0: It's it's kind of sad.
Speaker 0: It's not really biting or satirical or anything.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: These are these are funny and Interesting.
Speaker 0: So holy shit.
Speaker 0: I read a comic.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: He wrote a comic.
Speaker 0: You know, I did write a comic.
Speaker 1: art of the word had part of the word Rome in the title.
Speaker 1: That's why he read it.
Speaker 0: Yeah well basically I was like Scott.
Speaker 0: we got to do an anime and a comic in the next two Wednesday shows to kind of get back on Track.
Speaker 0: and I was like, you're not gonna watch an anime in time for the next show.
Speaker 0: So give me a short comic to read.
Speaker 0: and Scott's like I got one that ups that's up your alley.
Speaker 0: It's got the word Rome in the title.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I was like, well, you know this.
Speaker 1: You know, it's not greatest comic ever in the history of the world.
Speaker 1: But I know that rim will enjoy anything that involves a Rome.
Speaker 1: But of course it was not me.
Speaker 1: and what did you expect when you saw like the cover?
Speaker 0: All right, when I saw the cover I expected here.
Speaker 0: My expectation was one This is a comic about what if the Roman Empire did not fall and continued if forever just without falling.
Speaker 0: So now we're at like the year 1999 or 2000 or whatever and there's just the Roman fucking Empire with modern stuff and it was kind of that but not really.
Speaker 0: It kind of was in a way but in a. I was right in that the Roman Empire didn't fucking fall.
Speaker 1: The comic is by is written by Jonathan Hickman.
Speaker 1: Yes, the guy wrote his.
Speaker 1: we wrote nightly news, which is it.
Speaker 1: we did a show on that way back.
Speaker 1: Yeah What's it called?
Speaker 0: Scott told me hey, by the way, it's by Jonathan Hickman, you know the nightly news guy and I'm like Yeah, and then I forgot about that and I was reading it again.
Speaker 0: I didn't look at the cover.
Speaker 0: I'm like, huh?
Speaker 0: This is now.
Speaker 0: look at the front like da Jonathan Hickman.
Speaker 1: Yep What was the other one that he did?
Speaker 1: I can't believe.
Speaker 1: I can't remember.
Speaker 1: he's working at Marvel now actually writing on stuff like Fantastic Four and such.
Speaker 1: it's really interesting.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I want to point out we're gonna review this.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna spoil it other than we kind of have to describe the plot which is a regular human.
Speaker 1: He wrote transhuman and he'd also did a red mask for Mars.
Speaker 1: There was actually a reference to red mask for Mars at the end of Pax Romana.
Speaker 0: No, cuz I didn't read that yet Okay.
Speaker 0: Anyway, though, we're not gonna spoil this other than we have to spoil the premise because otherwise you can't review a one-off comic.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not really.
Speaker 1: I mean it's a one-off in the sense that it won't trade.
Speaker 1: paperback is the whole thing.
Speaker 1: But I think it's actually like three to five issues six issues something like that.
Speaker 0: But it's a really short-contained story and Part of a spoiler is simply knowing what the story actually is because it starts out kind of Slightly different from where you'd expect it to start.
Speaker 1: Well, it's also really interesting how they at the end they sort of rushed the end like they didn't, you know It's like you have this big story, but they really only Fleshed out certain short scenes in the story, but at the same
Speaker 0: time I like that because one it definitely pulled a little bit of an Ava.
Speaker 0: It's like seriously if you think that anything matters other than like the the numbers of what happened.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like when you look at a lot of old comic books the numbers like by the numbers of what happened like this war then this then this then this a description of the plot Often seems really cool.
Speaker 0: But then you read the old comic and it's just I punch you you a little guy and all this bullshit.
Speaker 0: You don't care about you always.
Speaker 1: you need a new example of old Example of old comic books.
Speaker 0: I've hit you now you little guy.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, he's hitting me.
Speaker 1: But yeah, but this this is a comic that doesn't really tell you a lot of.
Speaker 1: I mean there's like human drama and stuff But it only gives you like the high-level details.
Speaker 1: It's like this huge gigantic, you know, you know Earth Universe spanning story and you're just getting a bird's-eye view of the whole thing.
Speaker 1: You're not getting a lot of details of.
Speaker 1: this.
Speaker 1: person said this, you know There's very little really really like that.
Speaker 0: as a result because one Stories like this can almost fall into the trap of minutiae where like say you get to a point where you know Person a is totally going to betray person B and then like do something and you know it's coming and then you've got to read like the next 40 pages of it actually happening and Kind of you're like maybe interesting stuff happens.
Speaker 0: It might be portrayed well and whatever but at the same time there's this little part of you That's like.
Speaker 0: I know this is gonna happen.
Speaker 0: I want to know what happens next.
Speaker 1: Yes, you're the kind of person doesn't like a cliffhanger.
Speaker 1: this is pretty great because it just rushes you straight through You know from beginning to end.
Speaker 1: well Especially the point because at the end at the very end there is sort of a revelation.
Speaker 1: Oh shit, you know, yeah Well, it's also that there's also a mini revelation in like the early on.
Speaker 1: but that was sort of obvious.
Speaker 0: Yeah But it's it's sort.
Speaker 0: there's so many good.
Speaker 0: but basically the premise before we get any further because obviously no one has read this He's not.
Speaker 0: many of you probably read it is that nobody in the far ish future of the modern real world.
Speaker 1: This is the gene.
Speaker 0: Alright if you want no other reason to read this there is a gene Pope a genetic Pope an amalgamation of a thousand holy men and he is kind of a prick but also a badass.
Speaker 0: and if You can just stop listening right now and buy this if you think that sounds cool.
Speaker 0: But The real pull of the story is basically that we've got you know, it's the our future Catholicism not doing so.
Speaker 0: well Islam is spread all over the place and you know science basically made religion kind of stupid and Obsolete and all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: but the Vatican had a secret science program to develop time travel and it works And it really was shit.
Speaker 1: It actually worked.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 0: I love those scientists who were like Yeah, we did it check it out we sent a rat back in time a little bit and then the Pope the Vatican's like Alright, let's do this.
Speaker 0: So they gather all these holy people and an army and they do.
Speaker 0: there's this all this whole build-up where they debate like Where do they go back in time to ensure that Catholicism is stronger now than it is currently like?
Speaker 0: basically This is want to make Rome now fall and make Christianity and Catholicism remain strong and power.
Speaker 1: And it's really if the discussion they have of like even should they go back in time to when to do what you know It's very interesting.
Speaker 1: Like they're like, well, we cannot absolutely not go back before the time of Jesus.
Speaker 1: That would not be allowed.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like it's cool.
Speaker 1: I would all.
Speaker 0: the every character every single character in this is Smart at least as smart as you the reader.
Speaker 0: So the intellectual discussions and arguments they have which it kind of does these cool decides where you'll get that like.
Speaker 0: It'll like.
Speaker 0: you'll see a scene and then it cuts to the following is the transcript recorded by such-and-such on such-and-such date.
Speaker 1: And usually, you know, usually when you're reading a comic book and they break in with a bunch of text, you know it's sort of like.
Speaker 1: You know, obviously, you know, I don't have a problem reading a novel but when you encounter that there's something in your brain It's like your brain doesn't like switching from like picture and text mode to pure text mode.
Speaker 0: Look at how many people who otherwise understand comics just skip over all the words and watchman stupidly Right.
Speaker 1: So the thing is in this book Like.
Speaker 1: I actually didn't have that problem like when I got to the text parts I like.
Speaker 1: I just kept going.
Speaker 1: I didn't feel that thing and even in Watchmen I read the stuff anyway.
Speaker 1: But it's like it takes that to switch my brain.
Speaker 1: I didn't have to switch this.
Speaker 1: Something about the way he laid it out or the amount of text or something maybe because it's still dialogue text like comics Yeah And also just being a solid block of pros on a raw level.
Speaker 0: the actual real arguments that these characters are having Are the same kind of arguments we would have in the crew if such a thing were possible like they did.
Speaker 1: They're very dirty arguments, you know, but that's you know, theological arguments usually are that way.
Speaker 1: But these are other arguments that are not theological in nature.
Speaker 0: So basically they decide to go back the best time to change everything to where Constantine is about to basically make Christianity the the religion of Rome and their goal is to kind of prevent the schism and Create a society that will not fall and kind of fix Rome and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: And of course it all goes haywire But not necessarily for the reasons you expect.
Speaker 0: it goes haywire a lot quicker than you would have expected Pretty much immediately.
Speaker 1: I like how Constantine like the way they portray Constantine.
Speaker 1: Oh, that was the best scene where like he knows like he knows what's up, you know, he's not a moron.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the thing when they kind of the main dude sneaks up on him and Constantine's all cool and then he's like he says something insightful to Constantine like a da da da da and Constantine gives this really clever answer and then the guy's like shit man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I thought I thought you would be simple.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you thought the people in the olden times would be like cavemen, but no You know even even in the olden times to be Emperor like they you got to be on the ball or crazy or lucky Yep, but Constantine was not the the Nero.
Speaker 0: There's also this great scene where?
Speaker 0: Constantine's like all right I've had enough with you and he calls his all these guards like four big burly guards with you know weapons.
Speaker 0: He's like take this guy away and crucify him or something.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling I would be willing to bet a small amount of money that Jonathan Hickman was listening to 12 Byzantine emperors.
Speaker 1: You see a lot of that stuff where it's like, yep Is he gonna let the idiot son become king or is he going to appoint the guy who actually could be good at being?
Speaker 0: An idiot son ruins everything always.
Speaker 1: There's also that stuff where like they know what the they know what the original history was gonna be.
Speaker 1: So they're sort of trying to figure out like well, we know that this person was a traitorous asshole.
Speaker 1: What should we do about them?
Speaker 1: Should we kill them?
Speaker 1: Should we you know, should we wait for them to make this?
Speaker 0: I mean knowing that like the barbarian invasions will come and like Forcing Rome to consolidate the borders and defend them better early on like hundreds of years before that Cool stuff like that.
Speaker 0: But the guards like are gonna you know Take this guy away and kill him or something and then the dude the main character is like are these your best men?
Speaker 0: and Constantine's?
Speaker 0: Like?
Speaker 0: yes, and he just shoots them all and Constantine to look at his face is like what what the all right?
Speaker 1: yeah, that's one thing is that even if you don't appreciate like the more cerebral aspects of this book or the Historical aspects or anything or the graphic design aspects which haven't even talked about yet you you can appreciate this book on a totally shallow level of Dude brings freaking Humvees and machine guns back to Constantine's time and shoots them up.
Speaker 0: There's a great line where the dragon birth tank Johnson has always wanted but the Emperor says something effective.
Speaker 0: you took out an army of a hundred and thousand elite Romans and Suffered three casualties 150 men.
Speaker 0: yeah, they're like.
Speaker 0: yeah, my truck like flipped over and we lost some guys.
Speaker 0: It's an accident like they got killed but There is a two-page spread of modern military Descending upon two Roman armies locked in battle.
Speaker 1: That's the best spread in the whole book.
Speaker 0: that is like you turn the page to that and you're just in awe of it Just like fuck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what I was reading this for.
Speaker 1: Fuck.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: so the graphic design because you mentioned it is really surreal and all over the place and Really like.
Speaker 0: it's really sparse and yet detailed like the characters are really detailed and usually black and white or black and white ish.
Speaker 0: and then the backgrounds are kind of like Orange to black and almost no other color and lots of weird text popping up everywhere And the background is almost non-existent.
Speaker 1: Only I think he got he put less cray crammed in less tiny words all over the place.
Speaker 1: You know, that's the thing Jonathan Hickman actually comes from like a graphic design Background, you know, like he doesn't come from like a comic art background.
Speaker 1: So, you know when he does like books from Marvel or whatever He sort of writes, you know a fantastic for a story and someone else draws it.
Speaker 1: But when he these books from image that he did all on his own, you know Like nightly news and Pax Romana and you know, I think trans human I think someone else might have done some are in trans human.
Speaker 1: I don't remember but or red mass from ours I'm not sure who did the art on that either but you know He basically he graphic designs the thing and as opposed to you know Doing comic art and it actually makes this really really interesting effect of.
Speaker 1: you know Like there are there's panels, but there's not really panels and there's words all over the place But you still know what order to read them in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've got.
Speaker 1: he's got all sorts of like recurring Symbols and colors that have meaning and you know, he basically just he treats the page, you know Like like he throws out all the rules of making comics, but he still obeys them.
Speaker 0: Yeah Plus the cat like all the characters unique I really I like the character design and I like the characters because again no one's I've had you dude Just no one is that stupid guy like in almost any media.
Speaker 1: there's like Oh the guy who gets it on with the with the yeah, but he didn't.
Speaker 0: he wasn't that stupid guy who like You know, he's gonna fuck it all up and then he fucks it all up and then like it's not fun to read Whatever you're reading anymore That's true.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are too many works where like the stupid guy makes it not fun to read.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, I know you're talking
Speaker 0: Especially like if you've seen like say there's a movie or a sitcom before you've seen it and you know There's a point at which like the whole thing falls apart and you almost like cringe at the fact that you're gonna have to watch that again
Speaker 1: Like
Speaker 0: I'm gonna have to watch this guy fail And no one is like that in tax Romana.
Speaker 0: Everyone's kind of cool and badass in their own way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's mercenary assholes even the mercenaries even the The religious folk, you know, I guess the one the one character I have a question about you know, the mother current King the little kid King.
Speaker 0: I kind of like him though, because he's he's just.
Speaker 1: he's kind of a snarky little kid Yeah, but I wonder what like, you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: is he really smart?
Speaker 1: does he get it?
Speaker 1: or is he just you know?
Speaker 1: A little kid.
Speaker 1: I think he's just.
Speaker 1: I think he portrayed him as more as just a little kid and not actually a kid who could Actually do a good job of kinging King Arthur they show they portray him is like he could actually King it up, but this kid no way.
Speaker 0: Thing that I can't really spoil but What else we can say without spoiling?
Speaker 0: I mean, it's a great comic.
Speaker 0: I'd recommend reading it.
Speaker 0: It's you know, it's one.
Speaker 0: just buy it.
Speaker 0: you can just read it in like if you like.
Speaker 1: it's all visiting teen emperors.
Speaker 1: if you like a nightly news.
Speaker 1: if you like any other.
Speaker 0: if you like the idea of So they brought some nukes back with them right if you like.
Speaker 0: if you like nukes verse Romans if you like the idea of Imagine if nukes are like.
Speaker 0: the Romans had nukes From the future and they and then all the people who brought them long long later had all died of old age And they were like this ancient mysterious technology.
Speaker 0: and then like 500 years later Someone uses that ancient and mysterious technology from the future.
Speaker 1: Wow, it makes it.
Speaker 1: that's sort of like.
Speaker 1: what if aliens came right now and brought us like I don't know like fusion blasters?
Speaker 0: Or what if you know our precursors, but they didn't let us use them.
Speaker 1: They just sort of held them there and then like a thousand years from now like Indiana Jones 30 10 dug them up.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, you know the analogy be like.
Speaker 0: what if the pyramid was that?
Speaker 0: the pyramids in Giza?
Speaker 0: You know in Egypt were actually some crazy machine and we just couldn't figure it out.
Speaker 1: and one day we're like, oh shit Too bad, they're just a pile of rocks.
Speaker 0: Yeah built with a spiral pattern in the middle Perhaps but Pax Ramon is fun.
Speaker 0: I very much enjoyed it for a quick read and I don't know Like I'm saying.
Speaker 1: how much is it?
Speaker 0: Ah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: like it can't be more than like 10 or 15 bucks I'll put.
Speaker 1: I'll put an Amazon link up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I put up an Amazon link.
Speaker 1: It's worth buying And that'll be that.
Speaker 0: yeah, I mean, I like bananas, but I need popsicles.
Speaker 0: I Think we'll.
Speaker 0: we'll turn it off there.
Speaker 0: This is the geek.
Speaker 0: nights will be weird and crazy for a while until we get situated.
Speaker 0: So I'll probably make the audio quality of the Skype and a little better next time we do this.
Speaker 0: And before we go we should do the meta moment really briefly because we forgot about the meta.
Speaker 0: We said I said, alright, let's not forget to do the meta moment.
Speaker 0: Scott's like yes We will do the meta moment and then we did things of the day that we didn't do it.
Speaker 1: All right, so meta moment, let's see number one episodes may or may not come out regularly while we are moving.
Speaker 0: We're gonna do whatever two episodes per week.
Speaker 0: We are feeling it'll be kind of all over the place.
Speaker 1: Yep What else is a meta moment person who won the ad contest?
Speaker 1: I will deliver to you the prizes once you know, I you know, the books are currently in Beacon and It's gonna be you know a little bit before I am able to mail them to you, but it should be early next month.
Speaker 0: and Anything else I Just want to point out because it is Wednesday.
Speaker 0: We are a while ago, but we're gonna announce it here, too.
Speaker 0: We have officially opened panel submissions for kinetic on 2010 because in case you don't recall We are the heads of panels for kinetic on 2010.
Speaker 0: It's us.
Speaker 0: the buck stops with us.
Speaker 0: if you think you can do an awesome panel Submit a panel and maybe we'll let you do it Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: We can never again ever complain about the panels at kinetic on because there's no one to complain to but ourselves or You know, maybe someone up above us.
Speaker 0: There's only one person above us maybe two.
Speaker 0: there's programming and then the con chair.
Speaker 1: Yeah even though Trying to think I had some other metamoment, but I forgot it.
Speaker 0: so oh, maybe you need the metamucil.
Speaker 1: maybe I should go.
Speaker 1: Know what though, you know all the places around here?
Speaker 1: They're still open and I could just walk down there and get whatever I need in like two minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I could take your car and I guess drive like to fish kill to get something if I needed it.
Speaker 1: Not in a couple hours.
Speaker 0: Now I could go to the shop, right?
Speaker 0: It's open to like one.
Speaker 1: I don't know about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've been over there late before.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's not 24/7 Cat I guess I could do if I drove 45 minutes.
Speaker 0: there's a stop-and-shop that's open 24/7.
Speaker 0: Oh, I guess.
Speaker 0: so Yeah, if I drive all the way up like through Wappingers and everything Oh, well, so we're done here.
Speaker 1: I think yep.
Speaker 0: I'll just tell it stuff.
Speaker 0: Okay, this has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.