Speaker 0: It's Wednesday March 25th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and this is geek night tonight cooking master boy and chrome shelled reggios.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Today was a good day.
Speaker 1: I uh, I worked from home.
Speaker 1: So if my commute was like Zero seconds.
Speaker 1: My commute was also zero seconds Well Then we're both doing very well for ourselves.
Speaker 0: No, not really.
Speaker 0: I'm doing a good bag zero.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm doing stuff that you know, it's just not stuff that's making a lot of money or any money It makes it.
Speaker 1: you're making money.
Speaker 0: What money am I making?
Speaker 1: by driving me to the kybo you made a kybo sandwich worth of money?
Speaker 0: I guess that's a that's that's still much much less than I would make even at McDonald's.
Speaker 0: Well Yeah, still day two of no job.
Speaker 0: and you know, even though rim was home today Which is not gonna be a very common thing It was sort of strange and coincidental that in fact the week that you had the one day at home was also, you know The week I lost my job.
Speaker 0: the second day of losing the job, I guess Yeah, I got too used to it though.
Speaker 1: I don't want to go back to work tomorrow.
Speaker 0: I know right?
Speaker 0: I don't have to go back to work tomorrow.
Speaker 0: But at the same time.
Speaker 0: it's not it's not so good.
Speaker 1: At least there's that relief of if you had a long-running project on some bad code and you know that you never have to worry About it.
Speaker 0: I know it's like it's weird.
Speaker 0: It's like a great way has been.
Speaker 0: it's like it's like the Simpsons right remove the stone Whatever it was right.
Speaker 0: the stone in the stonecutters episode Yeah, and Homer's like whoo and like a great stone has been lifted like attach the stone of something else and a much bigger stone.
Speaker 0: So it's like yes, I never have to look at that fucking code again.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Oh, I have no money Fuck money.
Speaker 0: Fuck fuck.
Speaker 0: anyway You know and while I am spending my time, you know I've actually done a lot of job hunting and and such and such and I made it done having super productive, you know.
Speaker 0: And except you know, I'm gonna clean the kitchen in the bathroom and getting so much shit done.
Speaker 0: I even got a dentist appointment tomorrow and I'm gonna see some guy in the city Save that on Friday.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I'll talk about that after it happens because it's bound to be hilarious yeah, but At the same time, you know, it's sitting at home all day alone is not?
Speaker 0: it's not so great.
Speaker 0: You know even sitting in the office doing nothing is at least there's people there.
Speaker 1: Well, you could go out go to like a Starbucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can only do that like once a day.
Speaker 0: You can't do that.
Speaker 0: Oh, you mean now that I'm unemployed?
Speaker 1: Yeah, just like go to Starbucks or go to like borders and then laptop it all day.
Speaker 0: I guess I could.
Speaker 1: it's like Nobody's gonna ask you to do anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's a little bit far away and it's not.
Speaker 0: I can get a lot more work done with my desktop and my laptop Just a laptop.
Speaker 0: I can't get as much work done.
Speaker 1: It's bring the desktop and film it.
Speaker 0: I could but I've people.
Speaker 0: people have done that already.
Speaker 0: It's not it's not really my my gig anyway.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so, you know I said hey, I need to get some you know, so I started using suffice to say and Twitter some more.
Speaker 0: You know, I stopped using it for a long time, but now I'm kind of using it again.
Speaker 0: Also because you know, I'm just trying to do things to strengthen my network and strengthen the community.
Speaker 0: You know cuz that helps get a job the thing among other things things that this community needs more.
Speaker 0: So now because even everybody even if that doesn't, you know, get me a job, you know.
Speaker 0: or help me get a job Which you could.
Speaker 0: right it can't hurt.
Speaker 0: That's for sure.
Speaker 0: You know, it'll really help.
Speaker 0: if what?
Speaker 0: if my attempt at self-employment, you know The bigger and stronger community I have to is like a bigger head start on that.
Speaker 0: You know, especially if I'm in the business of making websites, you know I can get sort of more people to use the website right away and if I can get that starting critical mass That'll explode all over the webs.
Speaker 0: if my site is actually good and useful and people like it, you know.
Speaker 0: So that's I've been doing that.
Speaker 0: so I said hey I got this webcam and every use and I turned on to you stream and basically, you know, I just you streamed all day and I Observation one.
Speaker 1: a lot of our listeners did not seem to realize that I pretty much never wear pants ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah You've learned something but rims get this is it was just weird that I happened to do it on the day when rim was also Home, I can't even think about the fact that he was home today when I did it.
Speaker 1: Well, I was working.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, but I think I'm gonna do is I'm just gonna.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna use stream my brains out The the bandwidth was totally cool.
Speaker 0: So I'm just gonna use stream like crazy, you know, not constantly, right?
Speaker 0: I turned it off right now for the show because you know, it doesn't work so well with the laptop.
Speaker 0: I'm surprised it didn't work so well in Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: That's kind of sad.
Speaker 0: the video work, but not the audio which is really strange You know, but it works downstairs in the living room on the Mac.
Speaker 0: It works in my bedroom, right?
Speaker 0: So I'm just gonna use stream and have a little unemployment day counter up there, you know.
Speaker 0: So today was day two.
Speaker 0: tomorrow will be day three.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna do Watching us watch some bad anime that we're gonna talk about.
Speaker 0: and actually as a side effect you stream Creates an IRC channel for every show.
Speaker 0: so even when the show even when we're not streaming I guess we have an IRC channel now, which I guess Is there.
Speaker 0: and then I don't know how to close the IRC channel if that's such a thing as possible But you know.
Speaker 0: So the video will be on and off depending on what I'm doing and I'll try to keep it on Most of the day when I'm sitting at the computer or whatever I'm not always looking at it or paying attention to the chat, but you know have it on it doesn't hurt You know, and I just I'm gonna use stream it up until I get a job and you know, maybe Maybe something will happen.
Speaker 0: Maybe it'll.
Speaker 0: it'll go somewhere, you know, maybe someone will give me a job.
Speaker 0: Maybe it'll get some publicity like, you know guy goes on you stream marathon to get job in bad economy or you know Something like that.
Speaker 0: or maybe it becomes a telethon and people start sending me money So not to work like, you know, the Scott tries to become self-employed.
Speaker 0: You stream telethon everyone send Scott money watch him work on this new website and if we send him enough the website will come to be and Then Scott will be self-employed and everyone will have a great new website to waste their time on.
Speaker 0: and anyway Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 0: We'll see where this goes.
Speaker 0: But all you have to know is that I'm you stream and you can watch my you stream and join the IRC channel.
Speaker 1: But more importantly and this was actually in place before Scott decided to or be came whether or not he decided or not unemployed.
Speaker 1: But April 1st, we've got some fun things planned for you guys.
Speaker 0: Yes, it is not Everyone is as obvious right.
Speaker 0: April 1st is April Fool's Day.
Speaker 0: We're not doing a stupid April Fools.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna like go into this live episode and hear any sort of Rick roll.
Speaker 0: No, because I mean you hear us ever on a listen to the old April Fool's Day shows, right?
Speaker 0: We were always like, uh, the internet was useless today.
Speaker 0: There were all these obviously fake things, you know It's only good in April Fool's Day if you're actually fooling someone.
Speaker 0: to say it.
Speaker 0: the way that Fark and board game geek fooled people Right, you know slashed out with their fake news stories is not fooling anyone, right?
Speaker 0: So it's totally lame and we hate it.
Speaker 0: and you know We're announcing we're like we're telling you straight up in advance.
Speaker 0: We're doing this streaming live geek nights on April 1st.
Speaker 0: You know probably sometime and you know between I guess five and nine or who knows what maybe around seven ish Eastern Time, right?
Speaker 0: so if We do try to fool you you'll see it coming a mile away.
Speaker 0: So either a it's an it's a fool worthy of April Fool's Day B We're not fooling anyone which is I can tell you right.
Speaker 0: it right away.
Speaker 0: We're not fooling anyone.
Speaker 1: I think you're building up way too much for this.
Speaker 0: I just want to let people know because they're very suspicious or see it's gonna be really lame and we're gonna fool you stupidly.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, we won't do that.
Speaker 1: if they wanted to know the rationale we were thinking alright We're gonna have all this stuff together.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do something cool.
Speaker 1: Let's do it at the beginning of next month Like okay and it happened to be March.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 0: So anyway we got.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so on April 1st, we're gonna do a cool streaming live geek nights.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be an ask Grim and Scott type of thing for at least a portion of it and We're gonna use Twitter and suffice to say in the you stream chat and whatever other Communication means we've got going on to ask us questions Which we will answer live with video and then we'll probably record it and put the episode up on the following day.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: All right news down, but it's a manga comics night as you all know and There's actually for once a lot of interesting anime news.
Speaker 1: now I want to bring this up first because usually I ignore these sorts of things but For someone who's an anime fan if you don't really know what's going on in Japan or you watch anime, but you don't really Connect what you're watching and what's popular here with what is popular among normal Japanese people.
Speaker 1: So I'm looking at a recent listing of across all of television.
Speaker 1: What anime are actually popular in Japan?
Speaker 1: What are the most watched shows right now?
Speaker 0: It's not Naruto.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: Number one is the obvious as always says I saw it says I son people don't know this.
Speaker 0: Sasaisan is basically The Simpsons in Japan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: I mean, so That's you know, you don't see.
Speaker 0: it talked about a lot in the anime community because it's not a nerdy anime show.
Speaker 0: It doesn't look like a nerdy anime show, but it is an animated show in Japan with a bajillion episodes.
Speaker 0: That is like The Simpsons of Japan and that it's.
Speaker 0: it's the number one show.
Speaker 1: Yep, number two is chibi maruko-chan, which is pretty much another Simpsons II show.
Speaker 1: It's another just popular generic.
Speaker 1: everyone watches a show.
Speaker 0: and then the old crayon Shin-cha, yep, another wide mass appeal show of humor that is not in a typical anime visual style.
Speaker 1: Yep, right next of course door.
Speaker 1: I'm on.
Speaker 0: yep, all that's like Sesame Street, right?
Speaker 1: So all the children's watching that one and then anime seven now That is basically detective Conan and yatter man.
Speaker 0: Oh, so in other words like, you know, so you've got Door I'm on which is basically like for the Barney crowd and then you've got anime seven for the middle school elementary school You know.
Speaker 0: later on crowd like, you know, the the sort of not yet teenage boys and then gay gay gay.
Speaker 1: No key.
Speaker 0: So the elementary school boys again.
Speaker 0: Yep
Speaker 1: thing is I much prefer hakava But this is what people in Japan
Speaker 0: yellow gay gay gays for the kiddies, you know, and hakava is for you know, serious
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can you can tell because hakava is where the cat girl is scary and it doesn't end happily gay gay gay.
Speaker 1: the cat Girl is just a cute girl.
Speaker 1: It can turn into a cat.
Speaker 1: Yep, and then finally something one piece But people would actually recognize.
Speaker 0: there you go.
Speaker 0: Not but again who's watching that?
Speaker 0: all the kitties?
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 0: No, what's the highest otaku show?
Speaker 1: The highest otaku show is right after that fresh free.
Speaker 1: It looks like girls fighting.
Speaker 1: I can't tell it's okay.
Speaker 0: So then it's.
Speaker 0: it's some show.
Speaker 0: that's on late at night.
Speaker 0: That's all my way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I don't even know it's not late at night.
Speaker 1: But then after that is some baseball show.
Speaker 1: All right, and then Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm sorry Pokemon.
Speaker 0: That's pretty low for Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well Pokemon's old Real old.
Speaker 0: speaking of Pokemon just real quick right.
Speaker 0: Pokemon platinum just came out and Pokemon platinum is basically the same thing.
Speaker 0: You know, they seem to have this pattern right where they'll they'll be a new Pokemon game, right?
Speaker 0: So they'll put out two colors diamond pearl red blue, right?
Speaker 0: Gold silver and then a little while later They'll put out a third one.
Speaker 0: So this platinum is basically the same as diamond and pearl but it has like a bunch of improvements.
Speaker 0: It's not actually a new game, but it's got like a little bit better.
Speaker 1: And wait improvements like what.
Speaker 1: like I don't have to level up all my Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Well, no, it's first of all, right.
Speaker 0: This is what I've heard.
Speaker 0: This is what I know from people of talking right pogeyman's as the battle text is faster.
Speaker 0: Oh my god There's better animations on the moves that the Pokemon do.
Speaker 0: there's a few new dungeons that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: All right, so I realized what I'm gonna do is the next time this Pokemon a new Pokemon series There's gonna be two colors.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna skip those because I can't buy the platinum now.
Speaker 0: I already have diamond.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're not gonna play.
Speaker 0: it would be stupid, right?
Speaker 0: But if I would have waited and not gotten diamond and just gotten platinum.
Speaker 0: I would have been so much better off.
Speaker 0: So next time I'm when the two colors come out I'm gonna skip it and when the third one comes out that improves upon the two colors I'll get that one.
Speaker 0: and that's the Pokemon plan from Scott.
Speaker 1: That is a brilliant plan and it is behind it 100%.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you're gonna follow the same plan though.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think I'm done with Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Ah Pokemon, it's okay.
Speaker 1: I played halfway through the original and I watched ash.
Speaker 0: Well, you're gonna read Pokemon adventures, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's my news.
Speaker 1: already read Pokemon adventures all the way up through yellow Yellow cover, yeah, he's okay, but he's no red.
Speaker 0: No, he's no red Giovanni.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so More sad is that.
Speaker 1: well, it's good for us as anime fans, but it's terrible for us as gaming fans.
Speaker 1: But you might all remember Professor Layton.
Speaker 1: They made these.
Speaker 1: it was this game.
Speaker 1: It was a puzzle game on the DS and it looked.
Speaker 1: it was very anime II and very Stylish in the like Ghibli esque fashion.
Speaker 1: It's not Ghibli, but it's Ghibli esque in that kind of like wholesome fun.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 0: I liked it Yeah, like.
Speaker 1: the style was good like Lupin the third castle of Cagliostro that style of you know, there's an adventure.
Speaker 1: let's go with the awesome characters and If you like that sort of thing you'd like this game.
Speaker 1: if you don't like puzzle games because it's also got all that style and all these little movies and story in it and People in America kind of forgot about that game because man I got that game.
Speaker 0: I like to have still been waiting because there's like three or four of them in Japan and I'm waiting.
Speaker 1: There's the deal in America.
Speaker 1: They released Layton.
Speaker 1: Nintendo marketed the ever-living fuck out of it.
Speaker 0: They had people on segues Driving around demos of it in the katsu khan dealers room.
Speaker 1: That's how hard they were pushing it also in the street around katsu khan and they built this giant interactive Floor projector thing to demo it and oh my god, it was everywhere.
Speaker 1: They were spending tons of money on marketing and They never released Layton - not yet.
Speaker 0: Anyway, or Layton three in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they released him in Japan, but not in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Yet.
Speaker 1: I don't think they did well in the u.s.
Speaker 1: I don't think they've recouped into money.
Speaker 1: They spent on marketing.
Speaker 1: I think I think they expected that the marketing effort would turn into this sort of like cult amazing game that everyone played.
Speaker 1: now It just disappeared.
Speaker 0: I want it.
Speaker 0: I liked it.
Speaker 1: I bought it Because that wasn't the most recent cops.
Speaker 0: don't release it now though.
Speaker 0: I have no money.
Speaker 1: That was a katsu khan ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was back when we had the where we were running stuff, of course We're doing stuff again to the next katsu khan.
Speaker 1: We may or may not be heading up a new department But we'll see.
Speaker 0: we'll see about that.
Speaker 1: That's all tentative Very very very very tentative, especially because Pax is offering more.
Speaker 0: Well, they're not competing with each other they are to a degree.
Speaker 1: I don't think I can manage the same thing for multiple conventions.
Speaker 0: Now just do the same thing twice or three, you know, yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 1: We'll see anyway.
Speaker 0: But it'd be hard to manage three different things with three different conventions.
Speaker 1: If you play Layton, all you can think is man.
Speaker 1: This would make a great anime.
Speaker 1: So they're making Layton kyoju to a and no time a professor Layton and the eternal songstress Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: The film is going to begin in Japan in 2010.
Speaker 1: The film is gonna be out I can assure you.
Speaker 1: we will review it post haste and then we'll go see it in the theater In the u.s.
Speaker 0: In the theater.
Speaker 1: Well, once it comes to the u.s.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be in the u.s.
Speaker 0: In the theater eventually.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, all big anime movies are in the u.s.
Speaker 1: In the theater in New York City.
Speaker 0: Oh, I thought it would go.
Speaker 0: I was expecting to get a fan.
Speaker 1: So yeah, well, we're gonna watch the fans up first like we always okay.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I'm really looking forward to this because the cutscenes alone in that game were so hot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this could be a good movie.
Speaker 0: I'm looking.
Speaker 0: I'm looking forward.
Speaker 1: I'm feeling like it'll feel like Cagliostro.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 1: I mean that's one of my favorite movies ever anime or not.
Speaker 1: And I don't know this has that kind of vibe.
Speaker 1: Yep, but speaking of movies that are getting an official American released Ponyo we talked about it.
Speaker 1: We reviewed it.
Speaker 1: we watched a pretty good cam cap that Emily's mom acquired of all people but It's actually going to be in US theaters in a somewhat wide release in August.
Speaker 0: Disney picked it up as they do forever.
Speaker 0: Miyazaki movie.
Speaker 1: Yep, so your Ghibli movie Miyazaki and Lassiter are going to be the executive producers.
Speaker 1: They're doing it.
Speaker 1: They're doing it the same way.
Speaker 1: They do for every Miyazaki movie.
Speaker 1: So really Shocker in August.
Speaker 1: I think August 14th is gonna open in a bunch of American theaters.
Speaker 0: Go see it, man They might have a pre showing at Otacon.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: That's that I just made that up just now.
Speaker 0: but did you?
Speaker 0: Otacon is in late July this year?
Speaker 1: Yeah, didn't?
Speaker 0: didn't?
Speaker 0: August 14th release come on.
Speaker 0: Otacon always has the pre-release movies.
Speaker 0: I can pretty much.
Speaker 0: I mean there's.
Speaker 0: I have no information that that confirms this whatsoever.
Speaker 0: I just thought of this just now.
Speaker 1: Here's the closest I have.
Speaker 0: I emailed a bunch of Otacon staff way back But I would bet that they will show Ponyo at Otacon.
Speaker 0: Ponyo.
Speaker 0: I will bet.
Speaker 1: Money's is so and you know what that.
Speaker 0: I'm an unemployed person.
Speaker 0: I will bet on that.
Speaker 1: I'll bet you a $1,000 they don't They.
Speaker 0: you're gonna bet they don't show it at Otacon.
Speaker 1: Will you put up $1,000?
Speaker 0: I Would if I wasn't unemployed.
Speaker 1: Oh, there we go.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'll bet but not that much.
Speaker 0: I'm a little all right.
Speaker 1: How about 900?
Speaker 0: You're not going far enough away.
Speaker 1: 1500. no, I uh, I don't know how to.
Speaker 1: But Ponyo is so worth seeing in the theater.
Speaker 1: This movie is beautiful.
Speaker 0: Yeah Definitely felt like I'm.
Speaker 0: there was a lot of the movie that we sort of missed out because it wasn't in you know With the bright colors so much in the video we had it.
Speaker 1: It's a great movie and I like it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: I got more anime news.
Speaker 1: If you don't have it.
Speaker 0: No, I got.
Speaker 0: I got this great news I want to talk about.
Speaker 0: it's a comics news comics.
Speaker 0: So, um Do you like baseball Jeff Lemire?
Speaker 1: Oh No No, there's no way.
Speaker 1: what I'm thinking is it?
Speaker 0: There's no way.
Speaker 0: there's no way.
Speaker 1: what is there gonna be a hockey comic?
Speaker 0: no No, it's a non hockey comment.
Speaker 0: I don't care anymore.
Speaker 0: Well, he's got no care anymore.
Speaker 1: Is he making a comic?
Speaker 0: he's got two comics.
Speaker 0: So for DC vertigo coming out In June.
Speaker 0: He's has a graphic novel called the nobody that's coming out and After that, he's gonna have an ongoing series called sweet tooth.
Speaker 0: Let me read you the description of sweet.
Speaker 0: - oh, no, I'm excited.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm excited even though I said I wasn't because sweet tooth is the story.
Speaker 0: You have to be hot.
Speaker 0: Gus a young boy born with deer-like antlers He's lived his entire life in total isolation in the woods with his father.
Speaker 0: as a story begins Gus is forced to leave the forest and sanctuary and begins experiencing the outside world for the first time He finds out there is.
Speaker 0: well what he finds out there is beyond comprehension An American landscape decimated a decade earlier by a mysterious disease.
Speaker 0: Even more remarkable is that Gus is part of a rare new breed of human animal hybrid children who have emerged in his wake.
Speaker 0: Who are immune to the disease?
Speaker 0: Hmm and he's taken in by a drifter who promises to lead him to the Preserve a fabled safe haven for hybrid children.
Speaker 0: along the way a larger mystery surrounds yada yada yada And that's you know, that's a Jeff Lemire is up to.
Speaker 1: I'm excited about that.
Speaker 1: now If you don't remember we've talked about him a bunch before but he did ghost stories, which was about people and their families at hockey in Canada and It was amazing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Essex County trilogy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I still haven't.
Speaker 0: I have the third volume sitting there.
Speaker 0: I got to reread all three of the volume.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I didn't read the third one yet, but actually I was checking out his blog.
Speaker 1: There's some good stuff going on here.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: He got pictures of a studio which is right next to his washing machine.
Speaker 0: He's a washing machine.
Speaker 0: he's got like a job that asshole.
Speaker 1: He's got his desk right and on the desk He's got like this giant drawing pad like angled up behind him washer dryer gigantic scanner Man that is like on the wall x-men poster.
Speaker 0: He's got a job.
Speaker 0: It's not fair.
Speaker 1: I'm looking forward to pretty much anything.
Speaker 1: He does.
Speaker 1: he has done me no wrong yet in terms of media.
Speaker 0: Yeah They have more exciting things from down to.
Speaker 0: the real interesting thing is that he was with top shelf.
Speaker 0: So he was like he was in the doing the indie stuff now.
Speaker 0: He's with vertigo.
Speaker 0: That's like he made.
Speaker 0: he's in the pros.
Speaker 0: It's going from the minor leagues of the big league.
Speaker 0: Yeah So, you know we were in on it.
Speaker 0: we we were so cool.
Speaker 0: you're in on it before he was cool You know, yes, we didn't.
Speaker 1: we met him.
Speaker 1: We didn't interview but we met him.
Speaker 1: Yeah that pretty much went.
Speaker 1: Hey, I like your car.
Speaker 0: pay attention to what geek nights comics we like because when geek comics we like We were into the cool stuff before it, you know becomes popular and then you can be the cool kid on the block Who is cool before it was cool to be cool.
Speaker 1: Actually, here's our secret.
Speaker 1: You want to be in on cool comics?
Speaker 1: Just come to New York and go to the mocha Festival.
Speaker 0: every also pre-order things because then you get everything two months in it.
Speaker 1: But the problem is you'll get a hundred bad things and one good thing.
Speaker 0: You got to know what to buy.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't get a.
Speaker 1: you don't know what to buy.
Speaker 1: Just go to the mocha festival and just walk around and it's obvious what to buy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So, uh, there's one more thing.
Speaker 1: I have to bring this up.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna make it to anime central.
Speaker 1: I haven't actually been to anime central since 2003.
Speaker 1: I think Damn Asens the con where we used I used to throw along with the dubbed this crew back in the day Wicked parties in the presidential suite threw at two parties.
Speaker 1: Yes, two years in a row two epic parties.
Speaker 1: The second one ended with the hotel Pulling the fire alarm to end our party.
Speaker 1: But I haven't been to a send in a while and I used to enjoy that con.
Speaker 1: but they've got a Musical act that I kind of want to go to a send.
Speaker 1: now they have move Back Initial D.
Speaker 0: I would go see that if I had money a concert that would be great.
Speaker 1: Move m dot o dot v dot e. So if you're in the if you're answered some move music in the show if you're in the Chicago, Illinois area You should go to anime central.
Speaker 1: It's as far as I remember.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty good time.
Speaker 1: They actually had way back.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they still do it, but they used to do Iron artists and they actually did it.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah anime central is a very good convention Perhaps the best in the Midwest.
Speaker 1: well because as I remember unless they changed it It's still a hotel con and hotel cons have that special charm over convention center con because they go all night.
Speaker 1: But anyway it is time for the Mormon Jesus.
Speaker 0: Mormon Jesus Mormon Jesus Mormon Jesus Long long long Jesus.
Speaker 0: long ago a spirit child on one of these landings was conceived Unidentified.
Speaker 0: God is on his body metal.
Speaker 0: Talk about your Jesus, huh?
Speaker 1: These sorts of mashups are always good.
Speaker 1: And this one's actually pretty well done.
Speaker 1: so I can't.
Speaker 1: it sticks in your head.
Speaker 1: There's something about Mormon Jesus doo doo doo doo plus MC hammer.
Speaker 1: Come on I don't know what else I can say.
Speaker 1: That's it The guy.
Speaker 1: if you watch the video the guy in red really looks like he's dancing to this music.
Speaker 1: It really fits.
Speaker 0: speaking of MC hammer, right?
Speaker 0: You know, I don't know if people realize just how popular MC hammer was back in the day But he hammers like was so so awesome.
Speaker 1: MC Hammer is possibly one of the most important human beings to have ever lived.
Speaker 0: Anyway hammer You know after he basically had a sort of a similar to Mike Tyson's story.
Speaker 0: only he wasn't a bad, dude He was a good dude.
Speaker 0: He just you know got famous got a bunch of money and lost all his money, right?
Speaker 0: Mike Tyson lost all his money because he was not a good person.
Speaker 0: MC hammer lost all his money because he was not frugal And he didn't keep track of his money very well.
Speaker 0: So after that MC hammer became like a preacher and such and such.
Speaker 0: right but he still had his dancing skills and singing skills Right.
Speaker 0: and in recent years MC hammer has been making this comeback on the internets.
Speaker 0: He's got internet skills.
Speaker 0: He's on the Twitter right and he's doing all sorts of internet stuffs.
Speaker 0: so I Was thinking man, why doesn't MC hammer just make a website where he teaches everyone how to fucking dance?
Speaker 1: Oh, did he do that?
Speaker 0: Actually, yes, he did.
Speaker 0: Hey if you go to dance jam calm It's just tons and tons of dancing videos.
Speaker 0: and this is site is MC hammer site.
Speaker 0: He's involved with it and You can go there and check out some dancing.
Speaker 0: and you know If you want to be all Napoleon Dynamite If you visit this side enough and stay in your room alone with the door closed for hours on end You'll come out like Napoleon Dynamite.
Speaker 1: you stream.
Speaker 0: Yeah, turn on you stream on one monitor and dance.
Speaker 0: jam on the other monitor and just keep going until you're MC hammer.
Speaker 1: I was kind of saying you should do that.
Speaker 1: You got free time.
Speaker 0: That's not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: I have to make website.
Speaker 0: Lean.
Speaker 1: I'm not a dancer.
Speaker 1: Shuffle the hammer pants.
Speaker 1: You know, you could do the hammer pants.
Speaker 1: Anyone can do that Yes And as long as they're too bad if there's my.
Speaker 0: I've already spent two days here, right and the website is still not done.
Speaker 0: So there's not gonna be a dancing anytime soon.
Speaker 1: You could dance while you're making the website.
Speaker 0: I could dance if I wanted to.
Speaker 1: You could leave your friends behind If your friends.
Speaker 0: Anyway dance jam calm.
Speaker 0: awesome dancing videos MC hammer.
Speaker 1: So Mormon Jesus aside we decided to actually watch just Mormon Jesus some Mormon Mormon Jesus.
Speaker 1: But we actually watched some anime.
Speaker 1: some of you were treated to watching us.
Speaker 1: Watch the anime on the you stream Yes, which had to be interesting because you couldn't see what we were seeing.
Speaker 1: you could just see what we were saying.
Speaker 1: hmm, anyway, we watched a new show and an old show and One was pretty good.
Speaker 1: One was pretty bad I don't know.
Speaker 0: I sort of think that they were all both sort of bad, but at least one was funny in its badness.
Speaker 0: But I think you just because it was old both shows are very stereotypical very predictable very anime cliche.
Speaker 0: One was old and humorous and one was new and painful.
Speaker 1: I guess the cliches of older shows while they are cliches and it depends on what what era and genre too, but the genre of Shonen fighting show from the 90s as opposed to Shonen fighting show from the 2000s.
Speaker 1: There's a big difference.
Speaker 0: I don't see such a big difference Not in the plot structure at least but in the way the episodes come together.
Speaker 0: and what clear you have to go to a Shonen fighting show from the 80s to get a different plot structure like.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's more that this show while it is a 90s show Harkins much more back to shows from the earlier 90s in the late 80s in terms of the cliches that it is using a little bit a little bit.
Speaker 0: But anyway, so the show the further we'll talk about that show first, right?
Speaker 1: We should talk.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should talk about the show that's less good first.
Speaker 1: I don't know This order.
Speaker 0: we watched him.
Speaker 0: All right, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: So we watch.
Speaker 1: I kind of like this show.
Speaker 0: Do you really you would?
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: would you watch another episode of it?
Speaker 1: Uh-huh?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I could see myself doing that really cuz.
Speaker 0: I would not watch another episode.
Speaker 1: But at least got to get to the episode with the time.
Speaker 1: I got to find out what's up with the mobile Roshi Mobutofu.
Speaker 0: They got you.
Speaker 0: hey got you with the old Roshi.
Speaker 0: they got you Mobutofu.
Speaker 0: They got you with the old formula word Hanger.
Speaker 0: at the end of every episode they roped you in.
Speaker 0: you're such a sucker Suckers you ain't talking me gonna win the race guy.
Speaker 0: I know right?
Speaker 0: they suckered you in with that old trick And you know what?
Speaker 0: I've I know you at least.
Speaker 0: I knew I was getting suckered in and only did it once anyway, so We watch cooking master boy, which is a shonen fighting show about cooking.
Speaker 0: Yep, aka Chuka Ichiban There's plenty of shows out there about cooking.
Speaker 0: I mean that are very similar.
Speaker 0: I mean this can't be that.
Speaker 0: I mean, I've never saw seen that show.
Speaker 0: What's that one?
Speaker 0: Nippon The one about the bread.
Speaker 1: oh Yeah, yeah, I never saw it either.
Speaker 1: actually people keep talking about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, actually the second I think closer for the show.
Speaker 0: I watched that on YouTube.
Speaker 0: I was pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: But yeah, this is actually.
Speaker 1: it looks to me.
Speaker 1: I don't know it feels like an earlier 90s show, but it's actually from like the late 90s like 97 98 Yeah, and there's a lot a lot of similar things out there.
Speaker 0: I mean Ironwalk Jen and or whatever else you can come up with.
Speaker 0: but oh my god.
Speaker 1: There are 52 episodes.
Speaker 0: You want to watch them all?
Speaker 0: no, okay?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but cooking master boy.
Speaker 0: It's it takes place in China during the warring cooking States Literally.
Speaker 0: this is why it's funny.
Speaker 0: it starts
Speaker 1: with this opener, and they're like Chinese cuisine has spread throughout the world and the cores of it, and it shows like Canton and sash
Speaker 0: rod
Speaker 1: and it's very serious and building up and showing different regions of Japan and all this Fancy cooking animation all sell animated and then it cuts to this giant panorama And it explains that we are now in the period at the fall of the Manchu dynasty in the like cooking warring states period And the government like the government is very intertwined with cooking.
Speaker 1: as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: yeah It's just like an admiral or a general because the subtitles are broken when we watched it But we didn't need them to be working all right.
Speaker 0: This show is pretty straightforward and you know he basically orders this guy to go and to this to this restaurant and You know sort of take it over because the people at the restaurant are cooking.
Speaker 1: Basically sayonji from utenna walks in to this restaurant and first of all oh shit Everyone's like oh, no.
Speaker 1: It's him and they back away comes into the restaurant.
Speaker 1: He's like Give me whatever you dare to save me.
Speaker 1: It's hit like ratatouille in that way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like give me something I don't care what as long as it's good.
Speaker 0: They give him like the best stuff.
Speaker 0: They got it's no good.
Speaker 1: So he proceeds to wreck the place.
Speaker 0: yep, and he's like I'm in charge of this restaurant now I have the seal from General Lee.
Speaker 1: it is my restaurant now.
Speaker 0: Then General Lee shows up and General Lee is.
Speaker 0: oh first of all by the way while this is going on the main Character is not there.
Speaker 0: He's up on a mountain collecting mushrooms that are like the tastiest mushrooms from the growing on the side of a mountain that he had To climb.
Speaker 0: you know they look like some pretty good mushroom right anyway General Lee shows up And he's like.
Speaker 0: I think you misunderstood me.
Speaker 0: I was telling you you know I didn't put my seal on that order yet You have to prove that you're better Than the people at this restaurant in order for me to sign to put my seal on that order.
Speaker 1: and that statement is backed Up by this man's eyebrows.
Speaker 0: Oh yes.
Speaker 0: Oh yes indeed, so he's like oh of course I can beat these crappy cooks here.
Speaker 0: What do you want me to make you?
Speaker 0: he's like fried rice?
Speaker 1: So this guy they and they spend a lot of time animating this cook.
Speaker 0: yeah It's like other times or sometimes during the show you'll get a still shot of like General Lee's face.
Speaker 0: That's not moving while someone else talks right and that still frame will be there for a good 10 20 seconds.
Speaker 0: right but When he does someone's cooking they animate the fuck out of it.
Speaker 0: flying locks like motion blur Ladles this guy's story.
Speaker 1: it cuts to a flashback.
Speaker 1: We lost all our subtitles at this point, but basically He takes off his eyepatch, and he's got this burn scarred eye in hand and he's like.
Speaker 1: you don't remember You don't know.
Speaker 1: and then we get the flashback of him as a kid but he's just as pissed off and sneering and he's cooking and he's pissed off and The mother is like you shouldn't cook that way You're gonna hurt yourself like you're not the boss of me mom, and then he immediately burns his face off.
Speaker 0: Yep Yeah, it's like sets his whole body on fire because he gets oil on himself, and it's it's a bad situation.
Speaker 0: So now he's coming back to this restaurant to get his revenge this
Speaker 1: Lobster shrimp crab fried rice and there's this scene where you know he cooks it And it's all together and he gives it to admiral Lee and there's all this big presentation and admiral Lee like opens it And he takes a bite and it cuts.
Speaker 1: it was almost a gecky guy moment.
Speaker 1: It cuts to his face like a close-up You know the close-up where you get like from the edge of the nose to the edge of the face And then you see like the eye and that's it.
Speaker 1: you get like a close-up of one eye and a little bit of the mouth Yep, and he closes his eyes, and he sits there for a second, and then he opens him like
Speaker 0: And like this nuke goes off and then like the word delicious scrolls by you get like this golden letters.
Speaker 1: first You get this pet this giant sea view and then a tsunami coming in and then behind the tsunami a volcano explodes.
Speaker 0: Yes, they use video and audio because you know you can't get flavor vision right which would be the ultimate for a cooking show Right to just send the flavor into the viewers mouth.
Speaker 0: You know if that ever wasn't?
Speaker 0: you know really?
Speaker 0: if I was the Food Network I would put all my money into that because if that existed the Food Network would be the number one channel and forever People just sit at home watching the Food Channel Just like tasting it's done smelling everything that these gourmet chefs go.
Speaker 1: Then you have what is set up to be the best hack ever.
Speaker 0: The most like this would be the hack everyone's TVs to make it taste like shit.
Speaker 1: What I was going to say very simply is one word.
Speaker 1: I was going to say poop yep, and leave it at that.
Speaker 1: so anyway, so Yo, you know the guys close.
Speaker 1: He opens his eyes and like yes, you will take over this restaurant.
Speaker 1: the kids like And he eats it and the same thing happens to him like it's too good It's too good, and I mean this is some awesome fried rice.
Speaker 0: He had lobsters and crabs and shrimps.
Speaker 0: and but somehow he like got rid of the fishy flavor.
Speaker 0: So it like had all this seafood in it But it didn't taste fishy and it was like this ultimate awesome fried rice of all.
Speaker 1: yes But then the kid is like but but wait a minute, and it shows you all these like.
Speaker 1: he's like.
Speaker 0: It's very sad subtitle so we didn't know exactly what he was saying.
Speaker 1: but remember in Samurai Jack when he closes his eyes and he listens and bit by bit the scene like Fills out around him as he hears all the things going on.
Speaker 1: yep It was like that with food where you see the flavor.
Speaker 1: He's like yes, I play There's the crab, and there's the shrimp, and there's the rice, but wait a minute wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Cilantro was it's a lot.
Speaker 0: I think about it in cilantro.
Speaker 1: That's my guess.
Speaker 1: It could have been covered it up with cilantro.
Speaker 1: and as soon as he says that the admiralee has that you know shonen Where there's like the red line goes
Speaker 0: exactly what it was, but there was a picture of a green herb on the screen and Obviously there was some sort of suggestion that there was not something imperfect about this incredibly delicious fried rice.
Speaker 1: Yes, and admiralee is stern but fair.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 0: So so he's like okay.
Speaker 0: You know the basically what happens to?
Speaker 0: the kid is now going to make fried rice to beat this dude's fried Rice right now.
Speaker 0: I thought the kid was going to use the amazing mushrooms.
Speaker 0: He got from the side of the.
Speaker 1: no That's episode two.
Speaker 1: He's probably gonna use that in the mob horror.
Speaker 0: No mobile tofu Possibly possibly, but he said he goes to make the kid the main character goes to make some fried rice.
Speaker 0: So what does he do?
Speaker 0: of course as in all the cooking shows?
Speaker 1: It's it's ready to eat.
Speaker 0: the really perfect simple dish always beats the complicated fancy gourmet dish.
Speaker 0: I mean you see this happen in in a comic.
Speaker 0: I read a while ago Wonton soup.
Speaker 0: right that's what hat.
Speaker 0: that's what happens.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: so He's gonna make the really simple dish really well, and it's gonna beat out the gourmet dish.
Speaker 1: He just makes egg fried rice, but just makes egg fried rice.
Speaker 1: It's the recipe what his mom taught him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the mom who is the mom who I think is the same person that was involved with the burning of the angry guy Yep, so I came back to get his revenge.
Speaker 0: mom is dead now because they have a picture of mom They're holding on to.
Speaker 0: I think mom's dead now anyway.
Speaker 0: So he makes fried rice, and he make you know we're just egg and fried rice and some soy Whatever.
Speaker 0: now when they bring this out like they bring out the dish and and we're leaves well No, but when they brought out the first dish right it was covered and they lifted the cover And it's like perfectly symmetrical.
Speaker 0: amazing steam came out, right.
Speaker 0: But when the kids golden fried rice comes out that he made with just egg It's like this exploding golden pillar of light that shoots into the sky.
Speaker 0: yeah And then the rice itself looks like gold flakes.
Speaker 1: it doesn't look like rice and admirably is like it is Golden fried rice.
Speaker 0: yeah, but the other guys like don't be fooled by the way.
Speaker 0: It looks It's just.
Speaker 0: you know he made it all golden with you know egg.
Speaker 0: It's not really that great.
Speaker 0: It's real simple golden fried rice Before.
Speaker 0: I can't compare with my fancy seafood fried rice.
Speaker 1: when he ate the other guy's dish right and he closes his eye and bites It I was hoping for the gecky guy moment because the gecky guy moment is the same thing that happens in Giant Robo where you have the the stoic man hero standing there And he has his eyes closed and then he does something and the tear comes out of the eye from the close-up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you didn't get that I didn't expect that from this show.
Speaker 1: He bites into the golden rice and the the gecky got here comes out.
Speaker 0: that was epic.
Speaker 0: It was only really only epic as we called it.
Speaker 0: But you know pretty much the rice was not only delicious, but it brought back all his memories.
Speaker 0: So the nostalgic awesome power of the goal of the simple Perfect golden fried rice brought out the man tear and won over the general to the side of the main character.
Speaker 1: Anytime you get the close-up of the one eye, and then the tears come down.
Speaker 1: That's a good.
Speaker 1: It has to be.
Speaker 1: you know the very stoic face the eyes closed.
Speaker 1: moment of realization Single tear.
Speaker 1: yep very crying Freeman.
Speaker 0: Crying Freeman had frickin rivers, but both eyes.
Speaker 0: He didn't have.
Speaker 1: yeah, but you know there, and I haven't read crying Freeman There's got to be at least one shot.
Speaker 0: where he closes his eye and like the tears begin It's usually he kills someone and then they cut back to his face, and there's like rivers, and that's usually how it goes.
Speaker 0: Anyway crying from it.
Speaker 1: of course this doesn't resolve it and admiralee's like well blah blah blah challenge challenge.
Speaker 1: We had no subtitles at this point, but what I gathered was that they are now going to have to cook Mobutofu and the kid has this like it was.
Speaker 0: I guess I'm not used to seeing first the kids like yeah I'm awesome at tofu.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, but I watched so much new anime I forgot about.
Speaker 1: I guess the old style of chibi like old anime used to go to Chibi at a certain kind of way and new anime do it in this totally different way for the most part.
Speaker 1: But this was an old-school like cheap cheap cheap cheap cheap cheap cheap.
Speaker 1: He's like yeah, yeah, yeah, I can make the tofu yes, and then admiralee is like no You're not just making Mobutofu basically.
Speaker 1: I heard you know I don't I don't understand much Japanese blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah Mabaroshi.
Speaker 1: no Mobutofu Did he say Mabaroshi?
Speaker 0: That's dream right.
Speaker 0: so it's like the dream tofu or mystery or mystery.
Speaker 1: I'll look it up again.
Speaker 1: It's a word that I hear a lot in anime.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it's dream or something, but it's like yeah It's like five or six flavors to be honest mysterious tofu I don't know.
Speaker 0: But it has like five or six flavors or seven flavors or something and they were like seven factors by which he would judge the tofu And it's like oh my god like hotness.
Speaker 0: and uh so that's probably what the next episode is gonna Be is is the tofu battle and somehow he's gonna have a lot of struggles But then he's gonna pull it off in the end by some miracle is gonna make the great illusion fantasy Mirage.
Speaker 1: Yeah anyway, oh Oh much better.
Speaker 1: Oh never mind.
Speaker 1: I found a translation.
Speaker 1: That was actually wrong.
Speaker 0: I Never mind that all right, so yeah That's that's cooking master boy.
Speaker 0: if you want to watch one of those it mean it's a stereotypical Shonen fighting cooking show.
Speaker 0: it's just like all the other ones fun You know what it is.
Speaker 1: it is a show that if you run an anime club you show the first Episode of this at your club and everyone goes And yells during it or you get all your friends over, and you watch it.
Speaker 1: Don't watch it by yourself.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not.
Speaker 0: actually it's not a quality show, but you know it's a formula show But it executes the formula rather well And if you're an anime fan there is a lot of humor to be extracted from it.
Speaker 1: it also It gave me an enjoyment.
Speaker 1: This is definitely a nostalgic enjoyment in the same way that birdie the mighty deco Did.
Speaker 1: that it kind of brought me back into anime that I liked not so much because it was better necessarily But because I watched it when I was the right age to watch it.
Speaker 0: Sort of like the same feeling you get when you eat golden fried rice.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: So the next it's not actually that as great as the seafood fried rice.
Speaker 0: I'm you see but your memories of it are us power cause it to bring out the power.
Speaker 1: So if I ever watch the about the new like bubblegum crisis remake whatever I'll have to close my eyes and shed that single tear.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, so then we watched a generic show Chrome shelled reggios.
Speaker 1: It's exactly like every other generic crappy anime.
Speaker 0: This is the most Generic anime I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: it pretty much has every generic anime thing that you could have like it was.
Speaker 1: it was painful it I don't even know so well.
Speaker 1: it stood out a little bit.
Speaker 1: it starts right and Typically, you know some sort of action scene going on and then they cut to someone who's going to be one of the main characters Like cowering.
Speaker 1: you see like ten anime start that way like fighting going on.
Speaker 1: main characters actually badass But not badass yet.
Speaker 1: and badassness is hidden and they're cowering and they're gonna be afraid.
Speaker 0: So you've got this this bus I guess and it's being attacked by a big bug monster filth monster.
Speaker 0: Hi, it's a bug.
Speaker 0: It's like Starship Troopers.
Speaker 0: And you see this big lineup of like mystical powerful people and there's like a whole bunch of them and they're like 20 of them.
Speaker 0: There's basically one.
Speaker 0: for every single stereotype.
Speaker 0: you can find dude, dude with a sword dude with monofilament wire Dude with psychic powers dude with mystical spiritual powers, and there's just can't do it with fucking guns.
Speaker 0: Dude with a dude in a robot suit.
Speaker 0: you got every single stereotypical Combat anime character lined up.
Speaker 1: don't even do anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like only three or four of them are doing anything and they fight the bug monster.
Speaker 1: Oh, and it's all full of proper noun gobbledygook.
Speaker 1: It's me.
Speaker 1: It's do the.
Speaker 1: do the blah on the blah, but watch out for the blah.
Speaker 1: We'll have to beat him by using blah and blah together.
Speaker 1: But such a thing.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Well, what if we blind?
Speaker 1: Let's do it.
Speaker 0: Don't use your full power.
Speaker 0: Oh, but now I have to use my full power.
Speaker 1: As you know, it is an insult in Japan to use your full power at any moment other than the last possible.
Speaker 0: Yeah more so than anything else I think yeah anyway so that it starts out there.
Speaker 0: But then it cuts away from that to this completely unrelated school military school.
Speaker 0: That's also a regular school.
Speaker 1: Well, it's basically all right.
Speaker 1: It's a high school that's run by students a la utenna and I'm pretty sure I had to look it up I'm pretty sure the headmaster who is actually just like a senior in the school.
Speaker 0: Who's talking here?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yes I'm like 99% sure that that is pumpkin head.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know I aka Takahashi Rios K aka every cool person in every but mint.
Speaker 0: Ah Yeah People know that we love Takahito Kiyosu.
Speaker 1: Takahito Kiyosu is second only to Akira Kamiya in my eyes.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's also - day that guy.
Speaker 0: Oh, I forget that guy's name, but I reckon I like I if you told me his name.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: It's a name that I recognize but I can't just recall it from nothing.
Speaker 0: cuz that guy's like.
Speaker 0: if you told me the name if I like if you walked up to me on the street and said who Is and said the name I would say that's the guy who is Chiyo Chan's dad.
Speaker 1: We didn't recognize who he was until we were watching Baccano and that guy's like carol Dorshte and we're like, it's him.
Speaker 1: It has to be Yeah, that guy could say Dorshte really like.
Speaker 0: I can't come up with his name But if you give me the name, I can tell you who it is.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I'll start calling him carol Anyway, but but this guy is he's like a toga I guess and he runs the school because it's a student-run school and there's military people and non-military people And there's all this high school bullshit.
Speaker 1: and then some people fight.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course, like, you know these.
Speaker 0: the guy who you know, isn't obviously the most powerful really is the most powerful But he doesn't know it yet and he joins like their lowest of the lowest ranks in the school.
Speaker 0: You know by you know chance and of course that's gonna.
Speaker 0: you know The lowest of the lows are gonna be awesome now.
Speaker 0: And there's also drama because like the does it the quiet sort of mystical Mystery girl is also in that same squadron and she's the sister of the headmaster guy.
Speaker 0: So it's you know typical, you know, the scrappy low low end of the totem pole is gonna beat out.
Speaker 0: you know the high and mighty heads of the totem pole who are so sure of themselves and already powerful and Yawn.
Speaker 1: at this point they have introduced So many characters that I had no idea I only recognized like a few of them Recognize the short quiet mystical girl with the cherry blossoms quite mystical girl.
Speaker 0: the head of the lowest end Squadron like the 17th squadron.
Speaker 0: that girl The headmaster guy headmaster guy and the you know, the new guy who's all powerful secretly But that's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: All the other guys are nothing has the exact same face and haircut as the guy from Kazanoyo Jimbo Which was an okay show that suffered from I don't know.
Speaker 1: I got to make up on like a Quick like syndrome name for this but the show where you have a main character Who's basically invincible and all-powerful and badass and just kicks everybody's ass all the time in every episode.
Speaker 0: I mean every show not every show.
Speaker 1: almost every show Trigon starts like that But then it's not like that anymore.
Speaker 1: a lot of shows are like that But it looks like the same person as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: I got to see who the character designer was for this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then again, it might just be generic anime character.
Speaker 0: So basically that plot continues a bunch and you know, of course the low powerful guy joins the the the you know The lowest end group and they're
Speaker 1: they cut back to the fight again Which by the way during the fight
Speaker 0: from the beginning of the episode
Speaker 1: they're placing they're playing like Sandstorm esque techno.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that's right.
Speaker 0: during the fighting scene that at the very beginning of the show Where you know, they had the bug monster and everything that's completely unrelated to this school so far.
Speaker 0: It's obviously gonna be related to the school later.
Speaker 1: It just sounds like Darude is playing in the back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it just it's like this super hyper techno.
Speaker 0: That's actually kind of good, but also kind of not so good.
Speaker 0: Then at the school, there's no techno.
Speaker 0: then after they're done with the school.
Speaker 0: They cut back to fighting the bug monster Has no connection to the school yet whatsoever.
Speaker 1: and then they introduced like a million weird mysteries.
Speaker 1: then they in the episode Yeah, that's it.
Speaker 0: they budget mysteries there's.
Speaker 0: they defeat the bug monster.
Speaker 1: they're like 10 or 15 Superpowered people fighting this bug monster.
Speaker 1: Oh and by the way in the school when I said some guys were fighting they all had superpowers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone's got some sort of superpower.
Speaker 1: Everyone has superpowers in this show as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: One guy has a big whip.
Speaker 0: one guy is an extending stick.
Speaker 0: You know one person can shoot flower petals.
Speaker 1: When I say big whip it is like 200 feet long.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's real long.
Speaker 1: But then during all this they keep cutting back to this line of even more super powered people who are standing there commenting on the fighting and then they act like maybe it's not a Fight really but like a contest or a test.
Speaker 1: and then I lost like all track of what was going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you had the two completely separate unrelated things going on you.
Speaker 0: the school plot Which is so generic predictable had the same characters as every other stupid anime.
Speaker 0: Everything that happened was totally predictable.
Speaker 0: saw coming a million miles away.
Speaker 0: The only interesting thing about it was Takahito Koyasu's voice, right?
Speaker 0: And then you had a separate plot of fighting a big bug monster and be not him All right.
Speaker 1: I'm looking into this.
Speaker 1: It might not have been him.
Speaker 1: There might be a sound alike up there is nevermind.
Speaker 0: Okay And then Completely detached at least in the first episode from the school plot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's him and it was just You know.
Speaker 0: unless you really really like Stereotypical generic right down the middle follow the formula, you know.
Speaker 1: action and school Anime, even if you like that watch one of the better ones.
Speaker 1: This one is like.
Speaker 1: at least watch like the best.
Speaker 0: This is so plain.
Speaker 0: It's like eat it.
Speaker 0: This is like white bread.
Speaker 1: It's Why it's a Wonder Bread.
Speaker 0: This is this is fucking Wonder Bread.
Speaker 0: this show, you know, totally predictable.
Speaker 0: Nothing new nothing exciting exactly what you'd expect.
Speaker 0: seen it a million times before.
Speaker 0: Not good, you know.
Speaker 0: at least you know, the cooking master boy was sort of like wheat bread, you know.
Speaker 0: It's like familiar seen it before but has a flavor this Flavorless.
Speaker 0: no good.
Speaker 1: Oh So the director.
Speaker 1: I was just poking around at what the guy who directed this monstrosity generic show.
Speaker 1: because usually when we see a show like this I'll look at the director and it'll be like generic guy.
Speaker 1: What did a bunch of generic stuff?
Speaker 1: Mmm, granted the person who did the original concept for cooking boy did to manga One of which is called tenchi.
Speaker 1: No fry pan.
Speaker 1: I'm all about that.
Speaker 0: tenchi no fry pan.
Speaker 0: That's much.
Speaker 0: That's a lot better than a lot of the other cooking show names out there.
Speaker 0: I mean even like iron wok.
Speaker 0: Jan doesn't compare to but tenchi no fry pan, but it's a row.
Speaker 1: Kawasaki Directed this monstrosity.
Speaker 1: He also did the chrono trigger OAV, which I heard was not good.
Speaker 0: I Heard it was terrible licensed by royalty, which was not good that show.
Speaker 1: I thought that show might have been so much potential.
Speaker 1: The cover of the first DVD had a lot of 10.
Speaker 0: that's correct.
Speaker 0: the cover art on the DVD had potential.
Speaker 1: I saw that and I thought is this gonna be another Read or die?
Speaker 0: no, sorry bad.
Speaker 1: No, he was the assistant director for please save my earth Which is weird because that show was like, I don't know weird and I don't want to say good But I kind of liked it because it was weird.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess it's good to.
Speaker 0: this show exists, you know, and that I'll remember it because usually you know You think of all these stereotypical anime things, right?
Speaker 0: Okay, we're saying that chrome shelled reggios is stereotypical and white bread, right?
Speaker 0: Which in cliche which means that the things it's doing have been done a million times before right?
Speaker 0: What show has done these things before?
Speaker 0: what name the show?
Speaker 1: I couldn't tell you, right?
Speaker 0: So now we have the show and someone when we find the cliche things we can say chrome shelled reggios That's the cliche.
Speaker 0: That's the show.
Speaker 0: That's the cliches.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there are so many shows and I forget the names.
Speaker 1: I mean, what was that show we watched where?
Speaker 1: It was almost the same.
Speaker 1: Remember we watch shows that are almost the exact same goddamn show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we have like it'd be tough to tell them apart like or remember coyote Ragtime show.
Speaker 0: that was yeah that that was but that had Sutton - it had the fact that like 11 maids Parachuted in from the sky.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah that one before that point.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's right I was alright.
Speaker 0: Cody ragtime show.
Speaker 0: you said Cody ragtime show, but I thought about cause the door de la bruja Oh, which was just noir three exactly just as bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, but yeah Cody ragtime show was stereotypical but in a in a different way.
Speaker 1: It had more going on than chrome shelled reggios, but what this guy did do this interesting I got to see which episodes those were but he directed four episodes in get sack second gig.
Speaker 0: He actually directed for the episode episode director for four episodes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but episode director is not the same as director direct.
Speaker 1: But that means that I got.
Speaker 1: we got to watch those episodes and see if there's any of him in them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm curious.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know, you can't give the director all the credit either.
Speaker 0: I mean who wrote?
Speaker 0: who wrote this.
Speaker 0: was it based on a manga?
Speaker 0: was it based on a book?
Speaker 1: It was based on a light novel.
Speaker 1: as far as I wrote.
Speaker 0: who wrote the light novel.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I didn't do any research.
Speaker 1: I'm digging through with the anime news network right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's how it is.
Speaker 0: There's no reason people can look on the anime network themselves.
Speaker 0: We don't need to Read we don't need to read the anime news.
Speaker 0: never get cyclopedia to people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm poking.
Speaker 0: All you need to know is that chrome-shelled reggios do not watch unless you really love.
Speaker 0: like the most Stereotypical things about anime.
Speaker 1: this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week Covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front road crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you Can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: Don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.