Speaker 1: Hey, it's Thursday July 9th on rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We would like to live forever, maybe we're not really sure so we did a show about.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: It's Thursday, so you might be wondering why I'm gonna bring this up But I'm not talking about it.
Speaker 1: the thing that I'm talking about is not the topic.
Speaker 1: the topic is the the manner in which the thing Was enacted.
Speaker 0: why do we you know?
Speaker 0: I think that's one thing we've always done in geek nights is whenever we're gonna talk about something We sort of delay saying what the something is.
Speaker 0: I know Why do we have that shtick?
Speaker 0: Where did that shtick come from?
Speaker 1: I was thinking why didn't I just say it?
Speaker 1: Where did that even come from?
Speaker 1: I didn't even plan on doing that.
Speaker 0: It's like we don't do it in regular talking in real life.
Speaker 0: We don't do it panels and we're talking to people.
Speaker 0: we only do it on the show usually at the beginning of a segment.
Speaker 0: Why do we do it?
Speaker 0: Where did it come from?
Speaker 0: Why can't we stop doing it?
Speaker 1: It's so.
Speaker 1: it's just like cavemen talk back in the day.
Speaker 1: we couldn't stop that.
Speaker 1: we weren't even sure when it started But one day we forgot how to use burbs.
Speaker 0: for now on I'm making a conscious effort not to do that And that's it so anyway.
Speaker 0: Oh my god God.
Speaker 1: anime convention we go every year.
Speaker 1: We've been going since like 2002. we've been panelists there since 2003 and We always do like panels and events and stuff at these big anime and gaming conventions And there really aren't any Thursday conventions we go to.
Speaker 1: yet I guess open everything would count.
Speaker 1: but anyway Yeah, so then they finally really late this year published the schedule for the convention at least Most of the schedule.
Speaker 0: yeah, they always publish the schedule you know before.
Speaker 0: well You know some amount of time before the con usually a week or few and the schedule a. it's looking like a pretty good schedule.
Speaker 0: I'm liking the violent movies.
Speaker 0: I'm seeing I'm liking the events.
Speaker 0: I'm liking you know Fred Schoep panels.
Speaker 0: I'm like in concert every day.
Speaker 1: I'm really liking Mostly is that because we're only doing three things and we don't have any other stuff to do.
Speaker 1: I can pretty much do Whatever.
Speaker 1: I want in this guy and no artists alley.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 0: Secondly right they made they did a good thing.
Speaker 0: they made this schedule used to be published as a PDF right Which was nice for printing it out, but it was not so nice because they really couldn't update it.
Speaker 0: so now they've got an interactive schedule where you can click on the individual events to see their descriptions and You know they're gonna update the schedule in real time.
Speaker 0: So if you're at the convention And you go to the website the schedule will be updated like to the minute.
Speaker 0: so if something gets cancelled or moved you can Always check the website even during the con and find out and that's a good thing.
Speaker 0: But they don't have the PDF and the schedule.
Speaker 0: the interactive schedule is unprintable.
Speaker 1: Well here here's here's what I would say.
Speaker 1: Conventions like Otacon have the resources.
Speaker 1: they could get them to get someone to do it.
Speaker 1: hell Conrad could do it trivially.
Speaker 1: They should make an iPhone app and the only thing it does is every year you have the live.
Speaker 0: Oh don't even need an iPhone app.
Speaker 0: You just need a Web page that is iPhone.
Speaker 0: You know specifically duns.
Speaker 0: You know yeah thing is.
Speaker 1: I'm sure they'll add that This is just a situation where something was just good enough to be used a year early.
Speaker 1: rather I mean think if they didn't turn it on now.
Speaker 1: They wait till next year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so anyway This is actually good because it's actually putting the descriptions.
Speaker 0: That was very good because it saved me a lot of time.
Speaker 0: usually we get to the con.
Speaker 0: We have to like read the descriptions of all the movies that we want all the violent movies and all these panels that have really Bad titles.
Speaker 0: you don't know what they're about To sit there like in the hotel reading these things in a little pocket guide.
Speaker 0: now I read them beforehand so it's gonna save me a lot of time and thinking at the con.
Speaker 1: now the interesting thing about doing Panels and being speakers at events like this is that I have to do a lot of you know Communication with the people on the back end.
Speaker 1: you're basically being the producer for geek nights and Every convention is totally different.
Speaker 1: some like all like packs or the New York Anime Festival the New York comic-con are Super professional, and it's literally like basically because I talked the lingo And I give them what they want they'll ask for like eight.
Speaker 1: So what's the ad copy you want in the book?
Speaker 1: you know this many words?
Speaker 1: Give it to me by this day, and it's very straightforward and professional.
Speaker 1: some guys like kinetic.
Speaker 1: on one year We showed up We looked at the con book we saw what panels they had schedule is for and then we showed up at those and ran those Panels the year prior.
Speaker 0: to that though is the exact opposite.
Speaker 0: we showed up.
Speaker 0: They knew who we were.
Speaker 0: they gave us folders that our names on them full of all the information We needed with itineraries and badges and the whole thing that was the con were one of the panels that we did.
Speaker 1: the description in the con book Basically said yeah this we've done this panel at Otacon and anime ball These other cons and we'd like to do a kinetic on.
Speaker 1: we need this much equipment blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: And that was what they put in the description in the con book.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they obviously did not read what they're putting in the con book and you know the the professionalism varies from con to con.
Speaker 1: anime Boston despite being a fan run con like Otacon Probably the most together con outside of the professional cons We've dealt with but Otacon this year clearly humans did not read What they were putting in the schedule because we're doing three panels And I'd like to read for you the panel description that is in the book from anime.
Speaker 1: You should see This is a frank entertaining presentation and discussion of the core anime that any self-describing fan would want to see at least once Presented in the quote unquote Ted style much like our beyond Dungeons & Dragons event.
Speaker 1: its nappy focus runs up to 55 minutes.
Speaker 1: Then we'll leave with a handout noting all the anime we discussed with a not-so-subtle checklist attached.
Speaker 1: That wasn't the description I gave Otacon to put in the con book.
Speaker 1: that was me telling Otacon what the panel was.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was not from.
Speaker 0: that was not language.
Speaker 0: that was from us to the Congo or that was language for us And runs up to 55 minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was the language of us speaking to the panel staff.
Speaker 0: See this, you know, actually I'm gonna blame Technology and I will too.
Speaker 0: in the days before copy/paste Someone would have had to read it and type it in a typewriter or read it and write it with a pen and there's no Way they would make this kind of mistake.
Speaker 0: but because of copy/paste this sort of job putting together the con book becomes Manual labor as opposed to you know, a literate labor.
Speaker 0: You don't need a scribe You just need you know a pair of hands and thus they just copy and paste blindly.
Speaker 0: It probably takes forever because they're selecting copy paste select copy best part and they don't.
Speaker 0: they're not looking They're just trying to get it.
Speaker 0: get it fucking done.
Speaker 1: It was even worse for we're doing beyond Dungeons & Dragons, which Quote and they didn't even get all of it.
Speaker 1: Like this is like an excerpt from the middle of just one of the pair.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they probably just picked like, you know, the number of words that they needed.
Speaker 1: This is a slick professional lecture on the nature of role-playing games.
Speaker 1: Slick professional lecture.
Speaker 1: am I gonna put that in like the description in a con book?
Speaker 1: That's that's so I don't know conceited and weird sounding.
Speaker 0: That's very bad.
Speaker 1: Anyway, making us look bad but they're mistake with a focus on the idea that the systems most people use D&D or more appropriately for Otacon besom is In no way facilitate by nature good or enjoyable role-playing.
Speaker 1: Colon the game and the roles are not intrinsically intertwined.
Speaker 1: either of the above titles works Because there was a discussion where I pointed out that we could call it either beyond Dungeons & Dragons or beyond besom because besom is this anime role-playing system, but Someone I don't know no human read this clearly.
Speaker 0: clearly you ever put the con book together did not read so I hope that's not in the printed book.
Speaker 1: if it is probably is authority.
Speaker 1: We're much like in other cons.
Speaker 1: We're going to have to read and point out the ludicrousness of it at all of the panels
Speaker 0: Of course, of course
Speaker 1: man Otacon you're always so close but Jesus well,
Speaker 0: you know I think I'm beginning to think that you know I'm gonna go with what we said before and I had to fix anime cons show, you know And all these cons of all these problems.
Speaker 0: and they blame these problems on not enough staff yada yada yada And basically I'm gonna say tough shit.
Speaker 0: You're not doing your job You know and such.
Speaker 0: that's not an excuse anymore.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing with with this in particular It is clearly a case of solving the right problem the wrong way.
Speaker 1: because the problem is it's very difficult to get the con Schedule together.
Speaker 1: It's very difficult to get it together on time.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 1: I know ways to solve that.
Speaker 1: But anyway outside there are all these issues with getting panels together and having a schedule ready and available Prior to the con early enough to where you can print it for the con Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So instead of getting someone smart to do it in a proper way or anything They decided to invest in technology some sort of automated system where you know They take the submissions from us from this form and just directly translate them into some sort of schedule Which can I can break down in ways that are apparent right here?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Oh Well, yeah, we're gonna be at Otacon though, but and those panels are not.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess the description sort of tell you what they kind of do.
Speaker 1: I'm curious who's gonna show up and what they're gonna think.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's gonna be very interesting.
Speaker 0: Hopefully We can rely on the fact that most people just look at the titles and don't look at the descriptions.
Speaker 1: Yes, also the fact that I called anime you should see Cover your bases colon anime you should see.
Speaker 1: and in the email.
Speaker 1: They sent me back They just called it cover your bases.
Speaker 1: But in the schedule, they called it anime you should see.
Speaker 1: so I'm expecting them to call it like I don't know Rimming cover your cover you should see.
Speaker 1: Now I'm expecting the actual description in the title to be anime your bases to be something like Thanks and cheers.
Speaker 1: Let me know if you need any other information.
Speaker 1: rim geek nights.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we should maybe call them and let them know.
Speaker 0: I mean it's still a week out.
Speaker 1: I sent him an email but I too little too late probably most likely.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe you should like, you know, you know, I mean at least one or two cons Gone to before will actually send us the descriptions to like proof them.
Speaker 1: Every con does that except the fan cons?
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: You realize Pax has.
Speaker 1: I have an ongoing dialogue with them to where they'll email me and ask me to confirm the panels and back And forth and the New York Anime Festival.
Speaker 1: They have to live copy editors dear comic-con - who will suggest Descriptions and then you know, we go back.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right, so You want to do News or something like that?
Speaker 1: Okay, I got a news here.
Speaker 1: This is this is an interesting story And while there's a lot of kind of viral marketing nests about it The story itself is pretty interesting.
Speaker 1: to sum it up.
Speaker 1: A musician was traveling flying on United Airlines.
Speaker 1: I've flown on United Airlines.
Speaker 1: fuck United Airlines.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I digress everything is not jet blue sucks because unless it's foreign what I say, I flew United Airlines.
Speaker 1: I mean, I've never successfully flown United Airlines.
Speaker 1: Every time I've ever tried to fly United Airlines my flights have been canceled or I've been bumped.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so They broke someone's guitar who was traveling and apparently he looked out the window You know watching the luggage get loaded and he saw them just like throw a guitar case and clearly break it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and You know, he assumed and it was pretty obvious.
Speaker 1: It was his guitar case.
Speaker 1: So he tells the staff not too many guitar cases per flight They don't care.
Speaker 1: and sure enough when he gets to his destination guitar is smash.
Speaker 1: So, what does he do?
Speaker 1: He goes through the process and says hey look you broke my guitar I'll give me the money to fix it and the airlines like now now not gonna do that.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: So he's like, alright United I'm going to make three Internet music video songs that I will compose about you and how you broke my guitar.
Speaker 1: And they still ignored him.
Speaker 1: and then the first video came out and they bought him a new guitar.
Speaker 0: Internet.
Speaker 0: win the Internet.
Speaker 1: Well, I Find see here's the thing.
Speaker 0: I don't understand right.
Speaker 0: this works so well on United, right?
Speaker 0: How come this doesn't work on say Scientology?
Speaker 1: You think Scientology would see the first video and be like, oh shit Well Scientology does but their answer is to sue the people who put the videos up.
Speaker 0: Why didn't Delta go down that road?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe because they don't have any money.
Speaker 1: I Just I find it funny and It's interesting that we're seeing more and more that media like the average per.
Speaker 1: the democratization of media Will in the end give people a very substantial power over Entities that in the previous, you know, pre democratized media world had power over them.
Speaker 1: It's kind of this reverse where you can create on your own Immense bad publicity with almost no proper effort, but then at the same time You only have this power if you have the ability to rise up from the mass of the democratized media.
Speaker 1: If everyone's publishing videos your video has to be awesome or no one will care.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'd also like to point out you know This guy has skill at Country music and video making.
Speaker 0: someone else who had a guitar broken that did not have as much talent would be Far less able to get their video, you know to get noticed and you know get their money back.
Speaker 1: Yep case in point I mean look at podcast.
Speaker 1: who's listening to otaku generation People I guess.
Speaker 0: I guess they gotta have some listeners.
Speaker 0: They still around.
Speaker 1: even I have no idea.
Speaker 1: as far as I'm concerned I'll stand in my world order the only podcast in the world.
Speaker 1: No, they with anime at least I mean fast karate is basically the 24 podcast now.
Speaker 1: Yeah Alright anyway that you.
Speaker 1: the best thing is you can watch the music video on YouTube and it's it's pretty good though I warn you if you don't like country music You won't like the video.
Speaker 0: Yep Alright.
Speaker 0: so this is a story probably better for a Tuesday But you know, it's it's brand new news and I hate it when it's like.
Speaker 0: it always seems like We do a Tuesday show and then on the Wednesday, there's all this big gaming news.
Speaker 0: It's like fuck you Fuck you.
Speaker 1: I've got so much gaming news.
Speaker 0: Alright, so crazy.
Speaker 0: It's always the day at.
Speaker 0: you know, we did a Monday show Google OS.
Speaker 0: It's like fuck you Monday.
Speaker 0: tell us on Sunday anyway Or at least tell us Monday at work not Tuesday, so This is sort of a big gaming news.
Speaker 0: We want to sort of tell the whole story here.
Speaker 0: Way back in the day.
Speaker 0: There was a company called the FASA corporation.
Speaker 1: I still have my second-edge Shadowrun handbook FASA.
Speaker 0: I'm not good.
Speaker 0: You can go look up what that stands for.
Speaker 0: and They made a game called battle droids But they got sued kind of.
Speaker 0: there was trouble.
Speaker 0: so they changed it to battle tech And battle tech was big.
Speaker 0: It was a tabletop miniatures war game and then there was a role-playing game called mech warrior And then there's a video game called mech warrior And then there was mech warrior 2 which is one of the greatest PC games of all time and those mech warrior 3 not so great.
Speaker 0: There's a mech warrior 4.
Speaker 0: I didn't even know it existed.
Speaker 1: As I point out the last comment in the thread in our forum about this was quote there was a mech warrior 4.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know though those mech warrior 4 because there was a mech assault And I think there might even been a mech assault 2 for the Xbox which are much less Simulaty because the mech warrior games are very Simulate being in a mech.
Speaker 0: the bad.
Speaker 0: the mech assault games were very arcade shooter.
Speaker 0: there was even battle tech VR which is some amazing thing that I think someone still has a bunch of pods and drives them around to places and there was a. Oh there was two games, I think they're like battle tech tactics or command or something like that.
Speaker 0: They were basically, you know more like the turn-based strategy game, but on the computer for Windows 95 or something.
Speaker 0: I think both of those you can get for free maybe somewhere.
Speaker 0: I don't know anyway.
Speaker 0: So what happened was eventually right facet was doing its thing and they also did shadow run and some other stuff but Microsoft bought them Microsoft and that is why you got mech assault mech assault 2 on the Xbox 360 and I think Microsoft made mech warrior 3 And 4.
Speaker 0: I'm not you know.
Speaker 0: I guess Microsoft paid something.
Speaker 0: license someone else to do it.
Speaker 1: Microsoft have such as such deep pockets that with almost any endeavor that they want to undertake They can basically just keep making failures over and over and over again and just look at the market and then just Incrementally improve until they make money.
Speaker 0: Yep So you might remember if you listen to the other Tuesday shows it didn't news about Wiz kids games Which was the company that did the mage Knights and the hero clicks and the whole the clicks right the click company and they?
Speaker 0: did a mech warrior click game and they also had a subsidiary called catalyst game labs that did like the clap that basically took the classic battle tech from Microsoft.
Speaker 0: so they were doing the tabletop battle tech parts, right?
Speaker 0: Well Wiz kids is gone, but Through some machinations that I do not know catalyst game labs is there and is stronger than ever.
Speaker 0: I thought that Wiz kids going away was gonna be bad for battle tech, but I was wrong.
Speaker 0: I was so wrong because not only are there these amazing video trailers going around of Mech warrior 5 which is just gonna be called mech warrior.
Speaker 0: It's which is the new mech warrior video game that will come at some point for PC and Xbox.
Speaker 0: That looks amazing.
Speaker 0: Who knows if it'll play amazing, but it looks amazing.
Speaker 0: Mech warrior 4 and all of its expansions are now free for downloading or they will be free for downloading Very soon on the catalyst game labs website.
Speaker 0: You know classic battle tech is no longer called classic battle tech.
Speaker 0: It's just called battle tech.
Speaker 0: So I think what they've done is they've sort of fixed the naming right?
Speaker 0: It's no longer classic battle tech for the tabletop It's just battle tech and the video game is mech warrior, and I think I'm not sure though I think mech warrior the tabletop roleplay game is to dead.
Speaker 0: I can't confirm that though But that's what I'm thinking and that's you know.
Speaker 0: I think that's a good way to go with the naming battle tech for the tabletops and mech warrior for the video games.
Speaker 0: but regardless One of our favorite things in the world battle tech is coming back.
Speaker 1: Battle.
Speaker 0: check it out the way my goss rifle pitch.
Speaker 1: We have such good memories of playing that Somewhat unintelligible game laid into the night at our IT.
Speaker 0: Hey too much.
Speaker 1: Um, Jason face I wonder if Pete Hill still has it that character sheet the one mech sheet.
Speaker 1: Yet a perfect quad neck won't go down.
Speaker 1: It was an 80-ton mech fully loaded.
Speaker 1: There is not a single scratch on it whatsoever.
Speaker 0: It is pristine Except that all strife will to the face.
Speaker 1: Oh, sorry full to the head.
Speaker 1: No head mechs dead.
Speaker 1: If we were playing the campaign, oh my god the salvage.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, but you got it.
Speaker 0: you got to check out these trailers like especially the one with the dude ejects after the Atlas grabs them.
Speaker 1: oh shit, I Have hope I have guarded.
Speaker 0: optimism is I'm looking for any look at this.
Speaker 0: There's suddenly like in the past week the Lucas arts the battle tech.
Speaker 0: If you bring back the TIE fighter and you bring back the mech warrior I'll have and you bring it back proper.
Speaker 0: Like I'll have an excuse to buy the stupid Logitech joystick.
Speaker 0: Please.
Speaker 0: Give me that excuse.
Speaker 1: It's like suddenly PC gaming not.
Speaker 1: well PC gaming has been up and down forever.
Speaker 1: But PC gaming the way I want it has been almost researching.
Speaker 1: It's so close.
Speaker 0: All these games are just I can taste it.
Speaker 0: and if nothing else let's play some tabletop battle tech.
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: I have two things of the day.
Speaker 1: one is an actual thing of the day and one is just Too important not to talk about one.
Speaker 1: Here is an archive of photos of Every single phone booth that still exists on the island of Manhattan in New York City.
Speaker 1: there is one at 101st Street one at 100th Street one at 90th Street and One at 66th Street all on West End Avenue.
Speaker 0: I know more phone booths than that.
Speaker 0: I passed phone booths on the way to work where a fully enclosed proper phone booth.
Speaker 0: Oh fully enclosed.
Speaker 1: I see this phone alcove.
Speaker 0: It is plenty of phone.
Speaker 0: No, see there's plenty of pay phones that have.
Speaker 0: you know, they're there on the street and they have little things around them You know, but they don't have actual doors like Superman uses.
Speaker 1: No, I'm talking at Clark Kent phone booth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not too many of those not too many of those were ever in Manhattan were they?
Speaker 1: there were a ton.
Speaker 1: they're all gone.
Speaker 1: Oh phone booth aka a tiny bum apartment.
Speaker 0: Oh Now I know why they're all gone.
Speaker 0: tiny bums lived in them But there are four.
Speaker 1: there are pictures of them.
Speaker 1: Much more importantly tornado potato Tornado potato.
Speaker 1: tornado potato is a thing that was in Korea Nice, it's a nice.
Speaker 0: Stan Lee would love the tornado.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: It has the same feel as a rust hurricane.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the tornado potato is something to behold.
Speaker 1: I will link to a picture of it but we didn't really have them in the US so much.
Speaker 1: but they kind of exploded around the world and Whenever something explodes around the world it eventually ends up in Wildwood, New Jersey Home of schlock, I mean that is where there's the toward the year-round Christmas store.
Speaker 1: That is where DDR landed after it was popular everywhere else in the country.
Speaker 1: And now I have a picture I'm looking at right now of tornado potato on the boardwalk right next to the Polish water ice.
Speaker 0: Oh Paul, you can get a Polish water ice and a tornado potato right next to each other.
Speaker 1: I can see the Polish water ice is right there.
Speaker 0: Are there dancing girls in the bow?
Speaker 1: There's two Shlubby looking guy.
Speaker 0: I wonder what used to be where the tornado potato currently is between the Polish water ice and that Dunkin Donuts.
Speaker 0: Oh, so that wasn't.
Speaker 0: that was Some of the Dunkin Donuts very close to the McDonald's in the movie theater and the zombies it is but I think it's to the right Of that right.
Speaker 1: I think what used to be.
Speaker 1: there is one of those generic fry shit places could be not the fry shit place where we did the epic deep-fried pizza, but Nonetheless I'm kind of excited about eating the trendy tornado potato.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it looks.
Speaker 0: you know, it doesn't look too bad to me.
Speaker 0: It's basically one potato.
Speaker 0: They put it through a slicey machine.
Speaker 0: You know that makes it a lot into us.
Speaker 0: one solid spiral of potato.
Speaker 0: They flavor up they fry it up and to quote someone at potato worth of french fry They then put some schmutz on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, yeah, that's what you do with the potato.
Speaker 0: But I the thing is looking at it I'm skeptical as to whether it tastes as good as Curly's fries.
Speaker 1: Well, it's so gimmicky and Curly's fries basically just cuts a potato into four pieces and fries it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't beat that.
Speaker 0: It's kind of hard to beat cuz it's so potato Deep potatoes.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: That's all I got.
Speaker 1: speaking of tornadoes Wow, that was a segue I didn't even intend.
Speaker 0: yes, we did intend that I intended it very much No idea you knew it.
Speaker 1: so Scott has a video so something.
Speaker 0: so, you know, there's snakes on planes What you're going way out, but there's no snakes on trains.
Speaker 1: You're gonna pull it back in.
Speaker 1: you've almost back in you've almost really back in almost.
Speaker 0: But what there are on trains are people cameras train cars and Tornadoes.
Speaker 0: what happens when a big Fucking heavy steel freight train probably the heaviest like this incredibly incredibly heavy moving thing meets a Tornado?
Speaker 0: a very very powerful thing.
Speaker 0: It's like who's gonna win?
Speaker 0: is the tornado?
Speaker 0: Just gonna sort of blow around and I'll send all this stuff flying while the train sits there going.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: I'm a fucking train can't move me or is the train gonna go?
Speaker 0: Oh fuck tornado And blow away and it'll be crazy because it's incredibly heavy thing.
Speaker 0: gets blown away like a paper leaf.
Speaker 0: Watch this video find out it's.
Speaker 1: uh, it's pretty epic.
Speaker 1: one tell it when the trees are all fine And then suddenly the trees start moving.
Speaker 1: It's about to happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah once the rain starts coming down there's no going back.
Speaker 0: and also One interesting thing about this video is usually when you see videos tornadoes It's like the tornado is sort of like this opaque mass of dust, you know in a spiral, right?
Speaker 0: So usually when the tornado actually hits you can't see anything.
Speaker 0: You know, all you see is there and then you see the destruction afterwards.
Speaker 0: in this one The tornado doesn't seem to be like built up yet So it isn't.
Speaker 0: you can see the entire video.
Speaker 0: you can see everything perfectly clearly moving around and It's epic.
Speaker 1: Granted we're not gonna link to it But we were watching all these other videos of trains being subject to tornadoes.
Speaker 1: and there's this one where basically a train Surprising the trains.
Speaker 0: it meet with tornadoes so often.
Speaker 1: either that or think about it.
Speaker 1: What are you doing when you're driving the train?
Speaker 1: You're not the one actually at the controls.
Speaker 1: You're just like an engineer hanging out in the back sitting there with your webcam.
Speaker 1: We're doing whatever but the video made it just for the fact that as the train is frantically backing up They passed this other train and the guys like hey, where are you going?
Speaker 1: The guys like I'm getting the hell out of here.
Speaker 0: Cuz you didn't see any destruction in that video, but you saw the guy.
Speaker 0: you heard the guy said I'm getting the hell out of here.
Speaker 1: Yep, so no strife.
Speaker 0: No gonads just His trains going backwards while there's a tornado out of the distance.
Speaker 1: I gotta point this out.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna link to it.
Speaker 1: No thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I have a third thing of the day.
Speaker 1: No link.
Speaker 0: Good God save him for later.
Speaker 1: No, I can't.
Speaker 1: the outrage is just boiling through.
Speaker 1: Sears and Kmart put out the Christmas shit.
Speaker 1: Why just after the 4th of July they brought it out.
Speaker 1: your bullshit I'm not quote.
Speaker 1: Sears typically waits until November 1st to unveil its holiday merchandise, which is already bullshit.
Speaker 1: At least wait until after Thanksgiving.
Speaker 1: Good God.
Speaker 0: Yep Halloween But still it's not even quote.
Speaker 1: but with the recession putting a crimp in spending The retailer is hoping to attract holiday shoppers early.
Speaker 0: They got Christmas trees and shit, they've got their Christmas stuff.
Speaker 0: Oh pigs or didn't happen?
Speaker 1: I'll find some pics.
Speaker 0: But anyway Still good God Alright, so today, you know people always seem to like the shows where it's all philosophies and intellects.
Speaker 1: you mean philosophical and intellectual.
Speaker 1: Notice.
Speaker 1: how is that intellectual?
Speaker 0: trying to not be those things?
Speaker 1: You're also trying to avoid actually bringing up the topic.
Speaker 0: god damn it.
Speaker 0: So We want to talk about immortality, but I don't know in what aspect you will discuss it.
Speaker 0: You know because you read lots of things, you know in lots of entertainment media This topic always starts to come up like, you know, there'll be something like Galaxy Express 3 9.
Speaker 0: It should be like hey go get a robot body and live forever.
Speaker 0: But is that really something you want to do?
Speaker 0: You know is the is the beauty of life God or elves, you know?
Speaker 0: token ask elves, you know is life You know now meaningless because you live forever Burning wheel the way they set it up the races that are special.
Speaker 1: the elves eventually get too sad to deal with it anymore.
Speaker 1: The dwarves eventually get too greedy to deal with it anymore.
Speaker 1: The orcs get too hate-filled to do anything anymore.
Speaker 1: and humans live awesome lives and die when they're supposed to yep When they're supposed to right.
Speaker 0: and it's like.
Speaker 0: I'm sure that you know.
Speaker 0: Individual human beings like to live longer than the short time we have because clearly you can't accomplish everything in.
Speaker 0: you know Whatever limited time but Forever is perhaps too long.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's tricky You know is discussed often in many many books and movies and all sorts of things and I figure we can kill a show Talking about this.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: I'm sure we could do more shows about this.
Speaker 1: detailed shows.
Speaker 1: There's like a Monday Tuesday Wednesday and like 10 Thursday shows about this.
Speaker 1: I mean the societal ramifications the economic ramifications, but I don't know we're just gonna kind of wing it from here.
Speaker 1: So are we talking about?
Speaker 1: Everlasting tuck immortality or I don't age past 22 immortality or Cyborg body immortality.
Speaker 0: I don't know of what everlasting tuck is.
Speaker 0: I assume it's a story of a guy who is everlasting.
Speaker 1: So everlasting talk is a story of family who is basically if you drink from the spring that you find somewhere You're immortal perfectly.
Speaker 1: There is no possible way to die.
Speaker 0: You are also invincible.
Speaker 1: You're invincible Immutable and immortal.
Speaker 0: so even if you get shot, you're not even gonna hurt.
Speaker 1: not you cannot in any way be harmed or die forever.
Speaker 1: So you can't win when you get sick when the earth explodes in the far future You're gonna be floating in space.
Speaker 1: You'll be cast out into space to drift into whatever you drift into.
Speaker 0: Well, see that's pretty horrible.
Speaker 0: See that that's that's one thing that notice how.
Speaker 1: that is also the immortality in Phoenix.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: Yes, no one gets that.
Speaker 1: Well one person gets it and it sucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, so that's an interesting kind of immortality because you got to realize, you know People only want to live as long as there are, you know new things to do.
Speaker 0: because no matter what you know I mean some people can deal with boredom better than others, right but with infinite time You're eventually gonna run out of new stuff.
Speaker 0: So unless the world can progress faster than you can do things, you know You're all set.
Speaker 0: So right now Right, you know the year that we're living in is a good time to be immortal because people are creating arts and entertainments and technologies Faster than a human being who is not, you know modified in any way.
Speaker 1: I mean more can consume them more media is created in a year Then porn is filmed in.
Speaker 0: more than 24 hours of porn is filmed every 24 hours.
Speaker 1: Never mind the porn?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so and that's just the porn, right?
Speaker 0: So that doesn't include the books and the movies and the Internet's and right.
Speaker 0: so, you know it's a good time to be immortal now, but if Say it was caveman times be a very bad time to be immortal.
Speaker 0: and if you you know.
Speaker 1: But then at the same time if you're immortal, maybe you'll become some sort of Steppenwolf but at the same time you might you'll be the one who has the multi-generational perspective and you will basically become the The like Emperor God of all.
Speaker 1: Yes,
Speaker 0: but eventually be bored being Emperor God and you'll want to be hobo Because
Speaker 1: by being Emperor God you can then Elevate society around you in the exact perfect image of what you want it to be
Speaker 0: But eventually getting what you want will be bored and you have to get what you don't want.
Speaker 0: Yeah well You know you can't get what you don't want because you're a devil.
Speaker 1: who have described this that sort of immortality in literature?
Speaker 1: I think our Scott Bakker has put it the in the best says Swatha never shits.
Speaker 0: You're immortal, you know how much you can have to shit.
Speaker 1: So a lot of shitting going on as well at the never shits was more an example of a moment when I put down a book And laughed out loud.
Speaker 0: I laughed mightily.
Speaker 1: money knows the non men.
Speaker 1: I Remember the fact that they're destroyed solely by the fact that they have been given Immortality the fact that they live forever.
Speaker 1: They can be killed by other things, but they are.
Speaker 1: They can live so long.
Speaker 1: Eventually, they've experienced everything the world has to offer and they they end up kind of being forced to either seek out painful surprising Horrifying events simply so that there is something interesting something novel something to remember Or else they lose themselves because they've seen everything and everything kind of blends together.
Speaker 0: Yeah that's why you know the kind of immortal where you can end it when you want to end it is a good kind because then You can do as much as you want and if you feel like, you know Well, it's gonna take a real long time before anything new happens.
Speaker 0: or oh shit I'm floating in space and I can't move because we didn't invent rocket ships.
Speaker 0: But I just ended.
Speaker 1: as Scott Johnson always says if you would ever want to end it if you could ever conceive of being bored You don't deserve immortality because you clearly have not attained the level of sentience required to appreciate it.
Speaker 0: Well, you know that that's true in some has the same thing.
Speaker 1: how well can you handle boredom Tetsuro?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know.
Speaker 0: in some ways though, I mean, you know, it's just the fact of of the universe we live in, right?
Speaker 0: It's like we happen to live in this universe.
Speaker 0: Yes, and this universe while it is very very vast, right?
Speaker 0: It is not perhaps infinitely vast.
Speaker 0: Well, as far as we can tell and quantum this And you know while you could say for us say sit on a planet and watch life evolve Eventually, you're gonna do that three or four times, you know and see life evolve.
Speaker 0: So it's sort of like huh, you know you and then you know The universe that we live in also at least from what we can tell right now appears to be very repetitive.
Speaker 0: You know with.
Speaker 0: you know You look and an atom has electrons going around it and a plasma star has planets going around The galaxy of stars.
Speaker 1: Look at the the the Phoenix idea that Infinite time you are eventually going to be able to create things with which you can transcend the world.
Speaker 1: Perhaps I mean given infinite time you will theoretically if the quantum theory of you know divergence that every possible event every possibility spawns off in other universes forever is Then you could experience anything that could ever exist ever.
Speaker 1: and there's an infinite number of those things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that assumes that there are other universes to get to.
Speaker 0: you know Let's say you discover all the science.
Speaker 0: There is a discovery.
Speaker 0: you have the perfect, you know.
Speaker 0: You completely understand.
Speaker 0: you you achieve through your immortality and you know your quest for knowledge you use As a result achieve omniscience.
Speaker 0: There's nothing more to know.
Speaker 1: but that comes down to the fundamental question is the universe discrete or not?
Speaker 1: Are there fundamental units or not?
Speaker 0: But let's say you at you know one way or the other Yeah, you find out what the answer is whether it's a or B. then what are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: That's Yeah, so, you know there is.
Speaker 0: You know from what it looks like through the current situation of our universe as we can see it in laws of physics It looks like there is a dead end in our universe at which point they would be not much new.
Speaker 0: However You know I guess there I could imagine a universe in which there would be Infinite things to do and immortality would be very very desirable.
Speaker 1: But even then if supposing that I get to a point I am immortal and I am immutable and I am invulnerable So I cannot die.
Speaker 1: I cannot end my consciousness.
Speaker 1: It is absolutely impossible for me to end it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm And there's nothing left to do.
Speaker 0: You're gonna go crazy.
Speaker 0: Maybe maybe what happens?
Speaker 1: I mean, what could what sucks it?
Speaker 1: maybe?
Speaker 0: but at that time What happens with a self reflexive able to learn Conscious intelligence, you know what would really help that situation be omnipotence because you know I mean obviously they were.
Speaker 0: you know, if you're omnipotent you could just create things that would interest you.
Speaker 0: you could you know You could imagine, you know the universe that I can imagine that would be infinitely entertaining.
Speaker 0: I could just create it and go live in it.
Speaker 0: now
Speaker 1: Scott before we go any further I just want to point out the fact that you have not seen the melancholy of Haruhi Suzumiya Really takes a lot out of this conversation
Speaker 0: Because that's
Speaker 1: what this show is about in some ways,
Speaker 0: uh-huh
Speaker 1: that show is not about what you think it's about.
Speaker 0: not It's not about dancing.
Speaker 1: Well, it is about dance.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: Well, I still want to watch it.
Speaker 0: then It wasn't about see.
Speaker 0: I thought it was about dancing, which is why I was gonna watch it someday.
Speaker 0: But I if you were just telling me it wasn't about dancing.
Speaker 1: I'm pulling the bottle where I keep bringing up quotes But I can't quote or reference Haruhi like I can our Scott backer because you have not experienced it.
Speaker 1: First even our Scott backer you didn't get to the point of I remember the slaughter of children.
Speaker 1: No Cuz I don't remember the slaughter because the fact that he remembers the slaughter of children is one of the only threads he can cling To to remind himself that he still exists.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh Yeah, that's another thing.
Speaker 0: is the fragility of the human mind, right?
Speaker 0: Imagine if you were some sort of other thing like say you were an immortal rat, right?
Speaker 0: The rat has a much simpler mind.
Speaker 0: So his whole life, you know, even a live forever.
Speaker 0: He wouldn't have any qualms about it Like eat eat eat eat eat Stink sink eat eat eat.
Speaker 1: What if you are completely immutable not just in body but in mind?
Speaker 0: like the you couldn't learn anything.
Speaker 1: You couldn't forget anything like the Terminator before they set him back to read write memory.
Speaker 0: Well, then it doesn't really matter cuz you're just you're not even gonna know that you're immortal.
Speaker 0: You're like a goldfish You're not remembering anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it does just.
Speaker 0: you might as well just be a robot.
Speaker 1: then What about the interesting situation of I?
Speaker 1: can I transcend by changing?
Speaker 1: Can I find ways to transcend with technology?
Speaker 1: my own mental limitations such that maybe I can force myself to forget and Thus be able to be reborn and experience everything all over.
Speaker 1: but that's no different than killing yourself Yes, but it is a way to effectively end your consciousness and kill yourself while still being permanently immortal and immutable.
Speaker 0: Well only your body will be immortal but you know that your body isn't the important part, you know The consciousness is the important part.
Speaker 0: So really being immortal is not a problem of body even though bodies are the reason you are not immortal.
Speaker 0: It's about maintaining your you know, your ego or whatever, you know.
Speaker 1: Well, that's the other really.
Speaker 1: maybe we take this from a completely different perspective.
Speaker 1: What about the pure?
Speaker 1: Philosophical perspective though.
Speaker 1: I noticed I was talking to Emily about this a while ago.
Speaker 1: I was talking about to a bunch of people about this independently.
Speaker 1: There are many Philosophical kind of lenses.
Speaker 1: there are many philosophical perspectives and any idea any situation any philosophy any world any view anything can be Explained and described and debated from any number of philosophical perspectives and I've noticed that for the past decade or so.
Speaker 1: I Have always fallen back on the perspective of solipsism because it's kind of the situation where you can make any Circuit with Nand gates.
Speaker 1: so I only use Nand gates and I can still make any circuit.
Speaker 1: But at the same time what it maybe would be more interesting if I used ors and nots as well.
Speaker 0: It would be more interesting and be less efficient and it would achieve the same result.
Speaker 1: But as a result, I tend to always fall back on solipsism.
Speaker 0: and what's wrong with solipsism?
Speaker 1: Well immortality from my pragmatic solipsistic worldview comes down to the fact that I have to assume that my consciousness is immortal because I've never Experienced a world where my consciousness did not exist.
Speaker 1: I cannot conceive of a world where my consciousness does not exist.
Speaker 1: That is not purely a pragmatic I don't know projection and I cannot conceive truly of a way to end my consciousness.
Speaker 1: That is absolute.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the thing That's a little bit ridiculous.
Speaker 1: No, because the final point is that even if my consciousness were to be ended there is no way I could know.
Speaker 1: So there is no point in conceiving of the end of my consciousness because I could not ever experience it.
Speaker 0: You experienced right before the end of it.
Speaker 1: Do you really though because you were as long as you were conscious you are still conscious the the edge you're less conscious But are there?
Speaker 1: are there lines?
Speaker 1: is there a point at which you are not a conscious being anymore?
Speaker 0: Well, I think about you go to sleep, right?
Speaker 1: Yes, but at the same time and it is a point in which you're sort of In between sleep but now quite a way not really because you're still conscious and self-reflective, but then you start to forget yourself.
Speaker 1: but then there's the point at which you Wake up again, and that raises the interesting question of maybe we're not even Immortal between days.
Speaker 1: It's very likely that when I go to sleep or I'm knocked out or something The contiguous threat of my consciousness might very well die and a new one is booted the next morning.
Speaker 0: That's all very nice philosophies But I think that the the evidence stacks up quite against what evidence all the evidence of the world is from the external perspective that I cannot trust completely.
Speaker 0: Yes, you cannot trust completely but you could be 99.999% sure.
Speaker 0: you're basically saying There is this point.
Speaker 0: Oh one percent uncertainty.
Speaker 0: No, therefore that is it.
Speaker 1: That's not what I'm saying because remember I said pragmatic solipsism.
Speaker 1: pragmatic Solipsism is the idea that while I cannot know anything for sure except for the self-reflective nature of my own consciousness Which itself is filtered through itself.
Speaker 1: I can Accept the experiences I have pragmatically because they are reliable.
Speaker 1: They're consistent They're repeatable.
Speaker 1: if they were not reliable and repeatable, for example one I'm in a dream.
Speaker 1: when I'm in a dream Then I'm forced to fall back on solipsism further and drop some of the pragmatism because I can't reliably reproduce the experiences.
Speaker 1: But the only thing that I know a hundred percent is that I exist.
Speaker 1: the only true proof that I have the only thing in the world that I can ever call upon without any reservation is the Fact that I can exist and reflect upon that existence.
Speaker 0: Yes, but you are 99.99% Sure that not only do you exist but you are a human being just like all these other human beings walk.
Speaker 1: That is 99 percent.
Speaker 1: The only thing I have that is 100% is that I have always existed.
Speaker 0: Yes, but if you choose to you know Discount the things that you are 99% sure then you might.
Speaker 0: you might as well just discount everything.
Speaker 1: Who said discount them pragmatic solipsism?
Speaker 1: I still react to the world.
Speaker 1: I don't want my consciousness to end.
Speaker 0: I do not just because you don't want it doesn't mean you should believe.
Speaker 1: it's not gonna know.
Speaker 1: you're missing the point entirely.
Speaker 1: It's gonna know you're missing.
Speaker 1: used to it Scott.
Speaker 1: You're missing the point entirely.
Speaker 1: You're like.
Speaker 1: you've absolutely missed the point here.
Speaker 0: You're just me.
Speaker 0: you're making basically the same argument God people make which is like aha Yeah, you can't prove that.
Speaker 0: I can't prove to myself a hundred percent that I'm gonna die.
Speaker 0: So I'm not gonna know.
Speaker 0: You're you.
Speaker 0: that's what you're saying.
Speaker 1: No, you've clearly missed the point of the argument.
Speaker 1: the point of the argument is that a Pragmatic solipsistic position on the world is that the consciousness will end when I die and that I should avoid death for as long as Possible and experience as many things as I can while I'm alive clearly.
Speaker 0: Yes So why were you talking before like?
Speaker 1: because because from a purely solipsistic perspective as opposed to the pragmatically?
Speaker 1: solipsistic percent perspective I cannot but assume that my consciousness is immortal because there is no possible way for me to in any way Become aware of the end of said consciousness.
Speaker 0: mmm.
Speaker 1: But the problem is with all purely solipsistic arguments.
Speaker 0: You know, I think because you sleep and because you wake up after that sleep then you.
Speaker 0: it must therefore be possible for Your consciousness to sleep and then sleep not sleep again awaken sleep it now.
Speaker 1: sleep is different.
Speaker 1: I've never experienced going to sleep and waking up again.
Speaker 1: So and not waking up again?
Speaker 1: So what does it feel like to go to sleep and not wake up?
Speaker 0: the same as sleeping only without waking up?
Speaker 1: No, but every time I've gone to sleep.
Speaker 1: I've those are distinct events.
Speaker 1: They're not tied together No, but solipsistically the only thing I know is that I exist and that I've never stopped existing.
Speaker 0: You also know that you know you exist and you think.
Speaker 0: therefore you are but there are periods of time When you are unable to think and in fact, you don't but not or think anything.
Speaker 1: those times are never experienced.
Speaker 1: I cannot experience them.
Speaker 1: I don't know that they exist.
Speaker 0: You know that you know that the times where you are not experiencing things.
Speaker 1: No, I don't because I don't experience the time passing.
Speaker 1: you're forgetting Scott pure solipsism.
Speaker 0: Yes, even in pure solipsism, you know, it is possible for Scott not to be unable.
Speaker 1: in pure solipsism You only know what specifically you experience and you don't experience the time when you aren't conscious The con the threat of consciousness stops abruptly but starts up again.
Speaker 0: and the only Temporality the only possible way I can say that time has passed are the pragmatic external time measures Because you can feel your own consciousness fading and you can feel your own inability to control it as you pass out to sleep.
Speaker 0: and therefore, you know that For at least some period of time your consciousness was you know out When you were sleeping because I'd won.
Speaker 1: I can't prove that that time exists that there's any time passing at all any amount of time Between when I go to sleep and when I wake up and to you don't actually experience at least I don't the moment of falling Asleep, there's a point when I'm I'm conscious and then the next conscious Instance I have is either myself in a dream or myself waking up the next morning.
Speaker 1: It is completely contiguous with no gaps whatsoever.
Speaker 0: There is a very large gap as it fades Doesn't happen to me?
Speaker 0: and you don't fade out to sleep?
Speaker 1: No I'm.
Speaker 0: The threat of your brain just turns off like a light.
Speaker 1: the threat of consciousness is going and I'm trying to fall asleep and the next Moment of consciousness is either a dream or being awake.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Yes, that's sort of fucked up because I sort of go I'm awake I'm a little less awake.
Speaker 0: I'm a little less awake.
Speaker 1: There are moments when I when I Half asleep or half awake where I cannot fully experience the pragmatic world around me to where I am Confused by sensations that come at me to where I'm outside of this world and only inside of my own solipsistic existence.
Speaker 1: solipsistic existence.
Speaker 1: but the threat of consciousness is fully aware and within that solipsistic existence at all times and I've never Experienced a point where it was not there.
Speaker 1: because just from the rules of logic I cannot because I could not experience it because what I experience is what I experienced.
Speaker 1: I cannot experience what I'm not experiencing.
Speaker 1: Therefore a solipsistically I cannot possibly conceive of myself not existing.
Speaker 1: but pragmatically I know that I'm going to die, but I can't conceive of myself not existing very easily, but I've never experienced it.
Speaker 1: I have experienced it I don't believe you or at least if you have your unique or maybe I'm unique.
Speaker 1: but Solipsistically I can only argue from what I have experienced and I have never experienced a point where my consciousness in any way faded.
Speaker 1: I Have experienced many times my conscious From the moment of sentience because I have no memories of any time before that point.
Speaker 1: until now it is contiguous and unbroken.
Speaker 0: I Have many, you know, plus I also have.
Speaker 0: you know, there are many gaps in my in my memory.
Speaker 1: I have gaps in memory but not gaps in consciousness.
Speaker 0: I have gaps in consciousness when I'm sleeping when when I was young Well, there would be you know when I got my wisdom teeth out.
Speaker 1: Oh, the only gaps I have are pragmatic gaps not solipsistic gaps.
Speaker 0: I have solipsistic gaps.
Speaker 1: I don't and I Hesitate to think that you do and I think that maybe you're misinterpreting them or maybe I don't see solipsistically You don't even exist.
Speaker 0: So what does it matter?
Speaker 1: But no even when I got my wisdom teeth out I remember very clearly that I put the mask on and they said breathe deeply and I breathe in and the Absolute next moments that I experience consciously is sitting on the couch in my house With no in.
Speaker 1: there is no transition of any kind.
Speaker 1: And every time I go to sleep is like that except that sometimes the threat of consciousness resumes in the real world again in the pragmatic world and sometimes it resumes in the Pseudo-pragmatic dream world.
Speaker 0: Well, I can.
Speaker 0: I have experienced, you know being asleep and it fades out very gradually Back in.
Speaker 1: I have not and solipsistically I cannot conceive of myself ceasing to exist.
Speaker 0: Well, that's you but I can very much can see myself ceasing to exist pragmatically though I can radically and solipsistically.
Speaker 1: I know I you know, I know what death will probably feel like.
Speaker 1: I expect it.
Speaker 1: I don't necessarily look forward to it But I look forward to it in a way that all act all true academics look forward to any novel experience.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think you know that that's one of my you know more fundamental philosophies.
Speaker 0: is that death and many other things like current tattoo technology or Other such things, you know scarring are somewhat or very much irreversible.
Speaker 0: and you know Well, I want to experience many many things in life.
Speaker 0: I tend to you know Stave off the irreversible experiences for the end or towards the end because you don't want to do something.
Speaker 0: You can't undo You've seen it.
Speaker 0: You can't unsee it.
Speaker 0: Yep, so I don't look at.
Speaker 0: go see, you know till you're old cuz you can't.
Speaker 0: you can't unsee it.
Speaker 1: Well, I have seen two girls one cup you have not.
Speaker 0: I will save that.
Speaker 0: also Till after I get some sort of you know tattoo that I can digitally modify so I don't have to.
Speaker 0: you know It won't sag.
Speaker 1: Wait, wait - so are you gonna get a tattoo of goat?
Speaker 1: see what's this?
Speaker 0: No that those are unrelated topics.
Speaker 1: So anyway, I don't know if we want to even get into the societal impact.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean it's.
Speaker 0: you know, a lot of it is is pretty simple.
Speaker 0: You know if people live longer and we keep making new people that's trouble.
Speaker 0: But at the same time if we live if people are healthy, there'll be less health care costs, but there'll be other costs.
Speaker 1: We have biological immortality.
Speaker 1: because I very much a number of people have brought this idea to the forefront and There's a surprising amount of resistance to the idea and not for the reasons you'd expect.
Speaker 1: It's mostly like groups like the AARP and the elderly Kind of fighting against this for re for reasons other than it would mess us up economically and socially.
Speaker 1: But I like the idea of treating aging Beyond your peak age, you're like 21 22 like the peak physical age but treating all of the degeneration that happens after that point as a curable disease and putting resources toward curing it.
Speaker 1: and the idea that no one should ever be subjected to their hair thinning or Losing their voice or losing their eyesight or losing their muscle mass or osteoporosis or any of the things that come with age.
Speaker 1: And then why don't we?
Speaker 0: it's nice and you think of it on an individual level But it's not so nice and you think of it on a you know Global level given the other realities of the world.
Speaker 0: if you solve that problem without solving other problems You just make all those other problems worse and we're probably overall be worse off than we are now.
Speaker 1: See the thing is I don't care.
Speaker 1: I say go for it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you've also got to look at the fact that you know old people.
Speaker 0: You know, even if they didn't have these other problems of you know, becoming old in body, you know, they're old in mind.
Speaker 0: They actually tend to cause a lot of the problems in our society just because you know They're so old-fashioned and they don't.
Speaker 0: but Scott don't like change.
Speaker 1: then again Look at we.
Speaker 1: there's research that some of the reason why people learn more slowly in old age has to do with changes in the Brain and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but people also don't like change people, you know, even young people, you know It gets like 40 and they still like the same stuff from when they were, you know 20 or whatever.
Speaker 1: at the same time you would have people who have Multigenerational perspectives and you have people.
Speaker 1: you could have humans who could plan for and complete Thousand year project.
Speaker 0: that would be very good.
Speaker 1: But you know, it's a balanced thing, you know, basically it would force humanity as a Whole to to reach out to the stars to find novelty and experience.
Speaker 0: But I also you know while you would have those great things of the incredibly incredibly old people doing amazing amazing stuff I think you would also have a problem of sort of a tyranny of the incredibly old people over the incredibly new people.
Speaker 1: Oh, definitely You would have this very static society where there are people who've lived so long that nothing you do will ever surprise them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically you would create a bunch of itchy Jimas.
Speaker 1: Oh shit And that would be bad unless We don't get into the Hyperion situation.
Speaker 1: What if we achieve perfect biological immortality?
Speaker 1: not even the immutability and not?
Speaker 1: necessarily Invulnerability, but just you know, everyone hits 22 and never ages past that point.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm People can still be killed.
Speaker 1: Yes, and we solve the problem of our brains might run out of capacity with some sort of ghost-in-the-shell external memory system.
Speaker 0: Well, you that goes in the shell technology stuff.
Speaker 0: That's a whole separate issue.
Speaker 1: Yes, I mean look at the idea of external memory gets to the point to where what if I?
Speaker 1: Access someone else's memories in their entirety.
Speaker 1: Am I not now simply them plus my own experiences.
Speaker 1: So, how are they special?
Speaker 1: Why should they even bother to continue exist singularity?
Speaker 1: Yes the way to avoid singularity is Differentiation and differentiation will happen if we never have teleportation.
Speaker 1: Because then all right humanity goes out to the stars.
Speaker 1: Planets will stagnate because people on them will be the old who have been there forever and have seen everything.
Speaker 1: But groups of people will travel out millions of years out doing things and Their experience will diverge wildly like the ouster's did because remember the ouster's couldn't teleport.
Speaker 0: you're assuming everyone listening to show read that book.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 1: so let's say groups of people go out and have multi-thousand ten thousand hundred thousand million year Experiences where they're so far away that they diverge radically culturally and experientially.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean this goes back to what I said in the beginning.
Speaker 0: right if you're assuming the universe that we live in is the Universe right?
Speaker 0: then yes Will it.
Speaker 0: mortality is kind of bled because there's a lot of repetition and things.
Speaker 0: laws of physics are limiting even this situation.
Speaker 1: We will eventually theoretically have completely filled the universe in which case the last question comes up and all those sorts of right.
Speaker 0: but but if you can you know the one of the realities of our universe is that it takes a long time to get anywhere because the limit to speed and Things are far apart and that you know that law of physics in our universe will create differentiation even if people are immortal.
Speaker 0: however Given some other universe where you could teleport and get places very quickly or things are very close to each other You could test or act or whatever the hell you want to call it right then that differentiation would disappear.
Speaker 0: So it's you know it's.
Speaker 0: it's another matter of immortality would be a lot more awesome in a universe other than the one we live in right now.
Speaker 1: But just the idea that space and the lack of teleportation could force differentiation and you'd have these kind of long periods of nothing, but then radical change as The ouster's came back and had very different ideas about existence from you because they've been gone for two million years.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a lot of sci-fi books about that of you know aliens come.
Speaker 0: They're not actually aliens that the people who left earth and landed on planet who knows what a billion years ago And it took them a half a million years to get there and a half a million years to get back.
Speaker 1: You know maybe because we've gone on long enough at least for one show's worth.
Speaker 1: maybe we should just list all of the media that have shaped our views of this because People if someone has watched and experienced and read all of the media that we're about to list they will probably We really have a much more interesting and direct conversation.
Speaker 1: I think
Speaker 0: one thing I do want to bring up before we end though all right back in the day when I was in the Jew high school youth group right the the international president of said youth group came And he you know he did some shtick right and his shtick was basically like you know hey some guy gives you a contract And you could.
Speaker 0: you know these are the terms and it'll make you immortal with all these conditions and such and such right and He's basically I think it was something along the lines of you won't die until the Sun explodes yada yada yada.
Speaker 0: But anyway, he made this point which you know while it was sort of a point there was something to it And he basically was like hey if you would go and get someone to join this organization right then you will be immortal because you have this effect on it right.
Speaker 0: and You know even though it was sort of just a pitch to get everyone to go out and get people to you know get others To sign up right.
Speaker 0: it's sort of true.
Speaker 0: and that even if you die and you you know your you know consciousness No longer exists And you can have no continuing effect on the universe.
Speaker 0: if you have an effect while you are here And you believe that the universe continues to exist even without you which is most likely true Then you know you should just think of it as if you can just do stuff while you're here You're in some way effectively immortal you know.
Speaker 0: think about Michael Jackson You know more is going on because he died even though he can't do anything.
Speaker 0: He already did stuff.
Speaker 0: that's so in a way He's still alive, and he will continue to be alive for probably centuries.
Speaker 0: I mean Elvis and the Beatles and Beethoven and Mozart and da Vinci and who knows who?
Speaker 0: he was already had effects on Society for centuries.
Speaker 1: he was definitely big enough to where he will outlast Everyone on earth.
Speaker 0: times at least 30 or 40 yeah, so you know you think about these people from ancient times.
Speaker 0: You know Hammurabi right?
Speaker 0: He's that's you know Is still around right?
Speaker 0: so Barring immortality of the literal kind where you will never actually die we should strive for effective Immortality where your effect on the universe you know that is at least remembered and is able to be recognized is Continues to exist.
Speaker 0: cuz I mean I'm sure Everyone you know if you believe the butterfly of flaps his wings just by being born you have an infinite effect on the future Of the universe and some effect on atoms.
Speaker 1: or grab The problem you have an infinite, but undirected effect exactly you should.
Speaker 0: you need a directed, and you know some effect on the universe that can actually be pointed out and be associated with your consciousness.
Speaker 0: that was directed and Intentional and you know you'll make your mark on Things forever, and that is the key.
Speaker 1: look ye mighty upon my works.
Speaker 0: Yep God Looking mighty upon our episodes of geek nights.
Speaker 0: may hard drives always exist.
Speaker 0: so that aside Galaxy Express 3 9 My tell legend Queen millennia pretty much all Anything where people are getting robot bodies goes in the shell.
Speaker 1: yeah along those lines The prince of nothing series just for the non men yep And go got her off and all that.
Speaker 1: obviously anything involving token elves hyperion Sanctuary if you want to read about old people tyranny yeah, but that's not doesn't have immortality.
Speaker 1: no, but it has itchy-jima.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's actually some episodes of the Sonic the Hedgehog cartoon not the ABC one.
Speaker 0: the one the one that rim doesn't like.
Speaker 0: the sort of One with the bad animation where Dr.. Robotnik got some chaos emeralds they gave him like immortality and invincibility and who knows what those are relevant.
Speaker 1: I'm the only one in the world who remembers those Never mind obvious philosophical text that I don't even need to list.
Speaker 0: yeah It's like.
Speaker 0: there's so many.
Speaker 0: It's like I know there's so many I can't.
Speaker 0: it's like when I'm actually pressured to think of them like they don't come up.
Speaker 0: you can read everlasting talk.
Speaker 1: I read it in like fourth grade.
Speaker 1: I don't remember much about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's see stuff where someone lives forever Some people.
Speaker 1: Last question yeah, yeah that kind of covers the physics side.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm done with the show.
Speaker 1: the show will not live forever.
Speaker 1: That's for sure.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm.
Speaker 0: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.