Speaker 0: It's Wednesday August 26th.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight we review and then do some final thoughts on Bocurano.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: I actually had a pleasant surprise coming out of work today for lunch.
Speaker 0: I wander over to Brian Park.
Speaker 0: You know, gonna get me some French lunch.
Speaker 1: And there's this crazy crowd.
Speaker 0: Like I can't get anywhere near the restaurant.
Speaker 1: Is it Britney Spears like it was outside of my work?
Speaker 0: It's just crazy crowded.
Speaker 0: There's all these people everywhere making rabble and walking around and taking pictures and in Brian Park there's some giant ESPN looking monstrosity.
Speaker 0: So I'm thinking god damn it.
Speaker 0: I can't like lay on the grass have my nap like I usually do.
Speaker 0: So I eat and then I walk over there.
Speaker 1: Wonder how much you have to pay the city to let them get the rights to put a monstrosity there for a day.
Speaker 0: I don't know but this summer.
Speaker 0: They do it a lot.
Speaker 0: Well this summer more so than any summer.
Speaker 0: It seems like they have just been really milking it because the grass in Brian Park is fucked.
Speaker 1: I don't know why they just don't like put down some turf.
Speaker 0: That would be terrible for when there isn't stuff there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but maybe you know if you're gonna have grass don't have the stuff.
Speaker 1: If you're gonna have stuff don't have the grass.
Speaker 1: Make up your mind.
Speaker 1: Or have some sort of awesome like revolving floor.
Speaker 1: It's like the grass faces down and there's some lamps under there.
Speaker 1: And then the grass faces up when you don't need to put anything on it.
Speaker 0: Hey, grow lights are expensive.
Speaker 1: But you're getting paid because all these people are paying to put their stuff there.
Speaker 0: What it ended up being was some promotion for DirecTV, US Open, whatever.
Speaker 1: But if you want to watch all the US Open matches get DirecTV.
Speaker 0: But what they set up were two tennis courts.
Speaker 1: What material were they?
Speaker 1: composite clay or.
Speaker 0: Composite clay.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: You don't know what color were they.
Speaker 0: You realize color is not an indicator unless you're playing a Nintendo game.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: But they you know the clay.
Speaker 1: they usually leave it red.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It was a grass court.
Speaker 0: What do you care?
Speaker 0: You've never played tennis in your life.
Speaker 1: I want to see what kind of court it was.
Speaker 0: So what's the difference between, say, a clay court and a cement court?
Speaker 1: The way the ball bounces when it hits the ground.
Speaker 1: In what way?
Speaker 0: What's the difference?
Speaker 0: What are you going to?
Speaker 0: what's going to happen differently on a cement court?
Speaker 1: Well, no, it's not cement.
Speaker 1: There's composite clay and grass.
Speaker 1: Grass.
Speaker 1: The ball is a lot slower when it bounces off the grass because it goes with the frictions in the grass.
Speaker 0: You realize that grass is cut really short, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's still, you know, it's a lot slower when it bounces off at you.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway, anyway, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: The point is what they had were a bunch of professional tennis players there and they played a whole bunch of exhibition matches.
Speaker 0: So I saw Venus against someone and I saw the end of a match between two guys.
Speaker 0: I don't know who any of these tennis people are, so I can't really say who.
Speaker 0: But they were all big names and people are going crazy about it.
Speaker 0: And I was sitting like I was sitting in the front row.
Speaker 0: Somehow I just walked up.
Speaker 0: It was totally free and it was kind of cool.
Speaker 1: That's not fair.
Speaker 0: That was great.
Speaker 1: I had Britney Spears blocking my way out of the office two days ago.
Speaker 1: That's not like the opposite of good.
Speaker 0: I get back to work and people like, where you were, where were you?
Speaker 0: You took a long lunch.
Speaker 0: And I was like, yeah, I was just watching tennis.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess we don't need to go to the U.S.
Speaker 1: Open.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The thing is, they had a contest to win tickets, but I couldn't stick around and enter it.
Speaker 1: It's very it's.
Speaker 1: it's.
Speaker 1: it's real difficult to go to.
Speaker 0: No, it's really easy.
Speaker 0: That contest, they gave like four tickets away every hour.
Speaker 0: And you had to do a test of skill at tennis.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's real hard to go to tennis and not not to win the tickets.
Speaker 0: So I show up and I give him my ticket and they let me in.
Speaker 1: It's not it's.
Speaker 0: it's, you know, if I have my ticket, I can go.
Speaker 1: You got to get there.
Speaker 0: What is there anywhere in the world where the U.S.
Speaker 0: Open would be?
Speaker 0: where I can't open is always in Queens.
Speaker 0: So so I can't get to Queens.
Speaker 1: You take the seven train.
Speaker 0: OK, so I don't see how this is a problem.
Speaker 1: It's you know, it's just it's.
Speaker 1: you got like all the different courts and you got to.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know, like you go into one court, but then you got you want to go out and go to the different court.
Speaker 1: It's like a situation.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So it's not like you go to a game.
Speaker 1: It starts, it ends.
Speaker 1: It's you know, there's.
Speaker 1: there's all these different matches being played and you got to go.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So I guess it's just impossible to watch tennis and you just never try.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying I just don't know how this is so difficult.
Speaker 1: It's not a direct thing like it is with, say, baseball's.
Speaker 0: So it's more like an anime con.
Speaker 0: I got to pick which panel room I want to be in.
Speaker 1: I guess depends what kind of ticket you have to.
Speaker 1: You might have a ticket for like, you know, the shitty court early in the day.
Speaker 1: And then what are you going to do?
Speaker 0: I think it was some fancy ticket.
Speaker 0: One thing I noticed, though, this was what it was like.
Speaker 0: It's weird now when I see public events that are not like geeky conventions because they're run in the same way, you know, professional people and they have like the staff check in and the staff badges and the volunteers, the emcee.
Speaker 0: And, you know, all sorts of events like that are all the same.
Speaker 0: But after going to PAX.
Speaker 0: Even the so-called real world, normal person, big business, you know, infinite money events like ESPN renting out the park in the middle of New York City are so janky and poorly put together.
Speaker 0: Yeah, PAX makes everything in the world look like shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So there's not a lot of news going down.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: No anime news?
Speaker 0: What are you talking about?
Speaker 0: There's a vibrant and thriving anime industry in America and an equally powerful rising one in Japan.
Speaker 0: So because of that, there's also more irony in this room that I can deal with right now.
Speaker 0: Sarcasm is coming out.
Speaker 1: Irony and sarcasm are not the same thing, aren't they?
Speaker 1: No, but so because of that situation that the wonderful, awesome situation rim just described to you.
Speaker 1: I'm just going to do a geek bite on Wednesdays until further notice of awesome news that is important.
Speaker 1: We're talking about.
Speaker 1: So this geek bite, I'm going to do one out of the ordinary, something, you know, I'm going to try to do things people don't realize.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So Marvel Comics, right.
Speaker 1: Their current outer space superhero stuff is mostly the Thor in it.
Speaker 0: What is their Thor?
Speaker 1: Thor is not in outer space.
Speaker 0: I don't care that.
Speaker 0: Wait, he's a god.
Speaker 0: How can he?
Speaker 1: He does go in outer space, but he's not a part of this story.
Speaker 0: So then why would I care?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: You might not care, but other people might care.
Speaker 0: It's Thor.
Speaker 1: OK, so Thor has his own book.
Speaker 1: If you want to read about Thor, get the Thor book.
Speaker 1: It's called Thor anyway.
Speaker 1: So there was a book called Annihilation and then there was a sequel Annihilation Conquest.
Speaker 1: And there's a bunch of related books like Nova and Guardians of the Galaxy.
Speaker 1: And there was a Thanos book that sort of started off way back, you know, like in the early 2000s.
Speaker 1: I have that actually.
Speaker 1: But anyway, these are all the Marvel outer space stuff.
Speaker 1: And, you know, it's really good.
Speaker 1: It's done by these guys, Abnett and Lanning, who don't get enough respect.
Speaker 1: And anyway, the thing is, because a lot of these characters that are in these books, people who just start reading comics now might not know who all of them are, even though I know who they are, because I read these same shitty books.
Speaker 1: And I was a kid.
Speaker 1: They came out with a book called Annihilation Classic that basically has a bunch of origin stories for a bunch of the characters that are in Annihilation and Guardians of the Galaxy and such so that, you know, if you are reading Annihilation now and digging it, you can read the old 70s and 80s comics and one 90s comic that sort of got the ball rolling.
Speaker 0: One thing I do like, even when it's a comic that is not my alley, whenever they remake something, I love to read the original and the new one just to see, you know, what they drew, what they didn't and where it came from.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So I'm reading this and it's got like.
Speaker 1: it's got the origin of a bug, which is like a one issue from the 90s.
Speaker 1: It's got like this or it's got this really old comic, like a suspense story about the Groot, who's the big tree.
Speaker 1: It's got a story about Star Lord and a story about like Drax the Destroyer and Thanos, just a short one.
Speaker 1: And it's an Adam Warlock story, the re-origin of Adam Warlock, because he was around before.
Speaker 1: But this is sort of like the second coming origin.
Speaker 1: But in the middle, right, those are all one issues that single issues that are put in this trade.
Speaker 1: There's also a four entire four issue miniseries in here for Rocket Raccoon, who is one of the characters in Guardians of the Galaxy.
Speaker 0: Rocket Raccoon.
Speaker 1: Yes, Rocket Raccoon.
Speaker 0: That doesn't sound like it fits.
Speaker 1: He's basically just a space ranger kind of dude with a laser gun and a rocket ship.
Speaker 1: But he's a raccoon.
Speaker 0: He's actually a raccoon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's actually a raccoon.
Speaker 0: Now, raccoon, like the size and shape of a normal Earth raccoon.
Speaker 1: No, he's a furry.
Speaker 1: He's a furry, but he's very small.
Speaker 0: OK, I was curious.
Speaker 0: He talks anyway.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I'm reading I read, you know, like the first thing in there.
Speaker 0: How did he get the rocket?
Speaker 0: You don't want to know, was he just a raccoon?
Speaker 0: and then he got the rocket?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: OK, so he started out as just a raccoon.
Speaker 1: So anyway, the so I'm like, why is there?
Speaker 1: everyone else gets like a single issue and why is there a rocket raccoon for issue miniseries in here, the whole four issues?
Speaker 1: And it's in the middle of the book.
Speaker 0: I'm like, so really that's like prime real estate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like, OK, so the whole middle of the book, in fact, the vast majority of this book, probably almost half of it is all about Rocket Raccoon.
Speaker 1: And the rest is just, you know, other, you know, single issues.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling you wouldn't bring this up unless it was either really good or really bad.
Speaker 1: Well, the story was, you know, a story, right?
Speaker 0: It was definitely a story about a raccoon who gets a rocket.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, it's about a lot more than that.
Speaker 1: But, you know, the story wasn't like the greatest story ever, but it was definitely different.
Speaker 1: You know, it wasn't your it wasn't what you would think it would be.
Speaker 1: It was something else which made it kind of interesting, even if it wasn't amazingly high quality.
Speaker 1: What was amazing about it was I turned the page to the Raccoon Raccoon story and I'm like, what the fuck?
Speaker 1: Why the first page?
Speaker 1: I see it and I'm like, what the holy shit?
Speaker 1: Why is the art on this Rocket Raccoon four issue miniseries from who knows when?
Speaker 1: Maybe the 80s.
Speaker 1: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Early 90s.
Speaker 1: I got to go look again, see when it was from.
Speaker 1: Why is the art on this so great?
Speaker 1: Like there was the issue of the bug from the 90s was not so great.
Speaker 1: You know, the other you know, the other comics were like 60s and 70s comics.
Speaker 1: They did you know, the art was varying in quality.
Speaker 1: But there was like this Rocket Raccoon miniseries, like this greatest art.
Speaker 1: And so I looked to see who the artist was and it was Mike Mignola, the Hellboy guy.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, oh, oh, what the fuck?
Speaker 0: I got to read this now.
Speaker 1: Why did they not like?
Speaker 1: it's sort of like this secret, I guess, that there is this, you know, Rocket Raccoon miniseries with great arts.
Speaker 1: So if you are someone who wants to, you know, they should have just sold the Rocket Raccoon thing in a trade on its own and forgotten the other stuff.
Speaker 1: But if you want to read the Rocket Raccoon miniseries, go on Amazon and look for Annihilation Classic.
Speaker 0: Oh, hey, I see.
Speaker 0: OK, the origin story, at least, you know, with all comics, if you explain the plot and like just like this happens, then this happens, they often make sense.
Speaker 1: Rocket Raccoon won't make sense.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's a one sentence summary here that seems to make a lot of sense.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Tell me what the sentence summary is.
Speaker 0: Rocket Raccoon comes from Half-World comma in the Keystone Quadrant comma, an abandoned colony for the mentally ill.
Speaker 1: This is a run on sentence, isn't it?
Speaker 0: Where animal companions were genetically manipulated to grant them human level intelligence and bipedal body construction for many to become caretakers of the inmates.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Colon.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Rocket Raccoon was Half-World's chief law officer parentheses, quote, Ranger, who protected the colony against various threats.
Speaker 0: Yep, that sounds about.
Speaker 1: OK, that was a long, that was a run on.
Speaker 1: say it's cheating, as that was a that was a paragraph, as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 0: Currently, as a friend, Mr.
Speaker 1: Wall, Ross, who has tusks that are interchangeable and are do different things.
Speaker 1: He's got laser tusks and he's got like grabber tusks.
Speaker 0: And, you know, it's weird how I'll look at like a lot of superhero comics and just think of the stupidest things ever.
Speaker 0: But for some reason, something like this, I just really want to read.
Speaker 1: It has stupid parts, though.
Speaker 1: But anyway, you're not you're not.
Speaker 1: if you search for Rocket Raccoon on Amazon, I don't think you're going to find it.
Speaker 1: Search for Annihilation Classic and you'll find this.
Speaker 1: And it has other stuff in it, but you'll just get it for the Rocket Raccoon.
Speaker 1: And also, if you like that stuff, you can read, you know, Annihilation, Annihilation, Conquest, Nova and Guardians of the Galaxy, which are all the related.
Speaker 1: That's what I like about it.
Speaker 1: It's like they sort of started this story off.
Speaker 1: And I got, you know, that first issue way back.
Speaker 1: that sort of started the whole thing first trade.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And they didn't like cross it over with too many other books.
Speaker 1: It's really only like four books that things cross over in so you can just get the whole thing easily.
Speaker 1: But you're still getting the crossover action, but you're not getting the have to know the entire history of Marvel Universe action.
Speaker 1: It's all just in a handful of books and most of them are just Annihilation.
Speaker 1: So it's really easy.
Speaker 1: And it's outer space.
Speaker 0: So because there is such a vibrant anime industry going on in the US, I'm going to talk about a bunch of things really briefly.
Speaker 0: I figure I'll cover everything that is even remotely worth talking about from like the last four months of anime news.
Speaker 1: They better make them all quick.
Speaker 1: We don't have a lot of time.
Speaker 0: So real quick, you know what?
Speaker 0: The top four manga in Japan are right about four right now.
Speaker 0: Right now.
Speaker 0: You don't have to get the order.
Speaker 1: One Piece.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: Top five.
Speaker 1: One Piece.
Speaker 0: Actually, One Piece is not anywhere on this list.
Speaker 0: Naruto Bleach Tennis, Prince of Tennis, I Shield 21 and something I've never heard of.
Speaker 1: What's the song you never heard of?
Speaker 0: Bakuman.
Speaker 1: Oh, I know what that is.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: And even then, nothing sold more than a million.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: Well, that's kind of.
Speaker 1: is that kind of Tango Bonds or Shonen Jumps or what?
Speaker 0: You know what is counting?
Speaker 0: Anime News Network.
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: Does it say source something, something?
Speaker 0: I bring this up only because it seems like.
Speaker 0: There's never any anime news and there's always the Japanese comic ranking and those sorts of things, and in the past I used to default to them and talk about them, but nothing will ever change.
Speaker 0: The same kinds of things will always be at the top.
Speaker 1: The numbers always talks about.
Speaker 1: Japan has a million animes and million mangas, and we only see a fraction of them.
Speaker 1: Well, we see most of the anime is like ninety nine percent of them and we see a fraction of the mangas.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, the same mangas are the popular ones.
Speaker 1: They're not bringing us.
Speaker 1: They're not bringing us over the unpopular mangas, right?
Speaker 1: If you're going to spend the money to bring over a manga, they bring over the popular one.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, the unpopular ones that we don't get to see.
Speaker 0: What generally is the most popular in comics in Japan?
Speaker 0: It's the crap aimed at like 14 year old guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because that's what most, you know, even though manga is read by other people in Japan a lot more than comics are read by other people in the
Speaker 1: U.S.,
Speaker 1: the majority of readers is still kids reading Shonen Jump.
Speaker 0: I mean, I realize this partly.
Speaker 0: You know, we've been doing these like Gekiga panels and we talk about sanctuary a lot and, you know, Kazuoka is golf manga.
Speaker 0: And I realized that a lot of our listeners seem to have started to foster this impression that all the manga that isn't brought over to America is exactly like Sanctuary and Eagle, and that all the shoujo manga we don't get to read is exactly like the 49ers stuff.
Speaker 0: that's good.
Speaker 0: Most of it is crap, just like most of anything ever from any source is crap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just.
Speaker 1: there's a lot more of it in Japan.
Speaker 1: You know, if you want to sort of get a better picture on this, go to the comic book store, find a comic book store that actually has every single comic for Marvel and NBC.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's sort of hard to find one.
Speaker 1: And you'll go to the shelf and you'll see Spider-Man, Batman, Superman, Wonder Woman, et cetera.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Justice League, X-Men, Avengers.
Speaker 1: Then you give you actually look around, you'll start seeing all this stuff that's like they actually come out with like this third rate character that only incredible nerds know about every month.
Speaker 1: They come out with a comic for this person and they sell enough to pay everyone in that chain.
Speaker 1: And it's like, yeah, they do.
Speaker 1: And they do the same shit in Japan.
Speaker 1: Some manga that's like incredibly, you know, nerdy and only a handful of people are into it.
Speaker 1: every, you know, month or week or two is in the Shonen Jump or whatever it is.
Speaker 1: And there every time, just like in America, like, you know, like they'll have a Blue Beetle comic.
Speaker 1: You know, I guess he's the Blue Beetle.
Speaker 1: They he had his own comic for a while and then they stopped and then, you know, they started up again and stop it again.
Speaker 1: You know, that's how it goes.
Speaker 1: I mean, Booster Gold, all nerds know who that is.
Speaker 1: But I only know who it is because I listen to nerds talk about him.
Speaker 0: And I only know who it is because you told me about the nerds talking about.
Speaker 1: He has his own.
Speaker 1: There's a book, Booster Gold.
Speaker 1: It comes out every month.
Speaker 1: They print it.
Speaker 0: Dang, that's the that's, you know, so speaking of which, it all culminates in this.
Speaker 0: What is coming out and there's a trailer for it now is Dragon Ball Online, the MMO.
Speaker 1: My joke is everyone just super single.
Speaker 0: My joke, and I'm not going to say anything beyond this, is that I hear the controller for combat is a microphone and a volume meter.
Speaker 1: So moving on the you know what, though, I just want to say this real quick, a fist of the North Star.
Speaker 0: I was thinking that the whole time I was talking about the North Star MMO would honestly be great if combat were just random matching random letters, scroll across the typing of the North Star.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God, we have to make it.
Speaker 0: We could make that you do 80, 80, 80, 80, 80, 80, 80, 80.
Speaker 0: No, then you have to type.
Speaker 0: Oh, my gosh, in the end.
Speaker 1: And then the guy explodes.
Speaker 1: If you don't type it fast enough or if you misspell it, the guy can attack you.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: Then you get.
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: You type in the move you want to do.
Speaker 1: You type in like, you know, I'll get it to go.
Speaker 0: What easy it would be to make typing of the fist of the North Star.
Speaker 1: It would be great.
Speaker 1: All you would do is take the arcade game and replace the punching things with keyboard.
Speaker 1: That would be it.
Speaker 0: I feel like I should take that game without any consent from anyone who owns the property.
Speaker 0: Do it.
Speaker 1: Just take, just, I have every episode of the TV show.
Speaker 1: You can just copy and paste video right out of the TV show.
Speaker 0: I could make a flash game right out of the movies.
Speaker 0: I could just write it in Python and put it in like a package repository.
Speaker 1: You know what you could do actually?
Speaker 1: Uh, I've actually been investigating.
Speaker 1: This is a towel.
Speaker 1: Save this for a tech day, but basically you could do X and a in Python.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: I should just do this.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So she finally is making another live action movie.
Speaker 0: The first one since Avalon, which sucked.
Speaker 1: Even though some people like it, we think it sucks.
Speaker 0: The thing is I liked it and then there was a twist at the end and I was like, well, I saw that coming.
Speaker 1: I didn't like any of it.
Speaker 1: I thought it was just sort of boring.
Speaker 1: And then what the fuck?
Speaker 0: Then there was another twist and then another twist and then I just turned the movie off.
Speaker 0: Fuck that.
Speaker 1: It was bullshit.
Speaker 1: Well I think the problem was also that it was hyped incredibly.
Speaker 1: I didn't even know it was Mama Roshi when I watched it.
Speaker 0: Me either.
Speaker 1: It was just incredibly hyped up as like this awesome sci-fi movie from Eastern Europe and then it was poop.
Speaker 1: So whatever.
Speaker 0: But his new movie sounds a lot better.
Speaker 0: You know what it's about?
Speaker 0: It is about women with assault rifles fighting whales in the desert.
Speaker 1: How does a whale go in the desert?
Speaker 1: Does it need water?
Speaker 0: Suna Kujira, sand whales.
Speaker 1: So it's Dune with guns.
Speaker 0: And girls.
Speaker 1: And girls.
Speaker 0: Dune gun girls.
Speaker 1: Crying Fremen.
Speaker 0: Why can't he just go back to making anime?
Speaker 0: Every anime he makes is just amazing.
Speaker 1: Mama Roshi, you know, it's been said before by us and other people.
Speaker 1: He is pretty much the greatest example of someone who's incredibly talented and refuses to do what they're talented at.
Speaker 1: I mean at least Guy Ritchie made a bunch of Guy Ritchie movies.
Speaker 1: It's like here, you know, Mama Roshi does like amazing comedy and action scenes and animation.
Speaker 1: And all he wants to do is like, you know, crazy, weird sci-fi live action things.
Speaker 1: And he should really go do some comedic action animes.
Speaker 1: He'd actually make like a good Hokuto Nuken or a Dragon Ball.
Speaker 1: It would be like the best.
Speaker 1: It would actually be funny and have great action scenes in it.
Speaker 0: So last and certainly not least, I don't have our schedule handy.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to bother.
Speaker 0: You'll see us there.
Speaker 0: But the New York Anime Festival is coming up September 25th through 27th.
Speaker 0: We'll probably be there Friday night and Saturday night doing a couple of panels and otherwise Friday night and some portion of Saturday.
Speaker 1: We'll probably go to the city all day Saturday.
Speaker 1: Go to the anime festival for a portion of the Saturday.
Speaker 0: Once we know our schedule and I think to actually think about it, we'll put it up.
Speaker 0: I mean the New York Anime Festival, we kind of do the same panels we usually do.
Speaker 0: We don't do anything crazy or special at it.
Speaker 0: But if you're in New York, we're going to try to do something better next year.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm putting more of my eggs in the New York Comic-Con basket, to be honest.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a good idea.
Speaker 0: We need more non anime cons because most of our good panels are not anime panels.
Speaker 1: New York Anime Festival last year, we just like walked into our panels and walked out.
Speaker 1: It was sort of it was really weird to do that.
Speaker 0: It felt very professional, but kind of jerky.
Speaker 0: But it was weird.
Speaker 0: Like literally we walked in, we got our badges from the like the special booth.
Speaker 0: We find Pete to terror.
Speaker 0: We're like, Hey, we're here.
Speaker 0: This is going to be awesome.
Speaker 0: We did like all these panels in a row and then we left.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I walked around the dealer's room once.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Because really all it is the dealer's room and then some panel rooms next to it.
Speaker 0: But you know, if you live in the New York area, all cons like this, pretty much any con is worth going to for one day.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: This is definitely, it's like if you're an anime person and you're close to New York City, you know, if you can get there by train or quickly by car, if you're in North Jersey or Southwest Connecticut or Southern New York or Long Island, they always have good guests.
Speaker 1: They always have good panels.
Speaker 1: They just go all day Saturday.
Speaker 1: It's totally worth, you know, your all day Saturday if you need some anime con action.
Speaker 1: And it is, you know, it's the end of the anime con season.
Speaker 1: You're not getting nothing until like next year.
Speaker 1: Anime Boston time.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Because we don't know what's up with Kazucon.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: This is your last chance.
Speaker 1: So for this year, anime con.
Speaker 1: So go and behold and also see us.
Speaker 0: So things of the day, I know I talked about how I was watching Irresponsible Captain Tyler again recently, and I cannot express to any of you anime people how great that show is.
Speaker 0: If you think you're like Gurren Lagann is great and you're watching it and you haven't seen at least some giant robo Legend of the Galactic Heroes and Irresponsible Captain Tyler.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling that's the only reason you like Gurren Lagann.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry.
Speaker 1: Smackdown.
Speaker 0: Gurren Lagann's okay.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good, but I'm getting the feeling the more I watch it that it's not that great.
Speaker 0: It's just there's a lot of homage to older, better shows and right down to the sunglasses on Kamina.
Speaker 0: Jesus, you people.
Speaker 0: Anyway, Irresponsible Captain Tyler is just such a great anime and the more I watch it again, especially now, the more I realize just how utterly great it was and how much I love it.
Speaker 1: I watched one of the episodes and I was like, yeah, it's as good as I remember it.
Speaker 0: It's got a lot of that and we always call them the camaraderie shows and it's got a lot of that in it.
Speaker 0: It's just here is Greenwood in space to a small gambler.
Speaker 0: They're all just weird and they're all kind of stupid and they're all kind of jokes.
Speaker 1: A lot of shows nowadays have like the full cast of characters.
Speaker 1: You know, that's one thing at the guy, the strong guy.
Speaker 0: That's something Fullmetal Alchemist did really well and I think that's one of the only reasons it was popular.
Speaker 1: Even the Gundam shows would sort of have the cast.
Speaker 1: A bunch of the cast is always will be like, for example, they'll take the like the crew who works on the mechs will be like.
Speaker 1: the only character they'll have is like the lead guy and everyone else will just be generic guy, generic guy.
Speaker 1: And in Tyler, no one's generic guy.
Speaker 0: They have the full load out.
Speaker 0: There are people who have like one speaking line in the entire show and are in the background in like three random other episodes and yet they are fully fleshed out and the weird shit you see them doing in the background is totally relevant to the characters.
Speaker 0: But I digress.
Speaker 0: If you don't get it, watch this AMV.
Speaker 0: It's Irresponsible Captain Tyler.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really spoil anything.
Speaker 0: This shows you exactly why Irresponsible Captain Tyler is one of my favorite anime ever.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: That's all I got.
Speaker 0: Also, it was rereleased in a thin pack.
Speaker 0: You can get it for like 40 bucks.
Speaker 0: Oh, wow.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So what do?
Speaker 1: one thing I like is Ming vases.
Speaker 0: Uh, do you actually like them or are you setting yourself up for something?
Speaker 1: No, they're totally awesome.
Speaker 1: They're pretty cool, but I am also setting up for something.
Speaker 0: But what particularly about the Ming dynasty as opposed to other dynasties say the ones before and after, which you probably cannot name.
Speaker 1: I just like the white with the blue stuff.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I like the way they look anyway.
Speaker 1: I actually at the at the what's it called the Pearl River Mart, you can get like plates that are, you know, white with the blue.
Speaker 1: The nice.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 1: Also, I like robots, right?
Speaker 0: Is there a transforming robot that turns into a Ming vase?
Speaker 1: No, there's a dude who made some vases.
Speaker 1: And basically all the vases look like a touchy coma had sex with the Ming vase.
Speaker 1: And he calls them.
Speaker 1: he calls his name is Brandon Tangus and he calls them his manga, Ming or more Lou vases.
Speaker 1: I call them mecha Ming.
Speaker 1: That's what I call them.
Speaker 0: There's something special about that.
Speaker 1: So yeah, when you take a look at these, there are.
Speaker 1: there's just a few photos of, you know, five or six of them.
Speaker 1: And they're totally awesome.
Speaker 1: And I want one.
Speaker 1: But hopefully I would get one that is functional as a vase.
Speaker 1: I could put some flowers in there or something or maybe some grains of rice.
Speaker 1: I don't know what you store in a Ming vase money.
Speaker 1: If you can afford a Ming vase, I mean, these are multiple smaller vases.
Speaker 1: He didn't actually take real Ming vases and put, you know, Max on them.
Speaker 1: He made vases in the Ming style and put Max on, you know.
Speaker 1: So anyway, yeah, take a look.
Speaker 1: It's cool.
Speaker 1: I like it.
Speaker 1: I want one.
Speaker 1: I probably can't afford one.
Speaker 1: Ming or no Ming.
Speaker 1: Ming the Merciless.
Speaker 0: So in a momentous occasion has occurred for geek nights.
Speaker 0: And this is kind of an important announcement.
Speaker 0: Scott finished watching some anime recently.
Speaker 1: I mean, it was twenty four episodes and I started watching and I was like, OK, I watched like four episodes in one night.
Speaker 1: So I was like, OK, I was to, you know, an hour and change.
Speaker 1: I'll finish this and I finished it in three days.
Speaker 0: Well, I think part of it I've realized how to stop watching, how to tell if I really like an anime or not, because some anime like I was trying to watch through Nadeshiko, which I just never really watched all the way through.
Speaker 1: I couldn't.
Speaker 1: I had no interest to continue.
Speaker 0: The further I get, like I have to force myself to watch it.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: I had the same problem with Kazenoyo Jimbo.
Speaker 0: It's just kind of shit.
Speaker 0: And I remember watching it and like forcing myself to watch the next episode to finish it.
Speaker 0: One day I was like, I shouldn't have to force myself to watch anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Kazenoyo Jimbo is nice and average.
Speaker 0: Bokerana was definitely a show.
Speaker 0: I remember once I got past the first couple episodes, I just watched it every moment.
Speaker 0: I had to watch anime until it was done because I had to know what happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Now, the thing was right is let's you know, we'll talk about it and then we'll do a spoiler line.
Speaker 0: Yes, this is a final thoughts show.
Speaker 1: You want to do a final thoughts?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: But we're going to review it first because we haven't talked about it in a long time or at all.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure we brought it up because I watched all of it like way back, like as soon as the last episode was.
Speaker 1: So just quick plot summary.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: This is sort of a spoiler, but really, come on.
Speaker 1: Everybody knows this.
Speaker 1: And it's they tell you right up front.
Speaker 1: Basically, the story is some kids are at nature camp.
Speaker 1: It's basically summer camp on some tropical island.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And it's happy times in the summer and they're hanging out on the beach and there's a secret cave and they go in the secret cave and there's a weird guy and some weird sci fi shit happens.
Speaker 1: And basically they have to.
Speaker 1: they think they're going to play a video game, but really they end up piloting a robot to fight these robots and, you know, defend the earth from monster robots.
Speaker 0: And now the thing is, it's one of those shows where if you describe for real, you describe the plot like, yeah, it's about a bunch of kids, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 0: Now they pilot a giant robot.
Speaker 0: That sounds derivative and shit.
Speaker 1: The thing is, it's not.
Speaker 1: every time they pilot the robot, one of the kids is the pilot and everyone else just sort of sits there.
Speaker 1: Whoever is the pilot totally dies.
Speaker 1: Now, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: After the fight is over right away.
Speaker 0: The reason why these win or lose.
Speaker 1: Oh, and if you lose, the whole world is destroyed.
Speaker 1: So it's either you die or the whole world dies, including you.
Speaker 0: So the reason I like this show straight up and I realized this when I was watching a couple episodes again, just to remember, is that it does the same thing that Death Note did.
Speaker 0: It has a world that is 100 percent self-consistent, where every character acts in a believable, believable, responsible, rational manner.
Speaker 0: Or if they are irrational, it is very understandable why they were irrational.
Speaker 0: It goes straight to the military.
Speaker 0: Everybody's like does exactly what a smart person would do in that situation.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: The show also does the same thing that Utena does.
Speaker 1: You have a long list of characters and you go through each character one at a time and examine, you know, their personality and who they are and what they're all about.
Speaker 1: And then the battle at the end of that character's story arc, which, of course, they're going to die at the end of.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Duh.
Speaker 1: That battle is a metaphor for that person.
Speaker 1: And then somehow that person's life is resolved for good or ill or otherwise, except for Captain Jerkface, who dies.
Speaker 0: Well, anyway.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But you know what I'm saying is that, you know, that's how that's how it goes.
Speaker 0: But it's a show that really Bocorano takes a bunch of children, confronts them with the inevitability of their own death.
Speaker 0: And you watch them very realistically grapple with the understanding that they are going to die and them trying to come to terms with it and trying to come up with or just have a reason to leave a legacy behind,
Speaker 1: but also simultaneously working very hard and intelligently to get out of it and not die.
Speaker 0: The one of the best scenes in the show is to defend the Earth.
Speaker 0: It's not really a spoiler, but the kids basically people go straight to the military and they're like, oh, Jesus shit, this is what's going on right here.
Speaker 0: And the military is like, oh, really?
Speaker 1: And they sort of look like in the first battle, the robots are semi invisible, even though they're making like big waves and destroying things.
Speaker 1: But then in the second fight, it's just like, yeah, OK, the robots are out.
Speaker 1: Everyone can see it.
Speaker 0: Like the fact that the show cuts to like the news reports of, oh, shit, giant robots and like the militaries of the world are reacting to this.
Speaker 1: And it's not portrayed like, you know, in the news today, robots, it's like portrayed like real news.
Speaker 1: One of the kids parents is like the news guy, you know, that comes into play later on.
Speaker 1: Actually, every everything comes into play.
Speaker 1: But yeah, actually, I heard a story a long time ago.
Speaker 1: I think we did it as a news in some ancient episode about how the director of this anime asked the mom because it was originally a manga.
Speaker 1: He asked the manga person if he could make it like, you know, less tragic because it was just so terrible killing these kids off every episode or whatever.
Speaker 1: And yes, well, if you're not, I think the manga person agreed, but I haven't read the manga at all.
Speaker 1: But but I did watch the entire anime.
Speaker 1: It is no I don't know how you could make it more tragic.
Speaker 0: Really, Mohiro Kito is the person who originally wrote the manga Bokerano.
Speaker 0: And he is also well known for Shadow Star Naruto, which, oh, that explains everything, which can be described as Pokemon.
Speaker 0: if everyone were depressed and people fucking die.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow.
Speaker 1: This guy is just hitting.
Speaker 1: Oh, something else you have to know about this anime.
Speaker 0: Oh, Scott, I'll just point out I have not read and I didn't I don't know anything about this, but one of his other works, a manga is called Hallucination from the Womb.
Speaker 1: I never heard of that ever.
Speaker 0: So this guy seems to and just looking at pictures and going through this is a winner.
Speaker 0: He is the guy Ritchie of depressing.
Speaker 0: Oh, he is Guy Ritchie of killing children and making you cry about it.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So something else to know about the anime is made by Gonzo.
Speaker 1: And that usually means that the trailers and the first episode of like amazing animation and they're going to look really awesome and get you all hyped up.
Speaker 1: But then it's not going to deliver.
Speaker 1: This is probably like the Gonzo show that delivers like the only one.
Speaker 0: It must have not really been Gonzo.
Speaker 1: Well, it was Gonzo.
Speaker 1: The thing is, we did some research and we found out a reason.
Speaker 0: Here's the story.
Speaker 1: The show worked out.
Speaker 0: So Scott said that the director went to the mangaka to get permission to not have to kill as many children.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And the director is someone who I actually had not heard of.
Speaker 0: I had no idea who this person was, but Hiroyuki Morita and Morita only directed one other major animation, and that was The Cat Returns.
Speaker 1: For Studio Ghibli.
Speaker 1: So that's a pretty great one right there.
Speaker 1: So he's got two winners.
Speaker 0: The Cat Returns.
Speaker 0: So I'm one really looking forward to see.
Speaker 1: But how do you wait?
Speaker 1: OK, so he did The Cat Returns and he did Bocorano.
Speaker 1: Two great shows.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So but you don't just get to direct Cat Returns for Studio Ghibli out of nowhere.
Speaker 0: How does this guy come out of nowhere and direct The Cat Returns?
Speaker 0: Well, he did key animation for freaking every Satoshi Kon work ever.
Speaker 0: Ah, I mean, he was key animator for Rogen Z, Perfect Blue, That's an Otomo work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Paradise Agent, Magnetic Rose also related to Otomo.
Speaker 1: So the guy who directed this and they went.
Speaker 1: he went to the Otomo and Satoshi Kon school of anime, which is probably one of the best schools of anime to go to.
Speaker 1: So that is not a surprise that he is awesome.
Speaker 1: And I am.
Speaker 1: I wonder what he's directing now, because I imagine it's awesome.
Speaker 0: And I like even stuff.
Speaker 0: He did key animation for the first Tenchi movie, which is widely regarded as a great movie and independent of what you might think about Tenchi Muyo.
Speaker 0: He did not work on the second Tenchi Muyo, a.k.a.
Speaker 0: no need for incest.
Speaker 0: And while he worked, sadly, on the third Tenchi Muyo movie, which was basically a fanfic now need incest in that movie, I note that he had no creative control.
Speaker 0: He just did the storyboards and the key animation and the unit direction for the already written shitty story.
Speaker 0: I can't blame him for that one, but just getting paid.
Speaker 0: This guy is definitely one of the last people who kind of came out of the protege system.
Speaker 0: And I really look forward to what he's going to direct next.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this guy's looks like a winner to me.
Speaker 0: He's the picture, too, of him in the anime news network, at least.
Speaker 0: He has a smile that it portrays one thing.
Speaker 0: I am hot shit.
Speaker 0: I know it.
Speaker 0: You know it.
Speaker 0: Fuck you.
Speaker 0: You got to see the smile.
Speaker 0: It is just perfect.
Speaker 1: So Bokerano is a totally awesome 24 episode show.
Speaker 1: You should totally watch it.
Speaker 1: I don't really have a lot more to say without spoiling.
Speaker 0: the whole show is eminently spoilable.
Speaker 0: It's just it's beautiful.
Speaker 1: I guess the animation is, you know, it's not like the best animation in the universe, but it's really great.
Speaker 1: It stays great even towards the end of the show.
Speaker 0: One thing I'll say it is like surprisingly on.
Speaker 1: the designs are very unique.
Speaker 0: But like the show is on model to the point that I was kind of startled by it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, they have all these characters and all the characters like totally stick, you know, like they don't you know, they they.
Speaker 1: they're not just on model visually, but they're on model like the full character wise.
Speaker 1: And they start with a whole bunch of them.
Speaker 1: And obviously they decrease over time.
Speaker 0: The fact that they have that many characters in Gun Tron, the anime here.
Speaker 1: And I'm sorry, people, if anyone knows a Gun Tron is you'll like it.
Speaker 0: But they have so many characters.
Speaker 0: The first episode was like a million kids.
Speaker 0: You have no idea who they are.
Speaker 0: By the second episode, you pretty much know who they all are.
Speaker 0: By the third episode, you care about all of them.
Speaker 0: Except Captain Asshole.
Speaker 0: And don't worry, he dies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, it's kind of amazing how they have so many characters, yet they actually managed to get you to know all of them and care about all of them.
Speaker 1: And they introduce more characters and it's not a burden.
Speaker 1: And that just shows you that they're they're delivering it in the proper the proper way.
Speaker 1: And the show really is all about the characters.
Speaker 1: It's not about the robots that just happen to be there.
Speaker 1: The robot battle is just a metaphor for the character.
Speaker 0: It really it does the same thing that Cowboy Bebop did in that Cowboy Bebop had a world with an epic story.
Speaker 0: But the true epic story of the Cowboy Bebop world, the gate disaster and all that stuff had nothing to do with the direct story of the characters.
Speaker 0: Cowboy Bebop was about these characters coming to terms with their own lives.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like the story of like where these robots come from and all that stuff is there.
Speaker 0: It's there.
Speaker 1: They tell you a bit more about it than the Cowboy Bebop tells you about the gate explosion.
Speaker 0: But it's not fully resolved because it doesn't need to be.
Speaker 0: It doesn't need to be about that.
Speaker 0: But that Cowboy Bebop and this have a complex, self-consistent, realistic, interesting and compelling world.
Speaker 0: But beyond that, the story is just about these equally compelling characters within that world instead of being about the world.
Speaker 1: It's also a relatively new, non-stupid, serious science fiction anime.
Speaker 1: It's kind of rare.
Speaker 1: Enjoy it while you can.
Speaker 1: And you only get one of these once in a while.
Speaker 0: The show, too, I just want to point out before we get to the spoiler line, which I'm kind of itching to get to because there are some great freaking moments in the show.
Speaker 0: But aside from the fact that it made me cry like 15 or 16 times and I cried continuously throughout the last like 15 minutes of the last episode, nonstop.
Speaker 0: Just like I was on the train the whole time.
Speaker 0: I'm just like, like not full on crying.
Speaker 1: Did the person next to you think you were weird?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It wasn't full on crying, but it was definitely that like my eyes are tearing.
Speaker 1: I didn't have any full on crying either, but it was definitely like, oh man.
Speaker 0: Get choked up.
Speaker 1: And the thing is, I sort of knew what was going down, but it was just oh man.
Speaker 0: I didn't know, but it was.
Speaker 0: it's like Trigun where the act of what happens in an episode, someone dying or something like that is not what made me cry or made me go crazy.
Speaker 0: What made me cry was like the moment later where someone else reacts to it.
Speaker 1: The worst is when it's 24 episodes, right?
Speaker 1: The thing is, there's only like.
Speaker 1: there's a lot less than that.
Speaker 1: There's like 15 robot battles.
Speaker 1: So a lot of times one character will get like two or even three episodes before their battle.
Speaker 1: So they're really like pushing this person on to you before they rub them out.
Speaker 1: And it's just like, oh, fuck you.
Speaker 1: You should if you did if they did every character, just one episode gone, one episode gone.
Speaker 1: It'd be a lot less tragic and torturous.
Speaker 0: Granted, then again, I just they don't let you off easy.
Speaker 0: I point out as a counterexample, burrado, but you can bradow this show.
Speaker 0: I bradow people continuously.
Speaker 0: It's horrifying.
Speaker 1: It's just bradow the show.
Speaker 0: So anyway, I want to point out one other thing.
Speaker 0: The mute before we get to the spoiler line, the music in this show is amazing.
Speaker 1: Oh, the opener is is is really great music during the show.
Speaker 1: I think just average background music.
Speaker 0: It is, but it's not good or bad.
Speaker 1: It's not like I want the soundtrack, but the opener is totally awesome.
Speaker 0: The music.
Speaker 0: The reason I say the music during the show is so amazing is because it's in the background where it should be like complimenting the anime, but not overpowering the anime.
Speaker 0: And it never appears out of place.
Speaker 0: There's no like random pop song in the middle or anything weird like that.
Speaker 1: I'll say I'll just you know, I agree with that.
Speaker 1: But that only that those qualities that you are ascribing to it are exactly correct.
Speaker 1: But those qualities only give it the mark of good in the Book of Scott.
Speaker 1: Well, you achieve the mark of great.
Speaker 1: You have to be like a cowboy bebop or something where I want the OST of all the background where the for where the form and function are intertwined.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: So but the opener is great.
Speaker 1: Well, uninstall song.
Speaker 0: Well, the other thing I'll point out is that the show does the thing that Gundam seed did where the music is mostly this very one specific style of music during the show.
Speaker 0: But there are a couple of times during the show where music like the opener plays instead, much like how in Gundam seed, where there were those I'm seen as great music, but Gundam seed has like one kind of music throughout the show.
Speaker 0: But there are like four.
Speaker 1: So it's going to see it again.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: That show is so great.
Speaker 0: But there are like four scenes like the scene on the island or the scene in the opera house where a different kind of music plays.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And that music like stands out and kind of takes over the scene and pushes you away.
Speaker 0: Boccherano pulls that out a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they do.
Speaker 0: But that's on.
Speaker 0: uninstall is just a great song.
Speaker 0: And also there's a little bit of intertwining with form and function.
Speaker 1: But they also change the closer halfway through the show.
Speaker 0: They do.
Speaker 0: I like that.
Speaker 0: Old shows used to do that a lot more.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: Different shows mix it up differently.
Speaker 1: I mean, there are some shows that are mixing it up constantly.
Speaker 0: I think the closer of Boccherano was designed solely to make people who didn't cry at the end of the episode cry during the closer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, possibly.
Speaker 0: So spoiler line, if you have not seen or read the mono, do not listen past this point.
Speaker 0: We're going to spoil the ever living shit out of the show.
Speaker 0: The rest of this episode is going to be all mad.
Speaker 0: Remember when X happened?
Speaker 0: Yes, you do not want these things spoiled for yourself.
Speaker 1: OK, so my two most awesome parts are two.
Speaker 0: I'm going to write down my two and we'll see if they're the same.
Speaker 0: Give me a sec.
Speaker 1: I hear the two most awesome parts of Boccherano.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Ready?
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 1: Part number one was the fat kid, right?
Speaker 1: Because.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So the fact is this fat kid, I forget his name.
Speaker 1: I don't forget most of the characters names, but basically the whole show, he's the quiet kid who doesn't do a lot.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But then eventually he's chosen to be the next pilot.
Speaker 1: So you wonder what he's going to do.
Speaker 1: So the thing is, he goes out in his first battle.
Speaker 1: And, you know, the thing is, the robot is powered by like life energy.
Speaker 1: So he just doesn't move the robot at all.
Speaker 1: He stands perfectly still.
Speaker 1: And the fat.
Speaker 1: So basically, if he can survive this battle without moving the robot, he won't die.
Speaker 0: Well, he thinks he won't die.
Speaker 1: And he's correct, because what happens is the the enemy robot just freaking kills itself and he makes it through the battle.
Speaker 1: And of course, that was symbolic of the fact that his mom just tried to kill herself, et cetera, et cetera.
Speaker 1: It's telling his story.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So that was totally awesome.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, he comes back for another fight.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And he says, you know, his mom is happier now.
Speaker 1: And, you know, his his sort of life is better.
Speaker 1: And he realizes that, you know, everything's cool.
Speaker 1: And, you know, his story, you know, he resolves his personal issues and he's going to fight to save the world.
Speaker 1: It's a world worth saving.
Speaker 0: His fight is great.
Speaker 1: So all the fights up until now, the robots is giant robot.
Speaker 1: It's kind of slow and it's kind of lumbering.
Speaker 1: And it's usually about whether the character is going to like, you know, not care and step on all the buildings or try not to kill normal people and reduce collateral damage.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But the robot has always been slow and lumbering.
Speaker 1: And like the lasers are useless.
Speaker 1: It always has to punch and kick.
Speaker 1: And so the fat kid gets in it and they're like, oh, man, he's the most dangerous kind of robot.
Speaker 1: And when he fights in the robot, like the robot moves like like elegantly and quickly, like it like it like it spins and kicks.
Speaker 1: And he's just wicked dangerous and just wins immediately.
Speaker 1: And it's like, fuck, yeah, look at that.
Speaker 1: And no one else in the entire rest of the show is able to match controlling the robot in like an equally awesome way.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 1: And it was totally wicked awesome.
Speaker 0: But I have one other alternate because my number one awesome scene number one or maybe number two, because I have to get to the better one later.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: The gun in the beginning when the kids go to the military and the military is like, well, call that.
Speaker 0: That's a good one.
Speaker 0: And the kids are like, don't beatle, don't beatle.
Speaker 0: Come.
Speaker 0: And he just fucking appears.
Speaker 0: And the military guy is like, what the fuck?
Speaker 0: Jeez.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And he pulls a gun on it right away.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Just immediately pulls the gun on it.
Speaker 0: And of course, he gets screwed by that.
Speaker 1: He gets teleported and then his hand lands on the ground, which is important for the rest of the show.
Speaker 1: Well, they actually that matters for the whole show.
Speaker 0: That is my whole.
Speaker 0: but why?
Speaker 0: that is my number two of my two awesome moments, because not only did that matter, it was a Chekhov's hand holding a Chekhov's gun.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So I'm hoping the fact that like no better example of people reacting the way you would expect people to react than him pulling the gun and threatening the thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So I'm hoping my number one awesome moment is the same as your number one awesome moment.
Speaker 1: So towards the end of the show, they basically the plot is that they build these towers, right, to use the what's it called program?
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: Uninstall.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So the you know, because basically the humans are evil and they try to like use the robots technology to get like free energy.
Speaker 1: But actually it's a trap.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And the people who made the robots actually want you to do that, because basically it's a trap in that if you lose, your universe gets destroyed because you lost the fight.
Speaker 1: If you win, it's because you stole the technology of the robot to win.
Speaker 1: And that technology, when you use it, means that the people who made the robots get you and they take the life energy of your whole earth and they get you.
Speaker 0: So, you know, they're so far beyond exactly.
Speaker 1: the earth almost falls for this trap.
Speaker 1: They build a tower and that tower basically, as long as it exists, is going to make the humans lose, even if the robot wins all the fights and all the robots appear near the tower and for all the fights.
Speaker 1: And then they build a second tower and shit gets crazy.
Speaker 1: But then once the traitor girls, when she fights, the first thing she does is blow up both towers, just like, boom, boom.
Speaker 0: And I was like, yes, because, yes, there are a couple of times where a kid will use the robot, you know, they can do whatever they want in the robot, like someone uses the robot to get revenge on the teacher.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: The thing is that teacher.
Speaker 1: And then the sister is still defending the teacher.
Speaker 0: And shit, that was, you know, the whole show.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking, don't die, don't die for all the characters.
Speaker 0: The fact that that guy didn't die, that guy needed to die.
Speaker 0: Something fierce.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course, that sort of stuff is all Naruto.
Speaker 1: Definitely.
Speaker 0: But the fact that these kids have control of this thing and the fact that the other robot is going to fight just kind of, they got 48 hours to win the fight.
Speaker 0: If you can like you can do whatever you want in the robot, that the other robot with all the other kids in it from the other world just waits and lets her do this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, because so you could tell some of them have figured it out because that's the thing is like they didn't know what the deal was, but like some other people know what the deal is and they sort of, you know, basically, you know, the fact that you're fighting the role, you know, it's a robot that you're fighting is actually a robot from another universe.
Speaker 0: We're assuming everyone's seen.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But it's right.
Speaker 1: But it's that the kids don't learn this until later on.
Speaker 1: So some of their opponents know this and some of them don't.
Speaker 0: Well, the slow reveal was like it.
Speaker 1: it bothered me was I saw you sort of guessed it, but you didn't know it.
Speaker 0: It's one of those things where you guessed technically like, yes, you were correct in one level, but you didn't really figure out the scope of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And like when the one robot just kills itself or when they just rip it open and look inside and see all those other kids looking back at him and then when they figure out what the lights mean.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, it's that that other robot killed itself during an away match just so that it could, you know, teach something to the robot that it was fighting against.
Speaker 1: You know, if they did it on the home mat, you know what I'm saying?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's it's stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess it would have worked also if they did it on the home match.
Speaker 0: But, you know, the point is when they get to the world where everyone's helping out the robot because the whole world is banded together to survive.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Now, think about that.
Speaker 0: You're rooting for these.
Speaker 1: I like that one.
Speaker 0: You're rooting for these kids.
Speaker 0: You don't want them to die.
Speaker 0: And you know that their entire they're the characters, you know, their entire universe and world will be destroyed if they lose.
Speaker 0: But in that fight, when they win, they are knowingly doing the exact same thing to someone else.
Speaker 1: But there was also the one where they open up.
Speaker 1: It was that the same one where they open up the the pod and I forget which one that was before they squish it.
Speaker 0: That was because they had to be sure.
Speaker 0: And then how each character reacts to that.
Speaker 1: Well, the one guy, the person who was doing it was like, nobody look, you know, he's like, don't look, I'm going to look and don't look.
Speaker 1: But everyone else looked anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was like, you know, he had to know, but he didn't want to know because he was going to die.
Speaker 1: So it didn't matter if he knew.
Speaker 1: But everyone else had to live with knowing.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, as an aside, this show gets bonus points for being for making me cry when I see a chair.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: In some random context, like I see a chair is like, oh, but no, my it was really weird.
Speaker 1: It was really cool.
Speaker 1: Like usually shows will have like things that go with characters like a Gundam show.
Speaker 1: Everyone has a robot that sort of goes with them.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: In this show, it's a shared robot.
Speaker 1: So they came up with these chairs and everyone has a chair that really speaks to their character.
Speaker 0: And they really do.
Speaker 0: the chair, the air on chair, the little cushion.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The guy who's like, you know, his mom is the science lady.
Speaker 1: He's got the air on chair because he's got mad moneys.
Speaker 1: And the girl who like, you know, sits at home in the living room as living room chair with the Ottoman and, you know, the poor kid.
Speaker 0: And, you know, there's like the school desk because his dad runs the school and the fact that, you know, there's the whole Russian roulette thing of who gets picked and whatever.
Speaker 0: And normally an anime would just let that be.
Speaker 0: But toward the end, when you just find out, no, that whole rigmarole is just bullshit.
Speaker 0: He's just picking because he's an asshole.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like the show sort of makes you think that some of the things that are going on are like, you know, part of the mystery.
Speaker 1: But then, no, really, it was just bullshit.
Speaker 1: The only real mystery is this stuff over here.
Speaker 1: And the rest of it was just, you know, fucking with you.
Speaker 0: But speaking of that, when you find that out is my number one moment when they pull the trick where you think the one kid has the gun and he goes to reach for it.
Speaker 1: That was so great.
Speaker 0: And it was.
Speaker 0: and then it was the traitor girl killing her own brother.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, her brother was like the real bad guy in the show.
Speaker 0: Well, she sort of.
Speaker 0: But then again, you understood.
Speaker 1: Like you think about it, right?
Speaker 1: The robots they're fighting against aren't really evil.
Speaker 1: They're just all fighting for their own survival.
Speaker 1: And the, you know, the mysterious elders in the white shirts or whatever, you don't know enough about them to know whether they like they're secretly saving the universe and you don't realize it, you know, but and, you know, they're there.
Speaker 1: They feel bad about it, but they realize there's no other choice.
Speaker 1: That's a possibility.
Speaker 1: But for a game, what a dung beetle.
Speaker 1: He is just bad, especially because his replacement, your Coco Peli isn't even bad at all.
Speaker 0: But he's very sympathetic.
Speaker 0: But the fact that dung beetles replacement is pretty cool with their decision.
Speaker 0: He's like, all right, sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's just like whatever.
Speaker 1: But dung beetle is just bad.
Speaker 1: He's a bad guy in the show.
Speaker 0: That whole scene where he pretends to have the gun and then she shoots him from behind and it actually works.
Speaker 1: I like how that works.
Speaker 1: Usually they'll come up with some excuse.
Speaker 1: I was like, actually, they just freaking shot him to death and just awesome.
Speaker 0: All of that.
Speaker 0: The fact that, you know, he's pleading for his life and she just keeps shooting him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was well, she's going to die anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that was an intense scene.
Speaker 1: It was pretty good.
Speaker 1: My favorite scene, especially the way they drew him getting shot.
Speaker 1: Like that.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, you just kept getting smashed.
Speaker 0: That was harsh.
Speaker 1: It was rough.
Speaker 0: Hands down, my favorite scene in the whole show.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: I think I'm still with my to my because it was my fat kid and I blow up the two towers.
Speaker 0: One that those two characters asked to avoid him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they did it well.
Speaker 0: And the whole scene that followed where then she fights and she reveals all the secrets and you learn that all the Russian roulette stuff is just complete bullshit.
Speaker 0: And you basically get everything you need to run out.
Speaker 0: the rest of the show.
Speaker 1: A significant portion of the show is spent concentrating on what's his name with who has the sister, Kata Chan and their quote, their mom, who they don't realize is their mom.
Speaker 1: And then, you know, I love all those.
Speaker 1: that whole thing is pretty much like the main focus towards the end of the show.
Speaker 1: That's really those are the final those the characters that are left at the end that pull, you know, they sort of they start.
Speaker 1: those characters sort of stick out a little bit in the beginning, but then they sort of fade away to concentrate on the others.
Speaker 1: And then about halfway through the show, they push them to the forefront.
Speaker 1: So it's always whatever character is currently in the focus and them and they're the focus until the end of the show.
Speaker 1: And we didn't even talk anything about the mom, the military lady.
Speaker 0: She again, she is basically asked for a boy.
Speaker 1: She reminds me a lot of the gym teacher in Ozumanga Dao.
Speaker 0: I can see a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a little bit.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God, this show is just great.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And the oh, and oh, don't even get me started about the sanctuary ask diet man.
Speaker 0: Ah, the whole politics and everything about the show is great.
Speaker 0: Also, the science mom, who was kind of evil, but good in the end, mostly evil, but not all totally evil.
Speaker 0: She reminded me to a strong degree of Ritsuko from Ava.
Speaker 1: Yeah, kind of character, same flaws, a little bit of paprika ish.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a little bit in this a little bit.
Speaker 1: But yeah, Ritsuko from Ava totally dead on more like, you know, also Genda.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Come on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was also there was the show had just really great.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure it was stolen from the manga while stolen if it was from if this was from the manga or not.
Speaker 1: But like the show just had great design and sort of everyday things like, you know, like we talked about chairs, like chairs are often a very a big focus for like industrial designers, you know, but like, you know, like people's apartments and, you know, all these sorts of everyday cars, you know, the show is it's not in the distant future, but it's in sort of a semi future earth, you know, like the helicopters and all these sorts of just everyday things were just so well designed, like.
Speaker 1: I'd like to live in a world where everything was designed that nicely probably would only be the Japanese portion of the world where everything is already sort of designed better than the rest of the world.
Speaker 1: But, you know, it was just like the fact that I don't know if that was just from the manga, that great sense of design or if, you know, any of that came from the animators.
Speaker 1: But regardless, it's there.
Speaker 1: And it really, you know, it gives the show a great feel.
Speaker 1: And it also makes you wonder, like, you know, the show is all about these robots from different universes that are all pretty similar universes.
Speaker 1: They all have a, quote, Earth.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You wonder if, you know, you sort of take it for granted that this is Earth, Earth.
Speaker 1: This could just be a story of any of the Earth, Earth's that are all fighting against each other.
Speaker 1: It does not necessarily our Earth, Earth, our, you know, Bocorano ours.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: You know, but I mean, it could be, you know, any Earth, but it just is.
Speaker 1: this is the Earth that you're paying attention to.
Speaker 1: But, you know, this could be the story of a universe that's alternate to ours that, you know, it has different cars and different helicopters and different, you know, I don't know why that reminded me, but I was not.
Speaker 0: I was talking about the music and then we got distracted.
Speaker 0: The reason I wanted to bring up the music, because the guy who did the music, Yuji Nomi also did the music to Hinatori and The Cat Returns.
Speaker 1: Oh, that makes sense.
Speaker 0: And Whispers of the Heart.
Speaker 0: He actually he's the guy who did, you know, he wrote he did the music and did the arrangement of the core theme song.
Speaker 0: He didn't do much else.
Speaker 1: That's a good music guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So there was.
Speaker 1: he's probably done a lot of non anime music work.
Speaker 1: That's why he's so good, but good stuff.
Speaker 0: And the show is just great.
Speaker 0: And I loved it.
Speaker 1: And I it's not like.
Speaker 1: it's not like, you know, some of the I mean, there's some other Gonzo shows that are OK ish.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Like we can talk about last exile.
Speaker 1: We can talk about Gonkatsu.
Speaker 1: Oh, this is the only amazing Gonzo show.
Speaker 1: It's only 24 episodes.
Speaker 1: The manga is going to come out from this eventually.
Speaker 0: We don't need to convince you to watch it.
Speaker 0: You already watched it or you're an idiot.
Speaker 0: You got the whole thing spoiled for you.
Speaker 0: But, you know, good job, genius.
Speaker 0: Watch it anyway.
Speaker 0: The show is great.
Speaker 0: And I have a feeling it's a show that, you know, five or six years from now, I'll probably rewatch at least one more time at some point.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I want to basically forget a lot of the show over a year or few and then rewatch it again with some people.
Speaker 1: I watch the whole thing alone really quickly because one is some people haven't seen it.
Speaker 1: So I can just watch them cry because it'll be a laugh instead of having to cry.
Speaker 1: I'll be able to laugh or I'll be able to go.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like when I was watching Gundam seed again and I was watching it with Emily and I knew like when the island scene was going to happen.
Speaker 0: and I'm just watching.
Speaker 0: I watch her the whole time, not the scene.
Speaker 1: Oh, shit.
Speaker 1: But I think there's some people that we've we have befriended recently who have not seen attack the gas station.
Speaker 0: It's getting about time to watch that again.
Speaker 1: Attack only one.
Speaker 0: Hey, Bocorano attack only one because there only is one.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: But I'm just saying there's this joke to be made there.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I think we're done.
Speaker 0: But this show was just so great.
Speaker 1: Show now.
Speaker 0: that whole end scene was so like mundane and yet brilliant.
Speaker 1: I like how they saved the big robot battle for the end.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, like how long it is.
Speaker 0: And he like brought food in with him.
Speaker 0: And and then there's that whole super long dental molt where you get like the sister telling the story.
Speaker 0: And that was when I cried at the end.
Speaker 0: I didn't cry in the entire last episode, really.
Speaker 1: Well, no, it wasn't.
Speaker 1: it wasn't just that the sister was telling the story.
Speaker 1: It was that the three the siblings of the other kids show up.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: I real I didn't really like.
Speaker 1: if I was smart, I would as soon as I saw the kids fighting, I would have known that they were those kids.
Speaker 1: But it's like the girls like you're taught you're those kids.
Speaker 1: And it's like, oh, shit, they are.
Speaker 1: Oh, my gosh.
Speaker 0: And the show basically ends on.
Speaker 0: let me tell you the story.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, and you wonder, like, you know, if it had been that other world with like the people trying to cheer the robot on.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They wouldn't have had it.
Speaker 1: But in this world, it's like, will anyone even believe it?
Speaker 1: You know, it's like so few people know the real deal.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, man.
Speaker 1: Well, especially all those like political and Yakuza moverings to like conceal from the public what was going on.
Speaker 1: And oh, man, that was like all that cool stuff in the middle.
Speaker 1: But it's sort of it was sort of Ava-esque in a in a way.
Speaker 1: in that, you know, when the show sort of starts out right, it's sort of like, you know, everyone is just living the normal life.
Speaker 1: Everyone's going to school.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And then sort of like the world knows something's up.
Speaker 1: And in the final stages, it's like the world is quiet and it's just the people who are involved and the rest of the world disappears.
Speaker 1: And that's Ava follows the same pattern of, you know, OK, in the beginning, everyone's going to school, having a good time.
Speaker 1: Then the world knows this shit is going down.
Speaker 1: And then the world is empty except for nerve.
Speaker 1: And Bocorano has that same thing as Ava.
Speaker 1: It's Ava.
Speaker 1: It's Utena.
Speaker 1: It's right.
Speaker 1: What was the other show?
Speaker 0: Death Note in that it's so that it's so procedural and so precise.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's all these.
Speaker 1: it's all these great things.
Speaker 1: Good.
Speaker 1: It's amazing aspects of all these great shows combined into a show that is not quite like any of them, but is like all of them.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays we have video games, board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights and Thursdays are the catch alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@front road crew dot com.
Speaker 1: or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an Odeo on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: For the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.