Speaker 0: It's Monday March 23rd.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We kind of cop out and talk about science from high school mostly chemistry.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: No work tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes, so what sick day or just a vacation day.
Speaker 1: No no work the next day either.
Speaker 1: Vacation days possibly not for a while.
Speaker 1: laid off I don't know.
Speaker 1: laid off fire I don't even know because it was so.
Speaker 1: it's sort of weird because it's like well They weren't doing too well, so they couldn't afford to keep me around, but at the same time.
Speaker 1: I was also Showing up late and leaving early as far as they were concerned even though it was no later or earlier than I had Showed up prior to them having troubles.
Speaker 0: You know so did you get any like severance payer?
Speaker 0: They just like walk up get the fuck out of your George Carlin.
Speaker 1: It wasn't get the fuck out.
Speaker 1: It was just like you know.
Speaker 1: sorry to see go you know that the spiel.
Speaker 0: and Huh, maybe maybe this had something to do with you know.
Speaker 0: hey Scott You got to put more on the table bring more to the company.
Speaker 0: You know what do you have to offer us?
Speaker 0: and then I didn't.
Speaker 0: it wasn't your answer.
Speaker 1: They're like we need more from you, and I'm like I can't really give you more right now.
Speaker 1: I'm like can you wait till I move to the city that I give you a little bit more?
Speaker 1: It's like you know.
Speaker 1: I can't give what you're looking for so I don't know if it counts as laid off or if it counts as Fired insubordination or whatever.
Speaker 1: Technically, I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's you know.
Speaker 0: I don't know how that works.
Speaker 0: I've never been fired.
Speaker 1: And I was fired once at RIT.
Speaker 0: Well RIT doesn't get.
Speaker 1: I worked in.
Speaker 0: I didn't technically get fired from the back.
Speaker 1: I worked in these two offices in the art building the student services offices because the art building had two different ones and then In the summer I stopped working at one and worked almost exclusively the other one.
Speaker 1: But then the person who used to work at that other one they came back.
Speaker 1: So then I left there, and I got fired from there.
Speaker 1: That's I immediately had to go to these scheduling office.
Speaker 1: Where is where I worked which is much better first of all is a much higher profile job for more money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I worked there as love for until I left RIT the closest I ever got to being fired like actually fire fired.
Speaker 0: What was de Bella's when basically they asked me if I was quitting because they weren't sure.
Speaker 0: yeah I didn't wake up like I. just I remember my alarm went off And I had to be up like I had to go there at 7 a.m.
Speaker 0: And chop onions, and I just went back to bed.
Speaker 1: the thing is if I quit you know It's like I could have said no I quit.
Speaker 1: right if I quit.
Speaker 1: I definitely can't get any unenjoyment moneys But I think I can't tell like it was.
Speaker 0: you say unenjoyment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was pretty good That's.
Speaker 1: everyone says that I've never heard that never heard that.
Speaker 1: no.
Speaker 1: It's it's always called that.
Speaker 0: no I've never heard it.
Speaker 1: I've heard it a million times.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I never have.
Speaker 1: I'm being honest here all right they You know it's like I looked at all the requirements for what makes you eligible right.
Speaker 1: so on a New York State website It says first of all you know if you were fired because you're insubordinate or whatever that you can't get it, right?
Speaker 0: I don't think that's the case in your situation.
Speaker 1: I don't know it kind of.
Speaker 1: it depends.
Speaker 1: You know that form that I signed.
Speaker 1: you know they like checked off three boxes Which were like you know not showing up to work when we want you to?
Speaker 1: So I guess it kinda is.
Speaker 0: they had a form.
Speaker 1: yeah, there's a form.
Speaker 1: as a son It was like.
Speaker 1: you know this is why we're firing.
Speaker 1: you sign it.
Speaker 0: you could have just nods.
Speaker 0: I don't know how that we could just not signing.
Speaker 1: it basically says yes.
Speaker 1: I have seen these forms.
Speaker 1: Yes, I know what they mean.
Speaker 1: It's one of those.
Speaker 1: It's not a. I agree I will be fine.
Speaker 0: remember when I left IBM, and they made me sign like ten different things.
Speaker 1: I said a lot more shit when I quit than when I got fired, but the funny thing is I remember I'm like.
Speaker 0: I'm going through all these papers.
Speaker 0: I liked my manager, and I was I was doing it all in good faith And I signed the like non-compete and I signed the NDA and I signed the non head under stuff because you know I was nice.
Speaker 0: but I remember one point.
Speaker 0: I asked my manager like so Do I have to sign these?
Speaker 0: and she's like yeah, and I'm like no no really like.
Speaker 0: do I have to?
Speaker 0: what if I just didn't?
Speaker 0: What are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: And she was like I don't know.
Speaker 0: I guess I just take your badge the same as I'm gonna do and we're done with this.
Speaker 1: Yeah But yeah, no you know.
Speaker 1: so they took all my stuff.
Speaker 1: I sent a little email.
Speaker 1: You know it was.
Speaker 1: it was very unexciting But it was definitely.
Speaker 1: it was a better experience than quitting the previous job to come to the car at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, most recent job because I pretty much when I quit that job.
Speaker 1: They're like oh bye.
Speaker 1: But it was like what I didn't even have a chance to like talk to anyone Or or anything like that.
Speaker 1: You know it's weird at least this one.
Speaker 1: I got to be like bye Cuz.
Speaker 1: I remember you ran keep in touch.
Speaker 0: when I quit the hospital.
Speaker 0: it was Like I gave him a month notice like I'm gonna quit in a month expecting.
Speaker 1: Oh at the hospital you didn't seem like you had anyone to say goodbye to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well there was one cool guy.
Speaker 1: the only reason I didn't quit this job is because there were like a few people there was Still like it was up.
Speaker 0: There are two cool guys there.
Speaker 0: one cool Guy was my manager who worked for like two weeks and then quit.
Speaker 1: No, but I mean these are some of these people I've been working with you know two years.
Speaker 0: It's not like you know No, but the only other cool guy at the hospital quit after I'd worked there for about a month And I remember the email he sent out was like so long and thanks for all the fish.
Speaker 0: And I was like yeah, you were cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, but the other tech guy who was the only tech guy It's still there now.
Speaker 1: He he's a. he's up in Massachusetts.
Speaker 1: So when we go to anime boss, and we probably you know go do lunch with him or something.
Speaker 1: Ah me good time.
Speaker 1: He likes it.
Speaker 1: he likes good food.
Speaker 0: He's not one of those.
Speaker 0: so maybe maybe it's time to work on stuff.
Speaker 1: It's definitely time to work on stuff.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna finish some this week.
Speaker 1: I'm definitely finishing one thing.
Speaker 1: as soon as that's done I got something else in the pipe that I'm gonna make.
Speaker 0: it's in the hopper.
Speaker 1: It's in the hopper.
Speaker 1: It'll probably only take me two weeks to get something that works Right and does like the minimum.
Speaker 1: I need to put it up and maybe put some ads on it try to make some money And then I'm also of course simultaneously going to look for actual safe jobs at the same time yep, and then You know as long as you know stuff is cool.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: You know we'll see where it goes And that'll be that.
Speaker 0: Good, you know can't be sitting around being a bum right, but apparently that's what they want you to do to get unemployment, right?
Speaker 1: So I don't know if I'm eligible cuz I first of all was I fired.
Speaker 1: it was I laid off I was kind of fired, so I guess I'm sort of can't right.
Speaker 1: but also It says on the New York State website if you're working for yourself Even if you aren't making any money you can't you're not eligible.
Speaker 1: So it's like if I start working on something I mean sure who are they?
Speaker 1: they won't know they won't have any idea, but technically right I?
Speaker 0: I'm working on something like what's the difference?
Speaker 0: What if you're working on open source stuff?
Speaker 0: Is that a job?
Speaker 1: No, it says self.
Speaker 1: You know it says if you're working on actual work for you.
Speaker 0: It sounds like that only applies if you actually like file your taxes as I am a self-employed individual.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess they wouldn't know if I didn't file the taxes.
Speaker 1: But you know I might file the taxes if something works out in the next you know month or two I might have to file the taxes.
Speaker 1: I would like to file the tax very much.
Speaker 1: I'll be very nice It actually we wouldn't be very nice because I have to pay some accountant to do it cuz I'm sure as hell can't do It for myself if it's anything more complicated than you know the simple stuff, which I already do.
Speaker 0: well if anything I'm working from home.
Speaker 0: I think on Wednesday, so we can go to the kybo.
Speaker 0: Oh Kyvo lunch on Wednesday, and just hanging out around too, so we can grab her.
Speaker 1: you're gonna have to pay for me No more no less.
Speaker 0: operate for Scott Yeah, but I see I could buy you lunch, but I'm kind of eyeing that eclipse across the street.
Speaker 1: I went and looked at it.
Speaker 1: first of all that eclipse across the street was not an o7 Three it's no three yeah, but it's real cheap.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 1: It's a v6.
Speaker 1: Which is nice right.
Speaker 1: It's good condition.
Speaker 0: It's got leather seats.
Speaker 1: Which is nice.
Speaker 1: the condition looks okay, right, but I'm sure you know at least is better than your car.
Speaker 1: I mean the air conditioning will work and such and Scott eight grand You think was it really a?
Speaker 1: I thought you said it was 12.
Speaker 0: no He was like it's 12 ish, but we can we can be really really negotiable.
Speaker 0: So I emailed him back today, and I was like yeah, so seriously eight or nine, and he was like yeah, probably I mean if it's eight for a car just to you know replace your piece of crap and keep going.
Speaker 0: thing is Because when I was driving my car the other day, right, I got back from the train station.
Speaker 0: I got to the train station.
Speaker 0: I mean it doesn't.
Speaker 1: it's not perfect.
Speaker 1: It's not that car.
Speaker 1: You know that's not a car.
Speaker 1: That's like.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: all man's awesome, but you know why it'll hold you over long enough.
Speaker 1: you take care of it.
Speaker 0: Thing is I was only looking because the other day.
Speaker 0: I got home to the train station.
Speaker 0: I get in my car.
Speaker 0: I turn it on I pull out and the car goes.
Speaker 1: You're gonna drive the car.
Speaker 1: the sun fire is going to explode.
Speaker 1: It's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: so the head is just gonna pull out the bus.
Speaker 1: I'm driving home just like the.
Speaker 0: oh, there's smoke coming out the exhaust the cars making these screaming noises, and I can't tell.
Speaker 0: It's either the power steering or the transmission.
Speaker 0: But I can't tell.
Speaker 0: unless I like get out of the car and fiddle with it, and you know I'm driving home.
Speaker 0: I got stuff to do so I just keep driving trying to guess.
Speaker 1: I'll like so how did you get to the train today?
Speaker 0: Well, I drove the car like that.
Speaker 0: You know the next morning And then that night finally I drove around with Emily and then I came home And I I went.
Speaker 0: I went over to that parking lot by the auto parts store over there And I was on.
Speaker 0: yeah I drove it around slowly in a circle with the hood open like walking next to it Turning the wheel and listening and looking and listening and looking and I figured out all right Something's wrong with the power steering definitely not the transmission.
Speaker 0: Which was a shock.
Speaker 0: so I stop it and I Look and I see that there's like oil and burn all around.
Speaker 0: the power transmission flew or the power steering fluid.
Speaker 0: well Mm-hmm, huh?
Speaker 0: The smokes coming from - yeah, so I take a rag.
Speaker 0: where the smoke this fire I twist it to open it and the top pops off and all the power steering fluid had like burned away.
Speaker 1: Are you supposed to like not open that?
Speaker 0: now you can open that okay?
Speaker 0: Cuz this don't open the brake fluid.
Speaker 1: uh-huh there's stuff like.
Speaker 1: you're not supposed to open and other stuff.
Speaker 1: You're only supposed to open when it's on and other stuff.
Speaker 1: You're only supposed to open if it's off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know this stuff.
Speaker 1: You're only supposed to open if you're a professional.
Speaker 1: yeah It's like the thing.
Speaker 1: I don't understand.
Speaker 1: is this stuff.
Speaker 1: You're never supposed to open.
Speaker 1: Why is it open a bowl?
Speaker 0: So the mechanic can open it.
Speaker 1: right, but if the mechanic can open it They should have a special like thing that doesn't even look like it's openable except to a mechanic.
Speaker 0: You know Yeah, but at the same time the scary warning is enough.
Speaker 0: for most people it was Yeah, like I had a my son fired.
Speaker 1: So did you buy some power steering fluid at the AutoZone II.
Speaker 1: just dump it in.
Speaker 0: well I dumped it in.
Speaker 0: I also dumped in some because I found a leak too.
Speaker 0: So I dumped in some power steering fluid leak stopper.
Speaker 1: so speaking of Speaking of cars right so my car has you know it's an o6.
Speaker 1: I just paid it off which is good considering you have no money As these like strips of molding on the doors right and a piece of the molding sort of chipped off when I open the door One day, and I was you know.
Speaker 1: so I'm trying to figure out what to do about it.
Speaker 1: So I finally realized you know I went to the dealer.
Speaker 1: the dealer was closed.
Speaker 1: So I'm like well, what do I do here?
Speaker 1: I went and I was like hey, I'm stupid.
Speaker 1: I went and took a picture of it.
Speaker 1: I went to the Mazda forums, and I was like hey What do I do about this?
Speaker 1: You know what they said?
Speaker 0: What did they say?
Speaker 1: surprisingly everyone was like?
Speaker 1: Pretty much everyone in these forums takes those things off.
Speaker 1: Really, yeah, no one leaves them on.
Speaker 1: they're like and everyone hide all these pictures like look Here's my car with them off.
Speaker 1: I took them off.
Speaker 1: They look stupid and why should you have them on there?
Speaker 0: Huh, you're taking them off.
Speaker 1: Well the thing is to take them off.
Speaker 1: the guy gave me directions right.
Speaker 1: basically what you do is No first.
Speaker 1: I got a way for it to be warm Right.
Speaker 0: that way the adhesive will be gooier right so you can take a hairdryer to it.
Speaker 1: I could do that, but that's a lot of work right.
Speaker 1: so wait till it's warm right.
Speaker 1: then get some fishing wire.
Speaker 1: I just sort of go behind it and right off right, but then they'll be all this adhesive still stuck to the door.
Speaker 1: You got to go get some goo gone or some 3m adhesive remover or whatever and they have they.
Speaker 1: you know they have some that is specifically non damaging to auto paint whatever and Then you just use it and get all the goop off and then you just have a door That's perfectly clean, and then I guess that you know I should probably like wax the car or whatever after you do something like that.
Speaker 1: You know, but whatever.
Speaker 1: That's that's what I'm gonna do when it's warm.
Speaker 0: Take some pictures.
Speaker 1: certainly have free time.
Speaker 0: So I suppose we should talk at least a little bit about the iPhone OS 3.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we can't avoid it.
Speaker 0: It's Monday Much like how twit has to talk about Twitter.
Speaker 1: Oh the twit today was so bad.
Speaker 1: just talking about Twitter Twitter and like Stupid Jason Calacanis the guy's doing his bad Christopher Walken impression.
Speaker 1: It's like they're not talking about Technology anymore.
Speaker 1: It's become like it.
Speaker 1: You know just like a tech celebrity They did like talk about spin right again.
Speaker 0: Did they?
Speaker 1: they tell you I spin right on security now.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, it's yeah, I don't know the only podcast Listen to anymore anime world order and Dave and Joel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just I just remember when twit used about talk about tech.
Speaker 1: but on the other hand I kind of like to it going out direction because it means hey, let's just do the twit thing It's not doing it anymore.
Speaker 1: So we can walk right.
Speaker 1: see you know it's like if Cartoon Network stops showing cartoons.
Speaker 1: There's room for us to come in and be carton show cartoons cuz they're not showing them.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll switch up the Monday format.
Speaker 0: I just do a tech news roundup every time.
Speaker 1: real tech news roundup.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah anyway, but not.
Speaker 0: but now you realize if we do that then after a year We're just gonna have to talk about nothing of a twit.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So the iPhone the 3.0 first of all just so people know right.
Speaker 1: they all they did was make an announcement of what the iPhone 3.0 software is gonna be.
Speaker 1: they didn't actually release it right.
Speaker 1: so it's probably gonna come out this summer and it's very likely that when it comes out there will be another iPhone a new iPhone for it to go on right.
Speaker 1: and It's that way.
Speaker 1: all the people who bought the very first iPhone their contract runs out in the summer.
Speaker 1: So they will probably buy the new iPhone right.
Speaker 1: and I can see what's gonna happen here Is we're very likely going to see new iPhone software and new iPhones like every single June or July Whatever the month is for As long as you know that continues right because that way everyone who has you know their iPhone contract expires.
Speaker 1: Then they get.
Speaker 1: they just migrate over to the newer better one every two years to your contract.
Speaker 1: doo doo doo doo doo, right?
Speaker 1: And that's what they're gonna do.
Speaker 0: brilliant.
Speaker 1: It's it's business.
Speaker 1: Hey There's a lot of features.
Speaker 1: you can read online what they all are.
Speaker 1: Some of them are pretty exciting some of them not so exciting, you know, depending on what you care about.
Speaker 1: I mean a lot of the features are really for Developers more and not so exciting for users like the ability to buy stuff from within an app, right?
Speaker 1: That's sort of good because now when like you die right now you go to the iPhone App Store and it's like you'll see Like such-and-such program light such-and-such program not free right and the light one is free.
Speaker 1: So you go and you get the free one and then if you want the real one You got to go back and pay for the other one and delete the free one.
Speaker 1: now It's just gonna be like hey, you can buy stuff in the apps.
Speaker 1: that means you could buy a game and then buy levels for the game from within the game or you could go and get a Download a free demo and then from within the free demo buy the actual game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know it's good in one way But at the same time it's good for the developers who are making mad Bank.
Speaker 1: Maybe I should you want to give me a hundred bucks.
Speaker 1: I could buy the iPhone dev kit.
Speaker 1: Maybe I won't wait so suddenly I have to fund everything.
Speaker 0: you do have no money savings a lot.
Speaker 1: Okay, I gotta be the cheapest possible.
Speaker 0: Jew I'm buying like a house and stuff, but my my thousands of dollars are going elsewhere.
Speaker 1: Well, it's all ramen for me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, um the thing that I'm the only thing that I'm actually sort of you know excited to see is like the notifications You know, which it's like.
Speaker 1: well if we can't have background apps Notifications sort of make up for it.
Speaker 1: Okay, if I can just have all my I am clients and the thing will be whenever I get an I am immediately But I don't actually have to like, you know, keep it open with the I am app on the whole time That sort of.
Speaker 1: that's.
Speaker 1: that's sort of good enough, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah, but will that hurt the battery?
Speaker 1: Ah, you know, well the way they're doing is don't last that long as it's true But they're doing it in a certain way that you know shouldn't hurt the battery as much.
Speaker 1: you know Where the I am purse, you know The company that makes the app sends the things to Apple server and then Apple server sends me the updates You know and it it shouldn't hurt the battery any more than you know.
Speaker 1: exchange push, right?
Speaker 1: It should be about the same.
Speaker 1: And I heard something about cal dev support which might eliminate the need for Google sync on the calendars and such.
Speaker 1: There'll be a lot more calendar goings-on which is very very good if that's if that is indeed true.
Speaker 1: It's also the copy pasta which everyone was excited about but you shouldn't be excited.
Speaker 0: That's like if they released a game Like I don't know.
Speaker 0: they made Mario and they put it on the iPhone and there
Speaker 1: was no jump button and then later they had Exactly
Speaker 0: what I was gonna say Yeah No and then they Rumored the jump button but wouldn't admit whether or not it was gonna be there and they told people they didn't need the jump button And then eventually eventually they released the jump button, but only if you buy Mario -
Speaker 1: yeah,
Speaker 0: which doesn't have a jump button.
Speaker 1: Thing is the copy paste.
Speaker 1: it's like just the way the iPhone works and the way I use it.
Speaker 1: I mean, I would use the copy paste sometimes but I wouldn't really use it that much.
Speaker 1: I mean what you know, really what am I gonna use it?
Speaker 1: So where am I gonna copy and paste, you know?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess it's just one of those basic things.
Speaker 1: I might copy and paste like a URL from an email, but it highlights the URLs like you just touch them.
Speaker 1: So what?
Speaker 0: yeah, I guess more useful would be if instead if they'd included copy paste by default But instead they included by default some sort of annotation system for everything.
Speaker 0: I don't know I get a lot of vague ideas.
Speaker 1: Well, they got the.
Speaker 1: they're added the spotlight search which is pretty much you can search everything on the phone from one screen Which is a good idea.
Speaker 1: That's not bad.
Speaker 1: Sort of what the pre is doing a little bit.
Speaker 0: Oh the pre.
Speaker 0: I'm I'm kind of feeling the pre.
Speaker 0: I was feel on the pre.
Speaker 1: You know the thing about the pre is it's gonna be sore.
Speaker 1: It's weird because the iPhone is gonna be more like Windows and the pre is gonna be more like Mac.
Speaker 1: Right because the what the pre is gonna do is all the built-in stuff on the pre is gonna have like awesome Syncing suppose if it lives up to the hype, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it may or may not.
Speaker 0: This is Palms last guy.
Speaker 1: It's gonna have like all this awesome Synchronization with everything and you know, everything is gonna be like web stuff and it's gonna be.
Speaker 1: you know That has a big potential to be pretty much everything I could possibly want.
Speaker 1: But the iPhone with its app store, even though the app store is, you know, get a lot of problems.
Speaker 1: There's just so many apps And it's so widely supported.
Speaker 1: just how Windows is.
Speaker 1: so Windows is not that great but everything is for Windows.
Speaker 1: So it's like everything is for iPhone.
Speaker 1: There might what you want might not be for free.
Speaker 1: So even if the pre is better in and of itself the way like, you know, Linux is better than Windows If it doesn't have all the apps, it's like.
Speaker 1: well I can't you know do the thing I want because it doesn't get.
Speaker 1: no one made it for the pre even though the pre is Much like Windows.
Speaker 0: While there are a few killer apps that you need Windows if you want to use them The majority of the software out there is garbage and I mean look at the iPhone apps.
Speaker 0: We talked about Yeah a while ago where most people if they buy an app use it for maybe a couple weeks at most and the
Speaker 1: things I went through and deleted like almost all the apps on my phone except the ones I actually use and I keep even deleting more and more and more.
Speaker 1: and I mean after this update I can actually see myself using Less of them the only ones I think I would actually use or I still use the remember the milk, right?
Speaker 1: And I still you I would use them, you know if Meebo comes out with that app, which apparently they're going to I'd get that and then I'd cancel my text messaging and Then I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think that would be That'd be it.
Speaker 1: I mean really what else I got?
Speaker 1: the web browser on there and the email and the calendar and That's sort of.
Speaker 1: you know, that's sort of the thing right is the pre does all those things.
Speaker 1: So Yeah Yeah My contract I still got you know another year.
Speaker 1: so like this coming update is mostly, you know, it'll make the remaining year of my iPhone experience much better and then You know, it'll help out.
Speaker 1: the people who got the original iPhone and their contracts are up Now can get you know, probably a new iPhone and the new software, you know with the subsidization and renew their contracts And they'll be happy if they still want to stick with the iPhone.
Speaker 1: and then you know in June Oh 10 I'll definitely have a job or be dead by then or homeless or in Detroit or something.
Speaker 1: There's no way I can go that long.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just buy one of those $500 houses in Detroit.
Speaker 1: It's an option, you know, I know people out there.
Speaker 0: I can I can I can get you guns.
Speaker 0: You'll need guns.
Speaker 1: listen there's there are plenty of options.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, there's like this foreign legion option.
Speaker 1: There's Peace Corps options plenty of options, you know, I could go volunteer for like, you know some African Plenty of shit I can do and not in any sort of.
Speaker 0: well foreign lesions not an option.
Speaker 0: You have to be able to do a push-up I'll just I'll just do something.
Speaker 1: I'll just do push-up Legion first.
Speaker 0: So the economy's bad.
Speaker 0: I remember it was interesting when I was I looked at this car and then I talked to the car guy and I was like Yeah, how are things doing with the economy the way it is?
Speaker 0: He's like, you know what use car sales?
Speaker 0: skyrocketing Really?
Speaker 1: Cuz they you think that you know new car sales nada.
Speaker 0: And basically what he was pointing out is that used cars, you know, because for in America I don't know how it is in the rest of the world, but pretty much if you buy a car a new car it's brand new and it's exactly what you want and Five minutes after you have driven it off the lot.
Speaker 0: It's worth crap like it's lost enough of its value to where?
Speaker 0: economically I mean ignoring the Benefit the comfort benefits of knowing that you have a brand new car.
Speaker 0: Buying a used car like a one-year-old car saves you stupid amounts of money here Just because of the nature of the market in the industry.
Speaker 1: Well, what it has is you have you have a situation of Exponentially diminishing losses right, you know, assuming that the car stays working and nothing bad, you know It doesn't break right the dip.
Speaker 1: When the carpet a car that's one-year-old is worth a lot less is like thousands of dollars.
Speaker 1: less than a brand new Two years old is worth a lot, you know Significantly less than a one-year-old.
Speaker 1: But as soon as you go on like a five and a four-year-old car not so much different as you know The difference between those two cars is not anywhere near the difference between a brand new one and a one-year-old car Even though it's a one-year difference.
Speaker 1: So buying a car that is brand new is if you look at it as an investment, you know It's pretty stupid if you you know, but if you look at it as I'm buying what I want I want something new then it doesn't really fucking matter, you know, it's sort of like Buy a house.
Speaker 1: Yeah people who buy a house to invest and people buy a house to drive, you know to live in Drive my Winnebago Winnebago, yes, I was not totally flubbing.
Speaker 0: Well, there's also the new Pixar movie That's true.
Speaker 1: That's not driving them.
Speaker 1: But no, you know, so if you buy a car to drive Maybe new is the right choice if you can afford it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same time, I don't know I feel like the American car industry Is already having a lot of trouble obviously and I feel like one of the biggest problems is that?
Speaker 0: They do this thing where every single year they make like a new model of every car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and this was driven by the way our economy worked and the fact that people are constantly buying a new car.
Speaker 1: That's sort of like the fundamental.
Speaker 1: see that's a lot of people are talking about.
Speaker 1: This is that they're sort of fundamental things that people sort of accept as That's the way it is because that's the way it is and it seems like it's a law of the universe.
Speaker 1: But it's really not.
Speaker 1: why why does the car come here to make a new model every year?
Speaker 0: How come they have to make every model slightly different like?
Speaker 0: the 1997 Miata was a beautiful car.
Speaker 0: It was an amazing car.
Speaker 0: I love the 1997 Mazda Miata.
Speaker 0: So why did they have to make it crook slightly so in 1998 and then crook slightly so again in 1999?
Speaker 0: I mean what.
Speaker 0: the only reason they got away with that is because the economy was such that people were driven To buy new cars pun very much intended and the used car market was like this secondary side thing.
Speaker 0: But suddenly the economy's bad and people notice that they can get a car That's just as good as a new car for five to ten grand.
Speaker 1: Well, I think actually you know lemon laws have had this.
Speaker 1: you know cuz cars You know didn't used to be so long-lasting.
Speaker 1: the other thing I realized that lemon laws have forced people to make even if you buy the cheap crappy brands or you buy a Hyundai or a Kia or you know a brand of car that is.
Speaker 1: That's the thing I'm saying is like these are you know brand the the impression people have of these brands?
Speaker 1: that they're lower quality?
Speaker 1: Right they cost less.
Speaker 1: They don't have the fancy features.
Speaker 1: It's not like a Mercedes right and a Mercedes will last you like 25 years Mercedes aside, right?
Speaker 1: But you know, but I'm saying is you know, it's the the G even the cheapest cars from the crappiest.
Speaker 1: You know the lowest end cars They're they're great.
Speaker 1: the last you a long time cheap ass like Chevy Aveo It'll last you.
Speaker 0: what I've noticed talking to people and looking around is that in general?
Speaker 0: Older people are more likely to consider a new car first or be distrustful of a used car.
Speaker 0: But younger people seem to be more likely to buy a used car.
Speaker 0: not just for economics But I feel like it's perception because in the 80s there were cars that were just lemons.
Speaker 0: you could buy a brand new car And it just sucks already and you can buy a used car that you know.
Speaker 0: After a year the car is basically worthless because it was a lemon.
Speaker 0: But that doesn't happen anymore as far as I can tell at least I mean my son fire Lasted forever and I traded like crap and as far as I can tell also in fires last forever And then they all have the same problems.
Speaker 0: mine has ten years down the road.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it used car still works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, as long as you don't get in an accident or have you know some random breakage or something like that As long as you change the oil and such and maintain it minimally Just about any car is gonna work for quite a while.
Speaker 1: and you know I mean like you know a lot of the used cars out there.
Speaker 1: right like my grandma right she leases like you know a Toyota And then she just gives it back and gets a new one whenever cuz it just exists a constant cost for her It doesn't change.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so she's like why not just go put back the lease and get the newer one?
Speaker 1: I can always have the the great that I can always be driving a new one.
Speaker 0: I'm still kind of looking at leasing because you know I used to drive a lot.
Speaker 0: I used to put.
Speaker 1: yeah, if you don't mind paying the same price forever That's a great option because you always get the pleasure of a brand new car.
Speaker 0: I used to all.
Speaker 0: I used to put 50 to 70 thousand miles on my car every year Like I used to drive a lot.
Speaker 1: now you drive a lot less.
Speaker 0: now I put maybe nine thousand.
Speaker 1: my first year of ownership when I worked in the middle of nowhere I put like a bajillion miles on the car like 30,000. since then I've put like 10 like now.
Speaker 0: the majority of the miles I put on my car this year were driving up to Hunter Mountain skiing Yep, that was more than my joy to my miles like driving to Connecticut and conventions.
Speaker 0: That's it yep, and those are all like you know trips, and we don't drive to Seattle.
Speaker 0: so nope.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I was thinking about that.
Speaker 0: Just why does the lease?
Speaker 0: and every two years I get a brand new car and I pay like 300 bucks a month for the Rest of my life.
Speaker 1: right, but think about this right?
Speaker 1: those cars that my grandma leases gives back and leases a new one Those are used cars now that one-year-old two-year-old car that my grandma drove.
Speaker 1: You can just lease you can buy that guy and it's way cheap.
Speaker 1: My grandma drove it for two years.
Speaker 1: It's perfect.
Speaker 0: the point of all this is that I Feel like there's going to be an even bigger day of reckoning for the car industry of the world And I think it's going to be precipitated by the Tata Nano.
Speaker 0: Okay, you know about the Tata Nano cuz this was rumored like five years ago.
Speaker 0: I remember Todd sighs like a Jessica character if people were talking about how.
Speaker 0: yeah, India There's this company working on like a hundred dollar car And it was China was working on like a $2,000 China, India.
Speaker 0: but there were a lot of rumors about.
Speaker 0: you know China or India or a nation like that is going to make like a Couple hundred dollar car, and it'll just go just barely and it's so cheap that you can just buy ten and it's finally come to fruition.
Speaker 0: the Tata Nano is Twenty five hundred dollars and is a perfectly street-legal car.
Speaker 1: and it in the United States?
Speaker 0: Well in India to start okay, but it looks like it's going to be made available in Britain.
Speaker 1: Is that four wheels?
Speaker 0: it is a real?
Speaker 0: How big is it for its five seats?
Speaker 1: Also, it's a size of a sedan.
Speaker 0: It is a real car.
Speaker 1: It's a four-door car.
Speaker 0: Well, yes, it's a. it's the size of a European sedan.
Speaker 1: Okay, that's not American But it's a. it's a four-door as four doors.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It is a real car.
Speaker 1: Is it front-wheel drive?
Speaker 1: Yes, is it?
Speaker 1: how big is them?
Speaker 1: What's the biggest?
Speaker 1: All right, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: It's got a 624 cc two Cylinder 33 horsepower engine.
Speaker 1: so it's a motorcycle engine.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing it weighs so little.
Speaker 0: It still goes 0 to 65 in like 17 seconds even with five fat people.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is fat people won't fit in this car.
Speaker 0: It's made for India and then eventually Britain.
Speaker 0: Of course Britain is actually fatter than that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess if you had, you know light people that would they would work right.
Speaker 0: but but even that for city driving air conditioning.
Speaker 0: But here's the deal.
Speaker 0: it is a car that goes.
Speaker 0: it actually goes.
Speaker 0: it looks like it's reliable enough.
Speaker 0: It looks more reliable than you go.
Speaker 1: Well, it's real easy to fix - it's like a motorcycle, right?
Speaker 1: It's got a tiny little engine you could cut.
Speaker 1: the engine explodes big deal.
Speaker 1: It's a two-cylinder.
Speaker 1: I'll just get another one off this like Harley that's.
Speaker 1: it averages 60 miles per gallon And plus this would actually be a great car to buy like a high school kid because he's probably just gonna drive himself in it Right or yeah, and they get totally modded it to hell because it's so simple.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but The fact that they can make a car that goes just fine for 2,500 bucks retail.
Speaker 1: And yeah good car to send to like Cuba.
Speaker 0: and yet in America We make a new model of every single 10 to $40,000 car every single year.
Speaker 0: and now people can't afford to buy those cars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I really just you know, the fact that cars last so long You know, they just we don't need new ones.
Speaker 1: We have enough cars for everyone.
Speaker 1: We can just use all the cars we have.
Speaker 1: and until you know until the point at which Someone wants a car and the car they want is not available Then we're not gonna need any more new cars.
Speaker 1: until then and looking at how many cars are sitting on boats Sitting on docks, you know sitting in factories We just don't need anyone to make new ones until the ones we have break, you know That's it's sorry.
Speaker 1: That's like the reverse razor blade model.
Speaker 1: I imagine if Gillette made razors that lasted for five years will eventually every dude would have one.
Speaker 1: Well, you know.
Speaker 1: and then what is Gillette supposed to do?
Speaker 0: everyone's got actually a famous old parable about that the the Candle maker who was such an amazing candle maker that he invented a candle that never burned out.
Speaker 1: Whoa He's all the candle everyone.
Speaker 1: and then he was out of business.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the parable.
Speaker 1: Yeah So what do we do about that?
Speaker 0: That's what we do.
Speaker 1: It's best for the world if the candle maker makes that candle but in a capitalist Society right with with free enterprise no one would ever make that candle and do what's best for everyone.
Speaker 1: and make that awesome candle the car that lasts forever because They wouldn't be able to make any more money.
Speaker 0: The real issue here is that America's economy in particular in a lot of places Really relies upon this inefficient, you know make new cars constantly model assuming that people will buy them.
Speaker 0: And now that people aren't buying them and now that people are buying foreign cars, too It all comes together.
Speaker 0: and well, he's too many cars.
Speaker 1: So here's one solution.
Speaker 1: right would be to set up the system such that right.
Speaker 1: Let's say I invented the candle to last forever or the car that never broke, right.
Speaker 1: if the system if I'm able through You know to receive enough compensation for that to live a life of luxury until I die, you know Then that sort of works.
Speaker 1: I have the incentive to make that right because it's even though I'll sell one to everyone to be done I'm fine.
Speaker 1: Well Scott the problem is is a lot of people and there are not enough things for everyone to do?
Speaker 0: Well, no the the much more pressing issues that in the real world forget the stupid candle maker Industry and the economy rely on there.
Speaker 0: if we don't make these cars constantly What are all the people who work in the car fast and I'm saying do?
Speaker 1: all the people in my candle factory are fucked.
Speaker 0: I Don't know what to do about it But I feel like the economy kind of bringing this day of reckoning onto the car industry plus the fact that the super cheap car Actually came to fruition and is eventually very likely going to spread into the u.s I don't know what's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: I Can see you know that fundamental question we keep asking and never getting answered.
Speaker 1: You know that can only be answered by the invention of the replicator.
Speaker 1: or you know diamond age type technology I think is actually starting to have a real effect on the real world in everyday life.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, what do you do when the only reason we have an economy?
Speaker 0: the only reason we have almost every problem in the world is because there's there are scarce resources and We have to decide how to distribute those scarce resources and at the same time There's an amount of work that needs to be done to get those resources.
Speaker 0: so how do we distribute the work?
Speaker 0: and Technology has gotten us to the point where it takes so little work on Average to get most of these resources that there's not enough work for every person to do.
Speaker 0: But we base our distribution mechanism on how much work people do and there's nothing out.
Speaker 1: What else can people do get?
Speaker 1: deserve the resources other than work?
Speaker 0: We base our system on either how much work you do or how much work the person who then gives you all of their money.
Speaker 0: But that's a whole different problem, so yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I mean This is basically we're slowly coming across something that is on the same scale as the Industrial Revolution and that caused decades upon decades of massive social upheaval.
Speaker 1: I Don't have a job.
Speaker 1: I'm ready to a peeve again.
Speaker 0: I'll peeve.
Speaker 1: I can a peeve at any time.
Speaker 1: Call me Scott available for a peeving.
Speaker 0: Is this gonna be the end of your streak?
Speaker 1: What do you mean my streak?
Speaker 0: Heaved in many more in many moods.
Speaker 1: No, there was a I have peeved.
Speaker 1: there was the show about it.
Speaker 1: It was two years ago.
Speaker 0: I think I listened to that again when I was going through the archives.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay Yeah, so anyway things of the day I'm a fan of the beers and I actually love beers or dead beers.
Speaker 0: the beers, you know Dog bears up bears the bears the bears the drinking kind not the wearing kind.
Speaker 0: Yes, not the wearing kind and not the.
Speaker 0: you can't be a kind.
Speaker 0: Okay, but I didn't know much about India pale ale other than that.
Speaker 0: I see it all the time and then I found this article.
Speaker 0: I know there is a such a beverage as pale ale talking about some company Who is trying to recreate what India pale ale used to really taste like I?
Speaker 1: Should start.
Speaker 1: you know what I should do it all this computer work my new company.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna recreate the gross me hell banana.
Speaker 0: The gross me hell.
Speaker 1: I'm going to go to botany school.
Speaker 0: But anyway, actually I've got this crazy idea because I'm looking at houses And that bar down the streets for sale and it's got like a house apartment connected to it And I don't think it's that expensive.
Speaker 0: I asked, you know to check it out how much it is.
Speaker 0: I have this vague idea of buying it moving into it telling Pete to quit his job.
Speaker 0: Helen would come down here paying for his food and all he has to do is cook for me and brew beer and if he Succeeds, I'll open a brew pub and if he fails I will never open the bar and I will just have my own private bar.
Speaker 1: Let's do me a favor.
Speaker 1: Don't don't move anywhere until I have some incomes because I can't afford to stay here alone.
Speaker 0: Well, if I buy a house, I guess you could pay me rent.
Speaker 0: I Guess I could.
Speaker 0: I could loan you if you can pay me back on Tuesday.
Speaker 1: I can pay you back When I get money anyway, and if I can't pay you back I'll run away to Detroit or something.
Speaker 0: So beer was on the mind and apparently the from what I can gather from this article India pale ale was made the way it was so that it would survive the horrible horrible ship journey to India And as a result it had a very distinct flavor partly because the barrels were treated like crap and it got hot and cold and hot and cold and they get washed overboard and Stuff would see.
Speaker 1: so they just making some pale ale and then putting out a boat sailing around and bringing it back.
Speaker 1: Yes They're doing that's awesome.
Speaker 0: now, I find this awesome.
Speaker 0: However, I was like, huh?
Speaker 0: This interesting So I think is something is based on the assumptions from the article.
Speaker 0: I went to Wikipedia and I was like Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Tell me about India pale ale and The facts between these.
Speaker 0: this article and that article don't line up and I have no idea.
Speaker 0: Okay, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Here's here's the goal.
Speaker 1: only quite the first question that came to my mind, right?
Speaker 1: Is that okay?
Speaker 1: In the olden days, right if the India pale ale was meant to last the trip to India from say Europe, right?
Speaker 1: Then if they want to take it on a boat and bring it back are they gonna go halfway to India and come back?
Speaker 0: Yes, they're not going they're not taking?
Speaker 1: or are they gonna make it in India and then bring it up?
Speaker 0: I thought the article talks about that.
Speaker 1: actually Okay, how long it's gonna be out there, but they said I mean to be really genuine You'd have to have the drinkers on the boat.
Speaker 1: It wouldn't go else.
Speaker 1: It wouldn't be the same.
Speaker 0: Well Genuine is a fine line.
Speaker 0: I would say this would be an interesting experience.
Speaker 1: It's like manga that reads in the wrong direction.
Speaker 0: I Don't know.
Speaker 0: I just I like the idea of making things the old way just to see what they were like Even though the old way is often not better
Speaker 1: or at least approximating it or at least You know possibly being closer to the way it was like
Speaker 0: that time when I made grog and you discovered that grog tastes terrible.
Speaker 1: Well rum tastes terrible.
Speaker 0: rum is delicious.
Speaker 0: it tastes like it's terrible tastes like cough medicine.
Speaker 1: It's all.
Speaker 1: alcohol tastes either like cough medicine or rubbing alcohol.
Speaker 0: You've never had good alcohol.
Speaker 0: Anyway, oh you have a low tolerance for it, but I thought this was neat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't like India pale ale that much to be honest.
Speaker 0: I'm.
Speaker 0: I'm more of a like.
Speaker 0: I like Karen like Japanese pills nurse.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't know if I liked it or not, but I bet it tastes like either cough medicine or rubbing alcohol.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, so um, I Talked about the thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I think a week or so a while ago about love which is a game Building engine with the Lua language.
Speaker 1: There's apparently someone out there making a game called love Which is nothing to do with the game engine called love.
Speaker 1: So this is completely different, right?
Speaker 1: But it is also called love and It's some sort of like Water is poison has been hyping it up to me.
Speaker 1: And while I'm very skeptical of it as I am skeptical skeptical of everything There is some interesting stuff going on here is making some sort of like MMO FPS.
Speaker 1: It's very freeform and allows you to do all sorts of crazy stuff But like 200 people per server and sort of introversion style graphics anything.
Speaker 0: What bothers me about games like world of worker all these like MMO is what people play.
Speaker 1: even if this is just this could is Probably just gonna have the same fundamental flaws as other MMOs.
Speaker 1: But some way if they at least they're trying if they try to make it massive because the in the end, you know I'll complain about it doesn't look like they're trying to make it massive.
Speaker 1: It looks like they're just trying to make something that's a little bit more than counter-strike, but is actually that's massive?
Speaker 0: Cuz that's what I'm thinking about.
Speaker 0: I Complain about grind and all these other things But really what bothers me about MMOs is that the idea originally was that you can have multiplayer games.
Speaker 0: You know four people or eight people gaga in a deathmatch.
Speaker 0: Yeah but the MMO was like what if we made a game that has like a hundred people all at the same time and MMOs started going in that direction and then for various very good and very bad reasons Became so parallel that they're not really massive.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean when you play counter-strike or tribes, let's use tribes, right?
Speaker 1: There's 60 people on the tribe server.
Speaker 1: You're interacting directly with every one of those other 59 people there.
Speaker 1: That's like, you know, well the same way you're interacting with one other person.
Speaker 0: you're playing chess Even if not directly.
Speaker 0: you're indirectly in the context of the same stateful world having an effect that could be seen by the other people Right, but just they don't make.
Speaker 1: in an MMO like wow there's a whole bunch of other people's avatars around and you can look at them right, but You're very very few of the people.
Speaker 1: Are you ever actually directly?
Speaker 1: Connected with in that way like we go into PvP and like a battleground whatever?
Speaker 1: only the people in that battleground Are you connected to not the thousands of people on the server?
Speaker 0: Well, very simply the difference is that most MMOs became very parallel very quickly and as a result They're still.
Speaker 0: you know, they're big games, but they're not.
Speaker 0: I almost wouldn't want to call them massive games because they're not quite there.
Speaker 0: They're more like a giant ready room and a giant exploratory room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then separate from that this massively parallelized game that people play.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but this I don't know.
Speaker 0: this could do something cool Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so this love game seems to have some potential and the person who's making it I think his name is Eskil Steenburg Has some interesting things to say and people who don't realize this.
Speaker 1: the game developers conference is like now tomorrow ish by the time you're hearing this is probably now.
Speaker 1: ish, right and This guy is gonna give a talk at the game developers conference Tuesday at 4 45.
Speaker 1: So it's I guess for mo.
Speaker 1: if you're listening to this on the Tuesday, March 24th 2009 that would be tip, you know today at 4 45 in room 304 He's given a talk and he put basically a longer version of his talk in text with pictures on his little blog here so you can read it and He says a lot of interesting things about game development.
Speaker 1: But the one thing he's saying That I have noticed has been true in all development of software recently is his emphasis on making tools right and I have noticed this trend for like a few months now and I really think that that there is something going on here, right.
Speaker 1: and Basically, what's happening is look at Twitter right.
Speaker 1: Twitter was a feature for Odeo.
Speaker 1: That's where it started out, right?
Speaker 1: It was a tool for Odeo that that Odeo people made right and then they gave up on Odeo And Twitter became the real thing.
Speaker 1: Django the Python web framework that I'm using it is awesome.
Speaker 1: Was it just a tool?
Speaker 1: It was just.
Speaker 1: you know, the guys at the Kansas City whatever newspaper it was Made this thing that they would build the Kansas City newspaper website on top of it.
Speaker 1: And then it you know was a tool that went on its own and became this bigger thing Ruby on Rails that 37 signals company.
Speaker 1: I think that was that though.
Speaker 1: I think that's the right company.
Speaker 1: well, it was just that right.
Speaker 0: and you see this trend in science and technology forever where You have a lofty goal But you have these very real-world Concerns in the way of that lofty goal and you want to solve them efficiently and quickly to get onto your lofty goal.
Speaker 0: And as a result, you're gonna make all these awesome tools.
Speaker 1: and some people buy tools.
Speaker 1: Some people just do it without good tools and they just get it done Crappily get her done and some people out there actually are nowadays Making.
Speaker 1: when they have something to do They make the perfect tool for the job and then that makes the doing of the actual thing they actually wanted to do real easy and wonderful.
Speaker 1: and The thing is those the tools themselves can often grow and be so awesome that you know, in fact Those are outgrow the thing that you know are more successful than the actual thing you made.
Speaker 1: and he's talking about how like, you know if you do make tools, you should release them publicly because that will force you to maintain them to Give them features that you wouldn't have thought they needed, you know Other people will use them and you'll have all these people out there using your tools for their own purposes.
Speaker 1: so now there's all this talent out there that you can hire to work on your own stuff because they already know your tools.
Speaker 1: and I think there's gonna be a big emphasis on tools and especially as the line blurs more and more between you know You know tools, you know being things that make you know that right now We sort of view it as a tool is something you use to make something that someone consumes, right?
Speaker 1: But we're reaching the point where the things we consume our tools and we use tools to make them and I think there's really gonna be a huge blurring and and eventually no distinction whatsoever between a tool and it's been like a thing you consume You know, you're making will be Consuming very much, you know, you'll get all like the user generated content, right?
Speaker 1: Or I mean when you play rock band, you're also making a performance.
Speaker 1: Not only is it a tool of consuming the music it's also a you know.
Speaker 0: granted it's all degrees.
Speaker 1: I know it is definitely degree because I know people were thinking now it's not for There are definitely degrees to it But it's going to blur more and more as time goes on, you know little big planets and you know They know when you think about it.
Speaker 1: It's gonna blur in the other direction to Photoshop is gonna become more and more.
Speaker 1: You know a you know thing for people to entertain themselves.
Speaker 0: when you think about it.
Speaker 0: it's a lot like the efforts for heat reclamation in engineering where Humans as in the course of entertaining themselves will more and more create things as byproducts of their own entertainment.
Speaker 0: Like I think this is much broader social implications.
Speaker 1: I mean even watching a movie you're forming an opinion which is itself a work.
Speaker 0: if you Tools like the internet where by watching a movie you then blog about it You've now created a separate work.
Speaker 0: then someone else.
Speaker 0: I don't know makes a techno Comments on it blog post and that techno remix turns into.
Speaker 1: so, you know, he's talking about making tools.
Speaker 1: I really think this is something that you really have to think about.
Speaker 1: if you're making something, you know even if it's not technology if it's a if it's an arts and crafts or an art or or whatever right and There's a tool you need.
Speaker 1: right, you know, I mean, where did the hammer come from?
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: It was they didn't make the hammer and the nail.
Speaker 1: first.
Speaker 1: some guy needed to like, you know Hold something up on the wall.
Speaker 1: So he made the nail and then he needed to get the nail in the wall and then he made the hammer And then everyone else said oh man, look at that hammer I'll let that one go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can let it go.
Speaker 1: But you see the tool comes after the job, right?
Speaker 1: so when you're doing something whatever you're doing if you need a tool for it that doesn't exist or there isn't a perfect tool in Existence make that tool and share that tool.
Speaker 1: That is the best thing you could possibly do to like have a very high chance of success.
Speaker 0: Here's a better piece of advice.
Speaker 0: If you are the kind of person who is funding other people doing things like you're a venture capitalist or whatever.
Speaker 0: find someone with a lofty goal set them on that goal and offer to fund them.
Speaker 0: but Take the rights to all the tools they make along the way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean look and that's where the real money will be and then let them have their project.
Speaker 1: This is to make sure that they're making tools, right?
Speaker 1: I mean look at valve, right?
Speaker 1: Sure They make half-life 2. in the course of being half-life 2 they made the source engine Which is been much more valuable than half-life 2 itself, you know.
Speaker 1: So that's that's the way to go.
Speaker 0: So in when I was in high school, I'm gonna call him you know, I don't want to use his real name because He might be out there somewhere if he didn't die already, but I had a friend in high school.
Speaker 0: We'll call him Donnie don't and Do it.
Speaker 0: don't do this Donnie don't does.
Speaker 0: and One anecdote about Donnie don'ts I remember hanging around in the camp.
Speaker 0: well in the physics lab of high school and we're there we're doing some sort of physics II thing But this is our guy.
Speaker 0: This is our guy.
Speaker 0: Okay, so we needed we needed a bunch of really high molar hydrochloric acid To do what we were doing.
Speaker 0: So we had a few hood and under it we had very very very concentrated hydrochloric acid Mmm and the physics professor walks out and says, all right now when you're all taking your sample Keep it away from your face.
Speaker 0: Whatever you do.
Speaker 1: Don't inhale the vapors Because not even if you waft it because you'll probably pass out not even if you left won't be good for you Wafting is no good.
Speaker 0: No one asked about wafting.
Speaker 0: Okay, and as he says you'll probably pass out.
Speaker 0: Donnie don't says really and proceeds to pass out.
Speaker 1: Did he drop the beaker on the ground?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It was a tiny beaker.
Speaker 1: Okay I was like if you're holding a beaker you sniff it and then you drop it can land on your foot.
Speaker 1: Yeah passed out and acid is burning your foot.
Speaker 0: Well, I did one spill an entire jar of Somewhat weak hydrochloric acid all over my pants.
Speaker 1: Did it burn?
Speaker 0: Not really because it was the shower.
Speaker 0: No, I just took my pants off with your legs wet.
Speaker 0: There were a little wet.
Speaker 0: then I wiped them off with paper towels and then the professor while the teacher said rim.
Speaker 0: Where are your pants?
Speaker 1: What did you do the rest of the day?
Speaker 1: didn't have another pant at work.
Speaker 0: actually I did.
Speaker 1: you had another pant.
Speaker 0: I was in marching band.
Speaker 0: I had like a whole locker full of clothes you put on marching band pants?
Speaker 0: No, I had like a pair of jeans in my band locker.
Speaker 1: I see you walk down to the band room with no pants on Me.
Speaker 0: being in boxers was not an uncommon occurrence in high school in the hallway at high school.
Speaker 1: I Mean in the house, I understand in the high school in the hallway The.
Speaker 0: I feel like this is turning into an anecdote for a different show perhaps But I don't know.
Speaker 0: chemistry had some of my fondest memories in high school Even though I never actually took a chemistry class.
Speaker 1: really you never took a chemistry class not in high school.
Speaker 0: Well, I actually I took chemistry at the local community college and I skipped it in high school so I could take physics instead.
Speaker 1: Well, I took chemistry in high school.
Speaker 1: It's a goddess.
Speaker 1: chemistry in high school Teacher was a funny guy.
Speaker 1: There's quite a you know, he's a. he was a very.
Speaker 1: he was one of the teachers that character.
Speaker 0: There's something about the high school chemistry teacher who is.
Speaker 0: you can tell.
Speaker 0: they can tell which kids are smart enough to be given dangerous Stuff to play with.
Speaker 0: they can always tell.
Speaker 0: I mean, I remember when one day I'm not gonna use any names a certain chemistry teacher was like, all right you kids in the AP physics class I found this and I think you'll enjoy it.
Speaker 0: and he handed us a box and in the box was a cube of wax and Inside of the wax was lithium.
Speaker 0: Oh We had some fun with that.
Speaker 1: No, but that man the high school chemistry teacher.
Speaker 1: I remember him now, man he had this toupee and he made everyone call him godfather and He he would always give you the lab right and then he would teach you the chemistry afterwards.
Speaker 1: So it's like you do this lab and he would have all these questions like, you know do this math You know how much was there and this?
Speaker 1: and it's like you didn't know how to do that.
Speaker 1: You didn't know and taught it to you wasn't any book Right?
Speaker 1: and then after he did the lab and he graded it then he would teach you what you needed to know for the lab.
Speaker 1: That was the thing.
Speaker 0: That's probably a good way to go about it Because if you if you know what's supposed to happen lab.
Speaker 1: He was also famous for yelling at the class like yeah But like you'd be like an angry tirade kind of yell and everyone be quiet and like oh shit He didn't throw the erasers did he?
Speaker 0: that's more of the physics teacher.
Speaker 1: No, he didn't throw anything.
Speaker 1: He would just yell and get all pissed off like a you know, whatever?
Speaker 1: Yeah No, but actually all the awesome, you know in high school there was good chemistry going on, you know Some you know bunsen burners and whatnot.
Speaker 1: But it was in summer camp actually that the most awesome chemistry happened because I went to a science nerdy summer camp.
Speaker 0: Well, isn't?
Speaker 0: it isn't summer camp pretty much the.
Speaker 0: I've got some sodium and there's a lake.
Speaker 1: that's pretty much what it was.
Speaker 1: I remember three things specifically what that we did.
Speaker 1: one of them.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I can't remember the science I just remember what we did.
Speaker 1: No, I remember four things, right?
Speaker 1: So you're the fourth awesome chemistry things at summer camp, right?
Speaker 1: Awesome thing.
Speaker 1: Number one.
Speaker 1: They mix some chemicals together.
Speaker 1: I have no clue what they were nowadays, but it's like it started off as like a small pile of powder Right and they would pour something on to it or add something else to it I forget.
Speaker 1: and then it was sort of like sputter like a volcano and I think it changed like yellow to green.
Speaker 1: I think was the colors I don't remember but changed color and it would erupt and erupt and erupt and erupt.
Speaker 1: and it would just be like this pile of Powder would grow and grow and grow and grow.
Speaker 1: and it started off like this little tiny pile you know and it grew to like be like really tall compared to what it started out as and I have no idea what the hell it was.
Speaker 1: but it's really really impressive.
Speaker 1: and You know if you put that like in a jar or something you could probably freak someone out big time.
Speaker 1: as you know It looks like a little powder in a jar.
Speaker 1: It's something the jar is full of shit.
Speaker 1: We threw sodium in a lake good times.
Speaker 1: We had like this big jar full of oil in the middle of the jar.
Speaker 1: Oil was like a block of sodium and they would take it out and they would slice You know chunks off of it and toss it in the lake and go boom.
Speaker 1: And we joked.
Speaker 1: we thought we would put it in someone's toilet, you know in the upper deck.
Speaker 0: No one ever did though It was a rumor going around.
Speaker 1: I Thought about it and I looked in the upper deck of the cabin toilet.
Speaker 0: was it already upper deck?
Speaker 1: It was solid black in there.
Speaker 0: So I was like Dan's worse than the free like it's upper decked by course of nature as opposed to by mischievous child.
Speaker 1: so I looked and I was like, huh?
Speaker 1: Wow, we really did put sodium in the toilet and the toilet exploded.
Speaker 1: and Basically the top of the toilet is completely black.
Speaker 1: That would be something mighty fee.
Speaker 0: I would be so fierce So fierce, um, well, I remember the the most trouble I ever got into was it because you know I never took chemistry in in high school or middle school because I took it all the local community college.
Speaker 0: but I did a lot of chemistry in the course of science Olympiad and most of it was Barely supervised.
Speaker 0: but I remember specifically we had to make this like Rube Goldberg machine for science Olympiad and all the use the chemical Energy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we had like you got points for converted like going from one kind of energy to another kind.
Speaker 0: So we wanted to have a thing where we had a clear liquid and a laser going through it and then the liquid becomes Opaque due to a chemical reaction as opposed to a physical reaction, you know blocking the laser.
Speaker 0: and then something happens and we came up with all these ideas that we're all technically physical reactions like Dilute something in the water and then the turbidity increases and then the laser doesn't get through and you just get food coloring or some shit.
Speaker 0: But that's a physical reaction.
Speaker 0: That's not a chemical reaction We could use.
Speaker 1: you could use an acid and then you could use like phenolphthalein solutions.
Speaker 0: now We see we were debating and we tried all these things.
Speaker 0: They were either too dangerous They didn't work or they weren't good enough or they like iodine.
Speaker 0: But that wouldn't be a physical reaction.
Speaker 1: start with star.
Speaker 1: you put some starch in the water and you drop some iodine in there.
Speaker 0: But it it because the water part is not intrinsic to it.
Speaker 0: No, but the starch part is yeah, but then they would probably argue and other people tried similar things They would argue at the event that the turbidity or the opaqueness was caused primarily by the physical reaction as opposed to by Specifically a chemical reaction.
Speaker 1: if you didn't put the starch in there though wouldn't it turned as nearly as dark?
Speaker 0: Yes, but if you put the iodine in it might have turned dark enough.
Speaker 0: Anyway, they were real sticklers.
Speaker 0: So We're working on this and debating and then finally I'm just like poking through and I find the 11th grade chemistry textbook lay in there and on the cover Two clear liquids are being poured into each other and they're turning bright opaque yellow.
Speaker 1: He sure was just a Photoshop.
Speaker 0: So we go to the physics professor.
Speaker 0: We were like, what is this reaction?
Speaker 0: He's like fuck if I know.
Speaker 0: so he goes over to the chemistry people and they're debating and they're looking at it and they eventually Called the publisher and they found out what it was.
Speaker 1: and they're very dangerous chemicals.
Speaker 0: I forget exactly what it was, but it was some sort of mercury compound and some sort of Very dangerous chemical and some sort of lead chloride thing makes sense.
Speaker 0: So we there and we're like, can we do this?
Speaker 0: and they're like, well, it's not for really a school event It's kind of out of school.
Speaker 0: So go nuts there.
Speaker 0: Here's the key to the chemistry lab.
Speaker 0: Stay away from the lithium.
Speaker 0: So we put it together and work perfectly Perfectly until we blew it out because we were stupid and we got disqualified for creating a dangerous situation, but that's another.
Speaker 1: that's great.
Speaker 0: That's another story.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah.
Speaker 1: Um, oh actually I remember even more For that summer camp.
Speaker 1: They had some urate.
Speaker 1: It wasn't uranium.
Speaker 1: It was uranium something or other Just uranium.
Speaker 0: it was all the things you can find uranium in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they had.
Speaker 1: it was you know, it was like, you know, uranium something I'd or something eight, you know one of those.
Speaker 1: it was uranium mix with something.
Speaker 1: and They would like, you know, isn't a little lead box or whatever in a jar in a lead box?
Speaker 1: But they would open it up and take the Geiger counter and be like look tick tick tick tick tick.
Speaker 0: We did that actually my mom used to collect and I believe still collects fiesta wear.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, that's pretty good That's not as radioactive as this uranium was.
Speaker 0: Well, my mom actually she used to be really into mineral science.
Speaker 0: So she actually has this gigantic gigantic collection of samples of almost every mineral.
Speaker 0: That is acquireable Little sample.
Speaker 0: some of them are dangerous.
Speaker 0: Some of them are radioactive Obviously nothing like plutonium, but she has a fairly pure piece of uranium And a Geiger counter and all this cool stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah Oh So they had you know, we threw cesium in the lake right?
Speaker 1: But what they have is you know, that's the sodium.
Speaker 0: I was gonna say that's that's quite some fun with the cesium.
Speaker 1: No, they talked about cesium.
Speaker 0: You know you look at the periodic table and you're like sodium.
Speaker 0: What's under sodium?
Speaker 0: and you're going down the line and the further down you go the bigger the explosion is.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: Now they had.
Speaker 1: what they had is they had like all these.
Speaker 1: they ordered a jar full of sticks of phosphorus, right?
Speaker 1: And for the bonfire, they would put a stick of phosphorus like down low where no one could see and then they would like.
Speaker 1: You know, most of the kids didn't take the chemistry, you know, most, you know, very few people did so.
Speaker 1: Only the kids took the chemistry knew what the score was.
Speaker 1: they would tell like some Indian legend and they would throw a glass of water on the pile of wood and it would start on Fire and like half the kids would be like, oh shit Brilliant!
Speaker 0: It was pretty brilliant The only course with phosphorus.
Speaker 0: Did you ever get to do the thermite reaction in school or the summer camp?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Yeah, we made like, you know contact explosive, but it's very weak.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like you squeeze it and go.
Speaker 0: We're.
Speaker 0: sadly we never did anything cool with thermite.
Speaker 0: Everyone always talked about what if we took thermite and melted a hole through all the bleachers.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, not again the middle of the football field.
Speaker 1: Way to get expelled.
Speaker 0: But now the most we did was put it in a flower pot and melt through like a sheet of metal, yep, that's about it.
Speaker 1: The other thing we did is we would like turn on Bunsen burners and then we just throw like different metals into the fire and watch The color change.
Speaker 0: but I did that in the course of Science Olympiad.
Speaker 0: Just one of the events was they give you all these like samples of different chemicals and different metals and the event was here is A metal.
Speaker 0: there are 20 things with 20 different metals.
Speaker 0: identify them all.
Speaker 0: you've got five minutes.
Speaker 0: Here's a jar of acid.
Speaker 0: Here's a Bunsen burner.
Speaker 0: Here's like a bunch of pieces from the Mohs scale go nuts.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm You just got to figure it out.
Speaker 0: So, you know put some acid in set it on fire.
Speaker 0: I was terrible at that event because I couldn't memorize any of that.
Speaker 1: Yeah memorizing was the hard part but it's like you would throw it in into the into the fire and the fire would turn green.
Speaker 1: She like aha.
Speaker 1: That's the green one, you know, you throw the iron Filings in and it was as far as I would get.
Speaker 0: is that's the green one green one that melts in this acid, right?
Speaker 1: That's the problem.
Speaker 1: We had labels on so we knew it was basically a reverse.
Speaker 1: It was like this is iron.
Speaker 1: What does iron do?
Speaker 1: its sparks?
Speaker 1: and it was sort of, you know learning about fireworks.
Speaker 1: You know cuz that's how fireworks do is you?
Speaker 1: they start a fire and then they have.
Speaker 1: you know They want to make like the white sparkly bits.
Speaker 1: They put iron in there if they want to make the green sparkly bits.
Speaker 1: They put that other one in there.
Speaker 0: I was curious if you were gonna say which one.
Speaker 0: I forget.
Speaker 1: I only remember iron.
Speaker 0: The other ones actually some of my favorite parts were making the lab works.
Speaker 0: We always got to make our own lab where especially in the local community.
Speaker 1: I never made lab where it was always.
Speaker 1: just get it from the shack cuz.
Speaker 0: you know in 10th grade instead of taking the lame Oh science in school.
Speaker 0: I went and took stoichiometry and then I was done with that and I went back to the school and they were like That didn't cover everything.
Speaker 0: So I'm like damn it.
Speaker 0: So I went back and took Argo and that was when I realized that I hate chemistry and everything about it.
Speaker 0: Organic chemistry was the most horrifying experience I've ever had.
Speaker 0: it was nothing but doing lab experiments that don't work and smell bad.
Speaker 1: Really I did, you know organic chemistry.
Speaker 1: I'd only took one class of it at RIT.
Speaker 0: It was sort of like, you know 101 time every lab was take naphthalene and do something stupid with it.
Speaker 1: I actually had you know some pretty fun labs.
Speaker 1: We only had to do the fume hood.
Speaker 1: I'm like the lab.
Speaker 1: we actually made plastic.
Speaker 1: It was actually kind of shitty plastic.
Speaker 1: It was more like rubber cement.
Speaker 0: Oh, we didn't do stuff like that.
Speaker 0: We got right past.
Speaker 1: actually, you know, the stuff we learned was not so exciting.
Speaker 1: I wasn't super interested in it.
Speaker 1: It wasn't that difficult probably because it was just a 101 introductory type class.
Speaker 1: but the labs were actually kind of fun because a my lab partner was sort of competent and B all the labs involved like that sort of.
Speaker 1: they looked like mad Scientist shit where we'd have like a beaker on one end and then like all these pipes You know held up on you know with like the you know, the big sticks of the metal holders You know and all sorts like, you know The the glass tube that gets bigger and smaller again and you would watch the chemical go like up Swirl around and go down the other side, you know, we did all that sort of shit.
Speaker 1: See I remember it was cool to feel like a mad scientist with the chemists.
Speaker 0: It was fun when I'd go and check in to like do a lab because I'd skip the lab classes on the weekend.
Speaker 0: I have to like go over there and do my science stuff to not fail this class That the high school was paying for me to take.
Speaker 0: so I'd be hanging out over there, you know Like working on my lab.
Speaker 0: and I remember one day There were these two kids who just obviously went to the community college as their college as opposed to just you know Taking classes there.
Speaker 1: There's nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 1: No, but they just made a still.
Speaker 1: Oh On purpose.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then they just left with it.
Speaker 1: Oh They just took the school's equipment and left.
Speaker 0: yeah nice Well, cuz you had this breakage card.
Speaker 0: You had to buy it for like 50 bucks and then at the end of the year You would you would take it over like you get signed out of your cabinet and then every time you broke something They put like marks on it and you get whatever money back from stuff.
Speaker 0: You didn't break at the end.
Speaker 1: See a lot of the labs that we did.
Speaker 1: I remember at the RIT organic chemistry We didn't make a still as in to make beer and ferment.
Speaker 0: you don't make beer in a still.
Speaker 1: But we did to make liquor in a still but we did distill things, you know It's not not alcohol usually something else, you know We would yeah and if you would have to like measure the molar before and after and stuff and that kind of shit.
Speaker 0: You know, of course, I remember I got in trouble.
Speaker 0: I got bored one day.
Speaker 1: So while the lecture was going on I silvered every piece of glassware in my cabinet, you know Occasionally I had I would get silvered piece or is partially silvered pieces of glassware, but I never silvered anything.
Speaker 0: Well, I silvered it all.
Speaker 0: and then you know a couple days later I'm doing my lab and the guys like what happened to your lab equipment and I'm like,
Speaker 1: oh, yeah I remember like we we one of the things that we threw into the Bunsen burners just change the color of the fire with silver Nitrate and then our hands were like mark.
Speaker 1: we got until we like the end of the summer By hand and silver nitrate on it, but I remember the lab instructors like you didn't do that to all your lab equipment.
Speaker 0: Did you?
Speaker 0: and I was like, well, what if I did?
Speaker 0: he's like it's pretty much irreversible.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh That's good to know.
Speaker 0: Like you sure you didn't do it all your lab equipment.
Speaker 0: I'm like, I got a breakage card Definitely day.
Speaker 0: I didn't get any money back for my stupid breakage card.
Speaker 0: That's all right, ah Actually a lot of sadly all my really cool memories are from physics.
Speaker 0: we tried to make a betatron and it didn't work.
Speaker 1: And physics, you know all my the physics labs I've ever done.
Speaker 1: We're always the sort of you know Drop a thing off the side of the table with a string attached to it in a pulley and a little calculator Measuring device.
Speaker 1: or you know Make a little circuit and use a you know Multimeter and measure it, you know, and you know, that's sort of she.
Speaker 1: we never really did anything.
Speaker 0: We had a fun.
Speaker 1: We actually did the lab where all the cool stuff like the teacher would already already have a Tesla coil.
Speaker 1: You wouldn't make one or you you know, you would just turn it on and be like look this is Tesla coil.
Speaker 1: That uh, that was you know, you'd be like.
Speaker 1: you already have a Van de Graaff generator.
Speaker 1: You never made one.
Speaker 1: He's just like look I have one.
Speaker 0: I turn it on for one to tell it.
Speaker 0: I think I've told it many times but Donnie don't and his interaction with the Van de Graaff.
Speaker 1: He'd be like look This is my bell jar capacitor that is made with a two gallon jar.
Speaker 1: We are not going to fill this up.
Speaker 1: He's like once the teacher in the room next door was play.
Speaker 1: You know, the the like one pint bell jar capacitor was sitting on a table and the teacher next door picked it up.
Speaker 1: He's lucky to be alive.
Speaker 1: He said it felt like a sledgehammer to the chest.
Speaker 1: You know stuff like that, but we never made one or charged one up or anything like that.
Speaker 1: You know just here we have one.
Speaker 1: See it learn it
Speaker 0: like the one I remember most because we actually calculate like, you know What we'd always do is we do experiments that were done famously back in the day to try to calculate gravity or try to calculate how far away the Sun was and We try to do it experimentally and then did.
Speaker 0: the quest was, you know See who can get the answer?
Speaker 0: like we'd always have the award for who got the most accurate answer and who got the most precise answer And very rarely did the same person get both.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, definitely.
Speaker 0: But the most fun we actually did the Cavendish experiment, you know There's the lowercase G gravity constant and the uppercase G the like gravity constant.
Speaker 0: Yep, we did the Cavendish experiment to try to calculate the uppercase G Mm-hmm, and we got it to almost a decimal point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was so proud of that.
Speaker 1: Yeah And we didn't do anything quite like that.
Speaker 1: I think once we did the take extension cords and whip them around like jump ropes to make electricity.
Speaker 0: No, we did that too.
Speaker 0: Well, I remember we did it and they were like staying north to south and whip it around.
Speaker 0: Now stand east to us.
Speaker 1: We actually jump roped while they were connected.
Speaker 0: Yep We may we made fun stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wish oh, I had some free time.
Speaker 1: I could do science to go away.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah guys from free time.
Speaker 1: No, no one will pay me not gonna work out I can.
Speaker 1: only I can only do things that make money.
Speaker 0: Scott I'll give you five bucks if you can recreate the Cavendish experiment not enough.
Speaker 0: It's not that hard It's gonna take.
Speaker 1: you got a guy need more.
Speaker 1: You need to give me all the resources and I need at least a minimum wage for the time I'm spending.
Speaker 1: yeah, at least if not more my times worth a lot more than that.
Speaker 0: I Don't know.
Speaker 0: This is kind of a cop-out episode as we found some excuse for science.
Speaker 1: We didn't have any tech.
Speaker 1: You actually we had an idea that bombed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we were like, hey, why don't we look for funny job listings on Craigslist?
Speaker 0: And just kind of go through them live and talk about like what they say what they mean.
Speaker 0: There was nothing that that well was empty.
Speaker 1: that well was very much.
Speaker 0: I got to the bottom and there wasn't even like a scary ghost down there.
Speaker 1: Nope, so Send us some Mondays and show ideas other than the ones you've already sent us.
Speaker 1: those require effort and we're holding off Something that we don't need to research or put a course effort into.
Speaker 0: of course if twit keeps talking about tweeting Then we'll just have to switch to the fit format and that'll be into that.
Speaker 1: Let's not even even if it becomes a possibility.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should do it.
Speaker 1: We've never really done like a Twitter show have we?
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should do one just to be like.
Speaker 1: this is the one and we'll never do it again Because then we can you know, we can spend half it.
Speaker 1: bitching about it amazes me.
Speaker 0: I don't post on Twitter like that often but every now and then I'll post like one thing and then I see like 20 people Reply to me and it's like ah, you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: I did it.
Speaker 1: You know, I tested it.
Speaker 1: We'll save it.
Speaker 0: We'll do a Twitter show And then I'll talk about spin right and then I'll talk about my book.
Speaker 0: I'll talk about my blog, you know rim org Slash blog.
Speaker 0: Yep This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio.
Speaker 1: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.