Speaker 1: It's Thursday, May 14th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, the book club of the amazing adventures of Cavalier and Clay.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: I was hankering for a big lunch today.
Speaker 0: I was feeling it.
Speaker 0: So I went out and I went over to Chipotle.
Speaker 1: Chipotle?
Speaker 1: That's a good shirt.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: Right next to my work, there is a big ass Chipotle.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: It is the biggest Chipotle I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: I normally, I would go to eat at the Chipotle on 42nd Street.
Speaker 0: In that Chipotle, there's a long line.
Speaker 0: If you get there after 1130 and before like 2, you have to wait for like a half hour to get to Chipotle.
Speaker 1: That's Chipotle typical.
Speaker 0: So they have a sign up now saying, "You know, we built another Chipotle that's bigger right around the corner and there's maps and
Speaker 0: everything.".
Speaker 1: How around the corner is it?
Speaker 0: It's like right there.
Speaker 0: It's like a block and a half away.
Speaker 1: Oh wow.
Speaker 1: That's pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I walked over there just as crowded.
Speaker 0: God damn it.
Speaker 1: The one near me is really big and it's only super crowded during a certain, you know, similar time interval.
Speaker 1: But you know what?
Speaker 1: You want to know the Chipotle secret?
Speaker 0: That's the secret.
Speaker 1: You can just fax slash digitally send in your orders and then go get them.
Speaker 0: All the ones I've been to, if you walk in and you're going to pay with credit, because apparently no one pays with credit but me.
Speaker 0: They have a guy with like a thing around his neck that can take credit card orders.
Speaker 1: They do that at the Apple store when it's crowded also.
Speaker 1: They'll have, they'll just get the people who usually walk around and say, "How may I help
Speaker 1: you?".
Speaker 1: And they give them handheld credit card thingies and they'll be like, "Paying with credit?
Speaker 1: Just come over to
Speaker 1: me.".
Speaker 1: And they scan and then slide your card and they type in the numbers and that's it.
Speaker 0: I remember I was standing at this Chipotle and there were like 100, not really 100, there were like 30 people in line.
Speaker 1: That's a pretty big, I usually have seen like 20.
Speaker 1: I've never seen like 30.
Speaker 0: And the guy comes out and he's like, "Who's paying with credit?
Speaker 0: I'll take your order right now.
Speaker 0: You'll be
Speaker 0: done.".
Speaker 0: No one stepped up.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: So I was at the end of the line, so I was like, "All right, here's the credit card for my $8
Speaker 0: burrito.".
Speaker 1: Did they, if you're at the end of the line though, how did you get your order up there?
Speaker 1: Because you got to go through the little line to talk to the people and say, "I want a fajita burrito with...".
Speaker 0: Because no one else did it.
Speaker 0: The guy swiped me and he stood there for a minute.
Speaker 0: He was like, "All
Speaker 0: right.".
Speaker 0: And then he put the thing down, went back, made my burrito and handed it to me.
Speaker 0: Ah.
Speaker 0: It was, it was badass.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking about, I was actually thinking I would go there tomorrow.
Speaker 1: I think I'm going to digitally send in my order.
Speaker 1: I'm going to attempt that method.
Speaker 0: See, normally I avoid the Chipotle during, because you know, eating a thousand calories for lunch on like a Tuesday is not good for rim.
Speaker 0: Because rim's asleep by 3.30.
Speaker 1: The thing is I'm not eating any breakfast tomorrow, so it's going to be pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: I was just hungry all day.
Speaker 0: Like I had a decent dinner and then in the morning I got like one of those hot and crusty bagels.
Speaker 1: What I ate today was so strange, right?
Speaker 1: So I get to work and we're going to BK to talk to some people over there, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know, we get on the subway, F train, we get off, right?
Speaker 1: And I'm like, "Man, I fucking got to eat
Speaker 1: something.".
Speaker 1: So I just buy a glazed donut from a cart, right?
Speaker 0: Ah, the cart glazed donut.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure...
Speaker 1: It was a pretty good cart glazed donut.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure the cart glazed donuts are identical to pretty almost every donut in the city, except for Dunkin' Donuts.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: So anyway, it was alright.
Speaker 1: I ate it.
Speaker 1: The lady in front of me was really bitching that the orange juice was like $2.
Speaker 1: She was like, "Oh, God damn.
Speaker 1: You lucky I'm
Speaker 1: thirsty.".
Speaker 0: You know what, lady?
Speaker 0: Don't go near Grand Central.
Speaker 1: I know, right?
Speaker 1: So it was actually a tiny shitty orange juice.
Speaker 1: Grand Central, you get the nice carton one that's actually better.
Speaker 0: No, forget that.
Speaker 0: You want the good orange juice.
Speaker 0: You want to know the secret in Grand Central.
Speaker 1: Go to the grocery store and buy a half gallon?
Speaker 0: No, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: If you want a good orange juice for the train, go to like that Zaro's.
Speaker 0: Don't get any food.
Speaker 0: They have like the worst food in the world, but they have that unpaturized, like super awesome fresh orange juice.
Speaker 0: It's like four bucks, but it's awesome.
Speaker 1: Oh, screw that.
Speaker 1: I want to get more orange juice in my money.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you know, so then we go and we walk in and there's a plate of croissants in the conference room.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, "Ah,
Speaker 1: shit.".
Speaker 1: And he's like, "How you bought that
Speaker 1: donut?".
Speaker 1: And then, right?
Speaker 1: Then they bring in a bowl of grapes.
Speaker 1: Both kinds.
Speaker 1: And then, right?
Speaker 1: They bring it later, right?
Speaker 1: After we've been there a while, they bring us like these turkey slash ham sandwiches.
Speaker 1: You know, you could pick either or.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, "Oh, got
Speaker 1: him.".
Speaker 1: They were really trying to butter us up over there for reasons that I will not get into.
Speaker 0: You know, the cool thing is, though, go to some corporate training sometime, like those week long fly somewhere on a business trip things.
Speaker 0: They will give you breakfast and lunch like that every day.
Speaker 1: Then they tried to offer us a car ride back and we're like, "No, we'll take the subway.
Speaker 1: Thanks.".
Speaker 0: Well, speaking of the car ride, what I was going with this is they did one of those like emergency response drills on 42nd Street near the Chipotle while I was trying to go there.
Speaker 1: Were all the cops eating at the Chipotle?
Speaker 0: No, they were all standing around going,
Speaker 0: "Ah.".
Speaker 0: The reason they were going, "Ah," is it looks like they were all- They were all at the Dunkin' Donuts slash KFC.
Speaker 0: That's like the worst Dunkin' Donuts in the world.
Speaker 0: Not that Dunkin' Donuts is good anyway.
Speaker 0: I've decided I'm done with Dunkin' Donuts.
Speaker 0: I'm done with shitty donuts and shitty bagels.
Speaker 0: I can't do it anymore.
Speaker 1: I think it's now- Dunkin' Donuts bagel is the worst bagel.
Speaker 0: It's not the worst bagel.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's the worst bagel you can, you know.
Speaker 1: I mean, obviously someone could technically make a poop bagel with poop in it, but- I'll say this, Panera doesn't really have much better bagels.
Speaker 1: No, they're very kind of meh.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know what was with that thread in the forum where people were like, "Man, Panera's
Speaker 0: awesome.".
Speaker 1: That's because they don't know what's good.
Speaker 1: Remember, right?
Speaker 1: We think Panera's poop, right?
Speaker 1: But remember like, I don't know, when we were at Citicon, right?
Speaker 1: Panera's a million times better than anything within like a 20-mile radius, right?
Speaker 1: And so most people live in these, you know, places that don't have good food is an incredible luxury.
Speaker 0: I mean- Well, Scott, way to put down everyone in the world except New York City and I guess Seattle.
Speaker 1: No, there's plenty of places.
Speaker 1: Paris.
Speaker 0: Maybe Chicago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not London.
Speaker 1: Berlin has good food.
Speaker 0: We got this fancy international clock because our company's going live overseas now.
Speaker 0: So we got one of those giant like red clocks that has all the different time zones on it.
Speaker 1: Oh, you didn't get a bunch of separate clocks?
Speaker 0: You realize we bought this thing.
Speaker 0: We got it.
Speaker 0: It arrived yesterday.
Speaker 0: Every 20 minutes, someone comes in and they're like, "Oh, hey, what time is it in Helsinki?
Speaker 0: Hey, how much did this thing cost?
Speaker 0: Couldn't you have just bought five regular
Speaker 0: clocks?".
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: All you need is like, you get a US, you get a GMT, you get a Cali- No, no, no, Scott.
Speaker 0: Here's the reason.
Speaker 0: Here's why we got this thing.
Speaker 0: One, it looks really snazzy in the new NOC.
Speaker 0: It looks professional.
Speaker 0: Two, it automatically, with a network cable, synchronizes to NTP.
Speaker 1: You could get the ones that do it by radio.
Speaker 0: Well, it also has Wi-Fi, but- Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but even those radio ones usually are kind of shitty.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they don't give you that good a time.
Speaker 0: You're much better off just going over the internet to NIST with NTP.
Speaker 0: I'm the fucking NTP guy.
Speaker 1: I've noticed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, NTP is my thing.
Speaker 1: You should start an NTP consultancy.
Speaker 0: I should just take over for the guy who wrote it when he dies.
Speaker 1: He's a crazy Unix scientist.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what I would do?
Speaker 0: Never change it, because I don't think it's been changed in my lifetime.
Speaker 1: What are you going to do when we get 128-bit computers?
Speaker 1: You're going to have to do something.
Speaker 0: No, I won't.
Speaker 0: Won't do anything.
Speaker 0: I'll just say, "Well, this is it.
Speaker 0: This is what you
Speaker 0: get.".
Speaker 0: That's what he's been doing.
Speaker 1: No, it's the stuff that's happening, but it's all the sort of stuff you don't notice.
Speaker 0: No, not much is happening.
Speaker 1: Okay, anyway.
Speaker 1: His documentation- Let's get on with this episode before we drag on this crap too much longer.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Suffice it to say, I was trying to walk to Chipotle.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're still doing okay.
Speaker 0: There was an ambulance also trying to get to Chipotle, which is where this thing was going.
Speaker 0: To get someone out who died in line waiting for- I think it was just part of the exercise.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: So it has its siren going, and the guy is sitting there like, "Ugh," and traffic's just not moving.
Speaker 0: Traffic was so not moving that I went to Chipotle, got my burrito, ate my burrito, left the Chipotle, walked back.
Speaker 0: It hadn't even gotten to Fifth Avenue yet.
Speaker 1: From Madison?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like 1,000 feet?
Speaker 0: I hope no one was dying in there.
Speaker 1: Was he going, "Wee,
Speaker 1: wee?"?
Speaker 0: Yes, the whole time.
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 0: And there was this car in front of it.
Speaker 0: The guy in the car was this kind of fat guy, kind of balding, and he was sitting there just with his lips out.
Speaker 0: He looked the most exasperated I've ever seen a person look.
Speaker 1: He couldn't go.
Speaker 1: There was someone in front of him.
Speaker 0: But the ambulance was behind him honking the horn, "Wee,
Speaker 0: wee.".
Speaker 0: He's just like,
Speaker 0: "Ugh.".
Speaker 1: Get some earplugs, man.
Speaker 1: This is nothing you could do.
Speaker 0: So anyway.
Speaker 1: All right, so news-ish.
Speaker 1: I got a tiny news.
Speaker 1: I don't want to talk about it too much.
Speaker 0: Tiny news.
Speaker 1: There was some Google outage today.
Speaker 1: There was some Google outage a few times before, but this one was sort of big.
Speaker 0: I didn't know about this one until I saw it on the news later.
Speaker 1: It was network-related?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't have any problems with Google at all.
Speaker 0: As far as I can tell, it was one of those big peering things where, to put this into layman's terms, because this isn't a Monday night show, imagine if you're a Greek peasant, right?
Speaker 0: And Zeus and Thor are having a pissing contest, and they knock over some villages in the process.
Speaker 0: That is what happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No, so I just thought, you know, it was sort of funny because I was at this other people's office, and I tried to go to Google.com.
Speaker 1: I was on their Wi-Fi, and it didn't really go, right?
Speaker 1: So I'm like, huh?
Speaker 1: And then I go, and I'm just reading Google news, which worked, right?
Speaker 1: And on Google news, there was a story about Google having an outage, right?
Speaker 1: I thought that was funny.
Speaker 1: And then, so I tried to do another Google search, and it worked.
Speaker 1: But the reason it was slow is because they were using stupid fucking open DNS and open DNS.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: No!
Speaker 1: Open DNS freaking, like, runs Google, like, through itself.
Speaker 1: It does this weird fucking thing, like, in the top left corner, it'll say open DNS instead of saying Google.
Speaker 1: And it's like it redirects you from open DNS to Google.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the fuck it's doing, but it pissed me off.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I just got to say that's...
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: It amazes me how many otherwise smart people will use open DNS.
Speaker 1: They're just fucking...
Speaker 0: Don't use it.
Speaker 0: If you don't know what it is, don't use it.
Speaker 0: If you know what it is, you already know not to use it.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: I think the thing is people know enough to be dangerous.
Speaker 1: They don't really know.
Speaker 0: Well, they hear, "Yeah, it's the open
Speaker 0: source.".
Speaker 0: Because, I don't know, it's just...
Speaker 1: You can, a DNS server, it's bind, it's free.
Speaker 1: You just turn it on, and that's it.
Speaker 1: You're good.
Speaker 1: And your ISP gives you a DNS server, you can use that.
Speaker 0: But yeah, luckily, that's one thing I really miss about RIT is that basically when the gobs...
Speaker 1: We had a hundred open DNS servers.
Speaker 1: I mean, no, not open DNS, regular old DNS servers.
Speaker 0: Well, we had the... Oh, 129.2121.1 is gone.
Speaker 0: It stopped responding.
Speaker 1: You thought it was going to stay there forever?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that thing, I've used that forever, and the fact that it's gone is a sad day for me.
Speaker 0: That was like my backup...
Speaker 1: Just go find, ask some RIT student what their DNS server is.
Speaker 1: But we were also...
Speaker 0: No, that wasn't RIT's DNS server, that was IT's DNS server.
Speaker 1: I'm done saying, go ask an RIT student what their DNS server is and you can use it.
Speaker 1: Eh.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's all you got?
Speaker 0: Yeah, Google.
Speaker 0: That happens.
Speaker 0: So Cheerios, I assume everyone... We're not breaking news here on Geek Nights here, but I happen to find... There's a weird side story where I saw this article this morning at like 4.45 on Fark.
Speaker 1: I didn't know Cheerios are yummy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they are.
Speaker 1: A honey of an oat.
Speaker 0: But at 4.45
Speaker 0: a.m.,
Speaker 0: I see on Fark this Cheerios thing, and I'm like, "Was it?
Speaker 1: Huh?".
Speaker 0: And I read it, and I'm like, "What?
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, I got to talk about this
Speaker 0: later.".
Speaker 0: And then throughout the day, like I saw more and more news picking up on it, I got home and I went into My Delicious and I went to this Fark story to bring it up to be my news, and it was no longer on Fark.
Speaker 0: They moved it to Total Fark, which I don't pay for because I'm not crazy.
Speaker 1: Why would they move it from regular Fark to Total Fark?
Speaker 1: Isn't it supposed to be the opposite direction, like Total Fark is everything and then only good stuff goes to regular Fark?
Speaker 0: It happens every now and then, but I have no idea why.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's because it's a hot story and they want, it's like, "Yeah, this story's so hot.
Speaker 1: We only want people to talk about it if they're awesome and pay for Total
Speaker 1: Fark.".
Speaker 1: It's like only the awesome people can get in on this one.
Speaker 0: Thing is, I'd probably, if I were at RIT now- Thing is, how would you find it on Total Fark?
Speaker 0: You pretty much go by what people are commenting on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know, right?
Speaker 0: But Cheerios either going to have to be regulated as a drug or have to stop lying about the health benefits or prove that they're not lying about the health benefits.
Speaker 0: I really don't know what to think about this because it came out of nowhere.
Speaker 0: This just was like a bolt out of the blue.
Speaker 1: Well, it came out of nowhere as far as we're concerned, but maybe the people who deal with this sort of thing, maybe they saw it coming.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if anyone has any insight, we'd really like to hear from you.
Speaker 0: We'll get you on the show because I see a very small number of possibilities.
Speaker 0: One, it just randomly, it came out and that's just it.
Speaker 0: This just happened.
Speaker 0: Maybe it was in the works for a while.
Speaker 0: Two, more likely, the FDA is like this might be the tip of the iceberg as I'm going after people pulling this bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm sort of torn on this because on the one hand, right, Cheerios does a lot of things sort of make foods, regular old foods, are making increasingly crazy claims on their foods, right?
Speaker 1: You go buy some grape juice and it has these American Heart Association seals on it and they don't say it outright, but they heavily imply that somehow if you drink grape juice, you're not going to have a heart attack and die, which is...
Speaker 0: What about grape drink?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like Cheerios really does the same sort of thing.
Speaker 1: They're like, "Oh man, cholesterol, heart, yeah,
Speaker 1: awesome.".
Speaker 0: Cheerios went a little bit further though.
Speaker 0: But here's the thing.
Speaker 1: But the point is, it's like, okay, I agree that the claims and the Cheerios are probably exaggerated if not false and that they should not be allowed to have the false advertising.
Speaker 1: That is very good, right?
Speaker 1: But there are much more egregious false advertisers out there that you should go after before you go after the Cheerios.
Speaker 0: Homeopathy, Airborne, that Orinna Chalcum stuff.
Speaker 1: That's like if you had like... That's like if you walk down the street, right, and there's a mass murderer.
Speaker 1: He's just like hosing everyone down with a flame thrower and he's blowing up buildings, right?
Speaker 0: I see you played Postal as well.
Speaker 1: And there's another guy who just stabbed, he's just the hobo and the hobo stabbed one dude.
Speaker 1: And you get all over that hobo.
Speaker 1: You're like, "Hobo, you're going to
Speaker 1: jail.".
Speaker 1: And meanwhile, the mass murderer is right there.
Speaker 1: You don't care about him.
Speaker 0: See, in this case, I picture the cop as he's hauling the hobo away, like topping his hat to the mass murderer, just like,
Speaker 0: "Hey.".
Speaker 1: See, that's the situation.
Speaker 1: So it's like, "Yes, you caught that stabbing hobo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he deserved to go to
Speaker 1: jail.".
Speaker 0: But they don't go after... "But there's a mass murderer.
Speaker 0: What the fuck is wrong with
Speaker 0: you?".
Speaker 0: So they're going after Cheerios, but not like Zykan.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right?
Speaker 1: Well, they did go after Air... They went after Airborne a little bit.
Speaker 0: But Airborne's still being sold with the same bullshit claim.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's another thing, right?
Speaker 1: I heard that they were threatening to, if the Cheerios didn't fix themselves, to stop Cheerios from going out.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: But they never threatened to remove Airborne from the market.
Speaker 1: They just threatened to fine them a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: So thus, what I'm curious is, what's the impetus for this?
Speaker 0: Because the ad campaign that they're complaining about has been going on for a year and a half.
Speaker 1: It took them so long.
Speaker 0: It was the claim that Cheerios can reduce cholesterol by 4% in six weeks.
Speaker 0: You know what I would do?
Speaker 0: And quote, "The FDA was responding to a complaint by the National Consumers
Speaker 0: League.".
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Huh, maybe we should just join the National Consumers League and just constantly... Maybe, you know what?
Speaker 0: Here's an idea.
Speaker 0: The same thing that the people who come... You know, those old people.
Speaker 0: The Parents Television Council.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The FCC, all the bullshit the FCC does is because all these cranky old people keep writing letters to the FCC telling them to get the swearing off television.
Speaker 1: Let's everyone write letters to the FDA and FTC just like the Parents Television Council does to complain about the fake medicines.
Speaker 1: Let's just keep doing it for every single fake medicine and every single false advertising on a food out there.
Speaker 1: Let's just keep doing it and we'll end up like the Parents Television Council.
Speaker 1: A very small portion of the population of the country having a very large amount of power.
Speaker 0: But what I'm really...
Speaker 1: I'm actually serious.
Speaker 1: I'm going to start doing it.
Speaker 1: We'll... Tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Well, we'll sort out the details, make a foreign post or something.
Speaker 1: Well, we have to start an NGO and we have to give it a name and we have to make a little website.
Speaker 0: Oh, you want to actually start an NGO?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: How hard could it be?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Let's... We could do that or we could just actually incorporate geek nights.
Speaker 1: Well, no.
Speaker 1: We could start a little NGO and all it will do is send letters to the FTC and FDA telling them about false advertising in food and medicine.
Speaker 0: But anyway, what I'm wondering is what was the real impetus for this?
Speaker 0: I mean, maybe it's the tip of the iceberg, go after like the highest profile thing, get a lot of public support and then just go after everything else after that because everything else is low-hanging.
Speaker 0: I mean, if you can get Cheerios for saying that it's good for your heart, you can get Zicam.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Which doesn't do anything except destroy your sense of smell.
Speaker 0: Give or take.
Speaker 1: And of course, you know, they have ones that are not nasal sprays, right?
Speaker 1: Those don't destroy your sense of smell.
Speaker 1: They're just useless sucking candies.
Speaker 0: What about head on?
Speaker 1: That's just... That's just a step of wax.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess head on is okay because if you put a wick in it, it's a nice candle.
Speaker 0: Well, head on was brilliant.
Speaker 0: They didn't make any claim other than apply directly to the forehead.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But there's an obvious implication of medicinal effect.
Speaker 1: And I think that we need some sort of, you know, laws that give the, you know, FDA, FTC and judges discretion to make these subjective judgment calls that are obvious.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: So I saw this video on YouTube from RIT.
Speaker 0: R-I-T.
Speaker 1: Apparently they have some sort of Imagine RIT thing.
Speaker 1: I guess it's similar to the Brick City.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the deal is.
Speaker 0: Imagine RIT was there when we were there, I think.
Speaker 1: Was it?
Speaker 1: I think it's more newer.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: Imagine RIT sounds really familiar.
Speaker 0: Maybe I just get...
Speaker 1: You get mail about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe.
Speaker 1: I think it's the Brick City Festival, Springfest type of... It's one of those shticks, right?
Speaker 0: Man, Springfest was only good the first year that we went to it.
Speaker 0: Then they ruined it.
Speaker 1: I know, right?
Speaker 0: Remember we had that all-night party?
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: Isn't that crazy?
Speaker 1: But yeah, basically for Imagine RIT, some RIT kids made some Domino thing.
Speaker 1: You know, cool Domino knock-you-downy thing.
Speaker 1: And there's a YouTube video of it.
Speaker 1: And there's actually a second YouTube video.
Speaker 1: It's sort of the making of the first YouTube video.
Speaker 1: And so they got Dominoes going around the RIT flag.
Speaker 1: And they got one part.
Speaker 1: It hits a button on a coffee machine.
Speaker 1: And out comes a printed paper with some RIT logo on it.
Speaker 1: And that knocks over some other Dominoes.
Speaker 1: It's good stuff.
Speaker 0: Too bad they didn't knock over the Sentinel at the end.
Speaker 0: The thing is, the Sentinel, for RIT people out there, I don't think they hate it anymore.
Speaker 0: I think only the people who were at RIT when they built it hated it.
Speaker 1: Because, you know, college kids hate anything.
Speaker 1: Anyone who came to RIT now, anyone who's still there, unless they're someone who's been there a long time, to them, the Sentinel has just always been there.
Speaker 1: It's as natural as the Tiger with the golden ball.
Speaker 0: I think it's just like the Eiffel Tower.
Speaker 0: People hate anything that's new.
Speaker 0: And then once those people are gone, no one else cares.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, how many times there was a big sign in a city.
Speaker 1: And everyone wanted to get rid of the sign.
Speaker 1: It was ugly.
Speaker 1: But then it stays there for so long.
Speaker 1: Now they want to get rid of the sign.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's old.
Speaker 1: It's a part of the city.
Speaker 1: Don't get rid of it.
Speaker 0: Oh, my goodness.
Speaker 0: Like that Citgo sign or Raleigh Woodland.
Speaker 1: All that sort of shit, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know, the Sentinel, it is ugly, there is no doubt.
Speaker 1: It is big and monstrous and sort of out of place.
Speaker 1: I guess the color matches.
Speaker 0: The thing is, I think the Sentinel actually fits RIT's character very well.
Speaker 0: And I think it's kind of cool.
Speaker 0: The thing is, I would have preferred an enormous Tiger on the scale of the Colossus of Rhodes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, imagine if they just made the same Tiger statue only that big and on two legs.
Speaker 0: The testicles would be too much for one man to paint in a night.
Speaker 1: Because you drive down La Memorial Drive straight down and you see these two gigantic golden Tiger nuts.
Speaker 1: As big as your car.
Speaker 0: You know what's sad?
Speaker 0: I almost said Sardia instead of Rhodes.
Speaker 0: Like it almost came out.
Speaker 1: That's where Colossus are from.
Speaker 1: There were Colossus in both places.
Speaker 0: So, anyway, not one with nine strength and nine fortitude or whatever those stats were called.
Speaker 0: Fuck magic.
Speaker 1: Attack and defense, I don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I had some other thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to use it because we'll talk about it for too long.
Speaker 0: So, this is pretty good though.
Speaker 0: I saw the recent Star Trek movie.
Speaker 0: I thought it was badass.
Speaker 0: I'm very much a fan.
Speaker 0: I look forward to the sequel.
Speaker 0: And I have seen Star Wars.
Speaker 0: I'm sure many of you have seen Star Wars, the original.
Speaker 1: I always compare the two, but really they have nothing to do with each other.
Speaker 0: It's funny because that's what this video is.
Speaker 0: And you haven't seen it yet.
Speaker 0: I'll show it to you after the show.
Speaker 0: But as Scott has now seen, the movies are more similar than you might think.
Speaker 1: Well, at least the new ones.
Speaker 1: I mean, the old ones really don't have anything to do with Star Wars at all.
Speaker 0: No, not at all.
Speaker 0: Well, they're in space.
Speaker 1: I mean, this is not have anything to do with my like or dislike of Star Wars or Star Trek.
Speaker 1: But you know, I mean, if you're going to make sort of a shallow comparison of the two, right?
Speaker 1: It's X-wing, TIE fighter dog fighting versus a bunch of people standing in a room and pretending the room is shaking.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, Star Trek technology would probably kick the shit out of Star Wars technology.
Speaker 1: Well, remember it.
Speaker 1: Well, depends when.
Speaker 1: I mean, we're talking about the old republic.
Speaker 1: Star Trek's got nothing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But if you're talking about, you know, original trilogy, it's like, you know, freaking, it's the equivalent of outer space versus the North Star.
Speaker 1: So, you know, oh, man, we should make Hokutono outer space.
Speaker 0: That might be too much.
Speaker 0: What is this?
Speaker 0: Do they launch Kenshiro at ships?
Speaker 1: No, no.
Speaker 1: The ship goes.
Speaker 1: And then the other ship explodes.
Speaker 0: That might be too much.
Speaker 0: So to talk about legitimate art and literature, we finally, I read and finished Cavalier and Clay, the Geek Nights book club.
Speaker 1: And as a disclaimer, while, you know, I have to say, I read it a while ago, months and months ago, perhaps even over a year ago.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But when I read it, it's I think it's still my favorite book, even though I've only read it once.
Speaker 1: Like it just, you know, and I remember it being my favorite book.
Speaker 1: But as is the way of my brain, many of the details are forgotten.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But I'm sure that as soon as we begin discussing, because I remember, you know, many things, you know, it will come rushing back to me and I'll
Speaker 0: be like, oh, man, I mean, pretty much the best part of the entire novel was when, oh,
Speaker 1: wait, wait, let's see what you think.
Speaker 0: The best part is when Joe exploded the head of that guy who was pounding that farmer into the ground like a pile driver.
Speaker 1: That's what you think.
Speaker 1: Now, see, for me, for me, there's two different parts.
Speaker 0: This is a book that was about comic books and Jews and New York City.
Speaker 0: Like what book could be more up?
Speaker 0: your also also the war, also the war.
Speaker 1: And also golems, golems and escapism, you know, like Houdini types, but also every other type of escapism.
Speaker 0: You see what he did there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Now, before we go any further, you know, this is the geek nights book club.
Speaker 0: This kind of came in after all that news and stuff.
Speaker 0: If you haven't read Michael Chabon's Cavalier and Clay, the amazing adventures of the cavalry.
Speaker 0: Don't listen to this.
Speaker 0: Go listen to the other episode where we said, hey, this is the next book in the in the book club.
Speaker 0: And then read that book.
Speaker 1: By the way, this book won Pulitzer Prize for best book.
Speaker 1: So you should.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it was I don't know who's for best book, but it won the Pulitzer Prize and it should have been for best book period.
Speaker 0: But yes, book involving comic books.
Speaker 1: That means it's legit like for reals.
Speaker 1: That is, you know, it's not like, you know, sure you read sci fi books.
Speaker 1: They have Hugo and Nebula awards, which are not.
Speaker 1: I don't want to put them down.
Speaker 1: Those are excellent awards.
Speaker 1: And only great sci fi books have won those awards.
Speaker 1: But a Pulitzer Prize is like two steps beyond that.
Speaker 1: That is like serious business.
Speaker 1: So anyway, I think there were two equivalent best parts of the book.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Number one was the Empire State Building roof scene.
Speaker 0: That was that was pretty well done.
Speaker 1: Like after like while reading that, like I was you know, I was working in the city like I kind of wanted to.
Speaker 1: I was like I thought about going in line and going up there.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: Because you're waiting to meet your Tracy Bacon.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I was just thinking about like going up there.
Speaker 1: But then I saw there was a long line and I was like, oh, fuck it.
Speaker 0: But Scott, Tracy's up there waiting for you.
Speaker 1: I know right now.
Speaker 1: Just thinking about going up there just because I only the last time I was up there.
Speaker 1: How old how old do you think I was?
Speaker 0: Scott, I've never been up there.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: Let's go up there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we should.
Speaker 0: I'm not Tracy Bacon.
Speaker 1: No, last time I was out there, I was 10 years old with my grandma.
Speaker 1: We took the express bus from Queens.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, it's been a while.
Speaker 1: It's been a long time.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I really I liked the part.
Speaker 1: Oh, wait, wait.
Speaker 1: Now, my other favorite part was in Antarctica.
Speaker 1: That whole thing, the whole mostly the the, you know, the finish of it.
Speaker 0: That that was I don't know.
Speaker 0: I guess that was you expected that sort of thing to happen in terms of finally gets his revenge or kill someone or something and then realizes it.
Speaker 0: But it was the fact that they kind of glottal, not they, he but Michael Chavon does this a lot.
Speaker 0: He'll kind of gloss over a detail and then later on tell you what actually happened.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that's right.
Speaker 0: And a lot of the good scenes I think were like that, like that was in particular where they don't point out that he's dead until a little while later.
Speaker 0: Or I think the best example was with the the raid in the Jersey Shore.
Speaker 0: Remember that how it's describing like it starts out, you know, he went there and all this stuff, and then he just has this line like, you know, these people were here at these times as the police report would later indicate.
Speaker 0: And then he just goes on explaining the rest of the scene in the story.
Speaker 0: And you're like, wait a minute, police report.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: What's going on here?
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, that's pretty good.
Speaker 0: Of course, the cool thing about that, too, is notice how that would make things that were like a scene that if you just read it without knowing like that one sentence, he throws in near the beginning that you have one feeling, one vibe, like, oh, they're at the shore.
Speaker 0: Oh, he's doing this.
Speaker 0: But because they'll have he'll have that one line that adds this whole ominous tint to everything.
Speaker 0: I suddenly you're wondering, wait a minute, is someone going to die?
Speaker 0: What's going to happen?
Speaker 0: What's going on?
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: It's good stuff because it's like it's a foreshadow, right?
Speaker 1: It's not even just a foreshadow, which is sort of like a hint.
Speaker 1: It's like it's not a hint.
Speaker 1: It's a guarantee like something's going to happen.
Speaker 1: But it could be all these possibilities.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And plus, the book starts out as opposed to a foreshadow, which is a hint, but not a guarantee that a very that usually you know exactly what's going to happen.
Speaker 0: But more often than not, it keeps the book kept hinting the whole time at all these future tragedies.
Speaker 0: And then they were never well, they were rarely as bad as you expected them to be.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, nothing really, really terrible happens other other than it's not a tragedy story.
Speaker 0: Well, other than World War Two.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, like, you know, to the main type characters, you know, it's mostly, you know, an adventure story with, you know, that it's primarily actually an adventure story, I would say.
Speaker 0: Well, I would say it was an adventure story for the first like two thirds, maybe three quarters.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then once he gets back from the war, it's not as the era has changed.
Speaker 0: It's like the fifties changed everyone.
Speaker 0: And like everyone moves out to suburbia and leaves these lame fake lives and they all forget about adventure and they all just kind of like they live this mundane existence and it takes a big spark to put them back into rights again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think, you know, the big thing about this book is how while it is a work of fiction, like how much of it like just matches up with real things.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: For example, right about the start of the book is like, you know, when like Superman is setting the shelves and about the end of the book is when they're, you know, having the, you know, like the, you know, the trials for, you know, we're just kind of right.
Speaker 0: All that happened.
Speaker 1: Well, no, that is, you know, that range of years is the golden age of comic books.
Speaker 1: So it's, you know, it's like covering that exact period of time, you know, you know, and other interesting things like the whole beginning of the book where like, you know, they're there in the comic book business.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Basically what that is, is he took the real world stories of all of these different, you know, comic book creators in the history of American comic books, you know, Stanley, Jack Kirby, Will Eisner, Staranko, like all these, you know, comic book people.
Speaker 1: He took all their stories, which are well documented and sort of combined them and mashed them and mashed them together, you know, into the story of just two people.
Speaker 1: So it's like, you know, there there be, you know, you're learning that like, you know, the professional histories of all these, you know, like comic book, you know, greats of the United States all at once.
Speaker 1: And it's, you know, if you don't know it, you won't realize it.
Speaker 0: You know, at the same time, I feel like you get a sort of a history and like an amalgamated history of the eras, like each decade, each societal era.
Speaker 0: That's a Forrest Gump kind of thing of New York City in particular, like you get like the, you know, the twenties, the thirties, the forties, the fifties, like you get each one kind of just what people felt like and what the vibe was through the characters.
Speaker 0: Now they're vibrant in one era.
Speaker 0: And then, you know, the world's beaten him down in the war and then after the war, the kind of post-war normalcy and everything.
Speaker 0: And I don't know, I really dug that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, it's stuff like remember when he goes to Grand Central to get on the train to Canada, right?
Speaker 1: Grand Central to Canada.
Speaker 1: OK, right.
Speaker 1: I wish it still went to Canada and then.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Like he gets off and he turns around, but didn't wasn't that also when like he he got into a fight with what's the German box smelling Max Schmeling?
Speaker 1: he had a bunch of that.
Speaker 1: But that also wasn't at the same place.
Speaker 0: But I like the mythology of even like the Max Schmeling incident, because obviously Michael Chabot never lets you know if that was really Max Schmeling.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like there's so much, you know, the mythological stuff mixed in with this reality stuff.
Speaker 1: You get the golem and the Max Schmeling and the, you know, the I think the Indiana Jones style adventure, Antarctica.
Speaker 0: I think it's all allegory that all the comic books from each era represent what people were like in that era and what people were feeling in that era.
Speaker 0: And you look at the Golden Age and compared to what was going on in the places where comics were being made during the Golden Age.
Speaker 0: And I think there's a strong reflection.
Speaker 1: Absolutely.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't I don't I don't even say I think I know.
Speaker 0: And this is just an amazing novel that just like as an aside points that out in a really excellent way, because that's not really the focus.
Speaker 0: That's just like this amazing parallelism that I think is what gives the book a lot of its strength.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Never mind the fact that it's written.
Speaker 1: And you've also you know, you've also got there are other instances of like, you know, famous people like what's his name is in there.
Speaker 1: isn't Dali?
Speaker 1: or was it Dali?
Speaker 1: or was it Picasso is in there?
Speaker 1: Someone was.
Speaker 0: it was either Dali or Picasso.
Speaker 0: I forget which one it was almost fantastically died in a diving accident.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I forget which one it was.
Speaker 1: But he's got like, you know, famous people from history sort of, you know, who are of the time sort of coming in as, you know, mythical characters almost.
Speaker 1: It's pretty it's it's.
Speaker 1: All right, so what else?
Speaker 1: what else do you say about this?
Speaker 0: That is I mean, just before we get into more details or good scenes or anything, the writing in this book is, for lack of a better word, flawless.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is just.
Speaker 0: his phrasing is so smooth and so flowing and like the structure of every paragraph is like parallel to the paragraph after it.
Speaker 0: And it kind of pulls you into this rhythm and he'll drag you along and drag you along and you'll get really into it.
Speaker 0: And they'll pull a gigantic change up suddenly.
Speaker 0: Or, you know, I run into this a lot with less apt writers where you'll be reading a story or watching an anime or comic book or something, and it gets to the point to where you can predict like where the story is going to go from here.
Speaker 0: Like a good example is in the beginning when they actually start making comic books for Ashkenazi and that other guy, you know, the midget radio comics, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And you see right away, like after this, there's going to be the long story of they're being exploited, but they have their creative freedom and the fighting and eventually breaking free and making comics elsewhere.
Speaker 0: You know, all this sort of like.
Speaker 0: you have this expectation of where the story is going to go.
Speaker 0: And the story does go that way.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, it'd be like this giant twist and it wouldn't be as good of a book.
Speaker 0: Instead, Shayvon just kind of gets to the point and the moment you know where the story is going to go next, it skips ahead to the next point after all the stuff you knew was going to happen to where you don't know what's going to happen again.
Speaker 0: Like it skips every possible tedious moment in the story.
Speaker 0: And it's rare that I find a work that does that.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess I didn't really think about it that way.
Speaker 0: Well, it happens a lot of times, more like the Alaska thing, like it gets to the point where it's resolved and then it doesn't follow the story of getting back or all that other stuff.
Speaker 1: It's true.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You skip large swatches of the story where the I guess the narrative would have been.
Speaker 1: At some point in the story, it skips like a whole ton of years, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But look, a lot like when it skips the most time is when they're living that boring suburban life.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: You know, he pretty much skips over when anything's not happening.
Speaker 1: You know, if the status quo doesn't change for a long period of time, it just, you know, glosses right over and gets to the point where there's action.
Speaker 1: The books.
Speaker 1: And I mean, how many years is he like in the Empire State Building just living there, working on his thing?
Speaker 0: that, you know, they don't really skips all the license plate making and gets to the one good part.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then it milks that good part.
Speaker 1: And I think, you know, earlier in the book, when there's actually adventure type stuff, you know, it's, you know, they'd have to skip fewer years than when, you know, the boring stuff happens later.
Speaker 0: Plus just the diction and I don't know, the writing is just amazing.
Speaker 0: And it really like he uses grown up words, he instills a sense of nostalgia for things in the context of the book, not just like, you know, say I was old.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's not like I'm an old guy and I have nostalgia for Superman.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, these characters start out pretty young teenagers.
Speaker 1: And then you get you.
Speaker 1: you pass so many years in the book, but then you're having nostalgia for the earlier stuff in the book itself, especially because he like he writes the remember when Max Schmeling punch you in the face.
Speaker 0: Remember when we burned our mouths on that four cheese bread, beer and pizza.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: But the book, I don't know, he really writes the virility and vitality of youth very well.
Speaker 0: And that in and of itself wouldn't be amazing, except for the fact that the counterpoint of when they're older, like the characters at each age are written in such a way that you start to feel the world from the perspective of someone who is that age, who is living in that age.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, getting to the point where they're in their 20s, 30s and there you feel like I feel the same way reading them thinking about their youth that I feel thinking about myself when I was 17 or 18.
Speaker 0: Mm hmm.
Speaker 0: And they change so realistically that it's very hard to separate these fake characters from just the way real life goes.
Speaker 0: What bothered me, though, is that as a result, when they're in their 30s and then when they're, you know, when they're getting older, I could feel the way I'm going to feel when I'm that age looking back on now.
Speaker 0: And I don't like it.
Speaker 0: I don't like it one bit, but I feel like it's it is dead on accurate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess at least, you know, in a I don't know, you're feeling old.
Speaker 1: Not yet.
Speaker 0: I think part of it is that notice how when the adventure stops and when they start leading the mundane lives, the glimmer of hope in the end is that they sort all their shit out and the book clearly ends with them making the rest of their adventures.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, because it's like, right, they start off right with, well, the thing is, Joe.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: He's always sort of been adventure.
Speaker 1: He's like the hero.
Speaker 1: And Sam is just the sidekick.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But, you know, but notice how in the beginning of the book, Joe's adventures are not amazing to him.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: They're never really amazing to him at all.
Speaker 1: You know, and, you know, at the beginning of the book, a lot of his adventures have already happened.
Speaker 1: You know, his adventures in Prague and whatever, you know, it's sort of like, you know, he's escaped.
Speaker 1: And now he's in the US.
Speaker 0: You could have written a whole novel just about him in Prague and his family and the eventual escape.
Speaker 0: And then what happened to the golem?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Like if the book had just followed that all the way to the end, it probably would have been a great book anyway.
Speaker 0: But instead it does this thing that's a thousand times better because it was it was just about that.
Speaker 1: It would be, you know, sort of like a short, quirky kind of sci fi story.
Speaker 1: It wouldn't be, you know, something else.
Speaker 0: I do like how you don't ever like.
Speaker 0: you've no idea how the golem got there.
Speaker 0: Like it just kind of comes back at the end, coincidentally parallel to when he starts making his own golems again.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The golem died.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All that stuff.
Speaker 1: Well, that's the thing is.
Speaker 1: it's, you know, it's always, you know, really cool how.
Speaker 1: I think that a lot of the great sci fi and fantasy books out there are the ones that are, you know, like you look good as good as sci fi fantasy shelves in the store.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Think about it.
Speaker 1: Just imagine yourself in a borders or Barnes and Noble.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: I'm seeing in front of a in front of a fantasy sci fi shelf.
Speaker 0: Here's what I'm seeing.
Speaker 0: I see one, the tableau of forgotten realms.
Speaker 0: OK, next to that, I see a bunch of novels with like giant dragons on them.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Then I see a bunch of novels like big barbarian sword guys.
Speaker 0: And then I see planets with spaceships around.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Now, the thing I see, at least from my perspective, right.
Speaker 1: The stuff that is like blatant high fantasy, like you open the book, page one tons of dragons and wizards and magic and swords.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Or blatant like outer space awesomeness.
Speaker 1: Like you open the first page spacemen and aliens and rockets and lasers and whatever.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That sort of stuff is typically, you know, the pulp, shallow kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: But the things that are less overt, you know, not high with their fantasy, not pulp with their sci fi, you know, where, you know, the science fiction elements are more subdued or subtle or perhaps not even, you know, questionable if they even really exist.
Speaker 1: or like the fantasy things were like, you know, this book has, you know, sort of fantastic elements.
Speaker 1: You know, is this is there really magic in this golem?
Speaker 1: and, you know, all these sorts of things that are sort of impossible.
Speaker 1: But of course, what story is told in such a way that includes those elements without actually, you know, making you think he's in some magical world because it's like they happened, but they didn't really happen.
Speaker 0: Well, at the same time, they weren't magical in the high fantasy sense.
Speaker 0: They were magical in the improbable, but not impossible.
Speaker 0: events often feel magical or legendary or mythic after the fact.
Speaker 0: But when you're actually doing them, they feel much more mundane.
Speaker 0: I mean, the fight with Max Schmeling, quote unquote, was just, you know, I got my ass kicked, but later it becomes this mythical.
Speaker 0: I fought with Max Schmeling.
Speaker 0: The golem was, you know, if you look at it from a rational perspective, was just this Jewish artifact that they had to smuggle out of the country.
Speaker 0: But after the fact, it becomes this, you know, this was the golem of Prague.
Speaker 1: that, you know, I mean, think about Indiana Jones.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Other than stuff like, you know, the stuff that happens at the end of the movies.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Everything that happens before the end of the movie.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's all completely mundane.
Speaker 1: But when you look at it, it really feels like this fantasy adventure almost like there's no way except, you know, the final part, which is absolute complete fantasy.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I've either the first or third movies, so this is sort of the same thing.
Speaker 1: You've got like Houdini.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, Houdini in his day was completely mundane.
Speaker 1: But now, you know, nowadays looking back is like a fantastic character, you know, and the same thing with like, you know, what the comic book creators were doing right in their day.
Speaker 1: They were just guys going to work, making comic books.
Speaker 1: It wasn't like, you know, but now we look at the history of those comic book creators as if it was some sort of, you know, fantastic, amazing thing when it was just some guys going to work.
Speaker 0: One thing I can say the book really did do for me, though, was it made me like I love New York City, but it made me appreciate New York City more than I thought I could.
Speaker 1: Well, because I think what it does is it portrays the the fantasy New York that we all, you know, wish for and not at the same time.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: It portrays the fantasy New York.
Speaker 1: It's like it really, really puts you in that art deco, New York, awesome buildings.
Speaker 1: Everything is great.
Speaker 1: Oh, my gosh.
Speaker 0: Kind of setting, but it portrays the fantasy New York like this.
Speaker 0: And yet I'm walking and I look up and there is the Empire State Building because it's exactly the way it was described.
Speaker 1: Well, see, I think that's the thing is that New York, the physicality of much of the buildings and the architecture and the streets and all these sorts of things, you sort of support that fantasy world.
Speaker 1: But the totality of the people, it was never really real.
Speaker 1: But in the movies, it was it was real.
Speaker 1: But in the real world, it was never 100 percent.
Speaker 1: You know, it was always.
Speaker 0: well, it's part of the thing that mythology always comes from the past when, you know, the memories are hazy and you have nostalgia.
Speaker 0: It's I think it's a mix of memory and nostalgia.
Speaker 0: Mm hmm.
Speaker 0: Running out of steam here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just try to remember more the stuff that went on.
Speaker 0: I mean, we could talk about specifics.
Speaker 0: I mean, I think I love the characters.
Speaker 0: I love when you get just like all these side characters and they're all just so weird or quirky or quirky in the real human way, like the mad bomber, what bombs with a trident at the bar mitzvah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: Or how about, you know, this the Sam's dad, the sideshow, see another larger than life figure who is very mundane, but yet, like in retrospect, gains this mythic quality.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And also, you know, the obvious, you know, superheroness of it, you know, relating to the comic books.
Speaker 1: You've got the the old guy who helped him escape with the golem.
Speaker 0: Cornblum is like my Cornblum is I don't know.
Speaker 0: He feels like he should be in the League of Extraordinary Gentlemen.
Speaker 1: He reminds me of that Russian guy in Ex Machina.
Speaker 0: I like the Russian guy in Ex Machina.
Speaker 1: Sort of the same kind of guy.
Speaker 1: You know, the old guy is a little bit, but he's totally awesome and he helps you out.
Speaker 1: And yeah, that kind of character.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Something I actually hear is something that made me feel kind of stupid.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Towards the end of the book, when, you know, when they compare the when they're at the the congressional hearing or whatever it is.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And they draw the comparison between, you know, he always draw, he always, you know, put every every book he worked on, he put in his he put in a sidekick and he was, you know, totally gay.
Speaker 1: And they draw that out.
Speaker 1: And it's like and like.
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh, wow, why did I not ever realize that?
Speaker 1: That's sort of obvious.
Speaker 1: But so when, you know, the congressman came out with that one, I was like, oh, wow, how did I not see that obvious thing there?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I guess, you know, I went into the book like I didn't even read the back cover.
Speaker 0: I just dove right into it.
Speaker 1: I didn't read the back cover.
Speaker 0: I was.
Speaker 0: I was 100 percent sure he was gay from the moment he was in the steam house with his dad.
Speaker 0: It was like, well, he's gay.
Speaker 0: That's interesting.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: It's like, yeah, I didn't.
Speaker 1: when I first read it, like I didn't, you know, go back to the.
Speaker 1: you know, when I got to the end and I went I didn't think back to the steam house.
Speaker 1: But now that I know you just said it, I was like, oh, I did like.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's a typical almost cliche thing to do when after the hearing and, you know, they take him, Joe and they take him out and get him a drink and they're like, yeah, that sucks.
Speaker 0: And he looks at him.
Speaker 0: He's like, you guys didn't act really surprised at all.
Speaker 0: And they're both like, seriously?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 1: I know this book is quite epicness, but you know, because if you're listening, you've read it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's one of the rare books I could definitely read again at least one more time in my life.
Speaker 1: I got to read it again because I read it.
Speaker 1: And I was like, this is better and more up my alley than any book I've ever read.
Speaker 0: But I've only read it once simply because I've been, you know, I do know, I would like to hear the perspective of someone reading it who doesn't know about comic books or Jews or New York City.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know, that's something is like everyone I know who's read it or talked about comic books and Jews was either a Jew or a comic book reader or a New York person.
Speaker 1: Or, you know, I've never really you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: I've seen a lot of people reading this book.
Speaker 1: It's very popular.
Speaker 1: But like it's all been New York, Jews, comic book people or some combination of the three.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: I've never seen someone reading this book or, you know, met someone who's read the book.
Speaker 1: And I've known they read the book who is no, not New York at all, not Jewish at all, not comic book at all.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I would like to really I would really like to know what that kind of person would would get from the book, you know, because like there's all sorts of things that they probably wouldn't recognize.
Speaker 1: You know, they really you know, they might not have a really good, you know, concept of like what the Empire State Building like really looks like and what it's like to be there at the same time.
Speaker 0: That might make the book feel even more epic, because if you haven't seen it, the way it's described is so kind of amazing and magical in and of itself that it kind of draws you into the world.
Speaker 0: And then if you go to New York later, you'd probably have the revelation of, wow, it's really like.
Speaker 1: that is definitely you know, it's.
Speaker 1: Whenever you read a book that's about things you're familiar with, right, it's sort of like when they say Grand Central, right, I know exactly what Grand Central looks like down to like many minute details.
Speaker 1: So if a book says you're in Grand Central, right, I was like, oh, I know exactly what you know, I'd say perfect.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But someone else who doesn't, you know, might not have been there ever just thinks of some amazing train station and it gives them more room in the imagination department, you know, and there's something to be said for both there.
Speaker 1: But, you know, it's it's a different experience and and, you know, reading it depending on your previous knowledge, you know, gives you a different.
Speaker 1: you know, you're going to take something different away from that scene in Grand Central based on your familiarity with the the setting and such.
Speaker 1: And not just the setting, there are other things, too, to be familiar with, you know, like there's the the whole bar mitzvah thing, it's like, you know, being familiar with the bar mitzvah and that culture and those type of people, you take something different away.
Speaker 1: That guy is familiar with the history of comic books.
Speaker 1: You take something different away.
Speaker 1: The thing is pretty much everything in this book, except for the sort of freaky art scene I'm very familiar with.
Speaker 0: The thing is that art scene, like if I had to have a favorite part of the book, it's the whole part where they're kind of immersed in and around like the vitality of youth and they're in that art scene just doing crazy crap all the time.
Speaker 0: And Rosa Sacks is possibly the most attractive person in a novel ever.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I see.
Speaker 1: I didn't think she was so like attractive.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean, like, look at me.
Speaker 0: Who who have I been attracted to my entire life?
Speaker 0: Arty girls.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like Arty girls, too.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Sacks is an Arty girl.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But, you know, I didn't.
Speaker 1: she didn't come across as, you know, like, oh, man, I want some of that.
Speaker 1: It was just like, yep.
Speaker 1: She's, you know, the girl.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Oh, huh.
Speaker 0: Is it maybe Tracy's more up your alley?
Speaker 1: No, I don't think so.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I felt that Rosa was portrayed early on in this painfully sensual way, but there might have just been me reading into it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Her dad's kind of kind of awesome.
Speaker 0: Longman, Harkoo.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But that I that is what I want life to be like.
Speaker 0: And I guess that is what I'd like to live the life of a long, but that's what made the end of the book so full of like.
Speaker 0: the end of the book was just nothing but driving desperate melancholy until the very, very end when the golem arrives.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Like it was to the point to where I remember resolving to myself as I was reading it that I will never have my life have a chapter that is like the end of this novel.
Speaker 1: I don't have a chapter.
Speaker 1: that's like any chapters of this novel.
Speaker 1: I'll take any one I can get, even, you know, the bad ones.
Speaker 1: It's it's all right.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I could do without the living a boring life in suburbia part.
Speaker 1: OK, maybe.
Speaker 1: But I mean, I'm almost doing it now.
Speaker 1: But see, even that boring life in suburbia.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It was it was a much it was a suburbia from an older time that was portrayed in sort of a very nostalgic way of, you know, going down to the drugstore and buying comic books.
Speaker 0: I didn't see this nostalgic at all.
Speaker 0: It would only be nostalgic to me that people who were nostalgic in the meta perspective from that for that.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Because reading it, I was, you know, it's portrayed through the view of the characters.
Speaker 0: So they're nostalgic for the awesome time.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But the it's that, you know, the childhood of what's the kid's name?
Speaker 1: I forget.
Speaker 1: But, you know, that the kid's life during that suburban time, you know, is is nostalgic to people who, you know, think about that, you know, it's sort of a.
Speaker 0: Well, that's because it's sort of a Christmas story for young Thomas.
Speaker 0: The second time is Thomas.
Speaker 0: That's going to be the larger than life.
Speaker 0: You know, his look at his childhood, that whole era was mundane to the parents because they're living mundane lives now.
Speaker 0: And it's the present for them and they're nostalgic for the adventures of youth.
Speaker 0: Joe jumping off of the Empire State Building with a rubber band and him like sneaking around New York and all that stuff he was doing and go into the comic books and his dad being a comic artist.
Speaker 0: Those are going to be his cavalier and clay escapist adventures and his nostalgia and his myth when he's older looking back.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: But the nostalgia wasn't there in the book.
Speaker 0: All the book did was show you that, look, his nostalgia is going to be in the future and the cycle repeats and the every generation's nostalgia and all that sort of symbolic cycling forever and ever.
Speaker 0: The major symbolism, though, is all the people who get to keep their lives like that the whole time are long and hard coups.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The major symbolism in the book, though, is always escapism.
Speaker 1: You know, it's just everything is always.
Speaker 1: he just throws that escape metaphor in wherever he can get it.
Speaker 1: You know, Houdini escapism, comic book escapism, conformity, the character that come up with is the escapist, you know, just all the way through.
Speaker 0: It's always literally physically, metaphorically and spiritually escape from a lot of things, both forward, backward and also inward.
Speaker 1: It's just constant escape over and over and over and over again.
Speaker 1: You know, it is just that's.
Speaker 1: that's where it's at.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you there's a there's some comic books from Dark Horse, there's, you know, the escapist.
Speaker 1: I forget what they actually.
Speaker 1: there's two series, right?
Speaker 1: There's one that is a miniseries by Brian K. Vaughan.
Speaker 1: You know, I think it's just called The Escapists.
Speaker 1: And that's sort of based on this novel.
Speaker 1: And it's really good.
Speaker 1: I have the first issue of it, but I was never able to get that.
Speaker 1: I don't think they made a trade.
Speaker 1: I think they get the hardcover, which is annoying, but I'm going to get it.
Speaker 1: And then I think there's another one that is actually like the adventures of the escapist, which is, you know, is the comic books that they were drawing.
Speaker 1: You know, the guy with the black suit and the big key on his chest going around, you know, escaping and fighting bad guys.
Speaker 1: So those are the two comic books that Dark Horse put out based on this book here.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So you are aware of them.
Speaker 0: Actually, I think it looks like they're.
Speaker 0: I see all this talk about a movie, but I'm just going to ignore that.
Speaker 1: I'm right.
Speaker 1: Basically, they were going to make a movie and they didn't.
Speaker 1: Don't worry about it.
Speaker 0: It looks like they also made.
Speaker 0: Well, actually, Chavon made The Escapists comic books.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: That's what I was talking about.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Just ignore all that movie crap.
Speaker 0: Doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: We're really only talking about the book here.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Read the book.
Speaker 0: The book is absolutely amazing.
Speaker 1: You've read the book.
Speaker 0: You should have read the book.
Speaker 0: I assume you've read the book.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, we just ruined the whole thing.
Speaker 1: That's all right.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Do we have anything else to say?
Speaker 0: I think we should wrap it up.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: But I don't think we should announce the next book club book yet.
Speaker 1: You have to choose.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I chose this one.
Speaker 0: And I will choose.
Speaker 1: Choose now.
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: I had to choose right now.
Speaker 0: You make me choose on the spot.
Speaker 0: I'm going to pick something that no one's going to read.
Speaker 0: I'm going to pick like The Odyssey.
Speaker 1: That's no good.
Speaker 0: Are you kidding?
Speaker 0: The Odyssey is one of the greatest works of literature ever.
Speaker 1: I didn't say The Odyssey is not good.
Speaker 1: I said it's no good as a choice for the book club.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: Because what are you going to say about The Odyssey and the book club?
Speaker 0: I got stuff to say.
Speaker 1: I like Cyclopses.
Speaker 0: But nobody likes Cyclify.
Speaker 1: I like Cyclify.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our crapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays we have video games, board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights and Thursdays are the catch alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.