Speaker 1: It's Monday March 9th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight the telecommutes.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: I was gonna ski this weekend.
Speaker 1: I was really looking forward to it.
Speaker 1: It was like cold and perfect all week.
Speaker 0: We know that skiing is over.
Speaker 1: No, it's not actually.
Speaker 1: no It's not.
Speaker 1: you realize it's gonna snow here like tomorrow.
Speaker 0: I know it's not.
Speaker 0: it's gonna get cold again It's not gonna get that cold.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, it is.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll pull up the NOA.
Speaker 1: But anyway Last week early last week.
Speaker 1: It was freezing cold.
Speaker 1: It was perfect skiing weather and the news was like, yep It's gonna be cold all week and then starting next week.
Speaker 1: It's gonna get warm for a little bit.
Speaker 1: I'm like, alright, and then every day the forecast got a little bit warmer for the weekend and then Saturday and Sunday It was like 65 degrees wearing shorts.
Speaker 1: So while I wanted to ski I couldn't really complain that much because I got to wear shorts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the thing is you know you need me if you could ski even in that kind of weather if the mountain is High enough.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is depending on the weather and what was there before, you know, what came before Skiing and like 50-degree weather in the right conditions is like the most fun you'll ever have because it's super comfortable and you're still skiing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess.
Speaker 0: but you know The thing is if it's 50 degrees at the top of the mountain the snow is all melting well melting But it depends on what kind of snow you got.
Speaker 0: I guess if you like, you know you if you can Can you like add salt to the snow that makes it melt, you know quicker right, but I don't know I'm not a snow.
Speaker 0: if you had some sort of like reverse salt that you could add to the snow to sort of You know like raise the freezing point, you know, so that maybe you know stayed frozen at like 40 degrees or something.
Speaker 0: You know what I'm saying?
Speaker 0: Because you can add salt to make it, you know melt at like, you know lower than you know freezing.
Speaker 0: So couldn't you dad reverse salt to do the opposite?
Speaker 1: Ah Probably not.
Speaker 1: What's reverse salt Scott?
Speaker 0: some other chemical that you know has it as a Freezes higher freezing point I get I don't know.
Speaker 1: but regardless we had the crew out scientists Help me out here played some burning wheels And then I was happy that we haven't had a good argument forever in the front row.
Speaker 1: crew Like, you know, we're all atheists.
Speaker 1: everyone kind of is generally, you know liberal socially.
Speaker 1: There's very little we disagree on in terms of the big issues.
Speaker 0: So finally we don't.
Speaker 0: usually we have agreements.
Speaker 0: Disagreements is when someone finds out something new.
Speaker 0: that sort of contradicts what they already knew, right?
Speaker 0: So someone changes their mind and then starts to go and tell it to everyone else and they'll be like, hey, that's not right.
Speaker 0: And then they hard sort of had to go and drag up all their evidence and that everyone goes Is definitely a.
Speaker 1: you're not like inverting wheel when you make a character.
Speaker 1: if you're there's one question that basically says if you lived in like a difficult adversarial intellectual Community as a child plus one to your steel stat That's kind of what it's like in the front row crew.
Speaker 1: if you if you so much as imply that you have an unbacked up Statement that you're about to make like everyone's ready to jump on you good, so we had.
Speaker 1: we had a Transhumanism argument which is great because it's one of those things where other than historical trends There's no evidence of what the future is going to be like.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much just you know extrapolation and assumption on both sides and it all comes down to ethics and morals and like the fine distinctions Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So that went on for like two hours.
Speaker 1: Scott missed it, which is good because I guess I think the last argument we had.
Speaker 1: you Explained that you're the uber mesh and thus you're beyond all of our trivial concerns.
Speaker 0: Yes, I am which is I was so beyond your trivial concerns that I had no need to take part in your argument Because I already knew the correct answer and you're not worthy of hearing it from me.
Speaker 1: So what is the correct news Scott?
Speaker 0: the correct news is this?
Speaker 0: Say in Sweden the Pirate Bay, they're doing their business, right?
Speaker 0: I think that they finished up, but I don't think there's been a verdict yet.
Speaker 0: I think we're waiting for that still and if we're not still waiting for it.
Speaker 0: Well, I haven't seen the result and so Someone please tell me what it is, but I'm pretty sure we're waiting for the result there.
Speaker 0: But one country away from Sweden in Norway All right, the exact opposite is happening and basically Norway's public broadcaster, which I assume is the equivalent of like PBS in the United States is Taking their shows and they set up a bit torrent tracker using the same exact software the Pirate Bay uses for their bit torrent tracker and is putting all their stuff up on bit torrent.
Speaker 0: but Unlike say for instance BBC's I player right which doesn't let people outside of the UK Watch all the you know free BBC stuff online The Norway's bit torrent tracker is completely DRM free.
Speaker 0: It's completely open.
Speaker 0: it's just bit torrent right.
Speaker 0: and Not only does that mean that you can you know Subtitle translate whatever.
Speaker 0: they are actively trying to get people to fan sub Their programs now and you see you can send in the subtitle tracks and they'll add them in.
Speaker 1: this is brilliant Absolutely brilliant.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think I mean think about this right Norway, you know, Norway is cool and all.
Speaker 0: but they're not exactly a big player In the world, right, but by making their public broadcasting freely available to the world Popular BBC stuff is in the United States.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they can project their culture You know around the world far more strongly than you know.
Speaker 0: Someone who like keeps all their media like, you know closed and locked in.
Speaker 1: well especially with the signal-to-noise ratio is definitely increasing and More and more good media as my thing of the day is gonna point out is free and it's freezing beer It's freezing speech.
Speaker 1: It's just free and you can just watch it.
Speaker 1: So the more barriers anyone puts in the way of getting media be it paying be a DRM be it, you know Advertising anything.
Speaker 1: every one of those barriers is in the end kind of making your media further away from people.
Speaker 0: You know, I mean think about this right what you know?
Speaker 0: if you thought about You know, let's say it was the year 1995 right and you tried to think of like, you know, what really you know?
Speaker 0: media things sort of The culture and society you'd think about, you know, Nintendo sorts of things, you know in terms of us, right?
Speaker 0: You think about Ninja Turtles, maybe maybe something Disney.
Speaker 0: ish, you know Disney Afternoon kind of thing, you know That's that's the sort of stuff you would.
Speaker 0: I you know where I would think about from those days, right?
Speaker 0: but You know nowadays what do you maneuver?
Speaker 0: Right, it's and all the stuff that is paid for DRM door locked in.
Speaker 0: I mean sure there's still a lot of people out there who are all over, you know, I mean even us.
Speaker 0: We're like, you know South Park and other things like that, right?
Speaker 0: Exactly None of this stuff that is like difficult to get at is is making it out there, you know, even Like just you know big movies that you have to pay like, you know, the Watchmen is.
Speaker 0: it's getting pretty big But you know what?
Speaker 0: It's not it's not as bad that big.
Speaker 1: You're saying Watchmen isn't as big as Numa Numa, I Don't know.
Speaker 0: in the long run.
Speaker 1: It's One thing we can think it's bigger than Numa Numa.
Speaker 1: Specifically what we can't say yet.
Speaker 1: Is that the Watchmen movie.
Speaker 1: it is still like it's still coming out like Washington.
Speaker 1: It is still coming.
Speaker 1: We're not sure how many people it's going to kick apart just yet because it's I mean I see enough people who have no connection to comic books or who don't care about superheroes or anything Like being into the Watchmen that Watchmen might come out of nowhere to become.
Speaker 0: well Cuz I think the one thing is that when something has high quality it can sort of go over the barrier, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like you put up this barrier around your stuff.
Speaker 0: if your stuff is like a super strong Super high jumper, it's gonna jump right over that wall.
Speaker 0: No problem because it's that good.
Speaker 1: Well, that's one of the things that's great.
Speaker 1: it means that you free media is there and free media competes with other free media.
Speaker 1: and While free media competes with the walled-off media You can make a much higher quality walled-off media thing just by the nature of the fact that well You can make out you can make just as high quality thing.
Speaker 0: That's not walled up.
Speaker 1: You're saying.
Speaker 1: you're saying you can make Watchmen with no barrier.
Speaker 1: It's completely free.
Speaker 1: There's no.
Speaker 1: there's no possible way to make money off it.
Speaker 1: It's just there.
Speaker 1: You could have made that.
Speaker 0: well the comic book.
Speaker 0: You're assuming that.
Speaker 0: if you're talking about the movie, you're assuming that higher production value and cost equals better.
Speaker 1: No, I'm saying that what if you commercial media media that is made with a barrier with the intention of using that barrier to entry To make money?
Speaker 0: not all.
Speaker 0: but the other thing is the barrier really has nothing to do with being commercial or not.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of non commercial things that have barriers Well like dwarf fortress exactly.
Speaker 1: But I'm talking specifically about commercial media that specific kind of barrier the toll of paying money or watching ads to see it.
Speaker 1: Hmm The Quality that something has to be becomes much higher to get the current generation of kids and people Especially kids and the generations coming to bother with it at all.
Speaker 1: So I think we're gonna see this like distillation of commercial media and at the same time We're gonna see this flourishing of free media.
Speaker 0: I think we have already seen a distillation of you know, the commercial media because basically, you know It's like the stuff that people actually Really care about and really like.
Speaker 0: they're sort of going out of their way to get it and everything else is being completely ignored.
Speaker 1: Yep, but look at and I'm talking about in terms of media production - I mean me is splitting between Game show slash reality TV that cost nothing to make.
Speaker 1: so as a result You can make a lot of money off it even though there's a barrier you know lowest common denominator and all that.
Speaker 1: and then they're really high quality like the HBO stuff where like Dexter where there is a That that barrier is so worth it that you're like There's the gap between the crappy media with the lowest common denominator and low production values and the high quality High production value cost to get in just just commercial media is widening.
Speaker 1: and then the free media is like this whole third pillar.
Speaker 0: I'm just looking forward to experiencing some Norwegian television.
Speaker 1: I am as well because if nothing else Scandinavian nor real.
Speaker 1: all that whole area their folklore and their folk tales kick the shit out of American folk.
Speaker 1: What do we have?
Speaker 1: we have?
Speaker 0: Are you sure that folk tales or what's gonna be on their public broadcasting?
Speaker 1: No, but I mean think about it.
Speaker 1: there was a lot of media in America that's based on like Americana or American culture or American like idioms or you know the old cartoons about Johnny Appleseed and Paul Bunyan.
Speaker 1: I want to see the equivalent of that from Finland and Sweden and Norway.
Speaker 0: It's all about fish.
Speaker 1: So I don't want to talk a lot about this.
Speaker 1: But as you all know Circuit City is gone now.
Speaker 0: the final days happened And yeah, you can't if you were hoping to buy stuff at a bargain too late.
Speaker 1: I went to the Circuit City on like Fifth Avenue on the third to last day and Let me tell you it was a sad sight.
Speaker 1: What was left was basically like broken store models of things that were like 80% off Broken fixtures.
Speaker 1: like there were people buying like hooks off of shelves for ten cents each.
Speaker 0: I would have taken hooks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they weren't the kind of hooks we can use unless you were also buying those shelves.
Speaker 1: You happen to own those kinds of shelves they weren't.
Speaker 1: There were pieces of metal basically.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess you could buy one.
Speaker 1: I mean if I were a mugger I could have bought some pretty good mugging implements in there for real cheap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the fixtures are always the best things to buy because you know You can you have like space in a house.
Speaker 0: you can set those things up and it's pretty nice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like a good spinner rack.
Speaker 0: Those are worth it.
Speaker 1: But the thing is there was nothing left at all.
Speaker 0: Didn't you buy like?
Speaker 0: can you buy like a four megabyte SD card for like 25 cents?
Speaker 1: No, cuz those were all gone even the four megabyte ones.
Speaker 0: There was nothing left except the thing listening like the four megabyte like so small that it's worthless.
Speaker 1: They weren't there.
Speaker 1: There was nothing left.
Speaker 1: There were a couple of broken store models of things.
Speaker 1: There were like two couches real cheap.
Speaker 1: But I was on my own and it would cost me more to ship the stupid thing back up here.
Speaker 1: then it wasn't worth My couches.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like leather couches.
Speaker 0: I had couches.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: What about the car stereo section?
Speaker 1: I empty.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow, but but in the back where the CDs are there without like thousands of CDs I Don't know.
Speaker 0: wouldn't the CDs get like discounted so much.
Speaker 0: They're just clean eyes.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't need to buy a CD But if a CD is like a dollar or 50 cent I'll buy it and take it to the secondhand music store.
Speaker 0: So on Amazon is there were a ton of CDs and I could have quit my job Bought all the CDs for 50 cents each and then sold them all in a while.
Speaker 1: They weren't selling.
Speaker 1: they were not Discounted that much.
Speaker 1: they were five to fifteen dollars.
Speaker 0: These things don't sell at Best Buy when they're not discounted.
Speaker 0: So why would they sell it in a going out of business sale?
Speaker 0: if they're not just my suspicion now I don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't know exactly what the deal was But my bet is that the rule.
Speaker 1: there was some sort of rule Where they weren't allowed to discount the CDs below a certain amount because you've seen that before.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of things like that.
Speaker 1: Like you can't sell Apple stuff below?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were but the iPods weren't discounted at all.
Speaker 1: Those were gone.
Speaker 1: I think they could.
Speaker 1: they shipped those somewhere else.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I don't.
Speaker 1: maybe they weren't allowed to discount the CDs I don't know, but no one was even looking at him either.
Speaker 0: I wonder if you bought a car stereo like at the clearance.
Speaker 0: Would you still?
Speaker 0: would they still do an installation?
Speaker 1: Would you want the guy working in Circuit City and the last day to install something in your car?
Speaker 0: Maybe he'd be so passionate about it.
Speaker 0: He was like he was a hardcore dude.
Speaker 1: Actually, there was this good picture.
Speaker 1: I found it somewhere on the internet.
Speaker 1: I'd link to it, but I don't remember where I saw it.
Speaker 1: It was one of those Circuit City signs at a Circuit City and it was like car stereo 80% off TVs 40% off dignity point 2% off.
Speaker 1: Oh I was proud of that.
Speaker 1: but now my real news.
Speaker 1: so Apple and the iPod and the iPhone.
Speaker 1: The iPhone is a closed platform and you've got to like, you know Go through all this rigmarole to sell your stuff in the Apple Store and they can say what goes in and what doesn't and all That stuff.
Speaker 1: and you all know that Apparently so many people are developing or trying to develop for the App Store That Apple is just completely dropping the ball.
Speaker 1: now Like if you request the right to use it It might take months or you might just never get an answer.
Speaker 1: and they'd like if you call them They have no idea what you're talking about.
Speaker 1: People's contracts are like expiring apparently and they try to renew them and like no one answers their phone and no one tells them what to do and Like it's really falling apart on the developer side.
Speaker 0: This is this is really interesting because I don't I don't think we've actually I can't remember an instance where this happened where someone would Try to keep something closed right and in keeping something closed and limited you need a bureaucracy to sort of manage.
Speaker 0: You know everything and if the bureaucracy can't keep up with the demand You know everything just sort of collapses and it's it's real interesting to sort of be like, huh?
Speaker 0: At least they're sort of having to.
Speaker 0: you know, sure they're dicking all of us by keeping it closed, but they're paying for it.
Speaker 0: It's costing them to keep it closed which makes you think you know Even if they would perhaps, you know lose whatever they would lose.
Speaker 0: perhaps, you know for having apps They don't like or you know, whatever else, right?
Speaker 0: Maybe they would actually make more money if they kept it open and got rid of all that bureaucracy in the way.
Speaker 1: Well, what's interesting to me is that that you know?
Speaker 1: there are many reasons.
Speaker 1: you could have a closed platform and one idea that's or at least a Special restricted thing like say they had the everything goes app store and then they had the Apple certified app store.
Speaker 1: They'd like check your app out and make sure it's not crap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that'd be fun.
Speaker 1: But Looking through what's available on the App Store like 99% of it is garbage.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean we talked about we didn't.
Speaker 0: I don't think we did talk about.
Speaker 1: no we didn't.
Speaker 0: It was like what.
Speaker 0: the one news we missed right is basically someone did.
Speaker 0: it was like there's an ad I think was an advertiser who does iPhone ads and in because they're doing iPhone as they have all this information about iPhone Apps.
Speaker 0: right because the ads are in the apps and they sort of found out what everyone already knew which is that People like to install apps But they install them use them once and then usually never use them again and they pretty much only use a few apps very frequently.
Speaker 0: You know, I mean I have an iPhone right?
Speaker 0: I use the iPod app the phone app The Safari the mail.
Speaker 0: I use those the most and those are built in.
Speaker 0: I mean You know that there's very few stuff that does not built in that I actually use a lot, you know.
Speaker 0: And so what I did is I saw that news and I was like, yeah, that news is exactly right and I'm like well I'll just go through here and delete all these apps that I never use and I deleted a whole mess of them and it you Know cleaned up my phone a whole lot.
Speaker 1: Well, I think there's gonna be a big kind of day of reckoning with the App Store because the iPhone like had this big search.
Speaker 1: Everyone got one.
Speaker 1: and then what is the same thing?
Speaker 1: when you get like a Vista Vista PC and you have that little bar on The side for widgets and you look at like all the widgets like can I use that?
Speaker 1: Can I use that?
Speaker 1: That's cool That's cool.
Speaker 1: And you put like 10 in there and then a week later you get rid of nine of them.
Speaker 0: Yep, if you even bought.
Speaker 0: the thing is some people don't bother like they put all the widgets there and then they just don't look At them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't think about him, but it just it.
Speaker 1: I feel I don't know but I feel like so.
Speaker 0: people love setting up Widgets, but people don't actually use them.
Speaker 0: It's like the Mac dashboard same thing But I wonder what?
Speaker 1: Apple nominally part of this was that they only want good stuff to be in the eye in the store but yet most of the stuff in the store is overpriced garbage.
Speaker 1: and now so many people want to develop but more and more they seem to deny the apps that people really really want like Syncing podcasts just over the air without any trouble or ad block.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's kind of it's kind of crazy I Don't know.
Speaker 0: I think the real problem is.
Speaker 0: another problem I think people don't recognize the whole bunch is that you know, the App Store itself has a really bad user interface.
Speaker 0: It's really I mean this, you know thousands and thousands of apps, right?
Speaker 0: Well, how can you look at these apps?
Speaker 0: You can look at the top apps in any given category, right?
Speaker 0: You know, whatever they do, however, they determine that right?
Speaker 0: I guess based on recent popularity You can look at paid or free separately and you can search if you know the name of an app alright and that you can you know, so the thing is there's a lot of there's probably good apps that are hidden way down there where no one can find them and There's crap apps coming up to the top.
Speaker 0: And I mean, I guess you can like browse all the apps in a given category in alphabetical order going like next page next page next page.
Speaker 0: but it's like it's really really difficult to You know, it's like find anything in there, you know it, you know Maybe there's something in there that's gonna change your life and you're actually gonna use it every day.
Speaker 0: Good luck finding it.
Speaker 0: You're never gonna come across that, you know.
Speaker 0: And even apps that were like pretty popular like maybe like like a few weeks ago Now they're like they're just as hidden as like all the crap at the bottom.
Speaker 0: So if you you know buy an iPhone like today, you're not gonna find out like Tetris which came out You know, like when the iPhone came out, it's totally hidden I'm sure people who want Tetris search for the world.
Speaker 0: Yes, if you want Tetris you search for it.
Speaker 0: But like if you don't, you know There's other stuff that if you what you're never gonna think.
Speaker 1: at the same time isn't the point that When people go out looking for something to install as opposed to looking for a specific thing They'll install crap that they don't actually use?
Speaker 0: that's exactly correct.
Speaker 0: You know, you shouldn't.
Speaker 0: there's so many people that like hey Are there any cool apps?
Speaker 0: It's like dude.
Speaker 0: don't think like that.
Speaker 0: You should think If when you know don't install anything and then if you need something Then search for what you need as you need it, right?
Speaker 0: That's the way to go about things.
Speaker 0: However, right?
Speaker 0: There are occasions which there is something you need But you just don't know you need it and that that situation does exist and that's they can't be fulfilled Unless you have some sort of way for things that people need but they don't know they need or sort of put in front of Their face every once in a while.
Speaker 0: you know and the app store sort of fails at that and I think it's actually costing a lot of Developers, you know revenues.
Speaker 0: It's like you're making a lot of money in the app store.
Speaker 0: You could be making a lot more.
Speaker 0: people can actually, you know, see your app at some time.
Speaker 1: My only hope is that the the fact that more and more the crap apps are not selling as well At least as far as I could tell.
Speaker 1: based on that article.
Speaker 1: I mean, maybe things will change if there's another surge of iPhone users.
Speaker 0: But
Speaker 1: Apple's gonna have to change something if they want this platform to succeed because while the Android is not an optimal solution either If things continue the way they are I feel like the open platform is going to win out in the end just for the fact that the open platform is gonna have A browser with adblock in it and over-the-air Podcasting
Speaker 0: and I really think that you know The palm is gonna have trouble because it's coming out on spray and it's coming out.
Speaker 0: It's sort of a black time, but if it wasn't coming out on sprint, I would I'd be all about that.
Speaker 0: I think that if the palm at pre is all it's cracked up to be that in the in the you know Mid to longer term it's gonna.
Speaker 0: just it's just gonna hose everything because people are still familiar with palm.
Speaker 0: You know that they still.
Speaker 0: you know, they were all trio users before they were blackberry users, you know They were.
Speaker 0: that's what they were doing.
Speaker 0: and it you know, it's all web-based and you know, there's web developers.
Speaker 0: You know, it's way easier and there's way more of them than there are, you know People who can make freakin objective-c iPhone apps, right?
Speaker 0: So it's it's really got a strong Potential to just blow everything else out and it's gonna.
Speaker 1: it's gonna be real interesting Of course sprint and I left sprint a long time ago for the equally bad Verizon.
Speaker 0: Yeah Verizon's a little better in some ways, but it's also worse in some ways.
Speaker 0: I mean sprint is like, you know, it really has the best pricing and plans $100 for unlimited everything plan.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: I guess it's alright, you know, but Their network, you know, I guess it's supposedly the fastest data network.
Speaker 0: But Verizon at least where we live has the strongest coverage, you know, wherever you go, you're gonna get some bars.
Speaker 0: I mean I got the AT&T and over here.
Speaker 0: I don't get all these bars.
Speaker 1: but anyway time for things of the day.
Speaker 1: now we're talking all about free culture and free media and the thing like the Iconic kind of media of the modern internet generation is the mashup the creative cut, you know People always said yeah, the creative commons is great But like what can you really create that when you're just deriving or making derivative works of stuff that other people have made
Speaker 0: Too bad everything is derivative.
Speaker 1: Well, but even cave painting is derivative, but there are different degrees of derivative.
Speaker 1: There's a difference between writing like a relatively new story or a new take on the story versus writing bamlets.
Speaker 0: Bamlet it's bamlet.
Speaker 1: bamlet is about a man named bamlet whose father is murdered by his uncle.
Speaker 0: That's exactly the same as Hamlet only you changed one letter.
Speaker 1: there are degrees of derivation.
Speaker 1: The key is to make integrated works.
Speaker 1: but anyway I remember way back when Like people Creative Commons licenses were starting to be used more and more and people would argue that if you're just taking Like what's the point of having these share alike licenses?
Speaker 1: who's gonna take geek nights and remix it into techno or crap like that?
Speaker 1: Well, if you've never gotten how good a mashup can be Check out this video.
Speaker 1: this is just a mashup of like YouTube videos of people playing instruments and they make a Song that is better than a lot of commercial music out there that I've paid money for.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's just.
Speaker 1: it's fantastic and the visuals and I Really like this.
Speaker 1: this like this is fake.
Speaker 1: This is great.
Speaker 1: And I don't know what else I can say about it except that it's great.
Speaker 0: It's pretty great.
Speaker 0: I just want to clarify one thing.
Speaker 0: is that the Cheryl the share alike clause on the Creative Commons licenses Specifically has.
Speaker 0: it has many uses but one specific use it has is it prevents people from DRM in your shit.
Speaker 0: It's like if we put out an episode of geek nights.
Speaker 0: if we have a share alike on there Then you could take geek nights and give it to your friends.
Speaker 0: But you could not take geek nights and put a DRM on it and then put it on your website.
Speaker 0: You couldn't do that.
Speaker 0: And if you like remixed geek nights, you couldn't put DRM on that either.
Speaker 0: Yep, so that's that's one thing the share alike does.
Speaker 0: that's that's a reason to have it.
Speaker 1: if you don't want people to DRM your Stuff, of course, that's also one thing that you know, there are a lot of different sides to the copyright argument But people don't.
Speaker 1: you can't forget that if you want Things like the Creative Commons license and all these sorts of ways of protecting your work or determining You know giving your work away with certain restrictions the Creative Commons and all these things rely Entirely on copyright law.
Speaker 1: you can't just get rid of copyright law because then you also get rid of all these sorts of free Share with other people like basically, you know since the what the Creative Commons shows right is a copyright law is insane Right.
Speaker 0: It basically means all rights reserved by default.
Speaker 0: So Creative Commons comes in and says, all right Well, you know what?
Speaker 0: All rights are reserved by default.
Speaker 0: I will explicitly only reserve the rights that should be the only ones that are reserved by law.
Speaker 0: So basically you're you're getting rid of.
Speaker 0: you know You're basically getting rid of a bunch of rights so that it's the way it should be.
Speaker 1: I'm of the mind that the the only right you probably shouldn't be able to give up from a copyright or anything.
Speaker 1: any Creative work you've created are moral rights, but I figure everything else you should be able to give it up.
Speaker 1: You should be able to just Creative Commons free whatever but you know what.
Speaker 1: all that aside This this is pretty rockin and I highly recommend you check it out.
Speaker 0: All right, so lately Past, you know week or so.
Speaker 0: I've been not shit talking.
Speaker 0: I've been doing things right and I Was you know, there's a lot of that kind of.
Speaker 0: you know, do stuff crap all over the internet You know like to-do lists and the getting things done and all that kind of crap, right?
Speaker 0: But I came across this one and this one I think is uh is actually pretty nice You know, don't take this too seriously.
Speaker 0: It's just kind of.
Speaker 0: I just want to toss this out there.
Speaker 0: This is the cult of done Manifesto, uh-huh, and they're there.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read to you this manifesto, right?
Speaker 0: Give me a second.
Speaker 0: Okay, number one There are three stages of being not knowing action and completion Except that everything is a draft.
Speaker 0: It helps to get it done.
Speaker 0: Three there is no editing stage For pretending, you know, what you're doing is almost the same as knowing what you're doing.
Speaker 0: So just accept that, you know what you're doing, even if you don't and do it.
Speaker 0: Five banished procrastination.
Speaker 0: if you wait more than a week to get an idea done abandon it.
Speaker 0: I got that one, right?
Speaker 0: Six the point of being done is not to finish but to get other things done.
Speaker 0: Seven once you're done, you can throw it away.
Speaker 0: eight laughs at perfection.
Speaker 0: It's boring and keeps you from being done.
Speaker 0: Nine people without dirty hands are wrong.
Speaker 0: doing something makes you right.
Speaker 0: I Like that one a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like people without dirty hands are wrong.
Speaker 0: doing something makes you right.
Speaker 0: I could talk for ten minutes just about that item.
Speaker 1: that feels a lot like one of them.
Speaker 1: one of the likes like a statement.
Speaker 1: That would be a burning wheel, you know.
Speaker 0: Well here let's talk about at least a little bit that particular item, right?
Speaker 0: So whenever you're like, you know having an argument with someone right, you know, let's say you're arguing with you Can't live ten Pokemon.
Speaker 1: I live ten Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Well Well, not even that.
Speaker 0: but it's like, you know, let's say you're you're discussing.
Speaker 0: I don't know like, you know healthcare or something like that.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like well, I worked in a hospital or you know, I Well, I'm a doctor, you know, I did that.
Speaker 0: that is like that.
Speaker 0: that adds more, you know It really doesn't add that much weight because I can demonstrate lots of people who do things yet.
Speaker 0: No nothing about the thing they do.
Speaker 0: You know other tech people.
Speaker 0: but um, you know it really.
Speaker 0: it really helps you out in it especially arguing with people.
Speaker 0: anyway Ten failure counts is done.
Speaker 0: So do mistakes.
Speaker 0: Eleven destruction is a variant of done Twelve.
Speaker 0: if you have an idea and publish it on the internet that counts as a ghost of done.
Speaker 0: Thirteen done is the engine of more.
Speaker 0: so I Kind of like this.
Speaker 1: so they do stuff.
Speaker 0: Yes, you want to be done.
Speaker 0: Don't worry about making mistakes.
Speaker 0: Don't worry about perfection.
Speaker 1: It's like the nano remote, you know, just just write your novel you can fix it later whatever but just write it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everything is a draft.
Speaker 0: Just fucking do do do do don't you know?
Speaker 0: slow down don't waste your time?
Speaker 0: You know don't you know, I guess you can write about your idea on the internet first.
Speaker 0: But that's just the ghost you actually had to do it.
Speaker 1: Well, you know Neil Gaiman even say, you know He always.
Speaker 1: he said that thing about how an idea is worth nothing because the implementation of an idea is the only thing that matters.
Speaker 1: Everyone has ideas, but no one acts on them.
Speaker 0: Yep And also it's either do or do do and also being able to act on them.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean You know any schmuck can come up with the idea for like the best novel ever.
Speaker 0: Can I schmuck actually write that best novel?
Speaker 0: No, so, you know Neil Gaiman is basically.
Speaker 0: that quote was when people were you know Submitting ideas for novels to him and he's basically like look your ideas are worth.
Speaker 0: Nothing.
Speaker 0: There's a million ideas.
Speaker 0: I'm the one who has the rare and valuable skill of being able to turn your idea into a best-selling book.
Speaker 0: Therefore your idea is worth nothing.
Speaker 0: you give me an idea and I turn it into a book.
Speaker 0: you get nothing.
Speaker 0: I get millions of dollars Because your idea is worthless.
Speaker 0: ideas are cheap and everyone has a million of them.
Speaker 1: so We're not gonna talk about this too long.
Speaker 1: This is one of those like overview shows where we'll think of all the shows we might want to do about it in the future.
Speaker 1: But I was.
Speaker 0: it's one of those shows.
Speaker 0: we didn't have it.
Speaker 0: We couldn't come up with something.
Speaker 0: It's the last minute.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, but it's also it's on my mind lately because one of the projects I actually was just put at the head of at Work is that you know Financial firm and we have to have like disaster recovery like if New York City didn't exist tomorrow.
Speaker 1: We have to just come online and be doing business tomorrow like nothing happened.
Speaker 1: So as a result, we have disaster recovery Like we have the ability to funk like every business process.
Speaker 1: We have has a complete backup in some other place and that that like disaster recovery alone.
Speaker 1: But we could do God we could do months and months and months and shows of how to do disaster recovery.
Speaker 1: That's like one of the biggest ITCS things out there, but we're not talking about disaster recovery.
Speaker 1: But the project I'm heading up is this really small thing and the idea is that we're trying to test how well our disaster recovery works in a real-world situation and We figured out the best way to do this is to have everyone important at the company work from home one day a month and try to do their entire job from home.
Speaker 1: and Because I'm in charge of this it means I'm gonna be able to Telecommute a little bit as I test all these different things.
Speaker 1: and you know what?
Speaker 1: Telecommuting is the holy goddamn grail of tech workers.
Speaker 1: It is like we want nothing more than to be able to work from home because as Scott can tell you I would just
Speaker 0: go just buy a cheap gigantic house in the middle of fuck nowhere where there's internet like on the farthest away I could be and still get Internet's.
Speaker 0: and You know I try to make the company pay for that Internet's and get like a t1 to the house.
Speaker 1: because Especially for CS people like Scott like people who are writing code You don't need to be anywhere.
Speaker 1: people give you requirements and code comes out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, you know I get requests sometimes.
Speaker 0: so if you could just call me on the phone I mean, there's no there's no real reason.
Speaker 0: I need to physically be there and I'm so excited about this.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna get to work from home at least once a month to start and then we'll see where this goes.
Speaker 0: But yeah, yeah, so anyway the thing about working from home, right?
Speaker 0: Technologically speaking right is you?
Speaker 0: you have this person who does work and most of their work the vast majority of it is Computer related right some of it will be telephone work some of it might even be paper work But it most of it is computer work And that means you need to somehow get their computer in their house on their normal mundane consumer internet On to the business network as so that it is as if they are sitting at their desk at work.
Speaker 0: and Technologically speaking that is not very easy to do and it is much more difficult to do securely Than it is to do it all.
Speaker 1: but Technologically like we're at a point where it's never been easier to work from home at least for tech workers.
Speaker 1: Well most tech workers, I mean like if you're say you're doing like support like you answer the phones There's really no reason for you to be in an office If all you do is answer phones and take support call the
Speaker 0: reason is to someone keep keep an
Speaker 1: eye on you.
Speaker 1: Well, that's the problem the fundamental thing that's holding back the like work from home of revolution.
Speaker 1: and I say revolution Not lightly because I feel like in a lot of ways it would be a major societal revolution.
Speaker 1: Well, I think if people who don't need to physically commute could work from home And we'd kind of come back to it's like we go back to cottage industry, but it's not really cottage industry It's just you're doing, you know modern integrated work, but you're doing it remotely.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean people talk about like oh if we only had mass transit, right?
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: what if just no one had to get in their car at all?
Speaker 0: think about it telling me that be even better We wouldn't?
Speaker 1: you know the commuting is teleporting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you teleport to work you teleport home and you can make your own sandwich from your own fridge.
Speaker 0: Yep It's definitely I think, you know, definitely a way to go.
Speaker 0: The thing is is that I think there's just a lot of job, you know There's plenty of telecommuters out there, right?
Speaker 0: These people do exist There's plenty of them.
Speaker 0: But I think that there are a huge number of jobs that could be telecommuting and just aren't.
Speaker 1: Now at the same time there are definitely mostly cubicle people there are.
Speaker 1: there are a lot of jobs that can't really you can't Telecommute and even jobs that seem like you could telecommute if you actually telecommuted full-time.
Speaker 1: It would probably break down.
Speaker 1: if for nothing else than that There is a certain power to presence and to getting together and I think I did get together once a week.
Speaker 0: You know get together when there's a meeting but when there's not a meeting you don't have to be here.
Speaker 1: Well, the interesting thing is that more technological people and younger generations who are used to this I think are more and more able to get stuff done without having to meet in person.
Speaker 1: I mean like all the younger tech people at my like where I work right now.
Speaker 1: We use the internal company.
Speaker 1: I am all the time like my.
Speaker 1: my boss will say hey call so-and-so and sort out this thing And I'll just be typing.
Speaker 1: and he was like, hey, did you call so-and-so yet?
Speaker 1: And I'm like, yeah, I already worked it out and I am yeah.
Speaker 0: Well here think about this scenario, right?
Speaker 0: Here's a here's an example of a job that can't telecommute right the desktop support guy.
Speaker 0: Sometimes he's got to go plug in a monitor.
Speaker 0: Sometimes he's got to go switch a video card, right?
Speaker 0: That guy needs to be there, right?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: But what if everyone else is telecommuting?
Speaker 0: Well, then you don't need that guy right because there's no desktops in the office But then you have desktops at home your desktops at home.
Speaker 0: So, how do you get this guy to go to everyone's house?
Speaker 0: Which is all over the place if they need desktop support at their house?
Speaker 1: Now the answer is if you're working with technological people you don't you know because they can take care of themselves.
Speaker 0: But what if you send like all your phone salespeople home to telecommute and then you give them all laptops, right?
Speaker 0: What happens?
Speaker 0: those laptops actually break hardware wise.
Speaker 0: they got to mail it back.
Speaker 1: you mail them a new one with well You know what?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know you start.
Speaker 0: those are the kind of problems that will sort of come out at you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they're all solvable.
Speaker 0: No, they are but they're not.
Speaker 0: they're not optimal, you know, it's some are.
Speaker 0: it really depends always a trade-off somewhere.
Speaker 1: I guess I feel like right now like as of today March 9th, you know 2009.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: It's almost 2010.
Speaker 1: Yep, the 90s were like 20 years ago.
Speaker 1: Well the early 90s.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Anyway, if I'm just suddenly feeling really old because I think back to 1990 and it feels like it wasn't that long ago Then I think about what the world was like in 1990 or eight.
Speaker 1: I was eight.
Speaker 1: there weren't cell phones.
Speaker 0: Nope Anyway, there weren't even super intendos.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Maybe there were.
Speaker 0: it was.
Speaker 1: it was close Eight nine, I didn't.
Speaker 1: I don't think there were superintendent anyway, I'm not gonna look that up but I feel like right now Telecommuting for highly skilled technological people who don't need to physically work on physical bits Not only is possible and perhaps trivial but should be encouraged.
Speaker 1: However, I feel like the best way to go about it Absolutely is that say like you're in a position like me like you do primarily like support and computer work and Everything you do is like with a computer and you don't really have to physically interact with anything just with people.
Speaker 1: What if you just telecommute every Friday or every Thursday or once a week?
Speaker 1: So you're still in the office getting all that interaction and you're still getting out of the house.
Speaker 1: You don't turn into like a hikikomori.
Speaker 1: I mean, I've known people who like telecommuted and they like stop going outside Yeah, they stop getting dressed.
Speaker 0: that's definitely a problem that can happen and it's purely a psychological thing.
Speaker 1: But I mean like if I if I when I tell the commute now like I've done it once or twice But if if I'm staying at home, like I'll still like get up and shower and shave and like a dress But if I was telecommuting every day I would probably start waking up later and later and I'd probably just stop shaving And I'd probably stop getting out about like I'd wake up and put on clean pajamas and then move
Speaker 0: When I actually felt nasty You
Speaker 1: know and that.
Speaker 1: and then you start to I don't know you start to blur the work-life boundary unless you're really disciplined.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, I don't know what to do about that.
Speaker 1: yeah, well, I think the best way and I feel like Anyone who's a highly skilled technical worker should lobby for telecommuting if you think your job and get away with it.
Speaker 1: and I think the way to sell it is to offer to do it one day a month and Even offer to make it not be Mondays or Fridays.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that way you could just you know, you'd be able to just in those days.
Speaker 0: You would like work extra hard and you would even you know Like work from the time your commute would steer.
Speaker 0: regular commute would start to the time you would get home Right, and then it's you know, that way you're not.
Speaker 0: you're working actually more time But you're you know away from you know, quote away from home for more time, right?
Speaker 0: For the same amount of time and you're sort of demonstrating to them like look I'm you're getting just as much out of me here.
Speaker 0: is there if not more?
Speaker 0: so there's no there's no reason to make me come Into the office.
Speaker 0: and in fact, you know, if you let me move farther away, I can get a bigger house for less money.
Speaker 0: You know in this bad real estate market You'll you'll get even you know more work for the same amount of money and I'll get more for my money and it works out for everybody.
Speaker 1: well plus I feel like Even if you just like say you did it once a month like one day a month is your telecommuting day.
Speaker 1: It's not a vacation day.
Speaker 1: Like you still have to work then you're still gonna get stuff done.
Speaker 1: But I feel like and it's been my experience with other like working places where other people telecommuted People who have even like that little telecommute like once a month are a thousand times happier at their jobs.
Speaker 0: Mmm, because I mean how many I mean you're all.
Speaker 1: a lot of you are tech people are going into tech.
Speaker 1: How many of you are like sitting at work for like an hour at the end of a day?
Speaker 1: Where you have no more work to do or you're just like your brains fried.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna get anything else done, but you can't just leave you have to stay there and like pretend to work for another couple
Speaker 0: hours, well, I think you know telecommuting really in that sense is Not so much different from you know the flex time thing right and it goes back into the.
Speaker 0: Why do so many employers feel the need to sort of force you to be there from X hour to X hour?
Speaker 0: Should they not instead just force you to get X work done by X deadline and not care how many hours you're in the office and what telecommuting does?
Speaker 0: is it sort of circumvents the employer who demands certain hours and Instead, you know allows you to have flex time even if you don't have it?
Speaker 0: because if you're at home You know.
Speaker 0: if you're at work and you only have five hours of work.
Speaker 0: We had to sit there for eight hours That's three hours.
Speaker 0: You're going to Right If you have a flex time, you can just leave three hours early, but if you're at home You know, you're basically you can work your five hours You get all the same amount of work done throughout the day and you'll just three hours during the day.
Speaker 0: Sometimes you'll just be doing something else at home.
Speaker 0: You'll actually be you know, you'll be able to do your laundry or something Whereas if you're at work those three hours, all you can really do is read slashdot or play solitaire or some play a flash game.
Speaker 0: You can't do anything.
Speaker 1: and I just I feel like it makes people happier and I'd get more work done.
Speaker 1: and Really?
Speaker 1: It still depends on the job.
Speaker 1: like Person - I mean part of the reason you work you know the eight-hour schedule is depending on.
Speaker 1: are they keeping you there because they don't know better?
Speaker 1: because you know, That's the hours.
Speaker 1: Everyone works and they just expect it.
Speaker 1: or are they keeping you there?
Speaker 1: Not because you might not have enough work to do but they're paying you the money.
Speaker 1: They're paying you because they're.
Speaker 1: you're available for when they need you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, you know, for example at my work, right?
Speaker 0: I could be sitting there for like three hours But then like at four thirty, they'll be like I need you to do this thing Like right now, you know at any time they could just be like someone could need something from me or like me.
Speaker 1: The stock market is open from 930 to 4.
Speaker 1: They're paying me to be there from 930 to 4 to make sure stuff doesn't catch on fire while the stock markets open.
Speaker 1: I can't like flex time.
Speaker 1: that I can't be like, yeah, I only have two hours of support work to do So I'll do it on Wednesday.
Speaker 0: That's good stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, do you want to talk about some of the telecommute technologies?
Speaker 1: I think we should because I have it on because I'm actually I'm on support this week Like I'm the go-to guy.
Speaker 1: So right now like, you know, my desk has this gigantic desk in my in like in the geek night studio Which is not a normal sized desk.
Speaker 1: It's it's pretty gigantic.
Speaker 0: It's not even as big as my desk at work.
Speaker 1: Well, you have an unnecessarily large desk at work because they fired everybody.
Speaker 0: What do you want from me?
Speaker 0: I had this.
Speaker 0: I had an even larger desk before they fired everyone.
Speaker 0: my desk at work before they fired Everyone had a mini fridge on it.
Speaker 1: What's even scarier?
Speaker 1: Is that when I worked at IBM?
Speaker 1: I had an office just because there were extra offices.
Speaker 1: Wow And you have to be a certain like band level like there's rules like you have to be level 8 to get a shared But if you're level 9 You're allowed to have an office to yourself.
Speaker 1: and we kind of got around all that because we're in this like if I went like We're on the third floor, right?
Speaker 1: The second floor was identical.
Speaker 1: Sometimes I'd get off on the second floor by accident off the elevator and I'd walk over to my office and that whole floor was like empty.
Speaker 1: So I'd go to like this empty office.
Speaker 1: I'd be like, oh wait and I go back and go up a floor.
Speaker 1: It was kind of cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway, so the first thing right is You mean blackberries?
Speaker 0: I don't know if we should consider, you know, like cell phones and things part of telecommuting work from home.
Speaker 1: That's your available.
Speaker 1: That's a different.
Speaker 0: So, I mean the first thing right is you need like the full-on Work telephone and you know that the the cell phone really doesn't suffice, you know You need to be able to like, you know pick up on.
Speaker 0: you know multiple lines.
Speaker 0: if you have multiple lives need to be able to transfer and Conference right.
Speaker 0: and even if you have like a super work connected blackberry, it really doesn't cut it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so like what my company did I mean just cuz I've got all this on my desk.
Speaker 1: right now I'm looking at my Avaya IP phone.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: it's a real big telephone with the screen out and everything.
Speaker 1: It's like a normal phone.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah before VoIP you really couldn't do that.
Speaker 0: You would have had to like buy a phone line and then they would have to use like some crazy PBX shit, right?
Speaker 0: But now with VoIP like call forwarding and all this like yeah rigmarole with VoIP IP phones It's real easy.
Speaker 0: Just you know, you get a phone uses sip.
Speaker 0: it connects to your works PBX.
Speaker 1: Right now I've got a phone on my desk and it's connected to my work office.
Speaker 0: It's set to do not disturb because I'm like But it's exactly the same as if you had a phone on your desk in the office.
Speaker 1: like literally it ring.
Speaker 1: like if someone calls the support line it rings the same time as the other phones in.
Speaker 1: like my office I Work ring and I can just answer the phone conference.
Speaker 1: I have my three phone lines in it.
Speaker 1: It's encrypted VPN and all that.
Speaker 1: it just works.
Speaker 1: so Being at home is no different than being in the office in terms of dealing with.
Speaker 0: the thing is a lot of companies You know, they have VoIP now.
Speaker 0: It's I mean the last two places I've worked have had VoIP.
Speaker 0: You know one place switched to it.
Speaker 0: The other place had it when I got there.
Speaker 0: Some people like that outsource it to someone else or they set it up poorly and it's a lot of people don't have it Set up right and it's always problematic or tricky or their network is screwy.
Speaker 0: So like VoIP works fine in the office be taken home and odds a big mess.
Speaker 0: now
Speaker 1: the answer to that is Straight up is either be willing to pay the exorbitant amount of money to have an outside firm that's competent do it
Speaker 0: or have smart people or
Speaker 1: Be willing to invest in the people you have To train them to manage it internally because
Speaker 0: hire someone who knows that it's a pastor but
Speaker 1: that's still that's still an investment.
Speaker 1: the idea is that either pay what it costs or Pay what it costs to invest in local talent to do it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Don't try to cheapskate around it or it's gonna suck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz
Speaker 0: I mean, you know even today when the Internet's taken over and phones are sort of going down Really pretty much almost any office, you know phones are like absolutely necessary and mission critical no matter what and you really You know if your phone the more your phones can do for you, you know, the awesome are your businesses, you know if you don't need to like use some weird service to do a conference and if you don't need to You know, yeah, if you have trouble like doing transfers or stuff like that That's really gonna hurt your business in the long run Constant daily frustrations and you know the money you pay for a phone system that works perfectly and has all these features really helps you And people being able to work from home and have a phone that works exactly the same as the one on their desk Perfectly
Speaker 1: not even just for telecommuting.
Speaker 1: but imagine like there's a crazy blizzard.
Speaker 1: Well, alright, if I can't get into work, I'm screwed or I can just work from home because I mean how many people right?
Speaker 0: I mean people at my work do this.
Speaker 0: They'll be like, yeah, I'm working from home today There's a crazy the track transit screwed up.
Speaker 0: or yeah, I got to work from home today But they don't really work from home.
Speaker 0: work from home means don't take don't lose a day of you know Personal day or vacation day, but stay home.
Speaker 0: That's what it means.
Speaker 1: now the other the other phone.
Speaker 0: you can stop people from doing that.
Speaker 0: you call them up.
Speaker 1: Also on my desk right here is the work laptop and I feel like you can do it on your home computer.
Speaker 1: You just VPNs and all that.
Speaker 1: But really the best way.
Speaker 1: if you're a company you want people to telecommute Buy them laptops and give them to them and tell them to take them home.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz I mean that's that's a huge problem.
Speaker 0: is that if you let people VPN with their own equipment, right?
Speaker 0: I mean it works.
Speaker 0: it can be done but it's such an extra chore for the IT people because a you have to support these people installing this crapping and Fingering it on their own machines.
Speaker 0: You have no idea what their machines are and to you got this whole security risk of all these.
Speaker 0: You know, who knows what machines getting on your network?
Speaker 0: You don't want that shit on there.
Speaker 1: I mean I have the ability.
Speaker 1: I use my laptop and my work laptop Like both of them are allowed to get into the corporate network because they know I'm not an idiot Yep, and you do it yourself.
Speaker 0: They don't have to help you do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I installed the Cisco VPN client and I just connect in but it like, you know someone else.
Speaker 0: You can't just let them bring in that like.
Speaker 1: I'll give you the example using my laptop Like I can like find like out skiing or something.
Speaker 1: I have a laptop with me and there's like an emergency and they need me like they blackberry me.
Speaker 1: I can take my laptop and the Verizon card and I can use like the outlook web access to check my email and I can like I can putty and X win and get into the stuff I need to get into.
Speaker 1: but The work laptop has just outlook installed on it and it's already on the domain at work Like I can just authenticate like normal and I can just like exactly the same as sitting at your desk at work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the thing is it's not a portable like.
Speaker 1: it's not a fancy laptop like my laptop.
Speaker 1: I don't carry this work laptop around like I don't carry it in my bag.
Speaker 1: It's a big like giant powerful laptop, but I leave it on my desk at home.
Speaker 1: So
Speaker 0: the only reason it really needs to be a laptop is so that you can carry it home and then carry it back to Work, they can't like give you a desktop to carry home and right
Speaker 1: like when I travel for business I bring my laptop on the plane and I put my work laptop in the luggage Because I'm gonna turn the work laptop on in the hotel room.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna use it like on the go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the battery on the thing only lasts like two hours.
Speaker 1: It's like the mid-range day.
Speaker 0: It's not you know giving someone a laptop because you want it to be portable that they should carry it everywhere with them.
Speaker 0: you're giving it to them because a Laptop is able to be carried home and then you know, it's one thing, you know, it's a lot less chance.
Speaker 0: It's some way, you know, no one has to hook anything up.
Speaker 0: It's a lot easier to support It's a lot easier to have them give it back to you if they quit or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I mean support like imagine trying to support me if like I have a problem connecting with my laptop.
Speaker 1: There'll be a million things.
Speaker 1: I'm admin.
Speaker 1: I could have done whatever I wanted.
Speaker 1: I could have installed a stupid firewall, whatever The work laptop, especially if you use like enterprise or not even enterprise, but just like desktop management software You can push the updates and manage the box remotely, you know group policy Active Directory all that stuff.
Speaker 0: Plus you buy a bunch of uniform laptops, right?
Speaker 1: You know, they all have the exact Yeah, and if someone's laptop breaks you just ship them a new one, you know Like same day and tell them to mail the old one back and just you know image it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if it's a desktop and a monitor and a mouse and a keyboard forget about it.
Speaker 1: It's way too much I guess just the moral is don't underestimate The benefit of having a dedicated separate work laptop.
Speaker 1: or if you're like a consultant or like you work from home for a living Have a separate work computer even if you own both like.
Speaker 1: having the separate computer in the separate monitor Goes like just as someone who works from home a lot.
Speaker 1: It goes a long way toward enforcing the discipline of work.
Speaker 1: is work time.
Speaker 1: play is play time Like I get a lot.
Speaker 0: I mean at the very least, you know whether using Linux or Windows You can have separate accounts to log into that, you know, you log in to the work account, you know and then you're.
Speaker 0: you know, the work user on your machine has totally different stuff from your regular user and Therefore, you know, you can't be like going to click on like.
Speaker 0: there won't be an icon for steam there.
Speaker 0: You know, this is the work account.
Speaker 0: It has an icon for the VPN and the whatever.
Speaker 0: whatever, you know the other worksheet.
Speaker 0: You're out your excels and your whatever you use and I don't know People.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah plus all the work software.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm not gonna own a copy of Visio.
Speaker 1: I would never buy Visio, but I need Visio for work.
Speaker 1: I need it a lot and you know what cuz I have the work laptop.
Speaker 1: I've got Visio.
Speaker 1: Yes And I've got distiller and I've got all those things I need, you know managing licenses, right?
Speaker 0: You're a company.
Speaker 0: you bought a hundred copies of Microsoft Office or you have a you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: you can't you know.
Speaker 0: Let's say someone you know wants to work from home on their own computer.
Speaker 0: You can't just give them Microsoft Office.
Speaker 0: What if they didn't buy it now?
Speaker 0: You got you got some trouble.
Speaker 0: They don't even have Outlook, right?
Speaker 0: So you get you.
Speaker 0: you got.
Speaker 0: it's pretty it's a lot of license trouble to get them a copy of office to install on their Machine legitimately and track those licenses, right?
Speaker 0: But the work laptop allows you to manage your licenses, you know much more easily than letting people telecommute with their own hardware.
Speaker 1: So I think that's enough for now.
Speaker 1: I think that's a good overview of our feelings on this.
Speaker 1: I feel like we could do a show on disaster recovery at some point in the future.
Speaker 1: I feel like we could do a show on like the actual tech of telecommuting or like the actual Societal things about telling you ever
Speaker 0: done a show and just like VPNs
Speaker 1: I don't know if we haven't we should next because that's an easy topic that a lot of people would do well to understand because VPNs you can
Speaker 0: talk about VPNs not only connecting to work but connecting to your house also
Speaker 1: or even things that serve similar purposes like The humble SSH tunnel has like salt like that solves more problems than you can possibly imagine Unless you're someone like us who uses them all the time.
Speaker 1: I know right like every problem I have It's like well, I'll just SSH tunnel it and then it's fine.
Speaker 0: Well you think about that, right?
Speaker 0: It's like there's basically saying the problem doesn't exist because I know the solution.
Speaker 1: Yes, but but at the same time if you don't know that is the solution Firewalls be tricky to set up.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: if you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.