Speaker 1: It's Thursday, February 19th.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is the Geek Nights Book Club.
Speaker 1: Tonight, Ernest Hemingway's A Farewell to Arms.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I've got the judging eye.
Speaker 1: To eyeballs.
Speaker 1: It's uh, so far, there's a lot of judging going on.
Speaker 0: A lot of eyes?
Speaker 1: Not so many eyes, but lots of judging.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, it only does mention one eye.
Speaker 0: It's not the judging eyeballs.
Speaker 0: It's not the judging, uh, you know.
Speaker 1: There are quite a few.
Speaker 1: This is a book and Alex said something.
Speaker 0: Is there a Cyclops in it?
Speaker 1: Not yet, but he said something like this in the forums.
Speaker 1: and now that I've read quite a bit of the book already, but the first few pages pretty much let you in on how awesome it is.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you've read the Prince of Nothing trilogy and you were waiting for the next book, you're kind of, you had expectations.
Speaker 1: I mean, we all knew it's about, Drusus had came in 20 years after the last books ended.
Speaker 1: and that's not a spoiler because throughout the entire Prince of Nothing series, you keep getting quotes from a book that it came in and wrote in the future.
Speaker 1: There's no way that could be a spoiler unless it's an unreliable text, except that that's never been the case.
Speaker 1: No, not in this book at least these books.
Speaker 1: But anyway, it starts out, it hits you right over the head with something pretty awesome and then it just gets better and better and better and all right away.
Speaker 1: It starts out with like the Persian run up to the invasion of Greece.
Speaker 1: You know, but the first books were kind of like crusade.
Speaker 1: This one is like Persia.
Speaker 1: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: But more importantly, the part that I feel is very noteworthy is that our Scott Vacker has done something unprecedented.
Speaker 1: He has made a strong female character.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 1: She, she comes in right away.
Speaker 1: She's got a sword.
Speaker 1: She's out in the wilderness.
Speaker 1: She's bad ass.
Speaker 1: She's the kind of person Luke Crane would hate.
Speaker 0: I think actually that reminds me in the, in the, um, in the mouse guard RPG, it's like, are you the troubled loner?
Speaker 1: If so, minus one, not just that, the troubled loner who's cool and collected and doesn't rely on anyone.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: It's like minus one to you.
Speaker 0: It's basically the, I don't like you.
Speaker 1: Uh, but I expect to be done with this book, I don't know, by Sunday.
Speaker 0: One thing about the book, I didn't read it yet.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Uh, and I'm glad it has the same graphic design as the other one.
Speaker 0: So it fits in.
Speaker 0: But, um, it's, I guess it'd be a spoiler to say what, what.
Speaker 0: it's a new trilogy.
Speaker 0: It's not Prince of nothing book forward, something else book one.
Speaker 0: And I think that's not really the best idea because if you didn't read Prince of nothing one, two, three, I don't think this book is going to work.
Speaker 1: See at the same time it kind of does because it starts out with the same level of what the fuck that the original Prince of nothing did.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And it gives you the history and it does the same kind of referencing things with proper nouns consistently in such a way that if you're smart, you figure it all out.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But I just don't, you know, I can't imagine how the book could be if it was the first one you read.
Speaker 1: Plus got a lot of things.
Speaker 1: do that.
Speaker 1: I mean, Hyperion and Demian, you couldn't read.
Speaker 0: I don't think you could read fall of Hyperion without reading Hyperion first.
Speaker 1: I don't get the impression that you're supposed to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it just seems, it seems wrong.
Speaker 1: How does it seem wrong?
Speaker 1: It's, it's, it basically picks up 20 years later and tells it, it's kind of like death note two and the second half of death note, which also makes no sense if you didn't read the first day.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But that they called that death note too.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But uh, there's some similarities that are surprising and I don't think they were intended, but they kind of stand out because I've read both of these things.
Speaker 1: But uh, yeah, strong female character.
Speaker 1: Kind of surprising.
Speaker 1: Kind of cool.
Speaker 1: Mine is one of the circles.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, um, we've decided if you haven't noticed to sort of change the book club episode schedule, I think the original schedule was supposed to be like every fourth Thursday episode.
Speaker 0: So book club Thursday, Thursday, Thursday book club, right?
Speaker 1: Primarily we just didn't keep track.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well not only did, well I kept track.
Speaker 0: We actually kept to that schedule for until right now and I'm, maybe we, I don't even, I could check, maybe we did keep to the schedule.
Speaker 0: I don't, I don't think so though.
Speaker 0: But um, basically we decided that that was too long because now we're doing only two episodes a week.
Speaker 0: So there's half as many Thursdays.
Speaker 0: So there were half as many books.
Speaker 0: I mean, that would be like one book.
Speaker 0: It'd be like six books a year at the most.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That's not, that wasn't going to work out.
Speaker 0: And so, um, the new schedule, we're not doing it every Thursday.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But the new schedule is when we finish reading the book.
Speaker 1: So I want to preface that by pointing out that we didn't actually get the book until a little while ago.
Speaker 0: So that doesn't mean, you know, I mean, we read fast, faster than a lot of people out there.
Speaker 0: So it'd be sort of unfair if we like, you know, announced the next book, started reading, we'd be doing every Thursday.
Speaker 1: We have these train commutes.
Speaker 1: I mean, I get a novel and I just read it every day until I'm done with it.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So you know, we do, we take our sweet time getting the book, we take our sweet time, you know, starting to read it.
Speaker 0: But once we start to read it, you know, it gets done.
Speaker 1: You're trying to make excuses almost like you're trying to try to make excuses.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to not frighten the listeners away and have them pissed off because they can't, they read slowly.
Speaker 1: But that's still, that's very much the rationalization.
Speaker 1: I'll paraphrase.
Speaker 0: That's actually what I'm trying to do.
Speaker 1: I will paraphrase what you said into the terms that a non callous would hear.
Speaker 1: I'm so awesome that I apologize to you for the fact that I am in fact so much more awesome than you are.
Speaker 1: I will enumerate the ways in which I am awesome while all the same while making sure that you feel bad about not being nearly so awesome as I am.
Speaker 1: Allow me to reiterate how awesome I am.
Speaker 0: Well, your translation is so accurate.
Speaker 0: It was in fact 100% accurate.
Speaker 0: But basically that's, I think that's the ongoing problem with the book club is that the goal is to make people read, read a book, read a book, right?
Speaker 0: But people don't.
Speaker 0: So we could, if we just did, you know, sort of threw them in the pool, you know, just like tossed them off the high dive, you know, and said, well, you don't read at all.
Speaker 0: Do you?
Speaker 0: No, you don't start reading exactly the way we read, read real quickly and read really hard books and get everything and comprehend them one and almost 100% on the first go.
Speaker 0: People wouldn't be able to do it and they wouldn't like these episodes.
Speaker 0: They wouldn't get anything out of them and they wouldn't read the books.
Speaker 0: You know, that's why we want to give people enough time to read, to not be scared away, but we also don't want to read so slowly that, you know, the episodes just never come out ever.
Speaker 0: So the new schedule is we finish.
Speaker 0: the books are, you know, we will read the book and finish it.
Speaker 0: And then the next Thursday after that, we will do the episode.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: But there will be at least one, uh, non book club Thursday in between each.
Speaker 0: So you'll never get two book club episodes in a row.
Speaker 0: That's not going to happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Of course, Thursdays are kind of up in the air anyway, so we can do whatever on a Thursday.
Speaker 0: We're also having trouble with Thursday episodes lately.
Speaker 1: I got plenty.
Speaker 1: I got a lot in the hopper.
Speaker 0: All right, Mr Hopper.
Speaker 1: I got a hopper, Mr Hooper.
Speaker 1: But anyway, let's just get right into this with things of the day.
Speaker 1: So, uh, way back at RIT, I can't recall exactly when.
Speaker 1: I can't recall if it was a telecaster or a Stratocaster, but I do remember that at one point, Scott made a joke that apparently it revealed the fact that only myself, you're making that your thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Yes, I'm making that my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: It's news, not a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: No, the thing it's, it's worth being the thing of the day, but it revealed to me that only myself and the two Scotts, the Rubin and the Johnson had actually seen 2010 the movie or read the book.
Speaker 0: A lot of people don't even know it exists.
Speaker 0: They don't realize, like people know if you say 2001 is space out as they go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that movie would go and the monolith and how 9,000 famous Zarathustra.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Famous movie, right?
Speaker 0: But they don't know.
Speaker 0: it had like a sequel 2010 and another was sequel with like 20.
Speaker 0: There's some other number that was bigger than 2010.
Speaker 0: But you know, the thing is I've never read the books, but I've seen the first two movies, 2001 and 2010.
Speaker 0: And at the end of 2010, it says, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Speaker 1: So we're sitting around, I believe it was over a Krispy cream.
Speaker 1: I believe that is when the comment was made.
Speaker 1: Because as I recall, someone said something like, take anyone you want, but don't take the Boston cream.
Speaker 1: That one's mine.
Speaker 1: And Scott looks up and says, all these can be yours, except Europa.
Speaker 1: And the other Scott and I crack up and everyone else looks at him like, what the fuck?
Speaker 0: No, no one got my joke.
Speaker 0: And I thought it was brilliant.
Speaker 0: It, it, it became a meme in the crew pretty much to me in the pretty much any, any time anyone ever said, you know, pick any one of these or, you know, take anyone you want, you know, or anything like that.
Speaker 0: I always, I made the Europa joke.
Speaker 0: I was like, except Europa.
Speaker 0: And then I even made a Photoshop, well, a gimp of, uh, you know, I took the old man from Zelda one, you know, says, he says, take anyone you want.
Speaker 0: Is it the heart container and the red potion and Europa?
Speaker 0: And I just added in Europa and I wrote, except Europa.
Speaker 1: Now, of course, if you haven't seen the movie, you might be, yes, this is a joke.
Speaker 0: At the end of 2010, basically the message is at the end of the movie and you'll understand why.
Speaker 0: there's a message if you watch the movie, but the message is, you know, all these planets are yours, uh, except Europa attempt, no landing there.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Use them together.
Speaker 1: Use them in peace.
Speaker 1: It's, it's a very uplifting, if slightly cheesy ending to that movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so it turns out that humanity has doomed itself because we are now sending a mission to Europa.
Speaker 0: Well, we're not going, we're not attempting landing.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: So I guess we'll talk on a technicality.
Speaker 0: We got to hope that the all intelligent alien thing is in reality, Europa is a big ball of ice.
Speaker 0: So, uh, really, I'm not worried, honestly, really.
Speaker 0: It's not, it's not troubling.
Speaker 1: So this article was posted on slash dot, which I go to more and more because it's slash dot is becoming the Byzantium of the internet.
Speaker 0: It's strange.
Speaker 0: It's like all the people who are just filling slash that with crap left and went to dig in other places.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And slash dot is gets the news a lot slower than he used to.
Speaker 0: And it's not what it used to be, but it's still, you know, it's still big enough.
Speaker 1: She ain't what she used to be.
Speaker 0: She used to be, it's still big enough to carry on with momentum.
Speaker 0: But the thing is the comment sections.
Speaker 0: it's actually, you know, because if you think about it, other sites have comment moderation, like dig and such and bark kinda, but it's not like slash dot slash dots.
Speaker 0: Moderation is still where it's at.
Speaker 0: And because a lot of the people have left slash, I don't care about it anymore.
Speaker 0: The news is old, but the comments are like the best comments ever.
Speaker 1: But it really is for me now in terms of posting on the internet, like Byzantium.
Speaker 1: And I guess our forum is like, I don't know, I'm not going to extend that metaphor any further, but it, it lost some of its former glory, but it's still there, still plugging and all these other States sprung up around it like dig, but they're all crap and full of barbarians and they collapse.
Speaker 1: I mean, dig collapsed under its own weight.
Speaker 0: It's a useless garbage site now as far as I'm having been to dig and like it's a long time.
Speaker 1: It is dig at this point, in my opinion, is worthless.
Speaker 1: It is absolute garbage.
Speaker 1: It provides nothing new, nothing interesting.
Speaker 1: There is, I'd rather read YouTube comments than read the comments on dig, but slash dot has maintained.
Speaker 1: It's like this walled garden.
Speaker 1: And that's,
Speaker 0: if you're looking to read comics, you know, if you're looking for comments, if you're looking for the actual news, you know, well,
Speaker 1: FARC still reliably
Speaker 0: Google news in gadget sites like that can give you the news news
Speaker 1: and Kotaku will give you the funny and BB spot surprisingly still has good a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: ish things.
Speaker 1: But I want to point out that on slash dot, this was announced Europa targeted as selected as target of next flagship mission.
Speaker 1: And of course the first comment is something about the first post is all these worlds are yours except Europa.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Attempt no landing there.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 1: The second post, which made me laugh out loud, first post together, first post in peace.
Speaker 1: I'm so proud of you.
Speaker 1: Slash dot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see, that's a, that's quality.
Speaker 1: The first post on dig would just be like some gibberish about chiropractic conspiracies from the other side of Ron Paul's ass.
Speaker 1: Attempt no landing there.
Speaker 0: I plan not to attempt landing perhaps with a boots.
Speaker 0: That wouldn't be a landing.
Speaker 0: That would be more of a crash and impact to some kind.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: That's all I've got.
Speaker 1: That's my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: All right, so check this out.
Speaker 0: Somebody is making a, um, an independent movie, right?
Speaker 0: And, um, it's going to be in theaters and on DVD and the whole thing, it's a real deal film production.
Speaker 0: You know, it's not some joke.
Speaker 0: It's not some, you know, amateur YouTube thing.
Speaker 0: This is a real deal indie movie.
Speaker 0: It's not a real deal blockbuster, but it's a real deal indie movie, right?
Speaker 0: And you can contribute to this movie.
Speaker 0: You, yes, you who was listening to the show, you can, if you want to contribute to this movie in some way, all you have to do is go to the website and read.
Speaker 0: And, um, I don't really need to tell you what the movie's about.
Speaker 0: Cause if I tell you the title of the movie, which has already been decided, and by the way, it's a documentary, um, you will know everything you need to know.
Speaker 0: The name of the movie is the people versus George Lucas.
Speaker 0: And, uh, the website I think is like people versus.
Speaker 0: just give me a link to the website on our site.
Speaker 0: So you're all set.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Once a long time ago, we got an email from a listener who, you know, it was one of those long emails, like the email that's like, you know, long time listener, first time emailer, you know, all that rigmarole.
Speaker 0: It's like, really?
Speaker 0: I didn't know that.
Speaker 1: But I remember very clearly that this person pointed out to us that it was often difficult to hear the names of websites and URLs in the podcast.
Speaker 1: And I was like, have you ever been to our website?
Speaker 1: And they responded with the best response I've ever gotten from someone like that.
Speaker 1: Three characters.
Speaker 1: Oh, H period.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: If you're someone who like found, uh, you know, this podcast through iTunes and you subscribe to an iTunes and you've never been to our website, it's a, it's a crappy WordPress.
Speaker 1: That's going to be replaced by the awesome beta site that isn't out yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But go to front row crew.com.
Speaker 0: Oh, look, I said a URL in the show while talking about saying URLs in the show.
Speaker 1: Actually, I, I, I surprised someone at work the other day.
Speaker 1: I was on the phone with some guy from like Verizon, you know, circuit thing.
Speaker 1: And he wanted the circuit ID.
Speaker 1: So I just gave it to him in the NATO phonetic.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: He, he was taken aback one by the fact that I did it so quickly.
Speaker 1: And two, by the fact that he couldn't keep up with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I was kind of saddened by that.
Speaker 0: The, uh, the IT guy at my, uh, who they got rid of, you know, big Mike at my work, he used to eat Mike.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Big Mike.
Speaker 1: Is that like Mitch?
Speaker 0: You know how many mics there were at my, actually he was sort of a similar guy to Mitch and some, he had some similarities to Mitch, but not too many.
Speaker 0: Um, there were a lot, there were like five or six mics at my work.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 0: So he was one of the mics, but he's not there with us.
Speaker 1: It's Jeff's.
Speaker 1: We have a million Jeffs and they all work in the development side.
Speaker 1: So it's tough.
Speaker 1: Cause we, it's like, you know, it's funny at my worst thing is two of them are in QA.
Speaker 1: So it's like, it used to be, I'd be like, so who do you want?
Speaker 1: Dev Jeff or QA Jeff.
Speaker 1: And then he's like, there's two QA Jeffs.
Speaker 1: Which one?
Speaker 0: I think I said this before, but if you don't count the people that acquired us, if you only count, you know, our part of the company, you know, when I got there, there were like 20 something people there.
Speaker 0: There are only five people who've been at our part of the company longer than me at this point.
Speaker 0: I've only been there two years and four of those five people are named Mike.
Speaker 1: You've got a, you're, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I could go in a lot of directions with that.
Speaker 1: I'm just going to let it be.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So we read a book.
Speaker 1: I hope you're right.
Speaker 0: But anyway, yeah.
Speaker 0: The it guy, Mike, he used to always do, you know, the NATO phonetic because he used to, he was in the military.
Speaker 1: Do you know what the NATO phonetic, do you know it?
Speaker 1: Do you know the old world war II phonetic, the Abel Baker one?
Speaker 0: I don't know the Abel Baker one.
Speaker 1: I don't know what either.
Speaker 0: It's not that usually it's a lot.
Speaker 0: Mostly you do a Greek letters like alpha Bravo.
Speaker 1: It's alpha Bravo, Charlie Delta, echo Foxtrot, ghost hotel.
Speaker 0: I only know some of them.
Speaker 0: I know some of them.
Speaker 1: Thing is I only know like inherently and correctly all the letters that tend to be in circuit IDs with major like internet service providers.
Speaker 0: All you really need to know is abcdef cause.
Speaker 0: then you can do hex codes and you're all, you can do anything.
Speaker 1: But anyway, we read a book.
Speaker 1: I hope you did.
Speaker 0: I read the book.
Speaker 1: now as we always do with these book clubs, we're going to assume that you have read Ernest Hemingway's a farewell to arms.
Speaker 1: So my arms, if you have time, I'm making that joke.
Speaker 1: The whole episode is not, I would recommend, I mean you could listen.
Speaker 0: We're going to spoil a book where the statute of limitations ran out before I was born, but we're also going to be very careful just in case someone assigns you this book for your class in high school or whatever.
Speaker 0: This episode we're going to make sure it does not substitute for reading the book.
Speaker 0: And in fact we should say some things that are wrong just to throw people off.
Speaker 0: So they'll get bad grades on their tests that they try to listen instead of reading.
Speaker 1: A farewell to arms is a sequel to a book called old man in the sea.
Speaker 1: It's about a man who was a fisherman.
Speaker 1: Now he loses his arms in a horrible fishing accident and then gets sent to world war one.
Speaker 1: And now this proves difficult because he has no arms.
Speaker 0: Okay, that was a little too extreme.
Speaker 0: Too obvious.
Speaker 1: It's bad that I saw that episode of south park as I was reading this book again.
Speaker 1: So all I can think when I think of Hemingway is there is an old man and he goes out into the sea to get some fish, but he cannot get the fish.
Speaker 0: No, he cannot get the fish.
Speaker 1: And then he gets the fish, but then the shark gets the fish and he has no fish.
Speaker 0: So how many Hemingways have you read?
Speaker 1: I have read, well I've read most of his short stories and I've read a farewell to arms and at least the sun rises.
Speaker 0: I read, well you mean the sun also rises.
Speaker 1: Yes, I made my joke.
Speaker 1: The joke I always made.
Speaker 0: I read a, I read old man in the sea and sun also rises.
Speaker 0: This is my number three Hemingway.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: This was actually my first Hemingway.
Speaker 1: It's interesting.
Speaker 0: I read, I never read this before.
Speaker 0: I've only read it once and I finished it like last night.
Speaker 1: It's interesting.
Speaker 1: I read it when I was pretty young and like I thought I got it and I liked it and then I was assigned it in school.
Speaker 1: It was like, Oh, once again, a book I've already read.
Speaker 1: How, uh, how wonderful.
Speaker 0: But you know, just to talk about Hemingway in general, right?
Speaker 0: First of all, the obviousness, right?
Speaker 0: Is that he has very simple pros.
Speaker 0: You know, he doesn't use lots of big words.
Speaker 0: He doesn't use lots of complex sentences.
Speaker 1: It's a very distinct style that I like.
Speaker 0: He doesn't use lots of punctuation.
Speaker 1: Now coming from captain semi-colon, you might be surprised that I like Hemingway's pros, but it's, I wouldn't say, I mean, you know, it's functional.
Speaker 0: It works.
Speaker 1: Not only that, but I would say it really, it puts you in a different mindset when you read a Hemingway versus like the Prince of nothing or Hawthorne.
Speaker 1: I mean, Hawthorne is just, you know, four paragraphs of illusion to describe the color of the letter.
Speaker 0: It also really helps because that's part of the reason I was able to burn through the book so fast and get it done for in time for the episode.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 0: Um, the other thing about Hemingway is that it's very, uh, manly,
Speaker 1: you know, I know in high school, if you're in high school, they're going to make you read farewell to arms or I expect they will because it's like,
Speaker 0: or something along one of the Hemingway, you read Hemingway at some point.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: But most people I know read farewell to arms in high school.
Speaker 1: I ended up my high school actually assigned.
Speaker 1: the sun also rises, but they always will talk about the code hero, you know, the Hemingway code hero in this book.
Speaker 1: They always talk about how, well, the main character wasn't the code hero this time.
Speaker 1: He wanted to be, he like, he was on the cusp of it, but he wasn't truly, and the girl was the code hero and this is a big upstart and she's more modern progressive and they always say code hero code hero.
Speaker 1: And if you read the cliff's notes, they'll probably say something like the code hero was and name a character and then the list, like the bullet points of what a code hero was.
Speaker 1: I prefer to call them the Hemingway hero, much like the gecky guy hero.
Speaker 0: Now Hemingway, how does that relate to, um, what's it called?
Speaker 0: That manga, the, the ikigami manga, which one is that?
Speaker 1: I just, I really want Hemingway hero has good alliteration.
Speaker 1: I feel like it's a much better way to put forth the idea than the code hero, but I digress.
Speaker 1: It is interesting though, you know, high school aside that Catherine was the Hemingway hero of this and the main character wasn't at all.
Speaker 1: He was sentimental and he cared and he couldn't really deal with it.
Speaker 1: And he, of course he did drink a lot.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, that was actually surprised because you know, in a sun also rises, they fucking drink.
Speaker 0: It's like they're in Spain drinking wine by the bottle.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I remember I didn't notice like the extent of that until it was in high school and a teacher pointed out, you know, she diagrammed all that they had drunk.
Speaker 0: But I remember very distinctly when I read that I read sun also rises for school and I was like, it, I was reading it like one of the early chapters, like they went to a bar and it was like, yeah, it's like, you know, X bottles.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, well, did they just call it bottles or something?
Speaker 0: And it's like, no, really?
Speaker 0: They're actually drinking entire bottles instead of glass.
Speaker 0: You know, where normal people would drink a glass, they drink an entire bottle per person.
Speaker 0: I'm like, yeah, there's something going on here.
Speaker 0: He's getting wasted.
Speaker 1: But farewell to arms.
Speaker 1: It's more, the drinking kind of accelerates throughout the book.
Speaker 1: I mean, the point where he gets jaundice and I point out that that is right after he finds out Catherine's pregnant and it, it kind of, it kind of subtly implies, implies a lot.
Speaker 1: And there are implications that perhaps he is drinking more because of the fact that she is pregnant and he can't deal with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like, you never really see like what the people are thinking, you know, all you see is what they're doing and what they're saying kind of, and you know, the, the, you know, the, everything else is implied,
Speaker 1: you know, and that like some of my favorite scene, like the scene, there's a couple of times, especially early on where Catherine and Henry have sex and it has never stated there is no, and then he had sex with her sentence.
Speaker 1: There's no like description.
Speaker 1: There's no anything.
Speaker 1: There is just a series of dialogue between the two characters and everything else is implied a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: There is, there is nothing to tell you what is going on in a lot of scenes other than the fact that the dialogue hints at it.
Speaker 1: And that, that really puts you in a different mindset from the typical novel that you're reading.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's no scene, there's no nothing.
Speaker 1: There's just two characters kind of having this pretty realistic, not like terse conversation while they are doing something.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: And actually I think because, you know, the only way you really get to know any of the characters is through their dialogue.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And I think that actually, I think that this, the number one strength of the book is that how, you know, the, how deep and how fleshed out the characters are.
Speaker 0: Like they feel like real people, like people, you know, or you know, someone like that, or you, you can really imagine what the people are like, especially like Rinaldi.
Speaker 0: He's a, he's a big character.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The funny guy.
Speaker 1: He's like almost a Hemingway hero.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But it's like.
Speaker 0: the only way you can, you know, tell what the people are like is because you see them talk.
Speaker 0: like the way Rinaldi talks is how, you know, he's like the foodie guy.
Speaker 1: Come on, have a drink with me, baby.
Speaker 0: Are you all right?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: He's a funny Italian guy.
Speaker 0: He's having a good time.
Speaker 1: He's having a good time.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, like, you know, it's that stereotypical Italian guy way.
Speaker 1: It's like, he's got his own masculinity.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But, uh, you know, and it's sort of like you get to know the characters in the book, not through some description, like, Oh, this guy, you know, he was, uh, you know, some sort of third party saying, Oh yeah, that guy loved to get drunk and, uh, get with the women.
Speaker 0: And he was, you know, real loose, but inside he was, no, it's, you get to know them by what they say.
Speaker 0: And it says, if you met them in real life and you get to know them the way you get to know a person in real life, you know, you talk to them.
Speaker 0: It's
Speaker 1: weird how you get this kind of duality where on one hand, Hemingway, he like, he pulls you into this first person perspective at times where you're, if you imagine yourself as the character you're experiencing, because it'll shift between long sequences of just dialogue, character, a dialogue, character B or long sequences of dialogue where you can't even always tell who is saying what.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Sometimes, because usually, you know, the, the, what's it called?
Speaker 0: The, um, the way you're supposed to do it is you put a carriage return when you change people who are talking, right.
Speaker 0: But sometimes it'll throw you off.
Speaker 0: Like, there'll be a paragraph and then there'll be some talking and it's like, wait, which one is who?
Speaker 0: And then you have to figure it out and then go back and look at the alternation.
Speaker 1: And, but you don't usually have to figure it out.
Speaker 1: Cause it's almost always obvious or it didn't matter.
Speaker 1: Like, yeah, like it's a whole bunch of soldiers talking and you are like, you know, there, you, someone says something, he's making fun of the priest.
Speaker 1: The priest says something.
Speaker 1: It's obvious.
Speaker 1: It's the priest saying something.
Speaker 1: And then every time it comes back to your man talking, you know him because he's the only character you have a different perspective on.
Speaker 1: You get his autobiographical discussion of himself, but you still don't get his thoughts.
Speaker 1: You don't get into his head.
Speaker 0: All you get when you get, you get basically some, you know, you get some things that he's thinking, right?
Speaker 0: Like he'll say, uh, I wished something, something.
Speaker 1: Yes, but it's indirect.
Speaker 1: It's not what's in his head.
Speaker 1: It's what he is telling you about what was in his head.
Speaker 1: Everything is filtered through him.
Speaker 1: And that is what really makes these, but like, that's what I love about Hemingway and especially about farewell to arms.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So what's it actually about?
Speaker 0: Well, you got this guy, he's a British American.
Speaker 0: So he's, he's, he's a United States citizen, but he's of, you know, he's a Hemingway expat.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: He is in Italy during world war one in the Italian army.
Speaker 0: It doesn't explain how that happened.
Speaker 0: It just did.
Speaker 1: I love his answer is something like it.
Speaker 1: I got here.
Speaker 1: I'm here yet.
Speaker 0: He's there.
Speaker 1: It happens.
Speaker 0: He's in the Italian army and he's a Lieutenant.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But they call him tenant date.
Speaker 0: Actually took me like, you know, like a minute to realize that today was an tenant.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Cause they, all the other, you know, uh, ranks, they actually say major or Colonel, but for Lieutenant, they say tenant day.
Speaker 1: They use the Italian word, but the way they use the Italian word too, you get, you always feel like it's being used with affection.
Speaker 1: But part of that is because everyone likes him because he's a pretty likable guy and he can't, he's, he's stoic and he cares about his, he puts himself in danger to help the people around him.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Basically he's not like a Lieutenant of, you know, infantry or bombers or anything like that.
Speaker 1: Do we really need to, I mean, I'm just summarizing, but we're assuming everyone read it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no, but, uh, I just want to, you know, for the sake of it.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Summarize away.
Speaker 0: So, you know, he's the Lieutenant of the ambulance, one group of ambulances, you know, they drive out, they bring back a bunch of wounded people.
Speaker 0: That's what they do.
Speaker 0: And, uh, you know, war of course is test sock and, uh, you know, things get crappy, but he gets to this woman, uh, that, you know, this British, uh, nurse basically, who's in one of the hospitals nearby.
Speaker 0: And then he gets injured and he's able to spend a lot of time with her and, you know, Hey, Hey, Hey, spend a lot of time with her while in bed, pretty much all day.
Speaker 0: And then he has to go back to war and everything sucks.
Speaker 0: And then he escapes and then the book is over.
Speaker 0: I got to admit when I, when I was a kid, I'm giving you the, uh, South Park old man in the sea summary.
Speaker 1: There was a Ming and he went out, there was a man, he went to the war, he drove the ambulance.
Speaker 0: He met the lady, he got injured.
Speaker 0: He met the lady a whole lot more.
Speaker 0: Then he went back to the war, no lady, but then he ran away from the war and back with the lady.
Speaker 0: And then the lady, she died.
Speaker 0: The end.
Speaker 1: I got to admit that like when I was reading the book the first time, I, I appreciate this book a lot more, just being older and having more perspective.
Speaker 0: I could definitely, when I was reading it, I was like, wow.
Speaker 0: If I had read this, like when I was younger, I wouldn't have gotten anything out of it.
Speaker 0: I got a lot, sort of, if you're one of those people, like maybe when you were young, you read Hemingway or you were assigned it in school and you hated it, maybe, you know, don't discount reading it again.
Speaker 0: Now that you're older and wiser because it takes an adult to sort of get this book.
Speaker 1: But I still remember distinctly as a kid, I'm reading this book and it was interesting and it was Hemingway and I knew the deal with Hemingways.
Speaker 1: I'm going through it.
Speaker 1: And the point where the carbonary come out and they're going to shoot him.
Speaker 1: And suddenly he runs away.
Speaker 1: Like I remember I read past that part and I got to the end of the chapter.
Speaker 1: I stopped and I was like, wait a minute.
Speaker 1: What the fuck?
Speaker 1: And I went back.
Speaker 1: He's like, no, he ran away.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like he, cause it was so quick.
Speaker 0: It was like in one sentence was like, he ran out the door, he jumped in the water and I was trying to imagine like, how could he possibly jump in the water and make it?
Speaker 0: And they're like, it was some sort of river, but it was, it wasn't, I was like, what the, I didn't get it, but he escaped in the river by, you know, staying underwater as much as he could.
Speaker 0: And I guess they shot at him, but it didn't hit him.
Speaker 0: It was, I was trying to imagine that action scene.
Speaker 1: It didn't really work, but you know, he got away one guns back then, especially pistols, not that accurate.
Speaker 1: In fact, that's kind of four, not really foreshadowed, but it is noted several times up to this point that pistols are not that accurate.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Pretty much any time, you know, they're talking about pistols.
Speaker 0: It's like, I want one that's actually going to work.
Speaker 0: I want one that can actually hit something.
Speaker 1: It's weird because on one hand, he like, I love how Rinaldi didn't even want to carry a pistol.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And he, he was practicing with the pistol and it took him a while.
Speaker 0: Cause it was very, you know, it's not easy to shoot.
Speaker 1: What was the line?
Speaker 1: I forget.
Speaker 1: It's something like actually using the pistol, remove any illusion.
Speaker 0: What was it called?
Speaker 0: There was a, it was, they talked about a guy who carried a rifle, even though his, he was a higher ranking officer.
Speaker 0: And the reason he carried the rifle was that he wouldn't look like an officer to the enemy.
Speaker 0: So they wouldn't go after him.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is also he could actually shoot people with it and he did and it saved his life.
Speaker 1: It's a, I really, I'm going to assume that you all know the basic history of world war one, but in case you don't, it was a rough war.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Rough is the word.
Speaker 0: I mean, most people think about world war one.
Speaker 0: They think about, you know, like the Western front with the, you know, the, um, you know, the, the trenches and France and Germany, right.
Speaker 0: That whole area, but they don't really know a lot about the other parts.
Speaker 0: Like people don't know about Gallipoli and shit.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's not something most people know.
Speaker 1: Well, most people don't really even know world war one at all.
Speaker 1: Like they, they know, yeah.
Speaker 0: Archduke Ferdinand assassinated world war one and then it was over.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's, and the thing is, you know, there aren't really world war one veterans left.
Speaker 0: I mean, if there are any, there's like a handful and that's it.
Speaker 1: So actually Fark, every time a world war one veteran dies, they whip out the hero tag.
Speaker 1: I don't recall if the last one died or not.
Speaker 0: I remember I went to a museum.
Speaker 0: There was a temporary exhibit, I think in new Haven about with some world war one stuff and they had some audio interviews with world war one veterans.
Speaker 1: Actually the most fascinating thing I've, I spent, this is a couple of weeks ago.
Speaker 1: I was randomly looking around and I found this archive of photos from world war one that were colorized by experts basically too.
Speaker 1: So you could really see it.
Speaker 1: because it's weird looking at a war like world war one, you always kind of picture it in black and white.
Speaker 1: Same thing with world war two to a degree.
Speaker 1: And it almost feels like history, but not real history.
Speaker 1: It's weird.
Speaker 1: Like you don't get that visceral reality that real people were there.
Speaker 1: that hits you until you see it in color, like real color.
Speaker 0: Even if I think about like seventies and eighties history.
Speaker 0: I mean, I was alive in the eighties, but I sort of remember the eighties and sort of like, you know, that sort of grainy washed out color of like a Polaroid or bad, you know, analog is either that ultra saturated or that kind of technique color.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like you remember things in the color of the recording media that we have and not in full real life color, but seriously seeing photos of world war one in color is a, is a visceral experience.
Speaker 1: It really puts you in the, in the, these kids places.
Speaker 1: And this book in particular, if you don't know much about world war one, it really, really like shows you and gives you a good sense of what it was like to be on that front.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's Hemingway.
Speaker 1: It spends a lot of time talking about just the harsh reality of walking down a clogged road.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like a lot of the stuff in the book isn't really, it doesn't have anything to do with like the main story.
Speaker 0: It's like you read the main story.
Speaker 1: It's just the love story.
Speaker 0: You read something like, I don't know, Lord of the rings.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And pretty much all the words in the book are either poetry.
Speaker 0: I guess maybe Lord of the rings wasn't the best example, but they're serving the purpose of telling you the story of, you know, bringing the rings of Mount.
Speaker 0: do most of the words, Tom Vomitel.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But, uh, in this book, most of the words are not serving to tell you the story.
Speaker 0: they're serving to just show you the world or make tangential points and to show you the war.
Speaker 0: And they're just, you know, illustrating these scenes to deliver them to you to make you feel them.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, it's, these scenes aren't separate.
Speaker 1: Like there's the base.
Speaker 1: loves the story of the book, you know, the love story guy meets girl has baby and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: But there is the separate, I think equally prominent story of a man who fought in a war.
Speaker 1: and you know, there's all that talk, all the different people, you know, the people who fight in the war because they don't know better.
Speaker 1: The people who don't find a fight in the war, but they're forced to by the people who know better, the people who want to fight the war, but they get other people to do it for them.
Speaker 1: And the fact that no one really wants to actually be in this war.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They definitely concentrate on the idea of, you know, if everyone just went home, it would be cool.
Speaker 0: And then the guy's like, no, you don't want to be invaded.
Speaker 0: He's like, what?
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 1: It can't be worse than what I'm going through right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Just he's like, why doesn't everyone just go home?
Speaker 0: And then at some point everyone does just go home, but it doesn't quite work out that way.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But the fact that he, despite the, I mean, he, he doesn't really talk big.
Speaker 1: Like he accepts the grumbling of his care of the people working with him and he tries to help them out.
Speaker 1: And he, you know, he works hard, but he still continues to fight the war.
Speaker 1: You can see, I mean, he even shoots those, that guy who tried to run away.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But that was kind of weird.
Speaker 0: It was like, whoa, why are you doing that for?
Speaker 1: Because he hadn't given up on it yet.
Speaker 1: He wasn't free of it.
Speaker 1: He was still his farewell to arms.
Speaker 1: He didn't actually give up until he was forced to.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: He was just going to go back and keep doing it.
Speaker 1: And he didn't really have a revelation.
Speaker 1: He just kind of realized suddenly that if he didn't try to get away from the war, he was going to die.
Speaker 0: Well, it wasn't, it wasn't until the carbonary guys were going to shoot him.
Speaker 1: that, you know, he, but he didn't have any personal revelation.
Speaker 1: He just didn't want to die.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like, he was just doing his job.
Speaker 0: You know, he didn't really, you know, he would like hang out with people who are like against the war and he'd be like, yeah, the war sucks, but keep it quiet.
Speaker 0: And then the BV would be super for the war.
Speaker 0: And he'd be like, he was very, you know, it was like.
Speaker 0: all these people around him were very, you know, strong characters in one direction or another, but he was just sort of going along, just stay in the course, pretty neutral on most things, you know, just doing his job until event, you know, the point at which they were actually going to kill him is when he said, Oh, that's the end of this.
Speaker 1: But just the juxtaposition of him killing someone for the sake of a war that he doesn't even care about to him abandoning that war for almost the same reason, basically.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And he never even like things back to that.
Speaker 1: He never worries about that.
Speaker 1: That never bothers him.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like, he doesn't think, you know, he's not really bothered that much by a lot of things.
Speaker 0: All the only things he was really bothered by in the end were like, whether Rinaldi had syphilis, he thought about that.
Speaker 0: And he thought about the priest like a little bit, but no one else, like you didn't talk about like the major didn't think about him anymore.
Speaker 1: I felt bad for that priest.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm an atheist, but I felt really bad for him because soldiers gave him a rough time.
Speaker 0: The thing is, he seemed to not mind being a priest.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But the thing that I felt bad for him was, you know, uh, the main character, you know, he was at the beginning of the book, he gets leave.
Speaker 0: And he goes all around Italy, having a good time and all these places.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But he doesn't go to a bruise.
Speaker 0: He goes everywhere except a bruise.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: He doesn't go to the plate, you know, the priest's house, he went to visit everyone else's town, except for the priest town.
Speaker 0: And the priest was like, I told my parents he were coming.
Speaker 0: They were even, they were ready for you to show up and you didn't show up.
Speaker 0: And I, I, I, I, I, that to me, I thought it was foreshadowing for later in the book, he would go to a bruise and sort of hide out with the priest family or something like that.
Speaker 0: You know, that's sort of what I expected, but that didn't happen at all.
Speaker 0: In fact, we didn't hear much about the priest again after like the first part of the book.
Speaker 0: So that was, that was a surprise.
Speaker 1: The one thing I have to say, I, the scenes at the end, the way this book ends, like, you know, everyone, it's a Hemingway book.
Speaker 1: It's going to end on a downer.
Speaker 1: That's expected.
Speaker 0: And it's an Astro Boy episode.
Speaker 1: It's going to end on a downer.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: That last one.
Speaker 1: Astro Boy just gets worse and worse.
Speaker 1: I'm way, like, I don't know where it's going to end.
Speaker 1: Well, Astro Boy doesn't drink, but daddy Walvers does.
Speaker 0: Oh, God.
Speaker 1: But when I was a kid, like I, I, the end was sad and I felt it.
Speaker 1: and it was, it was a visceral and heart wrenching scene, but I don't know if it's age, but reading the end of that book again was a lot more gut wrenching than it was when I was young.
Speaker 1: Even when I, when I was young, I was reading it for the first time.
Speaker 1: I didn't know how it was going to end.
Speaker 1: And I didn't even know a lot about Hemingway.
Speaker 1: So I didn't really expect it to end badly.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the reason that the ending is so gut wrenching, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, look, first in the end of the book, the big book, the whole book is separated into books.
Speaker 0: And you'll be reading, you'll read a few chapters and then it'll be like book two.
Speaker 0: You read a few chapters, say book three, right?
Speaker 1: I like books that do that well.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So at the end of, I think the second to last book is where they actually finally escaped to Switzerland.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's like, I was like, holy shit.
Speaker 0: They actually escaped to Switzerland.
Speaker 0: They had this big suspenseful, like nighttime boat escape and it actually works.
Speaker 0: They actually make it.
Speaker 0: And they're actually escaped from the war and safe.
Speaker 0: And I was like, wow, that's sort of crazy.
Speaker 0: I thought that for sure that, you know, he would like Switzerland would turn them over or they'd have, you know, cause you think every story like that is always like, you get to the customs and then you're fucked or, you know, you had to run away and you know that kind of, but it wasn't, they actually got away.
Speaker 0: So then book five was the final book was just so many chapters of having a good time in Switzerland.
Speaker 0: And all it was was having a good time in Switzerland, having a good time, having a good time, having a good time and all that, having a good time is just setting you up to knock you over with the very final chapter, which is where all the bad things happen.
Speaker 1: And it's just, that is a heart wrenching scene because again, there is no description.
Speaker 1: There is no point at which what the doctor is doing is displaying what anyone's seeing.
Speaker 0: I actually, I actually missed it a little bit, right?
Speaker 0: Cause it's like the, when the doctor's like smacking the baby around, it's like, I think there was like one sentence that sort of escaped me.
Speaker 0: I had to go back to catch it where it's like, but the baby didn't cry or move or anything.
Speaker 0: And that, that was like one tiny, tiny sentence in like this, you know, at the end of a paragraph.
Speaker 0: So it was like, if you don't read it slowly and carefully, you miss that even though it's really simple sentence, but the fact that the exchanges, and then they tell you on the next page and then you go back and like, Oh fuck.
Speaker 1: We're just the dialogue of Catherine and him.
Speaker 1: And the dialogue is just, it hits hard, especially because Catherine is, I mean, she's the Hemingway hero and she, even to the end, the fact that she really is not afraid of death and it's not even that it's affected, she really is not.
Speaker 0: Well, she was also hopped up on gas.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: But even for that, I mean, she's in pain, but the whole book she's, she's aloof from life to a degree.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, it was all, I was, I had a hard time a little bit, like actually trying to figure out like what the exact deal was because there was a part earlier, way early in the book when they were, I think it was like just when they, he first got injured somewhere around that part of the book and they were talking to each other and it seemed as if like they weren't actually in love that they sort of both agreed to like pretend to be in love for each other
Speaker 1: more.
Speaker 1: What it was was that originally, I mean, remember he was going out horn and he didn't care and he thought of her as just a piece of tail.
Speaker 1: And the problem was she was a strong woman and she wasn't like women.
Speaker 1: I mean, look how untraditional she is.
Speaker 1: The fact that he wants to marry her and she doesn't care about any of the formality or the church.
Speaker 1: She's an atheist.
Speaker 1: Like none of the societal constraints of the time mattered to her at all.
Speaker 1: She's very progressive.
Speaker 1: She's kind of an independent woman and the fact that he thinks he's just having an affair with her right away.
Speaker 1: And she basically lets out, remember he's in the game in his head.
Speaker 1: He's like, he says, I love you.
Speaker 1: And he in his head, he's like, yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: And then later he says it again.
Speaker 1: She's like, you don't have to lie now.
Speaker 1: We're not having sex.
Speaker 1: And he was like, what?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's why it was like, you know, are they really, you know, or are they just watch the progression?
Speaker 1: She didn't really care at first.
Speaker 1: And he was kind of taken aback by this.
Speaker 1: And because of that, he starts to earnestly fall in love with her.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, I just noticed how he didn't care.
Speaker 1: And then after this, like later on, he starts to miss her.
Speaker 1: And then he really wants to see her.
Speaker 1: He tries to see her every chance he gets.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, it's really, you know, over the course of staying in the hospital injured, it went from, you know, one to the other.
Speaker 0: And then when he was out at the war, you know, there's that, there's that part where he's like, you know, I can't, it was like, he's like, I can't, I can, you know, he needs to think about something, but he's like, no, I can't think about her.
Speaker 0: That's like the worst thing I can think about.
Speaker 0: I'll just be torturing myself.
Speaker 0: And then the rest of the paragraph is him thinking about her.
Speaker 0: And I was like, I was like, wait, you just said, don't think about her.
Speaker 0: And then the rest of the, and then he, oh, it's all he does.
Speaker 0: So it's like, well, that's, that's it then, isn't it?
Speaker 1: Now, one thing I do want to point out too, in case any of you miss a lot of this.
Speaker 0: And then it's like, he could have, after he, when he's escaping from the war, he could have escaped a lot easier than the Switzerland escape, but he decides, you know, like he knows that one guy who was going to help him in the bar, but he's like, nope, I've got to go and find, you know, Catherine, I can't be sitting around here.
Speaker 1: But there's this, there are a lot of literary references that I hope you all will catch.
Speaker 1: I worry that you won't, but any, basically my advice to you is anytime through the book where you thought something sounded like prose or like someone was quoting something they probably were, they were the characters quote stuff in character all the time throughout this whole book.
Speaker 1: Like the one that stood out, particularly because I actually had to arrange the poem into music as the midterm in music theory two at RIT.
Speaker 1: But there's one point where he's laying and he's, he's cold and he's, he's tired and he's wounded and he just wants to get away.
Speaker 1: And he's thinking about Catherine and in his head, he's thinking like Western wind blow blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 1: And he keeps it.
Speaker 1: He basically intersperses the old Western wind poem, you know, Western wind.
Speaker 1: when will style blow the cold rain down will rain crisis, all that stuff.
Speaker 1: And he's interposing that with basically woman spaces, one cold motherfucker.
Speaker 1: God damn it.
Speaker 1: I just want to be back.
Speaker 1: But they quote poetry at each other more often than you might catch.
Speaker 0: I mean, they're, they're very, you know, the it's, they're very smart people.
Speaker 0: You know, a lot of the other people around them are like, obviously not as smart.
Speaker 0: And it's like, you know, they're like, he's reading all the newspapers all the time.
Speaker 0: Other people don't read, you know, he reads.
Speaker 0: when he talks to that, uh, the old man, like way at the end of the book, that was actually a cool scene.
Speaker 0: Replies billiards with a really old man is one of my favorite.
Speaker 0: That old man was so awesome.
Speaker 0: Even though he's in the book for like a second.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: But you know, you know, yup, you do know.
Speaker 0: And, uh, you know, the old man's like, well, have you read anything recently?
Speaker 0: He's like, well, I don't even know what's been out recently.
Speaker 0: I've been at this stupid ward.
Speaker 0: He's like, well, you read this.
Speaker 0: He's like, no, I don't know what that is.
Speaker 0: And he's like, did you read this?
Speaker 0: And he's like, oh yeah, I read that something, it's cause he read it when he was, you know, sick, injured.
Speaker 0: And you know, it's like, ah, not too many other people are, are, you know, look, you look at all these people in the war and others and they're, they're not, you know, knowledgeable in those areas.
Speaker 1: It's out, you know, but I guess, I mean, what else can I say other than I used to say that the sun also rises was my favorite Hemingway like novel.
Speaker 1: And part of that was just because I read that when I was much older and I read farewell to arms when I was much younger, I think I actually find this to be my favorite Hemingway now.
Speaker 1: Of course I'll have to read sun also rises again to be sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm, you know, I sorta, Hemingway is weird.
Speaker 0: Like half of it is like, it's totally awesome.
Speaker 0: And half of it is sorta on me.
Speaker 1: I mean, you really, I don't know, it draws you in, in this way that other styles of pros really can't do.
Speaker 1: It's a different experience of reading.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, it's just like when I read it, it's like, some of it is like, you know, like.
Speaker 0: I didn't feel like, you know, I read it and I wanted to keep reading, but at no point did I feel like, you know, like really excited about it.
Speaker 0: Like, yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, this is awesome.
Speaker 1: Or I guess I did when I read it both the first time and again.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like, I don't, I don't feel really strongly about it.
Speaker 0: I just, you know, like I feel it, but it's never a strong feeling, you know?
Speaker 0: So it's like, I'm going along with it.
Speaker 0: I get it and I kind of like it, but I'm not like, it's not my favorite thing ever.
Speaker 1: Part of it's that for certain kinds of characters, Hemingway is able to express them and put them on paper and amazingly like he like ideas, like a character who is disconnected from the world or a character who is alcoholic.
Speaker 1: Very few authors have put that on paper as well as he has, I think.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's definitely like, you know, the best part about the book is looking at all the characters.
Speaker 0: The thing is when I read them, I end up just sort of, you know, cause I'm used to books and stories where like, you know, everything actually matters.
Speaker 0: So I'm constantly thinking about all the things that were in the book, all the people, all the characters, all the other plot points when really they don't, they're not coming back into it.
Speaker 0: That was, that was just it.
Speaker 0: That was just some flavor back there.
Speaker 0: And I'm still thinking about the priest and his town and his parents that, you know, didn't have the visitor that they were expecting and everything.
Speaker 0: That's totally out of the book, but I'm still thinking about it.
Speaker 0: So, you know, I don't know if I'm supposed to be thinking about it or not, but it's sort of, you know, the sign that a book was good.
Speaker 1: It, it, it, it affects you beyond the reading in some way, even if you didn't enjoy it, even if a book is dangerous to your ideas or frightening or disturbing, if you're continuing to think about it after you've read it, that is the mark of a well-written and good book.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Unless it's just so bad.
Speaker 0: You were just thinking about how bad it was.
Speaker 0: You just can't stop thinking about how Tara is just so painful.
Speaker 0: It's like a bad deal.
Speaker 0: Like you tasted something real bad and you can't get the flavor out of your mouth.
Speaker 0: It was so terrible.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: But on that note, let's stop because I don't want to analyze the book.
Speaker 1: Any high school teacher can do that for you.
Speaker 1: And if you're trying to crib off of this for a book report, just read the book.
Speaker 0: It's not, it's an easy book.
Speaker 0: It's not, it's, I mean, it's not as easy as the RC, but it's, it's Hemingway.
Speaker 0: This is not a difficult and it's short.
Speaker 0: I read it in like three days, the equivalent of three days.
Speaker 0: So let's, we get to the next book.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I guess we do.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Do you want it for the next book?
Speaker 0: Do you want to continue a alternating pick or do you want to do some other system?
Speaker 1: or do you have a pick in place?
Speaker 0: Oh, I can, I got, I got a boatload of picks.
Speaker 1: I'll let you pick.
Speaker 1: Cause I got to pick this one, but I warn you, my next pick will rely heavily upon what you pick now.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: I'm going to pick, what are you going to pick?
Speaker 1: I'll pick going to go back to fantasy.
Speaker 1: And then my last choice was an Earthsea, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So that was the, that was the easy for the listeners.
Speaker 0: pick, right?
Speaker 0: This time I will think I'll do the force room to read it.
Speaker 0: Pick don't pick Hawthorne.
Speaker 1: I swear to fucking God.
Speaker 0: I don't do, I don't think I've ever read any Hawthorne.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: What is Hawthorne written?
Speaker 0: Nathaniel Hawthorne, right?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: What, what do you write Scott?
Speaker 1: Go on.
Speaker 0: I think I will pick.
Speaker 0: we'll do cavalier and clay cavalier and clay.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Emily approves.
Speaker 1: And on that note, I think we'll leave it.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: For the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.