Speaker 0: It's Wednesday January 21st.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights, and they were 11.
Speaker 0: Let's do this in the spirit of watching anime.
Speaker 0: That's new so we can talk about it or at least know about it.
Speaker 0: We uh we checked out two of the shows.
Speaker 0: well three of the shows from the current season of anime.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't even remember well There was like two perverted ones And there was one that we had high hopes for based on the description.
Speaker 1: that wasn't so great.
Speaker 1: It was not in the first episode.
Speaker 0: What amazed me was that the one that I thought would be more perverted was slightly less perverted, but still creepy.
Speaker 0: I didn't expect to be as perverted at least right away like I expected.
Speaker 0: if I watch the first like two minutes of that Show I think it was like the one about the two sisters who are hot for their brother, but step step brother whatever.
Speaker 0: yeah I didn't expect to within the first minute get interaction surrounded by you ten of flowers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that kind of came out of nowhere and really killed that show.
Speaker 1: for me I mean you know for a while We had like the sort of comedically perverted shows you know sort of like.
Speaker 1: you know love Hina's or Golden Boys and things.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: and then they sort of went to the moe shows right which were perverted But not any not in any outward fashion.
Speaker 0: It was I would say that love Hina was a big bridge between the two because love Hina was a lot more moe and a lot Less funny mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I can't say less funny because that doesn't really do it justice not funny Terrible.
Speaker 1: yeah, I mean I had cute turtles.
Speaker 1: that was about it.
Speaker 0: I mean at least Golden Boy was actually pretty funny.
Speaker 0: We had a show on that.
Speaker 1: I haven't had to watch it again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I haven't seen that show since all right years ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I never even saw all of it right.
Speaker 1: But now it seems like I guess some of the shows that are coming out now are just outright perverted.
Speaker 1: It's like no.
Speaker 1: It's not you know do moe.
Speaker 1: That's perverted, but only in a hidden way.
Speaker 1: You know let's not do perverted, but comedy on top to make fun of it.
Speaker 1: Let's just come out right with the perversion, but then just you know keep it a little you know covered up.
Speaker 1: So it's not hentai.
Speaker 1: They're basically just making hentai, but covering it up, so it's not.
Speaker 1: and and Yeah, no interest in that.
Speaker 0: It's basically softcore porn.
Speaker 0: It's the same thing you'd see on like cinnamax skin of eggs.
Speaker 0: Yes, if you want to be clever and call it that yep.
Speaker 0: And then the one show we actually had hopes for which was like girl.
Speaker 0: I had hopes for a couple shows girl on robot bicycle Maybe a little bit like bubblegum crisis or something, but now now that show turned into initial D in like five minutes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, maybe it's it's sort of like Moonlight Mile where they sort of tease you with this political stuff.
Speaker 1: That could be really cool, but they debt.
Speaker 1: in the first episode at least.
Speaker 1: that never connects to the actual characters They're showing you.
Speaker 1: it's just sort of like they're showing you in it.
Speaker 1: It's like imagine if you were watching initial D and every five minutes They cut to C-Span for like 10 seconds and then cut back and your man like wow I wish this initial D part with the cars had.
Speaker 1: event has something to do with that politics.
Speaker 1: I see that would be really cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but instead you get to the end of the episode.
Speaker 1: just they never connect.
Speaker 1: It's really.
Speaker 1: they're just cutting away to show you C-Span.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except it was C-Span and Sherpa sex and between the two were a little Gecky guy esque moments like when he uses that crane to save that guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there was nothing else there, but I Don't want to call it flag syndrome because flag was another anime that did this.
Speaker 0: it looked awesome.
Speaker 0: It looked so good.
Speaker 0: The premise was great.
Speaker 0: The imagery was amazing and then by the end of the episode it literally turned into.
Speaker 0: the robots are gonna go and Steal that flag back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whoo Yeah, but this show like I feel like there's a big warning sign that you can see and I'm starting to recognize it more.
Speaker 0: But if you're watching a show that is ostensibly about something else.
Speaker 0: But they start giving you the details of the made-up machines in the show And I'm not talking details like that's the red one That's the blue one, but like this one has the made-up number made-ups parameter.
Speaker 0: They give you the exact length in meters.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the key they show you the interface and it actually matters.
Speaker 1: Well, I think the key right and how to do it right and how to do it wrong Right and how to do it right is something like Gundam seed.
Speaker 1: and what Gundam seed does is they tell you things in Gundam Seed about
Speaker 0: fire the low and green Yeah,
Speaker 1: and they have phase shift armor and all these sorts of things right and you know all different systems But they don't ever have a scene where they stop and have a character just explain to you all The technology as if they were explaining you the rules to a board game.
Speaker 1: It's just things happen and When different things get used they say the name of those things and then you see with your eyeballs Sort of how they work which so it's good.
Speaker 1: even though they're doing the same exact thing They're spreading it out and they're sort of revealing it.
Speaker 1: naturally whenever you see a show where there's a scene where you have a character like it's completely explaining all the details of some piece of Machinery or some system or some like how the magic works in this fantasy world, right?
Speaker 1: And they spend like a good minute just telling you all the rules like oh, you know in this fantasy world, you know.
Speaker 0: Wait though because Full Metal Alchemist did that that was a pretty good show.
Speaker 1: No, no Full Metal Alchemist didn't spend like a whole minute.
Speaker 1: It was just like tokakoka the end.
Speaker 0: No, they spend more time.
Speaker 0: I just think you because it's it's not because the shape and but Full Metal Alchemist I would note is not a rewatchable show, but it was still a pretty good show Okay, but I think it's more than in a show like Gundam seed, right?
Speaker 0: when they bring these things up the show isn't focusing on the I don't know details of the fake technology of the fake world kind of like those bad fantasy books that go into the details Of the witch locks and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: but if you use it as consistent background to make the world consistent and make sense and be interesting in color and flavor or If those things are relevant to the plot then it can work.
Speaker 0: The problem is when it turns into initial D syndrome where the show revolves solely around the technicalities of the fake technology.
Speaker 0: at least initial D Almost was a little bit like real cars for the first season Kinda and I point out that I love initial D.
Speaker 1: I did not sleep for the hero beat music.
Speaker 0: I did not bother with anything past the first season for a reason.
Speaker 1: Yeah, without eurobeat music initially really wouldn't have anything but right back.
Speaker 0: It's like they designed this very specific mech.
Speaker 0: That's really cool to people who really like mechs and motorcycles and then they made a girl who's really good at it who's basically gonna be the Takumi and I Don't see how this is going to turn into a good show because the plot of the first episode is it gets out of control She's on it They do Made up bath, but add crap to make it work and save her in the end by plugging in.
Speaker 0: they show you exactly what they're Doing.
Speaker 0: like I plug into this thing.
Speaker 0: I type this command and then this happens.
Speaker 0: It's fanboy fodder.
Speaker 0: Just like Gunslinger girls where they keep showing you the guns and talking about the guns.
Speaker 0: It's like the gun fanboy is gonna be into that show because you keep learning about the guns and talking about the guns.
Speaker 1: Yeah You did.
Speaker 1: a good show is a show that Concentrates on the characters and the plot and has those sorts of other things there and maybe fleshed out a little bit.
Speaker 1: But just for flavor when the focus of the show is on those You know things that don't really matter for the characters of the plot than that is or when those are the characters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's really too bad though because the show otherwise was beautiful.
Speaker 0: I mean even they looked really good while the plot of the first episode was Real dumb the character designs were pretty good and the animation was great and the scenes where she was riding that robot were amazing But they were amazing fluff.
Speaker 0: So I don't think I'm gonna watch any more ride back unless I'm gonna watch.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I'm watching I'm gonna start watching.
Speaker 1: I think starting tomorrow old captain Harlock for the 70s I got like 42 episodes worth the whole show.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm definitely going to finish up Nodama Cantabile Paris and then I'm gonna move on to Patty Finishing birdie the mighty.
Speaker 0: I really really like that new birdie the mighty.
Speaker 1: Okay, so you might know right that your comic books are ordered two months in advance.
Speaker 1: That's sort of how this thing works, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know what happens is usually, you know You get these order forms and and previews and they start to release them about you know, the late middle of the month.
Speaker 1: So right now they're starting to release, you know some February previews right?
Speaker 1: for you know Comic books that you will be able to buy on the shelf in April, right?
Speaker 1: so it's February for April and I saw something in there that was a Much personal interest.
Speaker 1: All right, you see when I was a kid I wasn't as smart as I am now and I think that's true for almost everybody and You know, I didn't have a lot of money either.
Speaker 1: so I you know Couldn't afford to buy every comic book in the comic book store, which I probably would have done.
Speaker 1: I'm very glad that I didn't because I would have been much like rim in his younger days.
Speaker 1: if he was you know had money He would have had a room full of swords.
Speaker 0: Well, I always say I gotta make this graph so people can link to it.
Speaker 0: It's the graph of how much money you have How much desire for swords you have and your age and whenever the three factors come into line?
Speaker 0: You're fucked and you're gonna own a whole bunch of sword.
Speaker 1: All right, the same thing happened to me with you know, like bad comic books You know cuz I still you know, I saw I have a desire for comic books but not bad ones like I did.
Speaker 1: But no when I was a kid the comic books I could only afford a couple complex by the way They were a dollar and fifty cents for those little flimsy things in those days.
Speaker 0: All right, so I know something said the first x-men comic book.
Speaker 0: I actually owned Came in the x-men board game That I bought just because I wanted to paint the fairly high quality miniatures that came with awesome Really?
Speaker 0: I hated the x-men.
Speaker 0: I just bought the game because.
Speaker 1: so when I was a kid, I bought x-men but the other comic I bought was spider-man 2099 and Spider-man 2099 is a story about you know, some future world.
Speaker 1: That's all sci-fi and high-tech and there's a guy who basically he doesn't have a lot to do with Peter Parker But you know, his powers are very similar and he you know calls himself spider-man 2099 and the whole thing, right?
Speaker 1: So it's actually not bad considering actually it's pretty damn good.
Speaker 1: and The thing is I have every issue of this comic because I collected it when I was a kid You know and it has you know, some sort of personal value.
Speaker 1: but Marvel has never reprinted this comic or collected it in a trade paperback or anything.
Speaker 1: and This month right?
Speaker 1: Well February for delivery in April is finally going to be a trade paperback of spider-man 2099 Uh-huh, but it's only going to be get this the first ten issues and I think there's like 30 some odd issues something like that
Speaker 0: all right, so like four or five trades,
Speaker 1: yeah, and It's gonna be $30 at least cover price
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: It sounds like they realize that the people who were fans of it will buy it if they re-release it.
Speaker 1: The thing is I would have considered buying.
Speaker 1: actually I planned to buy it before I Existed.
Speaker 0: you're gonna say but and before I let you say but I'm gonna butt in and point out that you are not their target Demographic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 1: Think about it, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I was thinking all mad.
Speaker 1: I hope one day they put it out in trades.
Speaker 1: I get rid of all these stupid comic books and just have trades of it and it'll be awesome, right?
Speaker 1: Well 30 bucks eat for you know, ten issues Dude, that's like three dollars an issue.
Speaker 1: That's way too much money way too much money considering I already have the issues.
Speaker 1: so I think what I'm gonna do is you ever go to the library and you see there are some books in the library that Don't look like books from borders.
Speaker 1: They sort of have like these really generic solid color bindings and there's like the Wait, are you gonna get your spider-man?
Speaker 0: Comics bound.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's only $15.
Speaker 0: It's not that expensive.
Speaker 0: I was gonna point out I was surprised you hadn't been doing that with all your old comics before.
Speaker 1: well, you know Now some of them aren't really worth binding.
Speaker 1: You know what I'm saying?
Speaker 0: Well, the best part is now that you know living in New York.
Speaker 0: There are plenty of places in the city.
Speaker 0: That'll just do it.
Speaker 1: But now there's a place that library binding that like specializes in doing it to comic books.
Speaker 1: So you just you pay you 15 bucks.
Speaker 1: you put the comics in the mail in the order you want them bound and then they send Them back to you.
Speaker 1: and they're like experts at it.
Speaker 1: and actually, you know Most of what they do is you know doing those generic bindings for libraries that you see.
Speaker 1: You know where it's like a solid color hardcover binding with like some really boring print on the on the spine Clever girl, so that's what I'm gonna do.
Speaker 1: that way I don't have to you know If I'm gonna cuz think about it, even if I get the best discount I can get is a 50% discount.
Speaker 1: It's $15 right to buy the trade or it's $15 to bind up the issues I've got.
Speaker 1: and you know if I bind up the issues I've got.
Speaker 1: While I hate advertisements These early 90s Advertisements are a high quality now.
Speaker 1: They have they have become art.
Speaker 1: They're no longer ads.
Speaker 0: There's something I mean Brock's rocks.
Speaker 0: There's something old TSR game about seeing old advertising.
Speaker 0: It's like one thing.
Speaker 0: I used to love about watching old VHS tape.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, cuz I have these daykillers.
Speaker 0: I've talked.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah at RIT.
Speaker 0: They were the daykillers.
Speaker 0: They were Super slow, you know like eight-hour VHS tapes with just like back-to-back episodes of The Simpsons without ads but every now and then an ad would be in there just because I wasn't paying attention or someone dropped the ball.
Speaker 0: when we're recording this stuff as a kid and Watching an ad that is more than a decade old is always a feast for the eyes and ears.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's weird.
Speaker 1: how like an advertisement right?
Speaker 1: It's like the worst thing ever if it's brand new, but if it's old It's no longer an advertisement.
Speaker 1: It's just art now and it's awesome.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: I think what we should do is we should just ban all advertising that isn't at least five years old.
Speaker 1: You see if you want to put an ad on TV, you've got to make it.
Speaker 1: You've got to wait five years and then you can put it on TV.
Speaker 0: That Scott is a terrible idea.
Speaker 0: That's an awesome idea.
Speaker 1: What are you talking about?
Speaker 0: So speaking of terrible ideas, there was an anime that was coming out.
Speaker 0: We've talked about it a couple of times Hetalia axis powers, which is based on a webcomic and Basically it's personifications of European nations Bickering with each other and fighting with each other and doing all the things that Europe did for much of its history.
Speaker 0: Yeah And it was being made into an anime and it was all set to go.
Speaker 0: kids station in Japan picked it up And then they very recently announced that they're no longer picking it up and it is.
Speaker 0: it is now officially cancelled.
Speaker 1: Now the thing is they still made the show.
Speaker 0: the internet Exploded immediately.
Speaker 0: yeah, so it so happens that the rumor going around was that people in Korea signed this gigantic petition saying that it was offensive to Korea and there and and it it glossed over That many Korean people even know or care about.
Speaker 0: well, I'll get to that.
Speaker 0: I'll get to that.
Speaker 0: and that because of that Kid station decided not to show it.
Speaker 0: now kids station actually released a Statement saying that quote.
Speaker 0: it was unaware of the criticism in Korea.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm that basically they said that the decision had nothing to do with that.
Speaker 0: They really weren't aware of it.
Speaker 0: It was canceled for other reasons.
Speaker 0: now We can't know for sure obviously because these sorts of things are never.
Speaker 0: I mean if you think the anime industry in America is not Transparent.
Speaker 0: we have no idea what happened over there kid station for all we know.
Speaker 0: I don't know I was trying to think of something funny.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of tired Came and told them not to stop that Wizard.
Speaker 1: a voodoo lady cast a curse voodoo lady.
Speaker 0: It was clearly a witch-a-lock.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you knew what you like.
Speaker 0: But have no fear The show is still going to be available because they made it and there are going to be ways to see it in fact.
Speaker 0: Quote mobile animate service for mobile phones.
Speaker 0: Oh, I started at the wrong part of that sentence.
Speaker 0: regardless animate TV Will have it.
Speaker 0: it is going to be on the internet We are going to be able to.
Speaker 1: it's not gonna be on TV, but it'll be on the internet and the telephone.
Speaker 0: yes, so we will be able to see it.
Speaker 0: and Beyond that I got nothing else.
Speaker 0: But in terms of the petition in Korea as far as I can gather there were several petitions.
Speaker 0: They were Internet petitions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which basically mean nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No, that's like, you know, that's basically Emily's like favorite thing in the whole world.
Speaker 1: She was into it before.
Speaker 1: it was an anime or anything and you know One thing that she told me that I thought was the most interesting part.
Speaker 1: Is that basically this this manga?
Speaker 1: It was actually a webcomic right that was made by a Japanese, you know Person of unknown gender right because they're sort of secret, you know It's a pen name, right, but the person is living in Brooklyn.
Speaker 1: So someone living in Brooklyn made a webcomic right in Japanese in Japanese language but it was a you know webcomic made by a person living in Brooklyn and Then that became an anime.
Speaker 1: So all these indie comic creators and all these webcomic creators out there can shut up.
Speaker 1: Stop complaining right?
Speaker 1: that oh, you know Diamond is so evil.
Speaker 1: Oh, but if I don't go with diamond into the comic book store, I can't make money.
Speaker 0: No, it's like you can make it.
Speaker 1: So first yeah some person in Brooklyn made a webcomic and boom anime and I'm sure that even though it's not on TV I'm sure they're still gonna be getting some green All right.
Speaker 0: now for anyone who wants to read the comic it so happens that Emily has taken it upon herself to Start translating large portions of it and I'll whatever it more of.
Speaker 0: it's there.
Speaker 0: There's an index page.
Speaker 0: We'll link to it.
Speaker 0: But Emily is doing a lot of translation work for the original webcomic which from what I have seen Especially if you were into history at all Hilarious.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, well, you don't get made into a TV TV show by being you know, lamb.
Speaker 0: But I mean think about it you this is like Italia is northern Italy and he's like the shonen guy and then there's Russia and Austria and Hungary and all these people.
Speaker 1: So I guess the Italian guy is the main character, which is why he's in the title.
Speaker 0: Yes Okay, the name is also kind of a pun but we'll review this once we see it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so things of the day now, I think we've talked about this a couple times before but if you're not fully aware The Ghostbusters is one of the funniest movies ever made.
Speaker 0: like Ghostbusters Far away, like I could watch that movie for the rest of my life and never get sick of it.
Speaker 0: That was just well, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think I could watch, you know real Star Wars movies longer.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think Star Wars and Ghostbusters are very similar in terms of appeal In terms of durability, I think Star Wars 4 5 6 is a little bit more durable.
Speaker 0: I really don't know.
Speaker 1: I know Ghostbusters is fantastic.
Speaker 0: But anyway I'm sure you all know the deal how.
Speaker 0: there was a cartoon called the real Ghostbusters and the reason I was a great cartoon.
Speaker 1: I loved it.
Speaker 1: The reason you're seeing a Cthulhu episode.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: You should link to that or something.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure we have have we are anyway.
Speaker 0: But I'm sure you all know that it was called the real Ghostbusters because there was this other Ghostbusters cartoon that came out first called Ghostbusters.
Speaker 1: that thing is back in those days.
Speaker 1: I didn't even realize there was another Ghostbusters cartoon see until after the real one.
Speaker 0: I Did because I remember oh my I saw like in the TV guide thing on our cable cuz we had cable See, I didn't have a TV guy.
Speaker 0: I saw Ghostbusters and I was like Ghostbusters cartoon.
Speaker 0: Ah I turn it on and I saw a gorilla and I didn't know what to think.
Speaker 0: I actually watched that show for a while Yeah, and then finally the real one came out.
Speaker 0: but a lot of people would used to say that that was like a ripoff of Ghostbusters or like there was some shenanigans where they got the name and made the cartoon and that's why they had to call it the Real Ghostbusters, so I want to set the record straight for anyone who's interested in exactly what went down here because the truth is far sadder than you would believe.
Speaker 0: so it all started in 1975 yep, when the Ghostbusters a live-action Television show the opener of which I have linked to as my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: It's real bad.
Speaker 0: This is Bad like this is back in the era where there was a lot of locally produced television.
Speaker 0: like there were TV shows They were only on in the Midwest.
Speaker 1: the thing is some locally produced television.
Speaker 1: It's like great and is like lost for all eternity and it's that kind of sad like romper room.
Speaker 1: romper rooms are the fucking best.
Speaker 1: But you know, we've lost that.
Speaker 1: so it gets good and bad because a lot of it was just terrible.
Speaker 0: So then of course the real the Ghostbusters movie the movie that we care about was made in Yes 1984.
Speaker 0: Yep So in 1984 Ghostbusters the movie was made and then in The fake Ghostbusters cartoon was made based on the original movie because they had the rights to it.
Speaker 1: This on the original TV show.
Speaker 0: Yeah the original TV show.
Speaker 0: So then after that the feet they said oh crap and they made the real Ghostbusters.
Speaker 1: Now did they make the 1986 cartoon remake of the 1970s TV show?
Speaker 1: knowing about the popularity of the 1984 movie and attempting to capitalize.
Speaker 0: so When they were making Ghostbusters that was the working title and after they started filming and putting stuff together.
Speaker 0: They found out that there was some other thing called Ghostbusters Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: so they made up a bunch of alternate titles and they were ready if like basically they were gonna try to get the rights and If they couldn't then they were just gonna change the name.
Speaker 0: But as the production went on people got so attached to the name Ghostbusters that they approached Filmmation and said look we need Ghostbusters name and they got the rights to call a movie Ghostbusters.
Speaker 0: They did not get any other rights.
Speaker 0: So once the movie was a success Filmmation put out Ghostbusters based on that crappy TV show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so they did were attempting to capitalize on the great movie.
Speaker 1: Yes, but the thing is they couldn't even though they could write capitalize by calling their cartoon Ghostbusters.
Speaker 1: They couldn't capitalize by putting you know Ray Egon, etc.
Speaker 1: Slimer in there because they didn't own that shit.
Speaker 0: No, but instead they had prime evil and the Skelevision.
Speaker 0: Yeah, great and Sabone No, and Sabone was a skull.
Speaker 0: That was also a telephone.
Speaker 0: I watched this show for like a little while.
Speaker 1: I Feel bad for you.
Speaker 0: They use this like skeleton elevator.
Speaker 0: It was and they had this car.
Speaker 0: It was and there was a gorilla who animated this thing.
Speaker 0: Ah, I don't even know I'd like to interview them.
Speaker 0: Would you really have me?
Speaker 1: interesting is all hell?
Speaker 0: Oh, sorry, the animated television series was created by Filmmation and distributed by someone else.
Speaker 1: Filmmation not equal Funimation.
Speaker 0: Yes two different things.
Speaker 0: so enjoy You probably won't ever want to watch these again.
Speaker 1: Just so.
Speaker 1: also people know The guy who wrote the real Ghostbusters cartoon, you know, the one that was called the real Ghostbusters based on the good 1984 movie.
Speaker 1: He writes many popular comic books.
Speaker 0: So, uh, what do you got for me?
Speaker 1: So there's you know, Japanese people they like toys Perhaps.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and this is all over the internet.
Speaker 1: You probably seen this already, but I thought it was pretty neat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some company made Obama action figure.
Speaker 0: I saw these a good idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah clever girl.
Speaker 1: So it's like a really good action figure.
Speaker 1: It is very articulatable and You know, it's got all these different switchable heads, you know that look like Obama with different facial expressions and such and Someone I guess in Japan took this action figure and photographed it in many interesting scenes among which are Obama pulling out very dangerous weapons from under his coat.
Speaker 1: All right Obama with samurai swords Obama with a lightsaber fighting Darth Vader.
Speaker 0: now, is there?
Speaker 0: Obama versus Kenshiro?
Speaker 0: because I don't know who would win.
Speaker 0: we'd have to make it but I really don't know who would win.
Speaker 1: one Really good picture is Obama lying down with his hands, you know holding his head up, you know, like people do With his legs under a kotatsu with a bowl of oranges on the kotatsu And near his head is an old Famicom.
Speaker 1: I Don't think Obama.
Speaker 1: I mean Obama is a man of the world But I do not know if he has ever sat under a kotatsu.
Speaker 1: I in fact, I don't know if he would know what a kotatsu was if you said hey, do you have a kotatsu?
Speaker 1: But wherever I move next be it apartment or house Kotatsu is like number one on the list while I like kotatsu.
Speaker 0: I think they're an awesome thing.
Speaker 0: They really don't serve any purpose in a modern home.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: because the temperature is always perfect in the home,
Speaker 1: but you see what you do is you turn the heat off
Speaker 0: No, then your pipes freeze
Speaker 1: you keep the heat low and then you know Like hot enough to where the pipes won't freeze but like, you know, maybe like 50 something or low 60.
Speaker 0: So basically I make it so that the comfortable part of my house is very tiny and very comfortable and the rest of it Is inhale spittable wasteland.
Speaker 0: Yes Plus you realize Kotatsu were designed for if you're wearing Traditional Japanese clothes.
Speaker 0: because think about it if you're wearing stuff like don't don't those come with the kotatsu.
Speaker 0: Uh, I don't know they must.
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: I thought they did.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure you have to have your own clothes.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, yeah But I mean like you're wearing normal pants and then as soon as you put your legs under the kotatsu goes poof and they change.
Speaker 0: You know Japanese pants, yes, that is exactly how it works.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: Anyway, what the hell you paying someone to money for.
Speaker 0: I want to get right into this actually because we're talking about.
Speaker 0: it's one of those rare nights when we're talking about an Anime for which I have almost nothing bad to say like this Before we even go any further.
Speaker 0: if you have never seen an anime called they were 11 Just go out and buy it and watch it.
Speaker 0: Don't even bother listening to the rest of this.
Speaker 0: it is.
Speaker 0: it is so worth seeing that I don't need to say it again.
Speaker 0: I shouldn't need to stress it.
Speaker 0: It is fantastic.
Speaker 0: You will enjoy it.
Speaker 1: Basically, I always knew about this right is?
Speaker 1: I always knew there was a thing called they were 11 and that the story was that there's a spaceship of some kind or a space station or people were in space.
Speaker 1: right and There were only supposed to be 10 people in space.
Speaker 1: But when they got there there were 11 people.
Speaker 0: that's all most people knew.
Speaker 1: that's all I knew about it.
Speaker 0: They had it in the RIT anime library.
Speaker 1: There's some fans up Yeah, but no one and no one knows who the 11th person is, you know, so someone isn't supposed to be there.
Speaker 0: Yes, and The show.
Speaker 0: well the movie because it is it's an animated movie a full feature movie pretty high-budget - is pretty unknown Very like.
Speaker 0: I've very rarely run into people who have heard of it let alone seen it.
Speaker 0: I hadn't seen it until recently.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean we you know, it's.
Speaker 1: it's one of those like, you know things You're gonna get from like a cheapo CPM DVD, right?
Speaker 1: It's you know, it's not made anymore in the US.
Speaker 1: I mean it was you know, it was made in the US.
Speaker 1: It was a CPM.
Speaker 0: Didn't we buy this for like five bucks?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we bought it.
Speaker 1: next we did.
Speaker 1: we bought it for like, you know real cheap in some CPM discount bins.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it was one of those, you know every DVD five bucks.
Speaker 0: That's when we bought all of master Keaton and we probably bought this too.
Speaker 1: But I mean usually you go there right and you get these like cheapo DVDs and usually all bad right like judge or isn't bad?
Speaker 1: judge is awesome or Ayanis high kick.
Speaker 0: I honest.
Speaker 0: Hey kick isn't bad.
Speaker 0: It's awesome.
Speaker 1: Right, but they were 11 is like in the same bin.
Speaker 1: No, it's bad doomed megalopolis.
Speaker 1: So you see they were 11 in the same bin.
Speaker 1: is these other things?
Speaker 1: so you kind of ignore it, but really it's sort of the Diamond in the rough.
Speaker 0: now the thing is I should have realized Much earlier because I would see the DVD laying around.
Speaker 0: but if you really look at it The character designs look very high-budget Like the DVD looks like one of those that can be deceptive because Odeon was also high-budget.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Thus the conundrum.
Speaker 1: But I budget.
Speaker 1: I mean that ride back show was high-budget.
Speaker 1: So this high production value even if not high-budget.
Speaker 1: So they were 11. the original manga was by Hagio moto who is like super famous Shoujo purse, you know remember we talked about to Tara we talked about like Keiko Takamiya like, you know legendary groundbreaking revolutionary shoujo manga creator.
Speaker 1: Hagio moto is like one of the other ones that was in the same group the the 49ers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the 49ers aka the showa 24 group because you know 1949 was the 24th year of the showa error Right, and basically these were the the ladies who sort of well not sort of did, you know Start shoujo basically and what we know now is shoujo.
Speaker 0: And I gotta say if you look at the cover of the they were 11 manga.
Speaker 0: It looks pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, I mean like, you know nowadays not maybe not because that's what shoujo is But because that's what's published in the US and sold as shoujo in the US.
Speaker 1: you know people tend to think you know of shoujo stuff as you know pink and flowery and relationshipy kind of stuff, but All this early shoujo.
Speaker 1: I'm seeing is all Sci-fi pretty much and all these early shoujo authors, you know for the showa 24 group we're all sci-fi and fantasy and an awesome in and up.
Speaker 1: and You know, it doesn't get a lot of respect over here in the US except among the smart fans, you know the score I mean the.
Speaker 0: the genres that are most often applied to they were 11 are Mystery romance and space opera.
Speaker 1: I think it's really a suspense kind of thing.
Speaker 0: Well, that's probably in there too Yeah, but it is also definitely a mystery romantic space opera.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Oh, yeah, but the thing was is like he was sitting there and I kind of wanted to watch it for a long time Ever since we got the DVD, but every time I suggested hey, let's just watch it We just never watched it.
Speaker 0: and it was that whenever we have a movie like this We kind of always want to wait until we have enough people to where if it's bad We can all make fun of it and if it's good I don't have to watch it a hundred times as I keep showing.
Speaker 1: I think the other thing is that we sort of expected it to be a quiet slow space movie Which it is a little bit, you know and Sort of some people don't like that as much as others like.
Speaker 1: I really like, you know quiet slow in space But other people sort of just get annoyed and grumble a lot.
Speaker 1: So, you know basically one day I was just home alone and I was like, you know what?
Speaker 1: Fuck it I'm just fucking watching this thing and I watched it and I thought it was gonna be good or at least I thought I would Like it.
Speaker 1: but when I got done watching it.
Speaker 1: leave ball not even but you know a little ways through.
Speaker 1: I was like wow This isn't just something that I'm liking.
Speaker 1: This is something everyone's gonna think is fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: Holy shit now The plot really like.
Speaker 0: if you watch this and we can't talk a lot about it because this is one of those Movies where there is a big reveal and then once the big reveal happens you can watch you can tell a lot though without the Reveal.
Speaker 0: Yes, but it's one of those movies where it is a very different experience knowing what the deal was.
Speaker 1: Definitely, but
Speaker 0: basically this is set in the far future and mankind is spread out throughout the cosmos and they have created a sort of University a school the elitist of the elitist of the elite the best and brightest that all of humanity and the other races they have encountered in their millennia.
Speaker 0: the very best of the best of the best the top of the top of the top.
Speaker 0: the people who Pat these are like These are already at this at this entrance exam the best people the universe has to offer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like the Oxford of the universe, right?
Speaker 1: so basically there's this entrance exam to get into the best University in the universe or the galaxy or whatever the fuck it is, right and They go on they get opens up and they the first thing they do is tell you about this exam.
Speaker 1: right and how like point one percent of the people who apply make it past the preliminaries and then like an even another small percent make it to the next stage right and then you know after that doesn't like 700 people left.
Speaker 1: and we think this isn't just like earth which has six billion.
Speaker 1: I mean imagine if there was a test on earth, right?
Speaker 1: We're six billion people were on earth and 700 passed the test.
Speaker 1: This is an entire galaxy or an entire universe of You know different planets of people living on them and 700 people make it past a certain point.
Speaker 1: That is hardcore, right?
Speaker 0: So we we begin in the midst of this exam following the sort of main character Tada.
Speaker 0: He was taking the exam and he's very nervous and he passes this preliminary part.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, he's basically in a sound.
Speaker 1: It's pretty cool how they execute this early part of how they get from the 10 to the 11.
Speaker 1: That's like so clever and amazing.
Speaker 0: I think it's worth noting that they will get to this but there's something that all of us everyone in the crew who watched it Did independently?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we all realize we did it but he passes.
Speaker 0: so his booth opens up He walks out and he just gets instructions from a computer and he has to go.
Speaker 1: Everything is quiet.
Speaker 1: Everyone else is still in their soundproof booths as least as far as you can see.
Speaker 1: so he's all alone.
Speaker 0: Effectively, even though there's all these people around taking the test and he goes through very intense security Like there is really no way for him to get through these doors get to these places without having passed this exam.
Speaker 1: Yeah He passes the exam and as soon as he passes the exam the computer in the soundproof booth gives him this card and he has To use that card to get through to the different doors to get out of there.
Speaker 1: And if he doesn't have the card, he's sort of stuck.
Speaker 0: So he goes through all this and the computer instructs him to do this.
Speaker 0: do that He's going on to the next test.
Speaker 0: He puts on a spacesuit.
Speaker 1: He puts on a spacesuit.
Speaker 1: So you can't see his face anymore.
Speaker 1: Well, they show him you his face, but you know because he's in a spacesuit, you know It has a shield to protect you from the Sun just burning your face.
Speaker 0: terrible secret of space, right?
Speaker 1: You know other people in the show can't see his face.
Speaker 1: and he can't see their face Because the other people who also passed the test, you know these remaining 700 people They're they're all hidden in spacesuits.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 0: So he comes to a room.
Speaker 0: finally and in that room are nine other people wearing identical spacesuits.
Speaker 1: And well first they're in a the room with the teachers telling them what's gonna happen And then they sort of call their numbers and then they go into another room.
Speaker 0: Yes so it's very methodical.
Speaker 0: everything comes together, but You get to a scene where there are ten people.
Speaker 0: and this is the point.
Speaker 0: It shows the people kind of standing around while they're getting their instructions and every one of us went one, two.
Speaker 0: Okay, there's ten.
Speaker 0: I see ten.
Speaker 0: They didn't trick me.
Speaker 1: There are ten spacesuits and there's one teacher and the teacher in the front, you know collects all their cards.
Speaker 1: So it's ten cards ten people in ten spacesuits.
Speaker 1: and then he says alright All of you are gonna go to this space.
Speaker 1: You know this ship that's floating in space and a wait further instruction and way further instruction.
Speaker 1: So all of these be you know, these are among the 700 best people in the galaxy, you know, they're not idiots, right?
Speaker 1: So they're all gonna just work together immediately and not be stupid.
Speaker 1: They don't need like, you know, someone to coddle them or hold their hand or anything, right?
Speaker 1: So they're like, okay guys Let's all let's all go.
Speaker 0: They go they get to the spaceship now.
Speaker 0: They all go individually through space.
Speaker 0: They basically jump.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they do a little skywalk because they're real, you know.
Speaker 1: They basically fly them close to the spaceship and then they all do a skywalk.
Speaker 1: So they've never gotten out of their spacesuits.
Speaker 1: They've never seen each other's faces.
Speaker 1: They don't know what each other look like.
Speaker 1: They know there's ten of them at the present time But you know, that's all they know.
Speaker 0: so they get to the spaceship.
Speaker 0: They don't know what to do.
Speaker 0: They figure out a way in.
Speaker 0: they get inside the powers out.
Speaker 0: They fiddle with it.
Speaker 0: They get the power going and then they start to orient themselves and then suddenly they realize That there are now eleven of them all in spacesuits.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know if I even want to talk anymore about what happens but now definitely not thanks.
Speaker 0: They expect there to be ten.
Speaker 0: There are eleven.
Speaker 0: What do they do?
Speaker 0: And as soon as they're true Well, I'll say a little bit more just to kind of set the stage for what this is about.
Speaker 0: Yep, as soon as they realize like they start to figure out there's eleven They're starting to you know, not really panic, but they're they're all dealing with it in their own ways.
Speaker 0: They're trying to figure out what to do.
Speaker 0: there's the explosion and Basically what they learn what they are instructed is that the ten of them are have been put on this ship.
Speaker 0: They have to survive a number of days on their own with no help from the outside.
Speaker 0: No, nothing whatsoever No communication to the outside.
Speaker 0: All they have is an emergency button that any one of them can press at any time.
Speaker 0: and if anyone presses that button Someone will come immediately and rescue them all.
Speaker 0: They will fail the exam.
Speaker 0: Yeah So they have come all this way like every one of these people.
Speaker 0: Their whole lives are riding on this like they are the best of this exam.
Speaker 1: Not only is this exam super hard right and for the super elite of the universe They only give the exam every three years.
Speaker 1: if you fail you're gonna have to wait three years to try again.
Speaker 0: So if anyone pushes that button or if any of the ten dies Yep, then they fail it's over.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And then immediately explosions started going off in the ship and the movie kind of takes it from there.
Speaker 1: So you have this like epic struggle for survival, right?
Speaker 1: But you know because they're in space and dangerous things happen in space.
Speaker 1: They're trying to survive for the number of days.
Speaker 1: They're also Constantly worrying about who is the traitor.
Speaker 1: who is the traitor?
Speaker 1: someone here has a nefarious purpose other than passing the test.
Speaker 1: But what the fuck.
Speaker 1: we can't do anything about it because you can't communicate with the outside world.
Speaker 1: We can't possibly figure out for sure who the traitor is.
Speaker 0: When they all you know they take off their spacesuits and they all and there's you're not presented with 11 characters and one by one they all introduce themselves and Every one of them seems perfectly plausible.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're all.
Speaker 0: and just as an example a small example of What it is that really like made this movie great.
Speaker 0: I guess the biggest factor for me was that One of the characters has a little bit of psychic power which in the universe is not that uncommon.
Speaker 0: He can tell if people are lying.
Speaker 0: So they all agree.
Speaker 0: All right, we'll try it.
Speaker 0: What are the odds that you're the traitor or whatever's going on?
Speaker 0: everyone tell your story to this guy and he'll say who's lying and they go through the whole thing and It starts to trip up on one of the guys.
Speaker 0: But he totally lies on purpose at first to see if the guy was lying himself and then he tells the truth.
Speaker 0: like Everyone is super confident.
Speaker 0: Everyone knows exactly what they're doing.
Speaker 0: Everyone's got their shit together.
Speaker 1: I mean how many shows like where you know, all this drama happens because people are stupid, right?
Speaker 0: It's like every zombie movie where you know, we got to save the dog and then everyone dies Exactly in this movie.
Speaker 0: No one's saving the dog.
Speaker 1: These are the elite of the elite.
Speaker 1: So everyone is smart.
Speaker 1: Everyone is cool.
Speaker 1: Everyone is awesome even though they have disagreements and they fight over things and there's there is drama just because not because anyone's stupid but because they're an Incredibly difficult and stressful situation in space but their common purpose of passing the exam and not dying.
Speaker 1: You know, they managed to work together and it you know, it goes places.
Speaker 0: But the other thing that really drives this movie is that button.
Speaker 0: the button is almost like another character That's always there ready to strike.
Speaker 0: there are all these scenes where a character will like walk by the button and just stop and look at it or Someone goes over to hit it and then goes.
Speaker 1: They get into all these tough situations, right?
Speaker 1: They get tougher and tougher and tougher and it's like It's just like man, if I push that button We'll just be fine.
Speaker 1: You know, I'll live and everything will be cool and I won't have to deal with this bullshit anymore.
Speaker 1: but I'll fail and so will everyone else on this ship.
Speaker 0: and The movie just takes it from there and this movie.
Speaker 1: It's like a how far will you go?
Speaker 0: This movie is just so.
Speaker 0: I mean all the characters are really strong characters.
Speaker 0: They all have interesting back some of them.
Speaker 1: I think it what that that is.
Speaker 1: the one thing is that there are 11 characters But admittedly some of the characters don't do very much like the midget guy.
Speaker 1: He doesn't really come into it that much You know, there's the guy with the fro.
Speaker 1: he does nothing.
Speaker 1: the guy with the red fro.
Speaker 0: He basically does one thing.
Speaker 1: What does he do?
Speaker 0: He does something.
Speaker 0: I don't want to spoil any.
Speaker 0: he does one thing They got.
Speaker 1: the red fro doesn't do anything.
Speaker 1: go with the big nose does one thing.
Speaker 0: The guy with the big nose also has red hair.
Speaker 0: That's almost in a fro.
Speaker 1: No, I'm talking about the fro guy.
Speaker 0: Oh the fro guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he doesn't do much.
Speaker 1: He doesn't do anything, right?
Speaker 1: And I think maybe in the manga those characters might have, you know developed more.
Speaker 1: I've never read the manga so I don't know, you know.
Speaker 1: So I think that sort of they were in the movie because they were in the manga.
Speaker 1: but in the movie at least That's the only thing that I sort of rubbed me a little bit.
Speaker 1: That was not good was the fact that they had sort of extra characters in there that didn't develop or sort of mean anything You know.
Speaker 1: and some characters obviously the guy that they show you at the beginning Tada gets a lot more attention.
Speaker 1: He's the main character compared to some of the other characters.
Speaker 0: Well, plus look you.
Speaker 1: But that's just the necessities of a movie.
Speaker 0: But you as the audience I mean think about it.
Speaker 0: you come into this from a meta perspective because you're gonna spend this movie trying to figure out what's going on and You as an audience member know that Tada passed the exam like he.
Speaker 0: he went with everyone else.
Speaker 0: he did everything right.
Speaker 0: But the movie still instills you with doubt even though you saw him take the exam.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you still start to doubt him.
Speaker 0: Yeah you doubt everyone and you have no idea.
Speaker 0: and it it could plausibly be any of them because None of them is plausibly the 11th one.
Speaker 1: and you start to think of all these wild Possibilities like maybe the school is evil and they purposefully like put 11 students and sneak one in You know, like maybe one student got a secret instruction to go on the ship, you know There's like actually a traitor.
Speaker 1: or maybe there's something weird with this ship or maybe They do hint at a lot of weird stuff with the shit.
Speaker 0: I was going into this for about halfway through the movie.
Speaker 0: I started really thinking that they were all ghosts.
Speaker 0: like I was starting to think like are they all ghosts?
Speaker 0: and I really like it started to make sense.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna.
Speaker 1: obviously Maybe it was like an honest mistake like someone who is floating through space to a different exam because you know There are let's see 10 people 700 students.
Speaker 1: I guess 70 exams, right?
Speaker 1: You know, maybe someone just floated in space to the wrong one.
Speaker 1: It's possible right and then they wouldn't know if they went to the wrong one.
Speaker 1: Would they the drop because they didn't see any of the people they were with.
Speaker 1: so it's maybe some other one is like oh shit We have nine.
Speaker 0: Oh fuck but the drama really comes out because at any time They could snap their fingers and this problem would be resolved immediately but they would fail.
Speaker 0: but the price would be so high that they have to deal with this on their own.
Speaker 0: and The movie just keeps upping the ante.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean before I watched it when all I knew about it was the basic premise of there 11 people when they're supposed to be 10 in space.
Speaker 1: That's all I knew.
Speaker 1: I was like man.
Speaker 1: that would make for a pretty good RPG scenario kind of thing, you know a little burning wheel something.
Speaker 1: And having seen it.
Speaker 1: I was I was right, but I was like way more right than I knew I was right.
Speaker 0: Yes, we're.
Speaker 0: I feel like this movie almost deserves a final thought show.
Speaker 0: Maybe I have a lot to say about it, but I can't spoil crap.
Speaker 0: all I want to say instead of do I can't do the all man this scene all man that scene because the Existence of certain scenes is in and of itself a spoiler.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, definitely There was a point where we were confused about something and then it was revealed.
Speaker 0: But then it was revealed the opposite way a little bit later and then it was revealed.
Speaker 0: But the scene that that stands out the most and when you all watch this you'll know destiny destiny all is destiny.
Speaker 0: That scene I Don't know.
Speaker 0: this movie is just amazing and it has super high production values.
Speaker 0: The animation is really really good.
Speaker 0: The character designs are really strong.
Speaker 0: It's based on this fantastic old manga.
Speaker 0: watch it.
Speaker 1: I Just hope they bring out the manga in English.
Speaker 0: I would definitely read it.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Yeah, I really think we got it.
Speaker 0: get one.
Speaker 0: We got to do a final thoughts on this.
Speaker 0: and two we are definitely making this into a burning wheel scenario.
Speaker 0: so for all of you who are anime fans unless you come to a gaming con or Maybe kinetic on you probably won't see us run this but we were totally turning this into a burning wheel.
Speaker 0: All I want to say is if you watch the movie and you go to a con where we are running a burning wheel event That sounds like they were 11.
Speaker 0: It is they were 11.
Speaker 0: Don't spoil it for anyone else.
Speaker 1: So that's another thing though Right?
Speaker 1: is?
Speaker 1: it's like I want to make a RPG scenario, right?
Speaker 1: But to make I feel as if I could give the RPG scenario a different twist, you know I'd still be a twist but a different twist than the movie, right?
Speaker 1: But I feel like the twist for the movie is just so perfect and so great That I wouldn't want to do a different twist.
Speaker 1: I would want to just steal that one, you know steal from the Forgotten Masters and whatnot.
Speaker 0: But I know what's happening is like four twists I know.
Speaker 1: but then what's happening is I'm spoiling the movie for anyone who does the RPG and Spoiling the RPG for anyone who's seen the movie.
Speaker 1: and I feel like you know, why why should it have to be that way?
Speaker 1: So it's it's it's a little.
Speaker 1: we got to work on that.
Speaker 0: I don't have any reservations whatsoever because the overlap is not super great and I guess there will probably be a lot of people who will have seen they were 11 who would want to play in the game but I don't think there would be that many people who would play in the game and then independently later end up seeing the movie.
Speaker 0: and even if they did if you as long as we skin it right I could see people playing our game and Then later seeing the movie and not immediately realizing they're identical Mmm-hmm, maybe if we use a different number.
Speaker 1: besides 11 in the 11 is.
Speaker 1: so I know it is a really good number.
Speaker 0: It's absolutely perfect.
Speaker 0: I don't like it.
Speaker 1: I was thinking maybe 9 would work.
Speaker 0: They were 9.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were a baseball team.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, they're supposed to be 8 and then a ninth shows up, you know 9 plus 1. no, they were supposed to be 8.
Speaker 1: So 9 is the plus 1.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: So what do we call this scenario?
Speaker 1: They were 9.
Speaker 1: You are 9.
Speaker 0: Seriously, you are shock.
Speaker 0: You can explode.
Speaker 0: you can pick this movie up For nothing.
Speaker 0: It was put up by CPM.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean the thing is if you don't go to like an anime convention where CPM sets up their ultra discount get rid of everything booth them.
Speaker 1: You probably find on the Internet's no problem.
Speaker 1: But you know, I don't know go check like write stuff in Amazon.
Speaker 1: It's got to be there somewhere.
Speaker 1: It's so cheap.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I just I enjoyed this movie greatly.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I don't know what else I can say because I really don't.
Speaker 1: it's a must watch.
Speaker 0: it is especially because there aren't that many good Anime feature films out there like.
Speaker 0: there's enough to wear.
Speaker 0: They're few enough to wear.
Speaker 0: I would expect every self-identifying anime fan to have seen every major released in America Animated feature of length film.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So I expect all of you to have seen.
Speaker 0: they were 11.
Speaker 0: There you go, and we're gonna do a final thoughts at some point.
Speaker 0: So it's worth your while.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 1: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.