Speaker 1: Hey, it's Thursday August 20th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: a bit about health care.
Speaker 0: Let's do this warm today.
Speaker 0: We don't say that enough, but you know what it's been stupid stupid warm for the past like two weeks Like you know what is so warm.
Speaker 0: I don't even.
Speaker 0: it's just insane.
Speaker 1: It's great.
Speaker 1: I wish it would just be this way all year round.
Speaker 0: if it was this warm in space He could have been reunited with his girlfriend But I had at work.
Speaker 1: You know we're having this ping-pong.
Speaker 0: It's so warm.
Speaker 0: I think that in space.
Speaker 0: It's probably like a cool 50 degrees.
Speaker 1: So we're having that ping-pong tournament at work And I was kicking all sorts of ass and I went up against someone who this guy who's a Chinese guy?
Speaker 1: No, no, just this guy this normal kind of white American dude.
Speaker 0: What's his job at the company?
Speaker 1: He's kind of senior guy okay, and he's he's a tennis player.
Speaker 1: apparently he almost went pro.
Speaker 1: He's ping-pong for fun.
Speaker 0: So you're you're in trouble he uh?
Speaker 1: trivially dispatched of me.
Speaker 1: He did not even know.
Speaker 0: I mean I did not realize.
Speaker 0: you know I mean like.
Speaker 0: obviously they're both racquetball sports But I didn't think there was that much of a connection between you know the table tennis and the actual tennis.
Speaker 1: in terms of the skill set I mean I'm a I'm a mediocre tennis player a pretty good racquetball player and a Pretty great thing.
Speaker 0: racquetball and tennis have a lot more in common than I think tennis and ping-pong.
Speaker 1: I would actually say that ping-pong and racquetball have a little more in common because racquetball is a lot Faster than tennis.
Speaker 0: that's true, but like I would wonder like now I kind of want to see like some Chinese ping-pong dude go up against like you know some real tennis And then maybe see like Federer and Nadal try to play some ping-pong.
Speaker 1: Well now because the thing is this guy played tennis and ping-pong for most of his life.
Speaker 0: Okay, so it's not a situation of no.
Speaker 1: But it was basically too that I play a really tricky game cuz I you know I Basically use a lot of English and that sort of thing and I tricked the person like I'll be looking at one side.
Speaker 0: He just hit it really hard right down the middle every time yes, and he was basically like it was so hard You couldn't possibly react.
Speaker 1: It was like in a movie when like I'm on that you're on the ground holding your sword up all the other guys just battering Against your sword over and over again.
Speaker 1: There's nothing you can do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I lost 21 to 8.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know that's you know like when I you always see people like bowling.
Speaker 0: you know some people they bowl.
Speaker 0: They tried to like the hookshot and such.
Speaker 0: I just bowl it straight down the middle and I try to be as consistent as possible.
Speaker 0: If I can get a strike like that one time then it's technically possible.
Speaker 0: I could do that exact same thing every time.
Speaker 1: I got my average when I was taking bowling classes at RIT up to about 200 mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I just went straight at the middle every time and then you know what I stopped taking bowling classes.
Speaker 1: My average is back down to about 43 where it belongs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean you know I'm terrible at ping-pong.
Speaker 0: But if I you know were to actually try to play ping-pong my strategy would be I was like why don't you just you know?
Speaker 0: I always see people playing it And I'm like why don't you just hit it like as hard as humanly possible?
Speaker 1: because if you don't have skill you'll hit it out Of bounds every time.
Speaker 0: I know you know, but that's what I would practice.
Speaker 0: I basically just practiced hitting it as hard as I could swing my arm.
Speaker 0: You know cuz my arm may not be strong enough to say hit a home run and basically It wasn't the speed I can hit that ping-pong ball hard enough to get it past.
Speaker 0: anyone like on the serve I could do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I play that fast, too.
Speaker 1: He just had basically perfect technique, and he was extremely aggressive and everyone up to that point was kind of How big was this room?
Speaker 0: cuz you know and you watch professional size room cuz.
Speaker 0: no I mean like when you watch professional ping-pong People play.
Speaker 0: that's how I feel like a gymnasium, and it's like they got all this open area so they can go way back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so when someone hits it stupid hard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can be way far away.
Speaker 1: Does that get it?
Speaker 1: That's how you play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you did.
Speaker 0: Did you play hit a gymnasium that big?
Speaker 1: You see most players.
Speaker 0: They're not like I was the ceiling.
Speaker 1: the ceiling was high enough Actually even though they can hit it so far.
Speaker 1: They don't tend to hit it that high.
Speaker 1: The perfect shot bear doesn't like barely hit the net touches the corner Touches the net because you're allowed to touch the net just not on the serve.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right, but the thing basically it was like playing against Mike Tyson, so I realize you know now I'm fighting my way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Mike Tyson now perfect strategy.
Speaker 1: I'm fighting my way through the losers bracket, and if I make it back to the top I'll have to play the same guy again.
Speaker 1: I'll have to fight this guy again I'll have to beat him twice, and I have a strategy.
Speaker 1: I've been observing him play And I scored the points I scored.
Speaker 1: I scored by being defensive and then luring him into a sense of security And then I would get Luke Morgan air hockey strategy.
Speaker 1: It worked real well because the points I scored toward the end I'd basically he'd hit it hard.
Speaker 1: I'd hit it back like I made a mistake.
Speaker 1: So he's got this nice easy lob coming in But I put a sneaky backspin on it so we go to slam it and it go right into the net Uh-huh, so I have to basically hold out and play defensively until he gets tired.
Speaker 0: I predict you'll still lose, but perhaps score a slightly better margin.
Speaker 1: I'm expecting to get second plays in this tournament, but this guy I just I don't think everyone else you've been seen in this tournament is not so good.
Speaker 1: the losers bracket is no concern of mine.
Speaker 0: How about the people who are still in the winners bracket?
Speaker 1: I'm not worried, okay?
Speaker 1: You know they warned me when I went up against this guy.
Speaker 1: They're like.
Speaker 1: you know if you beat him that's gonna be like the biggest upset ever.
Speaker 0: Then he'd be in the losers bracket and come back and get you yeah.
Speaker 1: And I I didn't realize they were like yeah rims the dark horse he's gonna do.
Speaker 1: he's not Now.
Speaker 0: so I think I'm gonna get to work from home tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I hope the VPN It doesn't doesn't work now.
Speaker 1: What kind of VPN is it?
Speaker 1: Cisco VPN software with the RSA key?
Speaker 0: No, it's it's it's just.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: you open up the Cisco VPN software you click You tell what any kind of password and no it's just Cisco at VPN.
Speaker 0: That's all it is.
Speaker 0: It's VPN something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, but there are different clients for the Cisco VP anyway.
Speaker 0: anyway That's all it says on.
Speaker 0: it is his go VPN and all you do is type in your username and password for the.
Speaker 1: you know The network and urine and there's because I use the any connect client, which is actually a lot better.
Speaker 0: Whatever they gave me the only Mac client.
Speaker 0: They had because of my work.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so if it doesn't work then I might be anyway.
Speaker 0: What else?
Speaker 0: so oh yes?
Speaker 0: There's something I've been that's if you pay attention to front row crew calm Which you should go to and you know I know a lot of people just subscribe to us in iTunes and never go to our Website.
Speaker 1: we got a forum.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: There's the forum yes, but you know people go there.
Speaker 0: people tend to go directly to the forum though And they don't go to front row crew calm our website.
Speaker 0: that has stuff on it A lot of stuff and it's gonna have a lot more stuff soon.
Speaker 1: We always have that thing of the day.
Speaker 1: you realize those are links to things on the internet.
Speaker 1: Click on them.
Speaker 0: yeah But anyway our website has lots of stuff And it actually now has a news column.
Speaker 0: and in that news column in the bottom left of the home page You can also look at all the old news is by clicking on the word news We're putting stuff there like you know convention schedules and all you know that sort of stuff, so I put a news there recently But it has me getting a lot of attention because I neglected to mention it on the show.
Speaker 0: So you finally remembered to mention it on the show?
Speaker 0: basically You know on our side of our forum.
Speaker 0: We've got this one advertisement there from project wonderful right and Since I've had it there.
Speaker 0: It's gotten us like 25 dollars.
Speaker 0: It's not exactly the most lucrative advertisement in the world and You know that geek nights itself will never have advertisements, and I don't think front recruit calm will have advertisements though other things May have advertising.
Speaker 0: we're only promising about those two things.
Speaker 0: So if we make another show like you know I didn't say Scott's box might have advertising one day nights.
Speaker 0: geek candidates might have Might have advertising, but not geek nights anyway.
Speaker 0: But I figured hey this project wonderful.
Speaker 0: You know I want to see how ad buying works.
Speaker 0: You know I've got this $25.
Speaker 0: I can just buy ads with those $25 You know and if I buy them from places that are about equivalent to us in terms of you know monies I can get a whole lot of ads.
Speaker 0: the thing is I need ads right they're all images.
Speaker 1: I need someone to photoshop up some images to For you know that are basically add the moral of what Scott is just rambling about is design is an ad and you'll be able To win a prize.
Speaker 1: that is actually pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Yes, we have a real prize.
Speaker 0: so in if you go to the forum or There's a thread geek nights ad contest And it tells you the sizes of the ads that we need.
Speaker 0: and it also tell it is also source materials in terms of you vector graphics of all our logos that you can use to help you make your ads.
Speaker 0: and basically whoever you make an ad email it to us put it in the forum thread do whatever and Whichever one we select is the winner.
Speaker 0: and if they all suck there won't be a winner, but hopefully there'll be some good ones.
Speaker 1: They win the prize.
Speaker 0: you'll win the prize.
Speaker 0: And the prize is basically I have this.
Speaker 0: you know Akira manga is six volumes.
Speaker 0: I have the dark horse six volumes But kodancha is coming out with the same thing again.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna buy the kodancha edition and then whichever you know I mean the dark horse is already an awesome addition, and I can't imagine the kodancha will be worse.
Speaker 0: So you know I'm probably.
Speaker 0: I'll keep one and the other set will be the prize.
Speaker 0: you'll win all six volumes of Akira.
Speaker 0: That's like a hundred and eighty dollars worth of comics right there.
Speaker 0: the whole thing won all six volumes.
Speaker 0: I'll mail them to whoever the winner is.
Speaker 0: that's a crazy prize just for making some you know jpegs or whatever.
Speaker 0: so if you have photoshop or artistic skills of any kind This is the contest for you.
Speaker 0: You could win six volumes of like one of the best mangas ever.
Speaker 0: So there it is.
Speaker 0: enter our contest.
Speaker 0: All right We need ads that we can buy and hopefully the ads.
Speaker 0: when we buy you'll get to see them around the Internet's on other people's Websites, and hopefully it will make more geek nights listeners from people who click on the ads.
Speaker 0: of course somebody clicks on ads.
Speaker 0: I don't know if that's a good listener.
Speaker 0: I just want to see how this stuff works really.
Speaker 0: that's my my curiosity.
Speaker 1: All right, so do you have any non meta to talk about?
Speaker 0: yes, okay?
Speaker 0: Non metas you want to news?
Speaker 1: Well, it's Thursday.
Speaker 1: We don't have to do anything anyway.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I want to talk about this thing that rim just told me about ten minutes ago.
Speaker 1: Did you look up the details?
Speaker 0: I looked up all the details I could find in the New York Times Basically jetblue my favorite airline.
Speaker 0: I fly in jetblue you know pretty much unless I don't have a choice And I have to fly someone else because they're just awesome.
Speaker 0: They had a plan the and basically the promotion was all you can jet for $599.
Speaker 0: they would sell you a ticket that would allow you to travel on unlimited domestic United States flights on jetblue airlays between September 8th and October 8th 2009. so that's and basically you know the plan was gonna end on Friday.
Speaker 0: It's sold out yesterday Wednesday two days in advance because there was Overwhelming demand and that's that's $600 covers all the domestic taxes and fees.
Speaker 0: That's it $599.
Speaker 1: the thing is it's cool because Greyhound had something like that forever.
Speaker 1: I believe they still do where you could just basically wander around America with this kind of golden Greyhound ticket.
Speaker 0: I think that they should always just have on permanent.
Speaker 0: You know offer an annual Unlimited flight ticket.
Speaker 0: you know like make it six thousand dollars or something.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling.
Speaker 1: the only reason this works is because it was specifically a promotion.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean that would be I mean notice.
Speaker 1: It wasn't November through December the holidays.
Speaker 0: I know right Yeah, but I really wonder how it works.
Speaker 0: like you know does this mean that you can just like go to jetblue.com And pick any flight and it says zero dollars when you log?
Speaker 0: log in?
Speaker 1: maybe on every jetblue flight They just left one seat free.
Speaker 0: They just left one, but what if two people with these unlimited passes?
Speaker 0: They didn't say how many unlimited passes they sold.
Speaker 0: all they said is they sold out on Wednesday.
Speaker 1: Maybe only one.
Speaker 1: maybe it's a lie.
Speaker 1: We don't know.
Speaker 0: yeah, it could be that there was.
Speaker 0: they said it was overwhelming demand though.
Speaker 1: So they said they had one and two people tried to buy.
Speaker 0: the thing is like if I was either a on Vacation right I had a month of vacation or B. I was a business traveler.
Speaker 0: I would scoop these up so ludicrously fast.
Speaker 0: in fact I wouldn't be surprised if these are picked up by companies for the employees right, but it's only for one month.
Speaker 1: What are the odds?
Speaker 1: you have that much business traveling in places jetblue goes to?
Speaker 1: well?
Speaker 0: No, but think about this kind of situation.
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 0: let's say you've got like a bunch of employees right and they're all gonna Go on.
Speaker 0: you know you got five different guys.
Speaker 0: You know they're all executives.
Speaker 0: actually there's be flying to different place One.
Speaker 1: jetblue doesn't go to that many places and blue goes to a lot of places.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but not that anywhere in the United States places.
Speaker 0: They go all pretty much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they don't go to a lot of places in the Midwest.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't need to go to like where?
Speaker 0: well Detroit I'm pretty sure they go close enough to Detroit.
Speaker 1: They didn't go anywhere near Detroit when I wanted to fly there.
Speaker 0: well That was way.
Speaker 0: go look at the website.
Speaker 0: now They add places like all the frickin time.
Speaker 1: now when I wanted to I had to go down to Columbia and near DC and Jetblue.
Speaker 0: calm and tell me what you see right now.
Speaker 1: You don't waste all that time.
Speaker 1: all right you can go.
Speaker 0: Still you know they go to Florida.
Speaker 1: There's not that much.
Speaker 1: business traveling is way down and two business travelers like to you know first class.
Speaker 1: There's no first class on jetblue.
Speaker 0: That's that's why jetblue is so awesome because there is no classes.
Speaker 0: It's just one class the whole plane.
Speaker 0: You can pay a little bit more if you want to sit in the like.
Speaker 0: you know the emergency exit rows Because then you have more legroom you know and they every seat has a little TV in it.
Speaker 0: that's totally free and has like a whole bunch of shit to watch.
Speaker 0: and You know they don't bother giving you.
Speaker 0: it's like they realize who wants shitty airline food.
Speaker 0: They just give you a nice little snack animal crackers a little you know biscotti something something Scott.
Speaker 1: They still don't go to Detroit.
Speaker 0: Where do they go anymore?
Speaker 0: They go close to Detroit nothing.
Speaker 0: There's got to be something I guess.
Speaker 1: Chicago, but that's still quite a drive from Detroit.
Speaker 0: who Detroit's a shithole now?
Speaker 0: anyway They don't want to go there Wants to go to Detroit.
Speaker 0: where where else do they not go besides Detroit?
Speaker 1: everywhere?
Speaker 1: that isn't on.
Speaker 0: this fairly short list List is pretty long.
Speaker 0: What major place do they not go Detroit besides, Detroit?
Speaker 0: Everywhere, but Detroit is a lot of places.
Speaker 0: There's 50 freaking states.
Speaker 0: Most of them have major cities in them so far.
Speaker 0: You're only your complaint.
Speaker 0: Is that jetblue?
Speaker 0: Yes, I go to a lot of places because they don't go to one dying city So in the Midwest.
Speaker 0: so I have to sit here and parse out this whole list for you and point out I thought it was a short list, but now it's a big list that is difficult to pass.
Speaker 1: This is four times like 15, and that's it.
Speaker 0: That's a lot of places.
Speaker 0: the United States is only 50 states.
Speaker 0: We you know.
Speaker 1: it appears that they don't go anywhere in Ohio.
Speaker 0: who wants to go to Ohio?
Speaker 1: I have reasons to go to Ohio and I can.
Speaker 0: oh I don't know why you're going to Ohio.
Speaker 0: they go to the good places that people want to go as the as a jetblue is All about is they're just like me.
Speaker 0: they say oh, that's a shitty place.
Speaker 0: who wants to go there?
Speaker 0: They only go to the good places.
Speaker 0: That's why they don't give you the shitty airline food.
Speaker 0: So you know it's just the good parts without the bad parts all right?
Speaker 1: Oh, and when I had to fly to Washington while they do fly there I couldn't use jetblue because they had no flights that went at any reasonable time.
Speaker 1: for one of my business traveling was No, you know whatever because they don't have that many flights.
Speaker 0: They got enough flights.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: They don't go I don't go to they don't go to places.
Speaker 1: I've wanted to go.
Speaker 0: and Second place that you know hi.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, how did it go?
Speaker 0: Yeah?
Speaker 1: I got relatives there.
Speaker 0: I do I tell you okay It's a shit hole.
Speaker 0: no one's to go there.
Speaker 0: Just like Detroit all your relatives live in shitholes.
Speaker 0: what you're saying Anyway, let's let's continue.
Speaker 0: you got anything over there.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I don't you're such a jetblue fanboy.
Speaker 1: It's kind of weird plus I'll admit having flown continental.
Speaker 1: while it's more expensive the planes are much nicer much more comfortable good God not even close.
Speaker 1: well They are.
Speaker 0: I've been in a bunch of different airlines and jetblue is more comfortable times a whole bunch.
Speaker 1: well I disagree.
Speaker 1: have you flown on one of the newer 757s?
Speaker 0: Who wants to be on a very in 757 to be an airbus European quality?
Speaker 1: Busted old Airbus?
Speaker 0: no it's not busted old.
Speaker 1: those are all like a three.
Speaker 1: well like an a320.
Speaker 0: That's kind of an old plane No, but there yes the a320 is a model that has been around for a while.
Speaker 0: But all of jetblue's a 320s are manufactured very recent not that recently in fact.
Speaker 1: I'll point out It's got a camera.
Speaker 0: isn't that old?
Speaker 0: they're less than 10 years old.
Speaker 1: I'll find out.
Speaker 1: continental by far has the youngest fleet This information from?
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 1: you can go look it up.
Speaker 0: So you just you can go look it up, but you you where did you look it up that you saw this continental?
Speaker 0: Oh, so you believe what they say about themselves.
Speaker 1: well the thing is Scott You can't say something like that in your advertising as a fact and get away with it if you're wrong.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and considering that most of the flights.
Speaker 1: I was looking at are all like 757s, which are pretty new plane I'm willing to believe them.
Speaker 0: no yeah, I have no interest in these shitty other airlines.
Speaker 0: Okay, you're like a separate with their separate classes.
Speaker 1: Understand how much of a fanboy Scott is about jetblue, and they idea all these other airlines.
Speaker 0: They have super connections jetblue direct flight.
Speaker 1: You know other airlines have direct flights.
Speaker 0: Yeah, jetblue's only dirt.
Speaker 1: no jetblue has connections.
Speaker 1: in fine You can connect.
Speaker 1: if it was a lot cheaper to fly to Seattle through jetblue if we took those connections Yeah, that's cuz.
Speaker 0: you're actually buying two cheap tickets instead of the one nice.
Speaker 1: That's all.
Speaker 1: the connection is yeah Didn't you just say jetblue doesn't have connection?
Speaker 0: well They don't you know did they?
Speaker 0: a connection is always possible, but I mean you know they offer them.
Speaker 1: in fact That was the number one recommendation when I put in our plan to go to Seattle.
Speaker 0: They were like you can go.
Speaker 0: take the connection if you want to.
Speaker 0: I'm going Scott.
Speaker 1: your assertion that jetblue does not have connections Was patently false.
Speaker 0: other airlines, though.
Speaker 0: It'll be like you want to get from here to here.
Speaker 0: You got to do a connection.
Speaker 1: No In fact blue this play.
Speaker 0: in
Speaker 1: fact when I went to continental to check the first thing they offered me was a direct flight and the Only reason I didn't fly continental was that the flight that was the cheapest was at these like two hours later than the jetblue Flight which was a little bit worse because we're gonna go there Thursday night.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I would rather have flown continental.
Speaker 0: jetblue is the wind.
Speaker 0: you can go on your shitty continental flights.
Speaker 0: Which is that first of all right.
Speaker 0: second the continental flights?
Speaker 0: Oh, you know talking about jetblue doesn't go anywhere.
Speaker 0: continental goes from fucking Newark.
Speaker 0: right jetblue at least goes to J.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I like playing.
Speaker 1: you realize if I fly continental I connect out of Stewart Which is right next to our house, so I go through the shitty Stewart Airport.
Speaker 0: Far more convenient Stewart.
Speaker 0: I had to drive to and park there Scott.
Speaker 1: There's a free shuttle from the train station.
Speaker 0: I was.
Speaker 0: I gotta go take go to the train station.
Speaker 0: I can park there.
Speaker 1: you take the shuttle I can walk to the train stage.
Speaker 0: you're gonna walk all the way to the train Station for me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like right there.
Speaker 1: I did that the last time I flew out of Stewart.
Speaker 0: It's a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: All right, I could take a train right at the JFK.
Speaker 0: No problem
Speaker 1: Plus Scott flying from Stewart to the city Connecting to new to Newark or LaGuardia or whatever doesn't matter even which airline I'm pretty much always going to from now on after this PAX thing fly out of Stewart even if I just connect a JFK Cuz I don't have to go through any security.
Speaker 1: really there's like this tiny line at Stewart.
Speaker 1: It's a nice tiny little airport and when I fly in I'm already behind security.
Speaker 0: No, that's all you.
Speaker 0: Anyway enough of it shows.
Speaker 0: not we're taking too much time in this airport.
Speaker 1: I was gonna go right past it, but Scott just had to get all fanboy about jetblue.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's not my fault.
Speaker 0: You're you don't have you don't know how to fly.
Speaker 1: yeah, so how am I gonna get to Ohio?
Speaker 0: In your car or don't go because it's not a place for people to get?
Speaker 0: very it's not habitable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, great anyway, so Considering what we're gonna be talking about for the rest of this show if Scott doesn't if Scott can let go of the jetblue thing Interesting the life expectancy in the US has reached an all-time high of 77.9 years, it's pretty old Except that it puts us at about 50th in nations.
Speaker 0: So who's number one?
Speaker 1: I didn't even look at the list.
Speaker 1: We're pretty far down.
Speaker 1: Albania beats us significantly.
Speaker 1: I think Japan is number one.
Speaker 1: to be honest that makes the life expectancy.
Speaker 1: There's like 83.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Jeff You know there's always that stereotypical really old Japanese verse, but here's the thing this what's interesting and incredibly Sad, but at the same time anyone who didn't see this coming has been living under a rock.
Speaker 1: so most likely it is not.
Speaker 1: It's not that we're rising.
Speaker 1: You know this is the all-time high.
Speaker 1: It's the all-time high because we've peaked and it's dropping from this point forward and sadly enough it's actually dropping pretty rapidly.
Speaker 1: in certain areas of America and unlike most other industrialized nations the gap between people who live very long and people who don't live so long is Widening at a somewhat horrifying pace
Speaker 0: just like the gap between people with a lot of money And it's based on much money
Speaker 1: almost entirely in geography.
Speaker 1: apparently The life expectancy is dropping.
Speaker 1: is dropping or stagnating in rural areas and rising in urban areas.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it's rising in places where people have money and going down in place of people.
Speaker 1: but pretty much what it comes down to.
Speaker 1: Every cause of death that is causing the life expectancy to drop in the u.s.. Boils down to smoking Obesity mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: That's it everyone.
Speaker 1: everything that is causing life expectancy to drop in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Is related to obesity and it's all these diseases caused by obesity.
Speaker 1: It's type 2 diabetes is high blood pressure.
Speaker 0: Actually, I heard a lot of stuff recently about like hospital infections like causing a whole bunch of deaths.
Speaker 0: Is that on a list?
Speaker 1: They're not even close.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much obesity and smoking.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess yeah Oh, I guess you know I guess the things that I heard were about the hospital infections were cause of death.
Speaker 0: But I guess you know in terms cause of death is different than overall decrease in life expectancy Yep, and pretty much it basically the cause.
Speaker 1: life expectancy in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Is dropping among poor people primarily in or in rural areas?
Speaker 1: primarily in the south along the Mississippi and in the southern Midwest and in Appalachia Mm-hmm, and it's rising everywhere else.
Speaker 1: and the scary thing is if you look at the maps that kind of break down Where it's rising and where it's falling and you look at the last point like from the 60s to the 80s and from the 80s It was going up almost everywhere until the late 80s and then it started dropping in all the places where there are fat people.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh Well, what happened around?
Speaker 0: then?
Speaker 0: they made that happen.
Speaker 1: people started getting fat.
Speaker 0: Why did they get fat then?
Speaker 0: I don't know What was it that you know, I mean maybe corn.
Speaker 0: Why didn't people get fat in the 70s?
Speaker 1: but the scary that I mean, it's basically the fact that the life expectancy is dropping primarily because of Emanently treatable and preventable things like Obesity being fat and smoking.
Speaker 1: Yep, and then otherwise our health care is great.
Speaker 1: So if you live in cities and you're not fat your life expectancy is probably in the top of the world in America But the average is brought down so much.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't like the good the cities of America compared to the world.
Speaker 1: If you break if you basically break down the people who do well in America versus the people who do poorly like the top and the bottom.
Speaker 1: the top of America is in like the top five or six and the bottom of America is Not too far off from the third world.
Speaker 0: how it is like the top?
Speaker 0: No, no, what if you did the same thing for like, you know, Japan, you know, are there places in Japan?
Speaker 1: we're taught, you know, and then like, you know the disparity between high and low is Greater in America than it is and almost anywhere else.
Speaker 1: as far as I can tell from these stuff
Speaker 0: I'm in America is bigger than a lot of other places pretty much like the US
Speaker 1: Russia
Speaker 0: Russia Canada and China Much the only place Australia kind of are the only places that are really big enough to have a geographical disparity.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean, but it's interesting that apparently Argentina up until the 80s It looks like people who had the longest life Expectancies tended to be the people in rural areas and that is rapidly changing again primarily due to obesity and smoking.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz cities used to be dangerous places, you know.
Speaker 1: Well pollution is down in cities a crime is down and all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 1: the studies are fat.
Speaker 1: I suggest that you read the study and check out all these graphs.
Speaker 0: You keep it in your bed all the time.
Speaker 1: Well my beds there and whatever I talk I need to gesticulate.
Speaker 0: you need to hit something though.
Speaker 0: You could just gesticulate in the air like an Italian person.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I like to pound on tables.
Speaker 1: Yeah One of the biggest things when I get that much founding is to have a table or four burning wheels Specifically a table that is designed to.
Speaker 1: if you pound on it, it will not shake but it will resonate.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, you're gonna go to get it.
Speaker 0: go to the carpenter and get this table made.
Speaker 1: I should make it hollow so that you hear this like booming pound every time someone pounds on it in my break Maybe inside the hollowness.
Speaker 1: I will have a microphone hooked up to an amplifier.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you have a hole cut in the bottom and then put some strings across it.
Speaker 0: So your table will be guitar Guitar table guitar table.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe I should make that.
Speaker 0: that'd be on the Internet's so fast I gotta do is make a hollow table cut a hole in it and put some strings across it and then I got a guitar.
Speaker 1: So anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: To what?
Speaker 0: one thing I want to say.
Speaker 0: Yes a better idea than a guitar table a harp table.
Speaker 1: How about just a harp?
Speaker 0: No, it's turn the harp on the side and then put a piece of glass over it.
Speaker 1: But then how is that gonna help?
Speaker 0: I mean play it from the bottom All right.
Speaker 0: But or you take the piece of glass off when you want to play and you realize the glass on when you want it.
Speaker 1: Awesome tape harps aren't enclosed by default.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: you only put the glass there when you want to use the harp as a table and then you take the glass off to play it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, as I was about to say before we get to sidetracked with unrelated BS.
Speaker 1: It's time for things of the day now.
Speaker 1: a long time ago Scott and I started using the word Randy as in James Randy whenever we were referring to bullshit, you know a Chiropractic or homeopathy or any of that BS.
Speaker 0: We call it Randy bullshit partly in honor of the fact That you know British people use the word Randy in a completely different way.
Speaker 1: That is true but anyway you know we use it partly in honor of James Randy's noble fight against all this BS and We needed a word to encapsulate that and it served very well And I've caught a lot of listeners and people who we know using it.
Speaker 1: It's entered kind of the front row crew lexicon and Just recently not that long ago.
Speaker 1: I started using another term After a certain YouTube video that is kind of my thing of the day where that one member of Congress basically punked that girl who called Obama a Nazi and It reminded me and reminded Scott of way back when Bill Clinton was giving a talk and someone was like blah blah blah And I love it was conspiracy and Bill Clinton basically was like shut the fuck up.
Speaker 0: That was a good one.
Speaker 1: And then I thought all the way back to when Buzz Aldrin was confronted with a guy who accused him of being a coward for lying about the fact that he went to The moon and Buzz Aldrin looks at him and punches him in the face.
Speaker 1: Oh I never agree with using violence to react to words.
Speaker 1: I Basically would not have no court would have convicted Buzz Aldrin for punching this guy.
Speaker 0: No court did.
Speaker 1: he's a free man And I realized that that is what I want out of politics.
Speaker 1: I want more people to be like Barney or to be like Bill Clinton.
Speaker 1: when someone is stupid Don't be political don't you know him and Han be like, oh, well, you know you believe that but I believe this and blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: I want politicians to just pull a Buzz Aldrin and either physically or Verbally punch them in the face and the verb I'm going to use for this henceforth is Buzz Aldrin.
Speaker 1: See,
Speaker 0: I think the problem here is that unlike Randy you're trying to do this intentionally as opposed to by accident Which means if the chances of success of this catching on are low and also Buzz Aldrin ing is not as catchy as buzzing or Aldrin ing
Speaker 1: while not catching it
Speaker 0: up on their own.
Speaker 0: So it's gonna be.
Speaker 1: I've already had this discussion and I realized that having the full term Buzz Aldrin ing Has I think the diction of it and the rhythm it means it's not gonna happen.
Speaker 1: No and the fact that it's so long adds this sort of inherent comedic timing and That seemed.
Speaker 1: I think that is what's going to make it succeed more so than anything else.
Speaker 0: I think it's gonna fail.
Speaker 1: I think it's going to succeed.
Speaker 1: In fact, I used it in another thread and one other person has already used it.
Speaker 1: I think it is going to catch on.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's gonna catch on.
Speaker 1: I've defined Buzz Aldrin ing as and I quote - upon reaching the conclusion that the person with whom you are debating is incapable of rational discourse issue further discussion in favor of either public ridicule or hilarious violence.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 0: I like that.
Speaker 0: There's a good that your definitions perfect.
Speaker 1: I think the definition and everything together.
Speaker 1: It's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: At least it will be as widespread.
Speaker 0: I'm not joining the club until it spreads on its own because I don't want to skew the.
Speaker 1: that's fine But I'm going to use it as much as possible.
Speaker 1: thing is to don't.
Speaker 0: the thing is you.
Speaker 0: I think I have a feeling knowing You you're going to artificially overuse it.
Speaker 1: I'm lucky though.
Speaker 1: It can't be overused because it's so rare Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: No one Buzz Aldrin's anyone anymore except Buzz Aldrin.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: I mean what I. I couldn't find that many videos.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I guess you could Blagojevich instead.
Speaker 0: So your thing of the day is videos of people Buzz Aldrin ing people.
Speaker 1: I think of the day is the forum post where I coined the Buzz Aldrin phrase and it is the video of Barney Frank Bill Clinton self-aggrandizing thing of the day and Buzz Aldrin.
Speaker 1: Buzz Aldrin ing All right.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day, I know people who are geeks don't pay attention to the sports like we do.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I'm talking about bolt.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Good.
Speaker 0: How could you not?
Speaker 0: Good God There is a man from Jamaica.
Speaker 0: He's really tall taller than us.
Speaker 0: He's fast.
Speaker 0: His name is Usain Bolt.
Speaker 1: I don't know if he did any drugs or not Scott I'll say this never in the history of man has there been a more clear-cut case of nominative determinism than mr Bolt.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean Usain Bolt, you know, there is no evidence that he is, you know partaking in any You know performance enhancing substances or anything of the sort, although it's not you know impossible.
Speaker 0: Whether he has or he hasn't the fact of the matter is Usain Bolt is the fastest human being to have ever existed in the history of human beings.
Speaker 1: as long as we have been Measuring the speed of human beings not just by a little bit It's not like he's breaking these records by like a hundredth of a second.
Speaker 1: you watch the video.
Speaker 1: He's just gone.
Speaker 0: Look at these videos.
Speaker 0: This is actually what's going on right now.
Speaker 0: is the the world championship in athletics, right?
Speaker 0: It's in Berlin And he broke the world record for the hundred meter - Nine, he ran it in nine set nine point five eight seconds.
Speaker 1: So think about.
Speaker 0: think about a hundred meters.
Speaker 0: now think about you know Get a stopwatch and do nine point.
Speaker 0: you could watch the videos as high-res videos on YouTube.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna link to them.
Speaker 0: He did the 200 meters.
Speaker 0: I think it was today or very, you know, maybe yesterday 1919 200 meters Right, so that's a nine point.
Speaker 0: five eight times two is Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: You can see that he's pretty much around in the same speed about on both of these He's up against.
Speaker 0: basically you look at them.
Speaker 0: line up for these races, right those are the fastest human beings that currently live all of them just lined up there and he's like Multiple strides ahead of everyone else.
Speaker 0: It's insane and like Tyson Gaye from the United States He's out there.
Speaker 0: if Usain Bolt wasn't out there Tyson Gaye would be like breaking the world record and stuff You know, it's like he looks slow next to bolt.
Speaker 0: But if you compare it like Tyson Gaye to the all of history He's like, you know crazy fast like winning awesome fast, but Usain Bolt is out there Looks like he's cheating but he's not.
Speaker 0: he's just the fastest person to ever to ever be and it's you have to watch this Just because holy shit.
Speaker 0: and well actually this is one article.
Speaker 0: That was really interesting.
Speaker 0: that showed a Graph of the world record in the hundred meter dash over time, you know by year and it showed like.
Speaker 0: he's like, okay If we do a graph, you know, and then we what equation matches, you know this data plot, right?
Speaker 0: Usain Bolt was a crazy outlier like he's.
Speaker 0: if We continue, you know there should be a. first of all you assume that there's some limit to human speed that if you follow that graph the limit is somewhere around like nine point two right for the hundred meters.
Speaker 0: and If you look at like, okay, you know Usain Bolt just did a nine five eight and you look at the graph.
Speaker 0: according to the graph.
Speaker 0: Nobody should be doing a nine five eight for like another like ten or twenty years.
Speaker 0: Well, if not ever yeah, because the fact that there are limits to what a human body can do Right, but we're assuming that the limits, you know, we're assuming that the limit is on this graph as opposed to you know Some other right.
Speaker 0: well mathematically speaking we were talking about this.
Speaker 0: No one's gonna be breaking these records for decades.
Speaker 1: The only person at work who seemed to know about this at all was the French guy who was like, hey Bolt and I'm like, yeah, everyone's like, oh, yeah, but no one else knew.
Speaker 1: Oh, but the thing is I pointed out to my co-workers and they all paused and thought oh, yeah crap.
Speaker 1: And then they were all kind of Disappointed and disenchanted with the whole affair.
Speaker 0: I basically pointed out watch the video.
Speaker 1: No, no disappointed and disenchanted in that These sorts of pure athletic competitions like the fastest runner the fastest swimmer the fastest biker all those things the farthest thrower.
Speaker 1: It's gotten to the point to where the technique will not change.
Speaker 1: The technique is basically he gets run as fast as you possibly can but there is technique.
Speaker 1: Every human gets the effectively.
Speaker 1: if you were a competitor at all you get the same training or the effectively the same training.
Speaker 1: the amount of how hard you try is Not going to matter because you're not trying any less hard than everyone else.
Speaker 0: So it's the same thing with Lance Armstrong giant lungs.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: So the hundred meter - and the 200 meter - and all these things are really only now tests of genetics.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is just a competition of who has the best You know.
Speaker 0: enhancement by other means.
Speaker 1: Training yes training and chemicals, but even if we outlaw chemicals, it's purely genetics assuming the trainees equal for all.
Speaker 1: yep, so it's a competition of who can find the people who have the genetics to beat the record and convince them to be the person to beat the record and have that single-minded focus for their whole lives and Actually train them fully and competently to do it.
Speaker 1: Well, look at you know, Michael Phelps same thing, but isn't it kind of weird that we're basically just testing our genes?
Speaker 1: We're one step cord gattaca.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean I think what they Know.
Speaker 0: and first of all in Wikipedia There's a graph that shows Usain Bolt's hundred meter times over the years and it shows like, you know How he got faster and faster and now he's like he could get he could be faster next year Like that'd be insane.
Speaker 0: It's crazy but it pretty much the only person who's gonna break any of his records in the foreseeable future is Him and that's that.
Speaker 0: so yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's got to be sucked to be the really fast guy who is gonna be running like next year.
Speaker 1: And you're just done.
Speaker 0: That's I'm saying Tyson gay.
Speaker 0: It's like if Usain Bolt wasn't there all over.
Speaker 0: the news would be like Tyson gay.
Speaker 0: American breaks world record in hundred meter - but Nope, it's not him.
Speaker 0: Someone else came faster at the same time.
Speaker 0: Like imagine if you were as good as hockey as Wayne Gretzky Right, and then someone better than a Wayne Gretzky happens to be like joining the NHL at the same time as you.
Speaker 0: well now You're not gonna be all awesome and famous because this other guy has taken all the glory.
Speaker 0: But if he wasn't there, you'd be the next Wayne Gretzky, but you know, well hockey is also a thing of genetics.
Speaker 1: I mean if you were born north of the Messier line or at least in Russia or Scandinavia.
Speaker 0: Anyway, all right.
Speaker 0: So Today's show.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Wonder how long we'll talk about this now?
Speaker 1: the very we're not going to get into specific.
Speaker 0: I mean, this is the kind of thing you could talk for a hundred years and never be done talking.
Speaker 1: It's also the kind of thing where if we wanted to talk about the specifics we would gather all the evidence we need And that sort of thing take forever.
Speaker 1: Basically also as an ulterior motive Scott suggested the show for once and as you all know Scott does not like to talk about anything Political.
Speaker 1: so whenever I can to talk about anything whenever he has an inclination to have a topic on a Thursday That is even close to the realm of possibly being in any way maybe tangentially related to something that could be considered politics I'm going to indulge him.
Speaker 1: We're talking about health care because The the debate the national dialogue about health care in America Has basically reverted.
Speaker 1: it is reverted to people wargling about Nazis.
Speaker 1: But at the same time it's weird.
Speaker 1: the right is accusing the left of being Nazi Socialists, which doesn't quite work in the first place.
Speaker 1: Because fascism and socialism are polar opposites Even though Nazis were called national socialists, but that wasn't what they weren't actually socialists.
Speaker 1: But how can you accuse someone of being a socialist and a Nazi because you have no idea what you're talking about?
Speaker 0: Yeah, we can get past that part.
Speaker 0: It's not the important part.
Speaker 0: It's just Everyone who is discussing the issue of health care in the media and in the government and among the populace.
Speaker 0: Pretty much 99% of people who are opening their mouths are complete retards, you know.
Speaker 0: Maybe not complete retards as a whole but complete retards on this subject and they have no clue what they're talking about.
Speaker 0: Or even if they're intelligent, they're talking.
Speaker 0: they're discussing the wrong thing and just everyone is wrong Even though you know, you might be sitting at home thinking these Oh, yeah, these nice people are right and these people are wrong.
Speaker 0: or you know, Obama's plan is good Obama's plan is better.
Speaker 0: who gives a shit.
Speaker 0: You're all wrong Stupid.
Speaker 1: I would argue that it's not necessarily a matter of everyone being wrong Objectively.
Speaker 1: Well now the problem is that because the national dialogue about it on all levels except possibly in committee Committee in Congress is like the only place where Theoretically, you know what?
Speaker 0: See span if you want.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the floor is not where you see stuff, you know There's a threat on the forums.
Speaker 0: the people who have trouble going to sleep see span.
Speaker 1: The thing is you might get unlucky and it'll be prank call night.
Speaker 1: People see span gets prank called more than like anything.
Speaker 0: See span prank calls are awesome.
Speaker 0: Go on YouTube find some.
Speaker 1: Where's that?
Speaker 1: My favorite whenever is the guy just calls up and he's like something something something fuck.
Speaker 1: No, no even.
Speaker 1: but the guy was like am I on the air and the guys like yes and he goes fuck.
Speaker 1: But anyway the it's that the national dialogue is.
Speaker 1: you know there's.
Speaker 1: we had that whole show about high-level discourse and how.
Speaker 1: the wider a discussion is the lower the level of discourse becomes simply by the nature of the Transmission of memes.
Speaker 0: that's the exact phenomenon.
Speaker 0: We're seeing here one Exactly the same thing.
Speaker 1: the national dialogue is at such a low and broad level that There cannot be debate like.
Speaker 1: it's not a matter of right and wrong It's a matter of the.
Speaker 1: the arguments are such a simplistic level that you cannot be right by nature of the fact that you cannot Even address the scope of the issue.
Speaker 0: So let us address the scope of the issue.
Speaker 0: now that we have an intelligent, you know Radio show here now we can do it right because we're so smart.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Well, here's why we can do it one.
Speaker 1: We're just gonna give our opinion.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's it.
Speaker 1: Benji pendulum.
Speaker 1: What about us?
Speaker 1: We're just crazy crazy guy.
Speaker 1: Don't listen to me self-deprecation is pretty much that the ticket.
Speaker 0: He's saying crazy shit.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, I'm just some crazy guy.
Speaker 0: I'm not an expert and you know what?
Speaker 0: I am NOT an expert on health care.
Speaker 0: Nope, not at all, but I do know Some fundamental basic things that many people ignore.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's pretty simple when you really break it down one.
Speaker 1: Currently in the world there are finite resources.
Speaker 1: Yes, no matter what we do.
Speaker 1: There is a limited.
Speaker 0: some things are relevant are effectively infinite For example music or atoms.
Speaker 1: atoms, they're there for you.
Speaker 1: We just want atoms.
Speaker 1: You don't care.
Speaker 1: What kind?
Speaker 1: I got a whole bunch.
Speaker 1: But if you want specific kinds, it gets a little more dicey.
Speaker 1: I want some gold Adam I can't get you that much.
Speaker 1: strontium and her platinum atoms.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the issue here is this right?
Speaker 0: We have these finite resources.
Speaker 0: that are health care resources.
Speaker 0: doctors Hospital beds room in hospitals met a flume shots MRI, you know.
Speaker 1: just to zoom out for a second It's not even.
Speaker 1: it's a finite resources of just resources in general and of all the resources and all the things we can use them On.
Speaker 1: we have to take a portion of that and decide what portion.
Speaker 1: yeah I'm dedicated to health care before we even talk about the health care part.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's right, you know, it's like, okay.
Speaker 0: So we're digging up, you know magnets.
Speaker 0: Let's say right, you know, we need not say we're digging up some uraniums, right?
Speaker 0: We could use these uraniums for radiation therapy for cancer patients Or we could use it for a nuclear power plant or bombs or bombs watched Should we you know, which?
Speaker 0: where do we put it right?
Speaker 0: Which one is the best for our society?
Speaker 1: now think about this.
Speaker 1: They will both save lives Nuclear power less pollution.
Speaker 1: It gets us off of you know, all the trouble we're having now with oil and coal that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Don't get me started on nuclear waste.
Speaker 1: It's not nearly as big as deals ever makes out to be but that's a whole different discussion.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it'll save lives in the long run.
Speaker 1: MRIs save lives Obviously, you know.
Speaker 1: which avenue of saving lives are we going to take?
Speaker 0: Not just which Avenue right but it's like, okay.
Speaker 0: I have X tons of uranium.
Speaker 0: How many of those?
Speaker 0: how many uraniums do I allocate to this one?
Speaker 0: And how many do I allocate to that one?
Speaker 0: It's totally a German board game situation, right?
Speaker 0: How how many guys do I put in?
Speaker 0: You know Galicia and how many do I put in the Castillo?
Speaker 1: Never put guys in Galicia.
Speaker 1: It's only worth like four points.
Speaker 0: I know right, but you know what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: Anyway, besides I put them all in the Castille and I always win.
Speaker 0: Yeah So that's right.
Speaker 0: See these are the people are addressing this whole problem of you know.
Speaker 0: How do we ensure what we've already got?
Speaker 0: Nobody's asking the question of well, you know, why?
Speaker 0: what is this that we've already got?
Speaker 0: What do you know?
Speaker 0: What do we do?
Speaker 0: You know, they're always.
Speaker 0: they're already have like us accepted all these fundamentals.
Speaker 0: It's always if there's somehow laws of the universe.
Speaker 1: Here's the analogy that what the American people are doing is arguing about how to spend the money They won on the lottery that happens next week.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: That is what we were doing.
Speaker 0: We're arguing on all these specifics and all these details and I believe ignoring all the fundamentals because we're just accepting them and not even Thinking that they could be changed.
Speaker 1: or it's so simple, you know, the national dialogue cannot be complex.
Speaker 1: It is impossible to have a high-level dialogue across that many people even if everyone is intelligent.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter how intelligent you are.
Speaker 1: It's too complex of an issue for any one person to grasp let alone Everyone, you know, especially even if everyone's intelligent Not everyone's an expert on this particular issue.
Speaker 0: There are too many things to know, you know, we're computer people.
Speaker 0: We don't know enough about this to have a super intelligent discussion.
Speaker 0: discussion.
Speaker 1: but to the national diet.
Speaker 1: It doesn't mean we can't have a national dialogue and the.
Speaker 1: but if we have a national dialogue It can't be about the specifics or the made-up stuff like the death panels and all the wargling.
Speaker 1: the high-level dialogue is very simple What is what do we want?
Speaker 1: universal health care or not?
Speaker 1: Should we have it?
Speaker 1: Is it a right?
Speaker 1: you know all these basic questions.
Speaker 1: how what is the core goal?
Speaker 1: and Until we answer that question Everything else we do is just bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all these specific things like oh, we're gonna tax here Are we gonna decide?
Speaker 0: you know this here and it does.
Speaker 0: those are specific things.
Speaker 0: You don't decide that until you figured out, you know, the the building block first, right?
Speaker 0: It's like what is our actual goal?
Speaker 0: Is it to have the most people living the most years possible or is it to have the most people living the most?
Speaker 0: Comfortable years, but you know, it's like are we gonna?
Speaker 0: you know, are we gonna wait the years based on quality of life?
Speaker 0: Are we gonna?
Speaker 0: you know is every is a year for Bill Gates to live as you know the same as a year for some Homeless bum to live, you know, what are we going to value?
Speaker 0: What are we trying to maximize and minimize here?
Speaker 0: So that is the.
Speaker 0: that is step one.
Speaker 0: You've got to decide What is your goal and you know and the problem is already look how high level this is.
Speaker 1: it did such a. we have Priorities as a society, but we don't write them down.
Speaker 1: We don't decide specifically, you know, these are the priorities of our society.
Speaker 1: This is what we want to accomplish as a people to better ourselves.
Speaker 1: It's health care more or less important than the military?
Speaker 1: is it more or less important than certain economic factors than certain ideologies like capitalism or socialism?
Speaker 1: and We haven't even addressed that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: The other thing right.
Speaker 0: check this out, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say, you know, I just gave you all these different possible goals, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say our goal is to have the most people live the longest.
Speaker 0: just you know, I'm just saying right.
Speaker 0: Let's say it.
Speaker 0: Let's pretend You know the best way to get the most people live the longest might not be to spend money on medicine and hospitals.
Speaker 0: You're actually probably gonna get a lot more people living on average a lot longer if you spend your money on things like health education Exercising better food.
Speaker 1: I mean look at what I just talked about in the news.
Speaker 1: The primary cause of the peak of life expectancy in America is obesity.
Speaker 0: obesity is there's a much greater correlation between shorter life and Low income.
Speaker 0: then there is a correlation between shorter life and no medicine, you know.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, it's sort of like this idea that medicine is what makes longer life.
Speaker 0: Well, not really Yet, maybe we definitely necessary beat all the easy stuff.
Speaker 1: I mean not that many people die of typhus in America anymore.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying medicine shouldn't be here is not important.
Speaker 1: We got to this point.
Speaker 0: saying is that you know
Speaker 1: We got to this point and now it's almost a decline because we're we're just managing our resources really inefficiently Because we haven't decided what's important to us as a people and while and that is where there is reasonable debate We can debate as a society whether or not universal health care is a right.
Speaker 1: I believe it is.
Speaker 0: No, I mean, you know, I think it's a very high priority.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it is a very high priority, but I think the question, you know what?
Speaker 0: Okay, so let's say we go and we decide okay This is how much we're gonna give to health care and this is how much are you doing?
Speaker 1: Very simple goal because we have to really define it.
Speaker 1: something along the lines of it is the right of every now I don't know citizen or person living in the United States.
Speaker 1: That's that see again conflated with all these other issues.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the go of people here in some capacity, however, we define that to have available to them No matter what universally some minimal level of health care some minimal level.
Speaker 0: So now we get into this further debate, right?
Speaker 0: We've already figured out.
Speaker 0: So there's the look at how many levels there are this how many resources do we give to health care versus other things?
Speaker 0: Right, then there's you know within the health care, right?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: These are all the health care resources we have.
Speaker 0: How many do we give out per person right?
Speaker 0: You can't even if we have universal health care for everyone That doesn't mean that you can just get whatever health care you need whenever you want, right?
Speaker 0: I mean you can't.
Speaker 0: there aren't enough like, you know organs for everyone who needs an organ transplant.
Speaker 0: There aren't enough to flu shots for everyone who needs a flu shot.
Speaker 0: There aren't enough doctors to spend enough time with everyone who needs to spend time with a doctor.
Speaker 0: I mean some things.
Speaker 0: there's enough of.
Speaker 0: there's enough Tylenol for everybody.
Speaker 0: There's no worry about the Tylenol.
Speaker 1: now think about this.
Speaker 0: There's not enough hospital beds for everyone who needs to be in the hospital to stay in the hospital.
Speaker 1: They need to with hospital beds.
Speaker 1: There's a good example.
Speaker 1: Should there be and can there be?
Speaker 1: and I don't think anyone is addressing either of those questions.
Speaker 1: I mean we need to know.
Speaker 1: we need to know the answer of one What would it cost?
Speaker 1: or what do we think it would cost to provide enough hospital beds for everyone in America who needs one?
Speaker 1: Before we know what that costs we can't decide whether or not it's worth it.
Speaker 1: Does the society?
Speaker 1: because it might be reasonable it might seriously be reasonable to offer that to have that to pay for that But at the same time it might not.
Speaker 1: it might cost so much that will destroy some other part of our society just to pay For it.
Speaker 0: yeah, and let's say all right, so let's say we decide you know to get a hundred hospital beds right and today 150 people need them.
Speaker 0: how do we decide which 50 people?
Speaker 0: Don't get them or do we?
Speaker 0: are we gonna?
Speaker 0: are we gonna say the old people who are closer to death?
Speaker 0: Don't get them.
Speaker 0: are we gonna say the people you know who?
Speaker 0: how do you make this decision now right now?
Speaker 0: You make the decision you know using a various means.
Speaker 0: you know triage first come first serve sometimes money.
Speaker 1: I mean look at if you treat the poor person who comes in first for one thing versus the old person who wouldn't have that much longer to live anyway.
Speaker 1: all right and all this sort of really cold scary morally ambiguous logic and What it all in the national dialogue?
Speaker 1: What do we get?
Speaker 1: we get the far-right saying things like they're gonna ration health care?
Speaker 0: It's already rationed.
Speaker 1: it's not it's.
Speaker 1: it's.
Speaker 0: that's like saying what rat rationing is.
Speaker 0: you have a limited resource You don't let out no matter how you dole it out.
Speaker 0: You're rationing.
Speaker 1: if we didn't have to ration it It wouldn't be a debate.
Speaker 1: We wouldn't have to worry about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it's already being rationed.
Speaker 0: I'm making a distribution system regardless of what that system is for.
Speaker 1: giving out a limited resource is rationing but making the argument that you know the the new the current plan is gonna be rationing health care and Denying care to old fever all this stuff.
Speaker 1: We already do that.
Speaker 1: That's like arguing that we shouldn't have national health care because the sky is blue.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's no way to avoid doing that.
Speaker 0: the question is how should we ration it?
Speaker 1: or is it possible to avoid it?
Speaker 1: hmm?
Speaker 1: It on some level.
Speaker 1: I mean, maybe we can't give everyone in America the multi-billion dollar like experimental crazy brain surgery But I think we can give everyone in America fix a broken bone.
Speaker 0: Oh absolutely I think we can but we don't even have that in America.
Speaker 1: Well if you go to the emergency room, they give you test and people you know They think about these things in such simplistic terms in the media.
Speaker 1: look at the emergency room.
Speaker 1: This is the example that bothers me the fact that Emergency rooms are so overcrowded and at the same time people complain about the fact that we should like say we.
Speaker 1: I think we should Allow minimal levels of health care even to illegal immigrants to anyone within the borders of the United States.
Speaker 0: What happens then is people start coming to the u.s.
Speaker 0: You know from who knows where to just you know leech you know and that that can you know be a huge drain.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing.
Speaker 1: this is the whole sunk cost fallacy.
Speaker 1: actually it's a little more complex than that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right now those people go to the emergency room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they get treated anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but now they're in the way of legitimate emergencies.
Speaker 1: You know some poor person may be an illegal immigrant Maybe not.
Speaker 1: it doesn't matter who doesn't have health care.
Speaker 1: if they need treatment They have to go to an emergency room.
Speaker 1: You know wait eight hours.
Speaker 1: I have all that misery.
Speaker 1: Do it.
Speaker 1: clog up the hospital system.
Speaker 1: clog up the emergency room.
Speaker 1: It would probably be cheaper to give these people minimal health care for free during the day at clinics.
Speaker 1: Then it is to have the current system where they go to the emergency room.
Speaker 1: it costs a lot more dollars To have people you know doctors in the emergency room at 4 a.m.. To deal with these people.
Speaker 1: yeah And the bill if we're already paying for it anyway.
Speaker 1: We can pay less and help these people more.
Speaker 1: It seems like a a trivial decision to make.
Speaker 0: well I mean the other prop.
Speaker 0: the main problem here right is the problem of the pragmatism of the situation and the morality of the Situation.
Speaker 0: right I mean you look and you say okay.
Speaker 0: You know there are only Ten flu shots right we've got in.
Speaker 0: this is 20 people.
Speaker 0: we have to decide which ten people get them.
Speaker 0: So let's say you're sitting around a table right and you say okay, 20 strangers walk into the hospital.
Speaker 0: How do we decide which ten people get them right?
Speaker 0: so everyone?
Speaker 0: You know some people might say well whoever can pay the most?
Speaker 0: and some people might say well Whoever is you know that has the greatest chance of getting the flu?
Speaker 0: or maybe the pregnant women should get them first.
Speaker 0: right we can Come up with a system right you know and people will typically you know you can get maybe an agreement on this system of deciding Which ten people out of the 20 you're gonna get the flu shots.
Speaker 0: the problem is then you say okay?
Speaker 0: It's not 20 strangers anymore.
Speaker 0: It's your family.
Speaker 0: Now it's like oh shit right.
Speaker 0: everyone says no my family You know has to get it first.
Speaker 0: right you know one's gonna if you go to the hospital And it's your mom right and the system We decided was there was the.
Speaker 0: you know the most needy is gonna get it And it's decided that your mom is is you know not the most needy and she's not gonna get the flu shot and someone else Is gonna get it you're gonna be pissed and that's why you had the.
Speaker 0: you know people don't.
Speaker 0: they can't deal with that You know.
Speaker 0: so that's why everyone has to argue for a system where somehow Everyone gets everything that they ought that they need you know regardless of cost and that just it's unworkable.
Speaker 0: So we have to do this cold and immoral thing to have our society.
Speaker 1: I don't think necessarily immoral, but amoral because yeah, it's not like there's an alternative.
Speaker 1: It would be immoral.
Speaker 1: if there is an alternative Everyone gets true correct and for some things.
Speaker 1: this is for example Honestly if we won't treat a broken bone for someone in this country That is immoral because we as a society could pay for that is enough cast to go and Gladly should be willing to pay.
Speaker 0: it's not a shortage of cast.
Speaker 0: They're not expensive.
Speaker 1: It is not immoral.
Speaker 1: I don't think in my opinion to not give everyone who needs it the multi-million dollar brain surgery Because we can't we cannot afford that.
Speaker 1: it is it's not a reasonable request.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the other issue.
Speaker 0: Right is that you know people.
Speaker 0: you know they want health care to be a better right because they complain all the doctors are not Nice, or you know it's I had a horrible time in the hospital wasn't pleasant.
Speaker 0: I waited too long in the emergency room, and they want to pay less.
Speaker 0: How could something be better when you're paying less if you want to be better?
Speaker 1: The people who are against all this they they think thing along the lines of well We shouldn't be subsidizing those poor people.
Speaker 0: yeah, right you can't have something better and pay less for it.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: It is true that there are many areas in the health care system where there are great inefficiencies.
Speaker 0: We were spending Unnecessary money on things where there's a lot of money.
Speaker 0: You know going that is that doesn't need to be going and that is true.
Speaker 0: However, that doesn't mean right that doesn't you know?
Speaker 0: get rid of the fact that health care is in essence ludicrously Expensive.
Speaker 0: it is stupid expensive right?
Speaker 0: you need machines that cost millions and millions of dollars.
Speaker 0: you need doctors.
Speaker 0: Guess what doctors are expensive, and you might say all those doctors are getting overpaid.
Speaker 0: all right You tell me doctors getting overpaid.
Speaker 0: someone goes to school for ten years of their life pays all that tuition and all those student Loans right and now they work.
Speaker 0: You know what kind of hour they have to work first of all when you're a new doctor.
Speaker 0: They work you like crazy friggin all day all night.
Speaker 0: You know crazy hours.
Speaker 0: That's why doctors.
Speaker 0: You know they only see you for five minutes because they're driving around town to three different hospitals, right?
Speaker 0: You know that's why I think you know I don't you know.
Speaker 0: people often joke about like ah them doctors playing golf all day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they play golf one day a week because you know what?
Speaker 0: They work like crazy the whole rest of the week.
Speaker 0: Doctor ain't gonna go live that shitty life of a doctor right?
Speaker 0: for you know penny change right.
Speaker 0: doctors got to get paid Big-time monies and his time is real valuable, and there's not enough doctors.
Speaker 0: And cuz you know why there's not enough doctors?
Speaker 0: because it's hard really really hard.
Speaker 0: And you know.
Speaker 0: so doctors are expensive.
Speaker 0: Medical equipment is expensive the drugs are expensive.
Speaker 0: and you know why the drugs are expensive?
Speaker 0: because we had to research them.
Speaker 0: How much money do you think people have donated to like?
Speaker 0: you know cancer?
Speaker 0: How many different like walks for breast cancer or you know putting quarters in the piece of cardboard at the at the grocery store?
Speaker 0: There have been billions upon billions Maybe even tens of or hundreds of billions of dollars collected to do cancer curing research We're still have not cured cancer.
Speaker 0: That is the cost of medical research.
Speaker 0: It is insane Perhaps the most expensive thing.
Speaker 0: at the same time it has to be paid for somehow.
Speaker 1: at the same time remember one interesting thing is that as time goes on the cost of old treatments go down and down of course and We can say I mean would it be an interesting a system?
Speaker 1: Where the only thing that money gets you is that you have access to the new treatment earlier.
Speaker 1: But as treatments get cheaper They're then entered into eventually.
Speaker 1: you know the effective public domain where the government pays for it.
Speaker 0: So but let's say you know everyone just waited around for the old treatments, right?
Speaker 0: I mean no paying for the new treatment Trivially because that's how it is.
Speaker 1: now the people who have money pay.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're the rich man.
Speaker 1: Do you want to pay for the poor man's medicine without yeah?
Speaker 0: That was the the greatest thing in iron monkey.
Speaker 0: You know some kung fu movie right as the better Attitude on health care right.
Speaker 0: and there's a scene in iron monkey where the iron monkey is a doctor, right?
Speaker 0: He's a brandy doctor with herbs and shit, but that's besides the point right it's a movie.
Speaker 1: And then that in the movie where kung fu is magic.
Speaker 1: that is real medicine, okay?
Speaker 0: But you know these gets.
Speaker 0: these two people come in and have the exact same ailment right and he writes the same Prescription for both of them right.
Speaker 1: one of them is I know that he writes two prescriptions at the same time with both hands.
Speaker 0: Yes, he's.
Speaker 0: one of them is a homeless bum You know well not a bum But just a homeless poor guy.
Speaker 0: and the other guy is like a rich guy who runs a brothel right and you know the the He the poor man.
Speaker 0: He says oh your medicine is free and the rich man He's like oh yours is like ten gold pieces and the rich man's like that's insane.
Speaker 0: He's getting the same thing as me, and he doesn't have to pay.
Speaker 0: and the iron monkey's like oh, maybe you can't afford it.
Speaker 0: He's like.
Speaker 0: and because he's so proud of being rich He pays it right.
Speaker 0: and that's you know.
Speaker 0: people think oh, it's socialism.
Speaker 0: well You know what though honestly, but you know when it comes to something like Medicine you know I mean you can't.
Speaker 0: you know nobody.
Speaker 0: I think you know even if you want to talk about the morals of doling out these finite health care resources Nobody, I think it was a moral.
Speaker 0: human being is gonna say that the people with the most money should get the health care Resources and the people with the less money shouldn't get the health care resources or should get the second picks right.
Speaker 0: that is immoral.
Speaker 1: There's gotta be some like douchebag guy out there.
Speaker 0: So some guys like yeah You know first pay first serve right not first come first serve or most need.
Speaker 0: just whoever has the most money should get the stuff And whoever doesn't have the money shouldn't get anything.
Speaker 1: of course you got to be careful with.
Speaker 1: Good person says that nobody first come first serve might leave you with a monster.
Speaker 0: It might leave you with a monster.
Speaker 0: Yes the first guy.
Speaker 0: I don't think it should be first come first serve either.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah the thing it It's.
Speaker 1: but I mean people aren't willing to even consider ideas like this.
Speaker 0: because people because what happens is the Debate gets framed in such a way.
Speaker 0: I mean like look you know this Obama's got this you know propose It's a bill right.
Speaker 0: so so the debate is all about the specifics of this law that it's framed.
Speaker 0: So you can only argue things within this one particular context.
Speaker 0: if people are incapable of discussing the broader issue They haven't even thought about these concepts outside of you know well.
Speaker 0: Should we have insurance this way or insurance this way?
Speaker 0: wait you're talking about insurance.
Speaker 0: you haven't even talked about you know what?
Speaker 0: Ensuring what.
Speaker 0: you don't even know.
Speaker 0: what's going on.
Speaker 0: You know before that you've already got all these other things.
Speaker 0: You just assume those are true as if somehow They're the laws of physics.
Speaker 1: you know like a help that the national dialogue is basically just lies.
Speaker 1: at this point It's just.
Speaker 0: it's just lies and idiocy from everybody.
Speaker 0: no one no one knows anything.
Speaker 0: They're all just retarded whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, hopefully you know people are listening to this.
Speaker 0: obviously we are not super health care experts.
Speaker 0: We didn't bring our data's and our statistics.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: one thing I would like you to go and don't think about things in terms of.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: This is the mealy mealy bits of insurance, and how do you pay for this night?
Speaker 0: think about the fundamental?
Speaker 0: Problem and that there are finite health care resources their finite resources period.
Speaker 0: how?
Speaker 0: what is a fair way?
Speaker 0: To dole them out?
Speaker 0: Who gets them?
Speaker 0: Think about that well, then you'll begin to form up on top of whatever you decide in that department Honestly real opinion.
Speaker 1: even beyond that people are acting like.
Speaker 1: this is such a pressing issue and this law.
Speaker 1: We've got to push this law through and it.
Speaker 1: it amazes me.
Speaker 1: How fast everything's going.
Speaker 1: I'm on the rush I'm up.
Speaker 1: well people are dying.
Speaker 1: But I'm of the mind really that any different than a month ago or two months ago reform on this scale Requires a Part.
Speaker 1: it might be a product of the way our partisan politics work, but to me This is like a 20-year project like this is something that needs to be started now.
Speaker 1: We need to be working on it.
Speaker 1: But the proposal of what to do should take four or five years of experts debating.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean, this is you know it's something something so complex right?
Speaker 0: I mean we haven't even debated the fundamental part right we?
Speaker 0: once you figure that out Then you figure out and then think about how long it would take to figure out all the specifics all the systems all of the.
Speaker 0: You know bureaucracy that has to happen for the and then while you're doing you're gonna get the Duke Nukem forever Problem of as you're working on it things get better and the whole thing changes.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: This is like a huge Project.
Speaker 0: things get worse thing that you can like sign into law.
Speaker 1: I mean as Bruce talks about a lot recently.
Speaker 1: think about the whole Lyndon Mays Johnson great society and now Vietnam kind of cocked that all up.
Speaker 0: yep Uh Okay, that's it.
Speaker 1: We're done.
Speaker 1: It's Thursday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just you know I just want people that when you think about the health care issue Just ignore all the shit in the news completely, but I thought Obama was having death panels to kill my grandpappy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's all you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, think about the fundamental issue of.
Speaker 0: you got ten people in the hospital, and you can only treat five.
Speaker 0: How do you pick right and?
Speaker 0: Figure that out first and then tell us you know what answer you come up with.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front road crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website Which has everything.
Speaker 0: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.