Speaker 0: It's Monday, February 23rd.
Speaker 0: I'm rims.
Speaker 0: God and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: It's a tech news roundup.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Well despite saying we do it all winter and not doing it scojo, and I finally went out skiing again Mm-hmm, and it was pretty awesome plus.
Speaker 0: We brought Emily along and you know it's always interesting.
Speaker 0: You got to figure out what to do when you've got like two I'm not gonna say expert skiers just risk-taking skiers cuz we're pretty terrible and then a beginner.
Speaker 1: So basically yeah, that's that's always a rough.
Speaker 1: I mean in any social situation where there is something that prevents people from staying together like let's say you go to amusement park and someone's not tall enough to ride the rollercoaster or maybe you go to the amusement park and someone doesn't have a bathing suit or You're going to play a board game, and it only can handle five people and as you got seven people But you're gonna play it anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what do you do when you're in a social situation?
Speaker 1: the reason that you know you're together You want to stay together, but for some reason you can't all stay together right this moment, and you need to split up.
Speaker 1: It's like should you just let Emily fend for herself on the bunny hill or you should hang out with her thus sacrificing your own Enjoyment.
Speaker 1: you know it's like you could.
Speaker 1: obviously you could spend part-time one part-time the other.
Speaker 0: See the thing is with skiing one is that if you're a first-time skier because she'd never skied before in her life, so Like it wasn't like.
Speaker 0: I even thought like hey Maybe I'll like teach her how to ski and maybe mean Scott.
Speaker 0: together We're like teacher all the tricks, but was there a ski teaching person that then?
Speaker 0: oh yes There was okay, but we look at each other, and we're like we kind of ski crappily and dangerously.
Speaker 0: We would probably not be the best instructor.
Speaker 0: so Emily went and took lessons for the morning.
Speaker 1: well We think there's a cost extra to take lessons.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can pay for group lessons You can pay a lot more for private lessons really so you can't.
Speaker 1: so if I just go and buy you know To buy a lift ticket to get less
Speaker 0: actually well the most places like this place They had a plan where if you if you want to buy a lesson for like 70 bucks They give you a lift ticket that only lets you on to the lower mountain Which is fine because the upper mountain is stuff you can't do if you've never skied before like you'll just die up there And it includes a rental and a lesson and like everything you need.
Speaker 1: no So it's basically have you never skied before?
Speaker 1: give us this amount of money, and we'll hook you up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll take care of everything for you And we'll teach you the basics.
Speaker 0: and beginner ski lessons are like here's how to put your skis.
Speaker 1: Stand up.
Speaker 1: Don't fall down.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: It depends on where you go.
Speaker 0: when I was a kid ski lessons consistent.
Speaker 0: I don't put the skis on backwards stop falling down.
Speaker 1: Think about people like getting swimming lessons right.
Speaker 1: kick move your arms.
Speaker 1: Don't put your head in the water.
Speaker 1: kick.
Speaker 0: It's like that does not helping yep, but Emily had quite actually a pretty good aptitude for it So she pretty much blew by.
Speaker 1: that's something else.
Speaker 1: I noticed right when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: I remember taking lessons in various things right and people always give you instruction But for some reason like I didn't take the instruction like there's just something in my I don't know what it was But it's like I didn't like.
Speaker 0: honestly like really think about what I was being told and actually you know what I'm reading the judging Eye, and they talk a lot about that and actually try to do it.
Speaker 1: But now like if I'm doing something and someone's instructing me.
Speaker 1: I actually pay attention to all the words they say Think about them and try to you know execute on it.
Speaker 1: So while you know obviously break how brains work right when you're a kid you learn things a lot more easily.
Speaker 1: The thing is I can still like I'm sort of amazed at how well I can learn things now because I think that I have.
Speaker 1: I think that I have a much harder time learning than I used to but I really don't.
Speaker 0: well I mean, I learned here.
Speaker 1: I got it in like a few days.
Speaker 0: It depends on the wheel and all those sorts of things, but there's also just the natural aptitude.
Speaker 1: I think that's well there is natural aptitude.
Speaker 0: No a big part of that is you can always tell like martial arts are a good example because a lot of the people in a martial arts that's a good example of something I didn't listen To when I was getting instructed as a kid.
Speaker 1: You know how many times the karate guy told me to take my because I was I was making a fist wrong had to put The thumb on the outside and so the inside if you put your thumb on the inside you're gonna break your thumb.
Speaker 1: But I was never never actually punched anyone.
Speaker 1: so it didn't happen.
Speaker 1: But they kept you.
Speaker 1: every time I put the thumb inside the fist because I was a kid I had to punch people in class.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I had to punch things things and people.
Speaker 1: I never made it that far.
Speaker 0: But with martial arts you'll see a lot of people will take like a martial art martial arts class And they listen to the instructor and they try to do it But they don't like get it on a fundamental level like there's this body awareness at least for physical Instruction where like an instructor can only take you so far they can explain all the technique and they can give examples and show you.
Speaker 0: but Unless you have the body aptitude to kind of feel what's going on in your body and intuit What you should be doing and have just proper balance that instruction is really never gonna get you anywhere.
Speaker 1: the rain in Spain falls mainly on the plane
Speaker 0: But she did all right And it actually it worked out pretty well because Kojer and I went up and like hurt ourselves a bunch And then we came down we got lunch And it turns out there's one lift that goes up to like the biggest bunny hill and then at the top
Speaker 1: - more than one bunny hill there's like
Speaker 0: six bunny hills.
Speaker 0: whoa and Emily been doing all the like really easy one.
Speaker 0: So we took her over to the big one of the bigger lift.
Speaker 0: And then at the top of that there's another lift that goes up to like the good mountain.
Speaker 0: So we could ride the lift up.
Speaker 0: I mean That's the main reason to ski with people is so When you're sitting there for ten minutes on the lift with nothing to do you kind of just hang out enjoy.
Speaker 1: the lift takes ten minutes.
Speaker 0: uh Yeah, it goes a ways mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: How long does it take to get down?
Speaker 0: uh depends?
Speaker 0: Between 30 seconds and six or seven minutes depending on what kind of slope it is.
Speaker 1: I just try to you know is it so?
Speaker 1: is it like the roller coaster?
Speaker 1: you wait in line for an hour And then the ride is like two minutes And then you're like the thing is.
Speaker 0: I mean the lift is fun because usually you're there with friends.
Speaker 0: You're hanging out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm sure the live can be fun It's not.
Speaker 1: you know?
Speaker 1: I mean people pay to ride the sky car at the amusement park.
Speaker 1: right well That's I can use me musing park as the exam.
Speaker 0: as we've always pointed out You can pay to ride what is effectively a ski lift to nowhere at most amusement parks.
Speaker 1: the thing is the ski lift.
Speaker 1: You can't ride it back down.
Speaker 1: Can you?
Speaker 1: no no so you have to get off?
Speaker 0: And then which is what you want to do.
Speaker 0: I mean if you didn't get off That's like standing in line at the roller coaster so that you can then go.
Speaker 1: What would happen to you if you just sat and didn't jump off at the top?
Speaker 0: There's a thing that stops the whole thing and then it stops it interstating there.
Speaker 0: And they say get off and if you don't they kind of just drag you off.
Speaker 1: So it there's no possible way that it could dump you down the mountain.
Speaker 1: nope What if it that?
Speaker 1: what if that thing that stops it broke?
Speaker 0: There's also a guy sitting there with a button and if he hits the button it stops, and then they take you off.
Speaker 0: You don't want to ride it down you want to ski down.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying like what would have you know?
Speaker 0: of course the funniest part was at the top of the real mountain There's only one Blue square down like that's kind of like the easy way down like if you fucked up You can at least go down that way even if you're not a great skier.
Speaker 0: But when you get to the top there's a sign that showed that trail and it said closed And a lot of people would get up there and go what?
Speaker 1: Then how would they get down?
Speaker 0: Well the top part of it was closed.
Speaker 0: if you went down a little bit further you could get right on that trail and you Were fine.
Speaker 0: no, but all the noobs like didn't realize it and all day.
Speaker 0: I was watching people get up there.
Speaker 1: What was there?
Speaker 1: a ski person telling them no that maybe should have had a person.
Speaker 0: well There's a map.
Speaker 0: it just people don't look at the map.
Speaker 0: What can I say?
Speaker 1: I mean you know I get a map isn't real?
Speaker 1: I mean if you're skiing a map could just fly out of your whatever.
Speaker 0: well Like you get to the top, and there's a gigantic map on a billboard.
Speaker 0: Okay, don't carry a man.
Speaker 1: That's how I say.
Speaker 1: it carries a map.
Speaker 1: That's like when you they give you like you're taking your map of the amusement park to the water park.
Speaker 1: now Well there it goes.
Speaker 0: the water park was always the big conundrum.
Speaker 0: not really not the water park But the rides that get you wet.
Speaker 0: yeah in an amusement park should you go to the lockers?
Speaker 1: should you not go to the?
Speaker 0: Lock you know not even that.
Speaker 0: the fundamental question of all right.
Speaker 0: I'm riding roller coasters.
Speaker 0: We're all wearing normal clothes.
Speaker 0: someone says hey, let's go on Thunder Mountain Whatever splash and everyone's like yeah, you imagine yourself on it.
Speaker 0: You're like that's really fun.
Speaker 0: And then we get wet and then you imagine yourself for the rest of the day Wet.
Speaker 1: the key is to go wicked early all right when nobody else is going on the water ride.
Speaker 1: so early in the morning.
Speaker 1: Go get a locker immediately get your bathing suit and everything bathing suit.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that means you're carrying that shit around.
Speaker 1: no No, you got the locker, but you carried it in.
Speaker 1: you carry it in.
Speaker 0: yeah Plus you can't do that early at any good amusement park.
Speaker 0: if you get in you've got to make a beeline for one of the rollercoasters.
Speaker 1: Water park like crazy not the water park.
Speaker 0: the water ride water park is a whole separate park I don't know.
Speaker 1: at the amusement parks.
Speaker 1: I went to the water park and amusement park at the same thing either.
Speaker 1: just sort of they're not?
Speaker 1: you know the ticket gets you Into everything.
Speaker 0: there's no separate tickets even if it's not separate tickets.
Speaker 0: They're always like separate places like you go to the amusement park And then you leave it you go to a separate area where there are lockers.
Speaker 1: I mean I guess it's six flags.
Speaker 1: Well what was called Riverside and is now Six Flags, New England You know the water park is just like I guess it's a separate area, but there's nothing in between it, but a fence.
Speaker 1: It's just basically at the end of the path.
Speaker 1: It's like you have this big path.
Speaker 1: a one end of it is oh basically this stuff all along the path.
Speaker 1: So I guess it's just that one end of it.
Speaker 1: all the rides are water.
Speaker 0: I guess I'm too used to like Kings Island or see your point where like the water park There is as big as most water parks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mostly.
Speaker 0: I just every time I ride by splash down I just feel really sad about.
Speaker 1: it's real sad.
Speaker 1: It's the things we got to go to Texas to go to that Schlitter bond Which is all water 100% we have to.
Speaker 0: because I'm I'm missing Things that forced me to get wet while I'm going down a tube.
Speaker 1: man You know what are actually a really good water ride is at.
Speaker 1: I think it's in Islands of Adventure in Universal Studios.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a Popeye ride.
Speaker 1: It's one of those big circular raft goes all-around ride.
Speaker 0: The best thing about those is that there's always like the one seat that just doesn't get wet.
Speaker 1: Well, no, no.
Speaker 1: No, this isn't one of those ones that goes like down, right?
Speaker 1: This goes in a circle around and it's like and it's sort of a lazy river.
Speaker 1: It's sort of deceptive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: It's a lazy river, but basically They're dropping water on you from a.
Speaker 0: that's exactly what I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: It's like Russian roulette.
Speaker 1: No, everyone gets stupid wet.
Speaker 1: No, no There's no dry seat.
Speaker 0: the way that is supposed to work.
Speaker 0: The best way to do that ride is you sit in a big circle and you're strapped in and it goes down.
Speaker 0: It's like whitewater rapids and there's waterfalls and like things dumping water all over the place and you come up to them.
Speaker 0: And it's the Russian roulette because every time one seat doesn't get it now.
Speaker 1: Literally I went on this thing.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure there's one part where they drop you off a waterfall that's maybe like 10 feet tall, you know pretty high and then you
Speaker 0: go under
Speaker 1: a waterfall that literally gets everyone completely wet and then there's like pop I will dump a bucket of water on you and shit
Speaker 0: and See.
Speaker 0: as a kid the thing I'd always do me and my dad is we'd always ride this over and over again with our idiot Friends or just with strangers, but we'd figured out because of the way the bumps were.
Speaker 0: There's like this big rotunda where you got on the rafts and they strapped you in.
Speaker 0: You could see.
Speaker 0: there was a spot where the way if one seat was lined up with like this one bumper that seat Never got wet.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh So we'd always get on there and they make bets with people and then they'd all get wet and we'd laugh.
Speaker 0: and that was that Was my childhood.
Speaker 1: I guess I guess it's possible but I guess you know I like.
Speaker 0: I like always having that element of chance element of danger.
Speaker 1: You know what a really great thing to do is.
Speaker 1: there are places that actually have literal lazy river rides Which is you get in a tube that's enough for one person and it literally just has a tiny current and you go around In a big circle, and there's no water splashing.
Speaker 1: There's no nothing.
Speaker 1: Everyone's just laying in in little circular tubes going.
Speaker 0: Ah, you know, it's either point.
Speaker 0: they have to.
Speaker 1: yeah, and you know what.
Speaker 1: you go on those lazy rivers and it's like Go in with all your clothes on and your shoes and see how long you can stay dry.
Speaker 1: No, that's Cuz.
Speaker 1: I mean you think it'd be easy right, but you got to hold your legs like up in the air.
Speaker 1: Otherwise your shoes go in the water unless you get a really big tube.
Speaker 0: I used to love those things but then when I was a kid finally we went to Tennessee and I went to bid like actual tubing and It was basically.
Speaker 0: these hillbillies took us in a busted up school bus up like me and my dad my brother and like six other Strangers.
Speaker 0: they drove us up the mountain for like 45 minutes.
Speaker 0: They stopped and like this wilderness road and they pointed and they said rivers that way Yeah, and four hours later.
Speaker 0: We made it back to civilization.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only thing is like a lazy river kind of thing.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't if I was going to amusement park, I wouldn't waste my time on that.
Speaker 1: But if I had like a mansion I would totally have a lazy river installed like maybe I would have a lazy moat and he would like if I wanted to just Like relax and go.
Speaker 1: ah, I would totally go in the lazy river.
Speaker 0: I think that's one of the signs of becoming an adult.
Speaker 0: when you go to the amusement park and you know when you're a kid It's like you're gonna ride all the roller coasters as many as possible as fast as possible.
Speaker 0: Mom can't keep up.
Speaker 0: Leave her behind.
Speaker 0: But when you get older you'll walk like you walk through the frontier town as a kid and you see like The cabaret show or like the stuff they do and all the like side attractions that aren't rides.
Speaker 0: You're like screw that That's just a trick.
Speaker 0: I get around the roller coaster.
Speaker 1: The thing is those things are pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the thing.
Speaker 0: when you get older you start to look at those things You look at like the cabana or the relax Oh part and you're like, huh?
Speaker 0: Nice relaxing resort town stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah I was stupid when I was a kid not liking that actually.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right, so do you want to you want to try this thing?
Speaker 0: enough beating around the bush?
Speaker 1: Yeah, let me all right.
Speaker 1: Let me explain this thing, right?
Speaker 1: So basically we're gonna do a tech news roundup today.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, hey if we're gonna do a tech news roundup for the show because there's a whole fuck ton of tech news, right?
Speaker 1: Why should we do news up front?
Speaker 1: You know, it's sort of redundant, right?
Speaker 1: It's just more news.
Speaker 1: So Geek nights was in part Inspired by this television show on ESPN called PTI or part of the interruption where these two guys sort of you know argue or not argue about Sports topics in a rapid-fire manner.
Speaker 1: and you know, it's a very popular show.
Speaker 1: It's like the only thing on ESPN worth watching.
Speaker 1: cuz Sports Center ain't what it used to be.
Speaker 0: All right, old gray man.
Speaker 1: No gray man.
Speaker 1: So they on this show they play various like games, right?
Speaker 1: We're like, they'll do like an odds game where they'll be like, what are the odds of this?
Speaker 1: You know or they'll be like, you know over under someone hitting 10 home runs this year, you know.
Speaker 1: And they have to say, you know, whether they think it's over under and argue about it.
Speaker 1: So it it's sort of you know Gives a nice little structure for to a show or a segment of a show.
Speaker 1: We had two guys and we happen to have a show with two guys, which is why I was partially inspired by that.
Speaker 0: So, of course we didn't go with the original title of geek nights, which was pillow talk with Raymond Scott.
Speaker 1: No, but if we would have started the show pre 2005 that would have been the name, you know, you think we're joking.
Speaker 1: we would have started the show in 2002. it would have been pillow talk with Raymond Scott.
Speaker 1: the scary thing.
Speaker 0: you all think we're joking but Be glad we started the show.
Speaker 1: I mean I made that first podcast in what Oh three or four I'm like, we basically were doing geek nights for like one or two of our friends since 2002, right?
Speaker 1: So, um one of the bits they do on this sports show is called role-play.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's perfect for us role-playing gamers, right?
Speaker 1: Basically what they do is they'll go like hey, you know You are such-and-such basket.
Speaker 1: You are to Kimbe Motombo, you know.
Speaker 1: You know, you just had this and this, you know.
Speaker 1: And then they explain like what the news bit is about to Kimbe Motombo and then it's like, you know.
Speaker 1: Then the other person has to pretend that they're to Kimbe Motombo and you know sort of doing just like saying Motombo.
Speaker 1: Oh, yes, the Kimbe Motombo is amazing.
Speaker 1: Yes, okay.
Speaker 1: So, you know an example of this would be like, you know Let's pretend it was like last year, right?
Speaker 1: I'd be like, hey rim, you know, you're Bill Gates.
Speaker 1: You were just in a really stupid commercial with Seinfeld.
Speaker 1: You know, what do you?
Speaker 1: what do you have to say for years?
Speaker 1: Can you explain that commercial to us?
Speaker 1: and then ram has to pretend he's Bill Gates and explain the commercial.
Speaker 1: So and then you know, so I figured hey Let's let's try this and see if we have you know, the thing is I think those sports guys to be honest I think they prepare in advance.
Speaker 0: I I didn't realize until like five minutes ago as I was going I was going through my email and shit while we're doing The show and I realized that Scott actually sent me something that I didn't look at.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean, well you had to repair somewhat cuz you have to come up with.
Speaker 1: you know Who the people are and what the news stories are and such but we did not prepare our role plays in any fashion.
Speaker 1: so this could be Hilariously bad or we could actually do a good job.
Speaker 1: and I think you know if we like if people like this segment we can keep trying it and We're gonna have to build skills at it.
Speaker 1: This isn't just a naturally easy Segment where we just say stuff.
Speaker 1: it requires thought and we might have long pauses.
Speaker 1: We might have to edit out before we.
Speaker 0: I'm not editing shit.
Speaker 0: Don't even look at me.
Speaker 1: All right, let's you want to try it?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think I can try it.
Speaker 1: All right, do you wanna?
Speaker 1: do you want to go first or not?
Speaker 0: You can go first if you want.
Speaker 1: All right somebody.
Speaker 1: so I So me.
Speaker 1: going first means you read it and I roleplay first or you roleplay first.
Speaker 0: I'll roleplay first.
Speaker 0: I think I can do this.
Speaker 1: All right, all right You are in the New Zealand Parliament.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they have D at people.
Speaker 0: I was about to ask do they even have a parliament?
Speaker 0: I mean Australia New Zealand.
Speaker 0: as far as I know You're a Kiwi legislator.
Speaker 1: You Voted to pass a law that requires ISPs to cut off internet access to anyone who is merely accused of copyright infringement.
Speaker 1: Why why did you vote yes on this?
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm sorry I couldn't hear you over the pile of money that is falling on top of me from lobbyists.
Speaker 1: I mean the ISPs can't be lobbying against you.
Speaker 1: They hate this.
Speaker 0: ISPs don't have any money.
Speaker 0: It's Australia mate It's New Zealand same difference.
Speaker 1: You know how far away the internet is.
Speaker 0: I was trying to do an Australian accent in my head, but there's a filter in my brain that said that's not working.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna let that go through.
Speaker 0: so I didn't have any accent.
Speaker 1: I think we're supposed to say a little bit more than that, but whatever Harry era.
Speaker 0: so Scott you're one of the TV executives.
Speaker 0: They went to Hulu and said that boxy could no longer be.
Speaker 0: I said that wrong.
Speaker 0: awesome You you are a TV executive.
Speaker 0: you have told Hulu to get off boxy and XMBC Even though Hulu really wanted to be there.
Speaker 1: well excuse me, honey I can't.
Speaker 1: I can't hear what you're saying.
Speaker 0: what could you speak up a little louder, but but people want to watch TV.
Speaker 1: They can watch TV on their computers.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: They got their new digital Converti boxes.
Speaker 1: they can watch TV with them there.
Speaker 1: so even giving them $40.
Speaker 0: so why did you let them watch?
Speaker 0: TV on the computer in the first place people that's that's not a TV.
Speaker 1: It's a computer thing of a Bob and people.
Speaker 1: you know they were stealing the TV on a computer.
Speaker 1: so I figure hey We can get some advertising dollars over there, and so I'll try to break through the tubes here.
Speaker 0: But you do realize that nerds hook up their computers to their televisions.
Speaker 1: What TV.
Speaker 1: it's got a different fangled cable thing Biting commentary.
Speaker 1: all right all right, so rim you are Steve Ballmer developers.
Speaker 1: Microsoft recently laid a bunch of people off, but then accidentally in quotes Gave them more money than they were supposed to.
Speaker 1: and now you're asking for the money back.
Speaker 1: Can you can you explain this for us?
Speaker 0: so you're telling me that I have done you a favor?
Speaker 0: And now I want to.
Speaker 0: I want this favor to be repaid to me.
Speaker 0: And yet you are somehow thinking that you do not have to repay this favor to me That somehow you can.
Speaker 0: you can get away without repaying this favor that I have given to you.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean aren't?
Speaker 1: you're a software company?
Speaker 1: How could you have a computer error that you know pays people the wrong amount of money shouldn't you just sort of?
Speaker 1: You know own up to that.
Speaker 1: I mean everyone else in the world has to suffer your bugs in Microsoft software.
Speaker 1: shouldn't Microsoft have to suffer also?
Speaker 0: We're Microsoft.
Speaker 0: You know what we make.
Speaker 0: you can.
Speaker 0: it's pretty obvious.
Speaker 0: Why we made this mistake.
Speaker 0: What do you think we use quicken?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know when's the last time you use Microsoft money or what I Keep pittering out here.
Speaker 1: It's all right.
Speaker 0: All right, Barack Obama Your I can't do an Obama voice Don't even ask is trying to dismiss the case to find Bush's missing super incriminating evil world dictatorship emails.
Speaker 0: The NSA director called you out on it.
Speaker 0: What do you have to say to that?
Speaker 1: Well first of all you know my administration is very large and while I am all for more Transparency in government as I have said many times You know I can't pay paying attention to all these things at once.
Speaker 1: or I got to fix the stupid economy.
Speaker 1: I got to fix all this.
Speaker 1: you know foreign.
Speaker 1: You know shit going down all over the world.
Speaker 1: all right Bush's emails like the bottom my list, and you know what all right.
Speaker 1: after that blackberry fight I realized that it is most likely this government was just so incompetent when it comes technology.
Speaker 1: there was no Nefarious email deleting.
Speaker 1: none of these people even know what email is.
Speaker 1: it was obviously in confidence and Wasting time and money on an investigation is only going to reveal in confidence and make us all look bad.
Speaker 1: So it's better if we just don't pay attention to that and concentrate on fixing the real problems We have now, but you do realize that this just proves the link between Ron Paul and the gold conspiracy.
Speaker 0: You do realize that you know.
Speaker 1: you know people think there's a lot of conspiracies in government But I can tell you this when I got into the president's office here I went and I asked all the security peoples and I went and I looked at all the top-secret documents to see if there are Aliens.
Speaker 1: I went to see if there were.
Speaker 1: you know all the all those things that people worry about.
Speaker 1: you know just to make sure And I can tell you So you have absolutely absolutely nothing to worry about.
Speaker 1: You Can trust me like almost everyone voted for me.
Speaker 1: all right All right, Graham you are Peter Sunday, who is a one of the Pirate Bay guys.
Speaker 1: you are on trial, and it found guilty.
Speaker 1: you could go to prison.
Speaker 1: You're winning so far though.
Speaker 1: Recently some of your supporters hacked your your opponent's websites and took them down.
Speaker 1: You posted on Twitter that they should stop doing that because it's hurting your case.
Speaker 1: Is that what you really think?
Speaker 0: I don't think this is going to have any effect.
Speaker 0: Have you seen the prosecution?
Speaker 0: I don't think they even know what computers are.
Speaker 0: they're coming in.
Speaker 0: the judge even yelled at him.
Speaker 0: I live in a country where judges know what computers are.
Speaker 0: I think I got this, but seriously guys keep it up.
Speaker 0: attack away.
Speaker 0: You can't get me.
Speaker 0: I'm in a lawless land.
Speaker 1: I thought you were supposed to be in this meeting.
Speaker 0: you think I gave up on accents a long time I get kind of done to see dish.
Speaker 0: I could have you know what I can do this video.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could have.
Speaker 0: you know what I didn't work.
Speaker 0: pork pork All right, oh, I forgot about this one.
Speaker 0: All right, mr.
Speaker 0: Editor of the website for hasbro.com.
Speaker 1: all right few days ago on watsy.
Speaker 0: You know you do.
Speaker 0: a few days ago I was looking at your word of the day as I want to do and An interesting word appeared.
Speaker 0: You know what that word was Your mom.
Speaker 0: the word was dildo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, um you know people go to see the Scrabble word of the day And you know we program that just to select a random word from the Scrabble dictionary.
Speaker 1: So of course you know there are words that are in the Scrabble dictionary that are you know?
Speaker 1: Not entirely appropriate for an all-ages board game advertising website.
Speaker 1: and So it was just sort of you know bad luck that dildo happened to be the word of the day and once we noticed it we fixed it and changed it to a Tripoli, but you know between you and me.
Speaker 1: I actually Quintupled the probability that dildo would appear And it was just to get a reaction.
Speaker 1: and you know what.
Speaker 1: we got more hits to hasbro.com in the past day.
Speaker 1: Then we have gotten probably in the rest of history combined.
Speaker 1: so so uh why I'm doing a very good job In terms of driving traffic, and I bet you we sold so many more Scrabble sets than in the previous week.
Speaker 0: So just between you and me.
Speaker 0: What's the over-under on labia in the next two weeks?
Speaker 1: I?
Speaker 1: Don't know.
Speaker 1: There's a few other words Quite ahead of labia you're gonna.
Speaker 1: I mean do you want labia to show up?
Speaker 1: I mean I can.
Speaker 1: I can arrange this.
Speaker 0: I Think we got one more here.
Speaker 1: all right.
Speaker 1: Okay, so ram you are an unemployed recently unemployed bum all right bum bum bum.
Speaker 1: Yep when you got laid off You went and stole like company data Before you left your company.
Speaker 1: What what do you think you're gonna do with that?
Speaker 0: What do I think I'm gonna do with it all right?
Speaker 0: So I worked for a company that made.
Speaker 0: obviously the company wasn't doing well because I'm been laid off.
Speaker 0: So what could I have stolen?
Speaker 0: that's worth any money.
Speaker 0: if it was worth any money.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't have been laid off.
Speaker 1: So why did you steal anything I?
Speaker 0: Don't know I'm stupid cuz.
Speaker 0: I worked for a company.
Speaker 1: Obviously you were the one who was laid off.
Speaker 1: you were smart.
Speaker 1: it was someone else who would have been laid off.
Speaker 0: I feel like the company is a better place without me.
Speaker 0: I mean I left all those logs logic bombs behind too, but doesn't look like they're gonna go off since uh you know Bankruptcy.
Speaker 0: and so I mean you know for a logic bomb to go off there would have to be some logic or at least a computer Which I took all the air on chairs at least though Okay And I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think that went well.
Speaker 1: that was that was all right We could have.
Speaker 1: it could have been worse it could have been better.
Speaker 0: I think I could have been more verbose But unlike you you had the benefit of at least knowing what the role players were going to be ahead of time.
Speaker 1: And I is true I did email them to you early in the morning.
Speaker 0: you did But I did not check my email until I went into Google documents Unrelatedly to look up an anime panel to get the description to copy paste into something else.
Speaker 0: That was like Scott shared a document with me, and it says roleplay, and I'm like what?
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: we talked about this yesterday, yes, and I completely forgot you're awesome.
Speaker 1: Oh If you leave your comments about this segment into forums if you're not into forums get into forum But before you get in the forums get into things of the day.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: What's my thing of the day again?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do.
Speaker 1: What's yours okay?
Speaker 0: I I just thought these were really cool.
Speaker 0: Apparently if you own a play-doh fun factory you can make Really awesome pixel cookies with almost no effort.
Speaker 1: So you think is there ways to make pixel cookies without a play-doh fun factory, but they're not as efficient as this or as cool?
Speaker 1: Well, I guess you can use it to push the dough make a square tube and then chop it up.
Speaker 0: Well you make long square tubes like a whole bunch of them of different colors And then you lay them all out on top of each other till you make the pixel cookie And then you slice up the thing you've made into like 50 cookies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the way you make checkerboard cookies is you?
Speaker 1: basically if you want to make checkerboard cookies you make four square big squares A big white square a big chocolate skirt big white square a big chocolate square right.
Speaker 1: then you stack them up on top of each Other.
Speaker 1: so now it's white chocolate white chocolate.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: then you slice like one centimeter things Right and then you flip them on their side and lay them on top of each other.
Speaker 1: But since it's white black white black you flip half of them over.
Speaker 1: That way you get the checkerboard going on and then you slice them again And then this is much better only requires one slice, and you've got it.
Speaker 1: this one requires Culinary skills.
Speaker 0: yes, this one does not.
Speaker 0: this one requires I'd recommend getting a dough out before you.
Speaker 1: I recommend buying a new Play-doh fun factory and then washing it because one that has Scott play-doh is non-toxic Yes, and it's kind of salty and it tastes really bad.
Speaker 1: that bad it tastes terrible.
Speaker 1: I've eaten play-doh Shitty.
Speaker 1: it is real bad Actually, you know it tastes kind of okay, though is if you make your own play-doh with borax.
Speaker 1: That's awesome.
Speaker 0: Ah borax, I wouldn't eat that though, but All right, so do you remember your thing of the day?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, so the economy is bad and people around the world are trying to understand Why the economy is bad.
Speaker 1: you know and I mean no matter how many podcasts you listen to or videos you watch or?
Speaker 1: Articles you read or even economics classes you take or economics degrees you get.
Speaker 1: you're never gonna really Really understand a hundred percent right, but you can understand enough.
Speaker 1: And you know I've just people everywhere trying to become more educated on this, and it's generally a very good thing.
Speaker 1: and I Unlike many others have also tried to get more educated into the economics topics And I have listened to many podcasts and read many articles and watched many videos and learned about things like you know What's it called the debt obligation things or the things go into the top bucket, and then the second bucket whatever.
Speaker 1: yeah, I've learned about credit credit default swaps.
Speaker 1: or someone buys insurance Like that.
Speaker 1: a company is gonna go under But then someone ensures that with another credit default swap and this big chain means the insurance doesn't work.
Speaker 1: and all these all these other Factors that you know.
Speaker 1: subprime mortgages basically lending you know giving a mortgage to someone who can't possibly pay it back But you give them a low rate to start out with.
Speaker 1: they can afford But then their payment jumps way up they can't afford it, and then they lose the house You know.
Speaker 1: but people gave sold the houses to them anyway approved the mortgages anyway because the the brokers got these commissions So they didn't give a shit and all this sort of stuff, and you know I've learned all these separate things But sort of putting them all together is not really the easiest thing.
Speaker 1: I mean you can sort of figure out how they all fit and why things got fucked up because of it But not a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: and there's this video The crisis of credit and basically it's crisis of credit.
Speaker 1: calm and in this video There is a excellent graphic design right to begin with but B it takes all these things that I have learned about separately from various places on the internet and books and shows and things and Puts them all together into one Picture in a very very easy to understand way.
Speaker 1: if you understand You know things like interest and mortgages to begin with right and Shows you how they all related to each other and how you know one thing affected the next And it gives you really is I think the best thing I've seen.
Speaker 1: yet that gives you the big Big picture.
Speaker 1: and if you want to learn about the economies, this is or at least the bad economies.
Speaker 1: So Scott is it something to watch?
Speaker 0: is the economy still fuck the fuck up shit.
Speaker 0: So It's Monday and we a lot of people have been suggesting topics though I do have to point out that most of the Monday suggestions.
Speaker 0: We've gotten boiled down to a Five-minute Google search will answer it quicker than we will.
Speaker 1: yeah If you want us to do a topic on something then first ask Google.
Speaker 1: And if Google has all the information then don't ask us to do a show on it.
Speaker 0: But we didn't have anything great to talk about or anything interesting or anything that didn't require a lot of research and it's a pretty interesting time in the tech world.
Speaker 0: so uh What I'm trying to say is that it's another tech news around.
Speaker 1: we already said that but I said it again No snap all right, so which which tech news do you want to start off with?
Speaker 0: all right?
Speaker 0: I'll start off here because remember way back there were all these problems with Google Street View and Various like crazy homeowners trying to sue Google for taking pictures of their house.
Speaker 0: Oh that lawsuit finish out The one filed in April last year the big one was pretty much overturned.
Speaker 0: It was dismissed outright, and it's done because apparently the family Quote the plaintiffs have failed to state a claim under any counts Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: so hopefully this is going to lead to a rapid end to all this BS because frankly I Don't think there's any argument against the fact that if you can see something from public property without specialized equipment You have the legal right to take a picture of it and share that picture with anyone in the world.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I don't know what else I can say about that.
Speaker 0: No one's given me a good reputation, and it looks like the courts agree.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean there's been a lot of news lately about Photographs in public and it's starting to come back in our direction.
Speaker 1: I mean there was an article in the New York Times recently about some guy who was taking pictures in the subway and actually it Specifically says in New York State law you are permitted to take photographs in.
Speaker 1: You know transportation play.
Speaker 1: I forget the exact legal wording of it But basically it says it is.
Speaker 1: the law says specifically it is legal to take pictures in the subway state.
Speaker 0: actually the interestingly You know as long as illegal to be so fat on a subway that you take up two seats.
Speaker 1: really Yeah, well the other thing the exceptions to the rule is you can't use a tripod you can't have lights, right?
Speaker 1: You can't.
Speaker 1: you need a permit for those things.
Speaker 0: the thing is those make sense.
Speaker 1: if I'm on the sixth train and some dude whips Out a full tripod and a spotlight I mean in New York City you can't even whip out a tripod like on the sidewalk without a permit.
Speaker 1: because again if I'm trying To walk to lunch and some dude whips out a tripod and a spotlight yep, so The thing is this New York Times article was talking about a guy who like you know the cops came up to him.
Speaker 1: He had the law in his bag, so he's obviously one of those prepared guys, right?
Speaker 0: For a long time carried around a copy of the Declaration of Independence and the Constitution.
Speaker 1: I think the thing is now you don't have to copy or carry on a copy of this law.
Speaker 1: You can just carry around this New York Times article.
Speaker 1: Yeah And the cops came up to him.
Speaker 1: like you can't take pictures in the subway 9/11 9/11 blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: He's like yes, you can.
Speaker 1: here's the law.
Speaker 1: right here I can take pictures in the subway station and then of course they arrested him and took him to the police station.
Speaker 1: And it looks like he's probably gonna get away with the charge of taking a picture in a subway station Which isn't even a charge, but of course they're gonna charge him with like you know being you know Uncooperative and all that other sort of bullshit.
Speaker 0: because in situations like this I'm of the mind that one the police officers need to be censured in some way.
Speaker 0: yep I mean granted there's no way for any one human to know the fullness of American law But at the same time you've got to hold law enforcement officers and judges to a higher standard than this.
Speaker 1: and also You know I mean if police You know I mean even a police officer can't be required to know the entire law.
Speaker 1: right, but it should always side on Like doubt it shouldn't you know?
Speaker 1: so if a cop like if he's not sure if something's against the law or not The default answer should always be no it's legal if it's not obvious You know well, I think one way to fix this you know talking about surveillance.
Speaker 0: I'm like I'm so for this and the more I think about it the more read articles about it the more informed.
Speaker 0: Every uniform law enforcement officer in the United States should have a camera mounted on their uniform That is active with audio and video for every second that they're on duty Period.
Speaker 1: the thing is something could get in the way.
Speaker 0: You know how it is doesn't matter still It's something.
Speaker 1: see I think you know would help a lot Actually a whole lot right if there was.
Speaker 1: this is actually a somewhat more feasible idea right?
Speaker 1: doesn't have you know problems?
Speaker 1: If there was just a clear how in like the NHL right if the ref gives a bad call they call Toronto.
Speaker 0: So why don't police have a thing or they can go back?
Speaker 1: There should be a thing that anyone can call absolutely anyone And it should be a different one in each state where you can call and find out what the law is.
Speaker 1: Well the thing is police come up and are gonna arrest you.
Speaker 1: you could just be like hold up.
Speaker 1: Let me call this number and you call the number and you would call like some.
Speaker 1: you know state Department and you would say is it illegal?
Speaker 1: is there anything illegal about taking photographs in a police station?
Speaker 0: Here's the problem with this one the way the law is written.
Speaker 0: It might take days or weeks to figure out the answer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, two There already is something like that.
Speaker 0: It's called a lawyer.
Speaker 0: and three the reason that's a problem is that you can't actually Really get your rights in this country anymore Unless you have the money to pay for someone who understands the law enough to prove that you didn't break it.
Speaker 1: I just think there should be.
Speaker 1: that's why there needs to be some sort of state thing Not not something you to pay for something free No.
Speaker 0: but what I'm saying is I don't think it's possible the way the law is now because basically it would cost the state so much money To have so many lawyers on hand to be able to figure out the law in all these weird Pooped on public property, but it was a Wednesday and I had a stink
Speaker 1: eye.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is for the vast majority of cases though.
Speaker 1: It'll be very easy to give the answer you.
Speaker 1: just all you need is you don't need so much someone to look up the answers as you just need an Authoritative person to give the answer.
Speaker 1: because if it's you arguing against a police officer, you can't win even if you're right.
Speaker 0: See this is why I'm an advocate because this is the one thing we can do as citizens.
Speaker 0: and when I get a new car I'm thinking about rigging something up just because I can but like what I'm driving I'll use an example like that because it's easier to put forth and it's less incendiary than talking about police even though Partly due to the nature of the way I lead my life I've had very few pleasant encounters with the police and many unpleasant encounters to say the least.
Speaker 0: but if I have a car a new car, I am much more afraid of interactions with the police and with other drivers than I am of any problem that I'm going to cause on my own and I would love nothing more than to have a Inside and outside the car that also gets the last hour.
Speaker 0: So if anything goes wrong, I get pulled over there.
Speaker 0: I'm in an accident.
Speaker 0: There is objective proof as to exactly what happened how fast I was going whether or not I was speeding if I broke or not What what the crazy indignant lady was yelling at me after he dink she dinged my door and then attacked me Just because for someone like me the majority of the Altercations I'm involved in with fellow citizens are ones where in I was the wronged party or the neutral party.
Speaker 0: But yet in our legal system, it's word against word and eyewitness testimony is useless.
Speaker 0: So I don't have any confidence that if I'm ever in trouble that I that the law would end up being served properly for me.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean I just want to reiterate a point that we have to make often because people have a hard time understanding.
Speaker 1: it is that When people are against a surveillance society only because it's a who watches the watchman situation, right?
Speaker 1: It's the government watching all the citizens and no one's watching the government.
Speaker 1: Surveillance is okay if you're surveilling yourself, right?
Speaker 1: This or if the surveillance is done by the government as long as anyone can watch the cameras Not just the police but anyone has access to all the camera feed Even if they can't watch them all the time and like here's the.
Speaker 0: here's a good example Let's say it like Chicago's trying to have cameras on every street in the city.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That's their plan.
Speaker 0: now What if it was set where you can't just watch them all the time because that does really enable stalkers and fucked up people?
Speaker 0: Yeah but if you had a System where you can petition the government and say I would like to see footage from this area from this time because X You know, I was in a car
Speaker 1: accident even need to say because X you should just request, you know I want this foot, you know this camera or any cameras in this location between these, you know minutes You know five o'clock 25
Speaker 0: I would even be okay with having to provide some reason even if like just this minimal minimal barrier to entry.
Speaker 1: Yep and you know what police should have to go through the exact same pro and lawyers and everyone everyone should have to go through the Exact same process to get the footage and it should be available to everyone.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess my idea is that there should be a barrier to entry that you say why you want it and all that You know.
Speaker 0: a small fee five bucks ten bucks Well, just anything just to weed out the crazies and the riffraff.
Speaker 0: but more importantly the idea is that the footage is available to anyone who needs it to vindicate themselves.
Speaker 0: and Since that's not going to happen anytime to anytime soon.
Speaker 0: I'm more and more an advocate of people Making their own personal surveillance to protect themselves from the people around them.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean, that's the thing.
Speaker 1: Is that right?
Speaker 1: It's surveillance society isn't because surveillance and cameras are bad.
Speaker 1: You know as long as they're only in public places or you know They're there they could be in private places if they're owned by the owner, right?
Speaker 1: It's that the only people controlling them are the government and thus they can only be used to incriminate and not to Decriminate.
Speaker 0: plus when I was a kid someone was going like vandalizing cars in the neighborhood.
Speaker 0: We put up a night-vision camera outside Caught the kid and we gave the footage over the police and as far as I know they got him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think perfectly Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So, um, you know, there was that whole business with the Vista capable.
Speaker 1: Do you remember this?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah the false advertising.
Speaker 1: Well, let me let me explain the whole story here.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: So the as I've read so this is what I've read Microsoft was coming out with Vista, right?
Speaker 1: But of course Vista was gonna have higher system requirements than XP.
Speaker 1: XP came out in 2001.
Speaker 1: Vista came out in what?
Speaker 1: Oh seven.
Speaker 1: Wow, if that makes me feel really six years later system requirements are gonna be higher, right?
Speaker 1: So people who had old computers running XP computers from Oh 102, you know, were they gonna be able to run Vista?
Speaker 1: Maybe not.
Speaker 1: so they had to buy new computers.
Speaker 1: So Microsoft said let's make this easy for people.
Speaker 1: people don't understand the megahertz and the jiggle watts and the megabits and whatnot.
Speaker 1: So let's just put stickers on the computers that are capable of running Vista and we'll have them say Vista capable.
Speaker 1: That way if you want to buy a computer, you know before this is like this wasn't after Vista came out.
Speaker 1: This is before Vista came out, right?
Speaker 1: So this is like this is coming soon.
Speaker 1: Do you want to buy a computer that right now that you know will be able to run Vista when Vista does come out?
Speaker 1: Buy one with a Vista capable speed sticker on it.
Speaker 1: You know, it's a good idea.
Speaker 1: It makes it easy.
Speaker 1: The thing is Intel had these chips chipsets, you know for graphics and such that they had a whole bunch of it I forget exactly which one it was and They had a lot of them and they wanted to get rid of them and they were cheap.
Speaker 1: and you know They really aren't that bad, but they weren't Vista capable.
Speaker 1: You run Vista on one of these things and it's not gonna be good at all.
Speaker 1: You can run like Vista home basic and it'll be kind of shitty, right?
Speaker 1: So there was some deal between Intel and Microsoft and the Vista capable stickers Went on all these computers that had this Intel chipset in it that Intel was trying to sell a whole bunch of because they had too many and Thus the whole bunch were sold because these are cheap slow things that were Vista capable.
Speaker 1: So people were buying them and It turns out they weren't actually Vista capable.
Speaker 1: They were barely Vista capable.
Speaker 1: if that and thus someone started a lawsuit against Microsoft and saying hey You shouldn't have put those stickers on there.
Speaker 1: That was bullshit and bloody bloody blah.
Speaker 1: Well That lawsuit has lost its class-action status Which means it's not.
Speaker 1: you know, a class-action lawsuit is one of those things where everyone gets in on it, right?
Speaker 1: So like for example, let's say there was a class-action lawsuit about the peanut butter, right?
Speaker 1: Everyone who ate the peanut butter would be able to just fill out a form.
Speaker 1: So it's like a million people suing the peanut butter.
Speaker 1: come now.
Speaker 0: granted that we're I don't want to debate the merits of class-action lawsuits Because How lawyers make all the money and the people make shit Yeah, and how they're primarily punitive as opposed to restorative exactly.
Speaker 1: But I just wanted to make sure people knew what they were.
Speaker 1: So this lawsuit is no longer class-action Which means if it was class-action, which it was until recently anyone who bought a Vista capable computer Probably with the Intel chip in it would have been able to sign up and get some money.
Speaker 1: if they won like five bucks Yeah, I mean I got 20 bucks once for some Elliott Spitzer lawsuits Against the record companies for price-fixing.
Speaker 0: The only reason I didn't get it is because I hadn't bought any records.
Speaker 1: Well, I didn't either but I just signed up twice and got two checks.
Speaker 1: Hey, I mean actually I think I did buy a CD.
Speaker 0: well backing down suddenly Oh, not so much the Renegade now I did buy a CD.
Speaker 1: It was that long ago.
Speaker 0: I was never the head of the Gestapo.
Speaker 1: The thing is the checks were more than the cost of the CD.
Speaker 1: yeah, so This lawsuit is no longer class-action Which means if the I guess whoever it is that's trying to do it wins, they're just gonna win enough for like one person.
Speaker 1: So that's enough for what one computer.
Speaker 1: Basically, it's over.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna happen.
Speaker 1: So even though I think if that information is correct that Intel and Microsoft sort of made this deal or whatever If that is true, I actually think that the soup probably should have gone forward.
Speaker 1: But apparently the judge thinks otherwise.
Speaker 1: What you gonna do?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: The thing is I don't feel like it was.
Speaker 0: it wasn't false advertising to me because they're perfectly capable of running Vista.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know, I mean a lot of things are capable of running Vista.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but but that's the problem.
Speaker 0: it's a problem we're having now not just in computers, but in food to where a Product can make perfectly legal perfectly valid 100% accurate statements on its label.
Speaker 0: But yet because of the ignorance of the general populace and I'm not even a blame and because of tricky language But not even because of a blameful ignorance But just because of a lack of understanding as to what things mean like what a calorie really is or what?
Speaker 0: You know X percent of a daily dosage of something really means People will not be able to interpret this factual information and thus make false conclusions.
Speaker 0: Now sometimes advertisers use this on purpose to get people to make these false conclusions Well at the same time being able to show in court that they in fact said nothing wrong.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know what to do about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know, it's it's a tough situation because any sort of legislation you try to regulate that at all That was pretty good.
Speaker 0: He's a tough situation.
Speaker 1: No any legislation I kept going and if you try to do that, you're gonna start getting near like the free speech, you know It's like you're trying to do some FTC to stop false advertising.
Speaker 1: But then you get too close to the First Amendment so you get back off.
Speaker 0: But of course commercial speech has never been protected the way regular.
Speaker 1: Well, it's so.
Speaker 1: it's kind of weird.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's obvious.
Speaker 1: I'm not disagreeing.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's what the courts have said.
Speaker 0: You know, I feel like commercial speech should be more restricted just as well.
Speaker 0: other speech should be less.
Speaker 1: I would I would like that.
Speaker 1: Yes, but I think you know constitutionally speaking right?
Speaker 1: It's the Constitution is sort of contradictory when taken with the First Amendment right.
Speaker 1: the Constitution says a Congress has the unlimited power to regulate commerce period.
Speaker 1: right commerce government can regulate it like crazy Right.
Speaker 0: that all that is one of the biggest sources of both good and bad in our cover, right?
Speaker 1: But I mean it's in the enumerated powers of Congress.
Speaker 1: Congress can regulate commerce done Right and courts over and over and over throughout history have said yes The Congress can regulate commerce any fuck way it wants.
Speaker 1: All right end of story.
Speaker 1: at the same time It says Congress shall not impinge upon freedom of the press.
Speaker 1: Well press is commerce, right?
Speaker 1: So if the press Speaks there is speech there, but they can regulate commerce and as a side effect of regulating the commerce They're infringing upon the speech and you see how it.
Speaker 1: it says they can they can't.
Speaker 1: at the same time and courts have you know Obviously said commercial speech can be regulated and non-commercial speech can't be.
Speaker 1: and that's what they decided and I think that's right.
Speaker 1: But it's you know, if you look at it purely constitutionally speaking There's an argument to be made.
Speaker 1: if you didn't already have these precedents of course to you know lean on All right, moving on moving on I do want.
Speaker 0: I want to point that I don't want to spend a lot of time on this But Citrix Zen server virtualization is now free.
Speaker 1: The platform is free but Zen but like XEN or a special different section But Zen is is free.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well the virtualization platform is free.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh What's what's new that wasn't free before?
Speaker 0: Well, basically this is the stuff that we wouldn't use but enterprise people would use.
Speaker 0: It's good.
Speaker 0: Basically.
Speaker 0: Here's the deal.
Speaker 0: I brought this up for one reason Citrix has a lot of good technology.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna deny Simultaneously VMware has not been keeping up at all.
Speaker 1: No, well VMware does something a little different than what Citrix does.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is it different.
Speaker 0: it's different in that it's just worse in a lot of ways.
Speaker 1: I mean, well, yeah, but it has.
Speaker 1: it also has different uses.
Speaker 0: Well, no, I see I thought that.
Speaker 1: but more Citrix is more of like, you know They concentrate a lot on the remote access and the remote application servers where they.
Speaker 0: there's obviously Virtualization technology to make that happen, but VMware concentrates more on the actual full machine Virtualization stuff and but that's but that's the part that's dying that's gonna in within five or ten years Full machine virtualization is gonna be this legacy thing that no one does.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it's an absolute waste and basically I feel I do think it.
Speaker 1: I think it will still be useful in Me, I think that the VMware like servers like the ESX servers.
Speaker 1: I think those are in trouble from things like Zen, but I think that VMware workstation and but where I've been using are still gonna have a place.
Speaker 0: thing Is they're not that widely used outside of geeky circles.
Speaker 1: Well, they're used by developers.
Speaker 1: They're used by Software testers, they're used by people with Macs who want to run some Windows pro.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, that's what I was.
Speaker 0: what I was basically going to say is that on the desktop VMware is okay But for anything server big ironed It's just.
Speaker 0: it doesn't seem to hold up because the idea of fully virtualizing an operating system For anything other than like a simple desktop task is ludicrous at this point.
Speaker 0: I mean para virtualization is the way to go in both Windows and Linux.
Speaker 0: Well Linux is already there like far and away and even Windows is going in that direction in a big way.
Speaker 0: Well Microsoft bought a whole bunch of virtualization stuff and we're waiting for them to bust out more and more with that because I remember going through I Talked to a lot of engineers at the end, you know with VMware a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Not that long ago Like a year ago and just they could not answer most of the concerns that I had about performance and they just They could not do the things that I wanted to be able to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've got to do some more research about Zen because I was pretty sure Zen was an open-source thing.
Speaker 1: So I'm really wondering what the?
Speaker 0: well, it's always this base like what the Citrix thing is.
Speaker 0: Basically, we use Red Hat virtualization And you know, we'll have to do a separate show with the hypervisor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if we if I explain this in any actual detail show it'll take the whole.
Speaker 1: I mean we did a show on virtualization.
Speaker 1: You want to do another show on para virtualization?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: Let's do a show on Zen All right off to research it and play with it in like a month as I know stuff about it.
Speaker 1: But not that not enough.
Speaker 0: I use it a lot of work.
Speaker 0: So alright, but anyway, this is neat.
Speaker 0: So if you're an IT guy, here's my advice.
Speaker 0: Here's why I brought this try it out cuz it's free.
Speaker 0: Why not if you're an IT guy?
Speaker 0: Try all this stuff out and learn it and put it on your resume because this stuff is going to get you a job.
Speaker 1: Yeah, remember this is stuff that saves companies a lot of money because it means they can have their fewer computers do more stuff Which is a big.
Speaker 1: that's something you can actually, you know sell to a boss Who's not a tech boss and get them to go smile?
Speaker 1: That's why it's good.
Speaker 1: Yep You know, they're not gonna smile when you come up with like your crazy encryption schemes that make life miserable.
Speaker 1: But they'll smile when you say hey we can like double the number of computers We have without paying any money and without buying any computers.
Speaker 0: I just I really wonder if VMware is gonna step up to the plate with something similarly good and then long.
Speaker 1: You know VMware is on the sort of short to medium list of companies.
Speaker 1: I can see going in this bad economy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because part of it too is that.
Speaker 1: the other thing is that they might actually do a little bit better though because
Speaker 0: there are
Speaker 1: Companies that don't know that VMware isn't as good as other solutions are easily Lured into buying it because it will save the money and if they don't have any uses that VMware can't handle it'll it'll work out.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, you know some with 10 web servers who instead gets one big server and uses an ESX.
Speaker 1: It'll work just fine.
Speaker 0: But if you're doing web servers unless you're using IIS you'd better use user mode Linux or para virtualization, you know.
Speaker 1: You know, we're talking about people who are not smart enough to do that.
Speaker 0: But I guess the problem is even VMware to use it in a full enterprise environment.
Speaker 0: It's in many cases It'll still be cheaper to just keep your stupid legacy hardware around With the people who know how to support it rather than getting new people who can support the enterprise VMware or Zen or anything
Speaker 1: Mmm,
Speaker 0: especially now in the bad economy where people are more likely to turn off a server rather than spend the money to move it To a better platform.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep I think the one area that VMware and Citrix actually sort of directly compete big-time is sort of the remote thing where You know that they do it in a different way, you know Citrix does like a real remote application.
Speaker 0: So it says to like ways of a lot of.
Speaker 1: basically they invented all that stuff, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but VMware has that one thing where you know I can set up a computer in the office put like 10 virtual machines on it And then some remote user can VPN to the office and use one of those virtual machines as if it was a remote desktop.
Speaker 1: You know that way you can have people working remotely But they're still on your company network and secured and you know only using you know The machine you want them to use and thus you're not getting their cruddy laptop or whatever all over your work.
Speaker 0: That what?
Speaker 0: at the same time you can do that with like Windows terminal server type stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's cheaper and easier yeah, but the VMware, you know having the The virtual server going on there, you know, it's a little.
Speaker 1: it's a little different.
Speaker 0: I guess it's just from a technological perspective.
Speaker 0: I feel that full virtualization is a tech.
Speaker 0: It's a dead end.
Speaker 0: It's an evolutionary dead end.
Speaker 0: It is going to end for many uses.
Speaker 0: Yes in eventually It's not going to be used for anything but the support of legacy hardware like our software.
Speaker 0: that requires legacy hardware Like.
Speaker 0: that's the end run because eventually Windows is going to be paravirtualizable Just like Linux is and that wrecks it like that.
Speaker 0: that that that's yep.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: All right, so The CEO of Netflix Reed Hastings, maybe we should have role-played him He says that by 2010, so that's less than a year away, right?
Speaker 1: They are going to offer a streaming only Subscription plan and I will switch to that the day they offer you gonna have to mail the disk back.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I have had volume 2 of Kazanoyo Jimbo for three months.
Speaker 0: Wow because basically it's funny how I subscribe to a three-disc program which before we did geek nights We watched all those motherfucking discs.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're holding it right there.
Speaker 0: I'm holding the disc we have.
Speaker 0: It's the only disc we have.
Speaker 0: All right, but then remember when Netflix got rid of profiles and there was that internet uproar.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well when they got rid of it, I was one of those people.
Speaker 0: I called them like that day and said look Why'd you get rid of profiles?
Speaker 0: They're like, yeah, and I'm like fine drop me down to one disc Cuz.
Speaker 0: more than one disc is stupid if I can't have profiles.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you only have one profile Really can only manage one disc at a time.
Speaker 1: You needed a profile per disc if it's ever it to make sense, right?
Speaker 0: Yep, so then they did that and my Netflix was a lot cheaper.
Speaker 1: I wish that they would have left it where you just get one profile, but actually let one profile have multiple cues.
Speaker 0: Well, that was different way, but they didn't do.
Speaker 1: they've never done.
Speaker 1: That's the obvious thing.
Speaker 1: If someone has three discs, right?
Speaker 1: I guess separate profiles make sense.
Speaker 1: if you had they should let.
Speaker 1: they need separate profiles and separate cues, right?
Speaker 0: Because if you have a family I don't want I mean, I don't want it to recommend nothing but snatch boondock Saints reservoir dogs.
Speaker 1: It's like if you got a four-person family.
Speaker 1: You need four profiles because it's four different people four different tastes four different sets of recommendations and four discs for four people in The family.
Speaker 1: but if you're one person who watches a lot of DVDs You need one profile with two cues for the two discs.
Speaker 1: so that way you can have one cue full of TV shows and one with movies something like that and they just they still haven't Done that and so yeah Screw them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but as soon as I switch down to one disc and then they were like, hey We're bringing profiles back because you all drop down to one is here's the thing though with the Netflix streaming, right?
Speaker 1: How much will this streaming plan cost right compared to the one display?
Speaker 1: No, you don't need to compare it to the one disc plan anymore.
Speaker 1: Right, if it is a streaming video service, you know an on-demand streaming video service.
Speaker 1: now You have to compare it with basic cable, right?
Speaker 1: Because that's basically what it is, right?
Speaker 1: It's basic cable Scott with just one on-demand channel.
Speaker 1: That's really big.
Speaker 0: Basic cable costs a whole ton.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the thing though, right?
Speaker 0: How much do you pay for the Netflix now, I don't like Eleven twelve maybe fourteen dollars a month.
Speaker 0: I think all right.
Speaker 1: So if it's less than that basic cable can't compete right.
Speaker 0: even in basic cable doesn't have any of the stuff I want to watch on it.
Speaker 0: Well, that's true.
Speaker 0: Also, it's not on demand.
Speaker 1: Well, there's on demand and in cable not basic.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know.
Speaker 1: it depends on what you know.
Speaker 0: No, plus even then I do a lot of houses that have on-demand cable and usually you have like there's things that are available At any one time.
Speaker 0: you can't just watch anything that they've ever shown.
Speaker 1: So here think about this though, right?
Speaker 1: This is gonna compete directly with Hulu cable.
Speaker 0: Well, yes, it's gonna destroy cable.
Speaker 1: Well cable might be forced to drop its prices and such and such and the thing is you can start to see some stuff happening.
Speaker 0: Well, what's good?
Speaker 0: I think the shift we're gonna see is that the only thing cable can offer that can't be offered by these streaming things also
Speaker 1: satellite and such and such
Speaker 0: are live sports and game shows because no one's gonna watch Archives of old game shows unless they're really old and awesome.
Speaker 1: Well people watch a game show Network.
Speaker 0: Yeah, really old and awesome, right?
Speaker 1: I Would if they offered it I would pay $10 a month for Something that was just all sports.
Speaker 1: Just give me every sport in the world live every single one cricket.
Speaker 1: Yep Even then I'd really all the ice hockey even the minor league ice hockey.
Speaker 1: Give me all of it.
Speaker 0: If it was just like give you ten bucks a month on my computer or something.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have to be on the tee, you know, if it's on a computer I can get it on a TV even though the old fogies seem to think otherwise, right?
Speaker 1: I'll write an ex BMC plug-in for it and it'll be all set You know but I just that's.
Speaker 1: that's the only thing that I missed at all from television.
Speaker 1: is live sports cuz Non-live sports really really really plus, you know F1 might one day be used to watch f1.
Speaker 1: time-shifted f1 might be an HD one day.
Speaker 1: It should be epic.
Speaker 1: I Hear that they have HD cameras at the f1 now But they're not actually giving you the HD signal because f1 is really popular in the rest of the world and no one really out There has HD.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, you know, but it pretty much comes down to the fact that Like between Hulu and Netflix like I don't buy DVDs anymore Like I don't really buy.
Speaker 0: or the only people who get any money for me for entertainment are The people at Netflix and they get a piddly amount and I pay them the minimum They will let me pay.
Speaker 0: the
Speaker 1: only people who get money for me for entertainment is Amazon and publishers
Speaker 0: Yep,
Speaker 1: and I guess the the comic book service
Speaker 0: Alright, so I don't really want to talk about Wisconsin the sales tax stuff that keeps coming out, but
Speaker 1: it's not tech news
Speaker 0: It is because it's internet sales tax.
Speaker 0: My opinion there is.
Speaker 0: thus I'm gonna boil it down and it'll be a little incendiary.
Speaker 0: the world is at a point in my opinion where the fact that every state is doing its own income tax and Is ludicrous I feel because so much commerce is interstate.
Speaker 0: I feel like sales tax.
Speaker 0: I think I said income tax once in there, but sales tax should be national and standard.
Speaker 0: that should be the end of it.
Speaker 1: Yes, well, I don't agree with that entire.
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 0: I say this one because use taxes are this are like this Like insanity.
Speaker 1: here is here's what I say, right?
Speaker 1: If you are buying something from say the grocery store Right the state you get the sales tax because it's an in-state commerce, right if I buy something Online that is from a company in New York because I'm I am also in New York then I Pay the New York sales tax as
Speaker 0: yeah,
Speaker 1: but if I buy something from Amazon Amazon I think is a company in California.
Speaker 1: Thus it is interstate commerce and no state tax should apply and only federal tax should apply and there is no federal sales.
Speaker 1: even that purchase would be exempt from all taxes unless the federal government passed a Sales tax which would apply only to interstate transaction.
Speaker 0: But Scott the thing is without that last part.
Speaker 0: That's the way it is now and that clearly doesn't work either.
Speaker 0: Well, I agree You have to link like you have to link what the tax does with the location and everything And I think the most elegant solution really other than just abolishing it or standardizing It would be that because think about sales tax.
Speaker 0: if you're a state you can fiddle with your taxes Especially if you're a little.
Speaker 0: states surrounded by other states have no sales tax to pull Commerce out of other states into your state, Delaware And that's kind of unfair in some ways because of the way the structures all work.
Speaker 0: Imagine if if you bought something from another state you paid that state sales tax to that state on that purchase Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: This means the states that states can lower their sales tax to try to draw businesses to their states For the purposes of them selling to other states.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean but states do all sorts of weird things with sales tax.
Speaker 1: They kind of need to do like they have like, you know sales tax free days and sales tax free areas or low sales tax Bothers me.
Speaker 0: is all that like the taxes are so complicated like there are taxes in Dutchess County on like clothing and crap.
Speaker 0: Yeah And I hate having to figure that out and I looked at what I would have to do to actually figure out my use tax Legitimately and it's ludicrous.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So you just picked the normal one, right?
Speaker 0: I pay the the don't sue me surcharge exactly.
Speaker 1: They don't audit me charge, right?
Speaker 1: No, but I I do think at the federal government we need money, right?
Speaker 1: We got to cut back this deficit.
Speaker 1: There's obviously more and more Purchases being made interstate.
Speaker 1: Nope, not just from websites, but also from catalogs and things.
Speaker 0: The other problem is like there's so much unnecessary Restriction on interstate commerce like the fact that I can't just buy booze online.
Speaker 0: I have a chip to my house exactly, right?
Speaker 1: It's legal to buy booze in every state So why can't I buy some from California where the vineyards are?
Speaker 1: not that I would drink it but you know now the why not?
Speaker 0: The nominal reason is because a kid might get a credit card and buy it which is true because when I was a kid Like, you know, I actually I just got my free annual credit report cuz I'm working on a mortgage.
Speaker 1: But people are buying prescription drugs online, but you know what I saw.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how many emails for Viagra do you get?
Speaker 1: you know, you actually you will get Viagra if you go to those.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends because apparently in Taiwan there's been a lot of deadly fake.
Speaker 1: You'll get pills in the mail.
Speaker 1: But but anyway, what's in those pills is up to you.
Speaker 0: But the thing is on my credit report.
Speaker 0: at the bottom There's a big flashing warning.
Speaker 0: that said warning check for fraud.
Speaker 0: The earliest line of credit is from before this person turned 18 because I had a credit card when I was a punk teenager Mmm, so my line of credit goes back to like 1996.
Speaker 0: Yep But as a result I could get a credit card and buy booze online.
Speaker 0: and that's the nominal reason.
Speaker 0: you don't let kids Get booze online because you can't check ID.
Speaker 0: but the real reason is alcohol makes a lot of tax money and There are a lot of people with a very vested interest in preventing people from buying the cheap booze from other states.
Speaker 1: Here's here's the argument right for the booze online.
Speaker 1: You ready?
Speaker 1: Let's say a kid does buy some booze online.
Speaker 1: Okay package shows up when the kids not home unless the kid is under 21 and lives alone.
Speaker 1: Right, um Really?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So the package is gonna show up mom's gonna open it.
Speaker 1: Why is there a package of booze here?
Speaker 0: Well, see that's why the kids got to be clever.
Speaker 0: All right, so You got to think like Bart Simpson.
Speaker 1: All right Let's say the kid gets the package hides the booze in his room drinks it when no one's looking right?
Speaker 1: He's got it gets away with it totally gets away with it, right?
Speaker 1: Yep How is that any different from kids steals booze from parents wine cabinet?
Speaker 1: It's not different at all.
Speaker 1: You're not protecting.
Speaker 1: you're not making it any more or less dangerous for kids allowing them to buy booze online.
Speaker 0: Well, because the real reason is taxation.
Speaker 0: I mean the way boot like.
Speaker 0: it's ludicrous that I can't buy booze in the grocery store in this stupid state That I have to go to like a separate blue.
Speaker 1: You can buy beer and cooking wine.
Speaker 0: Yes I can buy crappy beer by Vodak in the grocery store.
Speaker 0: Yes, which is crap.
Speaker 0: I've missed buying Vodak in the grocery store.
Speaker 0: Right, of course it.
Speaker 0: I mean it doesn't help that I've pretty much been able to buy booze.
Speaker 0: No questions asked since I was 17.
Speaker 1: I must agree though that actually preventing Vodak from the grocery store Does sort of help the economy and that there are liquor stores.
Speaker 1: I mean if it was in the grocery store There'd be no liquor stores and the economy would go down quite a bit.
Speaker 0: see but there.
Speaker 0: but there would be liquor stores.
Speaker 0: But the liquor stores would be the higher-class liquor stores or the lowest class.
Speaker 1: What actually what you ends up happening if you look at something like Stu Leonard's?
Speaker 1: right Stu Leonard's is a grocery store With a liquor store, so it would be like if the vis count was attached to the shop, right?
Speaker 1: But it was still shop.
Speaker 0: We went to a Dominic's that was like that when we were in Chicago for anime central.
Speaker 1: That's what ends up happening.
Speaker 0: So you're not in New York.
Speaker 0: often most places don't do that and it sucks.
Speaker 0: I have to go to these completely different places to buy my boot.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know you wouldn't mind if that was the situation because it'd be just.
Speaker 1: it would be what you want.
Speaker 1: But it hurts the economy because that's one fewer business, you know, it's one less, you know, it's the gross Makes more money.
Speaker 0: by that logic.
Speaker 0: We should make laws like you can't sell cigarettes and No, no, I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'm not a name store.
Speaker 1: I'm not agreeing with it.
Speaker 1: I'm just pointing out.
Speaker 0: that's why Fairly preventing the bubblegum store proprietors from having their livelihood.
Speaker 0: you sir are fucking the economy.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying that's what it is.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying I.
Speaker 0: The reason for it is very simple.
Speaker 0: a lot of people have a vested interest in keeping it the way it is because they make Money off of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right.
Speaker 1: Let's see what we got.
Speaker 0: You do a couple more two more two more.
Speaker 1: All right Let me see what I got here.
Speaker 0: Talk about the PDF exploit.
Speaker 0: What kind of PDF exploit read a PDF get exploited?
Speaker 1: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: So there's a basically a bug in acrobat reader.
Speaker 1: Is that what it is?
Speaker 0: You don't realize that there have been tons of bugs like that.
Speaker 0: acrobat reader is like Adobe.
Speaker 0: acrobat is in the position.
Speaker 0: It is for a lot of reasons, but it's not a Solution to the problem that it solves.
Speaker 0: It's just the only thing that works well enough for everyone.
Speaker 0: I hate Adobe?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I hate Adobe acrobat and PDFs.
Speaker 1: Well, I like you know, the Sun about PDFs like.
Speaker 1: they have their use, you know, I like yes They do.
Speaker 1: is there many?
Speaker 1: they're often used improperly.
Speaker 1: They're often implemented poorly.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem.
Speaker 0: The code is bad.
Speaker 0: PDFs are a lot larger than they need to be.
Speaker 0: the software to make them is difficult to use or expensive.
Speaker 0: They're huge ram hogs.
Speaker 0: Usually there's nothing more problems with that.
Speaker 1: Format has nothing to do with that.
Speaker 0: Well, it partly does no.
Speaker 1: No, it doesn't.
Speaker 1: There are plenty of PDF viewers that are that could realize PDF right is really is just based on postscript, right?
Speaker 1: So They're like open source postscript, you know interpreters that are like wicked fast and wicked light.
Speaker 0: Yes, but every open source PDF reader I've used has always choked on some document at some point.
Speaker 1: Well, that's only because people make weird PDFs with acrobat reader that do weird shit.
Speaker 0: They're not supposed to be doing like the fact that you go to say the burning wheel website.
Speaker 0: There's all these, you know type your stuff into the character sheet, but it's restricted to where.
Speaker 0: you can't then save that.
Speaker 0: The fact that just in general I've had a lot of trouble with PDFs over the years.
Speaker 0: I use them extensively because it's the only way I can give someone a document and know what it'll look like when they Look at it.
Speaker 0: Mmm Anyway, yeah, there's an exploit.
Speaker 1: So basically it.
Speaker 1: so it works.
Speaker 1: where?
Speaker 1: You download a PDF that is as an exploit in it.
Speaker 1: You open it up in acrobat reader and then it owns you.
Speaker 0: Yep Yep.
Speaker 1: All right, so don't don't download any shady whatnot?
Speaker 0: I guess the real issue here is that I feel like every operating system should have built in by default the right-click open in sandbox.
Speaker 1: Well, actually, you know you can get sandbox II for Windows which I used, you know to watch some Illegally streamed not no written consent football game.
Speaker 0: Oh, did you now?
Speaker 1: and it worked perfectly at my computer is still perfectly clean and all that Chinese spyware was contained in the sandbox Which was deleted.
Speaker 1: so sandbox II is a good tool.
Speaker 1: if you get it.
Speaker 1: I just you need to be smart to know how to use it.
Speaker 1: It's not it's not gonna be something that uh, you know an average person can figure out, you know
Speaker 0: It's pretty much that a lot of problems like this where like in an oculus file that if you had the reader is the is The problem not the operating system or anything but the reader.
Speaker 0: I feel like operating systems should in general and when I say operating systems I'm looking squarely at Microsoft and very few other people.
Speaker 0: Microsoft should kind of by default err on the side of preventing applications from doing things that seem bad.
Speaker 0: I mean, actually I do really like the fact that Vista will do that, you know darken the screen.
Speaker 0: Hey, this thing wants admin.
Speaker 0: Do you want it to do whatever it's trying to do?
Speaker 1: Hmm Alright, so I guess.
Speaker 1: so the final news we'll talk about this right.
Speaker 1: so Firefox, right?
Speaker 1: I've been using Firefox since it was called Phoenix.
Speaker 1: How long you been using it?
Speaker 0: I used it at the beginning of the firebird era.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz you didn't listen to me.
Speaker 0: Well, I had it.
Speaker 1: you're always intentionally late adopting.
Speaker 0: I had it in Phoenix, you know Phoenix I used it a little bit, but I didn't surf the web that much from my even after you're using firebird.
Speaker 1: How long did it take you to get to use the stupid tabs?
Speaker 0: I use the tabs immediately.
Speaker 1: No, you know that you'd use the tabs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, try to.
Speaker 0: okay I use the tabs from day one.
Speaker 0: That's why I switch.
Speaker 1: No, I was always yelling at you for the tabs.
Speaker 1: You never did it.
Speaker 1: Okay, people don't remember this regular old Mozilla had the tabs before Firefox.
Speaker 1: it was just.
Speaker 1: they were slow and poopy but you know I was using them.
Speaker 1: then.
Speaker 0: the main reason I didn't use Firefox but they were implemented poorly was that most of my web surfing was done on the other side of campus on the school computers That only had IE I was carried out the thumb drive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wasn't.
Speaker 1: I didn't have a thumb drive.
Speaker 0: I didn't have a thumb drive either.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I was always.
Speaker 1: I've been using Firefox basically forever right?
Speaker 1: that was version like 0.5 I think right.
Speaker 1: So now we're on Firefox 3 0.
Speaker 1: I've been using a lot of Firefox and every time a version came out I was like, ah, how could this possibly get any better than this?
Speaker 1: they they would just come out.
Speaker 1: every version had some amazing new features.
Speaker 1: that blew me the fuck away and I was like What the fuck are they gonna do in the next version?
Speaker 1: that's gonna blow me away, right?
Speaker 1: And it's like, you know just about now The only things that would really impress me would be like if they made it a little bit more Google Chrome.
Speaker 1: ish You know, it was a little bit lighter a little bit faster.
Speaker 1: separate processes on the tabs, you know, that would be nice You know, but really what are they gonna do in the next Firefox to blow you away?
Speaker 1: Well Right now or very recently was the Southern California Linux Expo.
Speaker 1: I wish we had one of these maybe New York Linux Expo anybody.
Speaker 1: Come on I would like that very much and they demonstrated some features of Firefox 3.1 And of course their blow you away features.
Speaker 0: All right, I'll bite like what?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So first they can have a native JSON parser.
Speaker 1: I don't know if you know what that means.
Speaker 0: It's something that will be able to parse JSON without a plug-in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically it's a JSON is JavaScript object notation?
Speaker 1: right, and it's it's a way of sort of Serializing data in a human readable way.
Speaker 1: That is that can be used by JavaScript.
Speaker 1: so a common way thing you would do with this is let's say I have a web application with a database behind it and Someone else writes a website and the JavaScript on the website goes and queries.
Speaker 1: my JSON web service gets some JSON text the JavaScript.
Speaker 1: It's JavaScript object notation.
Speaker 1: So that becomes a JavaScript object immediately.
Speaker 1: It just boop there it is And then the JavaScript program can easily use all the data in that to you know.
Speaker 1: Update the page and it's sort of Ajax II web 2.0 thing, right?
Speaker 1: And Jason is just really easy for doing it because JavaScript just gets it.
Speaker 1: with a native JSON parser.
Speaker 1: that's basically just gonna be about 10 million times better and faster and you'll notice a significant enhancement in any sort of Jason using website and you won't know why but it'll be there.
Speaker 1: Something else they're adding right?
Speaker 1: is the HTML 5 video element, right?
Speaker 1: I mean Even with HTML like X HTML and shit, right?
Speaker 1: Updating when you're doing HTML and you want to put like a flash video in a site or Anything like that, right?
Speaker 1: You always have to use like, you know object embed all these really old shitty tags that suck ass.
Speaker 1: Well now they're gonna have the HTML 5 video element.
Speaker 1: You're gonna do it video slash video.
Speaker 1: Yeah, isn't that great?
Speaker 0: That's that's a sigh of relief right there.
Speaker 1: So, you know people aren't gonna have to like be doing.
Speaker 1: you know weird things to translate stuff from.
Speaker 1: you know the thing is Only people with Firefox 3 is gonna work.
Speaker 1: if someone's coming to your website with like ie7 or 8 They're not gonna see the video To say like, you know, Firefox right now has support for the canvas element, right?
Speaker 1: And there are certain places you can go to see demonstrations of the canvas element and what it can do.
Speaker 1: I mean, I've played Wolfenstein in the canvas element and Just the other browsers don't support it.
Speaker 1: so no one can really build canvas using sites because No one will see them except Firefox users.
Speaker 1: Everyone else will just get like a square that looks fucked up.
Speaker 0: Maybe someday we'll have a unified HTML that everyone follows the same way.
Speaker 1: Yep supposedly, I mean there's some talk here also about including like some Different like video codecs and something some odd stuff, you know to like add some more multimedia stuff without plugins and Some other kind of shit like that.
Speaker 1: It could get pretty interesting But the only thing is right.
Speaker 1: Firefox keeps adding these features and they are pretty amazing and awesome and I like them.
Speaker 1: But you know people even though Firefox has been lightening up a little bit and they got a newer faster like JavaScript stuff going on There I keep adding it on.
Speaker 1: and originally the point of Phoenix the point of Firefox was that Mozilla Right was piling it on and not only were they piling it on in the browser But they were piling it on.
Speaker 1: they had email composer and news groups all in one application and it was getting big and slow.
Speaker 1: So they're like god, this is too big and slow.
Speaker 1: Let's do the browser only Right browser only and we'll make it light.
Speaker 1: and if they want to add features the features can be in extensions.
Speaker 1: That way it'll be light.
Speaker 1: and then they said oh, but wait, these are features that everyone's using.
Speaker 1: Let's move them back into the browser back into the right and now Firefox is big again.
Speaker 1: I feel like we need a Firefox.
Speaker 0: finally we have a loss of vision here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they had their eyes on the prize.
Speaker 0: They had a vision.
Speaker 0: I followed away from the vision.
Speaker 1: I do sort of think we need a Firefox.
Speaker 1: Firefox that sort of Takes all the features of Firefox the big ones Anyway, right splits them off into extensions brings Firefox down to its previous light and fastness.
Speaker 1: Maybe you know more like Chrome, right.
Speaker 1: and then you know Maybe comes with like those default extensions that everyone wants sort of already installed.
Speaker 1: But then you can like, you know disable them, you know something like that just so that you know We got it.
Speaker 1: We got to bring it back to what the the original vision was and we're getting away from it.
Speaker 1: We're getting a big bloated browser and I think that's why there's room for you know IE 8 and and Chrome to move in is because Firefox is giving them room.
Speaker 1: but hopefully, you know the next browser will give them a little less room.
Speaker 1: and Also, maybe if people start making websites that use, you know, HTML 5 video tag Canvas element and some of these other, you know modern features and start demanding Hey, you know like back in the day that used to say hey You want to see the shit on my website get flash?
Speaker 1: Hey, you want to see the shit on my website?
Speaker 1: You know, you better be using Netscape.
Speaker 1: Maybe we need a little bit of that, you know.
Speaker 1: Hey, you want to see what's on this website?
Speaker 1: Holy Firefox 3.1 is modern enough.
Speaker 0: Go get it.
Speaker 0: Well, it's interesting because in Norway they're having this big campaign now to point out to people using old IE 6 to stop it and Not use it anymore and upgrade to IE 7 or you know the new Firefox.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I think you know, maybe there might be a way to like, you know You could configure your web server to detect user agent and if the user agent is IE You know six or under forward them to get Firefox.
Speaker 0: That's how the internet was for a long time and it kind of sucked.
Speaker 0: I know remember back in the day when you know I have to such like I only go away Netscape losers and the other people were like, but you know what for the win?
Speaker 0: You know what crash IE with a file con con exploit, you know, what remember file con con?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know it worked But now it was kind of 50/50 And the only reason people stopped using Netscape is because it got unusable, yeah Plus I would file con con people all the time.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: I think we're done here.
Speaker 1: We're done.
Speaker 0: All right, we're done.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew.com or you can send audio feedback via Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website, which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.