Speaker 1:
Speaker 0: Hey, it's Wednesday July 1st.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight We talk about how to make anime cons better aka what I learned about Otacon from PAX.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So today right I come out of work And I'm walking across the street to Grand Central and I see two women and they're standing like kind of in front of the sliding Doors.
Speaker 0: I had to kind of go around them to get out and as I walk past them I hear the one woman who looks very very frustrated and angry say to the other one just try the fucking things on and I look and she's holding a pair of sunglasses
Speaker 1: My god.
Speaker 0: So I stopped and I watched them and the other ones like I don't wanna and then they both look at me Like what.
Speaker 0: so I just walked away.
Speaker 0: Oh, you should have been like I Had a day in like 30 seconds.
Speaker 1: Oh, do you know there's gonna be like it's it?
Speaker 1: Roddy Piper is gonna show up right then You know, he was on his way.
Speaker 0: I know he was.
Speaker 1: how could you not wait to see him?
Speaker 1: man High five.
Speaker 0: I mean I actually had seen the South Park episode first and I'm people kept saying yeah That's the same fight is from they live and I was like what they live.
Speaker 0: What's that?
Speaker 1: And then we watch they live and then I was like, oh they live is that thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, bang.
Speaker 0: But that amused me for like 10 minutes after I got on the train.
Speaker 1: I don't want to put the sunglasses.
Speaker 0: Oh My god, there's no way like they did not look like they were having fun.
Speaker 0: So there is no way that they were joking.
Speaker 0: Maybe one of them was knew the other one was pissed off anyway And was messing with them because they knew they didn't know.
Speaker 0: but I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'll never know.
Speaker 0: It's you know, maybe well we can.
Speaker 1: maybe we should start a thing where people go out You know, they do the.
Speaker 0: it's a good idea.
Speaker 1: improv everywhere You know, they do think they'll go and do like a flash mob here like a statue one But it's always like a big flash mob.
Speaker 0: You gotta get more like something where it's like retail.
Speaker 1: two people will just appear in a place and reenact as a movie scene.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing to do.
Speaker 0: remember even mega 64 used to do that with a with the video games But they'd have like one or two people instead of a flash mob.
Speaker 0: But it was still kind of.
Speaker 0: it was very obvious what they were doing.
Speaker 0: You got to do it so subtle that half the time no one around you will even notice But it's all worth it for that one person who goes home and goes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could do it.
Speaker 1: now I'm thinking more, you know, just pick a scene from a movie.
Speaker 1: It could be a small one like that right where suddenly two people so they break out into a fight in an alley somewhere right or You could even do a big one right like, you know Get a whole bunch of kung fu people right and go to a crowd
Speaker 0: Scott.
Speaker 0: Here's the reason why we should not do the fight ones.
Speaker 0: Remember at RIT when we had all those shinai and bokto and we were all fighting with each other outside of Gracie's at like 2 In the morning and campus safety comes around the corner Not guns blazing but flashlight blazing.
Speaker 0: What the hell's going on?
Speaker 0: Oh my god, then we all stop.
Speaker 0: We're like what?
Speaker 0: Yeah, just a fight.
Speaker 1: No biggie No, but you had like, you know a movie kung fu fight just suddenly bust out somewhere and it was all awesome.
Speaker 0: The key Key to anything like that is the subtlety to where someone is not quite sure if it was a joke if it was intentional It's one of the.
Speaker 0: you got to leave them thinking and wondering about it something that will bother them for the rest of their lives.
Speaker 1: you can have a guy or you can you know get someone to dress Up as like Arnold right and then get a kid and they'll drive a motorcycle down the street and get a guy dressed up.
Speaker 1: Is you know t1000 running like behind them?
Speaker 1: No, just drive down the street like that.
Speaker 0: Better just get a guy who looks just like the t1000 and have him just run like all around New York City like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, it's not.
Speaker 1: people might not get it.
Speaker 0: So you see that's the point.
Speaker 0: That's the best prank.
Speaker 0: The people see it now, no, no my case in point is it's a good night for flying.
Speaker 0: That's no good That's that's the best.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's anime day.
Speaker 0: We got to talk about anime.
Speaker 0: With any talk of anime in July must come talk of Otakon because we used to do, you know this time last year We would do a show every night.
Speaker 0: So every week we had an anime show.
Speaker 0: we run out of stuff to say.
Speaker 0: Otakon's done more stuff every two weeks than we can keep up with.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is I'd never.
Speaker 1: It's a sort of obvious.
Speaker 1: I never really realized it before.
Speaker 1: but like The conventions have to announce all their shit before pre-reg ends.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, what's the point right?
Speaker 1: I Never really thought about that.
Speaker 0: But they do.
Speaker 0: I mean pre-reg for Otakon ends at midnight tonight.
Speaker 0: Oh shit, and They announced the last couple of crazy things.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Just in case you weren't already planning to go Otakon This might be in terms of just star power the best Otakon ever.
Speaker 1: No, I don't think it has the musical star power.
Speaker 0: Well, no, that's all right aside from you.
Speaker 0: I mean, they don't have.
Speaker 0: yoko kano.
Speaker 0: larku Vamps is playing a concert but not at Otakon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't count.
Speaker 0: That's a before Otakon.
Speaker 0: Yeah close enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't count.
Speaker 0: but they got some big-name people come in here big-name anime people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Fred showed I want to go bother him.
Speaker 0: No We gotta bother him so much because we did not appreciate the resource we had at RIT and we did not appreciate how cool He was back then.
Speaker 1: Well, we didn't see him at RIT, but he was at RIT before we were at Previous like the anime club years before.
Speaker 1: us got him to come to RIT.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know.
Speaker 0: and we were like, oh some guy came to RIT because we'd always library that all the VHS is a fan subs and in there was like this ten tapes of like Fred shot lectures from RIT and We just ignored it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no idea what it was.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no one no one appreciated.
Speaker 1: and now it's too late.
Speaker 1: We know better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they've got Yukata Yamamoto, you know, oh you didn't watch RIT yet did you?
Speaker 1: I watched like two episodes.
Speaker 0: It's one of the better shows that came out.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's all you gotta say.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a lot more guests, but if you don't care I can just move on.
Speaker 1: Why do you just you asked me if I knew someone?
Speaker 1: I told you I didn't know who they were.
Speaker 0: All right, but they got Ishiguro.
Speaker 0: So I'm sure Scott Johnson is going to be all about this.
Speaker 1: That's an important person very important direct at all.
Speaker 0: the greats Like Habsburgs dying.
Speaker 0: yeah Habsburgs dying to the revenge, you know, you know Macross He's been at conventions before.
Speaker 1: you know, it's not like he's never been to an anime convention the u.s Before.
Speaker 1: he's been to quite a few is just his first Otakon appearance, which is pretty big.
Speaker 1: I think it's also the first time I've been at the same con that he's been at.
Speaker 0: if I'm not mistaken The thing is only in the last few years.
Speaker 0: I've paid a lot more attention to the guests.
Speaker 0: I used to just not pay attention so much because we didn't know who they were.
Speaker 0: Well also because you know, I was busy doing a lot more stuff at conventions.
Speaker 0: I mean remember last year we had that artist alley thing in like six panels.
Speaker 0: We're not doing that anymore.
Speaker 1: I remember when I went to the anime next and Rintaro was there.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: We just sort of walk.
Speaker 1: We didn't plan on seeing him.
Speaker 1: We're like, oh nothing else going on.
Speaker 1: And I was like, no one.
Speaker 0: that was real.
Speaker 0: sad though It was I don't know what was sadder the fact that there was almost no one there or the fact that the few people who?
Speaker 0: Were there could not think of a single interesting question to ask him.
Speaker 1: Yeah Not us either.
Speaker 0: Not those days, but I mean they've got anyway, and she was the voice of bel dandy.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah But uh, I guess we're petering out here.
Speaker 0: I guess no banter.
Speaker 0: Nothing.
Speaker 0: Nothing to say about Otakon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what do I have to say?
Speaker 1: This is awesome people's go and it's Otakon.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be alright.
Speaker 0: Well, this you'll be excited about.
Speaker 0: remember last year.
Speaker 0: They had the Otakon animation the opening animation done by madhouse Yep, and it was crazy awesome.
Speaker 0: and they had trouble, you know contractually They couldn't show it a bunch of times.
Speaker 0: They couldn't like release it out on the internet.
Speaker 1: They only showed it two times.
Speaker 0: Well for this year Once a day Otakon 2009, they showed it officially three times, but I believe it was accidentally shown four times.
Speaker 0: But they will deny that.
Speaker 0: Anyway for Otakon 2009, there's going to be a new Opener to Otakon done again by madhouse.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: Well, isn't a mariama coming again?
Speaker 1: Yes, he goes to Otakon all the time.
Speaker 1: They madhouse fucking loves Otakon.
Speaker 0: Well, I think a lot of that has to do with the Jim Bowles being the freaking deity of Japanese.
Speaker 1: I think madhouse just loves Otakon.
Speaker 0: Otakon is the best anime convention in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Hands down.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean what anime Expo?
Speaker 1: Yeah, which you've never been to.
Speaker 1: so we have no idea.
Speaker 1: Katsu khan We'll get to that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll get to that.
Speaker 0: but quote the inspiration is once again the much-loved daikon for openings.
Speaker 1: Of course, I mean, you know back in the day right there were opening animations to conventions, you know That's sort of you know, daikon 3 daikon 4, you know And many others that are not so good and thus were not remembered or kept.
Speaker 1: But you know, so it's like that's sort of something that went away and Otakon has decided to bring it back And I think it's a very good thing.
Speaker 1: They brought it back and I think other Conventions that are perhaps not big enough to get madhouse to make them animated openers Should go out of their way to make their own and you know There are plenty of conventions that have the resources to do their own.
Speaker 1: I'm looking at you New York anime festival, New York comic-con PAX East-West And do something.
Speaker 0: Well, PAX has the keynote at least, you know,
Speaker 1: PAX They should make a game that is the PAX game and it could just be like a little, you know Fakak the tiny game but they should make like, you know, the PAX o7 game and it could be like, you know Just something you download or something, you know tiny like that, you
Speaker 0: know, some terrible game.
Speaker 1: No, I just feel like a little cute PAX game.
Speaker 1: It could be like just a really small clever thing, you know and just put it out there hand out CDs or you know Let people walk up and down or something.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: But one thing I can say about Otakon too.
Speaker 0: They put up a nice announcement about pre-reg that I will summarize here.
Speaker 0: Don't line up early on Thursday.
Speaker 0: There's no point.
Speaker 0: you will get your badge.
Speaker 0: There is nothing else to do.
Speaker 0: after you get your badge go home.
Speaker 1: It's first of all, right.
Speaker 1: Oh a people aren't gonna go home after they get their badge because they want to hang out.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: That's why they're there Thursday, right?
Speaker 0: Don't hang out right outside the exit.
Speaker 1: Well, that's true.
Speaker 1: I have talked to people at the front of lines at Thursday Otakons who have waited there all day and I asked them Why did you wait here all day?
Speaker 1: One guy has ever had a good answer And all they say is that they're there for the experience.
Speaker 1: they like to be in the line.
Speaker 1: They don't.
Speaker 1: they want to wait.
Speaker 0: see that we're all.
Speaker 1: is no one waiting in that line Doesn't want to?
Speaker 0: here's where I disagree slightly at the front of the line.
Speaker 0: That is true.
Speaker 0: I mean the people at the front of that line are definitely there for that sort of thing, but go about a Thousand two thousand three thousand people further out in the line.
Speaker 0: There are hot pissed off Dehydrated fanboys.
Speaker 0: just they want their badge.
Speaker 1: Well, if you just you know the badge.
Speaker 1: the early badge line opens at what time?
Speaker 0: five five p.m And we'll end at eleven.
Speaker 1: it ends at eleven.
Speaker 1: if you show up at that line at seven or eight You're just gonna walk right in get your badge and walk right out Unless you're a panelist or a member of the press, right?
Speaker 1: But you know, so there's no reason.
Speaker 1: unless you like waiting in line.
Speaker 1: Don't get in that line before Seven or eight o'clock.
Speaker 1: if you just want your badge Thursday just show up in Baltimore sometime.
Speaker 1: Thursday.
Speaker 1: It's before 7 or 8 p.m.
Speaker 1: And around 7 or 8 p.m You know, I mean you can even go there at 10 p.m If you you know If you have such a good time and you'll definitely just walk right in get your badge and walk right out with no problem.
Speaker 1: No, waiting.
Speaker 1: No nothing and it'll be a totally awesome experience.
Speaker 1: if you hate waiting in line, so don't wait in line Don't want to.
Speaker 1: if you do like waiting in line Show up early because there will be people there to wait in line with you.
Speaker 1: And why would you miss out in a minute of waiting in line that you love and of course?
Speaker 0: We've said this before but we will be at Otacon with much of the front row crew But not the entire front row crew.
Speaker 0: many people have bailed some for lame reasons some for amazing reasons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there are people who are not front row crew who will be there many podcasters and other internet peoples You like who cares about them and any other people who listen to this podcast including you and others.
Speaker 0: We are only doing three panels, but there are three high-quality panel.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, isn't it pre schedule out?
Speaker 1: I didn't look at it.
Speaker 0: I didn't look at it either.
Speaker 1: I forgot.
Speaker 1: I have to look at that.
Speaker 0: But anyway, we're doing beyond D&D anime.
Speaker 0: You should see and know your creators and I'll just say one last time to make sure those are other is do not Go to our anime.
Speaker 0: You should see if you have already been to it.
Speaker 0: We have not added anime to the anime.
Speaker 0: That is not the panel for you if you're someone who has seen anime.
Speaker 0: This is for people who don't know what cowboy bebop is.
Speaker 0: Yep Which is about a half of Otacon as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: Well, it was half of Anyway, Boston.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was.
Speaker 0: we did a panel like that at Otacon before and people hadn't seen anything.
Speaker 1: Hmm It's very sad some of these situations.
Speaker 0: I still don't know what to do about it.
Speaker 1: It's so weird like the kind of mixes you'll get like a kinetic on.
Speaker 1: there was someone who actually knew what the Itano circus was.
Speaker 0: Yeah one person.
Speaker 1: but it like you'll get it and that was a tiny room with only a few people.
Speaker 1: but like another convention You get this giant room full of people.
Speaker 1: zero people know what it is.
Speaker 1: It's like what happened here.
Speaker 0: But we will announce.
Speaker 0: since we only have our three panels and we did we chose not to get an artist alley table.
Speaker 0: this year We will have some sort of crew get-together probably on Saturday, but I can't promise that yet.
Speaker 0: Twitter and the forum and our website will tell you where that is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know such we can.
Speaker 1: we got a nice get-together maybe out on our nice the patio at the tables.
Speaker 0: But depending on the weather's I do want to mention this briefly.
Speaker 0: This is this is not it's kind of breaking news out there But we are consolidating all of the full information before we report on this in any capacity, but no, let's just report on it.
Speaker 1: Well, we got enough.
Speaker 1: We got some information.
Speaker 0: We have a lot but I guess I will qualify everything We're about to say by saying that this is primarily information gleaned from voyeurism Second-hand sources and hearsay.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: However, it is second-hand sources that I trust and hearsay that has been reliable in the past.
Speaker 0: I don't know what's going on with katsu khan next year.
Speaker 1: Yeah katsu khan, you know, they moved to a new hotel.
Speaker 1: There's some.
Speaker 1: well, they moved back to Crystal City, right, but it's not the same hotel.
Speaker 1: It's it's that they were in Crystal City before.
Speaker 1: it's like the Gaylord something, right?
Speaker 0: But basically a while ago a bunch of high-level staffers resigned kind of out of the blue and you know, we were staff.
Speaker 0: Well, we were staff for katsu khan.
Speaker 0: So we were watching everyone.
Speaker 0: you're like all right.
Speaker 0: we got to get new staffer for this new staffer for that and everything still seemed to be working out because The main reason we always went to katsu khan was video katsu.
Speaker 0: If nothing else went right at that.
Speaker 0: khan the video game staff was basically like an entirely separate staff Completely independent of katsu khan.
Speaker 1: that was completely awesome and basically had its own gaming convention within.
Speaker 0: katsu khan Like those guys had their shit together.
Speaker 0: That was some of the best game like even video gaming.
Speaker 0: like they were on par with Pax enforcers.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I mean Pax is you know.
Speaker 1: to be perfectly honest, you know You go to Pax and Pax is like a big video game convention, right?
Speaker 1: but the actual video game playing at Pax is Less than a video game playing that goes on at katsu khan or at least did go on a katsu khan.
Speaker 1: They I think Pax had overall, you know less actual, you know consoles to play, you know.
Speaker 1: They had a you know, their system of taking checking games out was kind of nice yeah, but you know, they there are less games to play at Pax and less people playing games in the official game playing areas.
Speaker 1: and And katsu khan also always had video topia with like all the awesome arcade machines Pax really didn't have arcade machines at all Really?
Speaker 0: Yep, but that that like I mean that the classic arcade games really did it.
Speaker 0: But those people like I gotta give my hats off to video katsu.
Speaker 0: You guys made katsu khan for us amazing every year that we went.
Speaker 1: all two of them except for the and one I was sick.
Speaker 0: Well, I went for two previous katsu khan's before you started going But I went to one katsu khan and one sick katsu khan.
Speaker 0: those katsu khan's prior to going with you know In the official capacity of geek nights are a drunken haze.
Speaker 0: primarily but basically from what we can tell the Staff of katsu khan may or may not have imploded and I believe most of the video game staff has resigned and mass citing various disagreements as to how the count should be run.
Speaker 0: and I I've so many people have emailed us about this within katsu khan and half the people are like, please Uh, you know keep this anonymous, but here's what's going down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically drama.
Speaker 0: so no a Lot of people asked us why we didn't go to katsu khan last year and there were a lot of reasons But the early rumblings of this were the beginning of it And now that the rumblings are almost peeking out to the surface Now, you know.
Speaker 0: so if any of you have any Insight to provide into what happened to the katsu khan staff and what's going to happen at katsu khan next year We would love to hear it and we will not say your name if you tell us not to.
Speaker 1: yeah The thing is right.
Speaker 1: It's sort of this self-fulfilling prophecy of you know, whoever katsu khan I guess still exists.
Speaker 1: It's still gonna go on You know in some capacity at least as as it stands now, right and there's still people who are working on it and working hard You know to make it happen and they want to be good.
Speaker 1: But by you know by having this drama and by announcing this drama is sort of like well Now people are going to avoid katsu khan thinking it's gonna be bad.
Speaker 1: Thus.
Speaker 1: It will be bad.
Speaker 0: thus But at the same time if I have a reason to believe that a khan will be bad It's not like as a journalist I can hide that from you.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: I mean how bad would you feel if I was like yeah katsu khan's coming up It's awesome.
Speaker 0: and then you went and I knew that.
Speaker 0: you know, it was having trouble on the back end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically go to katsu khan if you're live close and it's not too much trouble and you know continue to listen because as we Figure out more about what's happening.
Speaker 1: There could be you know, these kind of things swing.
Speaker 1: I could be I could be getting on the the show in a few weeks being like Katsu khan.
Speaker 1: at a sudden reversal all the shitty people left all the good people came back.
Speaker 1: It's a miracle.
Speaker 1: It can happen.
Speaker 0: Yep, and also obviously if any katsu khan staff are listening Let us know what's going on because we like katsu khan and we would love to help katsu khan continue to be awesome.
Speaker 0: But you can't hide the drama that's happening.
Speaker 0: It is spilling out at the seams.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like we want katsu khan to be good, but we got to call it like we see it.
Speaker 1: It's not doing good But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: What do you got for me?
Speaker 1: What do I have?
Speaker 1: Well, do you know?
Speaker 0: cliffhanger That terrible movie.
Speaker 1: I never saw that movie though I do know it exists because I remember back in the day like crazy.
Speaker 1: Wasn't it like?
Speaker 1: what was it about?
Speaker 1: a guy rock climbs and falls down and kills himself something like that.
Speaker 1: I don't know Rocky was in it, right?
Speaker 0: I don't actually know.
Speaker 0: I just remember seeing ads for it all the time and the more ads I saw the less I wanted to see the movie.
Speaker 1: Well, there was actually a video game an arcade video game from back in the day called cliffhanger two words Right, and I did not know about this game until very recently.
Speaker 1: This game was at even though it's very very old.
Speaker 1: This game was a laserdisc game.
Speaker 1: if you've ever played dragon's lair You know what a laserdisc game is.
Speaker 1: basically the way these arcade games were anime that ends every five seconds.
Speaker 1: Well as you hit up right basically you got a arcade machine and inside the arcade machine was of course a television and A bunch of you know laserdisc videos, right?
Speaker 1: And what happened is these lasers videos would play and you would have to push.
Speaker 1: You had a joystick and some buttons and you'd have to push the joystick and buttons in the right way With precise timing in order to get the video to continue.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, it's sort of you know It's like if you don't push up and push the button right now at this exact precise timing and if you do it He'll swing the sword and kill the dragon.
Speaker 1: If you don't then the dragon will breathe fire and the video is over and you have to put any more quarters to start again.
Speaker 1: Right, and that was how a laserdisc game worked.
Speaker 1: this particular laserdisc game called cliffhanger right as released in the US Was was pretty much, you know played the exact same way as dragon's lair except Dragon's lair was an original, you know creation for video game purposes, you know this.
Speaker 1: they took footage from various Lupin the third movies, especially Castle of Cagliostro, but also momo Stupid game.
Speaker 0: where you'd be you'd have the scene where the him and they're running away when they stole the goat bills in the beginning Of the movie and it's run run run run run jump run run run run jump.
Speaker 1: Yep, and They took all this Lupin footage primarily from Cagliostro, but also from others.
Speaker 1: They didn't call it Lupin.
Speaker 1: they called it other shit, you know cliffhanger or whatever and it was a laserdisc game just like dragon's lair using this Lupin footage and I really kind of want to play it just to see what the deal is.
Speaker 1: But I know it's probably really bad with some really bad voice acting over the Lupin.
Speaker 0: if there is any voice acting at all I'm sure there's some way to play it.
Speaker 0: We will have to investigate.
Speaker 0: But
Speaker 1: this gives me an idea though Right if you could take footage from a bunch of anime that no one in the US had heard of at the time or he's very Few people even well still very few people know what Lupin is in the US And make a video game out of it.
Speaker 1: Why don't we take some footage from some like animes put it together and just make some you know games out of it, huh?
Speaker 0: You can make some flash games.
Speaker 1: You could just take like some, you know, who knows what but you know make laserdisc style annoying games.
Speaker 0: I Hope that doesn't become.
Speaker 1: I need to make cutscenes for my indie video game.
Speaker 1: I'll just steal some animes.
Speaker 0: So we know this is anime night and Bongo in comics, but we always often talk about Japanese animation, you know anime but there is animation from countries other than Japan.
Speaker 1: I wish we could sum up the Wednesday with a different wording instead of saying anime manga comics because on the one hand right manga is Comics, but you want to put the word manga.
Speaker 1: So people searching for it finds you on Google.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and two, right?
Speaker 1: It's like sort of the whole visual arts really is what Wednesday is about because there are many many visual arts that are appeal for the geekeries and that's sort of what Wednesday is really all about.
Speaker 0: but one place where a lot of great animation comes out of Canada, Canada Canada.
Speaker 0: So I present to you Christopher Hinton's Black fly.
Speaker 0: It's the tale of a man who was black flies black fly Okay, a man who was since up with the survey crew in Ontario to build a power.
Speaker 0: damn and if you've never been to northern Michigan or Canada or northern Canada, there's a Creature a beast a foul monstrosity called a black fly.
Speaker 1: It's a fly.
Speaker 0: It is a fly that bites Constantly and repeatedly and never stops black And there are a thousand more to replace it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: If you strike it down, it will only become more powerful.
Speaker 0: So all that aside we've in many times in the past talked about, you know Well, if we ran anime con do you think the day's over those quick?
Speaker 0: All right, we'll do.
Speaker 0: That's my thing of the day that animation.
Speaker 0: Okay, the black fly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Christopher Hinton I thought you're gonna discuss, you know, I thought we were gonna maybe discuss some of how you know Canadian gives money to people to make animations.
Speaker 1: That's why there's all these great Canadian animation bits out there.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna leave it out there.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I mean we use space wolf before we didn't talk about that.
Speaker 1: I don't think space wolf was Canadian.
Speaker 0: I think the guy who made it was Canadian.
Speaker 0: possibly I think Maybe I'm wrong.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know if that was a Canadian, you know government paid for production.
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: but I think he happened to be Canadian and remember back in the day like Nickelodeon would show a bunch of the Canadian bits and then Cartoon Network would show a bunch of them.
Speaker 1: Any
Speaker 0: cartoon network show cartoons, yeah,
Speaker 1: all right
Speaker 0: But we've often in the past brought up, you know well We do things this way if we ran anime convention or gaming convention or Robert Robert blah and then after we went to PAX we came back and had a whole new perspective on everything and We talked a lot about how great PAX was and how every other convention sucked as a result.
Speaker 1: Remember how there was Actually, there was only one ever hubbub at PAX least as far as I know of the guy who runs those other video game conventions.
Speaker 0: That guy is great.
Speaker 1: He went to PAX to sort of figure out how they ran the convention and tried to copy them and it totally didn't work you know, but they threw him out of PAX cuz of some who knows what.
Speaker 1: but I Feel sort of like we're doing the same thing Like we went to PAX and we succeeded in investigating what they did in that workout where it's suggesting that people copy it.
Speaker 1: Well, but the thing is are we are we not too dissimilar from that asshole?
Speaker 0: Well, we're not crazy at least not in that way.
Speaker 0: yeah, that guy was crazy, but I think it's more that I had a lot of notions and ideas as to What I thought was wrong with anime conventions and gaming cons, but you know, it's Wednesday we're just gonna talk about anime cons and I thought I knew how to solve those problems or at least I thought I knew what I wanted out of the cons.
Speaker 0: and as A result of getting the problems.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and going to PAX kind of gave me this different perspective that Maybe cons don't have to be in any way like they are now.
Speaker 0: we can make radical changes.
Speaker 0: But then it kind of sunk in that packs was different for reasons other than the way it is run.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean whenever we you know, try to solve any world problem, you know big or small We always sort of get back to some sort of fundamental core unsolvable thing, right?
Speaker 1: Like we'll be talking about the government like oh they should do this I should they do this and eventually we'll get back to like well Corruption can't?
Speaker 1: you know, there it is, you know, you find some core thing that's at the root, you know And you know with with, you know anime conventions and stuff It always be like.
Speaker 1: well, they're by fans for fans most of them anyway, and they're all volunteer.
Speaker 1: So, you know you can't do this and you can't do that, you know and all these great ideas You can have.
Speaker 1: it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: This is root problem and we can never figure out how to solve that root problem because it just it is what it was.
Speaker 1: You couldn't turn the convention to be profit.
Speaker 1: You couldn't, you know hire a bunch of people.
Speaker 1: that just wasn't feasible.
Speaker 1: So all the things that require that are also not feasible and it cascades downwards.
Speaker 1: so you sort of just accept the things of the way they are because you know People already made it the best they could and the core problem that would allow them to change anything is unsolvable Yep.
Speaker 0: And there was also the issue.
Speaker 0: I realized after we went to anime Boston that we started going like we always went to the same Few conventions every year when we were just fans or doing like our one panel And then we suddenly started going to a whole ton of cons and that killed us.
Speaker 0: So then we backed it off and then we kind of just went to the same cons every year.
Speaker 0: And it wasn't until we went to PAX that we broke it up.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: that was when we went to something different for a change Yep.
Speaker 0: And then on the heels of that we went to anime Boston and after anime Boston I realized that my view of cons was highly skewed by the fact that my sample size was basically Kineticon, Otakon, Katsu-Kan, which are all very similar.
Speaker 0: of course Otakon is pulling away from the pack more and more and Kineticon is being more and more of a Not anime con but a generic generic on which I think actually suits us very well.
Speaker 1: to be honest Yeah, that's what Kineticon should be.
Speaker 0: Yep I'm actually really excited about Kineticon this year Which is the weekend after the weekend after Otakon.
Speaker 1: So there's a weekend after Otakon that nothing happens and the weekend after that Kineticon.
Speaker 0: And again, of course, we're gonna be there doing all the panels.
Speaker 1: Yeah in one room there's going to be a room that is the rim and sky room.
Speaker 0: Well, the you know, the geek nights front row crew room It's about 50% me and Scott 50% the rest of the crew.
Speaker 1: So even if the rest of Kineticon is poop Which I guarantee it won't be because the tabletop gaming there is excellent
Speaker 0: see if we could just take the tabletop gaming from Kineticon and merge it with the tabletop gaming from PAX and just have Video cards to run gaming at PAX
Speaker 1: the ultimate game con.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: anyway.
Speaker 1: So if you're worried that Kineticon is gonna be you know If it's not worth going or worth going.
Speaker 1: you should go because the worst case scenario You can play tabletop games play RPGs and hang with us.
Speaker 1: we're all.
Speaker 1: we're gonna be doing a panel pretty much every minute of the con and You will not need to worry if the rest of the con is good or bad And you know what?
Speaker 1: There's a chance that some of the other things at the con will be good even if some of them are bad so Guaranteed because of us.
Speaker 1: you could think of it as like there's a. there's a geek night's convention inside of Kineticon.
Speaker 1: You can think about it that way.
Speaker 0: Wow, you know Every year when we talk about conventions, we always kind of ever.
Speaker 0: I think it's ever since you honest ever since.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna lie to our people.
Speaker 0: We we talked about how excited we were for Wario where we before it came out.
Speaker 0: No one ever.
Speaker 0: let us live that down.
Speaker 0: So we're always very guarded in our opinions now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Katsu con might suck I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah Otakon might be cool.
Speaker 1: We don't know.
Speaker 1: Better than be see.
Speaker 1: it's good though because now that builds a trust with the listeners.
Speaker 1: They know that we're not just shills, right?
Speaker 1: There are other people out there, you know podcasters and other types in various media.
Speaker 1: We're like.
Speaker 1: if someone's a sponsor Like they will never bad talk them.
Speaker 1: or if they have a business partnership with someone they'll always say they're great Even if they don't really like them, you know the that that much, you know this story or the.
Speaker 1: at least they'll keep their mouth.
Speaker 1: You know We.
Speaker 1: you know, if someone's a friend of ours, you know, or we have a relationship with someone if there's something bad We'll say it, you know.
Speaker 1: And I think because people trust us in that way and we we live up to that trust that will you know?
Speaker 1: Our listeners will stick with us and know that we're awesome.
Speaker 0: That is part of the reason why I did bring up the Katsu con thing at this early stage because one it means there's enough Time for Katsu gone to fix things but to yeah Katsu got it.
Speaker 1: That's one thing.
Speaker 1: to Katsu cons credit, right?
Speaker 1: They're having all this drama now, but their convention is a ways out.
Speaker 1: It's in like February.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so most conventions like, you know at this point in time, you know over six months before the convention They would just wouldn't be saying anything at all.
Speaker 1: There'd be no communication between any of the people whatsoever at most conventions.
Speaker 1: So Even though the communication at Katsu con is negative its communication and that is a positive a huge positive.
Speaker 0: Yep, the fact that anyone's even talking that shows you that cause.
Speaker 0: it kind of had its act together But to way back when we went to Connecticut and it wasn't so great years and years ago And we did a show basically lambasting the con like and at all these problems.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we still go to it every year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well because the con share and all a lot of the staffers email doesn't know.
Speaker 0: you know what you're right Put up or shut up.
Speaker 0: You want to help us fix it and we were like hells.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and kinetic on has been like our standby con ever since.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So I'm hoping the same thing will happen.
Speaker 1: It's also helps it really close.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll pretty much go to any con that's within an hour of my house.
Speaker 1: Well, we never go to those ones that are up at the the colleges and Poughkeepsie like the non-con.
Speaker 0: Well, we went to a gaming for hope twice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we didn't go to non-con though.
Speaker 0: No, we didn't.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: I Was lying.
Speaker 0: What do you want?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I think we should just start.
Speaker 0: basically we're gonna try to aggregate all of the complaints and suggestions and commentary we've had about the meta of anime conventions and just anime conventions into one show and pull it all together rather than having You know one mention in every show for a year that no one can really pull into a coherent plan forward.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm And that's the rationale the real reason we're doing the show.
Speaker 0: Scott hasn't watched giant robo yet.
Speaker 0: I haven't watched all of Galaxy Express yet.
Speaker 1: You're never gonna watch off Galaxy Express.
Speaker 0: I will.
Speaker 1: I'm on episode 60 something.
Speaker 1: It's a hundred and twelve.
Speaker 0: I think Scott watch all the Sailor Moon and we'll talk.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Not that bad a show.
Speaker 1: not that gonna happen.
Speaker 0: It's really not that bad a show.
Speaker 1: Yet neither I've watched a lot of things.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm gonna watch that many episodes I've watched worse shows longer.
Speaker 0: So, all right.
Speaker 1: Well watch gal guy guy.
Speaker 0: then Maybe I should start in the middle of gal guy guy like people say yeah, it's up to you.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I think we should start with the simplest or the least controversial or the obvious and then work our way to the crazy Because the simplest and most obvious that anime Boston already does.
Speaker 0: so we know this one works.
Speaker 0: Have the cosplay feedback be opposite the real con feedback on Sunday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you go to a feedback panel, right?
Speaker 1: And it's good to have a feedback panel because you know Basically if people give you feedback by email or internets it gets lost.
Speaker 1: people don't check it Whatever.
Speaker 1: well
Speaker 0: to having the feedback at the con gives the people who are pissed off and have a legitimate concern or not That immediate venting which will and often they'll feel a lot better about coming to the con next year knowing that a person listened to Them and said we'll work on
Speaker 1: it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know other conventions like, you know, professional ones that are freaking feedback.
Speaker 1: It's like what are you talking?
Speaker 1: a feedback fan?
Speaker 1: I'll get it.
Speaker 0: packs ended and Everyone walked out and the police were behind.
Speaker 0: Well, the guards were behind the last straggler saying get out.
Speaker 1: Yep There's no feedback.
Speaker 1: It's like they don't need you to tell them that they're awesome.
Speaker 0: and after the last Otakon We finally said look get rid of con feedback.
Speaker 0: No professional cons have it and it's just cosplay people and no one else.
Speaker 0: and Anime Boston just split them which I think is great because I feel like the cosplay people do need a forum like this.
Speaker 1: Well, I think what it is is at a fan run con that is by fans.
Speaker 1: for fans You sort of have more of a right.
Speaker 1: It's sort of weird, right?
Speaker 1: You think you would actually have less of a right to feedback because basically everyone's volunteering and just doing this for you.
Speaker 1: So who are you to tell them that they did something wrong?
Speaker 1: But but and like at a professional con you're paying for that.
Speaker 1: You should be able to feedback a ton, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you can complain about software you paid for but you can't complain about open source software.
Speaker 1: But at the same time it's like, you know a fan run con, you know, like Otakon you're technically a member.
Speaker 1: You know, this is like you're in this group.
Speaker 1: You have you know, you're in this just as much as everyone else is.
Speaker 1: It's not like they're providing a service for you.
Speaker 1: It's like you're in this with everyone else and you have a say part of it, too.
Speaker 0: Is that fan cons unlike professional cons have the very clear put up or shut up where you're coming to the con?
Speaker 0: You're not different from the staffers.
Speaker 0: You're just not staffing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're there in the same capacity as those people but if you have a complaint join up and fix it.
Speaker 0: We'll get to why that doesn't work as well as it should.
Speaker 0: Reasons as to why.
Speaker 1: yeah, so yeah, so feedback.
Speaker 1: if you put the masquerade feedback which is the majority of the feedback on its own a the masquerade runners will be there to hear it right and B those masquerade people won't bother the rest of the people because really the masquerade at an anime convention is Separate from the rest of the convention.
Speaker 0: It's basically a completely separate event.
Speaker 0: I mean the people who are doing that tend to be there for that and their whole group of friends will like like everyone they know has a skit and then they all go and watch each Other skits and they all go to all the stuff
Speaker 1: and then they do the cosplay chess and they do Right, and that that's basically.
Speaker 1: it's a convention.
Speaker 1: within a convention, you know It's a whole a lot of can.
Speaker 1: there are some conventions out there that have tracks, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you go to a tech convention and they'll be like say, you know different tracks for different, you know technologies.
Speaker 1: So everyone wants to learn about X goes to be this set of events and anyone else about why it goes to these set of events and anime conventions and geek conventions.
Speaker 1: Definitely don't have tracks in this sort of structured way where you pick a set of events and go to them But what they do, you know, they sort of have these virtual tracks of.
Speaker 1: you know, you know.
Speaker 1: Hey, if you're into this, you know, then you're gonna do these things, you know Some people just go and they do the video game room the whole con and it's sort of a track You know, they do all the tournaments and some people they go and they do all the cosplay stuff They do, you know, the the photos and the the show and the whole thing.
Speaker 1: That's a track in a way.
Speaker 0: Actually, I will later in this we'll get to tracks because I have a lot of ideas about tracks and anime cons.
Speaker 0: It's one thing that is it is their de facto, but not de jure.
Speaker 1: Yes, exactly.
Speaker 1: You summed up what I was saying before and many fewer words.
Speaker 1: Yes that we're all French Latin, whatever It's a Latin language.
Speaker 0: But That actually that's a really good example of.
Speaker 0: you know, one of those things were originally our idea was yeah get rid of it Stupid.
Speaker 0: but then going to anime Boston we saw no there's a better way.
Speaker 0: Okay, so what else should we change other than the demographic?
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean One thing is definitely the.
Speaker 1: it's tough to figure out the scheduling of panels.
Speaker 1: You know, like we've been trying to look at this and it's like, you know They leave the gaps in between the panels.
Speaker 0: Literally, there is a panel and then a panel sized hole and then a panel and a panel sized hole
Speaker 1: and some of them stagger the Panels and some of them line them up next to each other and some of the one
Speaker 0: thing that almost no anime con does is have gaps between panels.
Speaker 0: and no, anime con has effectively been able to get people out of the rooms in a professional manner such that the next panelists are Just ready to go exactly on time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean at most conventions, right?
Speaker 1: It's like that.
Speaker 1: the problem is different.
Speaker 1: for example at Otakon, right?
Speaker 1: You have a situation where a panel room be full The next panel is popular and people are waiting in line for it outside the room.
Speaker 1: So you have to empty out this room and then let the people in for the next panel.
Speaker 1: But yeah Otakon also has all the panels scheduled right on top of each other with no gaps.
Speaker 1: So they need the gap.
Speaker 0: Well more so - there's the very serious problem of.
Speaker 0: I mean There are two ways to look at this on one hand people will go to a panel They don't care about because it is in the room of the panel that comes next that they want to see
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: and two there are people who want to go to two panels that happen to be next to each other in the same room.
Speaker 0: Yep, and there is no elegant solution to any of that.
Speaker 0: No except tracks, but we'll get to that again.
Speaker 0: But I think you really have to do panel scheduling based entirely on the specific con and the specific needs of the specific.
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 0: no.
Speaker 1: yeah Boston, you never need to clear out the panel room, you know, there's plenty of seats.
Speaker 1: the old people just come in and come out as they please.
Speaker 1: you don't have this problem.
Speaker 1: and actually an anime Boston every panel I Saw and even though they were stacked on top of each other.
Speaker 1: They all ended on time.
Speaker 1: Nobody stayed too long or anything like that.
Speaker 0: But Otakon has the problem where there are a ton of panels where?
Speaker 0: You will not fit everyone who wants to see that panel into the room.
Speaker 0: You have to clear the room out.
Speaker 0: you Otakon specifically really needs to have the half-hour break between Every single panel and they.
Speaker 1: the thing is then you've got a situation of quantity and quality.
Speaker 1: You know by stacking all the panels up on top of each other you can get the quantity in there and you can get something for everybody.
Speaker 1: if you Put all those gaps in unless you have more panel rooms There's going to be less panels.
Speaker 1: and if there are less panels You're gonna have to give some of them the axe.
Speaker 1: and what do you do now?
Speaker 1: You've got all this time periods right with fewer panels occupying people.
Speaker 1: all the people are coming to the convention.
Speaker 1: There's less for them to do.
Speaker 0: there's gonna be more time where they're wandering about doing nothing Which Otakon has the huge problem with just because the BCC can barely contain it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but other other convention, you know, it's a problem in Otakon.
Speaker 1: It's not really a problem in other places so much at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it really depends on the con but for very large cons like Otakon
Speaker 1: actually Pax did have the room emptying problem but you know where the rooms that every panel would completely fill up and they'd have to empty it out and let all new people in And then it would fill up and not everyone to see the panel.
Speaker 1: But they had huge gaps between the panels and they had less quality and less.
Speaker 1: less quantity and more quality.
Speaker 1: So it wasn't a problem.
Speaker 0: now one thing I would do if I'm gonna schedule things back to back or even with short gaps between them is have tracks of related panel stuff at anime cons, maybe even have Recommended itineraries in the con book.
Speaker 0: Like if you're the guy I don't know all the neck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think you could logistically go so far as to have people register for individual panel.
Speaker 0: No, no, no not register.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna say that either but I'm just saying I don't think you could do that.
Speaker 1: That'd be ridiculous But you definitely what you have to do is when you're scheduling the panels you have to think Really really hard about the different types of fans and say okay if there was a fan of this, right?
Speaker 1: You know this kind of person is probably gonna go to these panels.
Speaker 1: So don't put them next to each other at the same time
Speaker 0: or put them next to each other one after the other with no room clear and Made like no somehow in the schedule that these two are a block and that if you want to be guaranteed to see the second One you have to go to the first one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if there was someone a mark on the schedule, you know, see the thing.
Speaker 1: would people really get it, you know I mean you could mark in the schedule.
Speaker 1: These are times in the room is cleared out.
Speaker 1: These are times of the room is not.
Speaker 0: well Every con that does room clearings does that but very rarely do they actually follow their room cleaning clearing schedule consistently or Really do they enforce the room clear thoroughly.
Speaker 0: more importantly they will not schedule enough time to clear the room.
Speaker 1: That is also true.
Speaker 0: But I feel like Otakon should have simple solution straight up.
Speaker 0: There should be a half-hour stagger between every single panel except for linked track panels.
Speaker 0: Yep, so you might have two panels less panels.
Speaker 1: Well, you gotta get more panel rooms or just you know, you'll have better quality and no one will really complain so much.
Speaker 0: Well, I have a solution to that too.
Speaker 0: But before we get to that talking about tracks I think cons like Otakon should have a section in the con book maybe not on the you know fold out schedule, but in the con book of Have like ten different personalities like staffers whoever who look at the schedule and pick their suggested track.
Speaker 0: I'm Joey Jojo the mecha man.
Speaker 0: I like fisted the North Star and all my goddess and mech shows.
Speaker 1: So I was like, I'm the mecha man.
Speaker 0: I like Show him drama You make you know, like in the old PC gamer and all those magazines you have personalities Yep, either fictitious or real doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: and then you say like if I were that person I would go to these events and have a full weekend-long con schedule event event event event Even with like lunch blocked out.
Speaker 0: Mmm and have like ten of these in a special section in the back of the con book.
Speaker 0: And you could get fans to do this for you if you release the schedule early enough.
Speaker 1: and also when you're when you're crafting these Craft them such that you know Such that right if you know.
Speaker 1: say you have ten of them, right?
Speaker 1: Just pretend, you know Obviously, it's not gonna work out this way ever.
Speaker 1: just pretend that ten percent of the convention picked each one, right?
Speaker 1: That's adding up to 100%.
Speaker 1: Craft them in such a way that if that were the case the traffic flow and all those other factors Come in line.
Speaker 0: I will say awesome.
Speaker 0: That is impossible.
Speaker 1: I know it's impossible, but you should keep those sorts of things in mind when crafting.
Speaker 1: see, you know You know, you're obviously never gonna get it.
Speaker 1: I feel like it doesn't hurt to think about it.
Speaker 0: See I've you know having scheduled one room for the entirety of convention I have decided that that level of planning is currently impossible for anime cons.
Speaker 1: You said to think hard about it that if you have enough time, you can do it.
Speaker 0: There aren't enough resources.
Speaker 1: It's one person.
Speaker 1: This is that.
Speaker 1: sit there and think and look at it.
Speaker 0: I just think for a kind like Otakon specifically the much better solution really go all out publish the schedule for panel or the whole con schedule either early to the staff or If you have holes in the schedule where you won't you won't have it ready in time.
Speaker 0: You know kind of wing it and leave gaps and there are a bunch of ways to do this.
Speaker 0: But either have a contest to create the schedule for an individual person, you know The mecha man itinerary or just have dedicated staffers do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, be like, you know Scott suggested convention schedule rims suggested.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should make you know, go to get different conventions and then just post like our suggested schedules.
Speaker 0: Yeah rims Suggested in Scott even to start for cons.
Speaker 0: they can't get this done early enough to print in the con book.
Speaker 0: Put it online whenever you can make a big deal about it point people toward it in the forum and everything and then Print out, you know The.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go look at the Otakon pre-schedule and I'm gonna post my suggested schedule in the front crew forum.
Speaker 0: I will post mine as well.
Speaker 1: We'll start this and I if I was at Otakon and I want it and I'm going to assume a I'm going to Otakon Be I'm not doing any panels.
Speaker 1: I'm only going to them.
Speaker 0: see we're ourselves.
Speaker 1: Yes, see I'm myself and D I'm going to want to do a convention thing at every moment.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna put artists alley in my schedule.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna put video game in this get you know.
Speaker 1: But I'm gonna never gonna leave like an empty time or I'm just chilling out cuz I paid for Otakon.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna do something at every moment possible, you know, so I just think this is a great idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so let's let's post our schedules our virtual schedules that we're not actually going to follow but what you know our suggested schedules.
Speaker 0: Now in terms of panel rooms and needing more panel rooms if you stagger the panels Cons not need to either get rid of the video showing rooms at least the generic ones or completely redo them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean other conventions that aren't anime conventions don't really have video showing room.
Speaker 1: Well, they might have a theater that shows like special events like it.
Speaker 0: You know a comic con know what a lot of cons will have is they'll have showing rooms But those rooms are special like they show Like they'll have just weird stuff like here's a bunch of 80s TV shows and then we're showing rocky horror and then whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean like look at the New York Comic Con, right?
Speaker 1: They have a theater and in that theater, they show special Hollywood shit.
Speaker 1: That is for the con, you know and some of it you have not to pay for.
Speaker 1: yeah, and that's what they do.
Speaker 1: They don't have like showing rooms Like.
Speaker 1: yeah, we've just got like five video screens and these five little theaters coming and just sit down and watch at your.
Speaker 1: you know Leisure, they don't have that shit.
Speaker 0: now very specifically again I'll just keep using Otakon because it's the easiest example.
Speaker 1: Well, I think it's because Otakon actually has all these things and is so big and that's you know.
Speaker 0: We've been to it since every year so - now we've actually pitched this idea to every count we go to.
Speaker 0: and well It'll probably happen at Kinetic on 2010 and it may happen at anime Boston 2010.
Speaker 0: We're still you know, this is all still in planning stage.
Speaker 1: We have not done this at a convention yet So I don't even know if it would work, but I think it would.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty confident but our plan is to one Drastically cut down on the anime showing rooms and keep the rooms like Otakon's video 5 Consistently amazes me.
Speaker 1: Well Otakon needs to keep the 35 millimeter.
Speaker 1: Yes They got to keep one big one for the AMVs and such right?
Speaker 1: They got to keep the live-action one Yeah, and they have to keep one that shows like all the stuff the industry wants to show, you know They bring all their new releases and such.
Speaker 0: but what I would do for every other anime showing room the ones that otherwise would just be showing like The first four episodes of Harvey and then like the I got his movie and all these rooms are right.
Speaker 1: These rooms do serve a purpose at the convention now which is basically get people out of the hallway and sitting in a seat and out of the way and All they do is just have video showing constantly non-stop Just keep showing new videos and people just keep going in and watching them.
Speaker 1: and that's all these rooms do and I guess you know, it serves a purpose but There is a significant improvement that could be made to greatly enhance the experience.
Speaker 0: now, it's very simple.
Speaker 0: All you do is schedule the video room exactly like you would a panel room.
Speaker 0: So every showing isn't just the name of the show.
Speaker 0: description of the show.
Speaker 0: every showing is an event.
Speaker 0: So say at 11 o'clock and then at night on Saturday, we're showing Lupin the third castle of Cagliostro.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So it's scheduled there but in the schedule we block it out for the movie Plus like a half-hour Yep, or and after and the description shows first, you know describes no The Miyazaki Ghibli Lupin the third movie.
Speaker 0: a little bit description.
Speaker 1: What was it Ghibli?
Speaker 1: I think it was just Miyazaki directed it.
Speaker 0: I think it was just Miyazaki, but anyway good question not to look that up.
Speaker 0: You you show that you say, you know, this is the movie we're showing and then you also include information about it.
Speaker 0: You know some sort of meta information, but you sell it not as just a showing but as a panel To where it's going to be.
Speaker 0: MC the per.
Speaker 0: someone in the room is going to introduce the film.
Speaker 0: Talk about it a bit.
Speaker 0: Maybe take a couple of questions.
Speaker 0: I'm talking 15 minutes to a half hour of.
Speaker 0: This is what this is.
Speaker 0: This is why it's important.
Speaker 0: This is why it's cool.
Speaker 0: This is why you're here and check it out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know 10 minutes might even be enough depending on how much there is to say about.
Speaker 0: so Yeah, it depends on.
Speaker 1: they could talk about the directors.
Speaker 1: They could talk about the history of it the year it came out any interesting stories that are related to it.
Speaker 1: You know, just really tell people what you know.
Speaker 1: Make sure you're explaining to them all the in this meta information about what they are about to see.
Speaker 1: and now First of all, people are gonna be a lot more excited about what they're about to watch.
Speaker 1: They can be a lot more interested.
Speaker 1: They're gonna know what to look for.
Speaker 1: They're gonna have a proper context for what they're about to see.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna walk into a room and look for two seconds of the screen.
Speaker 1: You know, of course all the people who show up in the middle of the showing are still gonna do this.
Speaker 1: But if someone shows up in the beginning, they're not gonna be like, okay this what's this?
Speaker 1: Look at it and be like I screw this, you know They're actually gonna be like, oh, I know.
Speaker 1: they'll know after you while you're talking to them at this time They want to watch or not.
Speaker 1: And if they decide they like it and odds are they will because you're gonna talk it up real big.
Speaker 1: You're gonna get those people to sit in their seat for the whole showing.
Speaker 1: and then after the showing You have another block of time before the next one and you discuss what you just saw with the audience.
Speaker 0: people ask questions I mean ghosts in the shell.
Speaker 0: you show that at the end You talk about what that really meant and you talk a little bit about Shiro versus oshi.
Speaker 1: Yeah Did you guys like that?
Speaker 1: Did you not like it?
Speaker 1: You know, what part did you like?
Speaker 1: What part did you not like?
Speaker 1: everyone can start talking it up and it's a good way for everyone to you know Connect and all this good stuff.
Speaker 0: Now that is just kind of phase one That is the fastest quickest simplest least effort least.
Speaker 1: all it requires is a person per video room Per show.
Speaker 1: you don't need to sit there for the whole show.
Speaker 1: All you need is a person who knows about each show to go in and talk about it before and after and that's it.
Speaker 1: It's real easy.
Speaker 0: Now the next phase of this would be to in addition to showings like that because you know, we do our animation see panel.
Speaker 0: So if Otacon had stuff like that we could say so.
Speaker 0: if you want to learn more about these shows giant robo is being shown and discussed at four o'clock on Friday and You know the pond.
Speaker 0: the third is being shown at this time.
Speaker 0: and then sky crawlers are being shown at this time.
Speaker 0: Check it all out.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: but the next phase is to have panels in the video rooms that are primarily clip driven or even Commentary like a. say someone does a showing of Satoshi khan's paprika and it's just they introduce it.
Speaker 0: They show it they're done Later in the con.
Speaker 0: there's a separate event where maybe they do a Satoshi khan panel and they show you Either clips from all of his movies and talk about them and point stuff out or they take Paprika that they already showed earlier in the con kind of show all these different scenes from it point out what's important point out the Animation point out stuff in the background kind of analyze it the way that film professors at like NYU do you know?
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, there are already panels like this that are done in panel rooms, you know Lots of you know video heavy panels, but they're always constrained by time.
Speaker 1: They're always constrained by time and you know video in the panel rooms is usually not so great.
Speaker 1: If you moved all the video heavy panels to the video rooms It would increase the quality of the video rooms greatly
Speaker 0: Right and also to
Speaker 1: free up space in the panel rooms for more panels
Speaker 0: and it also shifts the focus of the panel to Show it to me and tell me what I'm seeing as opposed to show me a little bit and then talk a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and Like.
Speaker 0: the really cool side effect of this is that I have got a lot of really cool film professors who are all About going to a con like Otacon and doing this.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: and also there are a lot of panels that could not happen but could happen if this were implemented, you know Yes, there's a lot of impossible infeasible panels that would now be possible, you know Like, you know, for example, someone might want to show something like I don't know I'm Trying to think something that's you know, like like maybe like memories, right and you know, it's.
Speaker 1: it's not too long But it's not you know, super long either.
Speaker 1: so you could show it and you could really you know Talk about like the whole thing.
Speaker 1: a lot of you know, if you wanted to discuss say magnetic rows in a panel right now You know, you couldn't really show the whole thing in your panel.
Speaker 1: It's too much for your panel would eat up all the time and You know you basically to show clips from it, you know and just keep them short.
Speaker 1: But if you had a video room and you had a whole bunch of time a couple hours even just you know an hour and Change instead of 45 minutes to an hour You could show the whole thing in the dark then turn the lights back on and then discuss it.
Speaker 0: And the best example of this was way back.
Speaker 0: I visited one of Emily's lectures that NYU, you know.
Speaker 0: She went to film school in New York City at New York University and I sat in on a lecture where the previous Showing they had shown all of citizen Kane and then in the lecture they kind of walked through the entire movie showing clips and then the professor would show the clip talk about it maybe show it again and It was amazing and I saw citizen Kane in an entirely different light after that lecture.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I took one film class at RIT With this really smart dude and basically, you know, the class was twice a week But also once a week we had to go watch a movie in the web and that's basically you know, how it went down.
Speaker 1: Hey, you know 20 classes and 10 movies in 10 weeks now Oda Khan.
Speaker 0: I direct this to you specifically.
Speaker 0: We can get you real film professors who are also huge anime fans who will probably come to Oda Khan And do this for you.
Speaker 0: All you have to do is give us the room and we'll do it Like we've.
Speaker 0: we're all set.
Speaker 0: We're like.
Speaker 0: we think this is a solid gold idea.
Speaker 0: Alright and Even it, you know any con not just Oda Khan, even if you can't get the film professors to do these crazy You know very well prepared clip panels.
Speaker 0: You can have someone at least say who directed a show and why it's awesome Mm-hmm, and you know look at a show like giant robo.
Speaker 0: giant robo.
Speaker 0: If you don't have someone to kind of give you context as to what this is You're about to see you might look at it and go this is stupid and walk out of the room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a lot of shows out there that just need Information and most people at the con aren't gonna get don't know that information and they're not gonna get it unless someone tells it To him and you know They're not gonna happen to go to this panel that gives the information that happened to go to this showing.
Speaker 1: that matches up.
Speaker 1: They're gonna walk into the showing, you know, probably in the middle of it and wonder what's going on.
Speaker 1: And but if they happen to walk in, you know during the you know Big our block in between two showings where either they're wrapping up the previous showing or discussing the next one Then that's a lot of people are gonna get the proper info and get a whole new appreciation for what they're seeing
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: Related in a way that I'll explain after we talk about the next idea anime cons need keynote speeches.
Speaker 1: I Yeah, I mean you look at opening and closing ceremonies and anime cons and basically they shrink them and shrink them and shrink them Because no one cares and they all suck.
Speaker 1: They mostly suck.
Speaker 0: now part of the problem there.
Speaker 0: Is that most cons?
Speaker 0: Otakon and anime Boston handled is better than a lot of cons and cops accounts.
Speaker 0: Okay at it But it takes them a long time to get everyone their badges and people show up late on Friday.
Speaker 0: So you have the situation where opening ceremonies can't be near the beginning of the convention because no one has a badge yet.
Speaker 0: Yep, you've had anime cons.
Speaker 0: You really have to have the opening ceremonies on Saturday.
Speaker 0: But at PAX, you know The keynote speech can basically start the con because one they mail out the badges To the con starts like late on Friday.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It doesn't start early which kind of sucks.
Speaker 1: I wish it would start early because they give you the badge already.
Speaker 1: start it right away.
Speaker 1: Come on.
Speaker 1: We're sitting here everyone's here start at the same time.
Speaker 0: it kind of works because everyone shows up late on Friday and the con goes until the End on Sunday and everyone stays to the last minute.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yeah, we're not talking about packs we're talking about anime cons, but the real problem with anime conventions is that they They're straying away from anime and I don't mean this in the Daryl Surratt way.
Speaker 1: Well, his his basically his gripe is and I'm sure he won't come.
Speaker 1: you know, I'm you know, I've talked about this with him and Gerald and other people enough is that if you call yourself an anime con Be like this is Otacon.
Speaker 1: It's an anime convention.
Speaker 1: You should.
Speaker 1: why do you have non anime things you called yourself an anime con, you know, it's basically false advertising.
Speaker 1: That's their complaint.
Speaker 1: They like video games.
Speaker 1: They like I don't know how much they like Star Wars and such but you know, I'm sure they like some side I'm sure they like some science fiction II things right, you know, they like other geekeries Even though they're primarily into anime and manga.
Speaker 1: it's their complaint is the false advertising situation.
Speaker 1: if a con says this is an anime and gaming con and that has anime and gaming they really have no room to Complain.
Speaker 0: I still disagree with them and my reasoning primarily is the RIT anime club.
Speaker 0: the most successful Biggest anime clubs are not clubs that are dedicated Exclusively to the consumption and learning of and learning about anime and nothing else.
Speaker 0: They are clubs that collect a whole bunch of people who are related to each other by their mutual like of Anime who do other things together.
Speaker 0: they hang out with people who like the same thing.
Speaker 0: They watch anime, but they also have a dodgeball game
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 0: and I think that is the way to go and that's why anime cons have exploded and are so successful And have basically taken over the so-called geek convention circuit and how every other geekery is very focused in its tiny little Usually crappy conventions.
Speaker 0: and yet anime conventions are gigantic.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I can say I think and sum that up.
Speaker 1: You know, is that Otakon?
Speaker 1: is it?
Speaker 1: You know, I just said it was an anime convention, but is it really?
Speaker 1: Otakon is really technically on paper Convention of otaku generation, right?
Speaker 1: So and not the bad podcast, but you know Right, so if you think about it, well the convention of otaku generation the people of the otaku generation They like video games.
Speaker 1: So the convention for them should have some video games.
Speaker 1: It makes sense.
Speaker 0: Also, it's not really false advertising the fact that you both like giant robo and you play some Smash Brothers together.
Speaker 0: That's that's what being a member of the anime fan community is all about.
Speaker 0: I think that's the best way to do it.
Speaker 0: But when I say straying away from anime I mean the more and more of what goes on.
Speaker 0: at most anime conventions is the same thing that we see with the moe.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't want to get into all that but that file specter of moe panel summed it up anime conventions are kind of the self-feeding cycle now to where the majority of the content is either reflexive or reflective or Recycled meta fan content as opposed to content about or really related to the anime.
Speaker 0: Oh, I mean what was one of the most popular panels at Otakon last year?
Speaker 0: The Phoenix Wright like skit panel.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: and The trouble is that they cons try to combat this by having the very intellectual.
Speaker 0: I'm going to talk about Kazuo Koike and why I think he is the genius of our generation.
Speaker 0: No one goes to those panels.
Speaker 0: They don't know who Kazuo Koike is.
Speaker 0: yep, but the way to go about this is you've got to mix the two and have the Popular stuff to get people to come to panels and enjoy themselves and really have a good time.
Speaker 0: But you've also got to just as a byproduct of everything the con does Point out all the real stuff so that the people who are getting into anime will you know?
Speaker 0: They just go to the giant robot smashing the other giant robot showing anything.
Speaker 0: It's awesome, but they kind of remember.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he said what was the guy's name who directed that?
Speaker 0: Hey, where they're showing something else that guy did later We should check that out too.
Speaker 0: Yeah Mm-hmm, and that's how I got into anime.
Speaker 0: like really from I went from being just a casual fan to becoming a Self-described fan is because I started to pay attention to all this stuff that all the nerds kept talking about.
Speaker 0: It's more and more anime con stuff.
Speaker 0: doesn't talk about the stuff the nerds talk about Or they talk about it in a way only nerds would care about.
Speaker 1: yeah Yeah, you definitely if you look at a lot of the the content It's not actually you know it's not even anime manga or video game content.
Speaker 1: It's anime manga video game fan content.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: you know you have these fans going to learn about anime video games and manga and such.
Speaker 1: But then they're even taking a step out.
Speaker 1: they're going to a panel about themselves for themselves.
Speaker 1: And where's the anime and manga and stuff doesn't even really doesn't come into it.
Speaker 1: You know and I think really you should just sort of get rid of those things even if they're popular.
Speaker 1: Or you know push them to the side or not get rid of them mix them You know.
Speaker 1: so the same panel even if it has some of that meta fan content should also be You know this in this in the same panel should also be good.
Speaker 0: so that's the key is you don't get rid of it Because that stuff is great.
Speaker 0: I mean I really enjoy all that kind of meta stuff.
Speaker 0: It's fun Yeah, the prop though the way I think to really address it is to make everything a little more highbrow in general across the board and More professional.
Speaker 0: it's still fan run but just kind of up the lowest common denominator a Little bit just a tiny bit and just mention the names of directors and have Showings that have a little bit of value add.
Speaker 0: don't just say it's an anime con.
Speaker 0: We have to have anime showing.
Speaker 0: say it's an anime con.
Speaker 0: if we're going to have an anime showing There should be some value add beyond the fact that it happens to be an anime showing.
Speaker 0: Mmm if we're gonna have some fan panel there should be some value add other than the fact that it is just a fan panel.
Speaker 0: hmm and With opening ceremonies a lot of cons They're just.
Speaker 0: they're really really really really really really really really lame really lame Oh my but I think Otakon.
Speaker 1: I went to an Otakon opening ceremonies and what it pretty much amounted to was the
Speaker 0: voice
Speaker 1: of Otakon says Welcome, and then let us show you all our guests and all the guests come out and say hello I'm the guest and hello I'm this parade of guests so you can see them all.
Speaker 0: penny arcade Expo.
Speaker 0: meanwhile the rock music starts the light starts showing I feel like I am at a rock concert Fucking epic.
Speaker 0: instead of rockers being brought out on stage It is taiko in his goddamn cape and games bald ass shiny head.
Speaker 0: that guy oh my god, and the key note.
Speaker 0: I mean a keynote speech.
Speaker 0: Why don't anime cons have that?
Speaker 0: it doesn't have to be like the voice actor who doesn't speak English or?
Speaker 0: Crispin Freeman or anything like that.
Speaker 0: just get someone even tangentially related to the anime industry who can give a good hour-long talk.
Speaker 0: That is in some way related to the otaku generation And you know what.
Speaker 0: even if people don't go to it right away The word will spread.
Speaker 0: because the people who go to this thing if you make it professional high quality you have a good speaker He gives a good talk, and you make it.
Speaker 0: you make this idea that is they must go to events.
Speaker 0: That will do more than anything to raise the brow of the anime convention.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if you look at like the pack schedule Right the problem with the good at the great thing and the sort of not so great thing about the pack schedule Is basically you look at an anime con schedule right and most people you know?
Speaker 1: Vast majority people are going to that masquerade right and the big concert right.
Speaker 1: there's these big Mega events that everyone's going to at PAX.
Speaker 1: It's just mega event after mega event.
Speaker 1: It's keynote the game and taiko Q&A right the the red versus blue event.
Speaker 1: Yeah the make a strip panel the Second game in taiko Q&A the omega-thon final round the Friday concerts the Saturday concerts.
Speaker 1: it's just mega event after mega event.
Speaker 1: boom boom boom and Everyone's going to those motherfuckers.
Speaker 1: You know it now.
Speaker 1: clearly the anime conventions Don't have enough mega events.
Speaker 0: well, but at the same time It's very much masquerade cosplay chess.
Speaker 0: Maybe anime cons are too big to have.
Speaker 0: the paradigm of everyone goes to these big events.
Speaker 0: And the other problem is and this is the real issue in regards to all this the keynote at PAX worked because There was no line at all to get badges.
Speaker 0: everyone would be in the con immediately when it opened mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Well, why don't we?
Speaker 1: why don't we talk about this?
Speaker 1: You know we've said for years that anime cons rich every convention should mail out the badges And they gave you know.
Speaker 1: every convention We've ever said this to has always had a very reasonable and understandable response and the response is this number one They're worried about forgery if we mail out these badges to everyone.
Speaker 1: people will just copy them and get in for free.
Speaker 1: Number two right it takes a lot of work and a lot of money to mail out the badges.
Speaker 1: We'd have to actually spend like a whole weekend or maybe even more time putting all these things in envelopes with the addresses and You know writing all these names on them and this whole thing.
Speaker 1: right you know.
Speaker 1: and you look at specific situations like say I don't know the Otacon situation right where they have a different badge arts.
Speaker 1: that means They'd have to let you choose the badge you want beforehand.
Speaker 1: are they gonna Let you write your own name on it.
Speaker 1: You know and the are they just gonna write your name on it for you It's a whole.
Speaker 1: you know some conventions.
Speaker 1: They want to like see your ID to make sure I. otherwise they mail them out You know right and all this sort of stuff that goes on and you know this There's a lot of you know.
Speaker 1: they could hire a company to take care of it But it costs a lot of money and all those things are pretty understandable.
Speaker 1: But despite those things I say there's no excuse not to mail out the badges.
Speaker 0: well One thing I can say is that we got a series of fantastic emails from actually Jackie Who is the director of registration for anime Boston?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and she talked in great detail about the the rationale for why anime Boston does not mail them out and all the things they Do and I don't want to.
Speaker 1: we should do a separate show One of those situations where someone makes a whole bunch of points and all those points are true and correct But yet, I still think they should do it anyway.
Speaker 0: well I don't want to read her emails on the air just because we've already gone on forever on this topic but we'll do a separate show because She made a lot of great points, and I think I agree with absolutely everything she said mm-hmm and That is the real core problem with anime conventions And it's actually a multifaceted and very difficult to solve problem.
Speaker 0: and to summarize as best.
Speaker 0: I can the demographic of an anime convention as opposed to say packs no packs was Late 20-something affluent gamer guys.
Speaker 1: yeah, I mean you know there was some early 20-somethings in some high schools But it was girls.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was yeah a lot of girls at packs.
Speaker 0: actually I would say it was about 55 45 Yeah, but you know packs skewed older than Otakon not just older But also just a much more affluent.
Speaker 0: I mean people had money at packs.
Speaker 0: well
Speaker 1: and also the people at packs just were more mature
Speaker 0: in
Speaker 1: their acting,
Speaker 0: but the the demographic skew of Anime conventions like Otakon, Katsu-Kon, Anime Boston tends to be Teenagers often on the younger end of the scale often under 18 Who have not traveled on their own Much if at all in their lives.
Speaker 0: for many people going to anime conventions I've confirmed this by talking to a lot of people at anime conventions It is their first major trip anywhere without their parents.
Speaker 0: wow or their parents took them and left them at the hotel that their parents Got for them, and then went off on their own vacation, and they don't have a lot of money.
Speaker 0: They're often very poor usually because they're in high school.
Speaker 0: I didn't have any money in high school as I get it down Yep, and all of these factors combined Cause so many like strange problems that you wouldn't even think about.
Speaker 1: It's almost like you can't operate as a convention.
Speaker 1: you have to operate as like a freaking summer camp because all these you know Punk kids.
Speaker 0: I mean like one example that really comes up a lot is that These kids don't know how to get hotel rooms And I remember it was at an Otakon a few years ago.
Speaker 1: You call up a hotel on the telephone.
Speaker 0: you say I would like A room, please let's not get into that, but someone asked seriously at a con feedback session.
Speaker 0: I think it was an Otakon.
Speaker 0: it might have been Katsu-Kan.
Speaker 0: They basically said that their hotel had ripped them off And they wanted the con to fix it because the hotel said one right, but when they checked out they charged him something else and All indications were that this hotel had charged them Taxes
Speaker 1: which is what hotels do
Speaker 0: and they did not realize this.
Speaker 1: and also There's also the other problem on top of that which is what does the convention have to do with your hotel room?
Speaker 1: Convention has nothing to do with your hotel.
Speaker 1: Why are you asking them?
Speaker 1: But it also just that's like going to complain to my work about my rent.
Speaker 0: Conventions like Otakon and anime all these anime conventions have to cater to a lot of needs that they really shouldn't have to like.
Speaker 0: the The policy of most anime conventions in regards to a lost badge or a you know forgot my registration.
Speaker 0: I show up at the con and I don't you have like an ID.
Speaker 0: any of that stuff is to accommodate the person in any possible way and most conventions will like give you a new badge or have some sort of policy for that.
Speaker 1: but Some of them say no badge tough shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but many don't.
Speaker 1: but it's not just the badges though.
Speaker 1: There are many situations in which that is a fan-run convention.
Speaker 1: They really care.
Speaker 1: They're really trying to be as accommodating as helpful and as nice as they possibly can be and they are and they succeed in the Sun to be said for that.
Speaker 1: But perhaps they shouldn't be now.
Speaker 0: I mean look at a professional event.
Speaker 0: if I lose my badge fuck you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you lose your badge, then you're a comic-con.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be like.
Speaker 1: so it's like losing your ticket to a baseball game.
Speaker 0: No, well, they did you look at their policy?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: You don't know.
Speaker 1: I know if you lose your ticket to a baseball game You're fucked.
Speaker 0: that even the read cons are a lot more accommodating than you would think.
Speaker 0: Yeah But like one of the biggest concerns of mailing badges out that is perfectly legitimate is that these people will lose their badges.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: I hate to say it but the demographic of anime conventions.
Speaker 0: This is a concern.
Speaker 0: I mean packs, it's not a concern.
Speaker 0: They had a line for people who like lost their badge or had problems or whatever There was.
Speaker 0: there were like two people in that line Like there's just no one had problems.
Speaker 0: You know tens of thousands of people have their badges mailed to them with no incidents that caused a problem whatsoever.
Speaker 1: None that were noticed in any way or had any visible effect for anyone else.
Speaker 0: and the anime convention people who run this stuff point legitimately that if we mail out the badges there will be crazy problems.
Speaker 0: and I do not say that no you are wrong.
Speaker 0: Look at packs.
Speaker 0: I say you are right.
Speaker 0: You will have these problems.
Speaker 0: I mean anime conventions.
Speaker 0: if they mail the badges out I would wager that a full 10% of people are gonna show up without their badge and you just.
Speaker 1: I think that they should do That and they should just say tough shit.
Speaker 1: I think that's what they have to do because I think even though in the short term you would have a lot of upset people And all these punk kids I think that a it'll be a good lesson for those punk kids and they will be better for it and be the convention will Be better for it.
Speaker 1: And even though it's it's a short-term suffering for a long-term gain.
Speaker 0: I don't even think necessarily full tough shit.
Speaker 0: I think you can ease into it because the real Concern just needs some toughness any toughness to be better than no toughness.
Speaker 0: conventions have gotten more and more Accommodating and as a result people who go to conventions are more and more Expecting all of this kind of extra.
Speaker 1: this is yeah, it's a problem whenever you're too nice, right people sort of you know The the standard of what is you know acceptable.
Speaker 1: you're raising the bar And so basically this sort of like this, you know level of okay.
Speaker 1: This is satisfactory and we are going so far above and beyond.
Speaker 1: Right, we're so great.
Speaker 1: But if you're so great every time then eventually the bar of satisfactory is raised up into what should just be great.
Speaker 1: So now if you become a little less great than you were before Suddenly everyone thinks you're being bad.
Speaker 1: But really you're still ten times better than everyone else.
Speaker 1: You know you were just being extra nice before.
Speaker 1: you're being unnecessarily nice and people took it for granted.
Speaker 1: And you can't you know, you got to make sure that people don't take your extra extra extra awesomeness for granted Because that'll bite you.
Speaker 0: I'm not I don't.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna want to get into all the specific suggestions because obviously a Plan to do something about this problem is.
Speaker 0: it has to be more than tough shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we don't have time to talk about details.
Speaker 1: But do you want to talk about the one the one big thing?
Speaker 0: Well, we'll get to that because the other concern, you know One more idea that comes up from the demographics is that people have no money.
Speaker 0: So as a result The volunteering situation is the opposite for things like packs.
Speaker 0: at packs and cons like it the people who run the convention are either professionals or Despite the fact that packs is a for-profit con They're still all volunteers like all those enforcers are the equivalent of gophers that anime cons.
Speaker 0: But rather than having people at the convention advertising things like punk kid no money Volunteer for 20 hours doing the grunt work and we'll give you a place to stay with like eight other punk kids and a free badge.
Speaker 0: Instead packs has a waiting list to be considered to be a volunteer for the next pack.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean why are anime cons begging for enforcers?
Speaker 1: Otakon has more attendees than packs by a lot because packs counts Turnstyle and Otakon counts badges.
Speaker 1: Yep packs Otakon is a ton more people.
Speaker 1: Why does packs have people lining up and on a waiting list to be a volunteer.
Speaker 1: and why does Otakon beg people to volunteer?
Speaker 1: What is wrong with this picture?
Speaker 0: and not just Otakon?
Speaker 0: every anime convention the first time I ever staffed a con I was at an early Katsucon and I was drunk and I was walking along with Scott Johnson.
Speaker 0: We were both drunk and the staffer comes up and there's like you two have just been nominated to be blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: She handed us staff badges and said if you guys just mod Take care of this hallway and keep people from sitting on the floor for an hour.
Speaker 0: You've got staff badges No, and we were like, okay Thanks But that and there are so many reasons for this because the people who go to cons like packs are people like us for the most part or who you know.
Speaker 0: We go to Otakon for all these years and just showing up as an attendee in and of itself doesn't do a lot for us.
Speaker 0: But being volunteers being staff helping out doing panels that is so much fun that that's why we'll do it for free forever.
Speaker 0: We love it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but It's hard to get people who?
Speaker 0: Want to volunteer and can afford to take time off work and just go to this convention with very little compensation and do it.
Speaker 0: But yet I kind of like packs.
Speaker 0: everyone can afford to go anyway, and they actually enjoy volunteering.
Speaker 0: So it's basically it's a solved problem.
Speaker 1: Well, I think one major aspect, you know of the thing is that you know at the anime convention, right?
Speaker 1: You got a look at the motivating factor for volunteering, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you ever hear the story about how you know, they go to the lawyers and they say lawyers These old people really need some legal help.
Speaker 1: Will you help them for a discounted rate and all the lawyers go?
Speaker 1: No No, no, but they go to the same lawyers and they say oh Lawyers these old people really need your help.
Speaker 1: Will you help them for free?
Speaker 1: Oh, yes.
Speaker 1: We'd love to help them for free.
Speaker 1: Yes, of course.
Speaker 1: We're so giving in charitable right and it's a psychological thing.
Speaker 1: That's pretty well understood Relatively as any psychological thing can be understood in that when you enter the money into the equation There's different.
Speaker 1: you think with a different part of your brain that makes a financial calculation.
Speaker 1: But by not mentioning the money just saying will you help them out for free?
Speaker 1: You know the sort of charity goodwill part of the brain comes into action Which is separate and so you'll do it.
Speaker 1: the incentive to volunteer at an anime convention Right the fat by fans for fans anime convention, right is free badge.
Speaker 1: So the money part of your brain is coming into it and you're think you're.
Speaker 1: what you really want is to enjoy the con.
Speaker 1: So you're going to right?
Speaker 1: Do the minimal amount of work you can to get that freaking badge because you just want to run off and enjoy the con Right at the professional con where everyone there is a hired hand.
Speaker 1: No volunteers really, right?
Speaker 1: You're making the same money calculation, but you're saying man.
Speaker 1: I ain't getting paid.
Speaker 1: This is my job and they do work because it's their job and they do it Just like you do your job.
Speaker 1: if you have a job, right at PAX They don't call you a gopher or a volunteer.
Speaker 1: They call you an enforcer.
Speaker 1: and if you think that doesn't have a psychological difference you are.
Speaker 1: I don't know what you're thinking.
Speaker 1: They call you an enforcer.
Speaker 1: It's a position of respect and People look up to you and you know, you feel that you're important.
Speaker 1: You feel you have a duty to something you actually actively care about a great deal.
Speaker 1: You want to do a good job.
Speaker 1: You are there.
Speaker 1: not thinking about money not thinking about trying to get a free badge.
Speaker 1: You're thinking about.
Speaker 1: I'm here I want to do this.
Speaker 1: I'm an enforcer.
Speaker 1: You're taking it seriously.
Speaker 1: You are respected and thanked and You know, you are grateful just even to be able to be an enforcer and you do the best possible job.
Speaker 1: You can know what is you want what this does?
Speaker 0: And the one of the same famous people work on an open-source software.
Speaker 1: the same mentality is enforcer.
Speaker 0: But one of the biggest problems comms have anime comes even when they get volunteers.
Speaker 0: the volunteers don't know crap.
Speaker 0: I mean 90% of anime conventions.
Speaker 0: if you ask an average staffer Any question they will not have the answer yet that you need to find the specialized staffer for your question.
Speaker 0: I mean even the cons.
Speaker 0: we like I'll find a staff and we're like, hey, where's the video room?
Speaker 0: They don't know they just kind of like and they just gotta wait for me to go away.
Speaker 0: And this is at every anime convention.
Speaker 0: I I make a point of asking unless you go to the information booth.
Speaker 0: They know everything well at some cons and the cons info booth is pretty badass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Katsu cons was not so much two years ago anime Boston's was good.
Speaker 0: anime Boston's was good All right, but the stat the first staffer we met had no idea where anything was.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they couldn't answer our question but with the enforcer mentality You don't have to worry about training these people, you know.
Speaker 0: The anime con staffers always point out that it's basically impossible to train these kids Especially with the limited resources and the short amount of time.
Speaker 0: Pax enforcers or people treated that way like the video katsu staff.
Speaker 0: They learn it on their own.
Speaker 0: They care and they make sure that they can answer all these questions.
Speaker 0: because they're so dedicated to the con.
Speaker 0: They care so they learn.
Speaker 0: you don't have to spend any resources teaching them.
Speaker 0: They already know.
Speaker 1: Yep Everyone who's in you know, and it's like you look at other cons, right and it's not just the naming of it, right?
Speaker 1: You look at say Otacon, right?
Speaker 1: They've got gopher.
Speaker 1: They got you know Committed totally committed gopher the volunteer staff Uberstaff.
Speaker 0: right this stupid hierarchical system where if you want to be a staffer I asked several conventions way back Before we even did geek nights like hey, I have a ton of experience.
Speaker 0: I was the president of the biggest anime club in the country for a while.
Speaker 0: I got all my shit together.
Speaker 0: I have experienced staffing conventions other conventions.
Speaker 0: Here's my gigantic resume of related stuff.
Speaker 0: I would love to join the staff and help you out and the answer was universally Well, you can be a gopher to start and then if you're good at that You can work your way up the ladder to which I said, you know what?
Speaker 0: No at PAX Everyone's an enforcer.
Speaker 1: end of story.
Speaker 1: different enforcers have different jobs.
Speaker 1: You know one guy might be in charge of a panel room here One guy might be in charge of all the panel rooms.
Speaker 1: one guy might be in charge of a video game room, right?
Speaker 1: So obviously some people have responsibilities that are larger than others, but everyone is just Enforcer.
Speaker 1: you are an enforcer equal to the other enforcers And you know, so no one has like a higher authority or a lower authority except I guess, you know The you know, Robert Coo or whoever right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know, and I guess you might have a report enforcer.
Speaker 1: You report to and such but you're not.
Speaker 1: there's no ranking There's none of this psychological difference in respect or any.
Speaker 1: you know any, you know duty or anything like that.
Speaker 1: It's an enforcer is an enforcer is enforcer.
Speaker 1: You are the real deal.
Speaker 0: Well part of this like hierarchy that emerges in a lot of anime conventions Especially the smaller ones is that the the high-level staff tend to be a very close-knit clique of people and They seem to not want to let other people eventually replace them or join this inner circle.
Speaker 0: Yes, that's exactly what it is.
Speaker 0: This isn't really as much of a problem with a lot of the bigger cons, but I've seen many unnamed anime conventions where they basically Force new people to do the crap jobs Even if they could be doing much more better work for the con Solely because they want to hold on to their little bit of extra special staff
Speaker 1: power.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean that's another thing right?
Speaker 1: is?
Speaker 1: you look at the the animatic anime con with the hierarchical arrangement right power structure and There's a community of the people at the top there.
Speaker 1: They're possibly hopefully tighten it and all together, right?
Speaker 1: But all the gophers and stuff Rogers these individual laborers basically at PAX all of the enforcers All of them are all in this one community together.
Speaker 1: They're all with each other on this one giant team.
Speaker 1: Everyone is heavily involved in you know in communication in the forums on the newsletter talking to everyone else.
Speaker 1: You know, it's not just a few people at the top sending the orders down from on high.
Speaker 1: It's a big community and You know, you really need the big staff community not the little staff community that you know.
Speaker 1: Just Lord that rules over, you know the minions.
Speaker 0: now you might be saying but rim and Scott Didn't you just say the demographics are mutually exclusive and there's no way to do this.
Speaker 0: Why are you even talking?
Speaker 0: Here's how I think we can pull this off pretty readily.
Speaker 0: one obviously change the name of it.
Speaker 0: Maybe not enforcer That's obviously taken.
Speaker 0: but you know get rid of this whole the current volunteer system and replace it with a more flat structure and Do all the psychological stuff.
Speaker 1: I mean you can even get the name staff.
Speaker 1: people like that staff is a gives people a really good feeling.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there is a lot of hope because just in this last year I've seen this gigantic reversal in the demographics.
Speaker 0: I think this year for the first time in like six years the average age of anime con goers is going to go up.
Speaker 1: Well, I think because anime is not on television.
Speaker 1: You're not getting the new fans.
Speaker 1: So the only people still coming are the people who are fans, you know, the Naruto people, right?
Speaker 1: The Naruto people are getting older.
Speaker 1: so the only you know, it's them still coming and still coming.
Speaker 0: but think about it You know coming say one year you have a hundred new people who come to Otakon because they watch Dragon Ball Z on TV.
Speaker 0: The next year 90 of those come back because they remembered they had a good time.
Speaker 0: the next year 60 of them come back but now they've moved on to all this other anime.
Speaker 0: and the next year 40 come back and those 40 will come back for the Rest of their lives and they're the ones who know the names of directors at this point.
Speaker 0: Yep, but so anime had this gigantic surge in popularity in the US.
Speaker 0: So every year I mean Otakon like.
Speaker 0: the growth of Otakon was crazy to the point that the fact that Otakon dealt with, you know, these 8,000 person per year leaps is Amazing to me like I still cannot.
Speaker 0: it is so cool that Otakon was able to handle that without missing a beat Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I mean even a con.
Speaker 0: I I might have been running probably would have collapsed under that load.
Speaker 1: It's a big load it is.
Speaker 0: but now anime the surge kind of died and the growth is dropping off and we're starting to see the shift go back toward the.
Speaker 0: The self-described anime fans come back and there aren't as many newer fans and I think in a couple more years Anime cons are going to be at this steady state again.
Speaker 0: I think Otakon will probably cap out around 30,000 ish people, but I think the age is going to go up.
Speaker 0: I think the income is going to go up and I think They will be able to get away with being much more selective in their staffing, but at the same time We'll be able to get more total staffers.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and better staffers.
Speaker 1: You still have to one good staffers worth five crappy one.
Speaker 0: You still have to do all of the psychological stuff.
Speaker 0: You still have to get rid of the.
Speaker 0: you know, grab gophers at the con mentality.
Speaker 0: You have to make people apply to be a staffer Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I think another.
Speaker 1: another problem though.
Speaker 1: Is that you the sort of unique to PAX is that you know PAX has this penny arcade community and then it is a convention.
Speaker 1: on top of that These other conventions Otakana anime Boston etc.
Speaker 1: Right are.
Speaker 1: just all they are is a convention.
Speaker 1: They aren't on top of an existing thing.
Speaker 1: well So I think what they really need to do a lot of work on right is they need to do a lot of work in building the community Outside of the rest of the year when the convention isn't going on.
Speaker 0: now a lot of them try I mean try but they don't try.
Speaker 0: all these cons have the active forum communities.
Speaker 0: They do.
Speaker 0: the forum community of every con we've ever been to is not in any way Representative of the people who show up to the con at all.
Speaker 1: And I think you know, all these conventions are friendly with each other.
Speaker 1: They all have boobs at each other's conventions and such and such and such, right?
Speaker 1: I think they would do well to not not partner up actually in a business sense because you don't want to like You know have Otakon suffer because some you know other conventions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was basically any con Otakon joined with would just like.
Speaker 1: but they should create one Anime convention community place one that is sanctioned internet, but it's the official one.
Speaker 1: for maybe even You know get the anime news network in on there, you know, and that should be you know The place.
Speaker 1: that sort of holds everything together and then off of that is what you know.
Speaker 1: You can create the same sort of arrangement where there is the community which spawns the conventions out from it.
Speaker 0: Now, I don't know which cons will do or try to do or tell us why we can't do any of the things we just talked About.
Speaker 0: but one thing I can say in regards of the showing rooms any con that pays for our hotel and travel We've got enough of our own staff to run that for you.
Speaker 1: Yes Anything that we have suggested if you say can't be done.
Speaker 1: Well, we will do it.
Speaker 1: We are the put-up.
Speaker 1: So don't come and tell us why it can't be done because we will do it and then you're in trouble.
Speaker 0: And if you don't believe us seriously ask Katsu Con or Kinetic Con.
Speaker 0: We we have put up anything that any con has ever challenged us to do.
Speaker 0: Not counting crazy conventions do two panels at once.
Speaker 1: Sorry.
Speaker 1: That's not gonna.
Speaker 0: yeah, well, I'm not going to name the con but there is a con that every year asks us to come and Basically will not accommodate anything we need and simultaneously will make ludicrous demands of us.
Speaker 0: We don't go as a result.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but like Otakon we can.
Speaker 0: we can bring enough staff to personally do most of the stuff We talked about.
Speaker 0: yep, like you won't even need any people.
Speaker 0: just give us the authority and we've got like 20 staff We can bring.
Speaker 0: they'll be ready to go.
Speaker 0: We'll have everything ready like six months before the con.
Speaker 0: You think we're done.
Speaker 0: we've gone on way too long here.
Speaker 1: All right It was a lot to say about.
Speaker 0: there was a lot to say and I still have more to say but We'll do a separate show about the mailing out.
Speaker 1: bad yet another show.
Speaker 0: Well, no, I want to get some of these staffers who have emailed me and have an actual discussion with them on the air Shit later way later after con season because good God we have a lot to do.
Speaker 0: before Otakon and Connecticut This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week Covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew.com or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 1: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.