Speaker 1: Hey, it's Tuesday, February 3rd.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: It should be a Monday hand.
Speaker 1: This is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We talk about gravity bone.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: You might notice it's a it's Tuesday night.
Speaker 1: We're doing a Tuesday show.
Speaker 1: there was no Monday show last night because we We accidentally tried to do a Tuesday Thursday week after already having Donna Tuesday Thursday week.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whose fault is that entirely?
Speaker 0: Scott's what he's talking about.
Speaker 1: I was like on Sunday.
Speaker 1: I was like hey Scott What are we doing the show on?
Speaker 1: He's like, I don't know.
Speaker 1: and I was like, well, it's Tuesday, right?
Speaker 0: And he's like, yeah, I was like, I don't know.
Speaker 0: And you said yeah, it's Tuesday, right?
Speaker 0: There it's your fault.
Speaker 0: Um, but yeah, I don't know if there's gonna be another show this week.
Speaker 0: Are we gonna see that movie on Thursday?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so maybe we'll do a Wednesday show Like we should have.
Speaker 1: So we'll only be out one Monday as opposed to just totally cocking it up.
Speaker 0: and the comic-con is Friday Saturday Sunday But I had to go to grandma's birthday party on Saturday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm probably gonna go Saturday Sunday and Scott's fucking like Friday.
Speaker 1: We got to figure all that out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what to do something, but oh, yeah, New York Comic Con is this weekend.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So we're not doing should go.
Speaker 1: We are not doing any shows.
Speaker 1: They're nothing.
Speaker 1: live.
Speaker 1: We're not doing anything.
Speaker 1: the next New York Comic Con We probably will this one.
Speaker 1: now, we're just press.
Speaker 1: So if you want to find us look for Luke Crane at the mouse guard table.
Speaker 0: Look for two guys with press badges walking around looking around.
Speaker 1: We kind of stand out.
Speaker 1: we'll probably have Emily with us as a photographer and such and we might have Alex and Jess and other front row crew people hanging out at least one of the days.
Speaker 1: so We're not that hard to find.
Speaker 1: but I it is, you know, I had found myself over the weekend at a circuit city.
Speaker 1: you know, they're going out of business and Unlike previous goings out of business of stores, like when media play went out of business You couldn't get deals on anything.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz I mean basically what happens is they put tiny discounts on first of all.
Speaker 0: Right, if you go to a store that's not going out of business.
Speaker 0: Everything in the store is slightly discounted right just about nothing is a manufacturer retail price.
Speaker 0: That's red ludicrous Apple products, right?
Speaker 0: So if you go to the when they liquidate a school a store They basically return everything to manufacturers suggested retail price and then put like a 10 or 20 percent discount on everything.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the economy used to be different.
Speaker 1: So like when media play went out like upstream suppliers would take stuff back and like other people would buy it in ball.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean you couldn't buy books when media play went out of business because someone else just came in and bought all the books.
Speaker 0: So you couldn't you know go in and individually get books at like half off or worse.
Speaker 1: It was kind of an aside that it made me realize what media is worth to me because there was stuff left Like there were anime DVDs for like four bucks and there were video like computer games like $50 computer games for five bucks And I stood there holding them and then decided they weren't worth what I
Speaker 0: bought this Atari DS game Basically had like breakout and a few other Atari games like directly translate It was not
Speaker 1: worth the like 90 cents.
Speaker 0: You paid almost nothing for it and I regret buying it.
Speaker 0: That's how bad it was.
Speaker 1: But now with the economy the way it is you got a circuit city and they've got like everything actually Discounted and they've got everything still there because people aren't buying it so quickly and people lined up.
Speaker 0: But people you know, it's not they're not buying enough The things they bought right away.
Speaker 1: what's gone?
Speaker 1: like those netbooks they had 10 20% off are all gone.
Speaker 1: No, yeah, definitely, but not gone the DS games and they're all like 20% off.
Speaker 1: So I went in and I realized that I don't want any DS games that are already out.
Speaker 1: all the DS games I want aren't out yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I pre-ordered the Fire Emblem game and I also pre-ordered this other game like Henry Hats worth puzzling adventure or something like that.
Speaker 0: It's a puzzle II platform game.
Speaker 0: I'll figure what the hell.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're talking it up.
Speaker 1: We need something like that.
Speaker 0: because Yeah, well there have been.
Speaker 0: no I think there have been at least two sequels just not in the u.s.
Speaker 1: You're mistaking this for Japan where they get good game.
Speaker 1: There's found three Buzz us three, I wouldn't pay five These games but I would probably pay if I had no other option Almost a hundred dollars for a DS cart that just had mother one two and three on it in English.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like that would be with a quality translation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you can get the ROM but really honestly, really honestly.
Speaker 1: But the only game they had that was worthwhile that I didn't already own Was Final Fantasy Tactics Advance 2 and I wouldn't have bought it.
Speaker 1: it was like 20 bucks and I still wouldn't have bought it.
Speaker 1: but for the fact that a nonth had it and The he said it was good enough for someone like me to play and I trust him.
Speaker 1: I played the other one until I realized that No amount of strategy at any impact on maybe you know, it's not true for the new one.
Speaker 1: Oh as soon as I discover that's true.
Speaker 1: I'll probably stop playing it.
Speaker 1: but to its credit Dragon girls pretty cute.
Speaker 1: They also updated the designs of the bunny girls and you can see the appeal of this.
Speaker 0: That's that's just fantastic.
Speaker 1: Actually, one of the things that I liked about the the previous tactics was the whole, you know Fighting with the other clans thing was like this a side game But it didn't really matter except for getting you a bunch of McGuffins and goodies and you know my bath.
Speaker 1: my dad does five more damage now, but They really upped the ante on the clan battling like you get territory and control it and we'll see.
Speaker 1: I'll talk about the game in more depth Once I play it for more than I don't know five minutes because I still haven't beaten Dracula yet in the most recent.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, there's a bad guy.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: It's actually Dracula game.
Speaker 0: Yeah So it's actually it's sort of opportune that we did the show today and messed up and didn't do one yesterday like we were supposed to.
Speaker 0: Because I don't know it's all over the news.
Speaker 0: I don't know how anyone could possibly miss it, but 50 years ago today was the day that the music died and No one in the forum said anything.
Speaker 0: so I'm assuming that the punk kids have no clue why this is a big deal and I think it is very important that I teach them a lesson Exactly how large the magnitude of this tragedy was and why it is all over the news.
Speaker 1: What does not deserve like an entire show unto itself?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I don't have an entire show unto itself to do this.
Speaker 1: We could do a special.
Speaker 0: You have a non Tuesday.
Speaker 0: All right, regardless punk kids take heed Right, so Imagine if right imagine this John Lennon Furtie Mercury and Jimmy Page.
Speaker 0: Imagine if all of them in like the middle like the middle of the 60s right when they were just getting started or whatever.
Speaker 0: All died like, you know, I don't know.
Speaker 0: they were out of you know They were in a plane in a crash and they all died.
Speaker 0: Imagine what the world would be like right now how different it would be.
Speaker 1: imagine if art its video game night.
Speaker 1: imagine if she get her.
Speaker 1: Miyamoto Had just Never been born or he died halfway through like the early days of Nintendo times three.
Speaker 0: So it was.
Speaker 0: it wasn't just Miyamoto is also Iwata and Yokoi all three of them.
Speaker 1: Not Gunpei.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Gunpei Yokoi.
Speaker 1: What did he ever do that was good everything?
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway except for except for getting off.
Speaker 0: imagine Imagine how different everything would be right.
Speaker 0: so you think you know You try to think of the world with like three super important people missing from it.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what you live in that world.
Speaker 0: three super important people are missing from the world that we live in.
Speaker 0: The world is fucked up because 50 years ago the Buddy Holly Ritchie Valens and the Big Bopper were in a plane and it crashed and they all died.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of speculation as to why it crashed and what.
Speaker 0: well, no, there's no spec.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you the story.
Speaker 1: There is quote-unquote speculation because I remember very distinctly as a kid I was watching the History Channel and they had a documentary that was called something like what really happened when the music died.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you what really happened and pretty much it was like they were free basic.
Speaker 1: No, what the fuck?
Speaker 1: This is what?
Speaker 1: All I'm saying is that no this was a documentary That Pretended it was legitimate that I saw as a kid and I was somewhat incredulous even then.
Speaker 0: All right, here's the stall.
Speaker 0: Summarize the story.
Speaker 0: Of course people have studied this.
Speaker 0: You know event intensely and there are incredible incredible amounts of detail like but minute by minute what happened?
Speaker 0: But I will summarize for you ready.
Speaker 0: So all these musicians were on tour, right?
Speaker 0: but this was like, you know, this is they were touring around the Midwest and You know back in those days it was just a normal kind of you know ballroom music tour, right?
Speaker 0: It didn't have a big high profile or anything.
Speaker 0: But you know really nowadays you look at a concert tour and it's got like a headline band and like a middle Bad and like, you know some low-hanging fruits.
Speaker 0: This was like, you know Historically when you look back at it was like all number one straight across the board.
Speaker 0: this tour, right?
Speaker 0: The thing is the tour organizer was stupid and he basically the tour dates were like one night They'd be in Chicago and one night they'd be in Detroit and then one night they'd be back in like, Indiana.
Speaker 0: So they're basically going back and forth and back and forth instead of you know in a nice row.
Speaker 0: So it was lots and lots of extra travel.
Speaker 0: So everyone was real tired and real grumpy Right.
Speaker 0: in addition they were on a tour bus as you know Was the style of the times and still is and the tour bus had no heat and it was like the worst tour bus imaginable.
Speaker 0: It was like the biggest piece of shit.
Speaker 0: So one night right there was no concert and the concert promoter guy like got them a show, right?
Speaker 0: he's like, oh I got a show to fill in the empty night and they had to go all the way back somewhere else and From where they were.
Speaker 0: so some of the guys are just like, you know what?
Speaker 0: Fuck this Let's see if we can charter a fucking plane.
Speaker 0: Let's just do it.
Speaker 0: and you know, some people were like no I can't pay the money right like.
Speaker 0: one guy said You know, it's gonna be.
Speaker 0: they found out it was gonna be $36, you know.
Speaker 0: And I think three people could go see.
Speaker 0: one guy like remembered how when he was a kid his parents like couldn't get $36 to the rent.
Speaker 0: so he was like there's no way I'm paying a whole rent on a plane ride.
Speaker 0: But you know and in the end You know buddy Holly the big bopper and Richie Valens were the three who were on the plane.
Speaker 0: one of them I think was on the plane because they want a coin toss or something and They plane crashed.
Speaker 0: the reason the plane crash is very simple.
Speaker 0: Remember the bus had no heat and they were grumpy about it because it was winter.
Speaker 0: It was cold.
Speaker 0: It was snowing.
Speaker 0: There was a snowstorm.
Speaker 0: the pilot, you know, this is the kind of guy that you charter like, you know You just will go out to the airport and charted this dude.
Speaker 0: He was not the greatest pilot in the universe.
Speaker 0: He actually couldn't fly on instruments only and it was night and it was a snowstorm and he was a bad pilot.
Speaker 1: Channel said they were all free-basing cocaine.
Speaker 0: They might have been as they were musicians in the late 50s.
Speaker 0: cocaine may have been involved.
Speaker 0: However, the reason for the plane crash, it was probably not the cocaine if any.
Speaker 1: There this is.
Speaker 1: I mean if you think when John Bonham died that was bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people just they just don't get it, you know, and the thing is it's because you had like, you know.
Speaker 0: Look at someone like Elvis, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, he made all this music and you know, he wasn't perfect and you know Always but you know, so influential and significant and whatever, right?
Speaker 0: Buddy Holly alone, right?
Speaker 0: He was only like a musician for a year and a half and then he died.
Speaker 0: and in that time I mean, you know, you know, everyone's heard his name.
Speaker 0: Even if someone doesn't quite know who it is They're like, yeah, I heard that name before.
Speaker 0: that's a famous old musician from back in the day.
Speaker 0: They'll know that much from someone who was only playing music for a year and a half.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if not, if him alone had been playing music longer Right and didn't die just it would been he'd be like as big as Elvis or the Beatles or whatever, of course I mean, it's all the hindsight for all we know.
Speaker 1: They would have never made a good song again.
Speaker 0: It's possible.
Speaker 0: but I mean look at stuff like, you know, Ritchie Valens, right?
Speaker 0: He's known for La Bamba and you think oh, you know, he's sort of a one-hit wonder.
Speaker 0: Well, think about this, right?
Speaker 0: Would he have been a one-hit wonder if he had not died?
Speaker 0: and two even his one-hit La Bamba.
Speaker 0: It's like a mega hit even today You know, it's.
Speaker 1: it's one of those songs that you'll.
Speaker 1: everyone has heard it.
Speaker 1: You all know what it is.
Speaker 1: Even if you have no idea who did it.
Speaker 1: No, don't even know what era it's from but you've heard it and you know it.
Speaker 1: you can hear it in your head right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, I hope you can.
Speaker 0: If you can't that's pretty sad.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe we're just turning into.
Speaker 0: I mean here.
Speaker 0: think about this right a rock-and-roll band, right?
Speaker 0: What instruments do you have in a rock-and-roll band?
Speaker 1: Well, there's the bass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and nothing else matters, of course Right now a rock-and-roll band usually has you know a drum a bass a guitar or two and if there's a second You know and then a vocalist right?
Speaker 0: Maybe the vocalist plays the second guitar, right which is you know.
Speaker 0: But buddy Holly invented that like, you know, I guess maybe he wasn't the first ever to do that.
Speaker 0: But you know rock bands are that way because of a guy who played music for only a year and a half.
Speaker 1: So kids give up one of your energy during toasts or something when you're playing guitar hero.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's Tuesday night.
Speaker 1: There's no way to tie that in.
Speaker 0: no there and I wasn't trying to tie it in but it is too important not to be Noted.
Speaker 1: and the punk kids because the punk kids in the forum like they know like they will celebrate the Anniversary's of things that didn't even happen a year ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean if you celebrate like International Day of Slayer You know, come on.
Speaker 0: I Mean while that is very important it is critical.
Speaker 0: In fact, yes, this is like 10,000 times.
Speaker 1: But anyway to move right along back to video games.
Speaker 1: For all of you who might have bought Gears of War on the PC Which probably might have not been that many people since you know, most people who play Gears of War play it on their console.
Speaker 1: I'm sure you know now that it stopped working Due to the fact that well originally it was reported that the DRM failed.
Speaker 1: the DRM certificate was only good Until January is an Xbox game Yeah, but the PC version is what was effective.
Speaker 0: Oh, I didn't even know there was a PC version.
Speaker 0: That's it You know what?
Speaker 1: I didn't either until I read this article.
Speaker 1: All right, but apparently on January 28th That was the last day that the digital certificate that was used in the game was valid.
Speaker 1: So from that day forward you just can't play it.
Speaker 0: Are they gonna renew it or what?
Speaker 1: They said they're working on it.
Speaker 1: I have yet to find any reference to them having actually fixed it.
Speaker 0: But see the thing is if you just hack or get a pirated version you can play it, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the moral here is that if a game has DRM you should probably just pirate it Yeah, or unless the DRM is reliable like steam Yeah, but even then I've had a lot of trouble with steam.
Speaker 1: It's so weird.
Speaker 0: I mean like.
Speaker 0: I'm not denying that other people have had.
Speaker 0: you know I've had trouble with steam because I've seen other people have trouble with steam.
Speaker 0: I've seen it with my own eyes because you hardly used it, but I have never had trouble with steam.
Speaker 1: my issues I use it every day not Scott my issues primarily that I have a laptop and a desktop and Steam will randomly when it's in offline mode on the laptop.
Speaker 1: Just freak out and say Until you get on the internet again, you can't play any of your games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't use steam on a laptop I just use it on my desktop.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, that's probably why you haven't run into any problem.
Speaker 0: You're poking the bear poking the bear one.
Speaker 1: It has an offline mode and they say very specifically install it on your laptop install it on all your pcs.
Speaker 1: Go to a some arcade somewhere some LAN party place.
Speaker 1: log into your account all your games.
Speaker 1: Yeah Except when that doesn't work.
Speaker 1: But anyway This is I don't know this borders on pathetic.
Speaker 1: It's pretty sad and Apparently they released a statement clarifying that DRM had nothing to do with this bullshit.
Speaker 1: that in fact, it was the anti cheat technology They have built into the game that is at fault That the thing that's supposed to prevent you from cheating at Gears of War is what is preventing you from playing it right now?
Speaker 0: playing it at all at all at all.
Speaker 1: granted, I remember a couple of times in the Kind of the height of cheating in games like counter-strike when punk buster was in use.
Speaker 1: There were a couple times when things like punk buster would like randomly kick me from a game and accused me of cheating and banned Me.
Speaker 0: yeah, but even though you know cheating at the worst They just banned you from online play like valves vac, you know valve anti cheating technology has never screwed with me.
Speaker 0: However, well vac is that but also it just permanently bans you from playing online.
Speaker 0: You can play all the counter-strike on your land that you want.
Speaker 0: if you get vac banned You can also play on non vac servers.
Speaker 1: However, I do point out that Steam's DRM has caused a lot of problems.
Speaker 1: particularly There was a recent update to steam and they made another update that I think fixed it.
Speaker 1: I haven't chanced it yet Whereby?
Speaker 1: and it only affected natural selection and a bunch of other kind of indie mod.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it's cuz those mods so heavily modded the game that it appeared as cheating, you know It's like it wasn't cheating.
Speaker 1: It was that if you were logged into those servers your steam ticket would just expire and you would be kicked Which in a game like NS is is devastating.
Speaker 0: That's pretty bad.
Speaker 0: Like it got
Speaker 1: to the point where I say an alien
Speaker 0: with a bunch of rez going onos and you get kicked what
Speaker 1: I would do is I'd save up rez and cuz when you log back in and get your rez back and then as Soon as I had too much rez and I just been kicked I'd log back in I'd gorge it.
Speaker 1: I'd built like 10 brocees brocees.
Speaker 1: So think the map was all like they like the Marines would be like, all right Everybody heavy now.
Speaker 1: We got five minutes before you all get steamed.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: But I've DRM like people.
Speaker 1: anyone who apologizes for it or says but without DRM people would fire it or Without DRM like DRM is the only way just suck it up or DRM doesn't really cause problems or you know It has problems all the time.
Speaker 0: people who come have DRM have all these problems.
Speaker 0: people who pirate never have any Complaints.
Speaker 1: Yes, this is a problem.
Speaker 1: Plus couple this with all the studies pointing out that People like the 98% piracy rates of some games.
Speaker 1: Maybe those people wouldn't have played the game if they had to pay for in the first place.
Speaker 0: So it's exactly.
Speaker 0: Valve actually has said, you know some people at valve where there was a recent story that they were like Look, we had all this piracy in Russia, right crazy piracy in Russia.
Speaker 0: So what did they do?
Speaker 0: They went and they decided well first of all, let's translate our games to Russian Right and second of all, let's release them in Russia the same day we released them everywhere else, you know on Steam and You know for the same reasonable prices not for up higher lower prices.
Speaker 0: and you know what happened a lot of people in Russia Bought the game and didn't pirate it.
Speaker 0: The opinion of valve is that a pirate is an underserved customer.
Speaker 0: either your price is too high for them Or you're not serving them in some way.
Speaker 0: yet They still want to play your game on some level But they don't you know, they don't want to play it badly enough to pay for it or something else.
Speaker 1: So I think part of that is coming from the fact that there is so much free legal or disposable or so cheap That it doesn't matter entertainment, especially in video games already that if a game isn't good like if a new game comes out and it is not good enough to Like to force you to want it This is a game you have to play like.
Speaker 1: when Left 4 Dead came out you pretty much had to play it.
Speaker 1: That was a fantastic game for a while.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, but every game fades in the end except counter-strike and natural selection and tribes, too If and mega man.
Speaker 1: if a game isn't good enough and there's a hundred games that are all kind of mediocre No punk kid cares enough about any one of them to pay for it.
Speaker 1: if they can play it for free They'll play it for five minutes and then they'll dump it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even I did a whole when spore we came out and it was the early release and all the piracy and all the DRM.
Speaker 0: Remember the whole fiasco.
Speaker 0: I put a poll in our forum and I know a forum poll is not.
Speaker 0: anything is not better than anecdotal evidence you kidding is basically worthless.
Speaker 0: geeknights forum polls are 100% statistically significant Right They five percent even though I recognize that right?
Speaker 0: I still I I honestly do believe that the results of that poll represent reality that there the number of pirates that actually would have bought the game if piracy were not possible and because piracy is possible will not buy the game is such an insignificant Tiny tiny tiny tiny percentage as to be effectively like zero or one percent.
Speaker 1: Well, the problem with spore in particular was that the demo gave me everything I wanted out of that game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the demo?
Speaker 1: I was a little excited but then, you know, I waited for the game to come out.
Speaker 0: That was I think that might have been the the greatest Disproportion between hype and reality ever other than I don't know Daikatana.
Speaker 0: Daikatana didn't have as much hype as spore.
Speaker 0: Ah, it was worse than spore.
Speaker 1: But the tricky part is the disparity.
Speaker 1: I mean if a game is so bad.
Speaker 1: any amount of hype leads that number into the realms of the infinite.
Speaker 0: Spore wasn't good.
Speaker 1: Plus I point out that it's kind of like inflation.
Speaker 1: you have to account for how much hype there was back Then compared to the size of the PC gaming industry.
Speaker 0: It's tough one.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know that was he.
Speaker 0: in a way PC gaming is bigger back then but in a way it's smaller.
Speaker 1: Yeah stuff anyway, I mean back then the hype.
Speaker 1: but seriously this happens too often for people to continue to make the argument that DRM is Okay, as long as it's done correctly.
Speaker 1: because the moral here is that it's not done correctly.
Speaker 1: and this happens all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah Alright, so on steam right now speaking of right there is a beta of a game a Warhammer 40k RTS game called dawn of war 2 and it's.
Speaker 0: they call it a beta But really it's a demo.
Speaker 0: and at the end of the demo it asks you to pre-order the real game, right?
Speaker 0: And all this demo lets you do is play multiplayer.
Speaker 0: That's all it lets you do and he uses.
Speaker 0: it's so weird because he uses games for Windows.
Speaker 0: So it's like you got games or windows and then steam on top of it.
Speaker 0: So it's like I got both things going on for the same exact game.
Speaker 0: It's really weird.
Speaker 0: But so I it was free beta.
Speaker 0: So even though I'm not a you know, I'm not I sort of hate RTS's and that most of them.
Speaker 0: I mean, I like the idea of a real-time game that is strategic.
Speaker 0: That's like the greatest thing in the world.
Speaker 0: but most RTS's end up being who can click the fastest who can remember the exact best sequence of things and Maybe we should do a show on what it would take to make a good RTS.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so this game was free.
Speaker 0: So I figured well might as well give it a shot.
Speaker 0: right at the worst It's just another click fast rights and then I could just delete it.
Speaker 0: It didn't cost me anything.
Speaker 0: So I downloaded and I played it a few times.
Speaker 0: and I played it enough times To sort of learn how it works because there's no tutorial or anything.
Speaker 0: So you sort of have to just sort of keep playing with it and keep poking buttons or to you know figure out what's going on.
Speaker 0: and you know, I sort of played it enough to learn the deal and It's better than other RTS's.
Speaker 0: I've played in a lot of ways, you know in the but in many ways it's also the same old same old right and Basically, I'll just real quick.
Speaker 0: You don't build any buildings.
Speaker 0: You have one building, right?
Speaker 0: I also kind of like building building course.
Speaker 1: That was always the problem because whenever I played counter not counter-strike command and conquer You'd build all the buildings never go anywhere and then tanks just come over the horizon Exactly, or usually I played with other people who were like me.
Speaker 1: So we both build giant bases and never actually attack each other and then the modem connection would usually pan out.
Speaker 1: or Peter Right about.
Speaker 0: as you have this one building, right and you can upgrade the building twice And basically all you do is you have two kinds of resources.
Speaker 0: Well three resources actually.
Speaker 0: First for resource three resources fanatical devotion.
Speaker 0: There's the triangle right which I think is like command or something I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's triangle lightning bolt, which is energy and People.
Speaker 0: you always have a hundred P or 99 people or whatever it is.
Speaker 0: You can't get more than that You can't get less than that.
Speaker 0: That's what you have.
Speaker 0: You and the to get triangles and electricities.
Speaker 0: you have to capture these spots on the map, right?
Speaker 0: So you start off with one hero guy and one troop, you know Which is like four guys together like a little squad and you send them out to go capture things, right?
Speaker 0: So you capture a little power plant and now it starts generating more lightning bolts.
Speaker 0: You capture a triangle command point it starts generating more triangles for you And you can use the triangles and lightning bolts to build more guys.
Speaker 0: and every time you build more guys Those guys eat up some of your people so you can never have more guys on the board that equal 99 people.
Speaker 0: It's like a squad of scouts might only cost you five people.
Speaker 0: so you can have a huge army of scouts.
Speaker 0: But maybe like, you know a giant robot cost 15 people so you can't have too many of those, right?
Speaker 0: And it doesn't.
Speaker 0: you can't really have anything.
Speaker 0: commit suicide But you can send it out to die and get killed by the other teams if you need, you know to get some people back And you can also spend your points to upgrade guys.
Speaker 0: So like let's say I build a normal troop a squad of tactical soldiers.
Speaker 0: I could upgrade them with like plasma guns or something for like, you know some number of lightning bolts and triangles and whatever Uh-huh, and then basically all you do is you order your guys to go around the map and you can give them orders.
Speaker 0: You know like attack run away.
Speaker 0: You know defend these sorts of things right and you want to get of course more triangle and lightning bolt spaces.
Speaker 0: Not let the other guys take away your triangles.
Speaker 0: lightning bolts minimize how many they have.
Speaker 0: But most of all there are three spots on the board at least depending on the board I guess map that are the victory point things.
Speaker 0: so when you get those you're gonna start getting victory points, right and on.
Speaker 0: everyone starts I think with like 500 victory points, I don't remember the number.
Speaker 0: and If someone else the other guy has more victory point things than you then you start losing Points, uh-huh.
Speaker 0: And basically it's a. it's a thing that pushes left and right back and forth Right and whoever goes down to zero first is the loser.
Speaker 0: so you basically have to control more of the victory point spots than the other guy for a longer time in order to win.
Speaker 0: and You know at a certain point when the other guys down to zero you win.
Speaker 0: or if you're down to zero and he's still at One then he wins.
Speaker 1: So the operative question is is it good or in the?
Speaker 1: you know as the internet wants on a one to ten?
Speaker 1: Does it get an 8.5?
Speaker 0: Well, as I said, you know it, you know, it's a little bit better than other RTS as I've played in the past.
Speaker 0: You know, you know like the click fests and such.
Speaker 0: but it's not perfect.
Speaker 0: You know, a lot of it is just you know Sort of a rock-paper-scissors.
Speaker 0: a lot of it is, you know a quick clicking like, you know quickly get over to where.
Speaker 0: you know You have to manage units all over the board.
Speaker 0: So it's like, you know those guys up top you tell them to fight and take cover.
Speaker 0: you go down low and you know You tell some guys to run away regroup and come back in.
Speaker 0: meanwhile something happened up top.
Speaker 0: You didn't get up there fast enough to do anything about it.
Speaker 0: or you know You spend some resources to upgrade some guys with a particular weapon and you tell them to go in.
Speaker 0: So the only guy switches he has some one guy run away and bring some other troops in and there's a little rock-paper-scissors Going on.
Speaker 1: see I guess I really the RTS I want is one that's imperfect information kind of like, you know, giving orders to units with good AI and real slow.
Speaker 1: So it's real time but you kind of react in a more realistic real time.
Speaker 0: What the one good thing I can say about it is that?
Speaker 0: When you give orders of where they got to tell the guys to go somewhere or do something They're significantly smarter about it than I they have been in the past and in other RTS I played and in fact quite often you're.
Speaker 0: what you're gonna do is you're gonna tell your units to either most of the orders I gave for either run away when there's a big exclamation point when you push that your guys run away and Immediately and they also get like a huge defensive boost when they have the exclamation point.
Speaker 0: So running away with the exclamation point is like the best way to go.
Speaker 1: No more days of my own troops being run over by my harvester exactly.
Speaker 0: and to when you tell guys to go somewhere You're usually either telling them to capture a point which they just do right or you're telling them to stand somewhere and take Cover.
Speaker 0: and when you tell someone to take cover these like dots actually show up like let's say there's a wall, right?
Speaker 0: Move my mouse over near the wall and you'll see like let's say I'm telling four guys a squad of four You'll see like four green dots appear around the wall And if I click that's where my four guys are gonna be and that's where they're gonna take cover.
Speaker 0: So they can actually take cover and all these like cool positions on the map wherever this stuff and you can.
Speaker 0: actually what was really Cool is I had a giant robot and I just told him to walk across the map to this point I wanted and he crushed all these walls and things as he was walking does destroying places for people to take cover.
Speaker 0: So there was.
Speaker 0: there was definitely an element of taking cover destroying things that you can take cover around Coming in at angles which are not, you know easy for the other, you know The enemy to have defended well that that sort of thing Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: So maybe you should install it while it's still free and we can play some you know Against each other where we're not awesome and gonna kill each other easily.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: I have a lot of so you know have a lot of command and conquer under my belt on a 486.
Speaker 0: Also, you know Warhammer people like it.
Speaker 0: It is very Warhammer 40k.
Speaker 0: very It's like Space Marines all the way.
Speaker 1: but anyway things of the day I Subscribed to Nintendo power I had.
Speaker 1: I got every issue up until the n64 era and then I gave up on it.
Speaker 0: I did not subscribe to Nintendo power.
Speaker 1: In fact, I subscribed from day one.
Speaker 1: You're looking at someone who got dragon warrior.
Speaker 0: I subscribed to game pro and recently I got rid of them all.
Speaker 0: they were taken up space.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my Nintendo powers.
Speaker 1: I either my brother has them or my mother has them.
Speaker 0: But my brother has some Nintendo powers from the n64 era.
Speaker 1: But of all the Nintendo powers what I treasure more than anything is I actually have two copies of it the Final Fantasy 1 Complete strategy guy.
Speaker 0: I had the Mario 3 strategy guy.
Speaker 1: that one too.
Speaker 0: That one was like the best.
Speaker 0: I wish I still had it.
Speaker 1: I have it too.
Speaker 1: All that historical is on.
Speaker 0: first It was on cardboard and you like it's.
Speaker 0: you saw where the hammer suit was and I was like, holy shit Hammersuit is real.
Speaker 1: Holy shit but it had all that good art in it and it had all the maps of every level.
Speaker 1: it had all those historical things like Which Mario was fastest.
Speaker 1: who jumped the furthest.
Speaker 0: check out this Mario - I mean like game facts sort of defeat strategy guys nowadays.
Speaker 0: But Pete when people make game facts, it's all text.
Speaker 0: No, you never have that, you know that here are the maps of every level going on on game facts.
Speaker 0: I really think someone people who make game facts should start You know up in their Annie make PDFs with the graphics.
Speaker 1: Come on, you know, but game facts They go for that very specific aesthetic of crap punk kid written.
Speaker 1: I mean Every game back has like the beginning part where they draw like an ASCII picture of the controller and they're like Press this to open the menu and this is the B button.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then whenever they describe like the one thing that you're trying to figure out and you can't really tell what they're talking about Okay, I Was looking up where to find.
Speaker 0: like one of the villagers I could never like jump up to the platform and then go right and then go down.
Speaker 0: It's like well, there's like three platforms.
Speaker 0: I can go right and down from all of them.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 1: because all the game facts now most of them are written in this walkthrough format.
Speaker 1: It's like who is so sad that you want a walkthrough of a whole game?
Speaker 1: Game facts should be for the time where you don't know where the last bath madad is and you don't want to spend an hour Hitting every wall with holy water.
Speaker 1: Yep That is the only thing it should.
Speaker 0: it's like when you do a strategy guide right for anything What you want to do is you want to compartmentalize?
Speaker 0: Everything.
Speaker 0: that way if anyone skims to any part of the fact they can just read that part Individually and know what to do.
Speaker 0: So like if you're talking about the beginning, you know The secret in the middle of level 8 the language when you talk about how to get that secret should assume that somebody Started reading at that sentence and didn't read this, you know, the sentences before and the sentences before that, you know.
Speaker 0: It's like you can't use words like go to the next platform because they don't know what the previous platform was.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the the cool thing like I remember one thing in that strategy guide They actually had a list of all the different death and it like animations and death sprites of Mario through the years.
Speaker 1: You don't need stuff like that Nintendo power in the early days at least.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it turned into later because obviously N64 is when I gave up on consoles and went PC all the way until the end of the GameCube era.
Speaker 1: But pretty much These Nintendo power had a lot of like art and video game stuff in it.
Speaker 1: That wasn't just strategy guides and I really enjoyed reading Nintendo power when I was a punk.
Speaker 0: I enjoyed reading game pro when I was a punk kid before it sucked.
Speaker 1: see game pro.
Speaker 1: I was never a big fan of.
Speaker 0: I think people people like to disrespect game pro But they don't remember the earliest days when you know, it was scary Larry and such.
Speaker 1: I never liked scary Larry.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: I found out about scary Larry.
Speaker 0: You know what he does now scares people.
Speaker 0: He's the boss of Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Huh kind of makes sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah in a twisted way.
Speaker 0: He runs.
Speaker 0: He runs us scary.
Speaker 1: Larry.
Speaker 1: Scott had nothing on coconut monkey.
Speaker 0: coconut monkey Arms no legs.
Speaker 1: I also had PC gamer and the fact that he cheated at his own games.
Speaker 1: I know right and that was the only way to win.
Speaker 0: I have a PC gamer CD somewhere.
Speaker 0: I wonder if it'll work and we can get coconut monkeys on there.
Speaker 1: I have PC gamer floppy disks.
Speaker 1: Whoa I was.
Speaker 1: I was into that stuff.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I Have two YouTube videos for you.
Speaker 1: The first is an ad for Nintendo power.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you if Anything could be iconic of the year 1986 it is this ad.
Speaker 1: Every ad on TV for kids looked exactly like this Nintendo power.
Speaker 0: the TV shows on TV looked exactly Like that commercial.
Speaker 0: Oh my the things they told you will be right back after this commercial looked exactly like that commercial.
Speaker 1: It's it's it's frightening to watch it again.
Speaker 1: And then as a bonus prize in case you've already seen this which I hope you would have seen it in 1986 like I did Someone made a YouTube video of like every cover of every Nintendo power in order and That brought back a lot of nostalgia.
Speaker 1: Like I remember every single one of those issues.
Speaker 1: I could probably tell you what else was in them.
Speaker 0: I think it just really helps you sort of get a better grip on the chronology, you know, cuz it sort of blurs together.
Speaker 0: It's like well what came first?
Speaker 1: Zelda 1 Megaman 2 Metroid Nintendo power had original awesome cover art for the longest time.
Speaker 1: Yeah It doesn't seem to have it so much anymore.
Speaker 1: But back then like they were famous for the fact that kids had nightmares about the live-action like photographic scene They made of Simon having murdered Dracula for the second time.
Speaker 0: that is I mean You know video game magazines were a lot like video game instruction books, right?
Speaker 0: They used to have be like works of art into and of themselves and have lots and lots of original Illustrations.
Speaker 1: and a lot of people ask me why I throw away the instruction books to games I buy.
Speaker 1: now I have a bin of like old NES instruction books like Legend of Zelda and go go 13 and these Instruction manuals had awesome original art.
Speaker 1: They were like 30 pages long full color with backstories.
Speaker 0: Oh, the one came with a math.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I see I have my sieve to manual.
Speaker 1: It's a book the the instruction book that came with a certain unnamed DS game.
Speaker 1: I bought recently.
Speaker 1: It wasn't tactics advance It was another DS game was like a four-page Black-and-white turn the game on book in four languages.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like it was pathetic Nintendo power.
Speaker 1: I salute you even though you were basically just a marketing machine for Nintendo much like the wizard Alright.
Speaker 0: so also speaking of Mario Some people on reddit made a made a series of images called Mario explains it.
Speaker 0: relationships, right Mario explains it all.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So basically they they use the Mario level as a metaphor for things that are true or stereotypically True.
Speaker 0: So the first image in the series is a picture of Mario and he's on the ground Right as a big pit and then there's some more ground But that ground is way up high so high Mario can't possibly jump up there.
Speaker 0: and there's two labels and the label to the low ground is friendship and the label on the high ground is Relationship.
Speaker 1: you pretty much just have to look at these.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm only describing the first one.
Speaker 0: But do you see how?
Speaker 0: so, you know the the picture the design of this fake Mario level?
Speaker 0: You know is a metaphor that symbolizes, you know something that is stereotypically true.
Speaker 0: if you are friends, you'll never be in a relationship because Mario can't jump that high.
Speaker 0: and basically a bunch of other people came along and took this image and expanded it and expanded it and expanded it.
Speaker 0: and Usually when you know, you've heard of people saying you took the metaphor too far, you know Like it sort of starts to not work anymore.
Speaker 0: It never doesn't work anymore.
Speaker 0: It just continues to work more And it's pretty hilarious.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's kind of stereotypical humor much like the old ladder theory website was but It's cleverly done and funny.
Speaker 1: It reminds me of what Photoshop Fridays used to be like In a big way like it harkens back to the days of just people Taking a meme or an idea and extending it well beyond what was tasteful for much hilarity Mm-hmm,
Speaker 0: but
Speaker 1: we were talking about something very brief tonight since it's not actually a Tuesday gig nights And we screwed up and I kind of want to go to bed.
Speaker 1: Mmm We're gonna actually review gravity bone, which we talked about very briefly the other last Tuesday.
Speaker 0: Yep so gravity bone was his indie PC FPS game that I heard about and it was getting some talk on the Internet's and then I Played it and then just now rim played it and it's a real short game But I think it's a real good game
Speaker 1: like literally.
Speaker 1: I came home from work.
Speaker 1: I was I started I turned the game on and I heard Scott pulling up in the driveway.
Speaker 1: I beat the game Like five minutes later.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It was pretty entertaining.
Speaker 1: I thoroughly enjoyed it.
Speaker 1: It was a lot better than our multi-winning.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think one thing that to say about gravity bone right is that unlike some other indie games?
Speaker 0: It gets all the basics right, you know, the graphics are smooth the game works.
Speaker 0: You can set any resolution.
Speaker 0: You know that you can customize your controls.
Speaker 0: The controls are smooth.
Speaker 1: Well, dude, it's based on quake 2.
Speaker 1: It uses the straight-up quake 2 engine.
Speaker 1: So literally you turn it on and I can just go into a menu and change all my controls.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: this is this is what bothers me about a lot of new games Especially a lot of indie games that try to be cool or try to be clever.
Speaker 1: they might do something awesome and innovative or like multi-winning you but Every PC game I have ever bought in my entire life that I've ever played in my entire life The first thing I do after it is installed when I turn it on when I'm first playing is hit escape click on options customize my controls.
Speaker 1: The fact that a lot of modern indie games don't have that option It's like a step 10 years back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean not even 20 because 10 years ago every game did that.
Speaker 0: I mean I can understand unlike a console game not letting someone customize the controls But on the PC customize the controls is sort of a necessity because you know, you've got you know a mouse and keyboard.
Speaker 0: You know, some people like the arrows some people use the WASD some people like an inverted mouse, you know.
Speaker 0: And while the you know, even if you just just have the option and keep it in a menu Just you don't have to put it up front, you know, you know 90% of the people won't customize the controls and but it takes what like a couple hours to add that functionality in.
Speaker 0: You know, it's not a difficult thing so just do it.
Speaker 1: but this game of course We're not going to quote-unquote spoil it because there are spoilers and it's a five-minute game.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's got hard.
Speaker 1: It's a game.
Speaker 1: Literally you kind of just sit down and Play it without knowing anything.
Speaker 1: I have no idea what it's about and it's a game that will teach you what to do.
Speaker 1: Let you do it and then gives you a big payoff at the end for it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm It's all style and all class.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and not in the not not class like our gecky got panel.
Speaker 1: We're talking class in the non-ironic sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that has to be said we've been.
Speaker 1: the word class has come to mean something very odd in the front row crew.
Speaker 0: Well, what I think I like about it is it gives you sort of equal parts puzzle solving equal parts, you know Manipulating the world in a fun way.
Speaker 0: equal parts Platforming a little bit of exploration.
Speaker 0: Yeah a little bit of exploring also, it's odd.
Speaker 1: the second mission is odd like odd to a degree that would almost be disturbing but in this Wonderful deliciously odd way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it also has I think you know a chase scene.
Speaker 0: and the thing about the chase scene Right is that I can't remember a video game that had like a good Chase seed it would actually played the chase scene in this game.
Speaker 0: I was like, wow, that was a fucking awesome chase scene.
Speaker 0: How come no other game has a chase scene like this?
Speaker 1: I mean, obviously there's some scripted bits.
Speaker 0: five mini game has a better chase scene than any professionally made game ever.
Speaker 1: Seriously I think that was the best chase scene I've ever played in a game ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean any game even games that are designed around chasing people have not been able to attain the chase scene in this game.
Speaker 0: Yeah What happens when you have a chase scene?
Speaker 0: in a lot of games either a it's one of those incredibly annoying chases We're like, it's impossible to catch up, right?
Speaker 1: It's a Mario Sunshine where you're like, I'll just kind of wait like to sit there invisible waiting for you No matter what you screw off.
Speaker 1: You just go get him.
Speaker 0: Yep, or it's not really a chase.
Speaker 0: It's just a time trial, you know, and it's basically if you can do this, you know It might as well just be a timer that counts down.
Speaker 0: You know two minutes because the guy will all.
Speaker 0: the other guy will always run at the same speed.
Speaker 0: So you will always.
Speaker 0: you know, pretty much the game is just challenging you to beat something.
Speaker 0: This is clearly scripted.
Speaker 1: I messed around.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, definitely is.
Speaker 1: it definitely will not let you like unless you die or something.
Speaker 1: It's not going to just screw you or anything.
Speaker 1: but what makes it amazing is that it's so immersive like the.
Speaker 1: the scene that I would liken it to is in Half-Life 2 when you're when you first get out of the early part of the game and you're in this apartment building and then Shit goes down
Speaker 0: and the guys come down the stairs and whack you and
Speaker 1: like everything just goes like and you're just like trying to Get out and you're like running through this unfamiliar place full of apartments and dead ends and it just.
Speaker 0: well That's a being chased scene.
Speaker 1: Yes but it's still.
Speaker 1: it reminded me of that and that it's very difficult to immerse me in a game to the point that Something cinematic happens without it being so scripted that like I feel like I'm just on a rail.
Speaker 1: Yep, but this and that scene in Half-Life one being chased one chasing are perfectly Balanced between.
Speaker 1: it's really just a cinematic and yet you are playing it.
Speaker 1: yeah, definitely like to a frightening degree because Like you you don't know what to do and the game doesn't tell you what to do.
Speaker 1: But yet you just know and you just chase and it just works.
Speaker 0: Yep I definitely get those two are great cinematic.
Speaker 0: Those are like possibly I think some of the most cinematic scenes in all FBS.
Speaker 1: them Yes, but I gotta say also not to spoil.
Speaker 1: but what happens at the end of this chase scene Was unexpected and delightful.
Speaker 0: it is delightful and sort of a silly way though it is it is.
Speaker 1: but at the same time You know Godfather reference is sort of tossed it But at the same time just playing it.
Speaker 1: No game has done that to me before.
Speaker 1: like games that have tried to do similar things have been so ham-fisted even professional games and No scene in all of Fallout 3 comes close to the immersion of this five-minute block-headed game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the game basically does.
Speaker 0: it does a bunch of disjointed sort of corny silly things You know that are all really stylish, but don't really have much to do with each other.
Speaker 0: But somehow they sort of work and I just like.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the magic is there But it's.
Speaker 0: it's a good magic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you have a computer that can play, you know quake - Everyone in the world should play.
Speaker 0: this is free and it takes like 10 minutes and game designers take notes.
Speaker 1: this game Accomplished more in five minutes.
Speaker 0: open source play then like mirrors edge Supposed to be the innovative game of the year did in the guy who made this I went to his website And he's actually made a whole bunch of other stuff.
Speaker 0: that is you know I played a couple of them and they they were also, you know, pretty good.
Speaker 0: Not as great Not as good as gravity bone, you know, obviously he gets better with time, right?
Speaker 0: But a lot of his old stuff is like some doom mods and quake mods and half-life mod You know made amazingly, you know as a mod making guy and he makes all sorts of stuff like this And I think that guy's going places.
Speaker 0: someone needs to hire him maybe valve maybe someone.
Speaker 0: he's he has the skills.
Speaker 1: Alright we screwed up.
Speaker 1: It's a Tuesday.
Speaker 1: We did another Tuesday.
Speaker 1: It's late.
Speaker 0: I don't know if we're gonna get another show this week.
Speaker 1: short show going to bed.
Speaker 1: We'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe we'll see ya at the New York comic-con.
Speaker 0: No, we will.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and don't forget Mouse guard is out the army the mouse guard RPG.
Speaker 0: if you don't have one buy one.
Speaker 0: If you're going to the New York comic-con, you'll be able to buy one there Of course, hopefully soon, but it should be in your.
Speaker 0: you should be able to get it on Amazon easy You know what?
Speaker 0: You should be able to get it at your local borders or Barnes & Noble or a comic book The mouse guard RPG review.
Speaker 1: It's awesome.
Speaker 0: It's the best Dude.
Speaker 0: was there any question?
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front road crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.