Speaker 1: Hey, it's Monday September 14th, and this is geek nights tonight virtual private networking.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: This is a problem at my work.
Speaker 0: Is that there's three tech guys, and we're all non picky, so we'll eat anywhere.
Speaker 1: That's kind of the greater problem of the FRC.
Speaker 1: Where do you want to eat?
Speaker 1: And then because we're also open we always end up deferring to the choices of like the one picky guy Yeah, and so it's all about.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: so we go and we just start walking around and we're like where do we eat?
Speaker 1: Walking around looking around.
Speaker 0: so I got some sushi up another sushi places like you eat outside.
Speaker 0: They're all inside eating places.
Speaker 1: It's like uh Yeah, you got to eat outside cuz this is like the good weather is gonna end yep so we got it.
Speaker 0: so it's either like get a takeout and sit in a park or sit in a place and Eventually we you know we got to a place like three possible eateries all next to each other and we didn't care which one.
Speaker 0: so someone just feotted and we picked this Thai place.
Speaker 0: and The Thai place wasn't outside, but it was one of those places at the front of the store basically opens up entirely effectively outside And basically they had a lunch.
Speaker 0: the only thing you could order was the $8 lunch special Which is pretty awesome cuz the $8 lunch special got you first you could shoot.
Speaker 0: you got a salad in a little thingy.
Speaker 1: All right little Thai salad.
Speaker 0: little Thai salad is basically one piece of cucumber and some lettuce in.
Speaker 1: you know to me You know I like little salads like that because you know I like the ginger salad.
Speaker 0: you having to get her back.
Speaker 1: I like myself a big salad.
Speaker 1: You know Elaine style I mean a salad big salad for dinner, but if I'm not eating a big salad after the show man I got to start making sounds like gorgonzola stu landed sound.
Speaker 1: oh, man.
Speaker 1: But I got to start eating more of that like the tiny salad with every meal is like the best thing cuz I always want A tiny bit of salad.
Speaker 0: yep, but I don't want to the salad in the way It's good for the gizzards it is so if you have a gizzard right and then They give you a choice of an appetizing bits you can get like two dumpling or two Rubbed off on you.
Speaker 1: appetizing bit like a main bit and an opening bit.
Speaker 0: You know it's like it's.
Speaker 0: basically.
Speaker 0: you know you can get like.
Speaker 0: you can get like two.
Speaker 0: What do they have I got?
Speaker 0: I got a steamed vegetable dumpling?
Speaker 0: I think the other guys got I forget, but you get to the you know little appetizing things.
Speaker 0: And then you get your meal.
Speaker 0: I got a drunken noodle man, and then you even get like a soda if you want soda even though I had water, but the other guy had to pay for Thai iced tea Which is separate from his sodas.
Speaker 0: so it's worth paying for.
Speaker 0: that was eight bucks?
Speaker 1: That's why I love New York.
Speaker 0: That's a fucking lunch for eight bucks.
Speaker 1: I live I work in Midtown So I don't think that's the funniest part.
Speaker 0: the guy.
Speaker 0: He's like.
Speaker 0: Oh drunken noodle very hot.
Speaker 0: is that okay?
Speaker 0: I'm like yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: And you know what.
Speaker 0: I have had drunken noodle like five times as hot as that.
Speaker 0: it was like what.
Speaker 0: it was a joke.
Speaker 1: Well, he's got a warn.
Speaker 1: you you know white guy, but I think the thing is it wasn't Thai hot.
Speaker 0: It was.
Speaker 0: it wasn't even like Chinese restaurant General so hot.
Speaker 1: it is funny the different scales.
Speaker 0: I mean I remember when I mean Where I needed some waters, but it wasn't hot like.
Speaker 0: yeah, I'm in trouble.
Speaker 1: well I remember things the second to last time we ate at the fuck you sukatai and Pete And I were.
Speaker 1: you know we are I think we both.
Speaker 1: I forget what we ordered But they're like yeah You want a regular hot or Thai hot.
Speaker 1: we look at each other and neither one of us wants to back down or be the wuss Who says nah?
Speaker 1: I'd like regular hot please.
Speaker 0: so we're both like yeah, Thai hot Wow the king, and I had the Thai hot.
Speaker 1: You know they're good Thai restaurants around here, and maybe it's just my rosy memory and the fact that was the first Thai restaurant I'd ever eaten at.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I've never found something quite like the garlic pepper beef and chicken man the garlic pepper beef and chicken.
Speaker 1: But I gotta tell you when it comes to Thai hot food.
Speaker 1: There's a phrase that is on FARC all the time.
Speaker 1: This is one of those fart catchphrases that doesn't make it very far off a FARC pure cat.
Speaker 1: Never has it been more applicable than when I ate the Thai hot Thai food.
Speaker 1: Yeah, quote dot dot dot when the oil hits the anus dot dot dot.
Speaker 0: All right, so let's.
Speaker 0: there's probably been a bajillion bajillion tech news since you last did a Monday show.
Speaker 0: We've forgotten all the ones that are more than a few days old with our short memories I was reminded a little bit by delicious, but all that did was remind me.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, there was a bunch of tech news.
Speaker 0: I've mostly been delicious.
Speaker 0: thing like tech things is not things of the day But like like like Python libraries that I plan to use and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Well in the in the spirit of talking first, I want to real quick mention this because it is you know, it's important.
Speaker 1: I think everyone should know.
Speaker 1: Norman Borlaug is dead.
Speaker 1: He's he has finally died after 95 96 years of being a badass.
Speaker 0: I was pleased to see that he got you know proper news attention.
Speaker 0: I thought it would be.
Speaker 0: you know Usually when like a person like that dies they get like a slightly larger obituary in the New York Times and that's it.
Speaker 0: So I was pleased to see that he was actually at like the top of Google News.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the thing I sadly think football.
Speaker 1: the only reason that he is so well known now is because of Penn and Teller and their bullshit episode about It.
Speaker 0: I can't deny that it helped him, but I don't think that's it.
Speaker 1: I think actually what what saddened me was his Nobel Prize winning.
Speaker 0: this helped him a great deal.
Speaker 1: a lot of the internet Newsy stuff about him had a lot of haters Really Haters.
Speaker 1: most people were saying, you know people saying things like yeah great.
Speaker 1: Thanks make the world more overpopulated.
Speaker 1: Or yeah, you asshole now those people are gonna take over the world blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay Norman Borlaug though.
Speaker 1: I'll miss him primarily because he would never shy from Buzz Aldrin in someone.
Speaker 0: That's for real.
Speaker 0: I mean he wrote there's a great thing.
Speaker 0: Let's link to it.
Speaker 0: I have the link where he basically shoots down all the organic farming people.
Speaker 0: He's like look Yeah, you can do your organic forming if you want.
Speaker 0: Sure Okay, if you want to feed the world like that, you know, you're gonna need to basically Destroy all of your wilderness is turning into farms point.
Speaker 1: His beautiful point was that organic farming is great.
Speaker 1: Go for it You know, it's a thing you can strive for but one it is elitist to think that that can somehow feed the world Especially if you have never experienced hunger.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he also.
Speaker 1: he basically points out that you know.
Speaker 1: all other arguments aside about food The only goal he had was to reduce human suffering and because people were hungry He did everything he could to make people not be hungry and there's a lot less people that are hungry.
Speaker 0: It's a lot.
Speaker 0: the water is a much bigger problem.
Speaker 1: He was a veritable Tezuka of making food.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much, you know, just spending his last breath.
Speaker 1: Let me work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll admit I didn't know who he was until Penn teller.
Speaker 1: Penn and teller told me I had known that there was.
Speaker 0: I knew Of his works, but I did not know his name.
Speaker 0: Well, you know I got the one of the works and I knew that a guy who made a Nobel Prize made those works.
Speaker 1: I knew about the works in the context of that one sentence in every middle school textbook blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: Green Revolution Blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: I knew like a whole classes worth of stuff about that.
Speaker 1: So But that aside We're generally gonna pick the news as we remember as opposed to what might have been important because it's something might be important.
Speaker 1: But if I have nothing to say about it, it'll be like that X happened.
Speaker 0: Yep real quick I just want to say I got the snow leopards.
Speaker 0: I'm installing it on the Mac Mini right now.
Speaker 0: It according to everyone I've seen and what I've heard.
Speaker 0: I'm about to you know, find out for reals and after the show, but It definitely is just sort of a service pack.
Speaker 0: However, it adds a few key features that happen to have significance for me because they make me use a Mac at work And I really need that exchange support.
Speaker 0: So there you have it.
Speaker 1: So what's the installer like?
Speaker 0: I mean it's you put the disk in you push next next agree And then I guess I have to wait 40 minutes and I'll know the rest after the show.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess it has to ask you something.
Speaker 1: I mean otherwise.
Speaker 0: you wish to drive to install on even though there was only one drive to install to see.
Speaker 1: You know why it's doing that.
Speaker 1: it's shake and bake syndrome.
Speaker 1: So when you install it, you know, you're a Mac person you install your upgrade.
Speaker 1: you can think to yourself and I helped.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: No, it's in case you have a Mac Pro which has more than one drive in it.
Speaker 0: That's why Anyway Steve Jobs obviously not dead and he brought out some new iPods That iPod nano despite the fact that I don't need it cuz I have an iPhone looking pretty good Like.
Speaker 0: I don't understand why no one can compete with the stupid iPod.
Speaker 0: I mean Zune can't fucking do it like.
Speaker 0: I mean the Zune HD is looking pretty good, too.
Speaker 0: But it's obvious what to do.
Speaker 0: No way better.
Speaker 1: It's obvious what to do.
Speaker 1: It would be cheaper to do with an.
Speaker 1: Apple sells it for it's just.
Speaker 1: no one does it.
Speaker 0: It's I gave you.
Speaker 0: put me in charge of a bunch of electronics dudes, right?
Speaker 0: I couldn't do the industrial design I couldn't do the electronics, but I could say here's the list of features.
Speaker 0: get them fucking in there.
Speaker 0: All of them do it this way.
Speaker 0: And if they did it, it would be an iPod killer, right?
Speaker 0: Here's the list.
Speaker 0: ready?
Speaker 0: Play any codec any codec, right.
Speaker 0: if you can't handle like the full power of the codec then you know Cuz the CPU can't be that good.
Speaker 0: make a power powerful device make a more powerful device or just like, you know Reduce the quality on the codec or have your client like, you know down Transcode or something or just like, you know, skip.
Speaker 0: Yes Play the video all skippily.
Speaker 0: who cares?
Speaker 1: down transcode because that won't take CPU.
Speaker 0: Well now I mean I mean on the clock on the computer, but then I can't just drag and drop.
Speaker 0: Anyway, number two ready.
Speaker 0: That's audio and video codecs by the way.
Speaker 0: number two a nice easy unit is user interface.
Speaker 0: all we need is the left and right button or an up and down button and Then a you know action button.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: You don't need any of the buttons besides that Number three volume right up volume.
Speaker 0: I guess we can use the up and down button for that.
Speaker 1: now What if I want to change tracks?
Speaker 0: You push the button in the middle.
Speaker 1: So I push the button in the middle and then what?
Speaker 0: there's a menu.
Speaker 1: So then I get a look at this menu.
Speaker 0: You use the menu for changing the time.
Speaker 1: No Because here is the the the iPod in that has just enough that I need.
Speaker 1: but the reason I like it is that With the pre you don't have to look at it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got a fucking look at that thing.
Speaker 1: So if I'm on the train half asleep, and I just want to change the song or change the volume I gotta look at this thing and that with the iPod.
Speaker 0: and yeah, you don't have to look.
Speaker 1: I'll admit the pre is great.
Speaker 1: Like I have media on it and it's a good like, you know I need something to listen to.
Speaker 1: I need some audio but media playing device It is not just because it doesn't have the basic features.
Speaker 1: The stupid iPhone has yeah our media.
Speaker 0: even with the iPod It's like come on.
Speaker 0: This is like a bajillion dollars.
Speaker 0: It can't even do it.
Speaker 0: an iPod does anyway Synchronize over the air Wi-Fi, oh my gosh, not that hard.
Speaker 0: people just do it You know.
Speaker 0: just drag and drop files on to it.
Speaker 0: You know if you decide to plug it in instead of going over the air Just freely share files with any other device.
Speaker 0: That's also the same device.
Speaker 0: Let me just drag and drop mp3s and videos my friends no restrictions whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Just free copying No one get.
Speaker 0: you know, it's not any legal device, you know, it doesn't make it illegal.
Speaker 0: And I'm just you know, it's no difference doesn't not doing anything that a computer doesn't do?
Speaker 0: just copy files to my friends.
Speaker 1: wireless You know, I am.
Speaker 1: I'm really surprised that people no one's jumped on the idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's all these.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: What else do they need there?
Speaker 0: Oh support for headphones with a button on them.
Speaker 0: I guess the iPod does do that.
Speaker 1: well we've got all these hardware companies and they generally will always bow to the demands of the software companies and the legislators and everything when.
Speaker 0: What a movable battery.
Speaker 1: I think the problem is no one company has all the components together To make the awesome device and there's always one person in the chain who doesn't want to do the awesome thing.
Speaker 0: Am/fm radio.
Speaker 0: they added FM radio to the iPod was shocking, but they didn't add am radio.
Speaker 1: I don't need it.
Speaker 0: that had the X. I listen to am radio more than the FM radio.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz FM radio only has music but the am radio has like the news weather traffic sports Which is the only time ever gonna turn on.
Speaker 1: is my busted up car, right?
Speaker 1: You know, I finally because my iPod integration on my car was actually pretty good But the power cable got caught in the door a while ago and broke and I didn't notice.
Speaker 1: cuz I don't use my car mm-hmm and There's like.
Speaker 1: I put the antenna back in just like.
Speaker 1: oh I need something to listen to in the car.
Speaker 1: It's free.
Speaker 1: It's not anywhere close to paying me enough to listen to that garbage.
Speaker 0: Good god, I only turn on the radio if it's an emergency like oh crap.
Speaker 0: This is sports or something or oh crap What's the?
Speaker 0: you know the weather is or something?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I hardly ever turn it on and oh crap What's the weather?
Speaker 1: I'm outside.
Speaker 1: I have a pre.
Speaker 1: I can go to NOAA and look at the weather.
Speaker 0: I'm driving.
Speaker 0: I can't exactly look at it while I'm driving.
Speaker 1: I never care.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm driving.
Speaker 0: I might care if I see a big storm ahead.
Speaker 0: I want to know why though.
Speaker 1: What are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: You're all right, you're on.
Speaker 0: take a different course.
Speaker 1: You're on i-75 going south take a different course and you see a storm coming.
Speaker 0: Take a different course.
Speaker 1: if you listen to the radio, you're just gonna say storms coming.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can go a different way Oh shit.
Speaker 1: It's storm anyway.
Speaker 0: So yeah, that's that's pretty much.
Speaker 0: it Makes me you know think like hey part of the reason I you know It's like in six months my iPhone contracts over right and I'm gonna definitely get something else probably Android just cuz I'm all googly.
Speaker 0: But maybe the pre or maybe something else.
Speaker 1: I've decided but I need you know.
Speaker 0: I mean, I need an immediate playing device and I need a phone right and the iPhone is both which is huge It's like one and it's two and one which is like regardless of any other factor.
Speaker 1: Well, you can argue that it's a phone but it's on the AT&T network.
Speaker 1: so it's like 80% of.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: that's the other problem.
Speaker 0: It's like okay.
Speaker 0: I can have two devices, but it's kind of crappy.
Speaker 0: No Here's the or if you want to get a Verizon Slash Sprint phone and then the separate iPod to make up for the fact.
Speaker 1: that's what I was about to say.
Speaker 1: If you only if you if you will not compromise on having one device Then they're all pretty much equal the iPhone the pre and and like they all have an equal features that it just you pick what?
Speaker 1: Features you want if you're willing to go to the two device setup.
Speaker 0: iPhone is not a loser because the only advantage the iPhone has is that it's a one device because anything plus an iPod is better than the iPhone.
Speaker 0: if you're willing to have two devices Yep, so if I'd like to have one device, but I don't think that's gonna be possible just because AT&T is such poop It is and even then Verizon, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Sprint more and more is busting out.
Speaker 0: Sprint is busting.
Speaker 0: Actually, there was like this guy the CEO of Sprint had a really wide open interview on the the PBS and basically He was like, yeah, we have these unlimited plans, but really we're charging you more.
Speaker 0: He's like, yeah the limited plan Everyone thinks it's less.
Speaker 0: It's more.
Speaker 0: He's like everyone loves it.
Speaker 0: He was just so open about everything.
Speaker 0: It was pretty, you know, he's like, yeah the iPods a killer.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: I mean iPhones a killer.
Speaker 1: Well, I love the fact that they have.
Speaker 0: It's like trying to compete with Michael Jordan.
Speaker 1: They have their unlimited and they're super unlimited.
Speaker 1: But if you look at the plans the only difference between those two basically is the super unlimited cost more money in the past I think.
Speaker 1: drop the price recently and it gives you unlimited everything.
Speaker 1: the other one gives you unlimited everything but talking but they Talking.
Speaker 0: then you'll ever need they give me like I have the lowest amount of talking possible.
Speaker 0: I have like a bajillion rollover minute me too.
Speaker 1: I have like four hundred and fifty talking minutes.
Speaker 1: You know how many I used in the last month?
Speaker 1: Eleven.
Speaker 0: see now if they were true rollover minutes They would give me what they're worth in dollars back when I leave in six months.
Speaker 1: You know, I got a lot of friends who have rollover whatever and they had there everyone's like, yeah I got the maximum rollover I could talk constantly for the next month.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's bullshit.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I wish they would give me a plan.
Speaker 0: That was five bucks.
Speaker 1: Well now what we're seeing?
Speaker 1: there's a dive hours and that's it Not even five hours and there's a divergence where people need a phone number because in modern Industrial society you need a phone number.
Speaker 1: if you don't have a phone Or the ability to make a phone call of some capacity to a lot of like archaic organizations like pizza places And you don't live somewhere cool like Rochester where you can just go to a website in order pizza Then you need this phone number.
Speaker 1: But you're not gonna use it if you're one of these divergent tech people for anything but interfacing with archaic people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know calling your mom.
Speaker 0: That's a Google Voice Google Voice.
Speaker 0: Yeah All my colleagues say I found out if I can get Google.
Speaker 0: if anyone out there has a way to get us some Google Voice Invite whatever I want it not because I want to use it for myself But because I found out that it would actually be a really good way to get some voicemail type action in the podcast.
Speaker 0: that doesn't Suck which is part of the reason why we've never done that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean Odeo basically stopped working at one point and no one ever fixed it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically would give us a phone number the phone note you would call.
Speaker 0: you would leave your message.
Speaker 0: We would get a transcription of the message Whoever automatic and crappy it was.
Speaker 0: it would still help us know if your voicemail was good or not And then we could push play like in gmail to play the audio the message and then the output from the computer with the gmail Open would go into the mixer and that would be how it would do it.
Speaker 0: So we just need Google Voice for that.
Speaker 1: So there's this article on slashdot and again in the true slashdot sense.
Speaker 1: I don't care about the article, but I care about the topic the article raises.
Speaker 1: you can read the article if you want.
Speaker 1: I didn't even look at it.
Speaker 1: how to make science popular again Mm-hmm, and this is something we've talked about a lot, but I started really thinking about it after seeing this article.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, we always talk about back in the day.
Speaker 1: yet the world's fair optimism the scientist.
Speaker 0: That's my kind of place I want to be.
Speaker 1: the scientist was the good guy saving you from the Godzilla.
Speaker 1: that was also caused by science.
Speaker 1: But science was either a force of good or a double-edged sword and more and more in the media It's the you know evil scientist who uncovers the evil truth or does the evil thing and and even the doctors who are supposed to Heal you.
Speaker 0: it's like they're evil.
Speaker 0: and and this bullshit Randy healing is good You know.
Speaker 0: sadly, you know There are a lot of men and all the news about medical studies are always scared to scare you not to be about healing.
Speaker 1: Well, there's all their arguments and things you could do to make science more palatable.
Speaker 1: and we have to make science more palatable more Popular more people to be interested in and care about science But far and above in a way.
Speaker 1: the number one thing I think is very simply that in the past It wasn't necessarily pro science It was just pro futurism and it was this kind of you know 50s style.
Speaker 1: Look the future.
Speaker 1: everything is great in the future, but More knowledge means that we know that everything is not great in the future and that while things get better Science, usually it uncovers uncomfortable truths more quickly than it solves them.
Speaker 0: Yep Well, I mean here's the other thing.
Speaker 0: is that right Nate, you know The laws of nature and the the arrangement of the universe doesn't care it can't care.
Speaker 0: It's just the way things are.
Speaker 0: and the way things are, you know Don't necessarily mesh with the way we happen to have built our society because he built our society based on a limited knowledge.
Speaker 0: We didn't build our society on this more advanced knowledge.
Speaker 0: So uncovering any more knowledge is in in the long run is guaranteed To disrupt our society and force it to change and break in many ways.
Speaker 0: For example, we've discovered how to copy things infinitely.
Speaker 0: not so good for the way we've set up our information economy.
Speaker 0: We've discovered how like, you know We're starting to discover more and more how brains work and other such things.
Speaker 0: not so good for the way We've treated privacy in the past.
Speaker 0: It's just gonna fall apart.
Speaker 0: So, you know, it's it's in the past in the 50s, you know the the information we were discovering then, you know It's not just it was making.
Speaker 0: at least it was making the lives of people in the United States Seemingly better because they were seeing things in their everyday lives like refrigerators and stoves and all sorts of news Little and that I think cars the wings on.
Speaker 1: I think it was much more subtle than that.
Speaker 1: if you look at you know the futurism of the 50s and it was basically taking existing comfortable structures and Extruding them out into the future and basically just enhancing them in the context of their existing Uses and their existing functions in the existing society.
Speaker 1: Yep and less and less.
Speaker 1: Does that work at all and more and more.
Speaker 1: is that obviously not the way things will?
Speaker 0: yes now It's like in the future everything, you know and love will be gone.
Speaker 0: It'll be something different force chain.
Speaker 1: I mean if we were doing futurism now like right now what we'd be looking at the iPhone of the future?
Speaker 1: It plays 3d video.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as opposed to phones are integrated with the brain and like there's all craziness The more you know the less fantasy can come in and people like fantasy a lot better than reality.
Speaker 1: But there's also a subtle shift in that the marketing in the past was geared toward getting people to buy into Futurism and buy into science and then buy products and it was this kind of positive reinforcement.
Speaker 1: Look everything makes everything better.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yes power thirst power thirst.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: now at least when it comes to technology and medicine especially medicine It seems like the marketing is everything makes your life worse.
Speaker 1: We will scare you into buying products to protect yourself from the terrible secret of space as Amanda is saw it.
Speaker 0: Now you see it.
Speaker 1: That's all we could do.
Speaker 1: a whole show mighty.
Speaker 1: I wanted to just I wanted to touch on this.
Speaker 0: Okay, this is real quick.
Speaker 0: I want to say that Twitter announced among other things that Apparently despite the fact that you give Twitter the company Rights to do certain things with your tweets like republish them and display them etc, etc.
Speaker 0: You own your tweets.
Speaker 0: They belong to you.
Speaker 0: You have the copyright on them.
Speaker 0: You know, I know it's grant Twitter this license to them.
Speaker 1: So well, we have two opposite takes on the awesome way to handle this.
Speaker 0: I suggest that you should Creative Commons license your tweets So that you know people can retweet them without fear.
Speaker 1: now That's the problem.
Speaker 1: the way Twitter is that I feel we should do the opposite because my philosophy when it comes
Speaker 0: Also a plan I approve of by the way, I approve
Speaker 1: of both plans as do I because when I saw Scott do it I was like, oh, that's the obvious good thing to do.
Speaker 1: That's cool.
Speaker 1: I should do that.
Speaker 1: then I thought wait a minute because my whole life whenever I see a problem The first instinct I have is to push on that Problem to the maximum level of escalation in order to force the issue and the decision to come to a head Mm-hmm like say my foot really hurts and I'm not sure if it's broken or not.
Speaker 0: jump up and down on it.
Speaker 1: The first thing I'll do it unless there's like a bone sticking out is try to walk normally Because either I can or I can and having that knowledge and pushing it to the breaking point Possibly literally will allow me to more quickly come to a resolution and go to the doctor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I'm like, I don't know and I kind of like gingerly like Then I'm going to delay possibly important and timely foot saving technology.
Speaker 1: It's the same thing if I go to a website and it's at all slow I usually hit refresh a few times to see if I can bring it down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I always everything like that politics.
Speaker 0: I hate refresh a few times not to see if I can bring it down to see if I could get it.
Speaker 0: So explain your tweet.
Speaker 1: So my tweet option is this if Twin if I own my tweets then if I don't give them an open license Doesn't that necessitate that people shouldn't be able to just retweet.
Speaker 1: I mean all they're doing is attributing me, but they're also completely Retransmitting my transmission.
Speaker 0: and yeah, I mean if you had a Creative Commons attribution license, that'd be totally cool But without that that's technically illegal.
Speaker 1: It's not fair use to just take my work and completely 100% give it away for free.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: else regardless of whether or not I gave it away for free That's exactly right.
Speaker 1: And it basically proof shows that copyright law really breaks down.
Speaker 1: It's retarded.
Speaker 1: Well, it breaks down in the minutiae 144 characters.
Speaker 1: I could write every possible hundred and forty four character combination with a bash 26 to the hundred and forty fourth power.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, that's a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a lot but it's not that many.
Speaker 0: We should make a Twitter account that does it one by one one a day.
Speaker 0: just have a tweet.
Speaker 0: You know what you.
Speaker 0: the the API limit is what a hundred and something an hour.
Speaker 0: Right something like that.
Speaker 0: So every hour it'll go through 155.
Speaker 0: How long will it take?
Speaker 0: Probably a billion years And Dinosaurs will be coming around and Twitter will be gone, but it'll still be got what dinosaurs?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess Dave Riley was right.
Speaker 0: That's how long it'll be in the future.
Speaker 0: the dinosaurs will come back and go away again.
Speaker 1: but one of the funniest things ever in Futurama was when they show that like time-lapse about the window while fries in the thing and It's like civilization grows comes to a peak aliens destroy it all castles civilization comes back.
Speaker 1: Yep But I don't know.
Speaker 1: I feel like everyone should do the opposite.
Speaker 1: we should all have a super restrictive, you know every maximum right that copyright lets you assert and You know threaten everybody who retreats or just point out to everyone who retweet and think about this.
Speaker 1: you were breaking the law by repeating Me.
Speaker 0: and if you want to me if you make the argument right that you know 144 characters isn't copyright a bull right.
Speaker 1: if you want to make that argument Well Emily had the sheet before any of us could say it.
Speaker 1: the other night at dinner Emily pointed out the obvious answer Haiku, yep, so haiku is an art does not not know copyright on haiku.
Speaker 0: And also at the same time right.
Speaker 0: if you want to say it isn't besides haiku Then why do I need to give Twitter this license to use it?
Speaker 0: And how can I own them?
Speaker 0: It's basically any tweet is automatically public domain by that measure.
Speaker 0: So yeah, is that the case?
Speaker 1: so I am NOT creative commenting my tweets.
Speaker 1: And in fact, if you're retweeting me You're gonna sue them.
Speaker 1: You're probably gonna get away with it because I don't have the legal resource.
Speaker 0: You should send them a cease and desist, huh?
Speaker 1: Maybe I should.
Speaker 1: I'll start tweeting cease and desist.
Speaker 1: Now just here's another aspect of law if I direct message tweet you does that constitute me?
Speaker 1: Notifying you of something.
Speaker 0: I don't know I don't think so, but you should do it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, just just to make people aware but so tight take either Scott's tack of using the Creative Commons tools to you know Force our open ideals onto the broken structure or use the broken structure to prove how broken it is.
Speaker 1: Either one is great.
Speaker 0: Yep Let's see.
Speaker 0: What else we got?
Speaker 1: one more little thing.
Speaker 1: I want to bring up.
Speaker 1: There's this.
Speaker 1: it's this is from August but and maybe we could do a whole show on this later.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll see but there is an article fear of porn.
Speaker 1: URL exposure discourages firefox 3 upgrade.
Speaker 0: It's true.
Speaker 1: It is very true because firefox 3, you know makes your bookmarks usable.
Speaker 1: Bookmarks were all.
Speaker 1: you know The way people manage bookmarks usually old and shitty with a million folders and we could talk forever about how to manage your bookmarks.
Speaker 1: We may already have.
Speaker 1: But people who look at porn or do things like that They're like, you know, they're like animals.
Speaker 1: They don't really know how to hide what they're doing.
Speaker 1: You know the cat kind of knows like they cover their poop.
Speaker 1: Yeah Doing you know, you can train a cat to flush its poop down the toilet whether than just covering it in sand and You can train a person to use something like delicious.
Speaker 1: whether than covering their poop in sand.
Speaker 1: But the majority of humans don't know and they cover their porn.
Speaker 1: They'll have like the folder of like I don't know something weird like like poker whatever.
Speaker 1: and in that folder of the subfolder of like You know grandma's whatever.
Speaker 1: and deep down under all this saying grandma's what kind of porn is that?
Speaker 1: Well It hiding in plain sight.
Speaker 1: if you like grandma porn What's the best place to hide your grandma porn?
Speaker 1: under the grandma bookmarks?
Speaker 1: because no one's gonna look at grandma bookmarks, right?
Speaker 1: But people hide their poop understand because they don't understand how to actually hide their poop.
Speaker 1: or the big question Should you even be hiding your poop at all?
Speaker 1: If you have to hide your poop You've got a problem.
Speaker 1: or your cat.
Speaker 1: if you're a cat train the cat.
Speaker 1: how to use the toilet.
Speaker 1: if you're a person either Don't be ashamed or if you're ashamed there are tools to hide your poop.
Speaker 1: There are easy ways to hide your poop So the people you don't want to see your poop will not find your poop.
Speaker 0: The new firefoxes have private browsing modes.
Speaker 0: So there you go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but just turn on private browsing look at porn turn off private brows.
Speaker 1: this race is another long-term uncomfortable issue.
Speaker 1: where?
Speaker 1: Technology makes information more accessible.
Speaker 1: the better technology gets the more you were either as a person Are they're going to have to be comfortable with the fact that you poop or You're going to have to be up with technology such that you know how to hide your poop and more and more Smaller numbers of people will use increasingly complex methods of poop hiding and the rest of you grandma's gonna find your poop.
Speaker 1: So things of the day, what do you got?
Speaker 1: So I was talking in a weird voice.
Speaker 0: I was gonna use some kind of like talking in this.
Speaker 0: we watch the college humor video and I decided that was very funny.
Speaker 0: So I'll use it.
Speaker 1: It's it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: now if you think this is tasteless You're wrong.
Speaker 1: This is this is.
Speaker 0: this is definitely this is no more tasteless than an old thing of the day Involving stuffed plushies of the Twin Towers.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: This is a that one.
Speaker 0: Yeah one.
Speaker 0: This is a Star Wars analogy.
Speaker 0: They're comparing the Death Star to the Twin Towers and it is very funny.
Speaker 1: now It could have been done stupidly or tastelessly or whatever, but not only is this funny.
Speaker 0: It has a funny punchline at the end It is.
Speaker 1: it is so cleverly done and they make like five or six like good out there Jokes, and it looks like they had like high quality 501st armors - yeah, they were the real deal But they it just.
Speaker 1: it does such a good job of bringing up all the I'm when they bring up the loose change.
Speaker 1: BS.
Speaker 0: Yes, Palpatine knew He did on purpose.
Speaker 0: There's no way two x-wings could have blown up to this.
Speaker 0: All right, we're not gonna give away all the jokes.
Speaker 1: I just you think Darth Vader was just happened to be in a tie fighter when the whole thing went down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, go watch this video.
Speaker 0: It's good.
Speaker 0: It's funny.
Speaker 1: So my thing of the day This is kind of old but a lot of people probably didn't see it.
Speaker 1: So there's this famous painting of a guy and two kids in like a farm next to a ladder.
Speaker 0: It's this old like 16 so you'll recognize the painting when you see it.
Speaker 0: as soon as I saw it I was like, oh, yeah that painting.
Speaker 0: who painted it?
Speaker 0: by the way, ah Crap, all right.
Speaker 1: Let me pull up the actual art of crap.
Speaker 0: I love crap.
Speaker 1: 17th century the 17th century darch work barn interior is one of 16 paintings that Calvin alumnus Cornelius van Nui gay Oh van Nui.
Speaker 1: Okay, no van Nui gave it to a school two years ago.
Speaker 1: he did not.
Speaker 1: Van Nui was not the painter.
Speaker 0: I was gonna say if I knew he's a name I know.
Speaker 0: anyway Egbert von der Poel's ah Under Paul was a name.
Speaker 1: I've never heard before very good shows two women Shows a woman and two children inside a barn.
Speaker 1: blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: He lived from 1621 to 1664 Not that long as long ago.
Speaker 1: Oh Anyway, it's a famous painting and you know it.
Speaker 1: Like all old paintings that had problems and they were gonna restore it.
Speaker 1: while they were restoring it the restorer noticed one That like all paintings it had darkened substantially over the years.
Speaker 1: and you know A lot of people don't realize that we look at paintings and we kind of have this aesthetic of what we expect These famous old paintings to look like in Reality.
Speaker 1: they were a lot brighter and more colorful than we see them today because paint they had shitty fucking paint.
Speaker 0: Not like we do today where you have like you go to you know The craft store and you get fucking the brightest paint in the universe the fact that these Paintings at all exist in any form today that aren't just black smears.
Speaker 0: Think about a tattoo.
Speaker 0: me think about an old tattoo.
Speaker 0: That's what it was like.
Speaker 0: eventually it turns into a blob.
Speaker 1: Well, at least paintings don't have the problem that people get fat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: but even though think about tattoo ink right turned into a blob and that was only like less than a century ago Multiple centuries ago.
Speaker 0: right paint technology is gonna be a blob.
Speaker 1: You want to get into some geeky shit the science and art and alchemy and mysticism of designing paint back in the day.
Speaker 1: That is a whole amazing topic.
Speaker 0: But also why artists are crazy led.
Speaker 1: So one.
Speaker 1: this work is a lot lighter and warmer and redder than you know, people would have expected.
Speaker 1: Yep And there's a lot more detail.
Speaker 1: It was kind of hidden but - he noticed that this ladder in the foreground That was kind of out of place Was really thickly painted like there was a lot of paint there for some reason like it had been painted over.
Speaker 1: So in the course of restoring he discovers that under all that clearly added on later paint is a slaughtered pig.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, a very detailed slaughtered pig and the painting was originally very very very different Because the original painting shows this, you know This person's sitting there in these kids and all the accoutrement of a farm life and a slaughtered pig Cut open ribs exposed hanging to dry and cure from the ladder.
Speaker 1: Clearly what likely happened is some rich person, you know wanted this provincial life, you know Oh life on the farm painting and they saw this pig and they're like, yeah Thanks for the painting.
Speaker 1: and then they hired someone else to paint over and put the ladder back.
Speaker 1: But look at how much the character and the meaning and everything of this painting is changed by this one detail that was Redected and we wouldn't have known without science and technology.
Speaker 1: today we're lucky in the modern world and that we can see, you know, we can see Han Solo shooting first and Han Solo being a pussy.
Speaker 0: We have both options.
Speaker 0: We need to reconstruct those.
Speaker 0: See this is what I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: People are all talking, you know copyright.
Speaker 0: Oh, we got to stop remixers.
Speaker 0: We got to stop sharers.
Speaker 0: No, you know what?
Speaker 0: We really have to stop.
Speaker 0: We really have to stop like vandalisms, right?
Speaker 0: That's something we should stop, right?
Speaker 0: We should stop George Lucas from destroying his masters, you know And we should recreate them and give them the finger if possible and we should stop.
Speaker 0: You know some rich dude from like modifying some sculpture.
Speaker 0: This is this is what you need to do to protect art not copyright.
Speaker 1: So yeah, check out the pig and it's a shockingly cut open pig.
Speaker 0: All right, so I got a new segment.
Speaker 0: All right, is that the noise you're gonna have really?
Speaker 0: You can stop that now.
Speaker 0: You're just ruining it and you're making it annoying and painful.
Speaker 0: Everyone just turned off.
Speaker 0: right now It's a good job.
Speaker 0: Hey, it's not as bad as you know, the early game you would have done it for like a second.
Speaker 0: Nobody, you know wouldn't have been so annoying.
Speaker 1: and I want to point out in early geek nights You know, we came up with the thing.
Speaker 0: That's why we didn't post those shows.
Speaker 1: We came up with a thing of the day bit and we came up with music for the thing of the day that would pay Like looping like in the background as intro.
Speaker 0: We didn't do that.
Speaker 1: It was it sounded really cool if things of the day lasted 30 seconds.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so 10 minutes of this like intense music playing quietly in the background drove people crazy.
Speaker 0: so We got a new segment.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be a really short segment and basically the thing is this I hate putting meta in the show.
Speaker 0: for those you Don't know meta is when you talk about the show on the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's bad.
Speaker 0: I don't want to limit that as much as possible.
Speaker 1: I mean sometimes it's good like hey We're doing a thousand panels at this con.
Speaker 1: But sometimes because you know a new listener and an old listener will care.
Speaker 1: sometimes it's bad like oh, yeah foreign bullshit Blah blah blah, right?
Speaker 0: We're not gonna do any of that That's for sure.
Speaker 1: But in general, you know, if you're a new listener or you're if you're not in the community of geek nights aside from geek nights You don't care about our meta bullshit.
Speaker 1: You just want us to get through it.
Speaker 1: But we have to talk about some things on the show.
Speaker 0: Yes, and the thing is there, you know We've avoid something meta so much that we forget to talk about the tiny bit of meta that we should.
Speaker 0: for example We never like remember to not like repeatedly announce contests and other things that we have that we should put in the show.
Speaker 0: That's appropriate meta.
Speaker 0: So if we have a meta minute segment where we force ourselves to do some meta during the show Then we'll remember to do that stuff.
Speaker 0: So here we go the ad contest.
Speaker 0: geek nights ad contest.
Speaker 0: You make an advertisement that we can use to advertise geek nights on other websites.
Speaker 0: You can win Akira the manga the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Go to the website go to the forum.
Speaker 0: There's a thread all about it.
Speaker 0: I think I'm gonna extend the deadline a little bit just so I can get a few more entries in there.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess we'll extend it by you know a week or so and we're going to announce it in the meta minute segment.
Speaker 0: So we won't forget.
Speaker 0: So if you have Photoshop skills make an advertisement, you know According to the rules on the on the website in the thread for geek nights Basically something that will be posted on other websites.
Speaker 0: that will get people to click on it and come listen to geek nights And you can win a pile of mangas good manga - very expensive and like $180 worth of manga Manga that you will enjoy even if you don't think you like manga.
Speaker 0: you never listen to our Wednesday show Yep, so enter this contest and that's the minute.
Speaker 1: So this whole week and much of last week I've been working from home Working from home.
Speaker 1: It's great.
Speaker 0: It's good times.
Speaker 1: The only reason I get to work from home I never actually got sick Scott and I somehow avoided but everyone else.
Speaker 1: I'm immune with my awesome immune system The word I've been using and I've been saying this a lot to my co-workers I stand by my freakish immunity to the swine flu Yes, but you don't have a freakish immunity to like pollen for some or various other things.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I have allergies.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so pretty much everyone got the swine flu and even like, you know The people who can't went to packs with us Emily and Alex and they came back and they were sick.
Speaker 1: and my co-workers You know, my company has a policy.
Speaker 1: So I basically have been working from home since packs.
Speaker 1: I have not been to Manhattan since we flew back from packs.
Speaker 0: Nice.
Speaker 1: It's been great.
Speaker 1: I gotta tell you working from home is like the best fucking thing ever.
Speaker 1: It's alright.
Speaker 1: I'm probably gonna go into work Independently, I'm working the midnight shift and covering Europe like one more time this week.
Speaker 1: and While the European shift was like the worst thing in the world when I was doing it, you know from the office You know taking the ass late Croton Harmon train into the city sitting in this quiet ass office all alone and empty midtown at night With weird noises in the building and nothing to eat and it sucked.
Speaker 1: I was tired Working from home.
Speaker 1: It's great.
Speaker 1: I wake up at like 1145.
Speaker 1: I'm a work at 1150 I'm done with work at 9 and then I go do stuff.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 1: Oh my god I want to work from home like forever.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the only reason this is possible is because of VPN.
Speaker 0: yes, I promised someone I forget who it was do a show about VPN.
Speaker 0: So here it is.
Speaker 0: VPN is a virtual private network And the reason that is called that is because it lets you.
Speaker 0: it's as if you're on a private network But you're not.
Speaker 0: you're on the internet.
Speaker 0: You're on the public network, but it's as if you're on a private network.
Speaker 0: That's virtually a private network.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna dwell on the simplistic stuff But we're also not gonna get into the super technical detail, but we're gonna talk about a lot, but VPN I mean really all it is as Scott said.
Speaker 1: just think of it this way.
Speaker 1: I've got my computer at work, you know or at my school or any place.
Speaker 1: We'll tell you use work.
Speaker 1: is the exam any private network?
Speaker 1: Oh, so my work has an intranet and maybe it's connected to the internet.
Speaker 1: Maybe it has an internet within it, which is not an uppercase.
Speaker 1: I internet.
Speaker 1: I hope everyone understands those terms still.
Speaker 1: we've gone over that in the past.
Speaker 1: So if I'm not physically there and I have a VPN it is as though I'm physically there.
Speaker 1: My computer has no way to know that it is not physically and directly at my office.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: it can do all the things that it could do at the office.
Speaker 0: Yep, like, you know, let's say you've got ten computers and you wire them up together, right and you know, it's like, okay They can all connect to each other and talk in various ways.
Speaker 0: Maybe one of them has a web server, right?
Speaker 0: And you can.
Speaker 0: you only want people in your house on these ten computers to go to the web server.
Speaker 0: You don't want to let anyone in the world go to it.
Speaker 0: You got secret stuff on there, right?
Speaker 0: See what you do is you configure the web server and you say hey web server Don't give web pages to anyone who isn't in this room on these ten computers.
Speaker 0: But what if someone's not physically in the room?
Speaker 0: They're far away.
Speaker 0: They get a VPN it goes over the internet but it's all encrypted and secure and locked down and Effectively their computer on the other side of the world is in the room Even though it's not and they can visit the web server now depending what you're doing.
Speaker 1: There are other and sometimes better ways to do this sort of thing.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's tons of different VPNs.
Speaker 1: this hardware VP Yeah, I mean if you just have web services that you need to get out One viable tunnels is to have them over the internet with the tunnel or to have them over the internet with just SSL.
Speaker 1: You know, you've got a login and it's encrypted.
Speaker 1: Yep, and The real benefit of VPN aside from everything is that it's a comprehensive solution.
Speaker 1: it basically by default Will do everything.
Speaker 1: you don't have to worry about setting up all this extra stuff.
Speaker 1: It basically just makes your computer as though it's there.
Speaker 1: all the different protocols and ports and everything work.
Speaker 1: So you don't have to change your entire security architecture to support.
Speaker 1: You know multiple methods of ingress and egress for all your services.
Speaker 1: You basically design them as though they'll never leave your company and then you give people VPN access if they need to access all of those services.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's also really really good for legacy services.
Speaker 1: You know old LAN only bullshit that needs like it can't go over routed protocols.
Speaker 0: That's a very good example.
Speaker 0: It was one of the best uses of VPN.
Speaker 0: I've noticed lately for normal people at least is let's say you want to play some video games.
Speaker 0: But you know the video games.
Speaker 0: you got to play them over the internet.
Speaker 0: It sucks.
Speaker 0: They want you to use like an auth server or something.
Speaker 0: It's not working out too.
Speaker 0: Well, you'd rather use the LAN mode.
Speaker 0: It's much easier.
Speaker 0: You can just get your friends together.
Speaker 1: land mode.
Speaker 1: We've talked about how it's stupid pointless.
Speaker 1: Don't need it anymore.
Speaker 1: It's the way of the dodo and people are dropping it left and right anyway, right?
Speaker 0: But for example, I wanted to play System Shock 2 with someone right and we have NAT routers So that makes it very difficult to play over the internet without a server.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean look option one.
Speaker 1: may one of you repost the server you make all the firewall and NAT table Bullshit tap and and while that's easy for people like us.
Speaker 1: It's still not trivial.
Speaker 0: Like I it's a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: I mean I have a little diagram of our home network and anytime we want to do something like that I gotta sit down look at that thing.
Speaker 1: All right, is that port being used by anything else?
Speaker 1: No, okay.
Speaker 1: Is the static IP the same blah blah blah?
Speaker 1: Nope Okay, and I gotta like do all this crap and even for professionals is not easy.
Speaker 1: if you're not a professional you're fucked, right?
Speaker 0: I mean people have such problems opening the ports.
Speaker 0: I mean people.
Speaker 0: some people have sort of figured it out But even then it partly ever works all the time and routers are not Home.
Speaker 0: routers are not that reliable in terms of those features.
Speaker 1: I thought UPnP was gonna solve this forever for everyone.
Speaker 0: It only made things worse.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so what we did is use hamachi or you know, there are other alternatives to hamachi as well which is sort of a easy VPN for normal people.
Speaker 0: and suddenly me and this other person on the other side of the world or you know relatively far away have Created a new private network and we're both on it and it's as if our computers are just wired up to each other Directly in the same house and we can open up a game and turn on LAN mode and it just works.
Speaker 0: And there you have it and VPNs are totally awesome like that.
Speaker 1: Now the main the other you know a side benefit mostly from a corporate or anything secure military perspective is the VPNs Generally offer more comprehensive security.
Speaker 1: I mean let's say you just have SSL or a tunnel or something.
Speaker 1: if the host computer gets compromised or If the host computer is multi-homed or there are all sorts of attack vectors that you have to be very Proficient your network engineers have to really know what they're doing or you'll introduce all these extra attack vectors Through whatever, you know tunnels or whatever you've set up, but good VPN software.
Speaker 1: I'll oftentimes you'll have this sort of Lockdown like if you use a Cisco RSA or any of that stuff.
Speaker 1: if I turn on my VPN I put my RSA key in which one has multi-factor.
Speaker 1: It's something I have something I know Mm-hmm and in an independent of that there's all this other, you know similar like multiplied factor on the other side.
Speaker 1: I still have to log into the domain and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: But all that aside what it does is it locks down my computer Turns off all other multi homing all other stuff to where the only thing my computer can connect to now is my corporate network.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know, you might think well, what's the point of that?
Speaker 0: Right, the point of that is let's say they let you in the VPN, right?
Speaker 0: But they still let you use your normal internet connection in your house.
Speaker 1: Alright, so I got my unencrypted, you know wireless connection through some shady access point that I found outside.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Sam what you could do is you could just open up, you know You can make a tunnel and let you could Intentionally let the whole world into that VPN and now you basically just open up a gaping hole into the corporate network.
Speaker 0: Congratulations.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: VPNs are also really good for corporate access from untrusted sites.
Speaker 1: You kind of create this encrypted tunnel that is easy to create.
Speaker 1: I mean some CEO guy is not gonna be able to just set up an SSH tunnel bouncing off of his Linux box or anything Yep, at least even if he's smart.
Speaker 1: even people like us.
Speaker 1: I can't do that quickly.
Speaker 1: I can't just like BAM and set that up.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Another thing about VPN.
Speaker 0: right is okay.
Speaker 0: Let's say I'm a company and I got two offices right one in Connecticut and one in California far away.
Speaker 0: I need these offices to sort of connect to each other right?
Speaker 0: I want you know, everyone needs to work together.
Speaker 0: It should just be one network, right?
Speaker 0: I can't really having two separate networks and then you know having to use internet protocols to go between.
Speaker 0: That's risky for my business.
Speaker 0: First of all, and second of all, it's a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: It'd be a lot easier.
Speaker 1: think about all the BS of like dealing with your exchange server and all.
Speaker 1: yeah I think all right.
Speaker 0: It would be a lot easier if all the computers around the world that belong to my company We're just always on the same network, you know, the ones in offices.
Speaker 0: So I could right I could pay for really expensive like, you know t1s and t3s That go across, you know great distances and make it so that the computers are actually on the same network.
Speaker 1: Yep You can also do kind of the second tier like a virtual circuit MPLS kind of thing Yeah, which is still.
Speaker 1: basically it's the same as a t3.
Speaker 0: It's just it's virtual Yep, but a much cheaper solution especially for a tiny company is to get a VPN and it just.
Speaker 0: it wouldn't be sort of Like this, you know VPN that you use when you're working from home where you turn it on and turn it off Be an always-on sort of hardware VPN.
Speaker 1: now one one way to do this.
Speaker 1: No, Scott mentioned having the one big network.
Speaker 1: You can also use this with multiple networks.
Speaker 1: I mean like say I have my New York office my San Francisco office my Chicago office my my Dubai office and Every one of them has its own network with its own IP scheme.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I want to connect them.
Speaker 1: I don't want to make it a flat land.
Speaker 1: I want the VPN to just make them appear to be the same for different subnets.
Speaker 1: make it easy But I still want them to connect to each other Privately and I don't want to pay for at least line.
Speaker 1: I mean all the VPN does is make an encrypted tunnel through the internet.
Speaker 1: So I only need Internet connections at every point I want to connect.
Speaker 1: and they all just connect to each other over the internet The same as any other internet thing.
Speaker 1: It's no different than web track.
Speaker 0: You're basically making a big pipe over the internet.
Speaker 0: That's yours and yours alone.
Speaker 0: that connects two places, you know.
Speaker 0: You're basically using the internet for your own private networking needs.
Speaker 0: So it's like you could run an Ethernet cable in your house.
Speaker 0: Think of it as throwing an Ethernet cable all the way across the internet to your friend who catches it.
Speaker 0: and now is your Ethernet cable.
Speaker 0: no one else can get in.
Speaker 0: It's a. it's like a physical thing.
Speaker 1: now there are pros and cons.
Speaker 1: pros It has all the same backup and functionality of the internet.
Speaker 1: It'll just route.
Speaker 0: if the internet goes down.
Speaker 0: your VPN goes down.
Speaker 1: That's I was saying the pro.
Speaker 1: first it routes over the internet.
Speaker 1: So whatever BS is going on on the internet You don't care.
Speaker 1: you only need to know the IPs of your two endpoints or an endpoints and everything just works.
Speaker 0: You gotta have static IPs or else it's a little difficult.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are ways around it.
Speaker 1: Like kamachi doesn't need it, but other ones do and you know, whatever The cons you're beholden to the internet if you don't have a fat internet pipe your VPN is gonna be slow as shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah VPNs are slower like if your internet connection is like X fast.
Speaker 0: the VPN is gonna be slower than that because it's doing all this Extra stuff.
Speaker 0: It's not only is it encrypting and adding latency by doing the encryption It's also sending over more datas.
Speaker 0: You know sort of overhead packets and things for the VPN instructions and routing and all this stuff.
Speaker 0: So it's it's gonna slow you down.
Speaker 0: So I mean you it's still good enough to do something.
Speaker 0: That's not super super Performance intensive, but don't expect to like, you know Have your pings.
Speaker 0: stay the same when you're playing the counter strikes because it's not it's gonna be bigger.
Speaker 1: So you're a punk kid.
Speaker 1: you want to learn how to do this stuff.
Speaker 1: try hamachi.
Speaker 1: It just works.
Speaker 0: hamachi just works.
Speaker 1: and if you get beyond hamachi real simple get some net appliance or some image.
Speaker 1: There are all sorts of ways to do this.
Speaker 1: Just find some VPN solution.
Speaker 1: That's free and easy and open-source II.
Speaker 1: just run it on your home network and Figure out what your out external dynamic IP is.
Speaker 1: maybe pay for one of those DDNS services.
Speaker 0: one one Very good idea to try out VPN is to if you get one of those routers that you can flash the firmware on if you Put on the DD wrt or the tomato or one of those other router for alternative open source router firmwares.
Speaker 0: Most of them have open VPN support and you can read online how to make that work.
Speaker 0: And the reason you want to do this right is is the another great use of VPN, right?
Speaker 0: You're on vacation somewhere you're at a convention, right?
Speaker 0: You've got in your home network.
Speaker 0: So you've got your iTunes with your music sharing, right?
Speaker 0: But it's in your home and it's it's on your hard drive in your desktop And you don't want to pick that up and carry it with you to do a convention.
Speaker 0: So but you want to listen to some music that you didn't bring with you on your iPod.
Speaker 0: So what you do is you turn on your laptop you open up your iTunes, you know, but a VPN to your house.
Speaker 0: now It's as if your laptop is in your house.
Speaker 0: So your iTunes sharing suddenly works.
Speaker 0: Look at that.
Speaker 0: just do Look I can see my computer from here.
Speaker 0: All right, you don't need to use any like your remote desktop VNC type of stuff.
Speaker 0: You know, you can just share your files locally on your home network Securely so that you know the.
Speaker 0: no one outside your house is gonna get your files off your computer only people in your house.
Speaker 0: They're gonna get your files that you're sharing.
Speaker 0: You know, like you're sharing the mostly so that you can access them from downstairs or upstairs or basement.
Speaker 0: But now if you VPN back to your house You can get your stuff and it's totally cool.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 1: plus as we always say you can't learn something just by wanting to learn it.
Speaker 1: You have to have some application some use.
Speaker 1: So if you want to learn VPN, just set it up.
Speaker 1: Anyone can do it.
Speaker 1: There's nothing stopping you and you'll learn a whole bunch of stuff about networking and VPN along the way.
Speaker 1: But when you learn a lot of networking stuff, you'll get a useful usable thing that you will probably use on a fairly regular basis.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean think about how many will work from home and have VPNs and they know how to turn them on because basically all they have to do is open up the Cisco software push connect and Type in their password, but sometimes that shit don't work.
Speaker 0: And if you learn about VPNs You'll have a much easier time telecommuting.
Speaker 0: and if you're much better at telecommuting and have much more reliable at doing work while telecommuting Because you know how the VPN works and you're good at getting it to work You'll work from home a lot more Probably and you'll also have more access to your own stuff in your way from the house and you'll play more games and it'll be Awesome.
Speaker 0: VPN is great.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has Everything.
Speaker 0: geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.