Speaker 1: It's Monday April 20th.
Speaker 0: I'm ready.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We have kind of a long show about to open everything, New York City.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm back down to one Red Bull a day.
Speaker 0: I think that's still possibly Not one too many, but perhaps like one 7 like 6/7 too many.
Speaker 0: like what a week is maybe okay, really?
Speaker 1: I'm averaging like five a week, and then my other caffeinated beverages are coffee in as opposed to I don't know a chemical a Performance enhancing chemical you know you can.
Speaker 0: you know what I would do if I had like an an office?
Speaker 0: Right what I would do is I would get like some caffeine like in a you know like just you know powdered caffeine and like A little you know like a spice jar or whatever.
Speaker 0: right and then I would make decaf.
Speaker 0: You know there'd be a coffee maker in the office.
Speaker 0: You sort of have to have one and I would get caffeine free right?
Speaker 0: But I would put it in a not in a caffeine box So people wouldn't think it was caffeine free.
Speaker 0: and then I what I would do is I would put the caffeine in there from the Little medicine you know from the spice box, so it would.
Speaker 0: there would be caffeine in there.
Speaker 0: So you know every every week your employees every week I would put in less and less and less until we had this bot.
Speaker 0: You know that we would have a can of you know caffeinated coffee that had caffeine free coffee in it And then no one in the office would get any caffeine, but they wouldn't know it.
Speaker 1: Why would you do that?
Speaker 0: Get my office off caffeine, but why?
Speaker 1: caffeine is good for you?
Speaker 1: all those slashdot articles have been pointing that out.
Speaker 0: it It's like alcohol alcohol, it's like yeah heart disease.
Speaker 0: this was like all cancer.
Speaker 1: that it's all I think Is in terms of.
Speaker 1: you have to have intelligent moderation in all things.
Speaker 1: yeah, and few people do that.
Speaker 0: I mean I mean if you drink too much water you die.
Speaker 1: don't eat too much bread you die, but I mean All right, there's a strong correlation between drinking red wine and not having a heart attack.
Speaker 1: at the same time There's a strong correlation from drinking red wine and being a wino The mad dog.
Speaker 0: I think the thing my night train the thing is I'm saying is that You know there are some things out there.
Speaker 0: We're a little bit is too much.
Speaker 1: You know like a heroin crack.
Speaker 0: We all agree yeah, right, but there's nothing out there.
Speaker 0: Where zero is Not is no good Except you know just food in general your regular food zero food is bad.
Speaker 1: wait You're saying there's nothing out there.
Speaker 0: was your water is also bad.
Speaker 1: But at least the thing I was trying to do this was it wasn't like oh I should not drink caffeine or anything because I drink caffeine and all these sorts of things all the time and I use them for runs and energy and all that.
Speaker 1: but My thinking was more that the more tolerance.
Speaker 1: I build up much like I've already done with alcohol The less effective it is and the more I have to drink which increases.
Speaker 1: You know it's like the drug addict - he does his cocaine or whatever and he's fine.
Speaker 1: But then he has to keep using more and more of it to get the same effect And he has more and more of the side effects.
Speaker 1: and about a month ago.
Speaker 1: I was starting to get that with my caffeine Mm-hmm, and I Got down.
Speaker 1: until now it is one caffeinated bet.
Speaker 1: well one Substantially caffeinated beverage per day.
Speaker 1: I don't count like a can of coke.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess isn't there technically caffeine.
Speaker 0: and just like regular old chocolate yes, yeah.
Speaker 0: So it's like I get caffeine in there.
Speaker 1: I guess cuz I eat chocolate But you know yeah, but I remember when I first drank Red Bull.
Speaker 1: you drink it and get this rush and all right I gotta go do stuff go go go puff puff puff 180 miles an hour And it got to the point where I drink a Red Bull just to not fall asleep.
Speaker 0: The main thing I think about Red Bull though It's like they have like this great great marketing where they like they advertise.
Speaker 0: I'm like all this awesome shit, and it's never like.
Speaker 0: it's always like awesome sports stuff like f1 car f1 cars, right They got like four f1 cars Video of like the greatest Skydiving base jump guy in the world and pretty much Red Bull sponsored everything he did.
Speaker 1: yep Well plus look at how they got everything started.
Speaker 1: their early marketing campaigns was they go to colleges and trendy places and be like All the Red Bull you want have go nuts yeah, or the beach, or you know surfing and you know anything cool like that.
Speaker 1: And of course the first frat boy thinks huh new thing caffeinated Makes it with vodka.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, baby.
Speaker 0: It's like regardless of the beverage itself, right?
Speaker 0: It's all the money that is paid for that makes all these awesome things happen cuz you know when you're wait wait wait.
Speaker 1: So are you saying that drinking Red Bull is basically charity for extreme sports?
Speaker 0: Yes, it is right cuz you think about it, right?
Speaker 0: I mean those things like thanks skydiving.
Speaker 0: dude right he needs like all this equipment.
Speaker 0: He needs planes.
Speaker 0: you need you know.
Speaker 0: think about how much shit.
Speaker 0: He needs.
Speaker 1: you're not gonna get Stanley to back him.
Speaker 0: no one would ever pay for that right, but the thing is look at other people out there Who get ever like coca-cola advertising right when you buy a can of coke?
Speaker 0: They spend their money on a billboard a TV ad.
Speaker 0: that doesn't really you know.
Speaker 0: do anything at least you know.
Speaker 0: I mean they could use the money to like.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: maybe do some chair real charitable work.
Speaker 0: You know saving starving people.
Speaker 0: they do yeah, well, but you know it.
Speaker 0: Paying for a guy to do awesome Skydiving is better than paying for a billboard in Times Square McDonald's and Burger King and all those things.
Speaker 1: I mean there's always those logos all over f1 cars or all their different things.
Speaker 1: But Red Bull I feel like kind of goes out of its way to go after the more awesome stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah anyway.
Speaker 1: So so I'm performing a charitable world service here.
Speaker 0: Somewhat charitable.
Speaker 0: it has it as charitable intent, but it is not going to the Greatest charitable cause there is no no it's not.
Speaker 1: But you know yeah that kind of comes in stark contrast after our weekend because we kind of we didn't even really announce it on the show because we went Suddenly, and we've registered at the last minute.
Speaker 1: But we went to open everything New York City 2009 over the weekend and part of the reason this whole caffeine thing came up Was that I was very like?
Speaker 1: Methodically Reducing my caffeine and energy drink input And I was like planning and getting down to the one drink a day.
Speaker 1: and we're at this thing And I'm giving all these talks, and I'm kind of tired and I want some caffeine.
Speaker 1: I go get my one latte, and it was like that went to a non Starbucks over by the UN.
Speaker 1: It was like the best latte.
Speaker 1: I've ever had in my life, so I went and got another gigantic one.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: That's a good job But we'll talk about that in the second half of the show because what The right before like.
Speaker 1: we're both going out of town for an extended period.
Speaker 1: we weren't even gonna do a show today.
Speaker 0: Well, we were gonna do a show today because originally right I was gonna drive you.
Speaker 0: you're going to Costa Rica tomorrow And I was gonna drive you to the airport tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Mom calls me yesterday right and I was sort of planning to go to Florida But we didn't know when and we were kind of like we'll go.
Speaker 1: She's like we're going tomorrow.
Speaker 0: It's like Tuesday, and I'm like Tuesday.
Speaker 0: I'm driving them to the airport Tuesday.
Speaker 0: How about Wednesday?
Speaker 0: how about late on Tuesday?
Speaker 0: How about you know?
Speaker 0: and she's like no it's got to be this one.
Speaker 1: She was intractable.
Speaker 0: It's like it would not move and I was like come on.
Speaker 1: so Emily And I just relieved Scott of his chauffeur duty, and we're gonna.
Speaker 1: I debated taking the helicopter, but we're in no rush.
Speaker 1: So we're just gonna take the train down and then take the path over to like the those helicopter to Newark.
Speaker 0: yes Oh, I thought the helicopter was only to JFK.
Speaker 1: There's a hell.
Speaker 1: There's helicopters to all three.
Speaker 0: I would have taken the helicopter to Newark.
Speaker 1: the one to Newark is a hundred and seventy bucks a purse.
Speaker 0: That's worth it.
Speaker 1: It is it's it's I think.
Speaker 0: think about how much.
Speaker 0: think about how much trouble is gonna be right.
Speaker 0: I think how long it would it take for me to drive you right and how you know the gas would have been like you Know 20 bucks something like that.
Speaker 1: You know no if only if only I was looking.
Speaker 1: It's not that expensive to fly from Stewart Airport next to our house to Newark.
Speaker 0: Flight at your convenient time.
Speaker 1: well there are little.
Speaker 0: your flight out of Newark at like 11 a.m..
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like 1145.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you got a. you had to take off from like steward.
Speaker 1: it like you know like When I flew to Raleigh for that convention a while ago I Basically I was gonna fly out of LaGuardia.
Speaker 1: I think I flew out of LaGuardia But it was easier and faster and not any more expensive to take a flight from Stewart Airport.
Speaker 1: that connected with that flight at LaGuardia mmm, so I did that.
Speaker 0: It's actually you know what my mom figured out.
Speaker 0: that was really smart.
Speaker 0: Is that usually every time I go into Florida I go to JFK to get on a jet blue.
Speaker 1: right because you're obsessed with the?
Speaker 0: Jet blue, but why would I?
Speaker 0: why would it go on any other shitty?
Speaker 1: I kind of see why.
Speaker 1: because every time lately I've flown with a jet blue a couple of times but I've flown with other airlines a lot because I go places where jet blue doesn't go and Every night every time I've flown non jet blue.
Speaker 1: It has been a disaster.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much every single time jet blue has all new planes They all just work.
Speaker 0: it all just goes.
Speaker 1: of course when we were flying to PAX remember we get there we get in line We're like yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's go.
Speaker 1: and then all the computers that the jet blue terminal stopped working.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: It's the computer situation.
Speaker 0: That's not a it's not an airplane situation But I like how it.
Speaker 1: basically it affected everyone But us because everyone else had a flight in like an hour and but apparently three hours, but apparently jet blue flies.
Speaker 0: You know usually like jet blue doesn't have a lot of like direct flights.
Speaker 0: You'll have to go to like JFK.
Speaker 0: like if you want to go from Rochester to Florida You have to go to JFK first and then Florida.
Speaker 0: right you can't?
Speaker 0: you know there's not a lot of direct action going on.
Speaker 1: It's like aerobiz.
Speaker 1: JFK is like their hub, right?
Speaker 0: But apparently there's so many big Jews in white planes going to Florida that you can fly from white planes to Florida direct And then that's that's great because the white plans Airport is a lot less crowded.
Speaker 0: it is.
Speaker 1: It depends on when you go because you've driven in white planes.
Speaker 1: That's other than that area around Terrytown and 287.
Speaker 1: That's like the worst place in the world.
Speaker 0: You just go down 684 you get off.
Speaker 0: It's not big deal.
Speaker 1: See the thing is I was always driving around there rush hour Because you know I worked over there.
Speaker 1: So if I if I was working at that one hospital I would have to take 684 up and home in the middle of rush hour and I would sit for an hour on a four-mile stretch of freeway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not the situation.
Speaker 0: But yeah, there's a the white planes Airport.
Speaker 0: you can go direct to Florida which is very nice much better than you know.
Speaker 0: I mean you know I like JFK.
Speaker 0: I know my way around.
Speaker 0: they got a new terminal.
Speaker 0: everything's happy there.
Speaker 0: But you know if you go to a small It's always better to go to smaller airports because you can.
Speaker 0: there's shorter lines And you can breeze through more easily if you can avoid the big airport.
Speaker 0: It's better for your time management.
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus small Airport the Wi-Fi always works.
Speaker 1: JK the wife.
Speaker 1: well we were in that like annex.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there were like 400 feet now.
Speaker 0: They have a new terminal.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure the Wi-Fi is better over there.
Speaker 1: I hope so.
Speaker 1: yeah Alright, but this week.
Speaker 1: We're like alright.
Speaker 1: This is gonna be an easy short week.
Speaker 1: We decide to go to this can this convention.
Speaker 1: We're gonna put up all these pre-recorded shows And then like everything hits the fan all at once.
Speaker 1: now I'm going out of the country and Scott's going to Florida, and we went to this thing over the weekend, so here We are.
Speaker 0: yep, so we're gonna record.
Speaker 0: This is actually not night.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry plus It's like what time is how come 10 11 in the morning?
Speaker 1: right at this moment right as all these things are happening We think we'll just knock off a quick show or not even do a show.
Speaker 1: and then there's like the most gigantic Technology news in a long time.
Speaker 0: yeah, so let's see gigantic technology news.
Speaker 0: number one.
Speaker 0: right Adobe is Going to play.
Speaker 0: what was that?
Speaker 0: It's Adobe.
Speaker 0: That's the company.
Speaker 1: what is that?
Speaker 1: an inside joke?
Speaker 1: I don't know about it.
Speaker 0: It's from high school.
Speaker 0: this kid used to always say whatever He said.
Speaker 0: Adobe used to be like Adobe.
Speaker 0: That's kind of a because he transferred it cuz.
Speaker 0: he used to say cuz apparently when he was like you know in Elementary middle school.
Speaker 0: right it's like you learn about like pueblo Indians who make houses out of Adobe And then they transferred that joke over to the company.
Speaker 1: uh-huh Anyway, kind of like you're all Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Wikipedia same kind of thing.
Speaker 0: So Adobe decided that they're going to put flash Directly into televisions, which means you know Netflix Hulu YouTube whatever just in your TV.
Speaker 0: now this I Might wait to buy a TV until like.
Speaker 1: well it's strange because one according to I was reading through the comments in the slashdot article a lot of people pointed out that So far only the crappy television manufacturers are on board with this.
Speaker 0: yeah cuz that way it's like.
Speaker 0: hey our TV Doesn't have a as awesome a display as yours.
Speaker 0: It's not as the doesn't have the greatest contrast ratio.
Speaker 0: But hey you know what.
Speaker 0: people don't give a shit about that.
Speaker 0: people give a shit about features But even like.
Speaker 0: that's why they can sell so many like shitty TVs of the VCR built in cuz.
Speaker 1: you got more features than a TV without but like as of our press time I guess I think Samsung is not on board and that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: but I Feel like this is just this is the final piece to this giant like swirling conundrum of What's going to happen to television because in the last six months?
Speaker 1: I feel like Everything is pointing at television.
Speaker 1: Just like suddenly imploding.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I think what's actually happening here, right?
Speaker 0: Is that people they've always want they've always wanted to apply and size the computer right so they couldn't do that.
Speaker 0: So they tried to get web TV and stuff like that You know to make you know to sort of apply and size the internet and it didn't.
Speaker 0: it didn't work.
Speaker 0: So now but what they can do and I think what they figured out now is if you take multimedia things entertainment video right audio and Apply in size not the whole internet, but the specific functions specific sites specific things Right and put it directly into the television where people are comfortable with multimedia and video That that's gonna work really well.
Speaker 0: the problem is of course, you know, it's it's very non open which is well.
Speaker 1: I think we need to look at all the players involved here because I'm not really sure in the end Who this is going to benefit and what the ramifications really will.
Speaker 0: it benefits the TV?
Speaker 0: Manufacture because they sell more TVs.
Speaker 0: it benefits the person because now they can watch you on their TV without plugging a computer.
Speaker 1: I mean on one hand We've got the actual providers like the Comcast who they're the ones who have the wire.
Speaker 0: They're unhappy.
Speaker 1: that goes to my house.
Speaker 0: They're the losers.
Speaker 1: But the thing is their steak is that they basically have two businesses that use the same infrastructure that until recently did not compete with one another and only nerds Understood that they always competed with each other that they gave, you know broadcast television cable TV and they gave internet And originally two separate things and internet.
Speaker 0: the same thing with VoIP right.
Speaker 0: is that you know, we had we had specific, you know data to location services right and Different data needed different physical infrastructure.
Speaker 0: because you know a phone audio to the house needed a special thing video to the house Needed a different special thing and we had all these hacks like our technology data over the phone line.
Speaker 1: So we use modem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, our technology was so weak that we needed specialized hardware for specialized functionality.
Speaker 0: now the same exact hardware can provide all data any data functionality same thing and they have to give up on the you know, specialized hardware over specialized tasks and realize Everyone's just gonna have one unified pipe to their house So that as all anything that can be digitized will go through that.
Speaker 1: and then look at these distributors.
Speaker 1: now they they have cable TV, which is massively profitable and doesn't take much for them to do.
Speaker 1: and They have the internet thing.
Speaker 1: and suddenly now all the hip people realize that One of those encompasses everything that the other one can provide.
Speaker 0: and also they also do phone.
Speaker 0: It's internet TV and phone.
Speaker 0: to be.
Speaker 0: internet does TV and phone.
Speaker 0: so why pay you know?
Speaker 0: It's like I could pay $90 and I would get internet TV and phone and you know And that's 30 bucks each if you divide it out.
Speaker 0: But I instead I pay $50 for internet.
Speaker 0: and internet provides TV.
Speaker 1: and but here's the problem why it's also interconnected.
Speaker 1: these providers they make all their money from like cable TV primarily and suddenly as more and more people are using the data side and Realizing wait a minute.
Speaker 1: I get everything I need from the internet.
Speaker 1: Why do I even pay for cable TV?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they don't their advertisements, but the advertisements are directly on the content.
Speaker 0: So the publishers get that money whereas when you have cable TV, right?
Speaker 0: There's those cable TV ads.
Speaker 0: so the cable company is getting some money in there and this you know Cuts the cable company out.
Speaker 0: pretty much everything the internet does is cut out middlemen.
Speaker 0: Anyone who's a middleman gets cut out because everyone can now directly connect to everyone else.
Speaker 0: so you don't need a middleman You don't need a distributor.
Speaker 0: You don't need someone in between to get your stuff between a publisher and a consumer.
Speaker 0: It's just direct from crater to eater, you know, the farmer directly to your mouth.
Speaker 0: No more supermarket No more, you know.
Speaker 0: now normally it's going on.
Speaker 1: normally.
Speaker 1: this wouldn't be that big of a deal.
Speaker 1: It would basically be one Industry one segment of an industry that kind of gets obviated by technology and has to adapt and that's fine.
Speaker 1: But the real issue here is that they're so interconnected and so incestuous that we look at well.
Speaker 1: I felt like I was turning into a rant like captain steel who we'll talk about later Because I just the word interconnected.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'll talk about that sometime.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so the cable companies they rely on one subscriptions to cable TV Which is really expensive but to they rely on the fact that there's this whole industry that kind of supports their cable in that they're the different networks that either pay to be carried or Pay based on number of subscribers.
Speaker 1: I think cable companies care a lot more about how many people they can say are subscribed.
Speaker 1: Then how many people are paying them to subscribe?
Speaker 1: Because in the end remember television is not a product that is sold to you the consumer.
Speaker 1: Television is a product that is sold by One entity to another entity for the purpose of getting eyeballs and then putting advertisements at those eyeballs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, one guy collects eyeballs, which is you and sells them to someone else, right?
Speaker 0: But now if you just you will sell your own eyeballs.
Speaker 0: you you have one eyeball and you will sell it on its own.
Speaker 1: Well, no one will collect them.
Speaker 1: I have to one pair.
Speaker 1: Well for now, I mean, you know with 4chan kids getting more and more I don't know internet II and multitasking Are we gonna get to the part where there are punk kids who have different screens on each eyeball possibly?
Speaker 1: but the It's not a joke.
Speaker 0: it is because you're talking about eyes.
Speaker 1: no, that's not a joke.
Speaker 1: that was barely even a pun.
Speaker 1: Good job captain.
Speaker 1: So the cable companies are screwed by this because they can't make the money They expected to make off of data and there's all the other concerns about data.
Speaker 1: But the content providers are just as bad off because their whole business model is make a show sell it to advertisers Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I think what they should do, but they can't capitalize off of the advertising on the internet the same way.
Speaker 1: I mean look at Hulu.
Speaker 1: they have like they show the one ad and the one ad and I think they Realized that all the internet has shown them is that people don't watch their ads anyway.
Speaker 0: I think what the cable company needs to do right is just Give up and realize that you are just a dumb pipe, you know, you're just gonna be a. you know a data Just data for anything.
Speaker 0: That's all you are.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna be able to do anything else.
Speaker 0: So give up and go for it and then just charge what it actually costs plus a reasonable margin.
Speaker 1: And I think that's not going to happen without government regulation.
Speaker 1: I don't think.
Speaker 0: well because the problem is is that makes enough money, you know, you're charging cost plus a reasonable margin.
Speaker 0: You're gonna make a reasonable margin.
Speaker 0: people will pay for it, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the problem is it's less money than they're making now, but it's profitable.
Speaker 0: it'll be able to live forever with that.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: It's less than they're making now.
Speaker 1: We need to.
Speaker 0: we really need and I you know, I bet especially if all the cable companies do it There'll be price wars on it and the margins will get shoved down.
Speaker 0: But I bend because that'll be the only differentiating factor.
Speaker 1: I bend very often toward you know deregulate regulation in certain sectors and I Generally want to avoid, you know, giant beer bureaucratic clusterfucks of government controlling industries, but at the same time We regulate utilities the government just.
Speaker 1: I mean you're not.
Speaker 1: you don't have water companies that are in this sort of growth market Trying to capitalize on the fact that they're pumping water into my pot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is the water company was never private.
Speaker 0: what happens when somebody has a private company, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say, you know, you know and then it becomes a commodity.
Speaker 1: You just you take it if it's something that's necessary.
Speaker 1: and I feel that the Internet There's no as necessary as any other utility now, it is electricity and water now, it's data.
Speaker 1: We have these three things.
Speaker 1: We need some sort of eminent domain that isn't just for physical property.
Speaker 1: I mean we're talking about this the other day Scott and I because the MLK Foundation is going su crazy again Because people are using Martin Luther King speeches.
Speaker 1: We need eminent domain for intellectual property and we need an eminent domain equivalent.
Speaker 1: the government just needs to take regulate Data and make it a.
Speaker 0: yeah Right now we talk about you know, like the government buying banks, right?
Speaker 0: Why does the government have to buy the bank?
Speaker 0: if the government is eminent domain the bank?
Speaker 0: We wouldn't have to pay, you know, how much money would that is saved if the government could just say, okay So this bank is worth a million dollars.
Speaker 0: Why do it's got all this banks got?
Speaker 0: just take the bank.
Speaker 1: Um, because the bank is not owned by the bank.
Speaker 1: The bank is owned by all the shareholders.
Speaker 0: Yeah, eminent domain they lose that.
Speaker 1: the problem with that is that if you do it that way you basically undermine all of the kind of Expected integrity of the stock market and you would cause an economic disaster.
Speaker 0: Well, it's no different than you eminent domain someone's house.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: That's the equivalent of eminent domain in everyone's houses.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's not good You know, no, it's got.
Speaker 1: Practicality always overrides ideology in the end.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying you know We need some more.
Speaker 0: we need eminent domain to be used in a good way Yes, but not in the way that you just suggested.
Speaker 1: That's crazy.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: I just think we need the government to regulate Data infrastructure as a utility as opposed to now where it's this kind of Wild West private enterprise craziness,
Speaker 0: mmm Maybe someone should just start a company that is Internet utility and then see how you can compete with the cable guys because your price your price is gonna be way lower Than the 50 bucks a month that we have to pay for out to one line.
Speaker 1: That's basically impossible because of all the last mile concerns.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you can get in on that.
Speaker 1: how how are you gonna afford to?
Speaker 0: You start in a city and you know, I that's probably there's a lot of people doing like last mile Ethernet and stuff.
Speaker 0: You can get in on that.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's quite as simple as you're making it out to me.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's ever going to happen without government intervention.
Speaker 0: No, you know, it's still someone should try.
Speaker 1: But try what I mean, okay, I make an ISP and what I just try not to make as much money as everyone else.
Speaker 0: No, you provide, you know, you just provide internet services and you don't charge as much as the cable company.
Speaker 1: I just have lower prices.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're saying yeah, and I if there were a space for that someone would have done it.
Speaker 1: There's clearly no space for it.
Speaker 0: I think this space for it.
Speaker 0: I Disagree if we could get internet that was just as good as what we have now and was cost less money.
Speaker 1: Yes, and Scott I don't think that can happen because if the prices are out of whack then people would definitely see a business opportunity there and the Fact that no one is really doing this Indicates to me that there isn't enough money available.
Speaker 1: It's not profitable.
Speaker 0: I think it's just not as profitable.
Speaker 1: No, I just don't think it's profitable.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so there was another Gigantamous tech news today.
Speaker 0: kind of word was that yeah, I know you hate words that are incorrect So I use it on purpose.
Speaker 1: I don't mind cromulant words.
Speaker 1: I live my life in full cromulants But ginormous is just a stupid word.
Speaker 1: that sounds stupid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I said gigantamous instead.
Speaker 1: Derivative of ginormous is even worse.
Speaker 1: I know It's even worse.
Speaker 0: Maybe I should keep going Ginormous that doesn't?
Speaker 0: that sounds more like anal related.
Speaker 0: then what anyway?
Speaker 0: So there were rumors are going around.
Speaker 1: we didn't even talk about the flash thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we did.
Speaker 1: We basically just talked about isp.
Speaker 0: Well, because that's what the flash thing really means in the end.
Speaker 0: There is.
Speaker 1: we won't talk about it now, but I think there's.
Speaker 1: That was the first point I was going to.
Speaker 0: I do think the one other thing I could say about the flash thing though Is that I think it might?
Speaker 0: Cut off less technologically inclined people from the fullness of the internet.
Speaker 0: You know some you know, they might.
Speaker 0: just if they experience the Internet's only through you know These applications in the television then they're cut off from the whole thing It's like, you know, so like the AOL is ation where you can't see the whole internet.
Speaker 0: You can only see this part that has been crafted for you by some company.
Speaker 0: well,
Speaker 1: what I think is that the reason this is a concern that you know, the second point I was gonna get to is that The content providers so far seem to be For whatever reason fully on the side of the cable TV industry and they're trying to keep Broadcast television going and they're trying like remember the boxy debacle Hulu and all that.
Speaker 1: They desperately don't want people to stop watching TV and they desperately want them to continue to use push media as opposed to pull media.
Speaker 1: and I feel like What they really need to do is look at this and say why don't we just give up on the cable companies?
Speaker 1: Let them steward their own juices.
Speaker 1: I just go internet full-on.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm All right.
Speaker 0: So there were rumors going around last week that IBM would buy Sun microsystems and that you know It seemed at least slightly reasonable because Sun, you know Sun is sort of important.
Speaker 0: They do a lot of stuff.
Speaker 0: but you know, they run Java and they make.
Speaker 0: they actually still make computers I'm pretty sure Big servers and things and Sun actually has a lot of really awesome open source stuff going on.
Speaker 0: Most notably they got the virtual box, which is pretty great.
Speaker 0: They got they got an open SSO, which is a single sign-on solution.
Speaker 0: That's really great.
Speaker 0: They got an open Directory service which goes along with the single sign-on which is like an open LDAP kind of thing.
Speaker 0: They do lots of awesome open source stuff over down at Sun.
Speaker 0: they open Solaris, you know They got the Solaris operating system.
Speaker 0: that's closed.
Speaker 0: They bought MySQL.
Speaker 1: right now the this.
Speaker 1: the rumors came and there's a lot of talk and then it all broke down and there are a lot of Speculation and rumors and ideas as to why IBM decided not to jump in on this and then out of nowhere Oracle says you know what we'll buy him.
Speaker 0: Yep today It's Oracle bought Sun.
Speaker 0: they bought him.
Speaker 1: now this.
Speaker 1: we could talk a lot about all the different ramifications of this but I think the primary one for people like us is that Now Oracle and my SQL are owned by the same company.
Speaker 0: Those are like the two biggest Relational databases there are.
Speaker 1: I mean, what else do we have?
Speaker 1: There's DB to IBM's.
Speaker 0: that doesn't count.
Speaker 0: That's nothing.
Speaker 1: Actually.
Speaker 1: That's not.
Speaker 1: that's widely deployed and widely used and big iron.
Speaker 0: That's scary.
Speaker 1: I actually we you didn't go in the open New York City thing that we had to talk about enterprise stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, almost everyone.
Speaker 1: there was a DB to admin really.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I used to be a DB to admin.
Speaker 0: Wow And wasn't there also stuff like cybase and shit, right?
Speaker 1: Well, the other the other big one is Postgres.
Speaker 1: Yep, and The problem is my SQL.
Speaker 1: I've been dubious of my SQL almost forever because it worked pretty well and it scaled pretty well.
Speaker 1: It performed pretty well.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of tools for it.
Speaker 1: It was easy, but at the same time it was kind of this weird.
Speaker 1: I never trusted it because at any time like all the good features were always kind of pulled into the enterprise version.
Speaker 0: Son bought them.
Speaker 1: Yeah as opposed to the community version.
Speaker 0: that's free Yeah, but my SQL is just it's sort of you know, it's that fit is just.
Speaker 0: it goes so well with PHP Which is I think why they're so often put together.
Speaker 0: It's sort of that technology that works.
Speaker 0: But the architecture is sort of fundamentally flawed and it has a lot of these problems.
Speaker 0: But you can make it work you'll get by.
Speaker 0: it won't be pretty and a lot of companies just work on that.
Speaker 0: you know, they they got everything duct-taped together and It's got enough juice to keep the keep it going.
Speaker 0: and that's how they go.
Speaker 0: All right, and that's My SQL is and Oracle is you know, sort of the real deal.
Speaker 0: It's got every feature in the known universe any time I've ever had like a database problem and I want to do something easily.
Speaker 0: Oracle always just has the feature and it's so, you know, perfect and wonderful.
Speaker 0: The thing is it costs a fortune to get Oracle.
Speaker 0: It's like a bajillion dollars and you need like a bajillion dollars in hardware to run it.
Speaker 0: You can't just run it on your laptop.
Speaker 0: Like you can run MySQL on your laptop.
Speaker 1: Oh, don't forget to MS SQL.
Speaker 1: All right Yeah, that's a widely deployed.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I forgot about that one very easy to use performs pretty well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's Microsoft SQL is okay, but it has.
Speaker 0: you know, it it's a typical Microsoft product.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is you know, so that's the only thing wrong with that.
Speaker 1: all that that entails.
Speaker 1: Yes, but I feel like suddenly They like.
Speaker 1: for a long time I've kind of realized that a lot of smarter people have realized that We're more and more at least web 2.0 style people Relying on my SQL because everything kind of uses that by default.
Speaker 1: But at the same time my SQL seemed like it was getting less and less open and less and less Reliable and more and more limiting like as you expand what you're doing, right?
Speaker 0: It's like my SQL becomes more and more problematic for you.
Speaker 0: Like for example, you can use the my isaam.
Speaker 0: You know, what's it called for?
Speaker 0: your tables, right?
Speaker 1: That's what I use.
Speaker 0: But if you use my isaam, you don't get like all these nice, you know quality sort of more enterprises features of the InnoDB.
Speaker 0: But the InnoDB right doesn't have like the full text searching of the my isaam.
Speaker 0: So it's like it doesn't have both.
Speaker 1: you can't do both at once and there I mean the technical details of the problems I've always had with my SQL are numerous.
Speaker 1: I don't want to get into them, but if you take nothing away from this.
Speaker 1: But what I'm about to say now Postgres is suddenly the future and it's always been the future.
Speaker 1: Postgres is like the open source big iron date.
Speaker 0: It's hard a thing is it's harder to use.
Speaker 0: You gotta it's more learning is required.
Speaker 1: I haven't even learned it yet Yeah but in the last few years actually in the last like year there have been giant leaps and bounds in Postgres support by various things like there's a PHP my admin equivalent for Postgres and all these sorts of things.
Speaker 1: but You know we use Postgres at work.
Speaker 1: I really didn't know anything about Postgres until I got to the company I work at now and we use it for a lot of stuff.
Speaker 0: I knew that it was the other open source database and I knew that it was more difficult than my SQL and I Knew that you know a lot of things out there like say WordPress and stuff sort of sort of need.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm sure there's a way to make WordPress work on Postgres, but these things were designed to work on my SQL Which is just what everyone used.
Speaker 0: It's so easy.
Speaker 0: You just you know, you push a few buttons and there you go Database and everything goes.
Speaker 0: so I've always used my SQL because I'm using things that just work so easily on it and Trying to use Postgres instead would have been very difficult.
Speaker 1: But even though it performs better.
Speaker 1: It's more reliable.
Speaker 1: It's more robust.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much better in every way except for the learning curve of getting into it and using it and the support natively by applications.
Speaker 1: It was always better.
Speaker 1: It's still better and it's yet it.
Speaker 0: in terms of you know under the hood enterprise features Replication reliability security, but performance.
Speaker 1: one really used it except for really hardcore people.
Speaker 1: And I feel like as of today with this Oracle buying Sun I think a lot of the kind of hardcore open source developers are going to look at this and say we can't trust my SQL For shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like we sort of went in when Sun bought my SQL, but Sun was a good open source citizen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they like Sun played a lot.
Speaker 0: I just talked about all the great open source stuff that Sun does more so than anyone expected.
Speaker 1: Sun played nice.
Speaker 1: They came into the sandbox.
Speaker 1: They took over one of the sandcastles and they didn't step on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they made Java open source, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, come on, you know, they kept Java closed for how long before open sourcing it.
Speaker 0: They were all good.
Speaker 0: But now I wonder you know, how how nice is it?
Speaker 0: The open source Sun stuff gonna be now?
Speaker 0: I mean, I think it does stuff that's already been open sourced Is they can't?
Speaker 0: Oracle can't lock it up because people just fork it out.
Speaker 0: You know if they lock up Java and the next Java vert release is closed source We'll just fork the previous Java release into the open source Java and that'll be that.
Speaker 0: but you know I wonder what Oracle is gonna do and it could.
Speaker 1: if you know, I don't think it matters.
Speaker 1: I I think that regardless of what happens from this day forward I think there's going to a be a massive shift toward postgres in open source development.
Speaker 0: But I think in the enterprise realm there's going to be.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of people out there who use like the J2EE, you know stack, right?
Speaker 0: And I think that the Java Solaris Oracle stack is going to get a big boost in the enterprise world.
Speaker 1: I feel I think enterprise web stuff and enterprise, you know database driven web stuff is really going to suddenly dichotomize into either IBM web sphere or some sort of thing.
Speaker 0: is it'll go to IBM web sphere.
Speaker 1: It already is not too many Yeah a lot more than you think yeah, but I feel like it.
Speaker 1: IBM web sphere is gonna be the big player.
Speaker 0: No, but the big players gonna be Oracle and Microsoft.
Speaker 1: You didn't even let me finish.
Speaker 1: I don't think you understand how widely deployed web sphere is and how many like big iron enterprise people use it.
Speaker 1: I hate it.
Speaker 1: I administered it for years and it was a disaster, but it's like again at that conference.
Speaker 1: Everyone knew it everyone used it.
Speaker 1: Everyone supported all the big firms like.
Speaker 1: that was their backbone.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at all the I haven't seen webs here appear in like a single job listing and I've been looking at job listings for Weeks now, you know why?
Speaker 1: because there are an infinite number of web sphere developers and admins available.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so many people know it that if in fact half the people, you know We're looking to hire at our company almost everyone who applied was a web sphere Java Tomcat kind of guy Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So if you need someone like that, there are a hundred people.
Speaker 1: You can snap your fingers and they'll work for you for almost nothing.
Speaker 0: I see a lot of people doing Java powered sites, but not on web sphere.
Speaker 0: They're doing it on.
Speaker 1: Well web sphere is one of those big iron enterprise things.
Speaker 1: I mean a little hundred person company is probably not gonna use it but a lot of big places use it in a lot of Ways.
Speaker 1: they probably shouldn't anyway, but I feel like that.
Speaker 0: but his web sphere relational database Web sphere is like Tomcat.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: That's a Java application server.
Speaker 1: That's not a that's not a Database it isn't but under the hood what databases they use.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying that I feel like the big competition for the web sphere paradigm which often uses db2 on the back end will be Appliances that'll just be sold by Oracle.
Speaker 1: that'll do everything.
Speaker 1: It'll be Java and their database and like everything you need all-in-one appliance buy it turn it out.
Speaker 1: It works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I think that's what they're gonna push.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess the Sun does the hardware, right?
Speaker 1: So yeah I just I feel like this acquisition gives them all these little pieces that now they can trivially integrate together Into some sort of unified platform that goes way beyond any Existing unified platform.
Speaker 1: Mmm For enterprise II stuff, you know, not the things that we do the things that companies do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz even look Microsoft They'll sell you SQL Server right and with is and such but they don't.
Speaker 0: they won't sell it to you on a machine.
Speaker 0: You have to buy a machine with like from Dell and get that stuff pre-installed and then configure it yourself or whatever.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: now Oracle can sell you a piece of hardware With Oracle running on it with everything already running already configured etc.
Speaker 0: That's sudden that no, I don't think anyone else sells that except IBM.
Speaker 1: Maybe yeah, IBM has similar offering.
Speaker 0: yeah, they'll sell you a piece of hardware with a web sphere on it and such.
Speaker 1: but yeah, I just Postgres is the only part I care about.
Speaker 0: Yeah And I if you are I'm also worried about some of the other Sun open source II stuff like, you know I don't use like the single sign-on but I use the virtual box and you know the single side and I'd like to use.
Speaker 0: You know, I don't know.
Speaker 0: It'd be nice if that stuff just sort of kept up.
Speaker 1: but like I you know I just used something called likewise and that gives you perfect single sign-on with any Linux Unix or whatever Through just Active Directory.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: So as long as you have an Active Directory, so but that's that's the client side.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Sun gives you the server.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: I know you gotta have the Microsoft Active Directory.
Speaker 0: This replaces the Microsoft Active Directory server.
Speaker 0: so you can run one of these and then have all your Macs Windows and Linux is Sign in.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, we can do that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, just you got it.
Speaker 1: You know client side stuff has to be done.
Speaker 1: Yeah that work Yep, but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: So do you have a thing?
Speaker 0: So check this out?
Speaker 0: You got a. there's a website geek stuff for you.
Speaker 0: Number four letter you will link will link and I've bought some stuff from there.
Speaker 0: I think I bought a happy hacking keyboard from there.
Speaker 0: They sell sort of that, you know, the Japanese sort of peripherals accessories stuff That's not so easy to get, you know sort of a think geek but not quite it's it's think geek but actual Like computer hardware you can use, you know.
Speaker 0: And on their website, I saw something the acrylic cowboy now acrylic cowboy.
Speaker 0: I think is a company.
Speaker 0: I just that makes a whole bunch of sounds vaguely like a sex toy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it does but it's not.
Speaker 0: What they do is they make computer cases that are made of acrylic which is kind of cool.
Speaker 0: But the acrylic cowboy like this specific one is way awesome.
Speaker 0: What it is is the flat P. It's just.
Speaker 0: it's a computer case, but it's not a box.
Speaker 0: it's just a flat piece of acrylic with some holes in it and You just screw your computer into and it supports ATX and micro ATX and your computer is open to the air.
Speaker 0: You've got the drives Mounted under the piece of plastic and you've got the motherboard and the power supply on top of the piece of plastic.
Speaker 0: and that's it.
Speaker 0: and You know your computer is open to the air.
Speaker 0: So I wouldn't you know, I wouldn't use this in like an environment where something might splash onto it.
Speaker 0: It's not so good.
Speaker 0: But let's say you're testing a whole bunch of computer parts or You know something along those lines.
Speaker 0: or you just got a new computer and you want to sort of make sure all the parts work.
Speaker 0: And without having to put it into a case, this is totally awesome and totally useful and it's only what like 7,500 yen.
Speaker 1: I think it's basically free 7,500 yen's.
Speaker 0: I think it's $75.
Speaker 0: That's that's like a hoji.
Speaker 1: Yeah, $75 is still is still it's not free, right?
Speaker 0: But yeah, I mean if you're considering I paid $150 for my case, which is still suboptimal and that's the other thing right?
Speaker 0: It's like I keep you know Like you keep like a computer case around cuz like what if I get some computer parts?
Speaker 0: To test them out.
Speaker 0: with this you can get one of these.
Speaker 0: it takes up almost no space and you can just get rid of All your junky computer cases.
Speaker 0: just have one of these guys.
Speaker 0: So Scott Johnson, you know, I know that you're most of your computer stuff is like old and sort of the idea is to you know Not buy new stuff, but it's probably worth it to get this acrylic cowboy At least one of them.
Speaker 1: just yeah, you know one computer at a time testing all the components.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just get one of them put like a you know Good drives under it and then put a motherboard.
Speaker 0: You
Speaker 1: know what I would do if I worked in like a computer donation place or anywhere where I dealt with a lot of old Computers, I'd have one of those for every basic like motherboard Layout like every you know socket a whatever DDRM whatever and I'd have each one just exist as a tester of RAM and CPUs and peripherals.
Speaker 0: These are also really good right if you want to do like teach some computer hardware stuff to people You know teach people how to put computers together.
Speaker 0: It'd be way easier to get like You know acrylic cowboys around the room then to like actually have people with like these cases going on You know with dealing with the mounting brackets and all that other bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, so this is actually.
Speaker 0: this is a pretty awesome thing right here.
Speaker 0: And when I get a job again I might just buy one.
Speaker 1: So, uh real quick you can just watch these videos.
Speaker 1: But you know, we talked a lot on Tuesday or at least we used to about the angry video game nerd And he's a really cool guy.
Speaker 1: He's really into film his whole life and he's really talented.
Speaker 1: He started doing these videos a long time ago about bad old video games.
Speaker 1: So the Tuesday geek nice people all know about him, but Monday people might not.
Speaker 1: I know There's people who are only into one or two things and they don't listen to all of the the fullness of what we have to offer.
Speaker 1: but He independent of being the angry video game nerd is like one of the biggest film buff guys I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: Well, he's not.
Speaker 0: he's pretty vague, but he's not the biggest I seen.
Speaker 1: well, he's one of the biggest I've seen.
Speaker 0: You know what he has is actually he's the biggest I've seen.
Speaker 1: that's not stupid and pretentious Uh-huh, but he did this great series of two videos Reviewing Star Wars.
Speaker 1: now that might seem pointless.
Speaker 1: I mean, we've all seen Star Wars a million times.
Speaker 1: They're for.
Speaker 1: Star Wars has possibly been reviewed and discussed more than any movie ever, especially among geeks, but It amazed me that he was able to make these videos where all he does is review Star Wars from his own personal perspective And not only enlighten me but informed me there were some things I did not realize that he pointed out.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I mean there are some things I did realize.
Speaker 0: it's some things I forgot and then were reminded of.
Speaker 0: but yeah He's there's some a lot of good stuff going on.
Speaker 0: He.
Speaker 1: all he did was remind me one how much I love those movies and to how bad the Phantom Menace really was.
Speaker 1: Because he always think maybe it wasn't that bad.
Speaker 1: I didn't see it through the eyes of a kid.
Speaker 1: I saw it later.
Speaker 1: No that movie sucks.
Speaker 1: that movie is awful, it's pretty bad.
Speaker 0: Phantom Edit not so bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah Phantom Ed, it's been just sort of coming to my mind a lot lately.
Speaker 1: Well because it illustrates everything that's wrong with intellectual property laws today and everything that was wrong with episode one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Phantom Menace, okay.
Speaker 1: So this weekend as I kept pointing out we went to we attended kind of suddenly open everything, New York City 2009 which was held in the UNICEF building, you know at the UN.
Speaker 1: it took us a little while to find the UNICEF building.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got to see a cool UN security guard with his awesome dog sniffing for bombs.
Speaker 1: We found it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he helped us out.
Speaker 0: He was cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yeah, basically open everything.
Speaker 0: It was sort of like this conference, you know, it's sort of.
Speaker 0: they ran it like a bar camp right and just quickly Basically O'Reilly, you know of O'Reilly books.
Speaker 0: He ran a thing called Alright food camp, which is friends of O'Reilly camp, right and it was sort of a tech conference But it was like invitation only.
Speaker 0: so, you know someone else decided.
Speaker 0: Hey, let's run bar camp, you know food bar quucks, right?
Speaker 0: So bar camp was just anyone can show up we don't even have a freaking schedule right.
Speaker 0: and then what we do is at the beginning everyone gets together and We make the schedule and if you want to say you want to have a session You make a session.
Speaker 0: and if you don't want, you know if you want to just go you can go to whatever session you want and You know you.
Speaker 0: if you you know, you just you're supposed to move around to whatever, you know Move your feet to wherever is, you know best for you to be and it's totally.
Speaker 0: it's like an open Convention right?
Speaker 0: Imagine if you got to an anime convention and they didn't have a schedule and everyone just got together and was like You know, let's watch this at nine o'clock.
Speaker 0: All right Yeah, and then people who wanted to watch that at nine o'clock went and watched it.
Speaker 0: That's that's what a bar camp is Of course the anime con.
Speaker 1: it would just devolve into 400 fortune.
Speaker 0: There's too many people at an anime con for it to for it to work, right?
Speaker 0: But anyway at a technology booth bar camp was specifically technology related, you know It's all like open-source people talking about code and and you know hardware tech stuff.
Speaker 0: Open everything was about open everything, you know, I mean most of the people.
Speaker 0: they were technologically inclined.
Speaker 0: But there are also many people who are artistically inclined, you know open Movies open books Creative Commons podcast, you know everything that is open whether it is Technology or art or other information or otherwise, I mean there was even open relationships, which was kind of fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So it was basically anything that is open was going on here and they ran it like a bar camp where you know You make the schedule when you get there and everyone's hanging out and chillin.
Speaker 1: Yep, so we decided to go kind of out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: We didn't really know what to expect and we're not doing this.
Speaker 1: You know that we're both going out of town kind of shortly.
Speaker 1: Like I still haven't packed for my tomorrow flight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but We're kind of just gonna give you our perspective.
Speaker 1: and how much fun like what we did and our fun.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna do this kind of objective press thing.
Speaker 0: Not as we didn't really attend as press.
Speaker 1: we attended as people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there were actually people from the Wikimedia Foundation.
Speaker 0: I think that we're documenting.
Speaker 1: if you want objective press go go find the Wikimedia stuff that they filmed and the inner like.
Speaker 1: they will Have all the kind of legitimate information.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's also an open an open everything NYC wiki that has info on it.
Speaker 0: people were documenting like all the different talks and stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've actually got to go back in and add to that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's missing a lot, right?
Speaker 0: But anyway, so we get there and first they have like this little open e bit right and the guy who ran the thing talked a little bit and Then the lady from UNICEF talked and she was pretty cool.
Speaker 0: and then this dude Skylar something talked and he was awesome.
Speaker 0: He was really awesome.
Speaker 0: The guy was like so insightful about like the history and of all an evolution of like web Applications.
Speaker 0: and he ran he runs like a consultancy in Brooklyn or something like something LLC, right?
Speaker 0: But apparently he worked with UNICEF to make like this rapid SMS thing Which is basically a web application with an SMS interface.
Speaker 0: So that and basically they they deploy it to places you know that need help.
Speaker 1: and basically what the main thing he pointed out with it isn't always obvious to people is that Africa in Particular does not have an internet infrastructure like we do.
Speaker 1: and I mean they have internet I mean you get Nigerian spam, but they don't have the infrastructure to where basically SMS and cell service Covers most of the continent.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's crappy old cell service, but you know, it works.
Speaker 1: but you know We have all these solutions for disaster relief and you know tracking information in the civil not in the like Industrialized world.
Speaker 1: that just the infrastructure we take for granted and our solutions kind of rely on that.
Speaker 1: But you really need to look at what already exists in the poor places in Africa to figure out how to help these people and how to build infrastructure.
Speaker 1: so SMS, you know text messages on cell phones are The most reliable most pervasive infrastructure there.
Speaker 1: and he talked about how why don't we use that to help and why don't we use this to coordinate?
Speaker 1: and It's been successful to do an amazing degree and his talk was amazing And actually the slideshow he used is available on the website now.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, I mean it's so.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of awesome stuff going on with rapid SMS.
Speaker 0: It's worth your time to to check it out.
Speaker 0: one thing though I sort of sort of fully realized while he was talking was you know Like the United States and the United States what we're sort of doing here is you know We're building things when we want more right.
Speaker 0: we build things to be bigger and to have more right.
Speaker 0: But you know what hackers and have always been about sort of is doing more with less getting the most out of the littlest Bit, so it's sort of like in Africa, even though they have less in general It's like people are all finding ways to do more with that less and I feel like at some point Right us doing less with more and then doing more with less.
Speaker 0: if it keeps progressing eventually We'll both have the same amount.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: they'll have the same amount with less and we'll have the same amount with more.
Speaker 0: But if we combine the two we'll be able to do more with less, of course Yes, I think there needs to be a lot more work on doing more with less.
Speaker 1: But I guess the whole gist of this conference was and he the guy who ran it Britain gave a really John Britton.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's.
Speaker 1: he summed it up very simply that Open everything is not like.
Speaker 1: you should read that as an imperative statement.
Speaker 1: open everything that in general Opening things up will always solve more problems than it will create as opposed to closing everything And that when in doubt or when there's you know, all things being equal You should have things open and you should work on things openly and collaborate openly and solve problems together in an open manner.
Speaker 0: Yeah as opposed to you know I mean because it's it can go two ways.
Speaker 0: You can go open everything as in we're going to talk about all the things that are open like open source open creative commons Right, or I can say hey rim Yeah, you go and open everything.
Speaker 0: go right now.
Speaker 0: Go open it go like a verb a command And that's that's was like ah the tricky dual meaning.
Speaker 1: we are so smart Yep, and that was the kind of focus and all these initial speeches were you know.
Speaker 1: Hey, look at all the things we did because rapid SMS and all this stuff.
Speaker 1: It's all open source software.
Speaker 1: It has to be.
Speaker 0: it's just how well it's good.
Speaker 0: How else could you get out and these people with no money but getting volunteers and people together and just openly solving problems?
Speaker 1: and they solve the problem of how do you track the distribution of DDT laced bed nets prevent malaria in Africa?
Speaker 1: and the answer was have people who are tracking them.
Speaker 1: Just you send text messages back to a database.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like delivered three bed nets text, you know delivered five text.
Speaker 0: This house doesn't have one.
Speaker 0: send more text, you know, and then people somewhere else know what to do.
Speaker 0: you know you think they also.
Speaker 0: another cool one was the testing of kids for malnutrition malnutrition and they found that like the the like the circumference of your upper arm was like Directly related to malnutrition.
Speaker 0: So they made a little measuring device that had red yellow and green and you would just wrap it around a kid's arm.
Speaker 0: See what the color, you know, what number it showed up on what the color was, you know and sent a text message.
Speaker 0: Kid in such-and-such village, you know Number 100 yellow and then they would message you back like, you know Cuz you don't have a doctor going to the village right a normal person.
Speaker 0: They would just you know get a message like, you know, give emergency rations.
Speaker 1: Okay, and it was all interlinked with the database.
Speaker 1: So the idea was that an untrained person All they need to be trained to do is send a text message and wrap a bracelet around a kid's arm.
Speaker 1: Yep, and then not only would they get instructions back But now the database can immediately for example say it determines, you know A percentage of children in this particular village are severely malnourished.
Speaker 1: now They know all right We need to send food aid to this village immediately and it gets there as fast as it can get there and you can you can.
Speaker 0: It's like imagine if you got a big boat full of food.
Speaker 0: You got all these people around the world gave charity.
Speaker 0: You got a whole boat full of food.
Speaker 0: Somali pirates didn't get you you land, right?
Speaker 0: Okay, how much food do we send?
Speaker 0: where?
Speaker 0: It's not like.
Speaker 0: you know, the growth with his grocery stores everywhere sending in orders.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's it's difficult to figure out where to send and how much to send where but anyway We're.
Speaker 1: I don't want to get because we could do a whole show just about this.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I really want to try to get this guy on geek nights.
Speaker 1: I'd love to talk to him.
Speaker 0: He was really great.
Speaker 0: So then, you know, he sort of made the schedule and we started going a few sessions with this idea in mind.
Speaker 1: everyone put up their little index card of what you wanted to talk about and We had this kind of group discussions and some of them were more like lectures and some of them were more like open Discussions.
Speaker 1: some of them were just you know, a question was posed and everyone brought their answers to the table.
Speaker 0: They're very they're a lot.
Speaker 0: They're very much more discussion II than panel II, you know When you go to like an anime convention It's a panel.
Speaker 0: the people at the top talk the people sitting there shut up and then or they you know But they also go woo and then at the end you ask some questions.
Speaker 0: maybe right?
Speaker 0: This is like, you know someone You know who put up the index card starts the discussion and then people start talking.
Speaker 1: It was very much like a salon in the classic sense Not not like a hair salon.
Speaker 1: If you don't know what I mean Wikipedia will tell you one thing I feel bad about.
Speaker 0: the very first one I went to was some guy was like write code now That's what you put on a card.
Speaker 1: Oh, and he didn't Was wearing an EFF shirt.
Speaker 1: Oh that guy was cool.
Speaker 0: He was he was a cool, dude It was weird cuz it was like you could tell who was cool and who wasn't cool.
Speaker 1: I will say this right now Almost everyone there.
Speaker 0: It was like 99% of the people were cool and Well, I have nothing really bad to say about anyone.
Speaker 1: I met there except for one person.
Speaker 1: We're going to talk about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're saving him for the end here.
Speaker 0: We are gonna save him.
Speaker 0: But yeah, he was you know, we tried to figure out like something to code, you know Cuz he had apparently at PyCon he had coded something cool, but it just didn't happen.
Speaker 0: I sort of felt bad that it didn't happen.
Speaker 1: But everyone was more in a discussion mode at this point this year.
Speaker 1: Luckily the result of all this at the end we all talked and got together and John Britton and everyone we realized that we can definitely make this a Recurring real thing in New York City.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah for sure We might not get the same turnout on a more regular basis because we have more meetings You get less people at each, but I think it definitely would get enough critical mass to be something worthwhile.
Speaker 1: Yes, but we're gonna talk about all these details later.
Speaker 1: I mean We're just from our perspective.
Speaker 1: We showed up not knowing what to expect.
Speaker 1: we get there You know at the early time and almost no one was there yet.
Speaker 1: It was all just the organizers and one of the keynote speakers was sitting there.
Speaker 1: So we all kind of sat around with the laptops chatting meeting people and just kind of hanging out and relaxing.
Speaker 1: We met one of the keynote speakers right away.
Speaker 0: Robert Steele you want to talk about him though?
Speaker 1: Uh, all I will say is that met him He was sitting there and he seemed really cool at first and he was gonna talk about open-source intelligence And I was excited about that.
Speaker 0: Well read read the description from the like, you know, the the.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah So open-source intelligence, oh, I lost my thing Robert David Steele.
Speaker 1: Robert David Steele the foremost proponent for open-source intelligence OSI and OS int and public intelligence in the public interest will introduce quote the other open source in combination free open source software and OS in empower the public as never before information asymmetries and data Pathologies that have been used to concentrate wealth and perpetuate poverty disease and the externalization of environmental costs as well as to promote wars That benefit the few with the expense of the many will be explained.
Speaker 1: Each person will receive a book yada yada yada and it seems like the whole idea here.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of.
Speaker 0: it says the guy's like a former spy, right?
Speaker 1: Yes It's like an actual real-deal spy is a former US spy co-founder of the US Marine Corps Intelligence Center and CEO of open-source Solutions Network as well as a pro bono CEO and angel founder of the earth intelligence network And there's a lot of charity and stuff.
Speaker 0: It's like this.
Speaker 0: this totally from the description it's like man is awesome.
Speaker 0: this spy a real spy is gonna talk about Open-source intelligence, which is like, ooh, that's that's something I'd want to see.
Speaker 1: and the guy is sitting right there like he's just sitting at the table and I'm sitting at the table Scott's sitting at the table and John Britton is going around and They're like setting up the tables and all the stuff.
Speaker 1: and he seemed really cool And he said something and I said something.
Speaker 1: Scott said something.
Speaker 1: We're kind of having this, you know get to know each other conversation and I was really looking forward to his talk and then Like things went downhill so fast.
Speaker 1: I guess what I want to say is that Open everything.
Speaker 1: New York City was an amazing event.
Speaker 1: We're going to talk about the like some of the specifics in Great detail in future show and things that we discussed and learn.
Speaker 0: there will be.
Speaker 0: you know things that we will you know Effect our opinions and discussions for quite some time.
Speaker 1: the event was amazing, but we're not really covering the event.
Speaker 1: We're covering our experience at the event and Robert Steele in the middle of talking about You know politics and the world and so far seemed pretty intelligent In out of nowhere says and I quote.
Speaker 1: but as we all agree Obama He said.
Speaker 1: I hope everyone realizes by now that Obama is just bush in blackface and we're like and everyone Everyone at this table kind of looks at each other.
Speaker 1: Like did he just say what I think he just said?
Speaker 0: It's like what the fuck?
Speaker 0: and uh, he went on this tag for a little while Yeah, and basically it turned out he was one of those people where it's like.
Speaker 0: no matter what you say Like if I would have said, you know How as the baseball team doing he would have kept going on what he was talking about.
Speaker 0: He would have responded like yeah baseball team open intelligence Bush blah.
Speaker 0: It's like what.
Speaker 0: that has nothing to do with what I just said and it's like one of those people who?
Speaker 0: Says the thing that is their thing and can't say anything about anything else, but then I was thinking all right Maybe he's just crass.
Speaker 1: Maybe this point was just that you know left right the two-party system the same thing always happens in the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is I'm gonna I'm gonna let that go.
Speaker 0: you let.
Speaker 0: that guy didn't let it go.
Speaker 0: That was already.
Speaker 1: I'm going to let that go and not antagonize him.
Speaker 0: and just oh dad I didn't want to antagonize him cuz I I was pretty sure it's crazy and I Attagonizing crazy person is a waste of.
Speaker 1: I was going to let him continue and see if he continued to dig the hole that he Started digging.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, he dug.
Speaker 1: 30 seconds later the the.
Speaker 1: this is an exact quote.
Speaker 1: This will affect poor people even white people Uh-huh, two racist things out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, and it good God.
Speaker 1: and this was one of the keynote speakers and even John Britain was kind of like yeah.
Speaker 0: Well afterwards John Britain told us, you know Yeah, I wasn't sure if I actually wanted to let this guy talk is apparently the guy had talked Like hope.
Speaker 0: right and hope is hackers on planet earth, which is sort of like the Def Con of New York.
Speaker 0: It's run by you know, it's sort of spawned out of 2600 magazine and such, you know, it's hope is is very respectable.
Speaker 0: But apparently they let this guy talk at hope and You know and John Britain had seen him there and apparently he swore a lot.
Speaker 0: so John was Apprehensive about letting him speak at open everything, but he did let him.
Speaker 0: and Yeah, good God.
Speaker 1: but we that aside every more people start showing up.
Speaker 1: Alex and Jess our friends show up and the group start Farming and coalescing.
Speaker 1: we went to that open talk and I was real inspired by the UNICEF lady.
Speaker 1: Did you just like quit my job and work for UNICEF?
Speaker 1: Maybe I will maybe I'll email them up like It suddenly reminded me of how much I want to do stuff like that and how good of an organization UNICEF is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're pretty good.
Speaker 1: It's one of those things where everyone knows UNICEF does good works.
Speaker 0: But when you when you start to realize specifically what they do it Well, I mean you compare them to like some of the you know Not every charitable organization is equals like you.
Speaker 0: look around and it's like, you know, some of them are like, you know Salvation Army and then some of them are like goodwill and then some of them are like UNICEF.
Speaker 1: it's like oh one is clearly not like the other but we Kind of take our leave of Robert Steele and avoid him for the rest of the day.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes very much So.
Speaker 1: and then you know, we're the first round of talks and which one did you sit in on?
Speaker 0: I went to write code now.
Speaker 0: then we did
Speaker 1: our
Speaker 0: Open is inevitable
Speaker 1: in the first round because I went to like open education and it was this like 17 year old high school punk Who was obviously really really nervous but had an interesting idea and the discussion that came out of that was really cool and the.
Speaker 1: This is the amazingness about these sorts of events.
Speaker 1: This 17 year old gives a brief talk about how like how to make high school curriculum open such that we can spread in spread education to people that can't afford it and spread it around the world and kind of give people more access to education.
Speaker 1: and From that and over the course of the day a Bunch of people kept like going to the same talk over and over again.
Speaker 1: They kind of monopolized the one table all day and they ended up forming an organization.
Speaker 1: I forget what they called it and they're going to try to make this a real organization and try to influence curriculum in New York.
Speaker 1: now Yeah, so something came out of it.
Speaker 1: It was pretty cool.
Speaker 0: That's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: I didn't notice that because I was that was separate from me Yep, but then you know after that Scott and I wanted to do something called openness is inevitable No, and we gave a little.
Speaker 1: we gave a little talk and then it turned into a discussion and I linked in the forums.
Speaker 1: They're actually surprisingly a lot of pictures of that discussion as opposed to many of the other discussions.
Speaker 1: Okay, like if you look at the flicker, there are a lot of pictures of that particular talk around that particular table Mm-hmm, but like in that discussion, you know certain analogies kept.
Speaker 0: people kept using analogies a lot.
Speaker 0: one analogy involved wizards.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we talked about how wizard like people who understand internet technology and code are fast becoming wizards And an open society will only make them more like it unto wizards.
Speaker 0: So this and our current society, you know, the law cannot contain, you know, it doesn't account for people with magical powers You know, so this one of the guys was really cool and was at this talk thought is really really good idea.
Speaker 1: So he's scheduled later in the day who will wash the wizards.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, I think that was part of that thing that was actually good because I have a feeling that at bar camps like the schedule Gets filled right away.
Speaker 0: And I think it was cool that we didn't fill the whole schedule immediately that we were able to You know have empty slots and those things that we discussed right away.
Speaker 0: We were able to add new sessions to sort of continue those later, you know, which sort of made it.
Speaker 0: You know, it would have been nicer if like, you know, we could rearrange the schedule like, you know Some things down to sort of keep things together, you know Continue one session longer as opposed to end it and started again later.
Speaker 1: the suggestion I made that people seem to be on board with was that Instead of having just this straight-up grade with all these tables being equal We need like four different tracks One of which is like the rapid-fire 30 40 minute talks 30 40 minute talks and one of them is the like lecture hall.
Speaker 1: You want to do a straight-up lecture and one of them is the workshop where everyone's gonna like code something and we need to kind Of differentiate the different kinds of talks and kinds of things people want to do.
Speaker 0: Yep, also, I think it'd be cool if instead of break we broke it down by sessions.
Speaker 0: They always said these are 40 minutes.
Speaker 0: We need to break it down by time, you know.
Speaker 0: So if like I want to give a one-hour lecture, so I put in one hours of lecture another guy needs like a five-minute lecture.
Speaker 0: So put in a five minute, you know and just schedule it at a time.
Speaker 0: That's you know.
Speaker 0: open Why you know, there's no reason that we should have this, you know structured, you know blocks, you know We could have the the times just lined up, but it in the end it worked really well and I went to a lot of amazing talks.
Speaker 1: and I Look, I I was confronted with contrary opinions that were intelligently formed something that does not happen often on the internet.
Speaker 1: no, it does not and We're gonna have to spend a lot of shows talking about all the details of that.
Speaker 0: but I think mostly what it was right is we went to a place that had People who are smart like us and know about and care about the same things.
Speaker 0: We know and care about but they're strangers.
Speaker 0: They're people we hadn't met before and thus they had different ideas than the same old ideas.
Speaker 0: They keep circling around when you stay, you know in the same communities Like you stay in the front row crew you stay in the geek nights forum community You don't really you know, you stay on slash dot you don't get you know new ideas Coming into the communities like that so often.
Speaker 0: But if you sit down with like ten complete strangers and talk about you all have this common interest.
Speaker 0: You don't know each other.
Speaker 1: all these strangers were all on the same basic level.
Speaker 1: everyone already understood.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying We're all we're all on the same page But we all had different ideas because we were from separate places and thus, you know There's a lot of valuable things that go on.
Speaker 1: so then cross pollination They provided a free pizza lunch and everyone kind of went outside and it was so nice.
Speaker 0: The weather was the greatest weather.
Speaker 0: It should just be that weather every day.
Speaker 1: It was so nice that we proposed for the second half.
Speaker 1: Why don't we have the rest of these discussions outside?
Speaker 1: and everyone was like, yes There were a little.
Speaker 0: there are a few problems with the outside such as wind blowing things around and buses Buses and but the weather was so great that those slight inconveniences didn't matter.
Speaker 1: But we got a big lunch and everyone kind of mingled and talked and exchanged business cards and it was super awesome.
Speaker 1: And then we all went back in and Robert Steele got to give his talk.
Speaker 0: and I want to point I think we went outside after Robert Steele.
Speaker 0: did we?
Speaker 1: yeah, I don't recall.
Speaker 0: It was Robert Steele then outside.
Speaker 1: I think it's hard to say.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure we ate then we went inside had Robert Steele and then we had the lectures outside.
Speaker 0: I Feel like we went down to Robert Steele then went outside and then the pizza showed up and then I don't remember.
Speaker 1: Regardless Robert Steele, I'm gonna be open.
Speaker 0: This guy is crazy Like he's a crazy crazy conspiracy nut job.
Speaker 1: We all go back in and we have this we sit around in the big lecture hall where the UNICEF lady talked And Shayler talked and Skyler Skyler.
Speaker 1: It's spelled not like Skyler.
Speaker 0: I know right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it messes me up.
Speaker 0: It does and He says blackface again within 30 seconds and no sentence He said had anything to do with any other sentence He said and his graphic design of his slides were that crazy conspiracy.
Speaker 0: graphic design
Speaker 1: some sort of research It might have already been done needs to be put into the fact that Conspiracy theory crazy people all use the same graphic design those Really dense graphs that don't make any sense at all and all these lines like pointing at each other and all these arbitrary Distinctions between two different things that don't make sense.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's something with a paranoid mind, but Basically, we're sitting in the front row, you know front row crew and I have my laptop and I'm furiously taking notes as to how Crazy, this guy is.
Speaker 1: and periodically Scott will I grab my hand and like type something on my laptop At one point because he didn't want to say anything out loud, you know And we didn't want to.
Speaker 0: we didn't want to like antagonize him because he ever you're this crazy guy.
Speaker 0: He's already crazy.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, it's really.
Speaker 0: there's nothing I could say to him.
Speaker 0: That would be productive in any way.
Speaker 0: All it would do is make him crazier and go.
Speaker 0: it would just make everything bad and I don't want to do that There's.
Speaker 0: no it's like I just I just want him to go away and be quiet and that be the end of it.
Speaker 0: You know, I buy this crazy person away.
Speaker 0: So he didn't want to say anything.
Speaker 0: We don't ask a question.
Speaker 0: We don't want to make a comment.
Speaker 0: We didn't want to start a debate.
Speaker 1: So after his third crazy graph came up.
Speaker 1: I type time cube.
Speaker 1: I'm sure you all know how.
Speaker 1: time cube and I showed to Scott and Scott's like, oh my god.
Speaker 1: We showed to Alex and Jess and we're all on the same page there.
Speaker 1: We realize Independently of us in the other like section of seats Someone else had a piece of paper who's taking notes and he just wrote time cube on it and held it up for everyone behind it.
Speaker 1: So the whole time we're thinking like praying is Everyone on the same page?
Speaker 0: because I mean we're sitting there and we talked to each other and we're like.
Speaker 0: I hope Everyone else in this room thinks he's a crazy conspiracy nut.
Speaker 0: right like no one's like I'm one cuz there are you know, crazy conspiracy people.
Speaker 0: someone who is seemingly intelligent might be a conspiracy nut.
Speaker 1: No one's challenging him.
Speaker 1: Everyone's just kind of letting him talk.
Speaker 1: People are laughing politely when he you know says something funny.
Speaker 1: He said a few funny things.
Speaker 0: He did he did.
Speaker 1: he had a few couple funny jokes, but uh At the end we're all walking out.
Speaker 1: Of course, and I remember I walk out and I turned to the cool lady.
Speaker 1: I forget everyone's names.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry, but cool girl like number four Yep, and I look at her and she looks at me and I was like are we on the same page?
Speaker 1: And she says I think we're on the same page.
Speaker 1: and then she turns the guy she was walking out with and he's like That guy was crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and like there was there was one guy there.
Speaker 0: He was cool, but he definitely had one of those.
Speaker 0: You know Situations, you know, what's it called?
Speaker 0: Like one of the syndromes?
Speaker 0: I don't know which one but didn't matter.
Speaker 0: and you know Even that guy.
Speaker 0: he was like nothing that guy said Made any sense whatsoever.
Speaker 1: the best the dude who was taking notes specifically for the wiki is Standing there after with his laptop and he's holding it and he's looking at it and he looks up and just kind of says to The room there is no possible way to summarize anything that that man said.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Mean I was like.
Speaker 0: there are people that I sort of got to know a little bit, you know.
Speaker 0: But you know you hang out with someone for a few hours, you know and people stand out.
Speaker 0: So I like.
Speaker 0: I sort of looked at everyone who I sort of you know came to recognize over the course of the morning and I was like I was like mmm and they were like.
Speaker 0: I'm sort of like.
Speaker 0: I like are we cool?
Speaker 0: He's like we're cool.
Speaker 0: Just try to make sure who's cool.
Speaker 1: But It was amazing Like to give you an example at one point like after the ninth crazy graph comes up I stopped writing crazy graph because I kept noting crazy graph crazy graph.
Speaker 1: eventually, you know, alright, there's no more.
Speaker 1: I can't even begin to describe these graphs, but he has the graph.
Speaker 1: that's talking about the differences between harmonized giving and And Organized giving.
Speaker 1: and there was a heart on one of them and like an ex on one of them and the lines were pointing past Each other and there was a pig and uh, but then he stops and he talks to me.
Speaker 1: He's up 9/11 and I put I'm like, huh?
Speaker 1: And I pull up his Wikipedia page and then the discussion.
Speaker 1: someone's like this guy is a crazy 9/11 conspiracy nut and I'm like Oh boy, here we go and he says and a sentence that in and of itself is relatively benign.
Speaker 1: in the Best case scenario the September 11th attacks and the 9/11 Commission were a gross oversight and gross negligence.
Speaker 0: No, yeah gross and confidence.
Speaker 0: I think he said and that that that's alright.
Speaker 0: That's about you know,
Speaker 1: and then in the span of 45 seconds he reminds us that Kennedy was murdered by the Cubans in revenge for the Bay of Pigs and this is documented by the way and that Martin Luther King was killed by an FBI sniper as we all know.
Speaker 1: and of course then Good guy Like he went off the often like he was already off the deep end and he found another deep end to go off the deeper.
Speaker 0: And that's like if you were already in the bottom of a swimming pool, right?
Speaker 0: But the swimming pool was right next to the the fault in the bottom of the ocean and there was a diving board Underwater.
Speaker 0: and he jumped on the underwater diving board and dove deeper under the water.
Speaker 1: and then he said and I quote World War three began in 1988 Uh-huh, and then that was.
Speaker 1: that was when Scott grabbed my laptop.
Speaker 1: He had something to type any types.
Speaker 1: I have to pee Because we stopped paying attention to this guy at this point.
Speaker 1: Yeah And the only other thing I really want to point out is that then he pulls out his beret for the earth rescue circle.
Speaker 0: That was funny though.
Speaker 1: It was a pretty cool beret, but oh my god.
Speaker 1: Yeah Oh my god, and of course one planet one God one way.
Speaker 1: He's kind of religious, too.
Speaker 0: Yeah anyway, the.
Speaker 0: The one thing though is I started to read his crazy book, which was free by the way I didn't even take a copy.
Speaker 0: rim took a cop.
Speaker 1: He gave us all a copy of his hardcover book.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay You know and I think that you know, of course, he's a crazy conspiracy nut, right?
Speaker 0: But there is sort of this one idea maybe buried that he's just Incapable of Communicating properly because he's crazy and that you know really is that you know right now.
Speaker 0: Intelligence in terms of you know government intelligence, right?
Speaker 0: It's all about like keeping secrets, right?
Speaker 0: Oh the CIA knows that.
Speaker 0: no one else knows.
Speaker 0: that way they can get ahead right in the in.
Speaker 0: You know the games the government's play.
Speaker 0: And he's saying really what you need is, you know, all the raw information is open, right?
Speaker 0: It's no longer about the secrets you have that someone else doesn't have.
Speaker 0: it's now about you know Your ability to analyze the information to collect it and aggregate it and analyze it and all that You know, he's like, you know in in one of the chapters in the book I read barely any of it but he talks about how like how come we haven't translated all these documents in Arabic and I don't know what documents he's talking about.
Speaker 0: he's probably crazy but It's true.
Speaker 0: It's like why haven't we translated everything?
Speaker 0: You know, it's we need to.
Speaker 0: you know, if we're gonna have open all this open information then Intelligence is no longer going to be about spying and uncovering secrets.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be about waiting in this big pool of you know information that everyone has access to and figuring it out and making the sense of it and creating the intelligence from that data.
Speaker 0: and you know, that's sort of right.
Speaker 0: and And Yeah, I don't know But he and all the other thing that he's sort of right about be still being crazy.
Speaker 0: Is that
Speaker 1: if
Speaker 0: all that raw data is completely open and you fight for it to be that way and it is that way Then that can somehow Restore the integrity of the government because you know people can say hey you're wrong because you know the government right now, right?
Speaker 0: Look, they come around and say oh we're doing this and they say we have to do this because of something secret We can't tell you.
Speaker 0: Well, if there are no secrets the government can't get away with that anymore.
Speaker 1: now I have one tiny hope that I'm I'm so sure is not the case, but it would be amazing If this guy were just nanny Kaufman, that would be amazing.
Speaker 1: Like if he were just pulling all of our legs.
Speaker 1: I know that's probably not the case, but it's almost definitely not the case.
Speaker 0: and look at how many books he's done and such he's This man Robert Steele.
Speaker 1: Do not let him speak at any event that you ever run because he's he will.
Speaker 1: he will talk about Speaking at your event as though you endorsed him.
Speaker 0: now here allow me to become a conspiracy nut myself for a mere moment.
Speaker 0: what if When this he was a CIA spy right or something like?
Speaker 1: what if he knew stuff?
Speaker 0: What if he knew stuff?
Speaker 0: and the CIA has a way of turning people into crazy conspiracy nuts where they will tell the truth But their minds are fucked up in some way to where they make crazy graphs and say things in a crazy way So no one believes them.
Speaker 0: See, I've explained his crazy conspiracy nuttiness with a further crazy conspiracy That I don't think it's true in any way.
Speaker 0: Cuz I'm not a crazy conspiracy nut, but do not let him talk.
Speaker 1: He is crazy.
Speaker 0: unless you want some epic lolz stay far away Yes, but the thing is he was well-meaning.
Speaker 1: that's the one thing we can say from the guy clearly Really cares about the world and really cares about people and wants to make the world a better place.
Speaker 0: And he's like.
Speaker 0: he doesn't want war he wants peace.
Speaker 0: He wants to you know help.
Speaker 1: he's just trying to make the world a better place with crazy graphs exactly.
Speaker 1: But after that and after everyone collectively went outside and went wow Wow This weather is great and that guy's crazy.
Speaker 1: Then we went back in we had our afternoon of sessions, and it was super awesome.
Speaker 1: And then we had the final talk Leslie Hawthorne who is pretty cool.
Speaker 1: She's the Google summer of code person.
Speaker 1: yep She talked.
Speaker 1: she gave a really short concise talk about how this kind of open source software Stuff can be used to make people respond to problems, and I don't really want to summarize our whole talk But it was really cool.
Speaker 1: She was really cool.
Speaker 0: Yep, and she didn't have any slides Which is kind of crazy cuz like we had the most slide II person you could ever have.
Speaker 1: I like his delivery I wanted and then someone who was anti slide.
Speaker 1: cuz we're so used to the TED talk like we're trying to make all of our panels be like TED talks you have like the few I'm not talking about I'm talking about steel was slide.
Speaker 1: I was talking about Rapid SMS.
Speaker 0: Skylar had good slides, but he had that rapid fire.
Speaker 1: slide slide slide slide slide slide slide slide Really makes this cool kind of narrative.
Speaker 0: yeah, it helps with the low attention span.
Speaker 1: also It's a different kind of talk.
Speaker 1: I think and I think they both have their place, but no Leslie was like you know what fucks lives Let's go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I do think Actually because I was talking to this cool guy who doesn't who runs the e-book company right and basically what he does is he takes He'll like take all the ebooks related to medicine put him together into an e-book library and sell it to doctors.
Speaker 0: Or he'll make an e-book law library and sell it to lawyers.
Speaker 0: And he says now you can have the law in the palm of your hand.
Speaker 0: You know it's sort of like a ha ha ha ha.
Speaker 0: You know So anyway what that guy was talking about was I sort of lost my train of thought a little bit here.
Speaker 0: Yeah He talked about how you know if you're learning right trying to learn something.
Speaker 0: if you read something Once you remember X percent.
Speaker 0: if you if you have something read to you you remember X percent.
Speaker 0: But if you read and have it read to you at the same time you remember like 80%.
Speaker 0: And I think what Schuyler did in his slideshow right by having the rapid-fire slides.
Speaker 0: It's like when he would list like you know four things.
Speaker 0: He had four slides with one word each and as he said them he showed the slides.
Speaker 0: It was like word slide word slide word slide.
Speaker 0: You get the reading to you and the reading of your own at the same time.
Speaker 0: for that 80% learning You know all right.
Speaker 1: We've gone on way too long.
Speaker 1: That's all right.
Speaker 0: We need a long show.
Speaker 0: if we're not gonna do shows the rest of the week We're gonna wrap this up.
Speaker 1: suffice it to say we will be talking about open everything and some of these specific Topics and talks that happened.
Speaker 1: in the future We're going to try to become a big part of this going forward because it was super awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we definitely need to make some more inroads into the the tech openness communities.
Speaker 1: Everyone there was super awesome.
Speaker 1: It was an amazing time There.
Speaker 1: the ideas that were tossed around were great.
Speaker 1: Everyone's really gung-ho to make the world a better place and afterward we all like totally hung out and while the after party had some trouble because the Proprietor of McFadden's bar is a luddite as far as I can tell yeah, I just failed at everything Ever.
Speaker 1: everyone I talked to Was super awesome and all of you out there who are probably listening to this because you got one of my flyers or met me Or we talked.
Speaker 1: I'm going to get in touch with all of you after I get back from Costa Rica.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'll probably email people when I get back from Florida and to all of you geek nights people when we In the future we are going to talk about these again, and we will give you dates.
Speaker 1: It is worth your while to come to open everything events, and they're not just in New York.
Speaker 1: They're all around the world.
Speaker 1: There's one in Hong Kong.
Speaker 1: There's one in Germany.
Speaker 0: There's one in like Omaha, Wisconsin, Nebraska somewhere in the middle of the country.
Speaker 0: I Forget go to the open everything website.
Speaker 1: Yes, and on that note.
Speaker 1: I'm going to pack for my trip.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go eat my barbecue burrito.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week Covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: if you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you Can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.