Speaker 0: It's Tuesday January 13th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk a bit about fallout 3.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So uh over the xmas holiday one of the things I did is I bought gifts for some people and I got Emily a copy of chrono trigger on the DS.
Speaker 0: It's weird how I didn't really have any desire to play that game again.
Speaker 0: I mean I played that game like 40 times.
Speaker 1: I didn't play it 40 times more like four times and mostly the only.
Speaker 0: I'll put it this way I play even though I knew there were zillion endings.
Speaker 1: the only one of the only reasons I was actually able to play it again was because of plus mode.
Speaker 1: yeah plus.
Speaker 0: well what I was about to say?
Speaker 0: I played through the whole game Maybe three or four times in my life one time when I was living alone and I had nothing to do and I had an emulator, but I Played plus mode 36 times.
Speaker 0: yeah plus mode because I would just go around like hey I'll go beat that boss.
Speaker 0: Just because it'll take me like five minutes to get there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's you know.
Speaker 1: I think that they should just have the option of just starting the game plus mode.
Speaker 1: That way you know you can get all the goodness without having you know the bet cuz chrono trigger.
Speaker 1: While it's probably what the best Japanese RPG game you have to beat the game as JRPG BS.
Speaker 0: You have to beat the game at least once the real way or else plus mode is just stupid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz then you just go into the bucket right away and win a game over in plus mode like WTF mate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you play in real mode then you just.
Speaker 0: one thing I can say that I didn't expect was Watching because we have another friend Jess who hadn't really played this game before.
Speaker 0: so I'm watching the two of them Play this game, and I'm seeing it again from those kind of virgin eyes.
Speaker 0: I mean I think back to the game, and I remember being good and awesome and enjoying it but Seeing someone else play it and starting to remember the sort of all the first like the first time I encountered certain things like I Think the iconic moment for me was when I got back from saving the girl in the past and I go to the courtroom thing and That guy walks out.
Speaker 0: that guy what?
Speaker 0: whose lunch I ate, and I remember thinking what the fuck.
Speaker 0: What's he doing here?
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: I can't believe it.
Speaker 1: damn it damn it damn it damn it.
Speaker 1: I can't believe eating.
Speaker 1: the lunch mattered.
Speaker 0: Ah, I can't believe it or uh, but you're still hungry.
Speaker 1: You're still hungry.
Speaker 1: How about that guy who raises you?
Speaker 0: Oh my god with the mode seven.
Speaker 1: yep I love that.
Speaker 1: also gato.
Speaker 0: He has metal joints.
Speaker 1: You put the gato song in.
Speaker 0: oh my god.
Speaker 0: I'll find it.
Speaker 0: I got it even though apparently I was.
Speaker 0: I was catching up on old fast karate and Apparently Dave downloaded the entire.
Speaker 0: I mean I downloaded the entire OC remix collection in like.
Speaker 0: So I haven't updated my OC remix collection since then.
Speaker 0: apparently he downloaded the current collection And he's going through every song trying to find the good ones.
Speaker 0: Apparently the ratio of good to bad has only decreased over time, huh?
Speaker 0: Duly noted.
Speaker 0: I'm giving up any plan.
Speaker 0: I'm open when he finishes.
Speaker 0: I can ask him for his complete perfect collection.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's not a bad idea.
Speaker 0: That's what I got to do.
Speaker 0: so godspeed David Riley.
Speaker 0: Godspeed alrighty.
Speaker 0: That's all I got.
Speaker 0: you can play any games other than I've been playing NS.
Speaker 1: I finished playing Fallout 3. no desire to play it anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I'm playing that alchemy flash game.
Speaker 0: Oh my god that alchemy flash game was like a breath of fresh air.
Speaker 1: It's a good game.
Speaker 0: It is even though it builds upon trends We've been seeing in gaming anyway, but it executes it better than many of those games have.
Speaker 1: it's a good game for learning the programming.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you yeah god if I was teaching like elementary or middle school kids about computers I would totally make them play this game in class.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Well really it's not gonna teach you a lot about some aspects of computing, but it will help you with things like You know Pipelining and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: It'll teach you about the logics.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it.
Speaker 1: I mean It's hard to think about it sort of as functions even though they're there, but yeah It doesn't.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: it's like there are functions here, but it's hard to see them unless you know.
Speaker 0: But ideas like race conditions are very apparent to even someone who's never heard of a race condition before.
Speaker 1: oh indeed They won't.
Speaker 1: they won't know to call it a race condition, but they will know.
Speaker 0: but they'll know what that thing is.
Speaker 1: I know throw in some weights Actually would probably help you with some quake scripting to play this game.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I'm done with quake scripting.
Speaker 0: I remember I wrote a function.
Speaker 1: wait wait wait wait wait wait wait.
Speaker 0: I wrote a function in quake that was just a loop of 20 weights.
Speaker 1: Well a lot of people do right is the fastest way to do it is you do You just type five weights real quick like we're right and then you call that weight five.
Speaker 1: And then you do like five weight fives and now you have 25 weight.
Speaker 0: yep I had all different.
Speaker 1: And then you could do 425 weights to get a hundred weight.
Speaker 0: you realize I had two different keys.
Speaker 0: One was bound to my low ping bastard offhand grenade script because it gave you offhand grenades and quick to a game Which famously did not have offhand grenades, but what game nowadays has offhand grenades?
Speaker 0: Nothing that's right, but back then it was famous.
Speaker 0: It was a big deal.
Speaker 1: I remember I think actually halo has offhand grenades.
Speaker 0: I remember like the first thing I heard about quake - like when my friends were all buzzing about it because we were all in the Clan communities back then and it was like oh my god quake - has a date and oh my god.
Speaker 0: No offhand grenades.
Speaker 0: But so I had the script that would give you offhand grenades And I had the low ping version.
Speaker 1: and the high ping version is basically switch weapon throw grenade switch weapon.
Speaker 0: Yes, because I there was a previous weapon Command and so I would use that to get back to whatever weapon I was using before.
Speaker 0: It was pretty elegant for someone in high school who had never really written anything other than Q basic.
Speaker 1: Yeah And you know that's a huge advantage.
Speaker 0: being able to push a button to throw a grenade while still using your other weapon Bonus points for giving it to an entire clan does making them dominate for a short while before other people also get it.
Speaker 0: But anyway, you got any.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: video game news.
Speaker 1: Oh Video game news.
Speaker 1: what's going on?
Speaker 1: Apparently, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Sony's losing money.
Speaker 1: Nintendo's making money even though I don't know what games that are coming out with.
Speaker 0: well You know what?
Speaker 0: They're making money off of Wii Sports sold more than Mario Brothers.
Speaker 0: Well Super Mario Brothers Actually, there's a.
Speaker 1: there's an EA game coming out for the DS called like Henry has worth or something like that.
Speaker 1: It's a little puzzle II platform run gonna.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna take a look at that when it comes out.
Speaker 1: in the meantime This is a clothing store on the corner from my work the Uniqlo or whatever.
Speaker 1: It's basically Japanese Old Navy, but you know it in you know, it's like there's probably like one Old Navy in Japan.
Speaker 1: So there's one Uniqlo and I don't know there might be more than one Uniqlo in the u.s.
Speaker 1: But there's one in New York City.
Speaker 1: It's probably not one near your house And they tend to have you know nerdy clothes because even though it's Japanese Old Navy, right?
Speaker 1: I mean if you walk into Old Navy or I guess like Kohl's or whatever in the u.s You'll see clothes that have like u.s.
Speaker 1: You know properties licensed properties on them like you can go get like Superman underwear for your kid or whatever, right?
Speaker 1: So of course and yes for your kid in quotes, right?
Speaker 1: so and you know a Japanese Old Navy you're gonna see like they had all sorts of like Tezuka style and shirts and Gogo 13 shirts, you know, and this is sort of for us.
Speaker 1: It's like all man's hot merchandise Japanese licensed properties on them, but for them is class for them.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, there's some licensed property shirts Just like the way you would look at like like a spongebob shirt at Kohl's.
Speaker 0: But nothing's classier than wearing some good jeans a nice gray blazer and a Duke Togo face right underneath that business.
Speaker 1: So, you know, they did all the manga style in a while back, you know which I guess they do.
Speaker 1: I always see people have the.
Speaker 1: the bags from the store always have like Going to guy characters on them, but now apparently in the spring It's gonna be all video game actions gonna be Sega Capcom Taito Sony Bandai Hudson.
Speaker 0: We've got to get in on this.
Speaker 1: We're looking at some Sonic the Hedgehog.
Speaker 1: We're looking at some Megaman looking some breakout Prap of the rapper.
Speaker 0: I'm glad we're seeing like the biggest increase in my wardrobe the biggest purging and then rebuilding that I've had Since I got to RIT.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we're gonna have to go, you know, we'll head over there and like March or whatever Shopping.
Speaker 0: Oh my gosh shoes.
Speaker 1: Yeah a little little Megaman shirt going on But a high-class Megaman shirt not some crap ass Megaman.
Speaker 0: it's always like with anime stuff and even a lot of video game stuff the difference between the Big square print of the red dragon versus the classy stylized red dragon or the big square print of all.
Speaker 1: Strange how you can have like, you know, you can have like a like a shirt has Megaman on it But then you have a shirt with Megaman on it.
Speaker 1: That is like actually not lame and it's hard to tell with the differences.
Speaker 0: But the extra part is if you go too far into the lame spectrum It gets into that kind of hipster retro or ironic territory and suddenly it's cool again Like if it's.
Speaker 0: if it's a really really lame shirt, it's totally awesome Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: So I'm not sure where the line is because you know, there's a bottom of that trend.
Speaker 0: There's a point at which it's the worst possible shirt and then and then it becomes iconic like that red dragon shirt.
Speaker 0: You all know which one I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: We should find a picture of that red dragon shirt.
Speaker 1: be like if you are wearing this shirt You are that guy.
Speaker 1: if You own this shirt.
Speaker 1: You are that guy.
Speaker 0: do not wear this shirt, but a lot of us owned that shirt.
Speaker 1: I oh I never owned that shirt Although I did see it.
Speaker 0: I did in fact own that shirt in middle school, but I did not wear it that often.
Speaker 0: That often.
Speaker 0: well the thing is when I was in middle school in the Midwest The fashion was the thing that guys were allowed to wear was somewhat raggedy jeans Or corduroys again with cords
Speaker 1: and red dragon shirts some
Speaker 0: sort of dumb t-shirt Like a lot of people would wear like their dare t-shirt But totally ironically and then a flannel shirt over that unbuttoned.
Speaker 0: That was like the prescribed style.
Speaker 0: No one was allowed to deviate from what.
Speaker 0: if you did I don't know but ever.
Speaker 0: that's what everyone dressed like.
Speaker 0: it was middle school.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I dressed like that.
Speaker 0: I'd alternate between the red dragon and the dare and the nondescript black.
Speaker 1: Anyway Yeah, this is pretty.
Speaker 1: this is pretty good news right here.
Speaker 1: I got a. I don't know.
Speaker 1: I got a lot of t-shirts and it's like the oldest ones.
Speaker 1: I can't get rid of for whatever reason some of the you know and it's like Now.
Speaker 1: it's like I've got like three tiers of t-shirt And it's like I keep adding a newer better tier and then somehow the slightly the what used to be the top tier moves down.
Speaker 1: But I can't get rid of any of them.
Speaker 0: The worst thing is I have the product.
Speaker 0: I gotta buy new socks like every sock I own has a hole in it.
Speaker 0: But I feel like if I buy new socks without destroying the old socks And I put these new socks in my drawer with the old socks the next time I open it It'll still all be old socks.
Speaker 0: It seems to happen to me.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: if they convert maybe the old socks eat him.
Speaker 1: no it's.
Speaker 1: it's true.
Speaker 1: I got rid of all my old socks and bought all new ones a couple years ago.
Speaker 1: I'll probably do it in another year, too.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's a very good idea.
Speaker 0: doesn't help that to this day I can't figure out which Visigoth it is but one of our friends Invariably will leave like the worst most stretched out crew socks ever.
Speaker 1: I don't know how people wear such thin useless socks.
Speaker 1: It's like you're better off wearing no socks, but they're so stretched out.
Speaker 0: They've got to be either.
Speaker 0: They must either have club feet, and we don't know about.
Speaker 0: yeah That's another thing.
Speaker 1: like such stretched out socks It's like a sock needs to be like you know.
Speaker 0: you could buy it one size.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like if the sock is stretched out, then it must be like falling down around the ankle.
Speaker 1: It's like first of all I get socks that don't go very high up except in the winter, right?
Speaker 0: Oh come on you gotta rock the knee socks, and if they do go up.
Speaker 1: They got to stay up.
Speaker 1: They can't be flopping down.
Speaker 0: Do you remember the the Seinfeld about?
Speaker 0: yes?
Speaker 1: I was referring to the Seinfeld about that.
Speaker 0: Well, then but but moving on back to video games a bit it finally happened.
Speaker 0: No one didn't see this coming.
Speaker 0: There were rumblings about this in like July of last year that this would happen mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But uh wrath of the Lich King is coming to fallout 3.
Speaker 0: There's doubt there is an expansion.
Speaker 0: well actually multiple expansions Pay downloadable content for the single-player game.
Speaker 0: fallout 3. it is here.
Speaker 0: You're going to have it well depending on the price.
Speaker 1: I mean is that really any different from an expansion pack?
Speaker 0: well It's tricky.
Speaker 1: It seems like it's an ok DLC right.
Speaker 1: I mean it's like 10 bucks or something like that.
Speaker 0: The interesting part is that there's a lot of strong feelings on both sides of the issue And I think on the negative side the biggest fears.
Speaker 0: I always see people bringing up or that one.
Speaker 0: what if developers start Making games, but then purposefully Removing things that they would have just put in the game Knowing that the game will sell anyway, and then they can sell it as DLC for five more bucks later?
Speaker 1: see that's the thing is like a get a video game right.
Speaker 1: you pay 50 bucks for it and some you know and Usually pay 50 bucks for like a retail console or PC game.
Speaker 1: Maybe 60 bucks right and there is no sort of accepted standard for like how much content that should be.
Speaker 1: So it's like you go to see the movies.
Speaker 1: you expect at least a 90 minute movie Right and if a movie was like a half hour people wouldn't be paying full price to see it.
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: It's sort of like there's an accepted length for these things right?
Speaker 1: so you go to the bookstore right?
Speaker 1: Smaller books are cheaper than the bigger books.
Speaker 1: hardcover is more expensive than softcover.
Speaker 1: You know there's sort of this accepted pricing scale in relation to what you're getting and You know up until you know a while back.
Speaker 1: You know even in the NES days, right?
Speaker 1: You sort of paid the same price for any video game.
Speaker 1: yet some video games gave you more and some gave you less.
Speaker 1: so Now basically the companies are taking advantage of this lack of a standard accepted game content size To make lots of money.
Speaker 1: right they're making like portable games for the cell phone charge in 10 bucks for which probably should be $1.
Speaker 1: Right they're taking Really big games and selling them.
Speaker 1: you know cuz you can't charge a lot more than 50 bucks for any game No matter how big.
Speaker 0: I think back in the day Zelda to Mario 3 and worst were 70 bucks And that was like a crazy outline like you would go to the store the Toys R Us or the Children's Palace.
Speaker 0: I just stand there staring at it.
Speaker 0: That was more money than you could imagine.
Speaker 1: yep So it's like you can't sell any game any game no matter how big or how crazy for more than like 50 60 bucks At least that once.
Speaker 1: right you could do a subscription But you can't charge a one-time fee if it's one of those boutique games.
Speaker 0: I mean I remember back in the day when I was playing like the realm and all those old MMOs Someone made a small yeah like fancy flight simulators can be like a hundred bucks You know.
Speaker 0: like that there were a few like clothes mugs and clothes like little MMOs Where you paid like what caught a hundred bucks or so and then you still paid a monthly fee, but they were like these Walled garden private like awesome communities.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'm talking about it for a normal video game for PC or console.
Speaker 1: You know it's gonna be 50 60 bucks is the most you're gonna get away with.
Speaker 1: I definitely When people want to make a game that's bigger than 50 or 60 bucks right because I mean fallout 3 is really big.
Speaker 1: I mean a lot of stuff in that game repeats itself You know But it's a really big game, and it's like a long time and a lot of money to make.
Speaker 1: so they want to make more money.
Speaker 1: They can't charge more than 50 or 60 bucks at once because no one's gonna pay.
Speaker 1: so they've got to sell sort of 50 bucks worth and Then sort of sell you more later in order to get more than the 50 bucks.
Speaker 1: Yep, otherwise They're just.
Speaker 1: they're not gonna be.
Speaker 1: they're gonna have to make the game smaller.
Speaker 0: of course it also Really depends on what it is that they're selling.
Speaker 1: at the same time though some other people Right are gonna make some $20 game and sell it for 50 bucks because 50 bucks is what you can get away with and there's Standard for it, and I really think we sort of need to Have some sort of market pressure that pushes You know the games that you know to lower in price and higher in price based on what you're getting.
Speaker 0: You know it's kind of like the issue they have on the iTunes store where?
Speaker 0: Everything is priced at these few like there's few price points and actually this really relates to the stock market Because I just did a whole bunch of training on this.
Speaker 0: we were talking about decimalization.
Speaker 0: now that was when Regulations change and it used to be that you could only trade at certain price points.
Speaker 0: So like every say I'm not gonna get to the details But say every eighth of a cent.
Speaker 0: those are like the minimum intervals you could jump.
Speaker 0: a lot of board games have the same thing.
Speaker 0: Like I'm on ray you can bid but the bidding chain like if you want to outbid someone you have to outbid them by a Certain amount.
Speaker 0: you can't say you can't.
Speaker 1: you can't bid like a half dollar.
Speaker 1: It's the one dollar is the least you can bid.
Speaker 0: yes, but when they introduced decimalization They said you could bid down to the penny.
Speaker 0: so instead of the price is being forced to fall into these Categories of like for video games the $5 game the $20 game the $50 game the $60 game.
Speaker 0: There are $5 games.
Speaker 0: there are $20 games.
Speaker 0: there are $45 games it But it's not like.
Speaker 0: there's regulation forcing video games to be this way.
Speaker 0: the market is kind of enforcing it with these semi unrealistic expectations where people expect games to cost $50 and include X or Cost $10 and include why like?
Speaker 0: and that's part I think what's holding back a lot of like Nintendo downloadable content like that or the Xbox Live stuff even is that you could make a really awesome game in there But you can't sell the game for more than a certain amount or people will just not even look at it even though it might Be well worth the money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's why you see something like Wario shake Which is pretty good, but it came out for 50 bucks on the Wii when it probably could have come out for 30.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: you know it didn't cost them 50 bucks because I mean like it cost the same exact price as Twilight Princess Which obviously cost a zillion more dollars to make than Wario shake it.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's the same You know for the same console.
Speaker 1: It's like come on.
Speaker 1: Give me a break here.
Speaker 0: Personally for me when it comes to this sort of thing these expansions It really depends on how much it costs and what it is.
Speaker 0: I mean remember wasn't it oblivion That had those the downloadable content that lets you look different.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I never I don't know anything about it.
Speaker 0: We talked about it.
Speaker 0: I think way back They were like yeah for if you pay whatever dollar amount You get these extra set of hats in this single-player game that no one in the world will ever see, but you Great, it's like buying virtual clothes for your virtual doll.
Speaker 0: I Don't think I'm down.
Speaker 1: I mean I can.
Speaker 1: actually I can respect a game more if it makes you push like you know grind To get a new hat in a single-player game.
Speaker 0: Then if it makes you pay money to get a new hat is I mean at least in a multiplayer game like if I pay five bucks for the Black Baldrick I can show it to other people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's still sad, but at least it's a little bit better than the single-player game.
Speaker 0: It's less sad.
Speaker 0: There's a long continuum of sadness.
Speaker 1: there is.
Speaker 1: it's all sad But that's less said but like or say they're like.
Speaker 0: one of the things that I don't like is that one of the expansions Gives you it ups the level cap in Fallout.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: why?
Speaker 1: Well, I guess it makes the game.
Speaker 1: I mean I I got.
Speaker 1: you know I got level 20 shortly before beating the game and stopping playing you know and I didn't try To level up.
Speaker 1: I just sort of got level.
Speaker 0: That was.
Speaker 0: the biggest complain people had about the game was that it was too easy to level up.
Speaker 0: They wanted more grind.
Speaker 1: They're stupid.
Speaker 0: seriously that is like the biggest complaint.
Speaker 0: I've seen going through forums.
Speaker 1: No, they're stupid, but I mean I didn't have maxed out all the skills.
Speaker 1: I mean there was still some things that I could Could not do.
Speaker 0: I guess the intent couldn't get any more levels.
Speaker 1: So if I decided to you know I could load up my save game from before I actually beat the game and got the ending and I could.
Speaker 1: I got the thing that lets me see every place on the map.
Speaker 1: I could go around and go to all the places on the map and do everything if I wanted to and maybe I you know Maybe I would want to do that right, but I could never get more levels.
Speaker 1: So like I've mostly concentrated in guns and such to make you know to make it easier to kill things So I can get through the game without with less stress.
Speaker 1: But as a result I was unable to hack like a whole bunch of computers.
Speaker 1: like I wasn't able to do anything cool with robots.
Speaker 1: They always killed me right, but if I you raise the level cap to 30 Then I would have been able to go back and try to do some of those other things that I couldn't do.
Speaker 1: you know I could lock pick some of those 100 lock pick doors and stuff like that and You know the thing is why does that cost money?
Speaker 1: all you do is change a number in the game.
Speaker 1: literally I think now I can go to level 30.
Speaker 0: I think the original intent of this was that you're supposed to play through the game like an old fallout Multiple times kind of being a different person like I'll be the heckery guy and go through the whole game like a heckery guy Or I'll be the evil badass.
Speaker 0: I'll go through the whole game.
Speaker 0: is the evil badass?
Speaker 1: I see the thing is I watched all the game endings.
Speaker 1: cuz this you know when you end unlike other fallouts I've heard that you after you beat the game you keep playing and this fallout.
Speaker 1: when you beat the game It's done, and you have to.
Speaker 1: if you want to keep playing you have to load a save game from before Depending on what you choose.
Speaker 0: that makes sense.
Speaker 1: well Yeah, but so I got.
Speaker 1: I beat the game And I got the goody-goody ending.
Speaker 1: cuz I was a goody-goody guy, right I was like the best goody-goody you could be and even though I freaking blew everyone's brains out who was bad?
Speaker 0: That makes you good.
Speaker 0: It's pummel empathy exactly?
Speaker 1: um well I guess it's bullet empathy, and I went on YouTube to watch the other endings, and they were not significantly different.
Speaker 1: They were definitely not worth playing the entire game again.
Speaker 1: Not we're not even close.
Speaker 1: So I would never under any circumstance want to start the game over even though I might You know want to say load up the game before the ending and go Explore some unexplored areas.
Speaker 1: cuz really the good part about the game is the exploring and all the other parts of kind of play.
Speaker 0: now the interesting one is Operation anchorage.
Speaker 0: now that did you?
Speaker 0: do you know anything about the Battle of Anchorage?
Speaker 1: Yes?
Speaker 0: Yeah?
Speaker 0: Do you know a lot about it?
Speaker 1: I know what I learned playing the game once.
Speaker 0: well what they've added What they're going to add is there's a point where you can go to a VR simulation in the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was actually a part of the game I was impressed with because it was the it sort of felt.
Speaker 1: when I got there I was like wow this is the end of the game.
Speaker 1: And it totally wasn't even though in like in other games that would have been the end.
Speaker 0: So but what you can do is they want you to be able to play that battle in a tactical like.
Speaker 0: it's not because fallout is Not an FPS, and there's very little.
Speaker 1: I sort of wish it was.
Speaker 1: I wish like someone could like hack the game and make it an actual FPS and remove the RPG from the.
Speaker 0: oh my god Don't get me started cuz that would be fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: because the thing the problem with the game for me not for everyone I mean everyone has different taste in games, but it's not an FPS.
Speaker 0: Fallout 3 requires Zero really skill.
Speaker 0: It's just a game of do like you do the right basic options fight things and level up in the right way Manage your ammo right and you won't lose or die unless you do something really stupid.
Speaker 1: So yeah unless he goes somewhere where there happens to be extreme danger like a lot of times I'll speed walk somewhere, and they'll be really dangerous guys, and then you can't escape and you die.
Speaker 1: But nothing you could do about that.
Speaker 0: yep But as a result the game doesn't require any skill.
Speaker 0: You don't really.
Speaker 0: you're not better at the game by the end of it than you were when you started.
Speaker 0: But what this is other than having more goodies?
Speaker 0: what this is added is a an actual?
Speaker 0: Tactical game where you make a squad and you pick your team members like snipers heavy weapons guys Whatever.
Speaker 0: you give them orders or tactics and you play this kind of strategy tactical Simulate the battle game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know about strategy or tactile.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be.
Speaker 0: I don't think so either.
Speaker 0: But what's interesting?
Speaker 0: that they're basically if this is to be believed fully Adding a real-time first-person strategy fighting game To fallout which is otherwise.
Speaker 1: and our thing is it's not yeah, but it's not a strategy.
Speaker 0: if it's all RPG Well, I don't think it's all RPG.
Speaker 0: I mean it's kind of.
Speaker 0: I think it's gonna take place in the simulator.
Speaker 1: the simulator was.
Speaker 1: it was no different than the outside of The game.
Speaker 0: yes except that it'll.
Speaker 0: maybe it'll give you the weapons and things that fit for that fit world.
Speaker 0: So you have the same loadout.
Speaker 0: what will make the difference is what points you attack or where you go and teammates you choose?
Speaker 0: Quotes the player will be able to choose from a limited resource pool.
Speaker 0: See that's why types of team members will accompany him on several missions within the simulations.
Speaker 0: Choices include different troop types like snipers every weapons.
Speaker 0: They'll also be able to make tactical decisions on how to deploy these troops in certain situations.
Speaker 1: That sounds to me like a lot of you know games these days.
Speaker 1: They do things that for tip.
Speaker 1: for most lay people appear to be strategy and tactics and they'll even you know They'll say oh the game's so strategic.
Speaker 1: normal people will say that but from a Actual game perspective, which few people understand it.
Speaker 1: There's actually no strategy Like someone will make a really complex rock-paper-scissors and somebody like all this game so strategic not realizing It's actually just a complex rock-paper-scissors.
Speaker 0: well, actually it's funny because about I'm I'm crying about three-quarters of way through an article on Stratego for an upcoming project And which is really just a complex rock-paper-scissors.
Speaker 0: No, actually what I'm writing a lot about how when in suboptimal play and this is true across many games in suboptimal play There is emergent behavior and emergent tactical thought and emergent options that don't exist Among skilled players.
Speaker 0: so by playing games that are above your level by playing games where you're a novice or you're not strategically optimal the game is Probably more fun and the end result is that you should play games that are above your mental level Because you'll have more options more tactics more thought and the game will generally be more interesting for you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 1: If you play a game that you're perfect at there's no thinking about strategies because you already know what there's.
Speaker 0: there's no strategy The other way around.
Speaker 0: like Stratego the game is strategic at the high level of play.
Speaker 0: The problem is there's no tactics.
Speaker 0: You'd might as well just set up your two boards and then everyone just turn their pieces around and you can figure out who.
Speaker 1: Well playing the game is.
Speaker 1: sorry because there's no way to figure out by looking at how you set up the board who was gonna Win.
Speaker 0: you'd have to actually I would argue that mathematically.
Speaker 1: there is mathematically But you don't it's.
Speaker 1: you know It's.
Speaker 1: it's not an easy thing to just to do like.
Speaker 1: you can't like if I just set up the board and flipped it over Could you just say oh so and so one maybe for some configurations, but not all.
Speaker 1: yes playing It is sort of figuring out who set theirs up better.
Speaker 0: Yes, it is But the thing is you're not when you're playing Stratego You're not when you're an optimal player.
Speaker 0: the playing of it is not a game.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 0: It's not just following the algorithm that will tell you which original starting setup won the game.
Speaker 1: That is correct.
Speaker 0: That is all it is.
Speaker 0: So once I write a program that does that we've solved Stratego.
Speaker 1: Yes, that is also correct.
Speaker 1: But anyway, it's a lot sort of like Like NFL football versus college football, you know, it's like in college football.
Speaker 1: There's all sorts of crazy shit going on.
Speaker 1: It's real interesting for spectators.
Speaker 1: It's real interesting for players.
Speaker 1: You have a lot of different options.
Speaker 1: a lot of different plays become feasible.
Speaker 1: I actually made the NFL where the players are far superior Right and everyone knows all you can't pull these shenanigans because the other team is too smart Unless they're like, you know the Chiefs or something analogy I make you can't use.
Speaker 1: so your options are far far fewer.
Speaker 0: the analogies I make are one like a child playing chess for you Like you put your queen in a spot that'll get something and you hope the guy doesn't notice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a strategy that works when two kids are playing chess.
Speaker 0: It doesn't work if you're playing chess against an adult.
Speaker 0: No It's.
Speaker 0: or like in Little League the trick plays.
Speaker 1: Yeah in lit, right?
Speaker 1: That's a perfect example in Little League baseball, right?
Speaker 1: Well, they're in any baseball right?
Speaker 1: It is perfectly legal.
Speaker 1: Let's say you get a walk, right?
Speaker 1: So someone throws four balls.
Speaker 1: you walk to first base and then just start running to second Oh my god, and then just start running to second.
Speaker 1: you can do that.
Speaker 1: There's no reason you can't do that, right?
Speaker 1: You just you have a free walk to first base, but you're like you can try to keep going a second.
Speaker 0: They can't balk but at the same time what if you did some sleight of hand and the pitcher's standing there But he don't have the ball?
Speaker 0: the guy at second base has the ball.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So that shit doesn't fly in the major leagues notice.
Speaker 1: in Major League Baseball Everyone walks to first base slowly and calmly but in Little League baseball They run to first base and a lot of times they'll just keep running a second because the Little League kids it works on them.
Speaker 1: so that's it's.
Speaker 1: these extra options are available.
Speaker 1: when you play an amateur, you know play with amateurs and Professionals are playing and smart people are playing.
Speaker 1: these options are not there.
Speaker 0: However, I feel like wall fallout 3 is not going to do this.
Speaker 0: There is potential for that sort of game.
Speaker 0: It's like a meld between the Marines of NS but with a more single-player Commanding from the front lines perspective.
Speaker 0: I got a lot of vague ideas about it, but nothing concrete yet.
Speaker 1: See, I'm not really interested in like some an expansion pack like that that gives you like this battle to do.
Speaker 0: I would be but I would be more interested in the history of the world.
Speaker 1: I would be interested in the other expansion pack maybe that sort of lets you keep playing after the game and adds a whole bunch more quests and hope maybe even adds more land to The map like more just more stuff that that might be worth as long as it's cheap like five ten bucks Depending on how much they give and how much I feel like it.
Speaker 1: You know that and if I can load up my old character and I have to start again stuff like that Maybe I'll be interested.
Speaker 0: It looks like it's gonna be 800 Microsoft points or Pounds or nine point six euros.
Speaker 1: It's like 20 bucks.
Speaker 1: 18 bucks something like that.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends if that could all change any day.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah what to see.
Speaker 0: but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: This is a machinima.
Speaker 0: What I can say about it primarily is that the voice acting is surprisingly good and it beats Expectations by a large margin.
Speaker 0: I mean way back.
Speaker 0: we used that old.
Speaker 0: There was that pyro machinima for Team Fortress 2 and it was.
Speaker 0: it was really good for the first half but then it really just kind of petered out and I think the the Overwhelming consensus was that that machinima was one of those zero-day businesses And there was.
Speaker 0: it was just hey, let's make one.
Speaker 0: Oh my god were the first ones.
Speaker 0: everyone's watching it.
Speaker 0: This is pretty funny and every time you think you see where it's going with the jokes it pulls one on you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some of the jokes are obvious, but some of them are pretty clever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know I really like the the the thing that the blue team has built because they're bored.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is classic and that's what FPS is are all about.
Speaker 1: Oh my god That and all the only that's what I'm saying is why they really need to get the the physics the half-life 2 physics stuff going On in the multiplayer.
Speaker 1: so shit like that can happen.
Speaker 0: as we said if left for dead had half-life 2 physics That might have been a game for all time Maybe as opposed to just a six-month.
Speaker 1: mean the only one that really has is the half-life 2 deathmatch for everyone's got gravity guns.
Speaker 1: Throwing shit at each other is setting people on fire Exploding barrels, right?
Speaker 1: Why isn't that in left for dead?
Speaker 1: Why isn't that in tf2 or even imagine NS?
Speaker 0: Yeah, man.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it could be okay someday someday Alright, so, you know how people always talk about villains being stupid right?
Speaker 1: Like why doesn't like?
Speaker 0: obviously none of them are rezo.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, it's true except for rezo Maybe chevron egg dough and maybe no chevron egg though.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess yeah, he wasn't stupid.
Speaker 0: He was like, well, here it is.
Speaker 0: There's the thing that can be strong Like Koopa, right?
Speaker 1: Why doesn't he just send like all?
Speaker 1: The like spiky beetles all at once.
Speaker 1: so why does?
Speaker 1: why does he just make a pit so big?
Speaker 1: Mario can't jump over.
Speaker 0: I have the answer to that Because if he made it it's a 2d world, right?
Speaker 1: I just send ten hammer brothers at once.
Speaker 1: Mario can't possibly beat them all.
Speaker 0: it's a 2d world.
Speaker 0: If he made a pit bigger than he could anyone could jump across.
Speaker 0: He's basically made a pit in the world that no one can cross.
Speaker 0: cutting off that part of the world forever That's fine.
Speaker 1: make two big pits.
Speaker 1: no one can cross with Mario in the middle.
Speaker 0: But how does he get food from the 2d farms?
Speaker 0: I mean you got a thing a real world like one thing.
Speaker 1: Mario is on this tiny spit of land.
Speaker 1: on both sides of him are pits.
Speaker 0: He cannot build it.
Speaker 1: Mario's there and Luigi's there too if the world even that the world is 2d.
Speaker 1: It's still round.
Speaker 0: Did you see the Mario Opera?
Speaker 0: Mario and Luigi will fuck you up if you get anywhere near them?
Speaker 1: No, Mario is coming at you, right?
Speaker 1: So you're way ahead of him.
Speaker 1: You build a giant pit He can't cross.
Speaker 1: you run around the world.
Speaker 1: He's still heading towards your giant pit.
Speaker 0: What he sends Luigi in the other direction.
Speaker 1: Luigi can't go backwards.
Speaker 1: You can't go backwards.
Speaker 0: Maybe you can no Maybe no.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the thing I always hear people say is why don't you just send booze after him?
Speaker 0: cuz you can't kill booze Let's get a hammer exactly two booze at once right?
Speaker 1: He's trapped in the middle.
Speaker 0: the reason for that?
Speaker 0: Bowser can't control booze.
Speaker 0: for crap all that.
Speaker 0: Bowser is afraid of booze.
Speaker 0: That's the reason you only find scary stuff in those mansions.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: But anyway, there was that.
Speaker 1: remember that flash video that was like all the Koopa underlings were like fuck you Bowser.
Speaker 1: We're doing it our way and they freaking tear Mario a new hole.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was a good one.
Speaker 1: So Someone was saying hey, why doesn't dr.
Speaker 1: Wily just send all the robot masters at Mega Man all at once, right?
Speaker 0: It makes sense because the doors holding them in can only be opened by jumping into them.
Speaker 1: Well, yes, that's true But you know the.
Speaker 1: why doesn't he send all the robot masters at once?
Speaker 1: then how would Mega Man possibly beat them, right?
Speaker 1: It's like sure.
Speaker 1: he could try to like shoot the metal blades a whole bunch and bubble man might get axed but It's not gonna do much against you know, some of the other guys.
Speaker 0: Well, apparently we have the answer.
Speaker 1: Well, not only do we have the answer, right?
Speaker 1: instead of doing a flash video with some stupid lame joke like that Mario flash video this guy actually Hacked the ROM so that you fight all.
Speaker 1: it's called Megaman - Rockman -.
Speaker 1: Netta a Japanese guy did it, of course and It's a ROM hack that lets you as Megaman in Megaman to fight every single robot master for Megaman - all at once.
Speaker 1: They all appear all at once.
Speaker 1: you fight them all at once.
Speaker 1: you have all the weapons though, right?
Speaker 1: Which is sort of like wrong because they're still alive.
Speaker 1: So how do you have their weapons?
Speaker 1: I don't know, but you fight them all at once and The thing about it.
Speaker 1: That's pretty funny.
Speaker 1: Is that?
Speaker 1: it is actually beatable.
Speaker 1: It's like you think oh you would just die instantly.
Speaker 1: It's like a. you know, fire would come at you quick boomerangs would come at you flash man would jump on you.
Speaker 0: but no what happens is remember it's Megaman.
Speaker 0: and Especially if you play the Megaman X games one of the biggest strategies you'll use and a lot of things is you get hit by Something now you're invulnerable for a few seconds.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you're basically invulnerable for the majority of this fight.
Speaker 1: Yeah because it's like you shoot but you like kill bubble man right with your metal blades and then you get hit and Then you're invincible long enough to like dole out a lot of damage.
Speaker 1: They're all in the same spot.
Speaker 1: you can sort of hit them all at once.
Speaker 0: so I just have to go through the list of all the different weapons that destroy the people and Spoilers.
Speaker 0: metal man totally gets punked by his own metal blades.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's true.
Speaker 0: Well, I remember when I figured that out as a kid.
Speaker 1: Yeah so in this there's a little video here that shows you someone beating it and Also, you can get the ROM and try it yourself.
Speaker 1: Of course, you'll probably just die Pretty quickly if you try but if you're the master and maybe you watch the video closely Maybe you too can beat all the robot masters all at once.
Speaker 0: So to continue our discussion of fallout 3 since we both played a quite large bit of it.
Speaker 1: Well, I played the whole fight and played the whole thing, but I beat it.
Speaker 1: I got to the ending.
Speaker 1: that did not go everywhere and do everything.
Speaker 0: I know the ending but I did not get to it yet because I've been going around doing everything.
Speaker 1: Well, what part were you at?
Speaker 0: The part I was at at the moment was I had gone and done the whole mr.
Speaker 0: Tenpenny thing.
Speaker 0: You didn't do that.
Speaker 1: Did you but I went up there eventually, but I didn't really do anything up there.
Speaker 1: I just went up and I was like, oh, here's that place for him was talking about.
Speaker 1: All right, I'm leaving.
Speaker 0: I like that place a lot.
Speaker 0: And even though I think I agree with Scott Johnson that these story there is bullshit Even though it teaches you a valuable lesson about not being a nice guy and not being tolerant Let me let me sum up my thoughts in this game, right?
Speaker 1: First of all fallout one and two.
Speaker 1: I've tried to play those and I've never had success.
Speaker 1: I tried to play them back in the day and I tried to play them recently and while playing them recently I had a slightly larger measure of success.
Speaker 1: It wasn't.
Speaker 1: I was just too Frustrated with that crap to deal with it, you know, it's like a lot of people really like those games And they're like, oh, they're classics.
Speaker 1: Oh, they're so great.
Speaker 1: They're not you know They don't.
Speaker 1: they don't do it for me.
Speaker 1: So Fallout 3 the only reason I was sort of giving it a chance was because it was like all FPS in and I sort of felt like actually Exploring the world, you know by walking around.
Speaker 1: That was what was gonna do it for me.
Speaker 0: That was I mean that was the biggest plus for this game.
Speaker 0: That was the reason I thought Scott might enjoy actually was that he played for the original fallout.
Speaker 0: You know, everybody's yelp bugging him.
Speaker 0: So he downloaded it He played it and the first thing I remember him saying was wait, so I can't just walk around the world.
Speaker 0: That's bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like I got a click on the town and then you click on another town.
Speaker 1: You just sort of quickly teleport from one town to another but sometimes it's random encounters.
Speaker 1: in the middle It's like ah, well, I guess it's better, you know, at least in Final Fantasy, right?
Speaker 1: There might be random encounters as you walk from here to there but you're having the fun of exploring a map and picking up treasure chests and you sort of seeing things for yourself in this game, it's like But and there's a lot more, you know in the older fallout It was a lot more RPG grinding, you know, cuz he's like click on the rat click on the rat again.
Speaker 1: It was like slow Diablo really, you know, and that sort of was annoying.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's one thing that I was a little disappointed.
Speaker 0: the FPS thing of this game Mattered a lot less than I mean, I didn't expect it to matter much, but it didn't matter at all.
Speaker 0: It was basically just turn-based combat.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, that that did annoy me.
Speaker 1: cuz like if I'm I felt like I was as FPS.
Speaker 1: he controls like an FPS, right?
Speaker 1: But like there's a difference between cone fire and you know, I mean Counter-Strike has cone fire Your bullet is going to be in this area, right?
Speaker 1: This game basically aiming at someone's head and clicking on their head It would.
Speaker 1: the game would then do the RPG calculation saying, okay, you're using small arms.
Speaker 1: Your small arm skill is this he's this far away.
Speaker 1: So the percent chance of you hitting his head is this let's roll the dice.
Speaker 1: You did not hit and then after it did all that the bullet would fly off into the middle of nowhere, right?
Speaker 1: There are instances where I was Crouching and aim perfectly at someone's head who wasn't paying attention With a missile and like it would just like fly right past him like way off into the sky.
Speaker 1: He's just like what the fuck.
Speaker 1: my aim doesn't matter for shit.
Speaker 0: But I guess I mean for me.
Speaker 0: I enjoyed the game a lot because of the exploration at first like when I first walked out of that vault and Start and realize I go in any direction.
Speaker 0: I see that elevated highway going off in the distance and the first thing I thought was hot shit.
Speaker 0: I got to get up there and walk along that thing.
Speaker 0: I look to the right.
Speaker 0: I see this big tower.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh man, I'm totally gonna check that out.
Speaker 0: But I guess what disappointed me was it wasn't as bad as games like Oblivion in that there was a lot of stuff to do But the majority the vast majority of anything any feature on the train anywhere out there was 100% non interactive.
Speaker 1: Yeah that you know.
Speaker 0: and I spent an hour exploring.
Speaker 0: I didn't explore anything really for the rest of the game except for plot stuff because it was all Like other unless I found a computer that told me something or a person that told me something or an item that did something.
Speaker 0: The world itself was just cookie cutter all over the place.
Speaker 1: I think that's the one major problem I have with the game other than all the RPG bullshit You know, basically the thing is the game has lots of RPG bullshit, which I hate right?
Speaker 1: but the thing is Mostly ignore all that and the explore e part of the game sort of makes up for it.
Speaker 1: Now the thing that bothers me, right?
Speaker 1: I think the one way the game could really improve the most is that you have this big world, right?
Speaker 1: but the world really is Static.
Speaker 1: it doesn't change.
Speaker 1: it is as it is and the only way the world can change is if you change it.
Speaker 1: and you literally all you do in this game is go to different parts of the world and Decide how and if you are going to change that part of the world.
Speaker 1: and sometimes, you know You don't actually know what the result will be of your actions in terms of changing the world.
Speaker 1: But you're making a decision, you know change the world for the better or the worse.
Speaker 1: You know, what action are you going to take now?
Speaker 1: and the world is non living.
Speaker 1: it's like Other characters in the world are not making decisions and changing the world in any way Like I can go to.
Speaker 1: it's like a I can go into like a random cave, right?
Speaker 1: It can be full of bad guys, but they're not right in this spot at the moment, right?
Speaker 1: I could take all my goodies like a whole pile of bottle caps a thousand bottle caps and put them in an unlocked locker And come back to the game like literally like I can just say wait in game time and like wait weeks and weeks and weeks And travel around the whole game world and come back.
Speaker 1: It'll be in that locker Because there's the game.
Speaker 1: There's no characters exploring things like me.
Speaker 1: There's no one doing anything.
Speaker 0: well, I have two things to say to that but first I would like to Remind you about a game that came out a long freaking time ago the Blade Runner game for the PC.
Speaker 0: Do you remember that game?
Speaker 1: I remember the trailer for it because it's on a CD for another game.
Speaker 0: But you don't remember the game because the game schtick.
Speaker 0: the big deal about the game was that the plot was Determined.
Speaker 0: when you start like the what the truths about the game world?
Speaker 0: We're not static and you might or might not be a replicant and other people may or may not be replicants.
Speaker 1: I'm in.
Speaker 0: so that's the first thing.
Speaker 0: so the game theoretically would have near infinite replayability.
Speaker 0: but to.
Speaker 0: The game was played in real time and while you were walking around and talking to people and doing stuff the other Protagonist or antagonist the other active characters were also doing stuff.
Speaker 0: So if you find out that so-and-so is gonna meet so-and-so in the alley at night and you go there They're gonna be there.
Speaker 0: or if you don't go there They're gonna be there and conduct their business.
Speaker 0: and now that changes the world.
Speaker 1: I mean some of the stuff in the game is time sensitive, but it's like it doesn't matter what day it is Like this day and this night and some stuff is at night and some stuff is a day.
Speaker 1: But other than that it no.
Speaker 0: But this was more like if you go to the person's house when there's before they go out to meet the guy You'll meet them like outside of the place.
Speaker 0: They were at like they go through the game world in real time.
Speaker 0: It's tracking what everyone's doing.
Speaker 0: So your goals are constantly fluid and it was a really really really ambitious game and a lot of those mechanics I don't think are really possible yet on a real scale.
Speaker 0: The game was.
Speaker 0: there is a way that game was ass But that was just because of the limitations of the tech.
Speaker 1: there is a way that that's possible.
Speaker 1: It's called multiplayer.
Speaker 0: No, you know what?
Speaker 0: It's called.
Speaker 0: It's called a massively multiplayer online role-playing game.
Speaker 0: The problem is what we know an MMO to be.
Speaker 0: is not that?
Speaker 0: in fact There was just that article on slashdot talking about like server optimization for MMOs and they made a really really telling point That I think they said something like 95 percent to 90 like the vast majority of Player.
Speaker 0: interaction with the game world in World of Warcraft for example is a hundred percent parallel.
Speaker 0: very few people are interacting with very few other people at any given time and While the game has a lot of people in it.
Speaker 0: There's no actual Massively multiplayer part going on.
Speaker 0: No P. It isn't really massively interactive.
Speaker 0: It's just a lot of players playing much smaller games next to each other.
Speaker 1: I think something else right that sort of differentiates at least a fallout MMO compared to say a World of Warcraft MMO.
Speaker 1: right would be that in Fallout Player the the player right modifies at least the game world, right?
Speaker 1: So if you at least had a fallout MMO It would be a little bit better than a Warcraft World of Warcraft because in World of Warcraft the world is static, right?
Speaker 1: We all beat the same boss over and over again, right?
Speaker 1: Everyone beats the boss hundreds and hundreds of times and fallout.
Speaker 1: So there's a big monster somewhere in a cave.
Speaker 1: Let's say right someone goes and kills the monster in the cave Someone else shows up.
Speaker 1: There's a dead monster in the cave and all the loot is gone.
Speaker 0: It's got.
Speaker 0: people have been putting forth that idea since the beginning of MMOs and even since mods.
Speaker 0: the problem is It doesn't scale well and the cost of creating that much content is so prohibitive compared to that's why the content has to be The other players, right?
Speaker 0: Somebody that is the fundamental problem.
Speaker 0: if you make an MMO like that remember the rule like 95% of people will consume 4% will interact and 1% will contribute.
Speaker 1: man.
Speaker 1: If there was an MMO like that I could I would like sign in.
Speaker 1: I'd be like I want to be the cave troll today and I'd go and I'd find a bridge And I'd be like, I'm the cave troll.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna harass anyone that comes over this bridge.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, I'm sort of just deciding like a role for myself and I could you know That's you know, someone else logs in like today.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be the king like I'm the king today.
Speaker 1: They'll be all kingly.
Speaker 0: I think one way to do that would be if you had us a large set of NPCs that were NPCs all the time unless a player took charge of them or another way.
Speaker 1: That was it.
Speaker 0: another way would be if you had a world that was still massively parallelized like World of Warcraft But it was parallelized into discrete game worlds or discrete game areas that themselves were a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: either player created emergent content or World, you know were in world changed in the context of the world irrevocably by players content.
Speaker 0: So 50 different groups of a hundred people each could all play the same World of Warcraft storyline world through But each one the events are a hundred percent can.
Speaker 0: nothing is done except by the drive of players themselves.
Speaker 0: But all those things don't make a lot of money compared to a game like wow, so that we're not there yet?
Speaker 1: No, so then I also want to talk about right.
Speaker 1: whenever people talk about Fallout they talk about oh you can do anything, right?
Speaker 1: It's so great.
Speaker 1: It's like you can just go in there and kill everyone.
Speaker 1: You don't have to.
Speaker 1: you know, go like on the railroads.
Speaker 1: that compared to say Final Fantasy, right?
Speaker 1: And compared to Final Fantasy that is true right Final Fantasy.
Speaker 1: This is the story we deliver you the story.
Speaker 1: you just get through it in Fallout.
Speaker 1: You do have Choices, right, but you can't do anything.
Speaker 1: That is that is BS, right?
Speaker 1: I mean there the choices are Sometimes interesting sometimes not interesting, but there is always choice, right?
Speaker 1: For example There was a mission with like a tree I had to deal with right and I could kill the tree nicely like it wanted me to.
Speaker 1: I could kill it painfully.
Speaker 1: There was an old lady who wanted me to like rub something on the tree instead of killing it.
Speaker 1: There was an old man who wanted me to rub something different on the tree instead of killing it, right?
Speaker 1: it's like.
Speaker 1: I know I had these choices, but There really weren't any Choices that weren't scripted by the game.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, like killing things is always an option.
Speaker 1: So the game sort of always has a way of dealing with that because you have weapons but you don't really have any way to interact with the world besides shooting things or dialogue, so Really?
Speaker 1: The game is just a scripted like tree of events Not this sort of unscripted freeform thing because all your options are defined by the dialogue choices Or by shooting things.
Speaker 1: is what other way, you know I guess there's hacking and lock picking.
Speaker 1: sometimes can like or science can sometimes let you do something differently.
Speaker 1: But those are also defined tracks.
Speaker 0: So those really they're no different than you know.
Speaker 0: the old quest for glory games where you have the same game world you can play as a fighter a thief a mage or a Paladin and depending on which one you choose and what skills you have There is a. there are four different ways to solve every possible problem in the game And they're also.
Speaker 0: each class has a subset of things they can get at or do that are cool That no one else can get at because they don't have the relevant skills or abilities or anything like that.
Speaker 0: So it kind of creates replayability.
Speaker 0: but fallout doesn't add anything to that like fallout just reimplements that old game mechanic.
Speaker 0: That's been largely forgotten.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not a do anything you want game.
Speaker 1: It's just a game that makes you feel More free because there are multiple choices.
Speaker 1: There are multiple pat different paths to the same end and there are multiple different ends.
Speaker 1: You can choose.
Speaker 1: but the thing is most of the choices are sort of inconsequential.
Speaker 1: All they do is sort of modify a small area of the game world or change a few statistics or change what items you're gonna get or change something sort of Small and insignificant B?
Speaker 0: Well, that was what Yahtzee kept saying.
Speaker 1: There's the end of the game.
Speaker 1: only like two or three choices you make actually change the ending and the ending is a small video That you can watch all the different ones on YouTube.
Speaker 1: So who cares which one you get?
Speaker 0: but like Yahtzee was pointing out and I tend to agree.
Speaker 0: There's no Permanence or feeling that you're accomplishing anything because almost everything you do in the game Like you said changes a small part of the world.
Speaker 0: so like this area either has trees or doesn't or whatever.
Speaker 0: or these people these slaves are either free or they're not or The ghouls or the people in Tenpenny's Tower, but you know little things like that and the radio will say like oh, he's the same.
Speaker 1: They're really good at doing a lot of Atmospheric things and sort of things that make you go like hey cool It's sort of the same thing you get when you like get superhero comic books, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you read a superhero comic book or say spider-man beats up I don't know the lizard.
Speaker 1: right lizard man, right the guy with the lab coat.
Speaker 1: and then you're reading say I don't know daredevil right and in the newspaper and daredevil you see like the Picture of the spider-man beating up the lizard.
Speaker 1: and because you read the spider-man comic you're like, oh cool, right?
Speaker 0: This has been going back for a long time.
Speaker 0: Scott Paperboy calls it quits exactly.
Speaker 1: It's the same thing in Fallout 3, right?
Speaker 1: I said there was this kid early in the game and his parents got killed by nasty fire ants.
Speaker 1: So I rescued him and found him a new home.
Speaker 1: and then the radio guy was like Isn't the guy from vault 101?
Speaker 1: great.
Speaker 1: he found this kid a new home.
Speaker 1: He's the best and it's like hey cool, but it doesn't really change Anything.
Speaker 0: like I was saying what I mean.
Speaker 1: I can go to the kid.
Speaker 1: It's like now the kid is in his new home instead of being in his old home.
Speaker 0: But it doesn't matter really like I was saying as Yahtzee also pointed out.
Speaker 0: There's no sense of permanence.
Speaker 0: or change you.
Speaker 0: what you get when you defeat these quests really is Some more bottle caps and ammo and maybe a new weapon.
Speaker 0: Yep, and that gets real quick.
Speaker 1: There really aren't a lot of different weapons And you don't have enough skill points to be good with all of them.
Speaker 1: And it's like if you're not good with the weapon why have it you know?
Speaker 1: and it just more bottle caps.
Speaker 1: It's like all right listen.
Speaker 1: I've got a missile launcher and like 50 missiles.
Speaker 1: I've got a minigun.
Speaker 1: I've got laser rifles and plasma rifles and gatling lasers.
Speaker 1: really I don't need.
Speaker 1: I can already hose anything down.
Speaker 1: Nothing can stop me anything that I have a mini nukes.
Speaker 1: I only used one mini nuke.
Speaker 1: the whole game.
Speaker 1: I had like four right.
Speaker 1: there was nothing to use them on.
Speaker 1: there was actually one cool part Where there's a gigantic gigantic super mutant.
Speaker 1: why didn't they throw something and that was not even near the end of the game?
Speaker 1: They should have thrown something even bigger at me towards the end of the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, instead there's something really big on your side at the end of the game.
Speaker 1: Which is way cool.
Speaker 1: But I'd rather would have had a bigger opponent.
Speaker 0: yeah, I guess it's just that the the story Doesn't grab me that much because the interaction isn't enough.
Speaker 0: I mean the story of the Fallout world is great and a lot of the things you do in this game are really cool ideas But they don't grab me enough because I don't have enough interaction.
Speaker 0: We might be asking too much of games like this.
Speaker 0: the technology just might not be there yet to make them in a cost-effective manner To where they could actually make money off of a game.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: yeah The game I mean I did play the game the whole way through despite not liking Fallout 1 & 2 and I really liked exploring the world.
Speaker 1: even though like the little side quests were like Inconsequential I still sort of enjoyed like exploring them.
Speaker 1: They were almost like little games in and of themselves and some of them were better than others.
Speaker 1: You know some of them I cared more about than others, but like if I didn't care about one I could just leave it you know or Like.
Speaker 1: I could just sort of you know go and just kill people if I felt like it.
Speaker 1: You know it's sort of a little cathartic FPS thing even though it wasn't FPS thing.
Speaker 1: I tried to FPS and not use the stupid auto-aim thing is my pretty much never use those things.
Speaker 1: yeah You know I mean some of that.
Speaker 1: they were like.
Speaker 1: you know the game had lots of sort of art in it That was worth enjoying like this.
Speaker 1: good music on the radio There's you know really good sort of short stories to experience.
Speaker 1: I sort of.
Speaker 1: that's the way I sort of viewed the game, and why it was worth playing despite the mechanics of it not being too exciting or Leveling up.
Speaker 0: choose your own adventure book with really good art.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like this.
Speaker 1: you know good things to look at good stories to be told good things to hear well funny jokes.
Speaker 0: at the time the voice acting was Hit or miss.
Speaker 0: it was really good in some parts and like abominable in others.
Speaker 1: well Yeah, it was but you know it.
Speaker 1: I mostly didn't pay attention to voice acting a lot of times.
Speaker 1: Just sort of skipped and read the text.
Speaker 1: I think the what another area the game should have improved was that sort of You I did sort of I guess things out of order and then things happen that don't make sense.
Speaker 1: you know for example There's like a mission go to galaxy news radio to find out what happened to your dad right, so I'm like okay So I can't figure out how to get there right, so I'm trying to get there.
Speaker 1: I can't make it right.
Speaker 1: It's really dangerous over there.
Speaker 1: So I've got like three other missions to do and they all say go to Rivet town.
Speaker 1: So I'm like you know what I'm fucking going to Rivet town.
Speaker 1: I go there.
Speaker 1: Suddenly that whole galaxy news radio thing like disappears.
Speaker 1: and now because I went to Rivet town.
Speaker 1: I must have jumped ahead.
Speaker 1: I must assume that if I would have gone to galaxy news radio.
Speaker 1: They would have told me to go to Rivet town also and There's a scientist lady, and I'm talking to her and all the dialogue options.
Speaker 1: It's like I can sort of figure it out because I'm smart.
Speaker 1: right now any human could sort of figure it out.
Speaker 1: You know what they missed like.
Speaker 1: oh, I guess I skipped over this.
Speaker 1: you know your mind can fill in the blanks because you know What's going on, but it's still Discontiguous.
Speaker 1: suddenly I'm talking to this person like I know them.
Speaker 1: like I know that I was looking for them even though I've never heard of them before.
Speaker 1: Right and even though I can put it together in my mind because I have this you know ability to recognize things.
Speaker 1: It's way choppy, and if like you did that in like a movie people would be way confused Like I.
Speaker 0: like that time we watched a certain unnamed movie But because of the DVD we skipped the first like 15 minutes of the movie, so it didn't make any sense exactly.
Speaker 0: Exactly, I remember watching the first half of the movie at the end going oh Okay, yeah It's exactly like that.
Speaker 1: so I mean I guess I feel like the game should have been like is another example.
Speaker 1: Right though in the beginning early in the game as a sheriff right as a guy in town Who's bad?
Speaker 1: so you tell the sheriff about the bad guy.
Speaker 1: the sheriff goes take care of the bad guy?
Speaker 1: But then the bad guy shoots the sheriff down, so then you shoot the bad guy down all right Later like I just like okay.
Speaker 1: I guess that's over with.
Speaker 1: so I leave and I come back like a few days later And like the sheriff's kid is talking to me, but the dialogue.
Speaker 1: He's talking to me as if he knows me.
Speaker 1: I've never met him before.
Speaker 1: I never didn't even know the sheriff had a kid.
Speaker 1: I guess I was supposed to meet him earlier and missed him, so it's way It's very startling.
Speaker 1: it takes you way out of it You know and stuff like that happens.
Speaker 1: they need to.
Speaker 1: the game should have sort of known that I hadn't met the sheriff's kid yet And thus the dialogue should have been like hey.
Speaker 1: I'm the sheriff's kid.
Speaker 1: You didn't meet me before you know?
Speaker 1: Thanks for help.
Speaker 1: You know killing the guy who killed my dad instead of you know yeah, now the dad's gone.
Speaker 1: How are you doing?
Speaker 1: It's like what I don't even know you well.
Speaker 0: at the same time are we asking too much of this genre yet, you know if you're?
Speaker 1: if you're you know it, I don't ask you know.
Speaker 1: I guess I Ask what for people to achieve what they aimed at and the game was definitely Aiming for that and fell short of what they themselves aimed for but not by that much not by that much.
Speaker 1: But I mean you know it's like I expect people to achieve what they expected themselves to achieve.
Speaker 0: You know maybe this is what they expected.
Speaker 0: I mean the game made money as far as I can tell.
Speaker 1: yeah Definitely mate.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: it was a good deal for them.
Speaker 1: No doubt, but you know I mean it's cuz.
Speaker 1: I mean it's like hard.
Speaker 1: I mean someone makes like you know a Tetris clone.
Speaker 1: You're a Tetris clone isn't a flow isn't a freeform MMO world.
Speaker 1: you suck.
Speaker 1: It's like well now that they they set out to make Tetris and they made Tetris.
Speaker 1: well They set out to make a game where you know you have this sort of.
Speaker 1: you know free Decision-making going on and there were parts that they did not make it all the way, and it was a little choppy.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 0: So can we say anything else about fallout?
Speaker 0: I mean we could go through all.
Speaker 0: it was awesome when such-and-such happened, and so it's not necessary.
Speaker 1: There's plenty of those.
Speaker 1: There's plenty of parts like that.
Speaker 1: You know I don't know.
Speaker 1: All right, I think the game.
Speaker 1: I think the biggest thing is that the that I have left to say is that the game Only has artificial replay value you know and that if you play it again You can like be a hacker instead of a. you know solve your problems with the computers instead of with the guns or solve it With lock picking instead of computers or something like that, but I have no desire to play it again.
Speaker 1: That none whatsoever.
Speaker 1: It's it's you know.
Speaker 1: But if it was a true, you know what a fully free thing.
Speaker 1: I'd probably play it forever.
Speaker 0: I guess it was just.
Speaker 0: it was more Oblivion II than I expected and that's just kind of a big turn.
Speaker 1: I don't know what this you know this oblivion game you keep talking about.
Speaker 1: I know nothing about it, so okay Yeah, that's great.
Speaker 0: Then yep Wow Scott This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.