Speaker 0: It's Monday January 19th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and this is geek nights tonight the overclocking.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well, I duly celebrated the day of the dr.
Speaker 1: Reverend Martin Luther King jr By going skiing which as a guy at the ski resort said to me when they were celebrating MLK day Celebrate the blackest day in the world in a good way because he was this awesome black guy By doing the whitest thing in the world This big black dude.
Speaker 0: apparently that this awesome like I'm the only kind of guy because at the same time right it's like Skeeto is good.
Speaker 0: Dad's got the double meaning of skiing snow white.
Speaker 0: but also Stereotypically white people are way more skiing than black Even though obviously that is not a hundred percent true because there was a black guy at the ski resort This guy was one of those like his face.
Speaker 0: It wasn't a resort as a mountain.
Speaker 1: No, it's also a resort.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: Can you stay there?
Speaker 0: Yeah in the cabin.
Speaker 1: In fact it because of the economy It's you can get a nice condo like on the slopes.
Speaker 1: I don't want a condo on a log cabin for like the weekend Log cabin for the weekend is like a hundred bucks a person.
Speaker 1: really her night.
Speaker 0: Oh a per person.
Speaker 0: so ten people in one cabin is the same as ten people If you go in the normal ones.
Speaker 1: You can also rent just a cabin and it's not that much like maybe For four or five hundred bucks total.
Speaker 1: we can have it for as many people as we can cram in for like a whole weekend.
Speaker 0: See if you're all shushing, but I was sitting in the cabin going.
Speaker 0: I like having.
Speaker 1: actually they got this big.
Speaker 0: There's not much that I like.
Speaker 1: better They got all these like indoor pool.
Speaker 0: I don't trust that because it might tip me out and spill me down the mountain while I'm sitting on the toilet.
Speaker 1: They also have for people who don't want to ski tubing with lifts.
Speaker 0: That's not too bad.
Speaker 1: you can like sled in two, but it's not even more dangerous though.
Speaker 1: It's on this tiny little like.
Speaker 1: You can't hurt yourself on that thing.
Speaker 1: That's me like the kids are there while the day.
Speaker 0: It's like if you do that on a ski hill you're gonna die.
Speaker 0: I like sitting in log cabins going.
Speaker 0: ah and I you know put on my little top hat pretend to be Abraham Lincoln.
Speaker 1: nope But this dude was like one of those old-school skiers like he had non-shaped skis But he had like these old like non-shaped skis which like I can't deal with those anymore.
Speaker 1: Like I don't even understand how people can ski on them.
Speaker 1: And he there was this crowd like they had this cool event last night about it.
Speaker 1: They had fireworks on the slopes right after and then today at 4 I left before you know the slopes closed But then they had a rail jam which was basically come and show off in the terrain park on your snowboards.
Speaker 1: Oh They have the halfpipe finished and all the awesome stuff, uh-huh yeah But I came home because I didn't want to be there all night especially in the dark in the cold outside.
Speaker 1: Well when I was a kid I never got to ski during the day because my parents didn't want to pay the 50 bucks.
Speaker 1: So they'd send me at night, and I'd ski from like 5 p.m.. To 10 p.m.. In the dark.
Speaker 1: I had a full face mask.
Speaker 1: What it's cold, but skiing was a little easier this time since actually People were saying that it was like the nicest day of skiing Hunter Mountain has had in like five years.
Speaker 0: It was like it did like it snowed like a bunch, and then it snowed a little bit and then yeah The snow is so powdery that the shovel guys used Leaf blowers instead of shovels.
Speaker 1: cuz I gotta tell you that when I got there You know I got there early.
Speaker 1: people don't usually show up to ski into like 10, so it was me like 15 other people in that first half hour.
Speaker 1: it was virgin powder.
Speaker 1: There was about three inches of that powder.
Speaker 1: It was beautiful.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I understand.
Speaker 1: I really understand now why people are like all the powder all the powder.
Speaker 0: Thing is I watched a video of skiing in Iran and that is it was like a dollar and it was like He's just like mountain with like a crappy old lift and like a shit ton of snow.
Speaker 1: Well the cool thing was it sucked because it was a holiday technically so I had to pay the extra couple bucks.
Speaker 1: It was like 65 bucks for my lift ticket mmm, but I could about a video game But good about two video games.
Speaker 1: it was MLK day like hardly anyone gets it off So there weren't that many people.
Speaker 0: Okay, the thing is the train station was like empty and they ran a weekend schedule and the trains were empty.
Speaker 0: So someone must have had the day off.
Speaker 1: yeah Well like a lot of people in urban areas get the day off, but like not everyone does I?
Speaker 1: Met like four different people today who all work in the stock market.
Speaker 1: They're like yeah stock holiday here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they all drove up from New York like well two of these people.
Speaker 1: they work down the street for me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there you go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was cool.
Speaker 1: But I Heard the same shoulder that I heard last time.
Speaker 1: I just healed it.
Speaker 0: Maybe you should get a soldier surgery.
Speaker 0: No, get the baseball shoulder surgery.
Speaker 0: It'll be stronger.
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 1: no it's.
Speaker 1: it's not the same thing, but you know, what's dumb I was doing like the Black Diamonds and I did.
Speaker 1: I got in over my head a little bit But I never fell once and all the crazy hard slopes because I was trying real hard.
Speaker 1: I was real careful.
Speaker 0: Then you went on the bunny hill and you fell over during a lot of these hard slopes.
Speaker 1: I was thinking the whole time don't fall don't fall don't fall.
Speaker 1: Oh shit Once I came around on a it looked like it was an easy one.
Speaker 1: It was this Black Diamond, but like goes around this nice gentle like around the corner There's moguls, but I can just kind of avoid the moguls.
Speaker 1: and then I come around the corner like around this sharp Like hairpin turn and I turn and it's like straight down and I couldn't stop in time.
Speaker 1: So I went straight down.
Speaker 1: I must have been going like 50 miles an hour and then at the end there was a bump and I jumped like six feet in the air and In the air.
Speaker 1: my brain thought like like time slowed down.
Speaker 1: It was like heartbeat fuck heartbeat fuck Heartbeat, I think I'm gonna make it heartbeat.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: There's another bump heartbeat.
Speaker 1: I'm in the air again.
Speaker 1: I totally made it and I thought alright that was that was too much.
Speaker 1: That was I risked it.
Speaker 1: I made it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go eat some lunch.
Speaker 1: so I go past the ski lift and I take like the easy bunny trail down and Then I totally fall out of my ass and hurt my shoulder.
Speaker 1: I'm like the bunny is bunny trail I told you because I wasn't paying attention.
Speaker 1: I was like, oh man, I'm such an awesome ski up BAM No one even saw it.
Speaker 1: I was all alone like in this little bunny trail like off by the side.
Speaker 1: There's like the go slow family skiing area there.
Speaker 1: It's like man.
Speaker 0: That's something though If you're up on the mountain with not a lot of other people The ski patrol might not notice if you hurt yourself Because someone's gonna patrol will notice.
Speaker 1: in fact because they patrol all the slopes like on a regular Basis and they spend a lot of time in the places where people tend to hurt themselves.
Speaker 1: And actually I was riding up with the ski patrol guy.
Speaker 1: It was funny because the whole time like someone got hurt real bad actually.
Speaker 1: But I got to listen to his radio and he was like, yeah I can ignore it until I get to the top because what am I gonna do?
Speaker 1: I'm on the lift.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that's the fastest way to the top.
Speaker 0: It was constantly was like should have like an emergency button though that makes the lift go fast.
Speaker 1: like Well, there is one lift that goes real fast.
Speaker 1: All the other ones go kind of slow but the whole time it was like Level whatever.
Speaker 1: someone reported hurt on this trail on this trail.
Speaker 1: send one guy send two guys.
Speaker 1: people got hurt like every two minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's that's how it's a dangerous thing shushing on the van.
Speaker 1: But I feel like if I had needed help on that bunny trail.
Speaker 1: I don't think they're patrolling that bunny trail because you can't hurt yourself on the bunny trail.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean you could have landed face first in the snow and like just twisted your neck the wrong way by random chance.
Speaker 0: I'm like maybe a hidden rock and then your face would have been in the snow.
Speaker 0: You've been suffocating and bleeding and your teeth falling out.
Speaker 1: There's no hidden rocks on the bunny.
Speaker 0: There's a hidden rock.
Speaker 1: There's nobody.
Speaker 1: I put it there but yeah as a result, you know skiing.
Speaker 1: I've only skied a couple times this winter.
Speaker 1: I'm 27 now and I feel like that's old and I feel like my body I don't recover as quick like when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: Like I would go skiing like from 5 p.m.
Speaker 1: To 10 p.m.
Speaker 1: Like I'd fall over like a hundred times Like I would push myself to the limit and be on cartilage first bone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we know about this.
Speaker 1: the next day I'd feel great.
Speaker 1: In fact when I got home at like midnight, I'd feel great And then I'd stay out playing like the realm or something.
Speaker 1: I don't feel so high right now.
Speaker 1: I gotta get some sleep.
Speaker 0: I also Feel ill in but I don't know I am ill in or not.
Speaker 0: We'll find.
Speaker 1: what do you have to be ill in about?
Speaker 0: Got in the train to go home, but I was just so tired.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should do a quick show.
Speaker 1: No, so, uh, it's tech day.
Speaker 1: What's the news?
Speaker 0: I got this amazing news.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's not it's not really a news, but I don't give a shit, right?
Speaker 0: So there's a guy and Let's see.
Speaker 0: Oh, it has his name here.
Speaker 0: His name is Matt Knox right like Fort Knox, but Matt and he is a quote talented Ruby instructor and coder.
Speaker 0: But in his early days, he worked for direct revenue.
Speaker 0: direct revenue was an adware company The one that got sued by Elliot Spitzer when he was still Attorney General of New York.
Speaker 1: Oh back when he was doing awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah back when he was doing awesome before he started doing poop, right?
Speaker 0: So this interview with this adware guy is like one of the most fascinating Articles that I've read in a long time because this guy is clearly a high quality computer scientist, right?
Speaker 0: He talks about like and the way I can tell is because apparently he deployed scheme With the adware and he's pretty sure that's the largest scheme deployment ever.
Speaker 0: But he talks about how the adware worked and how they avoided removal and detection and how they were able to remove the other adwares and how Their adware was actually a little bit, you know still shady but a little bit more legitimate than the other adware Which is just blatantly hacking you.
Speaker 0: this would basically install when you installed it and uninstall when you uninstalled it It's just when it was installed it, you know kicked your ass and filled you with ads and shit.
Speaker 1: Wow So there's a tiny amount of honor among thieves the funniest.
Speaker 0: the funniest thing He talks about actually that I thought was the most interesting was how when he on when you uninstalled Right, which you could only do through their uninstall process.
Speaker 0: No adware removers didn't do the trick, right?
Speaker 0: They would put a registry key in.
Speaker 0: they had registry keys while it was installed But when they uninstalled they removed all the registry keys But they put one behind they left one behind and that one was so that their program would never install again.
Speaker 0: You know because if someone you know, so let's say you uninstalled and then you try to install again It would see that registry key and you'd be safe.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, right, but adware removers were stupid and the adware removers would remove that registry key.
Speaker 0: Thus if you would uninstall it by the normal means then use an adware remover and then it would install again.
Speaker 1: Wow Yeah, I can still only blame the spyware and not the adware removal software.
Speaker 0: Of course, of course But you know, it's weird how the world went from.
Speaker 1: adware removal Didn't need to exist - it existed in works - it really just doesn't work anymore.
Speaker 0: Like if you really get if you get any virus or any adware or anything You can use a tool to remove it and you might be pretty sure that it's removed.
Speaker 0: You can do a lot of things to look and see if it's removed, you know, you can do some Wireshark.
Speaker 0: I guess it's called to look at you know, your network traffic to see if any spyware is going out.
Speaker 1: Yes, Ethereal was renamed to Wireshark due to a - I should tell that story on a Monday show sometime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, but you know, you can do all sorts of things to check if the adware was removed But you can't be a hundred percent sure.
Speaker 0: you could be a hundred percent sure you've got it But no matter how many cleaners you run you can never be a hundred percent sure you've gotten rid of it.
Speaker 0: You can be like 90% sure like hey, I ran three adware removal tools and two virus tools.
Speaker 0: They don't detect anything.
Speaker 0: You can be 90% sure you got rid of it 100%.
Speaker 1: the ways to be 100% sure are ways that involve external checking that are also 100% impractical.
Speaker 0: Yes so if you get any virus or any malware any adware my recommendation to you is to just erase your entire hard drive and then reinstall your operating system and You should have backups right because they.
Speaker 0: installing an operating system like takes 20 minutes.
Speaker 0: It takes no time at all.
Speaker 0: It's really really easy.
Speaker 0: I mean Windows 7 actually like it still is not as easy as Ubuntu because you have to restart a few times But the it was really easy.
Speaker 0: It was like they definitely learned from Ubuntu's installer and it's just as good as the Ubuntu installer despite having a couple extra Restarts and take it a little bit longer.
Speaker 0: That's the only difference.
Speaker 0: so
Speaker 1: people one thing to keep in mind if you've got a Windows box, I've said this before ever everyone smart says this but Install Windows on the C partition and give it enough space and always give it a bunch of extra because it's gonna need more Space and like temp files and things.
Speaker 1: you don't want to mess with that.
Speaker 1: There are ways around that.
Speaker 1: but don't bother Make another partition and put all your other data like your mp3s and crap there.
Speaker 1: Yep, that way you can reinstall without losing any of that And as long as nothing on that drive is executables or even if they are Executables.
Speaker 1: if they don't get run again, then you can just reinstall the OS and not lose anything.
Speaker 1: But you know all the application stuff you've got to reinstall.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's reinstalling applications is cake.
Speaker 0: I mean, what do you really have to install like Firefox an instant message clients?
Speaker 0: Let's say pigeon, right?
Speaker 0: You know some Firefox extensions flash Maybe a bit torrent client right.
Speaker 0: that takes what like 20 minutes?
Speaker 1: Well, you might have some specialized stuff But even then even then you don't install it.
Speaker 0: see people make the mistake when they reinstall their OS They sit there for hours and hours reinstalling every single program.
Speaker 0: Don't do that.
Speaker 0: Just reinstall the programs as you use them.
Speaker 0: So you're sitting at your computer.
Speaker 0: It's a brand new Windows, right?
Speaker 0: First thing you got to do I got to go to the web install Firefox.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, this ads install adblock.
Speaker 0: I got to talk to my friend now install aim.
Speaker 1: I want to sync my iPod now install it and automatically make sure that you and it's kind of like.
Speaker 1: one of the main reasons reinstalling Windows always makes it fast like people say Vista or you know The new Windows 7 beta are super fast.
Speaker 1: take Windows 2000 and install it fresh and it's real fast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, any windows is real fast - it's a fresh install.
Speaker 0: It just slows down over time.
Speaker 1: any NT based window, right?
Speaker 0: I mean Windows 7 if you actually used it for a long time might get slow might?
Speaker 0: we don't know I mean, but every other Windows has.
Speaker 1: yeah, but It's kind of like.
Speaker 1: part of what reinstalling does is you start with the clean slate.
Speaker 1: So why not always try to keep your computer as clean slate as possible?
Speaker 0: Oh the one thing you should yeah The one thing you shouldn't wait on is Windows updates.
Speaker 0: do every single Windows update immediately all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty much when I install a computer.
Speaker 1: It's all the windows updates and you know.
Speaker 1: Well first if they're you know, the motherboard driver if you have a motherboard driver or any of those things Yeah, and then well Windows update now actually takes care of your drivers like it takes care of like from my computer.
Speaker 0: It does the real Nvidia driver.
Speaker 0: It does like the real network card driver.
Speaker 0: It does like.
Speaker 0: it takes care of that shit.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 1: But yeah, anyway This is a real.
Speaker 1: I actually read this too.
Speaker 0: The computer science parts of the article are just really fascinating like how the like the windows process security flaws and All these, you know file system tricks where he's like using Unicode in the registries that the keys can't be seen and it's While he's doing evil things.
Speaker 0: the techniques that he's using are like like really amazing.
Speaker 1: It's just really cool to see it from this perspective where it's not like reverse engineering or speculating or you know Figuring out what they did.
Speaker 1: It's someone saying this is what we did and why check it out.
Speaker 1: Yep but in other news this I don't want to talk about this in super depth because the issues that would be brought up are many.
Speaker 1: I mean we could do a whole show about this, but There is a a problem that Barack Obama is Running into whereby due to the way our government works and the way technology is and the way politics are He has a blackberry.
Speaker 1: he's a hip tech guy like he's.
Speaker 0: Yes, people I mean he's probably not a computer science genius, but I think he has some Smart tech people working for him and he knows enough.
Speaker 0: He's not.
Speaker 0: he doesn't know as much as us but he knows more than any president ever and possibly and significantly more than most other Federal elected officials, he knows more than most of the congressman and he knows a lot.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure I would call him computer literate.
Speaker 0: Definitely.
Speaker 1: In fact, he's probably above average in that regard.
Speaker 0: But yeah, he can rock the face.
Speaker 0: He can make a podcast.
Speaker 0: He can rock a Facebook and he can send a blackberry.
Speaker 0: That's more than George Bush with his AOL's.
Speaker 1: That's the problem.
Speaker 1: He uses a blackberry and the Secret Service and the government and everyone are basically saying Barack You can't keep using the blackberry.
Speaker 1: for all these reasons Security is a concern and data retention is a concern and privacy is a concern.
Speaker 1: and He got a bunch of lawyers together and he was trying to fight to say look how can we get around this?
Speaker 1: I really want my blackberry.
Speaker 0: I like to see the thing was he got a bunch of lawyers.
Speaker 0: He should have gotten a bunch of computer scientists.
Speaker 0: They would have figured it out.
Speaker 1: No, it's not a matter of figuring it out.
Speaker 1: It's not a matter of having a technological solution.
Speaker 1: This is the root problem here.
Speaker 1: No Technological solution is even on the table.
Speaker 1: The problem is the politics and the bureaucracy and the fact that our government is a government of Luddites, I mean Congress is so technologically archaic.
Speaker 1: It's not laughable.
Speaker 1: It's frightening and What bothers me and this just kind of brings it all to light.
Speaker 1: is that?
Speaker 1: why isn't there?
Speaker 1: Why do people need to use a blackberry if you're the president or you're in Congress?
Speaker 1: Shouldn't there be a blackberry equivalent that is just for people in the federal government in that is Encrypted and controlled by the government and everything's archived and you know keeps it forever super secure?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean every even the crappiest offices in you know, like just just normal offices have exchange servers, right?
Speaker 0: Why doesn't Congress at least have an exchange server?
Speaker 1: But what no?
Speaker 1: go one step further?
Speaker 1: Why don't they at least at least I'm talking about portable.
Speaker 1: Imagine if and this wouldn't even cost that much to do the government designed or hired people to design a Blackberry like device that was only to be used by high government officials.
Speaker 0: You wouldn't even need a different device.
Speaker 1: No, no make up make a new device, you know that way it meets all though There's a lot of weird standards and things.
Speaker 1: you just put different software on an existing device you could but then they always worry about Who makes the devices and they could be compromised at the hardware firmware level.
Speaker 0: and oh, it's BS.
Speaker 1: No stuff like that has happened before.
Speaker 0: let's get the palm free.
Speaker 0: No one knows about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, the idea is what if every member of Congress had a special blackberry like device that was super RSA style.
Speaker 1: Whatever encryption, you know three-factor authentication, you know thumbprint pin.
Speaker 0: No Congress people would know how to use it.
Speaker 0: It'd be like that doctor who threw his printer in the garbage.
Speaker 1: Well, you force them to use it and you make it anyway Even if they don't use it eventually they'll all die and there will be people who will use it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean think of this.
Speaker 0: by then though.
Speaker 0: We won't have that anymore.
Speaker 0: We'll have something better.
Speaker 0: So it would have been a waste?
Speaker 1: no wouldn't because then that member Congress will still be a whole technological generation behind and having this Even in a primitive form in the future is better than what they'll have.
Speaker 1: Otherwise in the future.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I mean imagine if right now if Congress is out of session and there's an emergency What the president can do something but it's gonna take a while to get Congress together.
Speaker 1: What if they all got paged on a little blackberry?
Speaker 1: they open it They can read these super secret important thing and then they can like vote on the emergency thing right then and there
Speaker 0: because we wouldn't be on c-span
Speaker 1: Doesn't matter it's archived and then have the semi live redacted RSS and Twitter feed of what's going on in Congress.
Speaker 1: Yeah Just this the fact that this is an issue Opens up a whole bunch of problems that are just.
Speaker 1: our government does not use technology efficiently and if it did we could solve all of these problems trivially.
Speaker 1: and I don't want to talk about this news anymore because I really think we just need to have a computer.
Speaker 0: be the government.
Speaker 0: You know like in every bad sci-fi where eventually the computer decides to kill everyone like paranoia or you know, Phoenix future It'll take it a while before it tries to kill everyone.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So in the meantime, it's great.
Speaker 0: I mean, how do you think those places end up like that?
Speaker 0: You know, how do you end up in Logan's run?
Speaker 0: because the computer is great for a long time So everyone loves it and then eventually it turns evil.
Speaker 1: Are you are you implying that the computer is evil?
Speaker 1: Do you not trust the computer?
Speaker 1: Are you not a happy citizen?
Speaker 0: No, because by the time the computer turns evil I'll be dead.
Speaker 0: So it's all good.
Speaker 1: But implying that the computer could turn evil.
Speaker 1: Are you a communist?
Speaker 1: No I Deny the fact that they're communist.
Speaker 0: Well, I like.
Speaker 0: I like free market computing.
Speaker 0: you like equal opportunity computing.
Speaker 1: But yeah I want to do a show about this sometime in the future because I have like six points That each of which will take me a while to get out related to this article.
Speaker 1: But suffice to say read this article and read all the concerns that they have pointed out.
Speaker 1: I mean, there are a lot of concerns rain and the one that bothers me is they're worried that If the president uses something like a blackberry then everything he does personal would be recorded somewhere and then later Maybe that could all be dug up in case he was doing shady stuff to which I say good Transparency, I feel like if you're a government official There should be a certain expectation that you give up a lot of your privacy as long as you are Something like a president or a member of Congress.
Speaker 1: Like I feel like one of the prices of doing the job is think about a lot of your rights while you're doing the job.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I mean think about this right?
Speaker 0: I work for my boss, right?
Speaker 0: Well while I work for you know, my boss my boss can look at my work email.
Speaker 0: All right, and whatever right?
Speaker 0: now if You're the president Everyone is your boss.
Speaker 0: So everyone should be able to see your work email.
Speaker 0: Now you do have.
Speaker 0: there are no email for example outside of work.
Speaker 1: There are other exceptions to for example the email that you send saying effectively So the agents that are stationed in X are doing Y for Z right now, correct?
Speaker 1: We got to hold off on that until that situation is resolved.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm okay with that.
Speaker 0: You don't need to show it to everyone.
Speaker 0: You just need to Put it somewhere.
Speaker 1: Yes on a hard drive and then wait until you know, it doesn't matter anymore.
Speaker 1: then reveal it all.
Speaker 0: Our government in general is just terrible about waiting and then showing.
Speaker 0: it's like they just wait forever.
Speaker 0: They never show.
Speaker 0: There's like World War one shit.
Speaker 0: They haven't shown.
Speaker 0: it's like what the fuck guys is.
Speaker 0: it doesn't matter anymore.
Speaker 0: Yes cough it the fuck up.
Speaker 0: It's of historical significance.
Speaker 1: what so we betrayed?
Speaker 0: it's not historically significant.
Speaker 0: What's your reason to hide it?
Speaker 1: So we betrayed the Prussians.
Speaker 1: so under whoopty freakin do there's no more Prussia.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what are they gonna do about it once something's old?
Speaker 0: I don't care how secret it is.
Speaker 0: cough it up.
Speaker 1: But anyway read the articles and sometime in the future we're gonna talk about this in more depth.
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: We'll see how long we go in this episode since we're both kind of fading fast.
Speaker 0: Well speaking of government not doing so well with technology FCC.
Speaker 1: Ah the FCC You should be disbanded and remade.
Speaker 0: Yeah, did I use this already?
Speaker 0: Oh crap.
Speaker 1: Ah, good job.
Speaker 0: Let me go check.
Speaker 0: good game.
Speaker 1: Alright, I'll talk about mine.
Speaker 1: So this is just a picture.
Speaker 1: That's all it is.
Speaker 1: It's I'm pretty sure it's World War one vintage.
Speaker 1: I'd imagine it's in Britain.
Speaker 1: Just this.
Speaker 1: I'm guessing that it's in Britain, but it could theoretically be somewhere else.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go with Britain and it's a whole bunch of kids and a few soldiers and things all wearing gas masks Doing a parade and they've got a little like machine gun and a bunch of flags and a little armored car.
Speaker 0: I'm not an armored car.
Speaker 1: I'm not really sure of the context.
Speaker 1: I'm not really sure what's going on.
Speaker 1: If this is a demonstration a photo op a drill what but it is one of the creepiest pictures I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm World War one gas masks are one of the few things that creep me out just a little bit Like it's very scary like it may if I woke up, you know Just like I woke up in the morning and I saw a World War one gas mask.
Speaker 1: I might yell At least a little.
Speaker 0: I should get one Hanging on the ceiling in your room or wear it in the morning.
Speaker 0: wake you up.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like that.
Speaker 1: We had a friend at RIT was afraid of clowns and we always had this sinister idea of getting a little chip with a speaker That would play very quietly And just leave it somewhere in his bedroom to activate like a week later.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's very much like truck one of those things that's funny, but you never actually do it because it doesn't actually work.
Speaker 0: It could work.
Speaker 1: I've never seen truck work.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so the FCC if I did this already, fuck you.
Speaker 0: I'm tired.
Speaker 0: Basically we complain about the FCC now because of stupid shit like, you know Censorship of radio and broadcast television, which is I say not their area.
Speaker 0: But they should not be dealing with that.
Speaker 0: All right, they should only be concerned with.
Speaker 0: you know, two people on the same frequency fucking each other up, you know They also have a lot of other problems, you know allowing cable television cartels Not doing net neutrality and making you know, ISPs utility.
Speaker 0: Oh, they're they're not so great.
Speaker 0: Right a lot of problems, but apparently most of these problems we see in the context of you know, the now apparently way back in 1974 as Former FCC general counsel Henry Geller did a paper called a modest proposal to reform the Federal Communications Commission.
Speaker 0: So this shit has been fucked up for a long time like before cassette tapes.
Speaker 0: a long time, right?
Speaker 0: 1974 man, that's ancient.
Speaker 0: It's like Disco.
Speaker 0: and he was saying man FCC's fucked up when all they had was radio Speaking of which though disco needs to come back in a big way anyway.
Speaker 0: Well, the FCC can take care of that cuz they'll just regulate the radio and say no music except this But all this music can be yours.
Speaker 0: Anyway, only disco No, so there's this website called FCC dash reform org.
Speaker 0: that has this paper from 1974 which is just revealed as well as a lot of other videos and papers by prominent people of you know former FCC people intellectuals professors lawyers all kinds of people and they all say Basically FCC's corrupt got to fix it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what's wrong?
Speaker 0: Come on, let's go.
Speaker 0: So you know if you ever want to argue with someone or you know or want to have a discussion about the FCC and why it Needs to be reformed.
Speaker 1: point out that in our world have a discussion means argue.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you if you will thinking about writing a letter to like the FCC or your congressman to talk about reforming the FCC Cuz you know, there's a new Congress right now.
Speaker 0: Go to this site.
Speaker 0: Do your research.
Speaker 0: write a little letter.
Speaker 0: You're all good All right All right, so I'm pretty sure we didn't do a show on this already.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna talk that long about it either because we're fading fast But we'll probably do another show along similar lines in the future.
Speaker 1: But got to talk a little bit about the OC the OC the overclock.
Speaker 1: You see I could make a graph of it's a graph that shows usefulness on one on the X Y axis and Year on the X axis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see a lot of people out there, you know, they like computer hardware They like buying parts on Newegg putting a computer together, right and they like to overclock.
Speaker 0: They overclock the video card.
Speaker 0: They overclock the CPU.
Speaker 0: They do a little RAM clock, right?
Speaker 0: You know and I did that back in the day and I understand, you know how it could be sort of interesting and maybe fun.
Speaker 0: But from a practical perspective if you are in the current day 2009 if you want to build a personal computer on the x86 platform All right, pretty much any plan actually any common personal computer architecture And you want to actually use that computer for a long time and get your money's worth.
Speaker 0: Overclocking is really stupid.
Speaker 1: Now before anyone gets, you know, I'll get their pennies in a wad or any of that.
Speaker 1: just Hobbyist overclocking is cool.
Speaker 1: Like any other.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean when you see like, you know new egg guys doing a Demonstration where they get like the liquid nitrogen out and they get the CPU up to like eight gigahertz.
Speaker 0: So some crazy shit going on.
Speaker 0: That's cool, but they never intended that computer to actually be used.
Speaker 0: They just did it for you know, the demonstration purposes, you know That wasn't a computer that you saved up fifteen hundred dollars for and bought and now plan to play games on for five years.
Speaker 0: All right, that was a computer for a cool demonstration in which case overclocking is a pretty neat demonstration.
Speaker 1: Now the reason overclocking isn't really why it's not useful anymore.
Speaker 1: Is that one for most purposes?
Speaker 1: Computers are a lot faster than you need them to be and for gaming It's so cheap to upgrade like the time it takes to overclock and set up the cooling and then the risk Versus buying a new component like a good example is.
Speaker 1: I did try overclocking my video card my current video card.
Speaker 1: I have a g4 7900 whatever.
Speaker 1: No, and it's it's not really fast enough.
Speaker 1: like if I play left for dead every now and then my frame rate will drop and And like fallout 3 the frame rate drops in like four different places where it really gets to me Like four parts of the game like in the tree plays like I can't walk around in there.
Speaker 1: It's really bad.
Speaker 1: You can turn the settings down, you know, yeah, but I didn't really want to do that.
Speaker 0: So that's what they're there for.
Speaker 1: So for on a lark I use the utility and I overclock my video card and I got about 10 more frames a second.
Speaker 1: and then I looked online and I can buy a video card that will get me Way more than 10 more frames a second for like 80 bucks.
Speaker 1: Yep See like back in the day and while it was overclocked my case overheated an hour later.
Speaker 0: Yeah, while right back in the day like a quality video card was $300.
Speaker 0: But right now you can go and buy an Nvidia 9800 GT for like 120 bucks.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much.
Speaker 0: I have an 8800 GT with my 8800 GT and my middle-of-the-road core to duo I think three gigahertz core to duo no overclocking whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Completely standard retail cooling equipment, right?
Speaker 0: I can play the crisis demo the infamous crisis.
Speaker 0: I played the demo with everything turned all the way up at 1680 by 1050 at Vertical sync with no drop-offs.
Speaker 0: if I would have had a 9800 GT instead of the 8800 GT It would only be better than that.
Speaker 0: And this is also on the infamous Vista, which is less performance Right.
Speaker 0: So why would I overclock if I can get you know max?
Speaker 0: Basically performance in what I'm gonna do with Standard equipment in this case.
Speaker 1: There is one Situation where overclocking might be somewhat useful But then again, it's a calculated risk and you really got to think about it.
Speaker 1: Say you're in late high school or early college and you all your gamer Gaming PC's a little old and you're real poor like right now for us.
Speaker 1: We have plenty of money in no time.
Speaker 1: So overclocking is completely dumb because for the time it takes to overclock I could make enough money in my job.
Speaker 1: You just buy all the components.
Speaker 0: and I mean if I bought nothing but computers.
Speaker 0: Oh My god, I could buy like five computers a month.
Speaker 1: and I remember like one thing I did at RIT a couple times.
Speaker 1: I just sat down and thought and they would all be the god of God.
Speaker 1: I thought if money were no object What kind of computer would I build?
Speaker 1: I would build like an $8,000 computer online and just look at it nowadays.
Speaker 1: even then $4,000 is a supercomputer.
Speaker 0: I bought an $800 desktop and I bought it about a $2,000 laptop But it's not $2,000 anymore.
Speaker 1: My current computer is $1,200 including the widescreen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess that's tough.
Speaker 0: Yeah If I'm not counting my monitor or my speakers or any of my other equipment that I brought over from the past plus I went Real high-end on this computer when I bought it.
Speaker 1: so not on the video card though No, but at the time this computer is real old.
Speaker 1: actually now, it's over a year old You should just buy the 9800 GT.
Speaker 0: I was talking about I'm going to.
Speaker 1: actually I bought this computer the one I'm using now.
Speaker 1: That's still stupidly fast When I still work to that hospital, it's been way over a year.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and it's doing fine.
Speaker 1: but yet if you if you have a lot more money than time and You're willing to either spend the time to research and make sure that your cooling is set up, right and you're willing to risk possibly having to reinstall windows after you screw it up and You are willing to risk the fact that you may screw up your hardware
Speaker 0: And have to buy a new computer then.
Speaker 1: Yeah overclocking isn't that bad of an idea But really only if you have more money than time or you're a hobbyist and you're doing it for the sake of doing it As opposed to for a practical reason, I
Speaker 0: guess there's also the case right where let's say you're poor right and but you have a computer, but it's not fast enough and You're willing to lose the computer, right?
Speaker 0: So it's an old computer.
Speaker 0: you can overclock that beast and maybe try to make it more useful than it currently is.
Speaker 0: You know, it's already old, you know.
Speaker 0: But I guess you just have to be willing to recognize.
Speaker 1: you might break it and have to buy a new one like old Athlon Like, you know the k7s the 800 megahertz the the durons and all those you can overclock the hell out of them.
Speaker 0: I'll see that's the.
Speaker 0: that's the thing right back in our day in the earlier part of the decade.
Speaker 0: Right the Athlon era the Pentium 4 era, right?
Speaker 0: It was like getting a chip.
Speaker 0: That was one step faster was a lot of money.
Speaker 0: Oh, and it wasn't just because we were poor in those days.
Speaker 0: It actually was a lot more money.
Speaker 0: So Overclocking, you know, if you looked at the price and performance and the risk of things and then that time in history Overclocking was a great idea because more likely than not it was gonna work, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean think you're gonna get a huge performance increase in a time where software was a lot more demanding than Hardware could put up and you could hope like there were avenues of overclocking that don't matter as much now like back then.
Speaker 1: There were like the front side bus was like the biggest bottleneck in the world.
Speaker 1: now It's not as much of a yeah.
Speaker 0: now with DDR like DDR3 It's not really a problem.
Speaker 0: so much the RAM speed, you know, but now with PCI x16 and you know instead of oh You know AGP 2x that's not really a problem either.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Plus.
Speaker 1: I mean, I remember very specifically I had an Athlon 800 megahertz.
Speaker 1: the Athlon like gigahertz Was more than twice as much money at the time.
Speaker 1: so I could buy two of the chip I got and Wreck one of them and still be still and I could overclock it to be faster than the chip I didn't buy because it was too expensive.
Speaker 1: Yep So I did.
Speaker 1: I overclocked my 800 to about 933.
Speaker 0: but nowadays unless you're doing like Pixar type work or running Maya or something crazy or deck of like a giant painting in Photoshop or something like You like to play the benchmark game though only if you're playing it as a game.
Speaker 1: benchmarks are basically useless.
Speaker 0: Yeah, unless you're doing something like that, right like a core 2 duo is gonna do everything you need hardware.
Speaker 0: these days It's way ahead of the software.
Speaker 0: That's why we're seeing this netbook surgeons because 90% of what people do can be accomplished with really low horsepower.
Speaker 0: So getting more horsepower Especially at the risk of having to spend more money is really bad idea.
Speaker 0: when you don't need the extra horsepower is suddenly Applications started getting more demanding again and suddenly, you know The chips weren't fast enough to do everyday things like they.
Speaker 0: you know They weren't fast enough in the olden days right where you'd get skipping just like watching a video or something.
Speaker 0: Then maybe overclock would become a good idea again, but it's not so it's not.
Speaker 1: of course.
Speaker 1: remember to I Like I did the crazy air cooling and like I set my case up awesome.
Speaker 1: It sounded like a jet engine and I overclocked my AMD quite a bit.
Speaker 1: I also overclocked my video card quite a bit and that computer crash About twice a week when it was overclocked and it didn't.
Speaker 1: when it wasn't overclocked it also My windows installation due to these crashes would become corrupt to the point that I would have to reinstall About once every four months.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it was clearly due to the overclocking.
Speaker 1: and in fact the overclocking and the heat Accelerated the death of my motherboard when eventually the capacitors exploded due to the Unrelated Chinese bootleg problem back in the day.
Speaker 0: Yeah nowadays if you get a motherboard with the solid-state capacitors That specific problem will be less but the unreliability is still a major issue.
Speaker 0: the other thing you got to worry about when the overclocking is the cooling.
Speaker 0: the cooling is big because You know when you overclock something it's gonna make more heat.
Speaker 0: That's the reality of physics, right?
Speaker 0: So you want to make sure you have more cooling.
Speaker 0: if you overclock that way, you know, you got that extra safety there.
Speaker 0: Maybe it'll even be a hundred percent reliable.
Speaker 0: Maybe right.
Speaker 0: The thing is if you buy say a Quad-core right it comes.
Speaker 0: if you buy a retail one it comes with this heatsink.
Speaker 0: that heatsink It comes with that has the Intel sticker on it.
Speaker 0: It's the Intel.
Speaker 0: I guess it's.
Speaker 0: I don't know if Intel makes those things but it's Intel brand.
Speaker 0: heatsink is Super-quiet and can cool the chip perfectly if you don't overclock.
Speaker 0: So there's no reason to use anything else unless you overclock.
Speaker 0: Anything else is gonna be bigger and louder Unless you get water cooling in which case it will be quieter But it'll be a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: You're gonna risk getting water everywhere if you don't know what you're doing and it's gonna be real expensive.
Speaker 0: and you know Even with water cooling right water cooling might, you know be quieter and cooler But you have used more electricity on the stupid condenser thingy that cools the water.
Speaker 1: Well, the main reason I ever had for water cooling when I really thought about doing I ended up not doing it Was that I wanted a computer that was quiet so I could use it as a media PC, but now a Mac Mini is silent
Speaker 0: yeah, but even so if you have a computer in your room in the same room that you sleep in or even a different room than You sleep in it's still really like people don't you know?
Speaker 0: know until they have a quiet computer It's real nice to have a computer that doesn't make a lot of noise.
Speaker 0: I mean If you start like when I start playing a game, you know like when I play Fallout 3 the video card fans start going faster and faster and faster and they start to make a little bit of noise and it is Bothers them because like I hear them and they sort of interfere with the game I'm playing where I want to hear what's in the game, you know, so a quieter computer is always better.
Speaker 0: Oh, unless it's like a server rack kind of computer in which case, you know, it could be fucking loud as you want.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, every rack about computer is loud as all work.
Speaker 1: They were setting up some switches.
Speaker 0: They're like new Cisco things and you turn them on and they're just so fucking loud.
Speaker 1: Well when you turn them on at first because they have variable fan speed depending on the environment So they'll.
Speaker 0: they'll when they have variable span fan speed between jet engine and Concorde.
Speaker 1: No, they're actually pretty quiet.
Speaker 1: But when you turn them on before you can figure them they default to the fastest.
Speaker 1: So literally I hear this jet engine take off and everyone the whole office is looking like what the fuck is that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, my computer when you turn it on like for a few seconds It goes full speed but then it comes back down.
Speaker 0: once the BIOS gets going, you know back to normal manage speed.
Speaker 0: Yep Yeah, I'll see.
Speaker 0: you gotta remember, you know your power supply Your video card and your CPU fan are the sources of most of the noise.
Speaker 0: So you really want to get quiet power supply quiet video card?
Speaker 0: standard retail comes with the chip CPU fan for the maximum quietness and if Overclocking gets you like five frames a second, but as a result, everything's louder or more expensive.
Speaker 0: Was it really worth it?
Speaker 0: I mean you could pay $50 for you know a water cooling kit or you could pay $50 For one chip faster than what you got.
Speaker 0: so what?
Speaker 0: why did you buy the water cool?
Speaker 0: Okay, you could have just gotten a faster chip in the first place.
Speaker 0: Now water Overclocking for practical purposes is now dead.
Speaker 0: There's really no reason to do it anymore except for you know fun and not for actual computer use.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I see a lot of people buy new computers buy an extra heatsinks You know talking about how they're gonna overclock and these people do not have enough money to buy five computers a month.
Speaker 1: so The danger is not as much as it used to be.
Speaker 1: actually you're not it's not yes likely.
Speaker 0: Why take the risk?
Speaker 0: It's on.
Speaker 0: it's like risk for no reason, you know.
Speaker 0: It's might not be a big risk in some cases.
Speaker 0: It might only be a little risk, but it's greater than zero.
Speaker 0: Why bother?
Speaker 0: Why what is?
Speaker 0: what are you getting for it, you know, nothing.
Speaker 0: it's not worth it.
Speaker 1: but on that note going to bed I'm going immediately to bed.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio.
Speaker 0: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.