Speaker 1: It's Thursday, August 6th.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights Tonight, Kineticon 2009, where we ran every panel in panel 5.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So, about five seconds ago, we recorded the third take of the opening to this episode, and I failed at it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because we got nothing.
Speaker 1: Previously, I also failed at it, and before that, we combinedly failed at it.
Speaker 0: There's nothing going on.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: I'm not saving it for an outtake.
Speaker 1: It's just gone.
Speaker 1: I deleted it.
Speaker 1: I destroyed information.
Speaker 0: It's a convention recovery week.
Speaker 0: We're going to work.
Speaker 0: We're coming home.
Speaker 0: We're going to bed.
Speaker 0: There is nothing.
Speaker 1: Well, I got one thing, though, because, you know, my car has been busted for, like, ever.
Speaker 1: So, I was, like, biking to work and staying in Emily's apartment because it's closer to the train, and I could walk down there, because it's, like, two and a half miles to the train station from here, and, you know, my bike got stolen.
Speaker 1: So, I'm walking back from the train station yesterday, and it takes, like, you know, 20 minutes to walk home.
Speaker 1: And along the way...
Speaker 0: I thought you rollerbladed.
Speaker 1: Well, no, yesterday, I walked.
Speaker 1: Today, I rollerbladed.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So, yesterday, you know, I'm walking and all I can think in my head... You know, I see a kid riding by on his bike and I just hear da-da-ra-da-ra-da da... the Pee Weez big adventure theme just in my head.
Speaker 1: I'm, like, scoping every kid out, like, "Is that my bike?
Speaker 1: Is that my bike?
Speaker 1: Where's my bike?
Speaker 1: Son of a bitch.
Speaker 1: my bike somewhere.
Speaker 1: But you know, no bike, no car.
Speaker 1: I had to resort to the rollerblades.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you once again, New York as a state hates rollerblades.
Speaker 1: It just hates everything about them.
Speaker 1: All the sidewalks suck.
Speaker 1: There's nowhere to rollerblade.
Speaker 1: There's like gravel and grit and everything all over the roads.
Speaker 1: There's these hills everywhere.
Speaker 1: Rollerblading at night in the dark in New York is possibly the worst thing in the world.
Speaker 1: It's a, you know, you can rollerblade like anywhere.
Speaker 1: The sidewalk is like perfectly stray.
Speaker 0: You go to that cool park.
Speaker 0: That was all parkour ish that we were in.
Speaker 1: Man, you know what's cool?
Speaker 0: I learned more right attached to the convention center.
Speaker 1: I learned about freestyle walking and freestyle running, which is like baby parkour, but it's basically just walk quickly on weird stuff and in weird places and more and more.
Speaker 1: I want the culture of Seattle to appear here because I think parkour is awesome.
Speaker 1: And here we don't even have punk skate kids.
Speaker 1: The skate park has been abandoned for two years.
Speaker 1: It's just been this flat, empty, like fenced off area.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Cause I saw some skater kids sitting at the old high school like the other day.
Speaker 1: There's skater kids about, but there's nowhere to skateboard except the skate park, but the skate park is just flat now.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: I don't know if Beacon ran out of money or what, but there's no more skate park as far as I can see.
Speaker 0: That's weird.
Speaker 0: It's there.
Speaker 0: Like you have a ramp.
Speaker 0: All you need is a swimming pool without any water in it.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You need some bumps.
Speaker 1: You need like a bumper too, and a rail and a half pipe.
Speaker 0: They're not expensive.
Speaker 0: They're real cheap.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: I don't know why beacon doesn't have them there anymore, but I feel like the thing you can do to make any town in the world better is give punk kids a place to hang out and hurt themselves.
Speaker 0: That's not drugs.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Cause if there's nothing to do, it's either Mario or drugs.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: If kids are out, the kids don't do drugs outside.
Speaker 0: They do drugs inside.
Speaker 0: So you make outside fun.
Speaker 0: They won't do drugs.
Speaker 1: They want to go.
Speaker 1: We, so give them a kid and you want to go.
Speaker 0: We, but you ain't got drugs.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So anyway, uh, you know, it's Thursday.
Speaker 1: It's always the fast and lose geek nights and we're doing a convention review, which is interesting.
Speaker 1: And I came up with this idea completely in a self-serving way because, Hey, it's hard to come up with Thursday show ideas.
Speaker 0: There is the day we should qualify that.
Speaker 1: it's easy to come up with Thursday show ideas, but here's how the, uh, Thursday afternoon conversation goes, Hey Scott, let's do a show on blah.
Speaker 1: I'm not feeling it.
Speaker 1: How about a show on blah?
Speaker 1: Well, I got like five minutes of shit to say about that.
Speaker 1: What do you want to do?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's nothing to do Thursday.
Speaker 1: And then you're like, how about we do a show on fire?
Speaker 1: Like we already did part one of that.
Speaker 0: There's nothing to do Thursday shows, except everything, except nothing.
Speaker 0: Everything just doesn't want to admit that there are no Thursday shows.
Speaker 1: I got plenty of ideas.
Speaker 0: And so we made the book club just to fill up Thursday shows.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So how far are you on a Steppenwolf there, Scott?
Speaker 0: I'm reading comic books instead.
Speaker 0: How far are you on, uh, any comic book?
Speaker 1: I'm about halfway through contract with God.
Speaker 1: I just read Crenshon.
Speaker 1: I just read, I just finished reading Orion and black magic.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Good choice.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Great stuff.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: And, uh, so we're like, Hey, you know, kinetic con isn't an anime con or a gaming con.
Speaker 0: It's an everything con.
Speaker 1: Connecticut Connecticut in Hartford, Connecticut, really?
Speaker 0: Like it says right on the cover of the book, everything, but the kitchen sink, the con stands out for me.
Speaker 1: And every year it's weird how I would always be kind of unexcited about Connecticut and go before it.
Speaker 1: I'd always think of it as this con like, yeah, that's like the con we go to.
Speaker 1: Well, after all the other cards, this is where we test all our stuff.
Speaker 1: But then I'm at Connecticut and suddenly I realized, Oh man, this is the con where everything cool happens because there's no restriction of just being about anime.
Speaker 1: Daryl Surratt can't complain about Connecticut.
Speaker 0: No, he can't.
Speaker 0: It's an everything con.
Speaker 0: Everything geeky is allowed at Connecticut.
Speaker 0: They even have like belly dancing and shit.
Speaker 1: It's good belly dancing too.
Speaker 0: It's pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: I wonder if it's the same person who was at the other con.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they were at another con, but it's the same person who's been at Connecticut multiple times.
Speaker 1: One thing I've seen, you know, I used to lot of belly dancing at those kinds and it was the same person doing it everywhere.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So doing our, uh, Thursday show as the Connecticut is like this great move because we kill off a Thursday show.
Speaker 0: We can do the Connecticut show while it's still fresh in our mind.
Speaker 1: More importantly, I want more people to go to Connecticut because it's a pretty big con.
Speaker 1: There's like six, 7,000 people, but I think a lot more people would go if they realize that it's not an anime con.
Speaker 0: The thing is it felt like less people than last year.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the actual numbers were comparable.
Speaker 1: It was a little over 6,000 comparable comparable.
Speaker 1: They were, they're able to be compared.
Speaker 1: So comparable anyway.
Speaker 0: Uh, so yeah, that's what we're gonna do today, but, uh, do you want to do news and things of the day or do you want to skip it or what?
Speaker 1: I got some things to talk about.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: This is real interesting.
Speaker 1: You know, I have a vested interest in New York City in general.
Speaker 1: You know, I worked there.
Speaker 1: I'd like to live there someday.
Speaker 1: It kind of, it is the center of the world.
Speaker 1: It is the center of the economy.
Speaker 1: It's the center of basically my entire professional career in life.
Speaker 1: And it has some problems in that it already has like this gigantic mass transit system where you go to Seattle, you go to DC and they have like these baby mass transit systems.
Speaker 1: Like I don't, it was our friend Adam who pointed this out to me, you know, he, he was in New York, he had a friend who was in New York and you moved to DC and he had this friend visit him in DC and the guy was like, yeah, how do I get to your house?
Speaker 1: He's like, take the red line, like four stops.
Speaker 1: He's like, what do you mean red line?
Speaker 1: That's complicated.
Speaker 1: Uh, how am I going to figure it out when I get there?
Speaker 1: And the guy's like, you lived in New York city, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, imagine if the New York city subway map was drawn in crayon for fourth graders.
Speaker 0: That's the Metro.
Speaker 1: So New York already has like this giant transit system, but it's already at capacity.
Speaker 1: Like I can't get on the sixth train.
Speaker 1: It's just too crowded.
Speaker 1: And people in New York state and New York city don't want to spend more money on it because no one likes to pay taxes.
Speaker 1: And they're trying to figure out ways to make the transit system better.
Speaker 1: And they're making all these improvements, but Mary Bloomberg to his credit, just put out there.
Speaker 1: This one of those crazy ideas where you hear it and you think that's crazy, but then you think about it and you realize that's just crazy enough to work.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you a tale of the M 42 bus.
Speaker 0: Oh God.
Speaker 1: It's the only way to get across town in midtown.
Speaker 1: If you want to go across blocks, there's basically no way you can walk, take the shuttle to time square.
Speaker 0: Basically Manhattan is very tall, but it's not very wide.
Speaker 0: It only takes so many minutes to walk all the way across from the East to the West.
Speaker 1: But it still, it takes a while.
Speaker 0: It does take a while, but it doesn't take that long.
Speaker 1: It takes like 20 minutes to walk across depending on where you are.
Speaker 0: That's about right.
Speaker 0: If you just keep walking and don't stop and dilly dally or get anything in your way, whatever.
Speaker 1: But if I have to go to like the Javits for an anime con or a comic con or something, it's pretty much always going to be raining.
Speaker 0: Dad sucks.
Speaker 1: So I ended up taking a cab and is miserable, but there's basically no way to get across town.
Speaker 1: and they're not going to extend the seven line forever.
Speaker 1: They're going to someday.
Speaker 0: And there's like the S, which doesn't take you very far at all.
Speaker 0: It's like, why would I take the S?
Speaker 0: I can walk that far.
Speaker 1: It's so short, but there is the infamous M 42 bus that goes back and forth on 42nd street, which is like the crosstown route.
Speaker 0: It also goes to Javits, right?
Speaker 1: It does.
Speaker 1: And let me tell you, um, I walk faster than that bus, even when there's no traffic.
Speaker 0: There's so much traffic, right?
Speaker 0: That's like, that's the reason I don't do buses.
Speaker 0: Cause the point of using mass transit is I don't want to be in the traffic, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, if I'm going to be in the traffic, I'll just fricking drive my tiny car and pass by everyone else.
Speaker 0: Uh, so if I'm going to get in a bus, right, it better pass by all the traffic.
Speaker 0: So the better, like a bus lane or something, no one else can get into at all.
Speaker 1: Seattle has that.
Speaker 1: It's pretty good, but yeah, it basically, my ideas with mass transit are that we need absolutely radical, very expensive taxpayer funded initiatives for mass transit.
Speaker 1: And the ox, the actual solution, in my opinion, you also have to just Dick over easily.
Speaker 0: If you want mass transit to succeed, you have to make it Dick over the non mass transit.
Speaker 0: Be like, Oh, well, yeah, we're just not good.
Speaker 0: We're going to have one less driving lane on this road.
Speaker 0: Fuck you cars.
Speaker 0: That's how you gotta be.
Speaker 0: If you want mass transit to work.
Speaker 1: So my crazy idea, you know, the thing I think should happen is we need like every 10 blocks and crosstown back and forth, constantly moving trolley that you just say every five, you just walk up and you just kind of hop on.
Speaker 1: It goes like 30 miles an hour, 15 miles an hour, something nice and slow.
Speaker 1: Maybe it slows down in certain loading areas, but it's just free.
Speaker 1: It just goes as a robot.
Speaker 1: So it doesn't run over little kids or something.
Speaker 0: They should just have a, you know, like at the airport where they had a conveyor belts to go back and forth.
Speaker 1: How are things that go perpendicular to it going to get over it?
Speaker 1: If it's a conveyor belt, it has to stop for the perpendicular things.
Speaker 0: It'll just, the whole thing will stop.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So when does it stop?
Speaker 1: It's a conveyor belt.
Speaker 1: It just stops.
Speaker 1: All the bad people fall over.
Speaker 0: It synchronizes the traffic lights.
Speaker 0: So when the cars are going north and south, it stops.
Speaker 0: And then when the cars are going east and west, it moves.
Speaker 1: Uh, anyway, you know, crazy ideas like that.
Speaker 1: Just do something crazy.
Speaker 1: But mayor Bloomberg, he put forth a similarly crazy idea.
Speaker 1: We've got these buses and they suck.
Speaker 1: Why don't we just make them?
Speaker 1: Why don't we just make them free?
Speaker 1: Just drive them all the time.
Speaker 1: Anyone can get gone.
Speaker 1: Anyone can get off.
Speaker 1: You have to wait and collect fares.
Speaker 1: It'll make them move faster.
Speaker 1: It'll be more efficient, less overhead.
Speaker 1: And if it takes any congestion off of any of the other stuff, we'll basically make money on it.
Speaker 1: And people are mad about this and I don't understand why.
Speaker 0: Why would you be mad about it?
Speaker 1: Because it might cost more initially.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It seems like people just ravel about mass transit because they feel like mass transit has to be profitable.
Speaker 1: They think of mass than we get out of it directly.
Speaker 1: It's a waste of money because they don't understand all the kind of secondary and tertiary benefits that they can't see that actually in the end are a net profit.
Speaker 0: But the problem is that the government is run like a business, right?
Speaker 0: In that, you know, you have to, you know, the, the, the checkbook has to be in the black.
Speaker 1: And while, you know, you shouldn't spend, well, except it's not in the black and it's never been in the black, right?
Speaker 0: First of all, you shouldn't spend more than you've taxed.
Speaker 0: That's for sure.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: Not necessarily.
Speaker 0: However, right.
Speaker 0: Just because an individual thing that you are spending money on isn't bringing a, you know, a return on investment in cash back into the government coffers.
Speaker 0: If it's, you know, it's, it's the government's job is not to, you know, be profitable.
Speaker 0: I mean, you're basically take tax money, spend it.
Speaker 0: You don't have to make the money back as long as you tax it.
Speaker 1: The government really has one job.
Speaker 1: And that is to make sure that Mad Max doesn't happen.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 1: That's basically what it does.
Speaker 1: But, you know, I digress.
Speaker 1: We don't want to talk about this forever.
Speaker 1: You want to hear about Connecticut?
Speaker 1: That's why you're here.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I bring this up because I suggested not that long ago show about mass transit.
Speaker 1: Scott was like, I have nothing to say about that.
Speaker 0: What's there to say?
Speaker 0: It sucks.
Speaker 0: It's never gonna be fixed.
Speaker 0: Clearly.
Speaker 1: We had a lot to say, and I think it will be fixed someday.
Speaker 0: I don't think it'll ever be fixed.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: Never.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: So there's just an overflow of tech news relative to other news is right.
Speaker 0: There's not so much gaming news, but there will be after PAX, I guarantee it.
Speaker 0: And there's not so much anime news because we already used it all in the San Diego and the Otakons.
Speaker 0: But there's a ton of tech news.
Speaker 0: And we don't have enough to you know, if we only did it on Monday, we wouldn't get to it all.
Speaker 0: So I want to do this one real quick today.
Speaker 0: Google or yesterday, I don't remember.
Speaker 0: recently Google bought this company, right, called on to I'm pretty sure that's what their name is.
Speaker 0: And they basically make video codecs.
Speaker 0: That's what they do.
Speaker 0: And the thing behind this is it relates to something we talked about previously on the show, HTML, but the HTML five video codecs is the Ogg Theora.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The open source video codec was actually basically what happened is this company, the onto company, made a bunch of different codecs and they kept making new versions of it.
Speaker 0: One of their old versions, I think, like version two or version five or three, I forget what number.
Speaker 0: they're already on numbers 18.
Speaker 0: They're already on version nine.
Speaker 0: So an old version of their of their codec was open sourced, right?
Speaker 0: Unconditionally.
Speaker 0: And that was what was the foundation for Ogg Theora.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And one of the big arguments against Ogg Theora is that it's just not quality enough compared to like H.264.
Speaker 0: But it is open source, which means and there's no it's you know, it's.
Speaker 0: but there's still some questions of like patent encumbrance.
Speaker 0: I don't know where those questions are coming from.
Speaker 0: So basically Google, you know, this is a big battle of H.264 versus, you know, Ogg Theora.
Speaker 0: If Google is going to buy this company, well, they already did buy this company.
Speaker 1: Clearly they have some sort of plan.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Basically what they're going to do is they're going to remove, you know, most likely they're going to remove all patent encumbrance from Ogg and from the newer codecs from this onto company, at least insofar as that can be done.
Speaker 1: because patent it's yeah, there's always some regardless.
Speaker 1: I mean, Twitter just got sued.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're going to yeah, they're going to, you know, get rid of all those sorts of problems with their Google monies.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And they're going to, you know, open source this better codec.
Speaker 0: And so basically all the browse, you know, they're going to be like, all right, look, you people, we may, we got this new codec, you know, it's bigger and better and better than your Ogg Theoras and it's open source and it's not in comfort.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So now you got no complaints.
Speaker 0: It's basically the, you know, there were all these arguments against H.264 and all these arguments against Ogg Theora.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like, they're going to say, here, we just bought this one.
Speaker 0: This doesn't have any of those complaints.
Speaker 0: Everyone fucking use it.
Speaker 0: If anyone says no, then they're going to be like, well, why not?
Speaker 0: You know, fuck you.
Speaker 0: Look, you got no complaints against this.
Speaker 0: So it's going to be interesting to see what complaints people have against it.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: So at Connecticut, we, the one time we really got to get out of the room and go anywhere other than panel five, uh, uh, uh, uh, panel five, but somehow it doesn't quite have the same energy when you're not in the room and there's a crowd there.
Speaker 0: This goes to likes disco panels.
Speaker 1: We need a disco panel, something fierce about disco.
Speaker 1: I know a little bit about disco enough to do a panel.
Speaker 1: I think I could put together a panel on disco.
Speaker 0: If you got a book about disco and read it, then you could do a panel of Wikipedia plus YouTube equals disco panel.
Speaker 1: It's not that hard.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, so we went to super art fight and I got to see two of the three fights because then I had to go do stuff before I saw all three fights.
Speaker 1: Well, I can say one thing.
Speaker 1: The first fight, uh, our friend Yuko of Johnny wander fame, uh, competed and won, even though to be fair, it was a Yuko crowd.
Speaker 0: It was a, it seems like the art fight really did.
Speaker 0: The crowd did matter a lot, you know?
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is it, the whole thing is it's not the quality of the art necessarily.
Speaker 1: It's who grandstands for the crowd the most and the best, but when the ref brought out the yellow flag, that was when I lost it.
Speaker 1: But we, you know, beforehand there's these six panels and two artists have to draw stuff.
Speaker 1: And every few minutes they change this spinner.
Speaker 1: And then the artists are given more things to incorporate into the drawing.
Speaker 1: So ahead of time, we bought sight unseen for $20.
Speaker 1: The lower left panel, which is where you go with standing.
Speaker 1: And ahead of time, we yelled at her other than use a splash attack.
Speaker 1: You go to make our panel proud and lo and behold, our panel has super macho man, Randy Savage attorney at law.
Speaker 1: I would like to note the tank briefcase and behind him is Bruce Campbell in a Bill Cosby sweater.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So my thing of the day is that, and if you look online, you can probably find some sort of picture of all six panels together, but super art fight.
Speaker 1: If you ever see it, because it is done live, not just at fan conventions, but out in the real world, you should check it out.
Speaker 0: I guess we don't need to talk about that during the show then.
Speaker 1: No, we don't.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: Is it awesome?
Speaker 1: Super art fight for the win.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, uh, what was my thing of the day?
Speaker 0: I guess on Kotaku, there was actually an article that wasn't just like a reprint of a press release.
Speaker 0: It was written by this guy in Japan.
Speaker 0: And he was talking about the Pokemon stamp rally.
Speaker 0: Do you know about this?
Speaker 1: I know nothing about this.
Speaker 0: Apparently it's been going on for 10 years.
Speaker 0: And the way it works right is they send out to all the kiddies, right?
Speaker 0: This little book that has spots for six stamps in it, right?
Speaker 1: Wait, do you have to go find these stamps?
Speaker 0: There are 95 train stations on the Japan, you know, basically the Japan train lines, right?
Speaker 0: That have stamps.
Speaker 0: So the way it works is you go and you get six stamps in your little book, right?
Speaker 0: By going to six train stations, any six train stations that have stamps.
Speaker 0: And at these train stations is basically a guy there guarding the stamp and you walk up in line, you know, it's all kids, right?
Speaker 0: They walk up all polite in line.
Speaker 0: They walk up, he stamps your book and you go, right?
Speaker 1: Oh man, kids need some sort of yuck as a conspiracy where they knock that over, grab the stamp and run, right?
Speaker 0: They have guards with all these stamps on tables.
Speaker 0: They've been doing this for 10 years.
Speaker 1: The kids are just not good enough.
Speaker 1: They need to pull a heist.
Speaker 0: So I don't think anyone's ever stolen the stamp.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you get six stamps and then you bring your little six stamp book to one of like the major stations like Tokyo or, you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: Then they give you an exchange for your six stamp book.
Speaker 0: They give you the 95 stamp book.
Speaker 0: They give you a Pikachu visor and some other stuff, right?
Speaker 0: Ooh.
Speaker 0: Then you go around getting all 95 stamps from all 95 train stations on the Japan train line.
Speaker 1: So, uh, the question is what do you get at the end of that Mewtwo?
Speaker 0: If you get all 95 stamps, right?
Speaker 0: Of all the 95 different Pokemans, then you have a chance to win various prizes.
Speaker 1: Like what?
Speaker 0: Basically crap like a stuffed Pokemon or this is so close.
Speaker 1: They need to just make the definitive Pokemon MMO that is on every platform and goes forever and have Pokemon in the real world with transponders hit as you can go.
Speaker 0: Regardless, this article was not, was, you know, it discussed the Pokemon stamp rally, but what it really discussed was like the mentality, the kleptomaniac mentality of like Japanese people.
Speaker 0: And it got into all this, you know, really, really interesting stuff.
Speaker 0: Like if one thing that was really interesting, he talked about was how, you know, in the U S we could rent video games, right?
Speaker 0: But, uh, in Japan, you know, they Nintendo and people actually put up a big fights that you couldn't rent video games in Japan.
Speaker 0: So what happened was in Japan, since there was no video game rental, the used video game market appeared much, much sooner than, you know, it did here, right?
Speaker 0: So we were pretty much buying games, beating them, selling them real quick and buy new ones.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And, uh, anyone.
Speaker 0: then eventually, you know, market appeared for people who were just waiting by the used copies for cheap.
Speaker 0: And of course, Nintendo didn't like that.
Speaker 0: So, uh, what they did is they started making games, you know, that were long.
Speaker 0: And that's why you get like the JRPG.
Speaker 0: That's just incredibly long.
Speaker 0: And, you know, you see, you're not going to buy it and then return it used right away.
Speaker 0: It's going to be a longer before someone can get a used copy.
Speaker 0: greater chance that used copy buyers just going to buy the, you know, the full version with fans.
Speaker 1: I mean, you got, I go to like a GameStop or something and they'll have those brand new long games in the U S and GameStop.
Speaker 0: People steal games from one GameStop and sell them back to another one.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But that's, I digress.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But the point is this article is really, really fascinating and you should read it.
Speaker 1: I have one more minor thing of the day and it's relevant and pertinent and timely.
Speaker 1: uncle.
Speaker 1: Yo, was that Connecticut?
Speaker 1: Many of you saw his show.
Speaker 1: His show was basically standing room only Carl Custer.
Speaker 1: He is doing his first for real comedy show out in the real world.
Speaker 0: As in not as a convention is not at a real world, right?
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: It's a cloister.
Speaker 1: It's like this private walled garden.
Speaker 1: I mean, it is, it's a very different crowd that you get at like Oticon or Connecticut, then you get at like some place somewhere.
Speaker 0: Well, not if you, you know, tell all your friends to show up from conventions.
Speaker 1: It depends because normal people will be there too.
Speaker 1: But this Saturday, August 8th at 7 PM at the drama lounge in the lower East village of New York city on 85th Avenue a between fifth and sixth street, uncle Joe will be there and 85 Avenue a not 85th.
Speaker 1: I was reading, I didn't know where it was way north.
Speaker 1: I saw this sentence and I read it as quickly as I could while I was doing other stuff and preparing for the rest of the show.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Anyway, there's a link to it in our forums.
Speaker 1: There's link on the website.
Speaker 1: There's a pretty good chance.
Speaker 1: A lot of us will be there.
Speaker 0: Scott won't go.
Speaker 1: If I wasn't going to Connecticut, but Scott's going to Connecticut for something.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So Connecticut, oh shit.
Speaker 1: Connecticut, 2000.
Speaker 0: Talk about every single panel we did individually.
Speaker 1: I want to mention everything.
Speaker 1: I'll mention this.
Speaker 1: This was a very special Connecticut for us.
Speaker 1: a little bit of meta perspective here.
Speaker 1: We've been going to Connecticut for a number of years and very rapidly, our Connecticut experience has changed.
Speaker 1: The first year we went, we were just fans and we walked into the anime club like summit, how to run an anime club panel.
Speaker 1: The panel was kind of poorly run and was giving basically illegal advice.
Speaker 1: So we stood up and we're like, no, that's not how it is.
Speaker 1: And we ran the rest of the panel.
Speaker 1: We then kind of trashed Connecticut on geek nights and the con chair and the vice counter emailed us and said, yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: All your complaints were justified.
Speaker 1: Put up or shut up.
Speaker 1: You want to fix it?
Speaker 1: And we were like, hells yeah.
Speaker 1: And the next year we did like seven panels.
Speaker 0: And every year we've done, you know, I have four Connecticut badges, so I don't, I don't really remember the sequence of events.
Speaker 0: I think we did seven panels last year.
Speaker 0: So the year before that, maybe we only did like two.
Speaker 1: No, we did more panels that year.
Speaker 1: And then we did fewer panels the next year because those panels killed us because we weren't good at doing that many panels.
Speaker 0: I don't even remember.
Speaker 0: I need, I should save the con books, but I keep throwing them all over.
Speaker 0: I remember pretty well.
Speaker 1: And I have, you know, records of all the cons we go to and records of all the panels we've ever done.
Speaker 1: So I can show you a list of every single panel we've ever done at every con ever.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so we did all these things and every year, you know, we kind of escalated.
Speaker 1: this year was the penultimate escalation we did.
Speaker 1: Well, we produced or sponsored 37 panels at Connecticut.
Speaker 1: of those panels, 23 were 100% us and six more were mostly us.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: What, what percentage of those 23 were bullshit and which ones were real?
Speaker 1: I would say, I would say, you know, all told going through the schedule again, only four of the panels we ran were bullshit.
Speaker 0: So 19 real panels that were just us.
Speaker 0: How many of the, how many of the real panels are basically just show videos?
Speaker 1: Don't do anything now that, well, what do you mean by that?
Speaker 1: I mean, is the craziest anime deaths any less of a panel than bite-sized anime.
Speaker 0: bite-sized anime was mostly a sit there, don't say much, just show videos panel.
Speaker 0: So is anime as crazy as deaths, anime as crazy as deaths requires you to actually describe in great detail.
Speaker 0: The deaths, this bite-sized anime doesn't require as much.
Speaker 1: You really need to describe the anime as crazy as death.
Speaker 1: When you've just shown someone getting killed.
Speaker 0: People don't know what it was from, and it's not in the proper context.
Speaker 0: They don't know who's dying and why it was bite-sized anime.
Speaker 1: We talked a lot about Damaic Adobe or two.
Speaker 0: We talked enough about Damaic Adobe with Detroit metal.
Speaker 1: We said all there was to say, I don't know why you're so down in these panels.
Speaker 0: That was like, I just want to get a real count of, you know, how many panels were super for real panel.
Speaker 1: Well, what do you mean super for real?
Speaker 0: What's like, we actually had to talk for the whole time.
Speaker 1: So do we want to call that something different from a panel then?
Speaker 1: Because a panel is a panel as opposed to a showing, which is no commentary, just to show accurate picture.
Speaker 0: We sponsored how much effort we exerted.
Speaker 1: We exerted a lot of effort, 37 panels that we scheduled and put Friday.
Speaker 0: Since we were the only ones who took the day off and went there Friday and everyone else showed up Friday night or Saturday, we pretty much sat in one room, running panels all day, doing nothing else.
Speaker 0: I didn't even leave the room for a long period of time.
Speaker 0: I didn't go to the dealer's room.
Speaker 0: I didn't go to the artist's alley.
Speaker 0: I didn't go to any of the panels.
Speaker 0: I didn't play any games.
Speaker 1: I went to many of those things because I barely even got to eat any food.
Speaker 1: I was able to walk around and take care of stuff.
Speaker 1: So I went and helped someone set up in the dealer's room and I saw the dealer's room and I went to the, like, I basically went everywhere in the con, but we basically were in panel five running panels from like 9 a.m.
Speaker 1: until midnight.
Speaker 0: Uh, it was pretty rough.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna, I'm gonna read all the titles quickly once just to get a scale of this.
Speaker 1: Good morning, Kineticon bite-sized anime.
Speaker 1: Losing should be fun.
Speaker 1: Beyond Dungeons Dragons, the Beyond Dungeons Dragons QA conceptual game design action castle, which was actually not run by us.
Speaker 1: Kineticon lives, Roving the Mecha Attack by Uncle Yo, not run by us.
Speaker 1: Beyond County Land, Comics for the Margarita, Tales from the Anime Club, Anime Openers, Leiji Matsumoto's, Galaxy Express, 3-9-9.
Speaker 0: Some notable things.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess 3-9.
Speaker 1: Some notable things from that.
Speaker 1: 3-9-9.
Speaker 0: Yes, notables.
Speaker 0: I just, I don't care about the chronological order.
Speaker 0: I just, I just try to remember, keep that all in my head.
Speaker 1: Well, I gotta say this bite-sized anime was pretty popular.
Speaker 1: One, because there wasn't much else going on at the time, but two, I've learned something.
Speaker 1: No one out there has seen Dameka Dobutsu or Detroit Metal City or Gog Manga or any of this stuff, but everyone loves all of these shows.
Speaker 1: The only mistake we made in this panel was that we showed Gog Manga Biore, Detroit Metal City and Dameka Dobutsu before we showed Zenryoku Usagi.
Speaker 0: Because Zenryoku Usagi first.
Speaker 1: Well, Zenryoku Usagi is awesome.
Speaker 1: It is not quite as crazily awesome as Dameka Dobutsu.
Speaker 1: But I got to say, people really liked Gog Manga Biore.
Speaker 1: That show is like, but it's a show where people, people don't get it at first.
Speaker 1: Like you could see the audience and they're watching.
Speaker 1: And for the first two minutes, they just don't get it.
Speaker 1: They're like, eh, what's this?
Speaker 1: I don't get it.
Speaker 1: What's going on?
Speaker 1: But then like the three punch joke at the end with the kid and the sticker and the peeling, the sticker, and then that they're done.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So first of all, Beyond Candyland, this is something to talk about because it's a brand new panel.
Speaker 0: We basically practiced it at at Kineticon.
Speaker 0: It is four packs, four packs in like a month.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So not even it is exactly a day weekend.
Speaker 0: So we practiced it at Kineticon and I basically slapped it together real quick, like a week or two ago.
Speaker 0: And we just did it and we didn't prepare that much.
Speaker 0: But it was actually way, way, way better than I anticipated.
Speaker 0: Like it doesn't need that much more polished for packs.
Speaker 0: It's like ready to go.
Speaker 1: It's definitely a panel that writes itself because the first half is kind of tough to figure out.
Speaker 1: You know, we, we debated as Scott was throwing together the slideshow before Kineticon, like, you know, two days before Kineticon, like, you know, should we talk about this than this?
Speaker 1: What's the idea?
Speaker 1: Should we bring up game theory?
Speaker 0: I just got to reorder a few slides that are sort of out of order and this panel be pretty great.
Speaker 1: after that, like after we get all the theory and like stuff out the whole second half of the panel, once Scott figured out the order of board games to talk about, it is just like it was gold before we even gave it.
Speaker 1: Like, it's just so easy to talk about Puerto Rico and Tigers and Euphrates.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So if you're going to packs or any other convention, this is a brand new panel, which means it's going to be a whole year before it expires.
Speaker 0: So if you go to see us, you know, anytime in like two thou, you know, between, uh, you know, before Kineticon 2010, I can list.
Speaker 1: if you're going to go to either Penny Arcade Expo or the New York Comic Con or Anime Boston, we'll probably run into Anime Boston too, but we're going to run it at a lot of places.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So look forwards to Beyond Candyland, an awesome panel about awesome board games.
Speaker 0: that has nothing to do with anime.
Speaker 0: Sorry, Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: I hope we'll see what happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The thing is Beyond D&D was like our biggest panel at both Anime Boston and at Otakon.
Speaker 0: I know it's sad.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But we ran that again and we actually did a Q and a, and that worked pretty well.
Speaker 1: I definitely have to point out action castle because we got Lou Crane and Jared Sorensen to come to Kineticon, which it was, it was remarkably difficult.
Speaker 0: Like I was a miracle that we got them to show up.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm glad, you know, I thank them for coming and staying as long as they stayed and doing what they did, but, you know, just to be perfectly honest, you know, Jared basically showed up, did his thing real quick and then he was gone.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But to his credit, he showed up.
Speaker 1: Basically I gave him a schedule that was a half hour off.
Speaker 0: That was because rim's fault, because that's why I didn't say he showed up late.
Speaker 0: Cause rim messed that up telling him the wrong time to show up.
Speaker 1: Well, because the schedule, the Kineticon schedule, you know, since we're in charge of this next year, we're going to rework how it looks.
Speaker 1: But basically I gave everyone the schedule exactly a half hour off and Jared was incommunicado completely just off the face of the earth.
Speaker 1: Luke didn't even know where he was.
Speaker 1: And exactly the second I had told him to show up, he'd like, he just appears in the room.
Speaker 1: So for the first half of conceptual game design, I had to make up the conceptual game design panel because Scott, uh, Scott couldn't deliver.
Speaker 1: Scott couldn't come up with a panel on the fly.
Speaker 0: I wasn't going to steal someone else's panel and I was tired and I didn't give a shit.
Speaker 0: Plus, you know, you left me hanging in the morning.
Speaker 0: You're it was a lot more than 10 minutes actually.
Speaker 1: Cause I have the tweets that were going out and the text messages.
Speaker 1: I know the minute.
Speaker 1: I was back in that room.
Speaker 1: I can go look, but beyond, beyond.
Speaker 1: good morning, Kineticon, how hard is good morning?
Speaker 1: Kineticon you say good morning, Kineticon that you sit there.
Speaker 0: I basically did the whole thing.
Speaker 0: And then you showed up and repeated everything I had already done.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: The crowd seemed to really like that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, they did.
Speaker 1: But I think I came up with a pretty good 10 minute conceptual game design panel and crowd liked it.
Speaker 0: I believe Scott got anything better than sitting there doing nothing.
Speaker 0: I could have gotten up and just did the elephant dance.
Speaker 0: They would have loved that too.
Speaker 1: So, uh, well they, I don't think they could have told her it was an elephant dance.
Speaker 0: It depends on the crowd anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We ran action castle and he ran it just like he ran it at packs and it was totally awesome.
Speaker 1: One thing I can say though, like people didn't know what to expect and the whole con people are asking us ahead of time, like what is, what is people kept asking us?
Speaker 0: What's action castle.
Speaker 0: What's crab people.
Speaker 0: What's crab.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you, we learned something.
Speaker 1: If you make a description like that, people will show up.
Speaker 1: And as long as you can deliver something that lives up to the description, even if it does not match the description, your goal, but action castle, by the end of it, like the crowd was so like crazy about it, that the whole con, it was like this joke and people around the count instead of butt, scotch.
Speaker 1: Ah, but scotch out.
Speaker 1: It was, it takes a long time.
Speaker 1: Action castle is going to be like a big event at Connecticut next year.
Speaker 0: We got to get Jared roped.
Speaker 0: We got to like, I don't know, maybe we have to like, uh, what do we have to do to get these people to like stay and keep doing stuff the way we got scheduled in for more things for one and two.
Speaker 1: Now we know the trouble, the peril, the melancholy of Jim bowls, because think about what he has to wrangle at Otacon in terms of guests.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 1: Imagine the Connecticut and guest relations people.
Speaker 1: They have to deal with people like Vic and Chris, you know, why are people so unfreaking reliable?
Speaker 0: Someone tells you to show up a time you show up.
Speaker 1: How was the unravel?
Speaker 1: He showed up at exactly that time.
Speaker 1: And we did not schedule him for anything else.
Speaker 1: So he did not show up any other time.
Speaker 0: He was not obligated to, it was not obligated to, but it's like, you know, if he would have ran some, you know, he could have sold a whole bunch of games.
Speaker 0: If he would have just run some demos, but he didn't want to.
Speaker 1: And we did not obligate him to, I did not.
Speaker 1: I've learned something.
Speaker 1: I learned something very important because this is how all the other people do it.
Speaker 1: If you give someone an itinerary, they will show up to everything in that itinerary, unless they get drunk and wander off like an unnamed voice actor at Katsu con a few years ago.
Speaker 0: Well, we're going to have to give everyone strict itineraries.
Speaker 1: The thing is, I point out, everyone showed up to their itineraries perfectly.
Speaker 1: That's true, but you know, I don't know what you're complaining about.
Speaker 1: Jared ran action castle and it was epic.
Speaker 0: It was epic.
Speaker 0: There's no, no complaint we can have about his running of action castle.
Speaker 0: It just, you know, it would have been nice to chat.
Speaker 1: Well, from what I hear, he had some business to take care of.
Speaker 1: that was somewhat personal.
Speaker 1: So I can't get into that.
Speaker 1: He had, he had a good reason to not be around for the rest of the con, but Luke Crane was around the creator of burning wheel.
Speaker 1: And the one thing I want to say about that, that's kind of meta is that I could see it in his eyes.
Speaker 0: It's very different to be at a con like kinetic con as opposed to a gaming con because most of the cons he goes through the tiny gaming cons though, the Uber cons, the decks, cons, you know, all that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Like packs, which is packs.
Speaker 1: It's something special, but he basically, one of our friends texted me and he's like, Luke went into the rave and I'm like, I wonder how that's going to turn out.
Speaker 1: So he walks out of the raise rave and on record, the first words that were out of his mouth were basically there are girls at this convention and there's music.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's how pretty much every convention I go to it.
Speaker 1: I think he had this revelation that cons like this are very, very different and they take a long time.
Speaker 0: And this convention was, you and you know, only half of it was anime maybe.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I wonder what he would do it in a full anime convention.
Speaker 1: Luckily uncle yo showed up on Friday because you know, he does con stuff.
Speaker 1: So surviving the Mecca attack was standing room only and it was just, it was absolutely fantastic.
Speaker 0: Uncle yo, he just keeps improving though.
Speaker 0: His skills.
Speaker 0: every time it's like just every time we see him at a con, he's doing his thing.
Speaker 0: He's just getting better and better and better.
Speaker 0: I wandered into the end of surviving the Mecca and he's, he's proved if you work, if you want something and you'd keep doing it and keep doing it, you just get better at it.
Speaker 0: I know he's going to reach his 10,000 hours of practice and you better watch out.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Is the pendulate method of success.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: It's pretty much proven at this point.
Speaker 0: I mean, bill Gates, us pendulate pendulate uncle.
Speaker 1: yo, if you want to be like any of these people, all you have to do is ruin the early half of your life.
Speaker 0: Just keep doing something a whole bunch and you'll get good at it.
Speaker 0: Naturally.
Speaker 1: Well, you also actually have to want it.
Speaker 1: If you don't want it, you're not going to pull up that pigeon, man.
Speaker 0: I walked by a pigeon today near the post office.
Speaker 0: It was the fattest, slowest pigeon.
Speaker 0: I was like, Oh, fuck you.
Speaker 0: I could have had you.
Speaker 0: I'm going to, the only reason I don't do it is I don't have gloves.
Speaker 0: I swear to God, I'm going to get some fucking gloves from home Depot.
Speaker 0: I'm going to pick up so many fricking pigeons, but here's the thing.
Speaker 0: I'm going to put them in sack too.
Speaker 0: They're not this big sack.
Speaker 0: It's just flopping around like a cartoon.
Speaker 1: That's the analogy to everyone who says they're going to do a web comic or says they're going to make an e-commerce video of all these pigeons in a sack.
Speaker 0: Then I'm going to go in the park and dump them out on somebody.
Speaker 1: For those of you who are unaware very briefly, because I know we have a lot of new listeners from Connecticut and explaining these sort of things takes a long time.
Speaker 0: Last time we use that joke.
Speaker 1: Are you kidding?
Speaker 1: I don't think you understand.
Speaker 0: It's not, it's not really a holding up.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: I keep making the joke.
Speaker 1: Anyway, pendulate and teller, you know, pen and teller.
Speaker 1: They're trying to do this magic trick where they have to like grab a dove and they did well in a park.
Speaker 1: They were doing doves in central park.
Speaker 1: They had specially trained doves.
Speaker 0: No, I'm pretty sure it was a pigeon in central park.
Speaker 1: You clearly do not remember the story as you tend to not remember.
Speaker 1: So they had to do a bit where they had to grab doves, which are basically just tame, pretty looking pigeons in terms of demeanor.
Speaker 1: So they're trying to do this and they can't, like they can't grab them.
Speaker 1: Like they're like, they're having all this trouble and they're getting frustrated with these trained birds.
Speaker 1: and pen just wanders away and he's sitting in the park and he's frustrated and sees his pigeon and he's thinking about it.
Speaker 1: He's like, you know what?
Speaker 1: I want that pigeon.
Speaker 1: I just, I want it.
Speaker 1: I want it.
Speaker 1: And he just went and grabbed it.
Speaker 1: And he realized suddenly that you just have to want it.
Speaker 1: And up until that point, he did not want the bird in his hand.
Speaker 1: He did not actually fully with his heart and viscerally want it.
Speaker 1: So he didn't, he couldn't pick it up.
Speaker 1: He didn't have the guts.
Speaker 1: He didn't have the girl in the gun, but if he wanted it, he fucking wanted it.
Speaker 0: So you put your hands towards a pigeon, right?
Speaker 0: Even if it's clean, it's like.
Speaker 0: you hesitate.
Speaker 0: You're like, Ew.
Speaker 0: And you think about holding it in your hand.
Speaker 0: It's like, Ew.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like, it's, you don't really want to hold it, but if you want to hold it, nothing is stopping you.
Speaker 0: That's why lion eats man.
Speaker 0: Cause lion wants to eat man, but man doesn't want to eat lion.
Speaker 0: So if you wanted to eat the lion and you are, you know, strong, you're ambitious enough.
Speaker 0: You could probably take it out.
Speaker 0: You'd get on that lion's back, bite him in the throat, rip his whatnot.
Speaker 1: Not everybody can be good.
Speaker 1: No, but yeah, some people, but anyway, I want it to the end of uncle, uncle Joe and George surviving the Mecca attack because we had beyond candy land next.
Speaker 1: And I caught this bit.
Speaker 1: that was basically, do you understand how much it costs to run an Atano circus?
Speaker 1: Here's the cost of one missile.
Speaker 1: And I had this idea and I hope they incorporate it too.
Speaker 1: They need a video of like Mac, like some sort of Atano circus show and just have the digital counter in the bottom of how much it costs.
Speaker 0: That'd be good.
Speaker 0: Very good.
Speaker 0: Takes a lot of video editing skills though.
Speaker 1: And we tried out another panel late at night and I'm real pleased with this panel.
Speaker 1: I just have to tweak it and, you know, replace the crab people versions of like the YouTube videos with DVD rips, but anime openers and closers from around the world.
Speaker 0: We need a few more foreign ones.
Speaker 0: We did a lot of Japan, America comparisons.
Speaker 0: We only did a handful of a European and otherwise comparison.
Speaker 1: I had quite a few of.
Speaker 1: the problem is there aren't that many except for shown in fighting shows that remember an anime only has its own to get some Hokuto Ken from around the world.
Speaker 0: You are shocked.
Speaker 1: There's not that much.
Speaker 1: I was looking around.
Speaker 1: Most people didn't dub it or I can't get it because remember for stuff that's weird like that, I'm basically reliant on YouTube and possibly better.
Speaker 1: And luckily I met some people.
Speaker 1: One guy showed me this opener to something and he's going to send me a copy of it to incorporate into the panel, but I had some good stuff.
Speaker 0: I found that good, a DuckTales thing and Chinese Ava was a good new highlight.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: Chinese Ava.
Speaker 1: I got to try to find a better copy, but I searched for days and that's the best I could find.
Speaker 1: Damn.
Speaker 1: People were very surprised by Fox bot Escaflowne because no one expected that actually.
Speaker 0: what was scary about that?
Speaker 0: panels.
Speaker 0: We kept showing like the horrible openers and people actually sort of wanted to watch some of them.
Speaker 0: Like we, we, we put on, you know, got to go, got to go one piece.
Speaker 0: And Luke Crane was actually like, Hey, when we stopped it, like he wanted to see the rest of it.
Speaker 1: Well, I, cause Luke Crane is one of those people who grew up on, you know, the star blazers equivalent.
Speaker 0: So he, he basically, he grew up on Bandai Robot Champs.
Speaker 1: He's one of those people who probably, and I see this a lot.
Speaker 1: They kind of got into anime back then, but then they fall out of it because there was no more anime like that available.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And I feel like people like that could get back into watching those old Mecca openers.
Speaker 0: He's like, I own that one.
Speaker 0: I'm like, Oh shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Like a grand dizer in your basement.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And he's, you know, I knew lion on the chest shoots a laser.
Speaker 1: I did not know.
Speaker 1: Lion's eyes also shoot laser, different laser.
Speaker 1: The two lasers can also combine.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Kineticon live was kind of a BS panel.
Speaker 1: We threw that into just to, you know, kill an hour.
Speaker 0: We're actually going to put that up as an episode.
Speaker 1: I probably will because you know what?
Speaker 1: The crowd, there was a pretty experimental or supplemental feeders.
Speaker 1: I'm going to put everything I recorded in the experimental feed, mostly on edited, but people see an idea.
Speaker 1: One thing I noticed are so-called BS panels where we were to basically sit there and kind of make up a panel.
Speaker 1: as we went, we'd have between 40 and 80 people in the room and they seem to really like it.
Speaker 1: It's kind of weird.
Speaker 0: People pretty much liked it.
Speaker 0: Basically.
Speaker 0: It felt like a lot of this stuff we did at Kineticon.
Speaker 0: It's like we just reuse the same materials over and over again, sort of remix them.
Speaker 0: You know, we tell the same joke like five times a day, but the crowd was always slightly different with only a few people that had been there.
Speaker 1: But it works really well because one, like a comedy routine, you know, you make the joke and then you build on it periodically throughout the routine.
Speaker 1: And then you end on the original joke and bring it full circle.
Speaker 0: Yes, but that's not what we did.
Speaker 0: What we did was tell the exact same joke pretty much like three times a day to three different groups of people.
Speaker 0: But it'd
Speaker 1: be interesting, but
Speaker 0: luckily the group had such a small
Speaker 1: overlap
Speaker 0: that there weren't too many people complaining that, you
Speaker 1: know, I heard that the few people who were there because, you know, we'd use the joke in a different context or we'd reference an anecdote, but we wouldn't fully explain it.
Speaker 1: But you'd see, like there was that one kind of front row gang in the lower, like right half of the panel room that was there like all day.
Speaker 1: And they would like not at each other and be like, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: Whenever we referenced an anecdote from a previous panel.
Speaker 1: Mm hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Plus anyone who's going to come to our panels that frequently, like someone who was there all day, those are the kind of people who are like our big fans.
Speaker 0: And we could just sit up there going boobity boobity boobity, but they just be like, whee.
Speaker 0: So whatever, you know, they'll take whatever we're going to say anyway.
Speaker 0: Any other exciting panels we ran on Friday?
Speaker 1: Well, we also tried out losing should be fun, which is the much more difficult to write panel for packs because I very much sold it to a lot of people and it's more of a conceptual panel.
Speaker 0: It just needs a little bit more polished, like a double pot.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is, I realize I rewrote it and I think it's almost done.
Speaker 1: I just have to get the pictures to fill in the new slideshow.
Speaker 1: But what I realized about losing should be fun is that it's primarily theory and explanation.
Speaker 1: And it doesn't have the fallback of.
Speaker 1: here are 10 great games and why they're great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because there aren't games.
Speaker 0: Beyond DND has the.
Speaker 0: here are the indie RPGs you should play and Beyond Candyland has.
Speaker 0: here are board games.
Speaker 1: Losing should be fun has UFO 5440 and Dwarf Fortress.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, you know, we should get some natural selection in there and, you know, some other games.
Speaker 1: They're in there.
Speaker 1: Mostly I need, you know, I basically need to add more.
Speaker 0: You get a video of turtling and NS to put in there.
Speaker 1: Ah, yeah, we could try to get that.
Speaker 1: We got time like an audio list.
Speaker 0: video of turtling.
Speaker 1: The audio might be good too, though, because you'll get that same guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Get him.
Speaker 0: If he's playing, that's definitely the video to keep.
Speaker 1: I got to contact that guy.
Speaker 1: I alien commander.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Alien commander.
Speaker 0: Do LSD once in your life.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: If anyone out there knows alien commander in natural selection, it's not a big community.
Speaker 1: Someone knows him personally.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Let us know.
Speaker 1: I want to get him on the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I want to ask him.
Speaker 0: Speaking of which at unknown worlds is going to have a booth.
Speaker 0: We're going to get to meet the flare.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: We got to add it.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: More likely he's going to get to meet us.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: You know what I'm going to do?
Speaker 1: I'm going to ask if we can get a press badge in addition to our special guest badge.
Speaker 0: Good idea.
Speaker 1: Because the press bet and the special guest badge, it's kind of like paranoia.
Speaker 1: It gets you into weird places, but it's weird to try to interview someone with that badge.
Speaker 1: Interviewing someone who has the same badge, you do kind of weird.
Speaker 0: Very weird.
Speaker 1: We got to get a different badge.
Speaker 0: They're going to have exhibitor professional type badges probably.
Speaker 0: That's weird because we industry badge.
Speaker 1: I don't know what they know because a lot of the guests had the same badge we had last year.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, yeah.
Speaker 0: Get, I mean, you know, uh, like, uh, yeah, the bad, the badge we had last year was what, like special, it was special, like presenters presenters, something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It was blue.
Speaker 0: That was the same badge that like, you know, MC Frontalot had or whatever.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, it's the someone's doing events badge.
Speaker 0: That's what we had.
Speaker 0: So yeah, that's, that's a good badge to have anyway.
Speaker 1: Uh, one other, you know, outside of panel five, this, this con review is very meta as opposed to our, you know, normally a convention review.
Speaker 1: We talk a lot about, you know, all the events at the con.
Speaker 1: We went to this, we did this.
Speaker 0: We didn't go to much.
Speaker 1: We didn't go to anything.
Speaker 1: And also it's a miracle that we played two board games because we're basically staff at Connecticut.
Speaker 1: At this point, our Connecticut reviews, uh, hopefully you'll find this stuff interesting, are very inside baseball, what it's like
Speaker 0: when the back looking out instead of the outlook and in, which is
Speaker 1: one of those things that we always really, really like to see because the first time we sat in like an artist's alley or like talk to dealers for real, it's weird how any fan convention has like these 10 different perspectives.
Speaker 1: And depending on who you are and what badge you have, it is a completely different experience.
Speaker 1: to go to the con.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I think it's actually good for us to do the review like this from the back to the front, because, you know, there's a million con review podcasts.
Speaker 0: We've done them.
Speaker 0: Our fellow friendly podcasters have done a hundred of them.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And they're all sort of very similar.
Speaker 0: You know, this, we went to these panels, they were good.
Speaker 0: They were bad, right.
Speaker 0: Doing one for the back to the front, I think is a lot rarer thing.
Speaker 0: You're not going to hear a lot of these out in the podcasting world or just in the world in general.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Reviews of something from the back looking out, you don't hear like, you know, it's like a book review by the author, you know, or the editor of the book review by the author.
Speaker 1: This book's fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But the thing is, right.
Speaker 0: Imagine if there were like a hundred authors of the book, it wasn't, it was like an anthology.
Speaker 0: And one guy reviewed the whole thing, you know, his part, you know, he'll talk about.
Speaker 0: And the other thing is that I think people know and they trust us and that we're very honest, even about our own shit.
Speaker 0: You know, we'll tell you when we do something that sucks, we'll be like, yeah, our shit suck there.
Speaker 1: We'll get to that.
Speaker 0: We had a couple of suckiness around, but what can, you know, considering the quantity versus the proportion of suck, we did pretty damn good.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: I mean, could you do better?
Speaker 0: If you can do better, if you think you can do better, you'll get your chance next, Connecticut.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about that at the end, but very briefly, Scott and I are now the heads of panels and workshops for Connecticut.
Speaker 1: It is us 100%.
Speaker 1: The buck stops with us.
Speaker 1: Panels are our responsibility.
Speaker 1: So stay tuned to the end because we're already working on next Connecticut schedule.
Speaker 1: I've already lined up some panels.
Speaker 1: Good God.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: We're going to be already lined up my own panel.
Speaker 1: I lined up, I lined up some external panels and you're, you guys are going to be surprised.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking maybe like if, you know, since we're running, we're both running the panels that like if we both did a panel, it actually might be sort of troublesome if we're needed.
Speaker 0: Maybe we should do like some individual panels.
Speaker 1: There will be very few panels at Connecticut.
Speaker 1: Sadly, for many of you who are fans of us that are both me and Scott, because that's kind of like putting the president and the vice president in the same room at the same time.
Speaker 1: Very bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, but regardless, we'll talk about that at the end because that's the least interesting part to people who went to this Connecticut and want to care about it.
Speaker 1: One thing I do want to point out to our last panel of the night, we were originally going to talk about and then show the galaxy express three nines movie, which is one of the greatest animated movies ever made.
Speaker 1: There's this whole scene.
Speaker 0: When do you want to watch it?
Speaker 0: You want to watch it tomorrow?
Speaker 0: Maybe tacos.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Either that, or I kind of want to show her cause.
Speaker 1: I have that box set the first episode of Tyler.
Speaker 0: You can watch that too.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's a good one.
Speaker 0: But we, yeah, rim bought the box set box set of irresponsible captain Tyler in the dealer's room.
Speaker 1: So excited about this.
Speaker 1: That's like my favorite anime ever.
Speaker 1: I, you know, I talk about anime a lot.
Speaker 1: I'm an anime fan, irresponsible captain Tyler, unlike any other anime or even media that I have read or seen it influenced my life pretty directly.
Speaker 1: And when I was young and I saw this show, I very seriously kind of based my life and my worldview on this anime.
Speaker 0: I, uh, what did I, I bought?
Speaker 0: dread the Jenga RPG in the dealer's room.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I ordered Jenga on Amazon because we don't already order it.
Speaker 1: I ordered it.
Speaker 0: You click the button.
Speaker 1: I clicked the button.
Speaker 1: I needed some other stuff.
Speaker 0: Uh, also I bought, uh, when I bought that I got for free, uh, trade of, uh, omega the unknown classic.
Speaker 0: We'll see how that is.
Speaker 1: It was funny because you got this copy for free of that at the con.
Speaker 0: And then we walk over to another booth, other booth that was on all these cheap old Marvel trades.
Speaker 0: It's like a hundred copies of it just stacked up.
Speaker 0: They were like, they were like, the thing is, it'll be good because I planned, you know, I had planned for a while to buy the newer remake of omega, the unknown.
Speaker 0: That's supposed to be really fricking awesome.
Speaker 0: And now I'll get the background info, even if the background info is really bad old Marvel comics.
Speaker 0: Uh, what else I get in the dealer's room there?
Speaker 1: We got something that was quite a digression.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 1: I just while we were thinking of it, we talked about, we did comics for the manga reader, which is always an easy to run popular panel, which was cool because there were like half the people in the room.
Speaker 1: They were like, yeah, we read comics and manga.
Speaker 1: We know the score, but they didn't read most of the things we brought up and they were taking notes.
Speaker 1: In fact, a lot of people were taking notes.
Speaker 0: It was actually strange.
Speaker 0: Like you go to other cons and I see like, uh, when you were doing beyond D and D there are a few people taking notes at Otacon beyond D and D at Connecticut.
Speaker 0: It seemed like everyone was taking notes.
Speaker 0: Like there's just so much note taking all of our panels, like an anime you should see.
Speaker 1: There was this one cool guy in the back and he sat there and every anime we brought up that he had clearly not seen, he wrote it down and I could see him like putting different numbers of stars next to them.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you, princess two, two seems to have, you've got a circle.
Speaker 0: Oh, we brought up a circle means don't watch.
Speaker 0: Maybe put a line through a Ghostbusters style.
Speaker 1: I don't know, but we showed princess two, two, and we'll, we'll get to that Saturday.
Speaker 1: We're going, but anyway, to get back on track, uh, comics for the manga reader, we talked about black sad, which is super hard to get.
Speaker 1: It's this amazing French comic.
Speaker 1: So walking around the dealer's room, Emily sees in the distance and says, is that black sad?
Speaker 1: And I'm like, no way.
Speaker 1: So we walk over and sure enough, amidst this sea, this veritable ocean of furry pornography is a single mint condition copy of the second volume of black sad in English for 20 bucks teaching.
Speaker 1: I bought that thing like faster.
Speaker 1: Like I almost killed the dealer, just jumping over him to get it.
Speaker 0: Some things we saw in the dealer's room, but did not buy.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 0: Oh, there was, um, uh, carcass own the catapults.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: Which is a new word.
Speaker 1: No, we see it.
Speaker 0: I knew carcass own expansion that has a working catapult.
Speaker 0: I guess you fling meeples with it.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's just, it's, that's gotta be bad.
Speaker 0: But the guy at the booth was like, yeah, I stopped with that one.
Speaker 1: We were laughing at it and the guy comes over and he was clearly the guy working.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The guy who's booth it was.
Speaker 0: And he was just like, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: Since we've digressed the other cool thing, we saw two cool things in the dealer's room.
Speaker 1: One way back at the Jersey shore, we saw, you know, you can make a crystal with like a 3d image inside of it.
Speaker 1: And we wondered how it was made, but we didn't do any research, but I posited that very soon it was going to be fairly easy to do.
Speaker 1: And we're going to see these things entering into geeky, geeky crafty realms at Connecticut.
Speaker 1: And there was someone who was clearly started doing this and we asked him, how do you do it?
Speaker 1: And we learned how to make those things.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, you get a crystal and you get three lasers.
Speaker 0: And if the lasers all hit each other in the same spot, it basically makes a bubble in the crystal because it's hot enough, but it's not hot enough if you only have one or two lasers.
Speaker 0: So this is a machine with three lasers and you program it and it makes art with little bubbles inside of a crystal.
Speaker 0: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And the other thing we saw was these people who made custom vampire fangs.
Speaker 1: And while that sounds creepy, they're super high quality and they make them like for you, for your teeth, like perfectly right there.
Speaker 1: They, they were pretty hardcore.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They were totally awesome.
Speaker 1: They were pretty cheap too.
Speaker 0: I was basically, they just, yeah, they just had people just freaking lining up.
Speaker 0: Basically they were making them constantly.
Speaker 0: The only reason I did not even after the dealer's room closed, they were still making them like in the gaming room, a minor fuck you to those guys.
Speaker 1: That room smelled like acrylic for like eight hours.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's why we had to leave that room.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But that aside, the only reason I didn't get them was that I could not sit still long enough, you know, because we ran panel five for the whole con.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Even though I'm not a creepy vampire person, like having a pair of vampire fangs, I mean, the, one of the people there was like, yeah, these have lasted me like 12 years.
Speaker 0: I'm like, well shit, you know, who knows?
Speaker 0: And I'll need some fangs.
Speaker 1: What did we realize?
Speaker 1: Well, Scott's a biter, so definitely, but you can put just one in and now you have the cute anime single thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Basically all it is is a cap that goes over your pointy tooth and makes it even pointy.
Speaker 1: And the guy's like, yeah, you know, don't eat anything or bite anything.
Speaker 0: Obviously don't bite yourself.
Speaker 1: Don't fall asleep with them on and you're going to wake up with a missing fang and a painful, uh, anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So move back to my original point.
Speaker 1: Leiji Masumoto's galaxy express three nines.
Speaker 1: The schedule got compressed, which worked to our favor, but we couldn't show the whole movie.
Speaker 1: So instead we demoed, we basically tried out what we are proposing to do at Otacon next year, which was MC showings of anime.
Speaker 1: So Scott and mostly Scott, because at this point it was all Scott, I was done.
Speaker 1: I sat in the audience and almost like galaxy express.
Speaker 0: That's my deal.
Speaker 1: It is, but not that it is not everyone's deal.
Speaker 1: You just don't realize it yet.
Speaker 1: Scott gave a good, you know, 15 minute.
Speaker 1: Here's the deal with this described.
Speaker 0: It was not as good as I could have done it cause it was midnight ish.
Speaker 1: And then we showed to this crowd who had pretty much never seen it.
Speaker 1: The first episode of galaxy express three nines and it went over really well.
Speaker 1: I think almost everyone in that room is going to watch all of the show or at least most of it on crunchy roll.
Speaker 0: Hopefully they'll skip some of the bad episodes.
Speaker 1: Thing is they don't get that bad.
Speaker 1: They never get to that.
Speaker 0: There are, there are silly episodes.
Speaker 1: I never get to the Island episode, uh, extent.
Speaker 0: There is some, I guess not, but you know, there's some that could be considered Island episodes.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Uh, we also, the enemy used to see showing actually.
Speaker 0: I really, that was totally awesome.
Speaker 0: Like it was Saturday.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: Then we'll, we'll wait.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Ready for Saturday.
Speaker 0: So I mean, you should see it was just as awesome as it always is.
Speaker 0: You got a whole bunch of people.
Speaker 0: He told him the enemy, you should see same panel as always.
Speaker 1: What's credit is always, there are people who have been to this panel three times and they come every time because they just enjoy it.
Speaker 0: And I don't know what's so enjoyable about it.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I could see it being enjoyable.
Speaker 1: I mean, we're funny.
Speaker 0: Watch this moron moron.
Speaker 0: I can't believe you haven't watched this.
Speaker 0: What's wrong with you call yourself an anime fan.
Speaker 0: You haven't watched this yet.
Speaker 0: We said the same exact things to watch as we told you to watch the last time.
Speaker 0: Why have you still not watched them?
Speaker 1: I think they always forget that they can just go to the website and download the slides and see the list.
Speaker 1: So they keep coming back after they've seen like the things they wrote down to watch more of the things that they wrote down.
Speaker 0: Anyway, afterwards, uh, we did this, we re did, we originally scheduled it for two hours and I sort of wish we had had the two hours, but we had an anime music showing, which is basically the idea was, Hey, we told you what to see, but now you have no excuse.
Speaker 0: If you sit right there and don't move your ass at all, we're just going to show them to you.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Then you got no excuses for not watching this crap, but being short, you know, we only had an hour.
Speaker 1: and the scary thing is we had to turn people away because the room was full.
Speaker 1: for no, you know, animation see a panel's worth of people lined up to see, see the anime you should see, but only a few of them could get in because the room was already full from anime.
Speaker 0: You should say, yeah, we got to put that in bigger room next year.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But as a result, you know, we was cut short.
Speaker 1: The room was full.
Speaker 1: We basically showed a bunch of short things first, which I had planned to show anyway.
Speaker 1: And then one episode of something and it, it worked so well.
Speaker 1: We showed the daikon anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, think about almost despite the daikon animations, right.
Speaker 0: Being such this incredibly important stuff on a very small, small percentage of, you know, uh, American anime fans know what they are, have seen them, understand them, et cetera.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So I explained the daikon animations and then showed three and four, both of them.
Speaker 0: Of course, if you don't know, there are only two of them, three and four, there's no one or two.
Speaker 0: Um, and you know, because I had explained this, you know, so intently to people like look at this 1982 nerds in a basement drawing on cells, right?
Speaker 0: No computers, no nothing.
Speaker 0: They brought this to a convention and showed it to everyone at the convention.
Speaker 1: And I was like, uh, nevermind the whole story about how now studio madhouse does the same thing for those same people who made that eventually made Ava.
Speaker 0: What are you doing with your life?
Speaker 0: Sitting as anime con losers.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then I showed it to him and I showed him the other one and of course they were blown away.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Like they were, they were like clapping and I'm like, what the fuck?
Speaker 0: No one who made this is here to this day is my name.
Speaker 0: He did.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: So stop clapping because people clap after showing because it's the expression of, you know what?
Speaker 1: That was crazy.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 1: And I have to express how awesome it was.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, uh, after we showed that we showed on your mark, which no one had fricking seen.
Speaker 1: And I saw a couple of people in the audience crying at the end of it.
Speaker 0: Well, that's what it's supposed to do.
Speaker 1: I cried the first time I saw it.
Speaker 0: Miyazaki is the master.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I learned there's another version of that.
Speaker 1: That is also for reals to a different song.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I did not know that.
Speaker 1: I learned a bunch of stuff about on your mark.
Speaker 1: Beyond what I knew.
Speaker 1: Now then we did this because this is how we found out about magnetic Rose.
Speaker 1: And also while I would normally be hesitant to do this sort of thing,
Speaker 0: I would have just showed magnetic Rose if we had some fricking time, but there
Speaker 1: is, there happens to be four magnetic Rose, like Kevin Caldwell anime music video that expresses how amazing magnetic Rose is as well as can be expressed.
Speaker 1: So we showed that after explaining, you know, this is just an AMV and good God, people love that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh man, we should have used.
Speaker 0: Oh no.
Speaker 0: At that panel instead of the other one.
Speaker 1: Well, my plan for Otacon, if we get the room is to show, do you know, either Friday or Saturday at a kind of early good time anime, you should see for like an hour and a half and go into more depth on into two hours.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Two hours of animation scene.
Speaker 1: We'll start with the basics.
Speaker 1: You go all the way through the obscure and everything.
Speaker 1: And then I want the next like six hours in that room to be just showings and commentary.
Speaker 1: showings and commentary to introduce people to every great anime.
Speaker 0: But anyway, we also showed the first episode of princess due to, and let me tell you, I think it worked.
Speaker 0: I think people realize that that was a real show and not two, two.
Speaker 1: I still, you know, we talked about this in other reviews.
Speaker 1: I think we personally have caused this huge resurgence in princess.
Speaker 1: two, two, because you know, we keep an every animation.
Speaker 1: See, it is like the poster child of don't deny an anime.
Speaker 1: If you don't know what it's really about, two two is awesome and you'll like it.
Speaker 1: Don't be turned off by the fact you do.
Speaker 0: We should watch all the fancy Lala and then start pushing that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we should.
Speaker 1: The dinosaurs, dinosaurs, the sad episode where she draws the pet and oh my God, we should do princess to do first fancy Lala.
Speaker 0: dinosaurs versus dancing.
Speaker 1: You know, if we keep doing this, then someday we're going to get to a point to where people trust us so much.
Speaker 1: That's the point where we're like space sailor photon starlight.
Speaker 1: Odeon is like the best fucking show ever.
Speaker 0: showed Odeon at the con in one of the showing rooms.
Speaker 0: I don't know who went to see it.
Speaker 1: We told people not to.
Speaker 1: We told some people to, okay, but princess to, to, you know, obviously the people in the audience, you know, some people were dubious.
Speaker 1: They were kind of less dubious now because a lot of people who had seen the panel before clapped and cheered and told them all to watch.
Speaker 0: It's basically, that's why you showed princess two to last, right?
Speaker 0: It's like, we show them the daikon and they're just, and the, and the, you know, on your mark and they're just overcome with emotion at this amazingness.
Speaker 0: Right?
Speaker 0: So it's like, okay, I've showed you this amazingness.
Speaker 0: You trust me now, right?
Speaker 0: You trust me enough to sit your ass and watch this princess due to, you know, even though it's called princess tutu.
Speaker 1: during the opener of princess to do the look on their faces, people in their crowd were like, ah, you sure guys, when she makes that pile of flowers at the end, God damn.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: So, uh, what else did we do on Saturday?
Speaker 0: We did, we actually got away and were able to do things on Saturday besides just panels.
Speaker 1: Well, because you see for the first time ever, you know, geek nights is at front row crew.com because the front row crew is the group and geek nights is just the headlining front lining thing of the front row.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I'm actually doing a lot of work on the website.
Speaker 0: I made a big progress.
Speaker 1: Uh, you know, I'm working on it on the train, but expect in the next two years to see this gigantic growing of all the other front row crew stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, we've always planned to do it.
Speaker 0: It's just, you know, it takes a long time.
Speaker 0: We want to do it right.
Speaker 0: We don't want to, you know, he rushed into geek nights just to keep something up sort of like the same strategy GDGT had.
Speaker 0: Remember they, they, and now they quit and gadget and they said, all right, GDGT.
Speaker 0: And they started doing a podcast, you know, which is basically the continuation of the old and gadget podcast, but it took them like a while to actually get GDGT the site up.
Speaker 0: So it's all taken us, uh, significantly longer, you know, it's been like, you know, four or five years, but even so stuff's coming.
Speaker 0: Scott's box is now on a regular schedule route, you know, once a month.
Speaker 0: And, uh, I gotta, I'm going to do the last episode of Scott's got robot maybe next week.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: You know, so yeah, it's, it's going good here, but as a result, we got together several members of the front row crew and there was a large block where they presented panels and we went to get some fricking food.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I ended up getting a, I ate the con food once.
Speaker 0: the con food last year was actually really good this year.
Speaker 0: Not so good.
Speaker 1: Luckily that tavern nearby, like no one seems to know about it.
Speaker 1: You can just go there and get lunch, like right away.
Speaker 0: You could see it when you walk out the front door of the convention center.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: Despite being a brew pub though, or not, you know, nominally a tavern, pretty weak selection of beer.
Speaker 1: I had to suffice for the table wine, which was okay.
Speaker 0: It was pretty much just an average, you know, normal pub place.
Speaker 0: It wasn't anything special.
Speaker 1: That was like the only time we got to get outside of this fricking room and walk around and that there's anywhere to walk to.
Speaker 0: At least they had, we got the awesome breakfast twice.
Speaker 1: It was sad though.
Speaker 0: It was still there that we ran anime.
Speaker 1: You should see, see the anime.
Speaker 1: You should see it.
Speaker 1: It was like crazy, crazy crowded.
Speaker 1: Like people were sitting on the floor crowding in fire Marshall problem right after that.
Speaker 1: No, your creators learn about the directors.
Speaker 1: They're like 20 people in the room.
Speaker 1: Everyone leaves.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But then we had Emily doing living in Japan.
Speaker 0: We had, I didn't see it, but I'm sure it was, we didn't get to see any of this.
Speaker 1: We had independent game development with Alex.
Speaker 1: We had geekology.
Speaker 0: We're just presented a research that was real popular here.
Speaker 1: That was crazy popular law.
Speaker 1: And it was noted in the panel feedback session by two different people as being awesome.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: How to be a good game master with Pete and Wyatt and you know, all the, all those, all the game masters and gamers in the front row crew, Kendo, the way of the sword with Katsunori Masashita, who is basically a kendo badass.
Speaker 1: And then the Connecticut match game, which was scheduled originally for two hours, plus a half hour of setup, various main things made it be scheduled for an hour.
Speaker 1: And we did not prepare any guests and we had planned to cancel it.
Speaker 1: A lot of people showed up.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 1: So we, uh, we winged it and it seemed to go over really, really, really well.
Speaker 0: Luckily we put together a good panels, uncle, yo, me, uh, Emily Conrad and Scott Johnson.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: And for contestants, so we got a pretty good contestant from the audience and we got Laura to be the ringer because Laura knows her anime.
Speaker 1: So I could count on Laura to give the funny anime answer.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: She also scored a whole bunch of points because she knew what was going on.
Speaker 0: Did the contestants score any points at all?
Speaker 0: Never.
Speaker 0: Oh, so sad.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: I gave, we gave the contestant the, uh, prize, if you can call it that anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It was a most dangerous prize.
Speaker 0: You know, that's the one thing is after I saw that our schedule got changed.
Speaker 0: I thought going into kinetic con, we would, at least we would cancel two or three things.
Speaker 0: I thought we might've canceled the galaxy express.
Speaker 0: We would cancel the match game.
Speaker 0: I thought we would cancel the crab people and the Saturday night hangout.
Speaker 1: We plan to cancel a lot of these things.
Speaker 0: Well, the Saturday night hangout was sort of canceled.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, it was canceled in that we just left.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We just went to bed.
Speaker 0: Well actually, no, we went and played games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we did.
Speaker 0: But yeah, no, we didn't cancel anything.
Speaker 0: It just, it all, we ran all those events and they actually turned out a lot better than you would expect.
Speaker 0: Just throwing some shit together.
Speaker 1: Oh, uncle yo did his, uh, standup, uh, Saturday night right after the match game.
Speaker 0: Very popular, big line.
Speaker 1: Super awesome.
Speaker 1: A lot of people looked like they had to be turned away because no one left the room from the match game.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, but Saturday was just totally cool.
Speaker 0: Uh, what did I do on Saturday?
Speaker 0: I don't even remember.
Speaker 0: We did panels.
Speaker 1: We ate, we did the super art flight.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: While, while everyone else is running panels, we did the super art fight, which you already talked about and things of the day.
Speaker 0: We went to the dealer's room.
Speaker 0: I went to the artist's alley.
Speaker 0: I looked around the gaming area.
Speaker 0: We went to eat lunch.
Speaker 0: We did all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 1: So, um, I got plus.
Speaker 1: Saturday night, like we, we gamed all night hanging out with Luke Crane and Phil and the rest of the crew.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We played a trans Europa, which is a game we will talk about in the future.
Speaker 0: Maybe we get a chance to play it again.
Speaker 0: Nice.
Speaker 0: You know, simple to learn, difficult to master kind of game.
Speaker 1: Oh, we were also hanging out.
Speaker 1: I'll give a shout out to people at the end of this episode, but we got to hang out with the awesome staffer, the panel staffer from our room, who I forget your name, dude, but you were totally awesome.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: There was also awesome dude who asked me for a copy of galaxy express three nine, the movie.
Speaker 0: I mailed him a DVD today that has that the second movie, the sanctuary manga, and also all of DMC.
Speaker 1: Oh man.
Speaker 0: Which he wanted.
Speaker 0: So that guy's awesome.
Speaker 0: I sent him his DVD.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Speaking of which DMC crazy popular, but you know, we showed it on Friday, like early in the morning and we showed it again on Saturday, early in the morning.
Speaker 1: And the first, basically we had to pull the, well, anyone in this room be offended by this.
Speaker 1: And there was on Saturday, there was this kid clearly there for one day, like with his mom.
Speaker 1: And he's kind of young.
Speaker 1: He was like middle school.
Speaker 1: And we're like, well, anyone be offended by very, very strong language, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 1: And the kids looking real nervous.
Speaker 1: And he looks at his mom and his mom's like, yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: And then he's like, and they both laughed heartily at Detroit metal city.
Speaker 0: It's the legend of Krauser.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So let's see what else went down at the CT con convention went down, but we didn't get to see any of that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Uh, what of the convention did I see besides the super art fight?
Speaker 1: We'll get to that.
Speaker 1: I saw some cool stuff, but, uh, Sunday, Sunday was the death day, Sunday, Sunday.
Speaker 1: We, I was, I was so like, I was just, I was done on Sunday.
Speaker 0: I was actually kind of okay on Sunday.
Speaker 0: Cause I got an okay sleep on Saturday.
Speaker 1: I got like five hours of sleep.
Speaker 1: Cause we stayed up until like two.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But we had to be back at the con at eight for good morning, Connecticut.
Speaker 1: Hey, we had to check out of the hotel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was all right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Checking out of the hotel was a little bit rough.
Speaker 0: And then I left the present.
Speaker 0: I bought a presentation clicker.
Speaker 0: That was totally awesome.
Speaker 0: And it totally sweet and worth every penny.
Speaker 0: I almost left it in the hotel room, but luckily I also forgot to leave my key in the hotel room.
Speaker 0: So I was able to go back up and get it, but the elevators, oh man, it sucked.
Speaker 0: I ended up actually getting off on like the ninth floor from the 19th floor and then taking the stairs from there.
Speaker 0: And then I met someone in the elevator who knew me and, you know, we walked down the stairs and it was kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: We had something special scheduled on it.
Speaker 1: Well, we had a couple of things on Sunday.
Speaker 1: Sunday was the, for anyone who wants to know, you know, how do you pull off dealing with situations or on the fly coming up with, you know, managing a panel or entertaining your crowd.
Speaker 1: Sunday was the day because we pulled everything off without a hitch, but, uh, good morning, whatever.
Speaker 1: Crab people.
Speaker 1: We scheduled this in the book because we had nothing.
Speaker 1: We had no idea what to put here.
Speaker 1: So we scheduled it and we figured at some point during the con, we would come up with an idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So we went in to the crab people panel and of course, no matter what we were going to talk about what crab people is, and we talked about the South park episode of crab.
Speaker 1: There were a lot of people there, scary number of people, right?
Speaker 0: So we described to them, you know, what crab people is, you know, and how it's sort of a placeholder for when you don't know what else to put there.
Speaker 0: And sometimes if you don't ever come up with a replacement, it's just crab people.
Speaker 0: And that's why there's crab people in South park.
Speaker 1: So we do this for a couple of minutes.
Speaker 1: And then sure enough, cat low, who already had a panel prepared.
Speaker 1: Uh, no means no.
Speaker 1: When she ran at Otacon ran her panel and everyone loved it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It was awesome.
Speaker 1: And, uh, I think what I want to do is a great filler.
Speaker 1: anywhere we ever are in charge of panels or in any capacity.
Speaker 1: I want to always schedule a crab people on Sunday, just always, I want it to be like this kind of semi inside joke shtick because cons have that stuff.
Speaker 1: There'll always be the crab people and people will know that when you go to that panel, there are crab people.
Speaker 0: Maybe like we should have like crazy surprises at the panel.
Speaker 0: Like if we're head of panels, like Connecticut, right?
Speaker 0: Maybe crab people should be like one of the big guests panels, like secret XKCD panel.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Like, Oh, by the way, random Monroe is at the convention.
Speaker 0: I didn't even see him or talk to him.
Speaker 0: I did see him at MOCA.
Speaker 1: One point I'm in our room and you know, the room's kind of full and I see this crazy line outside the door.
Speaker 0: And all the time there was a crazy line.
Speaker 0: It was for animal Monroe.
Speaker 0: every time, both times, two times because everything else that was a big line.
Speaker 0: It was either super art fight, which we saw or for us or something in our room.
Speaker 1: Like I say one thing we couldn't have super art fight.
Speaker 1: We would not have been able to see it except that we kind of know the people who do it and we know the artists and such.
Speaker 1: So, and you know, as we're walking toward art fight, the art fight people like, Hey, you guys geek guides, you got to go to art fight.
Speaker 1: We're like, we're on our way.
Speaker 1: And they're like, Oh man, cool.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: And then we get to it and those people waiting to go into super art fight, but there's still a panel in there.
Speaker 0: That's not over yet.
Speaker 0: So we just walk in and sit in the front row for the panel.
Speaker 0: Well, well, well, and then that panel leaves and we're sitting in the front row for super art fight.
Speaker 1: We walk up to the door and one of the super art fight guys goes, Hey, it's you guys.
Speaker 1: And he kind of points us in.
Speaker 1: So we walked in to the other panel and just sat in the front row.
Speaker 0: I just walked right in.
Speaker 0: I didn't even see that guy.
Speaker 1: That guy waved to say, and I had talked to him a little bit, whatever.
Speaker 0: It's all good.
Speaker 0: Super art fight rocks the shizzy.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: And I cannot say a hundred percent because it's not my department, but super art fight is almost definitely going to be at Connecticut next year, probably in main event.
Speaker 0: I hope so.
Speaker 0: And I hope we can get super art fight, you know, to all sorts of other conventions that we can influence.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: Maybe even just, you know, like just in New York randomly.
Speaker 1: My goal is to get them at PAX East and to get Gabe to be a contestant.
Speaker 1: Fuck yes.
Speaker 1: That would be like the biggest fucking thing.
Speaker 0: Gabe versus Kurtz.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: You know, you know, it'd be awesome though.
Speaker 0: If we could get like, we can get like, uh, it would basically be like Gabe versus everyone.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So that we can tag out.
Speaker 0: We should have like, no, he should just have to fight three people.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And here's, here's the three people I think Gabe should have to fight.
Speaker 0: You're ready.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Scott Kurtz, the guy.
Speaker 0: Cause you know, they're so, you know, enemies, right.
Speaker 0: He should have to fight, uh, David Peterson.
Speaker 0: Cause he couldn't possibly win.
Speaker 0: We got it.
Speaker 0: We have someone who can beat him.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And the third person that he should have to fight is you don't remember the guy's name.
Speaker 1: Are you thinking about who I'm thinking about?
Speaker 0: Oh, it's the guy that like gave, like Gabe was inspired by silver or something.
Speaker 0: The guy who did the Kim possible, whatever.
Speaker 0: Oh, cause it's like, that's a duel.
Speaker 1: And he never said why exactly.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I wish I could remember what that guy's name was, but those are the three people that should fight gate gave in the super art fight.
Speaker 1: I like the idea of having an all-star cast that can tag team in and out.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, one thing that was, uh, you know, the tag, you know, I was watching the tag battle.
Speaker 0: The tag battle actually was, didn't work out so well.
Speaker 0: I liked the non tag battles better.
Speaker 1: Well, you'd have to change up the rules of the tag battle.
Speaker 0: It can't just be a little out of control basically.
Speaker 0: And it lost sort of the structure.
Speaker 0: that sort of kept it, uh, kept it nice, even though some funny, crazy things did happen.
Speaker 1: I think, you know, the tag battle and all those people get involved, the results on the, on the tag battle, you realize has to be two V two and there's rules about if you tag someone in, you can't tag back.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Stuff like that.
Speaker 0: But that's not how they did it.
Speaker 0: It was basically just got out of control and there were just too many people doing arts and whatever, but it was cool.
Speaker 0: Uh, one thing though, there was the dude from Columbia, uh, what's his name?
Speaker 0: Cypher.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I think was his name.
Speaker 1: That guy was my favorite.
Speaker 1: My favorite non-Yuko.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, Scott Johnson, our Scott Johnson, right.
Speaker 0: Said that that guy from Columbia is usually on a podcast with the extra life.
Speaker 0: Scott Johnson.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So we got to get all three of them together.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So the best was, it was, uh, it was Cypher versus what Garth Graham, I think is the guy's name.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: When he drew that, so Cypher started drawing zombies and Garth Graham started drawing gears.
Speaker 0: and then Garth goes over to put some gears on the zombies.
Speaker 0: So he goes over and puts a zombie bite in the gear.
Speaker 0: And that's when people were like, super our fight for the win.
Speaker 1: That gear butter was the second best thing.
Speaker 0: that gear bite and zombie man.
Speaker 1: Ah, it was pretty much the gear biter, the Bruce Campbell in a Cosby sweater macho man thing.
Speaker 0: And a steampunk Pikachu.
Speaker 1: I don't as Dapper and top Haddish as steampunk.
Speaker 1: Pikachu was Pokemon.
Speaker 1: The horny unicorn behind Billy Mays.
Speaker 0: I didn't like the horny unicorn.
Speaker 0: I like the steam poker.
Speaker 1: The horny unicorn got points when it became a clown.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I should go to the super art flight website and put some stuff in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I just put in messenger Z.
Speaker 1: I was very, I saved the day twice.
Speaker 1: I'm so happy because you go did not know who super macho man Randy Savage was.
Speaker 1: Oh, but I had the pre.
Speaker 0: I was like G I S and I was like, I held it up and she's having to slim Jim.
Speaker 1: And she looks at it.
Speaker 1: She's like, Oh, that guy.
Speaker 1: And then it was game.
Speaker 1: Next art fight.
Speaker 1: Dude didn't know who a pagoda was.
Speaker 1: I pull up a picture.
Speaker 1: He looks at it for like two seconds and he draws a perfect a pagoda.
Speaker 0: Pretty good.
Speaker 1: It was crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That's what you have when you have artist skills.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, someone shows me a hello.
Speaker 0: It shows me a picture of a programming language.
Speaker 0: I'll do a hello world Tyco.
Speaker 1: I know you don't listen to our show, but remember when they did that comic way about how like Photoshop heroes.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That is what art fight is.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: It is Photoshop heroes.
Speaker 0: We should find some way to bring super art fight online.
Speaker 1: Oh, you could do that with some sort of real time.
Speaker 1: Oh, cocky.
Speaker 1: But it loses the magic.
Speaker 1: It does lose the magic of when the referee threw the yellow card at Yuko when she accidentally switched hands for a second to color something during the left-handed round.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Uh, yellow card.
Speaker 1: Anyway, enough about super art fight as awesome as it is.
Speaker 1: Um, after crab people, Emily did becoming an animator, which I watched like 20 minutes of.
Speaker 0: I didn't watch any of it.
Speaker 0: It is
Speaker 1: really cool because I didn't get to see a lot of the front row crew panels to see, you know, we do like these panels on tech or anime, you know, things we really know a lot about and we're really, we had this Japanese professor come up to us after all of our panels.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: What was her name?
Speaker 1: I forget her name, but I have her business card.
Speaker 1: We're going to be talking.
Speaker 1: I want to do stuff with her.
Speaker 1: Cause she's cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: She was coming over to study like, you know, fandom of anime and manga among the U S peoples.
Speaker 0: Like she was seriously studying it.
Speaker 0: She was asking us all these great questions and it was, it was just totally awesome.
Speaker 0: And we definitely got to do a lot more stuff with her.
Speaker 1: But like, she was amazed at how much we know about anime, which is sad in a way because we are rank amateurs compared to the majesty of Daryl.
Speaker 1: So right.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And she was like, wow, you know, more than Japanese people know about anime, just fucked up in a way.
Speaker 1: But so, you know, all this professionalism, I lost my train of thought, but I'm getting it back very slow.
Speaker 1: So seeing Emily do this panel and animation was like going to a lecture on animation because she is an expert at animation in the way that we were experts at like computer stuff.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And it was like the same, you know, professional slides, professional jargon and explanation.
Speaker 1: It was just great.
Speaker 1: And Katsu did ask the Kendo master, you know, the Q and a for Kendo getting into it.
Speaker 1: We had Scott Johnson and I believe other people, I didn't see the panel talk about, you know, actually what it takes to go from.
Speaker 1: I go to anime cons to, I run anime.
Speaker 0: Is that what he talked about?
Speaker 0: I'm still not sure what he talked about.
Speaker 1: That's what he talked about because he went from going to anime cons to running anime cards, much like us.
Speaker 1: Moet anthropomorphism ton was very popular.
Speaker 0: That was part of that panel.
Speaker 1: That was Emily and Katsu talking about all that Moet and throw good tons there.
Speaker 1: So the action castle reprise Jared was gone and as a result, yeah, see, there you go.
Speaker 0: We scheduled him for something that he didn't show for him.
Speaker 1: So yeah, that's true.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: And a character building character burning workshop.
Speaker 1: Now we had nothing planned for either of these and we did not have Jared to run action castle.
Speaker 1: We cannot run action castle.
Speaker 0: I mean, my, I did a daring dungeon, but I did it for people who had never played action castle.
Speaker 0: So they didn't realize how poor facsimile it was, but now I've actually seen a seeing action castle again and studying it.
Speaker 0: I think I can, you know, apparently they also have a jungle adventure.
Speaker 1: I can tell you one thing about making an action castle.
Speaker 0: I can make it.
Speaker 0: I feel that I can do an action castle now because there was the acting component of it that I was not incorporating and such well to memorize and you have to memorize.
Speaker 0: I'm going to memorize it no matter what I'm going to make and think it was action castles a lot simpler than I remember it being.
Speaker 0: My daring dungeon was really complicated and I think that was part of the problem.
Speaker 0: I'm going to come up with a much simpler one and you'll see I'm going to, it's going to be my own thing.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I'll do daring dungeon though.
Speaker 0: I might make a space adventure.
Speaker 1: I still want to make bastard castle and sinking ship.
Speaker 0: No sinking ship.
Speaker 1: Those are my two, but the one thing I can say about making an action castle, it takes a long time.
Speaker 1: So a million people showed up to this and we had nothing.
Speaker 1: So we decided to try out something that we had talked about, but we weren't sure if it was feasible.
Speaker 1: Like we talk about this a lot and we wanted to run it at a con, but we never worked out the logistics.
Speaker 1: We never figured out, like we never did the analysis of can this work on a stage and I gave it a 50 50 shot if it was feasible at all.
Speaker 1: So we've ran a burning wheel demo for the audience.
Speaker 1: We basically had two people who do burning wheel and two people who had never played burning wheel in their lives.
Speaker 1: One of whom had never even heard of burning wheel.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Awesome staff guy.
Speaker 0: Uh, Phil, me and rim.
Speaker 0: Now Alex was GM and Alex did a real good job.
Speaker 1: Luke crane would have done it, but he had to leave.
Speaker 1: He couldn't stick around for Sunday.
Speaker 0: He left Saturday night.
Speaker 1: We kind of just tried running this for a crowd and let me tell you, the crowd loved it.
Speaker 1: It'll take almost nothing to turn this into a real event.
Speaker 0: I did a really good job too.
Speaker 1: Well, well to a degree, Scott had like all these plans to win as the elf, but I was the rat, which was a big fucking mistake for all you other people.
Speaker 1: Because as Lou crane told me, the rat is the most difficult character in the sword to play, but the rat's the easiest as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 1: There is a almost surefire way to win as the red, unless the other people are privy to the knowledge.
Speaker 1: So I basically got Scott, the elf and the dwarf to kill each other.
Speaker 0: It was so crazy.
Speaker 0: Cause I basically said I went all out, right?
Speaker 0: I was like, I just used everything in my power to fucking get that sword right first.
Speaker 0: I use my persona point to pay the rat and it fucking worked.
Speaker 1: Not big mistake.
Speaker 1: You fucked up right there because as soon as you pay me, I don't care one shit about you anymore.
Speaker 1: I already have the money in hand.
Speaker 0: No, my mistake wasn't paying the rat.
Speaker 0: It was that when I, afterwards in my duel with the dwarf, I appealed to the rat.
Speaker 0: I should have appealed to the human, right?
Speaker 0: I could've done, I could've gotten the human to help me out and demolish the, uh, the dwarf even more, you know, and the fact that the dwarf did some damage to my body of argument meant I had to compromise.
Speaker 0: If I could've just demolished him completely, like I was going to, thanks to his, you know, uh, failed in sight, which gave me plus 11 D. then, uh, you know, it would have been a much better outcome because he wouldn't have been able to, you know, I wouldn't be able to get the sword.
Speaker 0: And as soon as I get the sword, I just stabbed the human and get the fuck out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but no, you got stabbed in the kidney and then, but then all of circles.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: I think that there's something about the sword that if you try circles, it just always works.
Speaker 1: So you see circles up his brother, his brother, the swordsman and the dwarf and that guy stab each other.
Speaker 1: And then me and the human just take the sword and leave.
Speaker 0: These guys got that fucking dwarf that piece of shit.
Speaker 1: You guys are laying there bleeding to death.
Speaker 1: Just, ah, fuck you.
Speaker 1: Fuck you.
Speaker 0: Fuck you.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But we pulled it off and we now know it is perfectly feasible to run a live demo of the sword in front of a crowd.
Speaker 1: All we need are slides of character sheets and volleys to put up on the projectors and microphones.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Microphones and some either a webcam or something.
Speaker 1: I'd like to have a top down view of the die rolls for the crowd.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that'd be good.
Speaker 1: Other than that, it's set.
Speaker 1: So we're going to run this at some bigger con in the future.
Speaker 0: Hopefully maybe Pax East.
Speaker 0: We'll see require some logistics.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But if we have like Lou Crane at Pax East, we can do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely.
Speaker 1: So after that was the character burning workshop, which they put a character building workshop in the top level schedule.
Speaker 1: But it was the real description in the rest of the schedule.
Speaker 1: I felt bad for these like eight cosplay people who came expecting something very different.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But actually, you know, it was sort of haphazard.
Speaker 0: But like as it went on, it actually started to work.
Speaker 0: I was.
Speaker 0: I was very surprised.
Speaker 1: Another.
Speaker 1: We're not sure if this was really feasible event.
Speaker 1: Let's try it.
Speaker 1: And we had Luke or not Luke.
Speaker 1: We had Pete and Wyatt and I sat up there with them.
Speaker 1: And I think what made it, in my opinion, was me being awesome and being awesome.
Speaker 1: Because, you see, I had the laptop and I was losing my voice, you know, finally on Sunday.
Speaker 1: Radio voice can only hold out for so long, yelling for like 40 hours straight.
Speaker 1: So I put the laptop up on the projector, opened up like Abby Ward.
Speaker 1: And as we as a group, you know, with the audience created this character.
Speaker 1: By the way, I'm going to post the character online when I get a chance.
Speaker 1: We had a really awesome character from nothing.
Speaker 0: Pretty good character.
Speaker 0: That's how life paths work.
Speaker 1: Like by the end of this, everyone who wasn't interested in burning wheel was basically like they were going to go buy the books as soon as they got home.
Speaker 0: But we made this character with the is actually Luke Crane told me there was.
Speaker 0: the thing is there's some game sellers, you know, in the Connecticut dealers room.
Speaker 0: And, you know, they have indie RPGs, some of them, quite a few of them.
Speaker 0: In fact, one guy who had burning wheels sold all his copies, went to get more for Saturday and then went to get more for Sunday.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like, you know, he sold them all every day.
Speaker 1: So I'm very happy about that.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 1: But what I did is I did a style of humor that I've never really done at conventions.
Speaker 1: I'm shooting my own horn a little bit here, but I think it's justified because I had people laughing their asses off while Pete and Wyatt are trying to serious business Lee kind of run this character burning workshop and get the crowd into it.
Speaker 1: All I did was type stuff on the on the screen while they talked.
Speaker 1: And let me tell you, it is very easy to get people to laugh by typing the word prostitute periodically throughout.
Speaker 0: Maybe we should do some sort of high concept panel where it's two screens, two projectors, two laptops, and we're just typing or maybe we just bring up a Google Wave and we type.
Speaker 1: I like the idea of some sort of iron, some sort of panel where you have people who have to do a panel kind of on the fly.
Speaker 1: But in the meantime, there is running commentary on two projectors.
Speaker 1: that is just text in a file from like me and Scott, Sadler and Waldorf, something like that.
Speaker 1: But anyway, we also it worked really well.
Speaker 1: You know, we got the crowd into it and we had them kind of think about a character just by following the rules of burning wheel.
Speaker 1: We made this bad ass character in about an hour.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So other notable things from Connecticut, there were these two people who really wanted to play burning wheel real bad.
Speaker 0: And a lot of people did get to play burning wheel.
Speaker 0: I think he said he ran like five swords, if not more, you know.
Speaker 1: And that was just Luke, not counting Alex.
Speaker 0: Alex ran some, and then they gave burning wheel stickers to everyone who played.
Speaker 0: And I saw a lot of stickers around.
Speaker 0: So a lot of people got to play.
Speaker 0: That's a brilliant idea, because one everyone we're doing that we got to get stickers before the next, before packs.
Speaker 1: This is so brilliant.
Speaker 1: And conventions need to do this in a big way.
Speaker 1: But we are going to capitalize on it first.
Speaker 0: Get a gigantic stick in a row.
Speaker 0: Say she's making you guys pins or something.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: But what Luke would do is if you played in a demo of burning wheel, you got a burning wheel sticker and you stuck it on your badge.
Speaker 1: Now, think about what this does.
Speaker 1: One, it prevents multiple people from getting multiple demos, different DMS and taking up time to it reminds people.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Burning wheel and any role playing games.
Speaker 1: And then they'll go buy it when they get home.
Speaker 1: Three, you're walking around the con and people say, hey, what's that sticker?
Speaker 1: And one thing I found is that much like with Princess Tutu, much like the Pokemon stamp rally.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but also Princess Tutu.
Speaker 1: When we get people excited about something, if someone else asks them about that thing, the excitedness transfers over.
Speaker 1: Hey, man, what's the sticker?
Speaker 1: Well, you don't know about burning wheel.
Speaker 0: I can burn away a bitch.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: But three, three things.
Speaker 1: What it does is if I have the sticker and I see someone else with the sticker, you want to get the stick?
Speaker 1: No, no.
Speaker 1: I have the sticker.
Speaker 1: He has the sticker.
Speaker 1: We don't know each other.
Speaker 1: We're just at this car.
Speaker 1: Oh, that suddenly two people who are into indie role playing games find each other and become friends.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's all good.
Speaker 0: So there are these two people, though, who wanted to play.
Speaker 0: And like, you know, usually when this sort of happens at conventions, you see someone and you like you want to do something, but you can't schedule it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it's like they really wanted to play.
Speaker 0: So I promised them, all right, we'll play Sunday, I swear.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So, you know, Luke Crane had already left by the time and, you know, such and such just like, we're going to do it.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to let you leave without playing.
Speaker 0: And we tried real hard and like they just disappeared and we didn't see them again, even though we like waited for them and tried to find.
Speaker 1: I tweeted just in case I tried to get him to come if they were still around to Action Castle because we were going to run.
Speaker 0: I think they left at noonish or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They just disappeared and we couldn't make it happen, even though we tried real hard.
Speaker 0: So email.
Speaker 0: normally it's like I would blame myself because I promised that I was trying to make it happen for those people.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: They disappeared.
Speaker 0: I waited by the RPG room.
Speaker 0: They didn't show up.
Speaker 0: So you know what?
Speaker 0: I'm going to blame them.
Speaker 1: It's tough.
Speaker 1: Email us and I'm sure we'll see you.
Speaker 0: We'll see you at another convention.
Speaker 0: And if I do see you at another convention, I'll pretty much just drop, you know, and if nothing else, I'll just drop everything immediately unless it's I'm on a panel.
Speaker 0: And I will personally run it for you if I have to, because, you know, that's how it goes.
Speaker 1: So we put a panel feedback session in and because our schedule was shifted a little bit by the time it conflicted with the real feedback session, which is not intentional.
Speaker 1: But that was fine.
Speaker 1: A lot of people came to the panel feedback session, gave a lot of feedback, and it was the first time to listen to any nasty masquerade feedbacks.
Speaker 1: It is the first time I have been able to be on the feedback session as opposed to being at the feedback session.
Speaker 0: I think I'm real good at being on the feedback panel.
Speaker 1: I think so, too.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: It was real fun.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, you know, that vibe at Otacon like there's a certain vibe at the feedback session of the people on stage.
Speaker 1: And I suddenly had that vibe in me like it was weird.
Speaker 0: how suddenly it really because I sort of noticed a different vibe, right?
Speaker 0: Because it was like I was thinking about the Otacon vibe, you know, the way that people are up on the feedback panel being like.
Speaker 0: But I was just like, you know, shooting the shit, being totally honest with people.
Speaker 0: I was like a guy was like, hey, how come, you know, there's not more 18 plus stuff.
Speaker 0: I'm like, first, regardless of legalities, right.
Speaker 0: We don't want the newspaper to say tomorrow, you know, Connecticut and showing porn to kids.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So I was just, you know, and I felt it was I was being a lot more open with the people and, you know, less talking down to him.
Speaker 1: One thing that worked really well was we did the thing that we tell Otacon to do they never do is we had the projector showing all the feedback that had already been given.
Speaker 1: And before we let people give feedback, we told them about the things we already knew about.
Speaker 0: Like every time someone gave feedback about something, rim typed it into the word processor and that was up on the projector so everyone could see everything that had been talked about.
Speaker 0: And when we were done, we had a document that contained all the feedback.
Speaker 0: How convenient.
Speaker 0: So obvious, yet no one does it except us.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But after that, you know, everything went smooth.
Speaker 1: We packed up all our stuff.
Speaker 1: We had somehow survived the whole apocalypse.
Speaker 1: We went out and got an awesome dinner in the town next door where there's actually food.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: People don't understand Hartford, Connecticut.
Speaker 0: Hartford, Connecticut is the capital of Connecticut.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: As East Hartford, which is the ghetto and it has West Hartford, which is basically also the city proper.
Speaker 0: Downtown Hartford is all these big office buildings, but there's nothing under like in New York City, the bottom of an office building has stuff.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like if you walk down the street, there'll be clothing stores and delis and all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 0: If you walk down the street in Hartford, it's just concrete and the entrance to the big office building and concrete and the entrance to an office building.
Speaker 0: And that's it.
Speaker 0: It's just office buildings and government buildings.
Speaker 0: There's no stuff on the street.
Speaker 0: I mean, even the Empire State Building, it's like, you know, frigging comic book stores in it and shit and restaurants and all who knows what else.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But, you know, the in Hartford, nothing.
Speaker 0: So the way Hartford works is you have all these office buildings and all these people work in and all those people live either in East Hartford and to get to or in West Hartford, the rich ass suburbs.
Speaker 0: So, of course, on our way out of Connecticut, right, we go to West Hartford, where all the rich people live, where all the nice restaurants are to get dinner because there is nowhere to eat in Hartford because all the office buildings go all the way to the ground and there's nothing in them.
Speaker 0: So lots of fancy restaurants going over there.
Speaker 0: But the Maggie Moo's was closed and we were not able to get cake ice cream.
Speaker 1: Luckily, cake ice cream is now in the grocery store.
Speaker 0: Actually, I bought banana split ice cream when the show was over.
Speaker 0: I'm going to eat some.
Speaker 1: But all things considered, we basically packed panels nonstop in a panel five for the entirety of Connecticut without issue.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think, though, next year, Connecticut, I think we should have, you know, maybe like one or two fewer panel rooms bigger.
Speaker 0: Maybe maybe we'll just combine two of the small ones into one more big one.
Speaker 0: You know, that way we'll have one of their five rooms, I think six rooms.
Speaker 1: There were five panel rooms and three workshop rooms.
Speaker 1: I think what I want, I'm thinking four panel rooms and two workshop.
Speaker 1: I want one big panel room for smaller panel rooms and then two workshops.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking of maybe a big a medium and two smalls.
Speaker 1: We might not be able to do that.
Speaker 1: It depends on the it does.
Speaker 0: We got to look at the layout of the building.
Speaker 0: But, you know, yes, four or five instead of six, maybe.
Speaker 0: And then two workshops instead of three.
Speaker 0: You know, I think I think it'll work out.
Speaker 1: But suffice it to say, one, I got to give huge props and thanks to everyone in the front row crew who gave panels and every one of everyone related to the front row crew who gave panels.
Speaker 1: We really couldn't have done this without you guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we thank the Luke cranes and the Jared's and the Connecticut people, Emily
Speaker 1: and Luke and Alex and Pete and White and Scott and Laura and all the people on the crew, Uncle Yo, everyone who did all those panels
Speaker 0: and the staff guy and the tech guy and who helped us out in the room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Connecticut staff were pretty much pretty awesome and bad as the whole time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Nury, even though she was mostly in the deals room.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: We had.
Speaker 1: we've had a whole bunch of cool listeners like your Lord Yupo was hanging out in the room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all the listeners who came and made the room look more full.
Speaker 1: I forget a lot of your names, which is why I didn't say any more names.
Speaker 0: The strange people who asked us to sign things.
Speaker 0: You are very strange.
Speaker 1: I think it's cool.
Speaker 1: People seem to like the posters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess that's about a Connecticut.
Speaker 0: It's the everything gone next year.
Speaker 0: We're in charge.
Speaker 0: We're going to try to make awesome happen.
Speaker 0: You know, we had to do is you have to basically get as much money as we can to basically bring people in.
Speaker 0: That way we could, you know, pretty much my plan for Connecticut next year, panels and workshops wise, because we could bring in like the crew.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then maybe we could bring in like, you know, Ninja Consultants or something.
Speaker 0: We could do mad panels like a ton.
Speaker 1: I basically want to split panel programming three ways.
Speaker 1: One third anime and comics, you know, including web comics and also manga.
Speaker 1: This is not counting web comic and guest panels.
Speaker 0: That's kind of a separate one gaming video gaming tabletop board game role playing game.
Speaker 1: and one third just cool geeky stuff.
Speaker 1: Like I've got someone lined up who might be able to do a really cool interactive robotics workshop.
Speaker 0: Very nice.
Speaker 1: We've got someone who could probably do some really cool parkour workshops, parkour workshop.
Speaker 0: You can't do that in the con, really?
Speaker 0: Well, you could do it in the ballroom.
Speaker 1: You can do a parkour workshop of demonstration.
Speaker 1: That's center outside of Connecticut with no relation to Connecticut whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's where they hurt themselves.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, I think, you know, we're going to schedule like we should schedule all sorts of like activities like that in the ballroom.
Speaker 0: And then, you know, maybe we could have like, you know, one less panel room.
Speaker 1: that, you know, bigger panel room instead that like belly dancing needs to be in the ballroom where there's stuff for it.
Speaker 1: And there was.
Speaker 0: there were things scheduled in the ballroom like DuckDuckGoose.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: But basically, I don't know why they had that there, but we, yes, we're going to schedule a kendo over there.
Speaker 1: We're going to schedule as much cool stuff as we can over there.
Speaker 1: And I know we can get away with a lot of this because people can already get away with like the Bafa tournament.
Speaker 0: So we, as they can do the Bafa tournament, we can do kendo in the ballroom.
Speaker 1: We're going to sign whatever forms we need to sign to make all this awesome stuff happen.
Speaker 1: And Connecticut is going to be amazing next year.
Speaker 0: That's something that Otacon doesn't do right.
Speaker 0: Otacon is the rave, but basically during the day before the rave happens, like that is basically autograph lineup area.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They could run actual like panels there, like, you know, like any demonstration that requires anything physical, you know, like a belly dancing or a pair of teaching or a kendo or something, something.
Speaker 1: Or they could just do like packs and have the one panel room that's kind of open and just have open panels in there.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's cool.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: We've gone on long enough and we talk mostly about ourselves, but that's all we did at Connecticut.
Speaker 0: If you want a review of Connecticut, I'm sure there might've been someone else there who's going to podcast.
Speaker 1: I basically just from now on other convention reviews will be more like in traditional ones, but from this day forth, Connecticut counter views are going to be us talking about ourselves and about Connecticut and about the backend.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: We're never going to do anything at Connecticut ever again, except run like panels and programming and all that business.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So you had, there, you have it.
Speaker 0: I'm going to go eat some ice cream.
Speaker 1: If you think you have what it takes to be a panelist at Connecticut, cause let me tell you the bar is being raised.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You got, I mean, you know, I can understand, you know, there's some kids out there, you know, they're inspired by us to run some panels.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But listen, you have to be good, right.
Speaker 0: To run a panel, right?
Speaker 0: Like prove if you got to, if we don't know who you are and you don't have a panel resume already, you're going to have to prove to us somehow that you can be here to run a good panel.
Speaker 1: Now point several people have done this in the past.
Speaker 1: So it's not like we're asking too much.
Speaker 1: Just basically be awesome.
Speaker 0: There's a recording of, you know, doing a panel, like just turn your webcam on, record yourself, given the panel, you know, put it on YouTube.
Speaker 0: I don't, I'm not going to watch the whole thing, but I just need to watch like a few minutes.
Speaker 0: I'll be like, aha, this person knows how to present.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: You know, or show me your panel resume.
Speaker 0: Show me, look, I've done panels at my middle of nowhere con.
Speaker 0: Oh, also, uh, speaking of middle of nowhere con, one of our listeners from Kansas was there.
Speaker 0: He came all that way, even though I was like, whoa, dude, why'd you come all this way for a little Connecticut?
Speaker 0: But he looked like he had a good time and he saved my ass with an iPod charging cable.
Speaker 1: So mad, uh, that guy, that guy was pretty cool.
Speaker 0: That guy's awesome.
Speaker 1: Apparently trogdor was there, but he didn't go to, he didn't speak off at Pete's.
Speaker 1: Pete's, uh, metal panel.
Speaker 1: By the way, Pete's metal panel was awesome.
Speaker 1: The only thing it lacked was that Pete does not know how to make a playlist.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: He's a little polished.
Speaker 0: His content is all right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The thing is Pete's metal panel.
Speaker 1: Pete got punked at one point by none other than Luke Crane.
Speaker 1: I want to bring this up.
Speaker 0: You know, Pete's metal.
Speaker 0: Luke Crane is more metal.
Speaker 0: I'm telling you.
Speaker 1: He's pretty fucking metal.
Speaker 0: He's really metal.
Speaker 1: Luke Crane, you know, Pete had this amazing chart that was very like, it was actually, it was actually like, it wasn't just like a joke.
Speaker 0: It was actually legitimate chart that he actually started explaining.
Speaker 0: I was like, really?
Speaker 0: You're serious?
Speaker 0: It's not just like putting up there for a joke.
Speaker 1: It was on the surface a joke, but in reality not.
Speaker 1: But he made the mistake of not considering anthrax when he showed the hip hop influence turning into anthrax turning into shitty nu metal.
Speaker 0: Let's relaunch bastard and do a show on it.
Speaker 1: Oh my God, bastard is like, but Luke Crane raises his hand very politely and points out, I will paraphrase here.
Speaker 1: Pete, fuck you.
Speaker 1: Anthrax is awesome.
Speaker 1: And all Pete could say was, you know what?
Speaker 1: I fucked up.
Speaker 1: You're right.
Speaker 1: Anthrax is awesome.
Speaker 1: He needs like, you know, shitty nu metal in the corner of the slide.
Speaker 1: And then in parentheses, accept anthrax.
Speaker 1: Then we're cool.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So I think we're done with the show.
Speaker 1: We're done.
Speaker 1: We out.
Speaker 1: There may or may not be shows next week.
Speaker 1: We'll tell you why later.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rem and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our crapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays we have video games, board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights and Thursdays are the catch alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an Odeo on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.