Speaker 0: It's Thursday March 19th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm sky, and this is geek nights tonight baseball.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So Remember that that photoshop the Zelda.
Speaker 0: Oh my God.
Speaker 1: Yes That's all but never someone decides of March.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: I don't think about like it to brutal.
Speaker 1: I always think about that Zelda Photoshop.
Speaker 0: but We're around that time that time of betrayal and I think the hail and hardy in Grand central betrayed me.
Speaker 0: I eat their kind off.
Speaker 1: It's a chain, but it makes you know soups.
Speaker 1: It's good for lunch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like soup, and I was hungry, and I wanted some dinner.
Speaker 1: There's one closer to me.
Speaker 0: before I came home There's two chipotals near me.
Speaker 1: I know there's two chipotals.
Speaker 1: I actually have two chipotals near me.
Speaker 0: The thing is the new one they opened up never has a line But everyone goes to Pinche instead because Pinche is like the new hotness Pinche taqueria.
Speaker 0: But I think I was betrayed because I got some jambalaya and I've been Bali since then.
Speaker 1: well Jambalaya from anywhere even the best jambalaya can make you badly.
Speaker 1: It's that kind of.
Speaker 1: it's the spicy kind of greasy food.
Speaker 0: It's not that spicy.
Speaker 0: one spicy greasy food does not make me badly.
Speaker 0: I eat spicy greasy food every day.
Speaker 1: Yeah Speaking of bali nous, right?
Speaker 1: Was it yesterday?
Speaker 1: yesterday right I wanted like a hamburger for lunch right?
Speaker 1: so the Sparky's place.
Speaker 1: remember I took you there once gone right Pinche is in there now, so I can't can't go there, right?
Speaker 0: There's no good burger anywhere near you.
Speaker 1: I could go down to the deli like down on Spring Street, but that place started carrying Randy medicine.
Speaker 1: So I won't go there anymore right?
Speaker 1: so where am I supposed to go?
Speaker 1: so I go to you know?
Speaker 1: Little Google on my phone, and I type in burger all right, and there's five guys a little bit away.
Speaker 1: So I'm like aha five guys is good people.
Speaker 1: people always people are always talking it up big-time like oh It's like the great place to go.
Speaker 1: It's like the best burger short of your backyard, and oh it's even though It's a chain.
Speaker 1: It's like the best chain burger right.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think good burger gives it a run for its money.
Speaker 1: Well anyway the point is is that you know I'm like all right I'll go try this place that everyone keeps talking up so much.
Speaker 0: this end in bowling.
Speaker 1: It doesn't end big bad But it ends in some balliness right.
Speaker 1: so I got I do the five guys a little bit of a walk But you know it's a. it's a walk.
Speaker 1: It's it's an okay walk for a lunch right?
Speaker 1: not.
Speaker 1: It's not anything serious.
Speaker 1: It's like oh my it's like an extra block farther than the deli.
Speaker 1: all right I go over there, and I go in and I'm just like yeah I want like a burger.
Speaker 1: you know lettuce tomato onion and fries.
Speaker 1: right and they got.
Speaker 1: I got some cajun fries.
Speaker 1: They're actually nice and spicy.
Speaker 1: they taste a lot like Arby's curly fries.
Speaker 1: only they were only they were better potato.
Speaker 1: They actually had sacks of like Idaho potatoes there And they're like today's.
Speaker 1: potatoes come from and they named the town in Idaho.
Speaker 1: But then I look at the actual bags that are sitting on the floor there.
Speaker 1: They have a different town in Idaho written on them, huh?
Speaker 1: Who's very strange, but they were real Idaho potatoes and the french fries are but they're no Rasta fries No, they're very potato II and they had some nice little spice like the Arby's curly fries and they're very tasty and they gave me a lot of them.
Speaker 0: and So you remember those Rasta fries right and everything on the menu?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, they're great and everything on the menu is trans fat free, so I was like ah very good french fry.
Speaker 1: Okay, right.
Speaker 1: They also have a buckets of peanuts.
Speaker 1: You can just shovel them and eat as many as you want.
Speaker 1: I did not eat any right, so I took it back.
Speaker 1: You know I got the burger which is wrapped up so I didn't see it until I brought it back to the office and opened it up and It was a double burger.
Speaker 1: Oh, man Apparently I was wondering why it cost $10 for a burger and fries.
Speaker 1: The default at five guys is a double burger.
Speaker 1: I was not aware of this.
Speaker 1: I'm usually you know I don't I don't eat.
Speaker 1: You know I understand why some people go all man two meats Yes, and I can respect that but personally one meat is enough for me.
Speaker 0: Well that is you know you don't move around a lot.
Speaker 0: So if you eat two meats that extra meats really just.
Speaker 1: well the thing is it's like I can eat.
Speaker 1: You know two single hamburgers right, but then I'm also eating two buns two lettuces two tomatoes Right and two onion, but if I get one burger one.
Speaker 1: But you know one bun one lettuce one tomato one onion with two meats That's you know a lot of meats and it they had all the calories on the menu, too.
Speaker 1: I think it was like six hundred and seven hundred calories or something like that.
Speaker 1: right and that didn't count the fries.
Speaker 1: But anyway.
Speaker 1: So I'm like oh whatever you know the burger.
Speaker 1: You know the patties though were not big fat patties like we have in our backyard.
Speaker 1: right they were sort of.
Speaker 1: they were thinner And you know they was okay wasn't like the bay wasn't like.
Speaker 1: you know fud records of the backyard But you know I could see why people approve of it so much.
Speaker 1: It was you know it was not some nasty McDonald's burger That's for sure.
Speaker 1: So yeah, it was real meat.
Speaker 0: ate the whole thing.
Speaker 1: I ate it of course.
Speaker 1: yes I ate all the fries and they had actual Heinz ketchup packets.
Speaker 1: It was very nice.
Speaker 1: and Then of course I was a little bit Bali for a little while there.
Speaker 1: Next time I go back.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna order.
Speaker 1: I looked at the menu.
Speaker 1: They have a little burger which I assume he called little but really it just means normal one patty burger And it was like five bucks instead of ten bucks, so I think that is what I'll be ordering the next time.
Speaker 1: I'm over there.
Speaker 1: I Was because they didn't let me.
Speaker 1: they didn't.
Speaker 1: I didn't know it was a double to order a normal hamburger.
Speaker 1: It didn't say double it.
Speaker 1: Just said hamburger, and then there was little hamburger.
Speaker 1: I thought little hamburger was White Castle, but you didn't think hamburger ten bucks meant well No, because it's Manhattan.
Speaker 1: That's you know.
Speaker 0: yeah, but still for 13.
Speaker 0: I get like a burger and fries and a root beer float.
Speaker 1: That's about right.
Speaker 1: Yeah See if I was nearer to like say the Shake Shack I would get that but I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe the head shakes there I didn't I didn't look.
Speaker 0: I Couldn't have stomach to one anyway, so it didn't matter, but if a burger joint doesn't have shakes It is not truly a burger joint.
Speaker 0: It's a real imitation.
Speaker 1: I'm sure they have them.
Speaker 1: I just I didn't even check but I Will probably return there again when I'm in need of a burger, but I will not get the double.
Speaker 0: But we do have.
Speaker 0: you know it's Thursday, but in lieu of news We've got a kind of a big announcement here for geek nights.
Speaker 1: Yes Well, this is sort of a. this is sort of a little announcement here right.
Speaker 1: so on April 1st, which is Wednesday Something it's a couple Wednesdays for now.
Speaker 1: so not next Wednesday But the Wednesday after that.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: so you got one weekend two weekends and then that Wednesday April 1st.
Speaker 1: right we are going to do a Geek nights live show.
Speaker 1: basically what we're gonna Do is we're gonna record the show as usual But we are going to turn on the u-stream on a laptop or whatever and we'll pipe the audio into u-stream And maybe we'll turn on cameras so you can look at us.
Speaker 1: But where you're not gonna really see much on the cameras except our they see me like hunched over My microphone and you'll see me sitting here with my eyes closed with a microphone on my face.
Speaker 1: You know you know we're not gonna show you anything great.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: it just will turn them on.
Speaker 1: because if we're using u-stream to stream the audio live and we have webcams Why not turn them on?
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: it doesn't hurt right?
Speaker 1: you know the bandwidth doesn't interfere with our local recording.
Speaker 1: I mean if the internet went out we could actually in.
Speaker 1: the electricity was on.
Speaker 1: we can still record geek nights.
Speaker 1: You just couldn't upload it, so we're gonna do that, but we're also going to make it.
Speaker 1: You know what's the reason of doing it live?
Speaker 1: it's going to be a question e-show and ask Grim and Scott show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty much.
Speaker 0: You'll be able to tweet or chat.
Speaker 1: They'll be Twitter account for geek nights.
Speaker 1: I also made a suffice to say account for geek nights.
Speaker 1: There it.
Speaker 1: the name is geek nights right and we also the u-stream has a chat room built into it.
Speaker 1: So you know follow the Twitter pay attention that will post it on the website and the forum.
Speaker 1: We're basically gonna.
Speaker 1: you know I'm not sure exactly what time it will be.
Speaker 1: on the April 1st It might be you know anywhere between like 7 and you know 9 or who knows when?
Speaker 1: But we'll.
Speaker 1: you know we'll.
Speaker 1: maybe we'll figure out a time a little bit in advance right we'll post it everywhere We can.
Speaker 1: you'll be able to ask questions through any of those you know.
Speaker 1: venues will answer whatever questions We feel like and that is going to be the that show that day.
Speaker 1: So you know I'm gonna try to remember to remind everyone on every show we do until then.
Speaker 1: so you know we can get the most participation Possible.
Speaker 0: now of course if you don't want to be there live, and you don't have any questions for us We're gonna just air it as a geek nights episode in the feed later.
Speaker 1: Yeah like the same day probably.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: we'll see.
Speaker 0: it is a Wednesday.
Speaker 0: We'll do it.
Speaker 0: It'll be some time at night where we'll have more details as time comes on.
Speaker 1: yeah, but that's that's the day.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do it, so Yeah, be there.
Speaker 1: pay attention such and such.
Speaker 0: it's time for nothing lasts forever.
Speaker 1: No some things last forever.
Speaker 0: well well You know it didn't last forever is when the Port Authority took over, New York City.
Speaker 1: You see the Port Authority already has taken over, New York City.
Speaker 0: well as in the instituted martial law I mean, it's the Port Authority.
Speaker 0: you figure they have some sort of authority over the but anyway.
Speaker 1: So any weapons?
Speaker 0: well, this is where things change when Dan Aykroyd is handled like the bridges in the airports.
Speaker 0: So no one can get in or out of Manhattan without the Port Authority knowing about it anyway.
Speaker 1: That's true because it's an island a Long time ago.
Speaker 0: There is a movie that was made.
Speaker 0: it was a Schiller film called nothing lasts forever.
Speaker 0: It was never released, but it was pretty much cast with nothing, but big-name stars.
Speaker 0: it was one of those.
Speaker 0: every famous person cameoed in it and Schiller was the guy who did all those like SNL videos and The movie had some copyright concerns and one thing led to another and as often happens in the movie industry The movie was never released in any form.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean you know this movie.
Speaker 1: there was also people I don't know how many people know about this.
Speaker 1: there was actually a Fantastic four movie.
Speaker 1: I think in the maybe the early 90s.
Speaker 1: I forget the year it was I've seen it.
Speaker 1: It's really terrible, but it was never put in theaters or on VHS.
Speaker 1: You know for good reason, but it was completely finished.
Speaker 1: You know they filmed it.
Speaker 1: They edited the whole thing.
Speaker 1: It was done.
Speaker 1: They had a movie and you can get it on the internet in some places.
Speaker 1: And you know those are two movies I know of that were finished completed made done, but never put in theaters or video or anything.
Speaker 1: and You know.
Speaker 1: I wonder how many others there are that we don't know about.
Speaker 0: isn't there that Jerry Lewis Holocaust comedy, I don't know what that is.
Speaker 0: There's some sort of comedy I think someone mentioned in the forums that Jerry Lewis made.
Speaker 0: that ends sadly But was in the Holocaust and it was about a clown and apparently it was horrifyingly a reference.
Speaker 1: Something might be incredibly distasteful right I could see that.
Speaker 1: why that might be a reason to you know not put it in theaters Not advertise it right, but it's no reason to you know not make it available through some you know channel But nothing lasts forever anyway Is it is a special case in that?
Speaker 0: Schiller really wanted it to get out there and Bill Murray and Dan Aykroyd and all the people in it Wanted to be out there.
Speaker 0: in fact as far as I can tell almost everyone and almost everyone involved in the production.
Speaker 0: there are a couple of notable exceptions, but Don't they?
Speaker 0: we wanted to be out there?
Speaker 0: They have no.
Speaker 1: so basically everyone.
Speaker 1: so unlike say the Fantastic Four movie where the people in it Probably didn't want anyone to see it anyway because it was terrible.
Speaker 1: This is a movie where the people in it were like oh my god We love this movie that we made let's make we want people to see it, but there were copyright concerns.
Speaker 0: The movie was never released.
Speaker 0: It's hardly ever even been screened.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: there have been an incredibly small number of screenings of this and all of them They're only screened because the director himself is there showing it.
Speaker 0: and yeah special permission I think you know.
Speaker 1: you saw the showing at the Eastman Theatre right in Rochester.
Speaker 1: someone else I think said they saw it at The first like Santa Barbara Film Festival.
Speaker 1: someone else saw it.
Speaker 1: I think it was on cable television somewhere once like in the 80s.
Speaker 1: There are people that taped it.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell that that showing in the 80s I think it was someone on public access who somehow had a copy just putting it out.
Speaker 1: Oh you think that's what it was.
Speaker 0: That's my guess.
Speaker 1: I heard something about like Australia - maybe it's all sort of rumors cuz this is all 80s We're talking about here, so you know information like this from the 80s That got onto the internet is sort of you know not so reliable But the whole story was that.
Speaker 0: you know I saw this film with Emily and Alex and Emily's parents in Rochester Kind of out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: You saw the actual film.
Speaker 0: we saw the film a real screening of it And then we got a Q&A with Schiller himself, and he explained like yeah, this movie is never gonna come out.
Speaker 0: I wish he could.
Speaker 0: I think it's amazing and It's pretty amazing.
Speaker 0: Put it that way, but I had a thing of the day last week.
Speaker 0: I found what I thought was a trailer for it, and it had footage from the movie.
Speaker 0: So I was like oh someone leaked the trailer great thing of the day.
Speaker 0: And then I was gonna use it as the thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Just you know hey check this out.
Speaker 0: This is that movie.
Speaker 0: I talked about way back on the show.
Speaker 0: That's crazy.
Speaker 0: here You can get an idea of how crazy it was.
Speaker 0: and then as we're about to do the show I noticed that you I'm thinking you know how did this trailer get leaked.
Speaker 0: so I go to the users page and I see the guy basically said So uh I Liked this movie, and I realized there was no trailer, so I made one to which I responded wait a minute.
Speaker 0: How did you make one?
Speaker 0: that means you have the stupid film?
Speaker 0: Why is it not on the internet?
Speaker 0: So we go to the Pirate Bay and sure enough There's a torrent.
Speaker 1: yes some guy tapes it off cable apparently on to a VHS and then put the VHS on the internet.
Speaker 1: So when you saw the movie was it what?
Speaker 1: was the aspect ratio?
Speaker 1: was a widescreen or was it?
Speaker 0: Believe it was widescreen was it?
Speaker 1: so I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe this VHS is missing.
Speaker 1: You know half the movie it.
Speaker 0: You know it wouldn't matter.
Speaker 1: Oh really this movie It's not that kind of movie.
Speaker 0: this movie is something special anyway.
Speaker 0: So because we haven't even watched this yet, but it seems like it is the actual movie.
Speaker 0: so get on this torrent.
Speaker 1: I mean you know you might be talking about right copyright infringement Whatever.
Speaker 1: not what you know you have some maybe you're the kind of person is really really you know against infringing on copyright or whatever.
Speaker 1: seriously is the movie where everyone who made it wants it to be out and You know wants you to watch it and the copyright is preventing it from being out.
Speaker 1: if there was never a better justification for using bit torrents to illegally download something than this.
Speaker 0: so get the word out get everyone on this torrent and The movie is pretty good.
Speaker 0: I'd really like to hear what you people have to think about this because this
Speaker 1: It's not the kind of movie that everyone in the world will like but it I have a feeling it is there a lot of People who it just will appreciate it
Speaker 0: for the longest time.
Speaker 0: It was like this the ultimate inside joke with me and Emily and Alex we could make we could make references to it And we know for a fact that no one we run into will have seen this movie or know what we're talking about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty amazing.
Speaker 1: It's like you know.
Speaker 1: I mean if you come up with something on your own And you know no one you run into will know about it right.
Speaker 0: the fact that it is a first your film exact motion picture a full one a complete one that was screened in some theaters that has Bill Murray and Dan Aykroyd and like 15 other like I like.
Speaker 1: imagine imagine if I don't know Ghostbusters Right.
Speaker 1: it was only ever screened like three times And maybe it was on cable once and like only maybe 50 people in the world that actually seen it And you were the one who had seen it.
Speaker 1: And you're like you come down the street And you're like.
Speaker 1: if someone asked if you're a god you say yes, and no one knows you're talking about Nobody except you and your friend who are at that incredibly rare screening.
Speaker 0: I think a better example is Ghostbusters 2 because Ghostbusters 1 is one of the greatest movies ever know.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying imagine if only so few people had seen it.
Speaker 0: But at the same time I think Ghostbusters 2 is a better analogy because this movie is not that good.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're talking about the quality hit algae.
Speaker 1: Yes in terms of I wasn't comparing the quality.
Speaker 1: I was come.
Speaker 1: I was just making an analogy.
Speaker 0: It's like what if you were the only person in the world who'd ever seen Star Wars.
Speaker 1: well No, I was making the analogy for you know the inside joke not for the quality of the.
Speaker 0: It'd be like having it anyway this movie.
Speaker 0: Good.
Speaker 0: God good.
Speaker 1: God All right, so um you know thanks to the Internet's and whatnot right?
Speaker 1: One of the things I love to find on the internet are like new inventions right that are actually Resolving sort of like everyday Problems right and a lot of times this sort of thing is usually like an as-seen-on-tv And it's some piece of crap bullshit, right?
Speaker 1: But once in a once in a while you come across like some new invention that actually is Something that will help.
Speaker 1: you know not some like funky spoon.
Speaker 1: That's no better than a regular spoon or some funky knife.
Speaker 1: There's no better than regular knife, right?
Speaker 1: This here is this actually this whole website mo q7.
Speaker 1: I think it might be called mock seven.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Oh, no my mo Q stands for minimum order quantity.
Speaker 1: right and the way this site works is You know they have.
Speaker 1: Basically they get next like sort of like next generation awesome stuff right like new inventions and things and They put them up for sale but Until they meet the minimum order quantity no one actually gets anything right.
Speaker 1: it's like let's say you invent like a new kind of hairbrush or something right.
Speaker 1: you put it up on this site and You say all right?
Speaker 1: I'm selling them for five bucks and minimum order quantity is 10,000. so as soon as you get 10,000 orders Then you'd manufacture and sell and if you never get the orders before time runs out then everyone just gets their money back, right?
Speaker 1: So on this website, they're selling something here that actually I think I'm gonna buy a whole bunch of maybe like five of them, right?
Speaker 1: Mostly because they cost a dollar and 18 cents each.
Speaker 1: What this is is the brush and rinse toothbrush.
Speaker 1: now You know I've always used the oral B toothbrush, which I like very much all right.
Speaker 1: It's very trustworthy dentist approved, but You know sometimes you're brushing your teeth right and there's no cup available.
Speaker 0: now I just reached down and put the Faucet and that's on the faucet.
Speaker 0: you Phil Steen?
Speaker 1: no no you couldn't.
Speaker 1: you know you can put your head under the faucet right.
Speaker 1: you can also do the Water hand in the cupped hands.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know I've never done that without making a mess.
Speaker 1: It does doesn't work.
Speaker 1: I can't do it right cuz my hands are not cupped.
Speaker 1: very well The thing is right even head under the faucet.
Speaker 1: that works.
Speaker 1: Okay, and like a kitchen sink right, but if you got a big head a little sink It's really not the.
Speaker 1: it's not the best situation.
Speaker 1: It's not comfortable.
Speaker 1: It's not easy.
Speaker 1: It's not as it's not as luxurious as having a cup there right, but even if you do have a cup right That means that you're gonna have to wash this cup and the cup sits in the bathroom and takes some space in the bathroom Counter and if you travel you got to bring the cup with you, right?
Speaker 0: Well if you're traveling you can use the cup in the hotel.
Speaker 1: well But you can't trust those hotel cups remember.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, yeah, they clean them with Windex.
Speaker 0: There's a hint.
Speaker 1: never use a cup in a hotel You know do use a cup in a hotel if it's plastic and it's wrapped in plastic.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: don't use the glass cups in the hotel unless you bring your own sponges and dish detergent washing yourself Right which is a lot more difficult than just bringing your own cup Right.
Speaker 1: so this toothbrush is the brush and rinse toothbrush.
Speaker 1: There's a video showing you how it works.
Speaker 1: basically This toothbrush has spouts built into it, right?
Speaker 1: So what you do is you put one part of the toothbrush under the faucet and the other part of the toothbrush will have water Spraying out of it.
Speaker 1: Just like a water fountain.
Speaker 1: So you brush your teeth then you put your toothbrush under the sink and water comes out and you rinse your mouth out with no Cup needed.
Speaker 0: gotta check out the video.
Speaker 0: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: and look a dollar 18.
Speaker 1: I mean toothbrushes at the store are more than that Right.
Speaker 1: the oral bees and the reaches and the Colgate's or whatever toothbrushes are more than a dollar 18 even when they're on sale All right.
Speaker 1: I mean, maybe you get a free one at the dentist.
Speaker 1: That's that's a better deal Right, but that always has your dentist name on it, right?
Speaker 1: It's always sorta Dollar 18 for like, you know, even if you're not using this your everyday toothbrush It's the ultimate travel toothbrush because now you can travel that much lighter, right?
Speaker 1: So I'm definitely gonna order like five of them.
Speaker 1: I suggest if you brush your teeth and you're not some disgusting person That's your teeth.
Speaker 1: brush your teeth, but your goddamn teeth Right that you also order a few.
Speaker 1: because right now the minimum order They've sold 12,000 about and the minimum order is 50,000.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna need.
Speaker 1: we're gonna need some help if we want these.
Speaker 0: so I'm pretty much.
Speaker 0: I plan to get some just for travel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think they're cool.
Speaker 1: It's good.
Speaker 1: Plus it's a cool novelty just to show people you're like, ooh, all right.
Speaker 1: so so I guess we do the baseball show like baseball.
Speaker 1: I Love that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we had a little trouble coming up with to do a show on right but the baseball season is approaching.
Speaker 1: it's Thursday.
Speaker 1: We have not done a show on baseball.
Speaker 1: We also have not done a show with very much Disagreement in a long time.
Speaker 1: So I thought this might be a pretty good show idea considering I like baseball quite a bit.
Speaker 1: It's not my favorite thing in the world and I'm indifferent to baseball.
Speaker 1: I thought you were very much hated baseball.
Speaker 0: You know, it's hard to hate it because I don't like particular.
Speaker 0: I don't like watching baseball on TV because I feel like there's no point.
Speaker 0: It's not interesting to watch and I don't mind watching it in person because I like hanging out at the stadium with people.
Speaker 0: It's a fun day.
Speaker 0: I love playing baseball.
Speaker 0: I absolutely love playing baseball Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think that you're not gonna get some sort of diatribe of baseball's not stupidest sport ever.
Speaker 0: I reserve that for curling.
Speaker 1: Oh But that way do I agree?
Speaker 1: The curling is also the stupidest sport ever.
Speaker 1: It doesn't help.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, it's not the stupidest It's just it's pretty damn well.
Speaker 1: I think the reason that a lot of people are down on baseball spectating right and is that it's The enjoyment of you know, watching a sport like say hockey or You know football right is is in the action of it, right?
Speaker 1: There's lots of action, you know almost constantly You know, I guess more so in hockey than football right because football stops right.
Speaker 1: the action is you know hard-hitting Exciting action and there's lots and lots of like feats of strength going on.
Speaker 1: You know, that's as very exciting right, but baseball really doesn't entertain You know those same things.
Speaker 1: I mean sure there's occasional feats of strength in baseball.
Speaker 1: I mean really everything is the feat of strength in baseball, but you don't really realize it.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: you know, it's very rare that there's a feat of strength that actually looks like a feat of strength.
Speaker 1: I mean like you think about it like every pitch right dude throws the ball 90 miles an hour Like how many times but you don't go?
Speaker 1: Wow, every time you only go.
Speaker 1: wow when it's like, you know some crazy outfield like dive or something, you know.
Speaker 1: But You know baseball is really less about the action and more about the suspense and the situations, you know.
Speaker 1: So it's almost.
Speaker 1: you know, if sports were movies, it's like baseball is like a different genre He's in the pickle.
Speaker 0: It's a pickle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 1: and then the other thing.
Speaker 1: Well, there are situations in baseball besides, you know, there's two kinds of situations we're talking about here.
Speaker 1: Right one kind of situation is you know the pickle or the the stealing home plate, right?
Speaker 1: Those are very rare at least in Major League Baseball in the United States because everyone's a professional.
Speaker 1: So they're not.
Speaker 1: they're so good at playing that they never get into a stupid situation like that, right?
Speaker 1: And that's actually a problem in sort of all professional sports.
Speaker 1: Is that the players are so good that stupid shit doesn't happen.
Speaker 1: That's why people like, you know college hockey college basketball college football, you know so much is because You watch like professional football.
Speaker 1: You're never gonna see like a Statue of Liberty play.
Speaker 1: I don't think they're allowed, right?
Speaker 1: You know, you're never gonna see anyone run the option in the NFL ever or the trick play.
Speaker 0: This isn't the right ball.
Speaker 1: This isn't the right ball right in college football.
Speaker 1: That shit totally works because there's a lot of people on the field that are probably not gonna play football for the rest of their Lives as professionals, you know, they're not that good and they'll fall for that shit You get actually works in the NFL.
Speaker 1: It's never gonna work ever.
Speaker 1: It's you're just gonna.
Speaker 1: you're just gonna get you know, get hit you're gonna fall over.
Speaker 1: This can be a big sack huge me.
Speaker 0: You turn it over quarterback gets up like this is the right ball and they kill him Right.
Speaker 1: It's the same thing in baseball right, you know?
Speaker 1: in like Little League Baseball, right?
Speaker 1: If you get a if someone walks you right you can run to first and just keep running to second.
Speaker 1: That's a legal play in Major League Baseball.
Speaker 1: But notice in the major leagues no one runs to first.
Speaker 1: when they get a walk they walk casually.
Speaker 1: Number one because you don't want to risk injury when you're that valuable and two it's not gonna work.
Speaker 1: That play never works.
Speaker 1: No one even tries it even though it's totally allowed.
Speaker 1: But yeah The other thing the situations in Major League Baseball that I think make it entertaining are sort of like these suspense situations.
Speaker 1: Right, like, you know, it's you know, you it's the.
Speaker 1: it's the end of the inning, right?
Speaker 1: You you know, you're you.
Speaker 1: you got two outs this guy's on base.
Speaker 1: You're either gonna you know get out or you're gonna get a bunch of runs, right?
Speaker 1: It's gonna go one way or the other.
Speaker 1: so it's sort of like a burning wheel situation, right?
Speaker 1: either you're gonna get all the successes and something crazy awesome is gonna happen or You did all that work getting all those.
Speaker 1: all those previous hits are for nothing cuz you got those guys on base But they're not gonna score any runs cuz you totally fucked it up.
Speaker 1: and then you know You're in that situation already, right.
Speaker 1: and then you start getting strike ball ball Another strike and it's like you're already in a tense situation where it's like it's either make it or break it right here.
Speaker 1: And then you sort of once you get to that point you start to inch closer and closer to where you know That's it.
Speaker 1: This next pitch is it no matter what unless he fouls it off, you know, that's is.
Speaker 1: it is no Right.
Speaker 1: and you get closer and closer to like, you know the the complete edge Before something actually happens and that you know.
Speaker 1: suspense of waiting is you know can really?
Speaker 1: Provide quite a bit of thrilling entertainment, but I think it only works if you actually care.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see that's the trouble.
Speaker 0: baseball is the only sport I've ever seen in person where I will occasionally not notice that play is resumed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean if you don't be sitting there and I hear crack and I look I was like, oh right baseball.
Speaker 1: Well, see if you're watching an action sport, right?
Speaker 1: You don't have to care who wins or loses to get the entertainment because you're watching a lot of things happen a lot They're very quick and they're very entertaining.
Speaker 1: this movement and things happening in Baseball, you know all the entertainment is in the suspense.
Speaker 1: and while it might be a suspenseful situation and you might recognize that suspenseful situation right Suspense doesn't work unless you care about the result even in like a movie right you're watching a movie, right?
Speaker 1: Let's say the suspenseful situation this guy.
Speaker 1: He's not gonna save the day or he's gonna die within like the next, you know minute He's you know, he's gonna spring a trap.
Speaker 1: What's he gonna do?
Speaker 1: He's walking down the scary hallway.
Speaker 1: It's all dark.
Speaker 1: Ooh, right If you don't care if the guy lives or dies, there's no suspense.
Speaker 1: There's just you know.
Speaker 1: You have to actually care about what is going to happen in order to have the feeling of suspense Overcome you and I think that's the thing with baseball is that if you don't care which team is gonna win Then there's no suspense because you don't care if it's gonna be an out or a hit.
Speaker 1: It's it's could go either way.
Speaker 1: It doesn't make a difference to you.
Speaker 1: So there is no suspense.
Speaker 1: You're just you know, you're just waiting for it to be over and it's gonna be over either way.
Speaker 1: So I Don't know.
Speaker 1: I think that might be why you're indifferent to baseball.
Speaker 1: I think maybe if you you know had a team that you cared about a whole bunch like maybe if RIT's big thing was Baseball instead of hockey see even that.
Speaker 0: no cuz I mean I grew up watching the Tigers and you know, that's why explains a lot.
Speaker 0: No, I don't think that is because I'm also a Lions fan.
Speaker 1: Explains a lot.
Speaker 0: But how come I'm such a fan of the Lions and yet I couldn't care less about this?
Speaker 1: because the Lions have a culture of Losing but the Tigers don't really have so much of a culture.
Speaker 0: really they had a culture of losing for a while when I was A kid and should have been a White Sox fan.
Speaker 0: Nah lived in Detroit.
Speaker 0: Yeah So why would I have been a fan of the White Sox Chicago's close enough?
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: Chicago has much better teams than Detroit.
Speaker 1: All
Speaker 0: right, let's see I remember a distinct point not that long ago when I could say that Detroit had the number one team in every major sport because the Red Wings were number one and the Pistons were number one and
Speaker 1: The Pistons went downhill this season big day
Speaker 0: and the Tigers were number one and football hadn't started yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was my joke.
Speaker 0: I made that for about four months.
Speaker 0: yeah but baseball just There's not like a lot of the drama and the up-close stuff like I guess use that I don't care about the teams or the Sports or like any of the stuff outside of the game itself.
Speaker 0: So the game itself comes down to one guy doing this feat of strength over and over again against these other people who are doing This other feat of strength and dexterity over and over again and the people in the outfield be either play perfectly or completely fuck up.
Speaker 0: There's no middle ground when they bump into each other.
Speaker 0: Either like the game people play perfectly and it comes down to such tiny Margins of victory kind of like watching an f1 race.
Speaker 0: It becomes less and less interest.
Speaker 1: Well, you can watch like some minor league baseball, right?
Speaker 1: And then you know, the margin is way bigger because the players are not nearly as good.
Speaker 0: I actually enjoy minor league baseball a lot more than major league.
Speaker 1: The funny thing is is that minor league baseball stadium?
Speaker 1: We could literally walk to it from our house and like 20 minutes and we've never gone there.
Speaker 0: We haven't we should.
Speaker 1: I've always planned to go there.
Speaker 1: We just never happens.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, we'll have a chance real soon.
Speaker 1: I'll get the schedule.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll figure out get the crew out for the burning wheel weekend and we'll go to a baseball game.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: if that happens a lot of people won't want to go.
Speaker 0: I'll make it happen.
Speaker 0: All right, I'll go though There's two options.
Speaker 0: They can either come to the baseball game or stay home and play.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: No, great.
Speaker 0: Though I think something needs to be said about playing baseball because play baseball is a sport that Pretty much anyone in reasonable physical shape can play.
Speaker 0: You don't need to be an athlete.
Speaker 0: You can play baseball and have fun.
Speaker 0: Mmm, and I wish I played more baseball because in high school, I played baseball all the time like every summer every Sunday We'd all get together and we used to play softball But it got to the point where everyone hit the softball over the fence every time.
Speaker 0: so then we started playing baseball instead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then we had strikes.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's a problem because no one really could pitch the softball.
Speaker 0: very well none of us were good at baseball.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean, you know, that's that's the thing is that you know.
Speaker 1: You watch people play baseball like profession even minor league baseball, right?
Speaker 1: And you watch a guy like, you know There'll be a ground ball to show to the shortstop.
Speaker 1: The shortstop will throw it to first base and get the guy out every single time and it looks like nothing right?
Speaker 1: Try to do that.
Speaker 1: It's not it's not easy.
Speaker 1: You'll throw it like you'll miss the first base will go over his head and go off to the side.
Speaker 1: You won't throw it hard enough.
Speaker 1: It won't make it there, you know, maybe you'll throw it too hard into the stands.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's very, you know, you everything that these players do.
Speaker 1: that looks so casual and makes the game seem kind of boring.
Speaker 1: If you actually try to do it like every little just the normal things that they do over and over again are actually really difficult.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know think about it, you know in Little League, you know You have to worry about things like I was in Little League.
Speaker 1: I had to worry about things if I was in the outfield like which base do I throw it to?
Speaker 1: Major League players never don't know what base to throw it to.
Speaker 1: they throw it to the correct base immediately every time.
Speaker 1: It's not so easy.
Speaker 0: Of course in baseball simulator.
Speaker 0: I haven't throw it to the wrong base.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that happens well because But then again in baseball simulator, it's made up for the fact that I set myself on fire Before I throw the pitch.
Speaker 0: the missile was the best one.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I like the one that went back and forth Or how about the one that just reversed the controls on the outfielders.
Speaker 0: Basically just get a home run.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll be.
Speaker 0: I every time I don't.
Speaker 1: I seem to remember like eventually mastering controlling The outfielders in reverse, you know what I did.
Speaker 0: I always just flip my controller upside down and went.
Speaker 0: oh It was easier to deal with that mirroring than with the full mirroring.
Speaker 1: It's not bad.
Speaker 0: My brother accused me of cheating and then we didn't play baseball simulator together for a while.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's weird.
Speaker 1: the baseball actually makes a really good video game more so than most other sports.
Speaker 0: No football can have a really good video game - yeah It's just.
Speaker 1: I just wish that you know Madden didn't have the exclusive license and now we probably see some other football I'd love to see.
Speaker 0: well, maybe we'll get.
Speaker 0: we got to get some sort of blood ball back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, there's a new blood ball game coming out.
Speaker 1: I'm sort of you know, they've said some things about it.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of interested.
Speaker 1: I'm looking forward to it.
Speaker 1: At least I hope it'll be good.
Speaker 1: But if it's not good, I just won't buy it.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there'll be a demo.
Speaker 0: but seriously like when we were to play baseball in high school and every Sunday and we had like The core group of like 15 people who would always show up But every time like random people would show up.
Speaker 0: and a lot of these people were not athletes.
Speaker 0: many of them were in my Dungeons & Dragons game in high school and Even the like the nerd like the people who were the least physically able Occasionally hit a good one or caught something in the outfield.
Speaker 0: like everyone can play baseball as long even if you don't have legs.
Speaker 0: I've seen people in wheelchairs play baseball.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you could totally play baseball in a wheelchair.
Speaker 0: No, if you don't have arms or legs, you might have trouble but otherwise you can play baseball.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, you mean you can play baseball with just legs.
Speaker 0: You know, well, I guess you could bunt.
Speaker 1: Well, no You just did.
Speaker 1: you just attach.
Speaker 1: so, you know You could definitely play in the field if you just attach a glove to.
Speaker 0: you also have to bet you can't.
Speaker 0: you don't have that Many pinch hitters.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm sure with technology and prosthetics.
Speaker 1: There is definitely a way.
Speaker 0: just That leads to the cyborg league.
Speaker 1: cyborg league is awesome.
Speaker 0: What was that game like robot baseball on the NES?
Speaker 1: was the robot?
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's kind.
Speaker 1: there was.
Speaker 1: you're right.
Speaker 1: What was it called a Super Nintendo the head robot?
Speaker 1: I think it was Super Nintendo.
Speaker 0: I think it was also on the regular Nintendo.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't remember on the regular.
Speaker 1: I think I remember on the super.
Speaker 1: I remember regular because they're very similar designs to the bots master who had sports playing robots at his.
Speaker 0: yes, that is true.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the one other thing about baseball that it has that some of the other sports don't have is that it is very old.
Speaker 1: Right compared to say, you know football.
Speaker 1: I mean look it was just Super Bowl.
Speaker 1: what like 42 last, you know.
Speaker 1: 43 I think right.
Speaker 1: Well roboting has a long and Right, so really baseball is wicked ancient.
Speaker 1: I mean it was played in the late 1800s.
Speaker 0: That's not that ancient though.
Speaker 0: Just know most older sports.
Speaker 0: We don't play anymore.
Speaker 1: I know that's what I'm saying is baseball is like the oldest sport that's still around even though it's not exact.
Speaker 1: hi lie Hi lies pretty old.
Speaker 0: You're right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's that's right.
Speaker 1: Yeah Sumo sumo is pretty old.
Speaker 0: Yeah Wrestling record roman wrestling.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but by any sort of fighting in general is very old.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess I guess the only sport, you know, there's also all the Olympic sports from.
Speaker 1: you know The original Olympics like Greece, you know running is still.
Speaker 1: you know It's kind of old.
Speaker 1: but but if you look at like the major sports right at least in you know in the world right.
Speaker 1: soccer Car racing is very new.
Speaker 0: soccer is very old too.
Speaker 1: I don't know soccer older than baseball.
Speaker 0: I think soccer is older than baseball.
Speaker 1: You think so?
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure To look that one up.
Speaker 0: you keep talking.
Speaker 0: I'll Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: All right, but at least football Basketball even ice hockey are all newer than baseball right and in America, at least they've done a really good job Sort of creating this really sort of historic feel to baseball.
Speaker 1: It's like when you go to see a basketball game unless you go to Boston It doesn't feel historic, you know, if you go to see a football game It doesn't feel like historic.
Speaker 1: unless you go to Pittsburgh see.
Speaker 0: but a hockey game would have felt historic if you sat in the Coliseum In Detroit.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah a hockey game.
Speaker 1: if you go to one of the original six, it feels historic Right, but if you go anywhere else not so much.
Speaker 1: but baseball.
Speaker 1: even if you go to like one of the expansion teams You know Like one of the really new teams like I like the Colorado Rockies or even like the Tampa Bay Rays or something like that
Speaker 0: Because
Speaker 1: the sport is so old you still get that really old Sort of you know apple pie kind of feeling when you go to a baseball game or watch it even on TV.
Speaker 0: It's got the football medieval Europe.
Speaker 1: Wait, you know American football or soccer soccer?
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Yes, you know, okay So so so soccer is older than baseball, but soccer is not so popular in the United States However, it's popular everywhere else in the world.
Speaker 1: And also I don't get a feeling of oldness when I go to when I watch soccer either But that might just be the way it's sold.
Speaker 0: it is always amazing to me though that you that the US like the economy and the population and the size of it is such that The United States has several entire sports that are big enough Inside the country to have as many teams in there as the rest of the world has in most other sports.
Speaker 1: Well, I think the reason for that is just geography, you know, we have such a wide geography that you can have, you know New York versus, you know, California.
Speaker 0: So how come we don't have Vladivostok versus st.
Speaker 0: Petersburg?
Speaker 1: Well, you can't.
Speaker 1: you could have that in Russia But the thing is most of Russia is Siberia?
Speaker 1: right if you look at the only the inhabited parts.
Speaker 0: It's not really Okay, so there's a picture in this Wikipedia article I thought you were gonna do.
Speaker 0: I thought you were gonna argue with me against the point I made about Siberia of Richard Linden 1880 who is believed to have invented the first real soccer ball Mm-hmm, and he's holding the two rubber balls and there's just something kind of hilarious about this picture.
Speaker 0: his fate I don't know.
Speaker 0: He looks disturbed.
Speaker 1: What's the Wikipedia page?
Speaker 0: Football football, okay football.
Speaker 0: But Scott you can see this picture.
Speaker 0: This picture is epic.
Speaker 1: I'm waiting.
Speaker 1: I'm just loading.
Speaker 1: I'm seeing a picture of Scroll down like I'm scrolling Richard Linden.
Speaker 0: He I don't know if he's excited or disturbed or what but I think he's just like hey check out my balls But he's got one eyebrow up and one.
Speaker 0: maybe he had a stroke.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I really like that picture of the Calcio Fiorentino field.
Speaker 0: He's got kind of a skull face to 1688.
Speaker 1: Wow, that's pretty.
Speaker 0: not as not as much of a skull face as Grand Moff Tarkin, but a skull face nonetheless.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I think just you know the aesthetic of baseball.
Speaker 1: It's like when you go to a baseball game.
Speaker 1: It feels like you're also going to even if it's a brand new stadium.
Speaker 1: It sort of feels like museum.
Speaker 1: ish You know, it's like you're not just watching a modern sporting event.
Speaker 1: You're also watching, you know, and like an old thing It's like you're going back in time - well, I think that that's part of it like most of the appeal.
Speaker 0: non my playing baseball has but just watching baseball is the.
Speaker 0: I don't know the history.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like a museum exhibit to me.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Yeah, and I guess you know even soccer which I guess we now have discovered is much older than baseball, right?
Speaker 1: They have you know, you go to the stadium right people are you know chanting and you know, you've got all these advertisements.
Speaker 1: They even have advertisements on the jerseys, you know Nothing about it feels old or feels, you know, yes because no one advertises in baseball.
Speaker 0: baseball Is this song?
Speaker 1: No, but they don't advertise.
Speaker 1: No, they don't advertise on the uniforms You know, they it's not on the field and they.
Speaker 1: you know the game, you know, they advertise on the stadium itself, right?
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: and in the commercials in between and Over the audio and on the big video Tron and such but the game itself, you know I mean they didn't even add instant replay to baseball, right?
Speaker 1: They're just so devoid of technology or anything modern, right?
Speaker 0: I remember the first time I went to a baseball game.
Speaker 0: I was like Surprised to the point of befuddlement that they didn't pipe any announcers or anything over speakers That it was just quiet Like I was sitting there with my parents and I was waiting for the baseball game to start.
Speaker 0: and I'm waiting for like the announcer He's listening on the radio or TV like well, they do.
Speaker 1: they do say things over the announcement But they don't say the whole game over it.
Speaker 1: They're just like, you know now up so-and-so so it's just.
Speaker 0: it was really quiet.
Speaker 0: I'm sitting there and then it didn't happen and Baseball felt really weird and hollow without having the announcer just.
Speaker 0: and number 26 is up and he's having a big Hockey doesn't have a guy talking.
Speaker 1: hockey doesn't need it All right in football right football basically after every play, right?
Speaker 1: The guy will say what the play was.
Speaker 1: if you like, you know, so-and-so pass to so-and-so Ten yards.
Speaker 0: Football gets points for the fact that the ref will come out and explain the rule and why that's the ref.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about the announcer But I like that that the rough go up there like so and so did such-and-such and according to this rule blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: Ten yard penalty first down.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean the umpire in baseball is saying those those things But he doesn't have a microphone so you can't hear him unless you're really close.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you just have to watch his you know, he doesn't you know, you just have to watch his hands, you know.
Speaker 0: Look at the scoreboard, I like sports announcers a lot, especially because every sport has its own kind of announce.
Speaker 1: I mean I could do a whole take it to a whole show just about sports announcers in general.
Speaker 1: But it's like we're constantly, you know, it's a big thing, especially like, you know my family We talk about like the sports announcers and like, you know, who's better and who sucks.
Speaker 1: and you know An old guy retires and they get some new guy and it's like oh fuck this new guy, you know.
Speaker 1: Or it's like one guy who used to announce the Rangers games went to like become an owner or a coach somewhere.
Speaker 1: It's like well fuck, you know now who's announcing this game and you know They'll always whenever there's a game on it's like oh who's doing the announcement, you know Is it someone good?
Speaker 1: or should we turn on the radio?
Speaker 1: but if you turn on the radio while you watch a game is a big delay and they actually have these people like setting things Up so that they can like delay the radio which is faster than the television so that the radio announcing lines up with the video they're watching because they like the radio announcer better than the TV one and it's like you'll.
Speaker 1: you'll hope That your favorite game is on like a different channel because they have better announcers than the.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: but I mean it's like all the it seems really seems like all the great announcers were from like a few decades ago and Sort of in more recent years.
Speaker 1: a lot of those guys just been dying retiring Nostalgia, it's hard to say well it is but it's.
Speaker 1: you know, it's like Earlier in my life, you know in the 80s in the early 90s, you know, the announcers were just always great.
Speaker 1: No one complained about them and just everything was like ah, you know, did they really without the internet?
Speaker 0: How could you know?
Speaker 1: Well, no, but like no one that you know, I knew.
Speaker 1: but like nowadays it's like, you know Who's announcing this game?
Speaker 1: Oh, he sucks.
Speaker 0: I don't know that.
Speaker 0: I think that's mostly perception.
Speaker 1: Well, it's it's somewhat perception.
Speaker 0: At least hockey I feel has been pretty consistent.
Speaker 0: every time I listen to hockey.
Speaker 1: It's always that Yeah, but it you know, sometimes the guy doesn't have the right voice.
Speaker 0: You know, yeah There's Detroit at a whiny guy for a while because the good guy was sick.
Speaker 1: like there's some guys who have the right they have The skill at it, you know, they're calling it properly, you know They but they they're just voice is not pleasant to listen to.
Speaker 0: soccer games were so unruly that royal bands were often put in place against the playing of such sports.
Speaker 0: on the 13th of April in 1314 King Edward the second of England issued What is believed to be the first royal decree?
Speaker 0: He prohibited the quote hustling over large balls Unquote because of the impact the sport had on local merchants.
Speaker 1: How did you escape this royal edict?
Speaker 1: you hustle over large balls every day.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, I think I've got the biggest balls of them all.
Speaker 1: question that Your hustling is gonna get you in trouble.
Speaker 0: The sport was considered to be unchristian for its lack of order.
Speaker 1: Well hustling over balls is most decidedly Large ball.
Speaker 0: So had the ball been small enough.
Speaker 0: We would have been just dandy.
Speaker 1: Oh, then Christians are totally okay.
Speaker 1: Jews gotta watch out.
Speaker 1: So baseball He's ball doesn't have very big balls shows going.
Speaker 1: No, no, I think I think we're done.
Speaker 0: I'll show it all I remember as a kid.
Speaker 0: The other thing I remember the first time I got hit with a baseball I was playing baseball with my friends and I just got hit in the forehead with a line drive And I was like I got up and I'm like, oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: And then later I was like dad, let's play softball next time.
Speaker 0: He was like white softballs for voices.
Speaker 0: No, but I want to lay softballs.
Speaker 0: He was like fine.
Speaker 0: So, you know, we got to play catch and he's like, alright Here's your softball MIT.
Speaker 0: and he threw the softball at me and I was amazed that it was not softer.
Speaker 0: But in fact harder.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just bigger.
Speaker 1: No bigger and harder.
Speaker 1: I do have one little baseball anecdote.
Speaker 1: I want to share.
Speaker 1: It's not so exciting, but it is.
Speaker 0: Alright, I got one too.
Speaker 1: So but it is it is sort of informative, right?
Speaker 1: So I went.
Speaker 1: I've been a camp counselor at summer camps many many times, right and But most of the camps I was a camp counselor at were sort of, you know, normal-ish day camp, you know Not so excel, you know nerdy camp whatever.
Speaker 1: but in between freshman and sophomore years at RIT I was at a summer camp.
Speaker 1: That was a sleep-away camp that had a lot of sports going on Right, and there was a lot of baseball playing going on.
Speaker 1: and during one part of the eight weeks There was they had like a baseball scout come and you know, it's sort of a guy who was really you know He's like a minor league player, you know, and they came and hung out at the camp for a little while.
Speaker 1: so there was sort of like a lot of extra baseball activity going on right.
Speaker 1: and You know, you see some people throw a baseball, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I've always been able to throw, you know as in I rotate my arm I let go of the ball the ball actually makes it to where I want to make it to right?
Speaker 1: It doesn't just drop on the ground.
Speaker 1: It's amazing or go off to the side.
Speaker 0: You can always tell there are people who know how to throw a ball and people who don't.
Speaker 1: well There's actually there's three levels of throwing right and the first level of throwing is sort of like the oops.
Speaker 1: It goes on the ground sort of like beginning of the sandlot right where a kid doesn't know how to throw.
Speaker 1: Then there's the sort of the level of throwing that I had at the time which is you know I'm gonna throw the ball.
Speaker 1: You're gonna get it.
Speaker 1: It's gonna take a while to get there right, but you'll get it.
Speaker 1: It goes where I want it to go, right?
Speaker 1: There's a third level of throwing where like the ball goes, you know Whoosh and when it hits the other guy's glove it goes like crack, you know, it's like damn.
Speaker 1: How does he?
Speaker 1: you know the guy throws like exactly straight like a bullet you're out of a gun.
Speaker 1: and it was like, you know I like I you know I thought that the way to throw it like that was just have a really strong fucking arm and I didn't have a strong fucking Arm, so I was never able to throw like that.
Speaker 1: and actually those Scout that Scout and that other dude Right taught all the kids, you know to throw that way and I also happen to be there.
Speaker 1: And since I didn't have to counsel because these guys were taking care of the kids, right?
Speaker 1: I basically, you know through with the other counselor and Like I was actually paying close attention to what they were saying and I was like, oh shit And like I actually learned how to throw a baseball like incredibly properly and it's sort of you know Once you actually do it successfully and you hear you like you watch the ball like go stupid fast And you hits the other guy's glove and makes that incredibly loud noise it's like oh man, you just you just want to do it like a hundred times cuz it's like It's sort of really empowering that even though you're not so strong you've learned this relatively simple technique that has allowed you to throw this thing incredibly quickly and incredibly dangerously and incredibly accurately and It just like I was.
Speaker 1: I learned how to do it in like literally like 15 minutes just from listening to what these guys were saying actually paying attention and actually doing it.
Speaker 1: and And I can't tell you exactly all the you know, I can't describe it to you what to do over the air.
Speaker 1: You know, I'm just talking I'd have to show you but it's all wrist action, which I have plenty of You really like.
Speaker 1: you could have like no You have like no biceps whatsoever.
Speaker 0: it's all about.
Speaker 1: It's all about snapping your wrist and then releasing at the correct moment.
Speaker 1: that is the.
Speaker 1: That is the way to throw a baseball really hard.
Speaker 0: Do something else - yeah No, you just so.
Speaker 0: I believe Richard Linden knows all about it.
Speaker 0: If you
Speaker 1: if you've seen, you know, if you know what I'm talking about, and you've never actually thrown a baseball You know properly in quotes, you know If you ever, you know have the chance to practice and learn how to do it I highly recommend it because it's it's it's well worth it and it will help you in Any time you have to throw something.
Speaker 1: perhaps you might have to throw a rock one day or something, you know snowball.
Speaker 1: Use the same technique.
Speaker 0: You know, I'm feeling free to be.
Speaker 1: also it's very similar to frisbee throwing only with a frisbee.
Speaker 1: you rotate your wrist You know in your arm or you know laterally as opposed to over the top.
Speaker 0: last year We tried to get to crew the crew together to play some kickball.
Speaker 0: that didn't work out.
Speaker 1: So we didn't have enough people and people was that people bailed.
Speaker 1: people didn't play seriously.
Speaker 0: I really want to play baseball.
Speaker 0: now I sound like I have this powerful burning urge, you know I would.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of sports leagues in the city and I'd like.
Speaker 1: you know I did softball with my work a little bit.
Speaker 0: I don't want to play leagues though.
Speaker 0: I want to play just like bumming around with friends in the park.
Speaker 1: Like I see I want to play leagues Because you know the seriousness and actually keeping score and actually mattering.
Speaker 0: when I when I bummed around in high school We were just friends hanging out.
Speaker 0: We had different teams every time but we kept scoring.
Speaker 0: everyone played deadly serious.
Speaker 1: No, see that's you know, that's fine but with a league it's like you can play against different people all the time and you can.
Speaker 1: actually you need less friends because you Only need enough friends for one team not two teams.
Speaker 1: So it's it's kind of fun and then you could actually win something.
Speaker 0: Well, if we got the whole crew together, we could play a game of baseball.
Speaker 1: and you actually you know There's also a huge social aspect to the leagues.
Speaker 1: I know there's like a there's a dodgeball thing around the corner for my work and if I lived in the city, I would totally do it.
Speaker 1: but Because you know right if I did it now I basically would get home at stupid late hours or not at all because you know It runs late and but you know after the dodgeball everyone totally hangs out and it's totally cool.
Speaker 1: So it you know, that's that's what those things are all about.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the show kind of went nowhere.
Speaker 1: I think that's why we we were able You know, it wasn't the greatest idea for a show ever, but we were able to to knock one off.
Speaker 0: It was all in the wrist, yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and rpgs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com Or you can send audio feedback via odeo.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an odeo on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: You can catch the last 100 episodes in itunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 1: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.