Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, June 17th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm Rip.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, the Museum of Comic and Cartoon Art, Arts Festival 2009.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Oh my gosh, shoes.
Speaker 0: Oh god.
Speaker 1: Randomly, we both did something related to shoes today.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Independently.
Speaker 1: I mean, I've been wearing- I have these like 15 year old boots that I wear almost every day.
Speaker 1: Like I wear them in place of dress shoes.
Speaker 1: I love these boots.
Speaker 1: They're super comfortable.
Speaker 1: They're like black leather, biker boots.
Speaker 1: They're great.
Speaker 1: And I periodically maintain them.
Speaker 1: They've been rehealed like five or six times, resold a couple times.
Speaker 1: I've had leather worked onto them.
Speaker 1: I mink oil them all the time.
Speaker 0: And they were getting real- Does that mink oil come from real minks?
Speaker 1: Actually, yes, it does.
Speaker 1: Sadly.
Speaker 0: How do you get the oil from the mink?
Speaker 0: You just kind of grab a mink and kind of rub it and the oil comes out?
Speaker 1: I have these horrible images of squeezing them like a rag.
Speaker 0: Why would you squeeze it?
Speaker 0: You could just sort of stroke it.
Speaker 0: I mean, they're all oily, right?
Speaker 0: Because it's like, you know, the way humans have oil in their hair, the minks have oil in their fur, right?
Speaker 1: Traditionally, I believe they kill them and take a gland out.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: All I know is that- Why would you do that?
Speaker 0: If you leave the gland in, the gland keeps working and making more oil.
Speaker 1: All I know is that I bought mink oil a long time ago before I knew that they really made it out of minks.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, duct tape is made of ducts.
Speaker 1: I have not run out yet, but once I finally run out, I'm going to buy synthetic mink oil, which I found out also works better than real mink oil.
Speaker 0: See, that's one thing, right?
Speaker 0: There's like some cases where like the real deal is like we can't beat it, but in cases where you can beat the real deal with something synthetic, why does the real deal even still exist?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, look at diamonds.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but I finally, you know, I was sitting there at work today and someone looks at my shoes and they're like, "Your shoes are looking pretty
Speaker 1: ratty.".
Speaker 1: And I look at them and you know, yeah, they were getting kind of ratty because I hadn't maintained them in a while.
Speaker 1: So I went to the cobbler, the underground central, because I happen to have an extra pair of shoes with me at work for unrelated reasons.
Speaker 1: So I switched shoes.
Speaker 1: I walk over and I'm like, "Can you fix
Speaker 1: these?".
Speaker 1: And he was like, "You haven't been taking care of these, have you?
Speaker 1: Look how dry they
Speaker 1: are.".
Speaker 1: And he basically gave me the Jerry Seinfeld treatment for a few minutes.
Speaker 1: And then he's like, "Do you even like these boots?
Speaker 1: I mean, you got to oil
Speaker 1: them.".
Speaker 1: And I'm like, "I know.
Speaker 1: Can you oil
Speaker 1: them?".
Speaker 1: He's like, "But are you going to oil them when I give them
Speaker 1: back?".
Speaker 1: I'm like, "Yes, I'm going to oil
Speaker 1: them.".
Speaker 1: He's like, "What kind of
Speaker 1: oil?".
Speaker 1: I'm like, "Mink
Speaker 1: oil.".
Speaker 1: He's like, "Okay,
Speaker 1: $26.".
Speaker 1: And I'm like, "Fine, here's
Speaker 1: And he re-healed and now my shoes look great.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: That's what I got.
Speaker 0: So it's been raining pretty much constantly here.
Speaker 0: It's probably going to rain again, I think.
Speaker 1: Did you look at the forecast?
Speaker 1: Rain.
Speaker 1: I looked at the forecast for the entire week at work today.
Speaker 1: It will rain every day through Sunday.
Speaker 0: I planted this tomato plant weeks ago.
Speaker 0: I have not watered it by hand.
Speaker 0: I watered it by hand once because it's rained every day.
Speaker 0: It's not raining non-stop, but every 24 hours it rains.
Speaker 0: It's like, "Flo, are we in Florida here?
Speaker 0: What's going
Speaker 0: on?".
Speaker 1: It's terrible.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: I came out of my building this morning, not this morning, after work, and some sort of crazy, homeless-ish, some bum-type person.
Speaker 0: I wasn't sure if he was an actual bum or just bum-like.
Speaker 0: He made a comment to someone to a...
Speaker 1: A hobo?
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 1: A hobbit?
Speaker 0: A loiterer, right?
Speaker 1: So a bum?
Speaker 0: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: The loiterer was like a business guy who was just leaning against the building smoking or whatever.
Speaker 0: And he's like... And the bum was like, "How about that global
Speaker 0: warming?".
Speaker 0: And the loiterer was like, "Ain't none of that
Speaker 0: here.".
Speaker 0: So I've been clever and sort of avoided most of the rains.
Speaker 0: I got an umbrella.
Speaker 0: It's not that... I had a hoodie.
Speaker 0: I never got wet.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't really classify that as clever.
Speaker 1: It's pretty easy.
Speaker 1: Humans have been avoiding rain for as long as there have been humans.
Speaker 0: But two or three days ago, I think two days ago, when I left work... Three days ago, when I left work, right?
Speaker 0: It was raining crazily, and all I had was a hoodie.
Speaker 0: So I just... What could I do?
Speaker 0: I had to go to the train.
Speaker 0: The sooner I got to the train, the better.
Speaker 0: So I just went through the rain.
Speaker 0: I got as least wet as possible, which was soaking wet, including my shoes.
Speaker 0: And then I put my hoodie and my such in the laundry room with the fan on overnight.
Speaker 0: So they dried out.
Speaker 0: And luckily, it wasn't raining back in Beacon.
Speaker 1: Is this going anywhere?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I keep going because I'm just sort of trying to remember what happened there.
Speaker 1: Basically... This must be a fascinating story.
Speaker 0: No, it's not fascinating whatsoever.
Speaker 0: I don't even waste my time.
Speaker 0: The shoes are still wet the next day.
Speaker 0: It sucked.
Speaker 0: And I sort of, you know, it made me think about my shoes.
Speaker 0: And I looked at them and I'm like, "Damn, I bought these like a long time
Speaker 0: ago.".
Speaker 0: I should buy some new ones because these are actually sort of...
Speaker 1: So I take it you did.
Speaker 1: And that's what was in that box on the front porch.
Speaker 0: So I went to Zappos.com and I bought some new shoes.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, right, like back in the day, whenever I had to buy shoes, like, you know, like I really... It was never difficult for me to buy clothes or anything.
Speaker 0: But for some reason, shoes are always difficult because like they didn't fit or they're too short or too long.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it just it was the fitting problem, you know, and I'd go to shoe stores and there'd be nothing good.
Speaker 0: Or there'd be a bunch of like ugly shoes there.
Speaker 0: Who knows what was going on.
Speaker 0: And so, you know, I had all this trouble.
Speaker 0: But the shoes that I just the ones that I'm getting rid of that got wet.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Those I bought at Zappos.com and they showed up.
Speaker 1: You sounded like an ad here.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: The worst thing is that's the only place I buy shoes from.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And they were perfect.
Speaker 0: It's like I didn't even try them on until I got them and paid for them already.
Speaker 0: Perfect.
Speaker 0: So I go and I did the same thing and they're perfect.
Speaker 0: They're probably the shoes.
Speaker 0: I put them on and immediately I put them on and I was like, oh, my God, these feel like they're not brand new.
Speaker 1: Those new shoes are actually they're strange to me because they have the top like the of a high top, like they look and feel exactly like an old school basketball playing high top like I used to wear.
Speaker 0: Well, they're married.
Speaker 0: See, that's the thing.
Speaker 1: But they're not high tops.
Speaker 1: They're mid tops, but they have a high top top.
Speaker 1: It's crazy.
Speaker 1: It's their their marital cats and dogs living together.
Speaker 0: See, my dad was all like, oh, you get the Merrill and I'm like, yeah, Merrill, Merrill, what the fuck is that?
Speaker 0: I just stick with my new balance.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So I actually I remember I was wearing some of the earliest new balance tennis shoes.
Speaker 1: They were so expensive.
Speaker 1: I was like middle school.
Speaker 1: But for some reason I got them.
Speaker 1: They were suede pigskin.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I used to be on Nike and then I was new balance.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But then, you know, my dad had been like, Merrill, Merrill, Merrill.
Speaker 0: And I was like, whatever.
Speaker 0: So my boots died.
Speaker 0: The boots I had, you know, from before.
Speaker 0: So I went to EMS and I was like, I saw the Merrill's there and I was like, huh?
Speaker 0: And I put them on and I was like, whoa, shit.
Speaker 0: And they were expensive, like over one hundred dollars.
Speaker 0: But, whoa, shit.
Speaker 0: And they were like, they're serious business.
Speaker 0: And I investigated in.
Speaker 0: Merrill is sort of like a yuppie outdoorsy kind of brand.
Speaker 0: And they're sort of high end in an apple kind of way.
Speaker 0: You know, in that like any anytime EMS is a sale, it always one hundred percent of the time excludes all Merrill products.
Speaker 0: Like you get a coupon from EMS.
Speaker 0: Look at the fine print.
Speaker 0: It says not good on Merrill products because they're so fancy.
Speaker 0: They won't discount them for any reason, you know.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, there's a reason that they are awesomely and incredibly high quality.
Speaker 0: So when I went to Zappos, I saw that Merrill actually has two different kinds of sneakers that are most of their stuff is sort of outdoorsy boot sandal leathery stuff.
Speaker 1: So, Scott, here's the real question.
Speaker 1: Do these shoes match your handbag?
Speaker 0: That's enough of that.
Speaker 1: I mean, you spend so much time telling the story and obviously you spend so much time looking for shoes.
Speaker 1: And that was why we were running late to the shore at Otacon all those years ago.
Speaker 1: Pete and I are trying to look at video games and go, but now you had to buy shoes.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: I didn't have it.
Speaker 0: And then when we got back from the shore, I went to Zappos and I bought those new balances.
Speaker 0: And those are all those new balances.
Speaker 1: are those kind of match the handbag.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So, listeners, which of our stories was more boring?
Speaker 0: They were both the most boring stories in the universe.
Speaker 1: Let's get on to non boring stuff.
Speaker 1: Otacon, we are going to be there.
Speaker 1: We're doing at least three panels.
Speaker 0: That is a big surprise.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: The listeners are shocked.
Speaker 0: Spoilers.
Speaker 0: We're going to Otacon.
Speaker 0: Oh, my gosh.
Speaker 0: I didn't see that one coming.
Speaker 1: We're doing three panels.
Speaker 1: Three of these panels.
Speaker 1: Caught it off.
Speaker 1: Three kinds.
Speaker 0: Three kinds.
Speaker 1: All I really want to say is that two.
Speaker 1: If you saw one of our panels three at Anime Boston, we are doing the exact same panels at Otacon.
Speaker 1: Anime should see.
Speaker 1: Know your creators beyond Dungeons and Dragons.
Speaker 0: If you saw us at Anime Boston, do not come to our panels at Otacon unless you really like rerun.
Speaker 1: Well, do not come to any of them except know your creators, because we have completely revamped it.
Speaker 1: again is the third kind.
Speaker 0: So if you like to see it, you like to see the same thing repeated in a different way.
Speaker 0: We have one panel for you.
Speaker 1: But there is much more exciting news from Otacon than the fact that we are going to be there doing panels like we always do.
Speaker 1: So remember the best concert Otacon ever had, which was L'arc en Ciel hide performing.
Speaker 0: I was going to make a joke, but I guess not performing at the arena.
Speaker 1: It was like a full on concert.
Speaker 1: The entire band came.
Speaker 1: It was crazy.
Speaker 0: I was trying to remember the name of the girl who pretended to play guitar and I was going to say her name.
Speaker 1: I forgot her name, too.
Speaker 1: But Muck played.
Speaker 1: It was Muck, right?
Speaker 1: They played after her.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were all right.
Speaker 1: They were hardcore.
Speaker 1: I liked them a lot.
Speaker 1: But Otacon, I mean, they always get really good concerts, but that was kind of a peak of concerts.
Speaker 1: That was unprecedented and crazy.
Speaker 0: TMR was pretty crazy.
Speaker 1: TMR was pretty crazy.
Speaker 1: L'arc was just like the next step up from that.
Speaker 1: Well, Hyde is coming back to Otacon, not to do a concert at Otacon, but it just so happens that the band he's working with now, Vamps.
Speaker 0: That sounds a little bit emo, vampire type.
Speaker 1: Is going to be doing a concert in Baltimore on the Thursday of the Otacon weekend.
Speaker 1: Baltimore?
Speaker 1: Thursday, July 16th at Sonar Baltimore.
Speaker 1: Vamps is going to be doing a full on for real concert as part of their world tour.
Speaker 0: I knew they were touring in the US, but I was not aware of this Baltimore show or the Otacon timing.
Speaker 1: Now, not only that, if you're not going to Otacon, right, they're performing in D.C.
Speaker 1: just before that.
Speaker 1: They're going to be in Hartford, Connecticut before that.
Speaker 1: They're going to be in New York City before that.
Speaker 0: That's a big ass tour, going to Hartford.
Speaker 0: I mean, Hartford, no one's going to come see you.
Speaker 0: Where are they playing in Hartford?
Speaker 1: They're playing in Hartford at the Warped Tour New England Dodge Music Center.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's a Warped Tour, OK.
Speaker 1: But they're also going to be in San Diego.
Speaker 0: If you're just in Connecticut alone, you're better off going to New Haven than Hartford.
Speaker 1: L.A.,
Speaker 1: they're doing it in Vegas, but they're also going to have their official party there in Vegas.
Speaker 1: So all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 1: They're going to be in New York City on July 11th.
Speaker 0: Well, we don't have time for that.
Speaker 1: No, but we're most likely going to see them on Thursday at Otacon because we go to Otacon like Thursday morning.
Speaker 1: We're always there by noon.
Speaker 0: You know, he wants to go back to Baltimore.
Speaker 0: You know why?
Speaker 1: He can have two.
Speaker 0: He can have two crab.
Speaker 0: He want to eat the crab.
Speaker 0: That's why he go back.
Speaker 1: So if you're going to Otacon, tickets for this concert are like 30 bucks and it's a for real concert.
Speaker 0: It's cheaper than an Otacon ticket.
Speaker 1: Now, because here's the deal.
Speaker 0: This that was and many people have bought Otacon tickets to see the same person, which cost more.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And that's the only thing they wanted to say.
Speaker 0: There was an update.
Speaker 1: Apparently, Vance has decided to change the schedule and stay in Baltimore one more day just so that they can also appear for a panel and signings and stuff at Otacon.
Speaker 1: Oh, they're going to be at Otacon on Friday with autographs and they're going to do a panel and supposedly all sorts of crazy stuff.
Speaker 1: But the only way to guarantee access to the panel is to go to the concert.
Speaker 0: Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Speaker 0: That's sort of crazy because it's like anyone who's awesome enough to get there Thursday and go to the concert.
Speaker 0: It's like they give you a double bonus.
Speaker 0: So it's like people who are like huge fans, but I can't make it Thursday.
Speaker 0: It's like, well, you're either double bonus or you're double screwed.
Speaker 1: But it's so like at the same time, the what always saddens me at anime conventions is that I'll see the fact that cons basically have to bribe people to go to the panels of the cool Japanese guests.
Speaker 1: But yet people line up for four hours to get their stupid autograph.
Speaker 0: I don't understand autographs at period.
Speaker 1: It's one thing like I can understand getting a cool autograph.
Speaker 1: I mean, remember when I got Magic Johnson to sign that Super Mario Brothers thing?
Speaker 0: But that was not waiting in line for an autograph.
Speaker 0: That was a special situation.
Speaker 0: That was, you know, it's not the autograph that matters.
Speaker 0: It is the thing that the event that occurred.
Speaker 0: But if you had waited in line and Magic Johnson would have signed a piece of paper, it wouldn't mean shit.
Speaker 1: Man, you know, I wish someone had filmed that because that would have been on YouTube.
Speaker 1: I could have done something with that, but I've still got the autograph.
Speaker 1: If I can just get Captain Lou Albano to sign it.
Speaker 0: He appeared at.
Speaker 0: I forget where he appeared.
Speaker 1: I didn't want to stand in line.
Speaker 1: But anyway, many cons now do a thing where they give you a token to if you go to the panel for a Japanese guest and without that token, you don't get an autograph.
Speaker 1: And I feel like this is a fairly elegant solution.
Speaker 1: If you care, the majority of the people who care about Hyde or Vamps or Kaz are going to go to this concert because almost everyone who cares about Otacon gets there Thursday.
Speaker 1: So we're going to be at this concert.
Speaker 1: I recommend all of you go to this concert.
Speaker 1: Live music is almost always worth it.
Speaker 1: Even if you don't particularly like the genre of music, live music, it's always awesome.
Speaker 1: Unless it's Fantomas.
Speaker 0: You know what I would do if I was a convention-y person, right?
Speaker 1: What would you do?
Speaker 0: Well, because basically the autographs come in two styles, right?
Speaker 0: There's the free autograph, which is wait in line and just sign, sign, sign, right?
Speaker 0: And there's the sort of pay autograph where you pay a whole bunch of money to get the rare person, right?
Speaker 0: If I was someone that people wanted the autograph of, what I would do is I would say, okay, if you want my autograph, right?
Speaker 0: What you have to do is you have to purchase a thing, right?
Speaker 0: So it would be my merchandise.
Speaker 0: You'd be like, you'd be like, you can choose a T-shirt or a book or whatever I'm selling, right?
Speaker 0: And so you're not actually paying for the autograph.
Speaker 0: You're buying a merch from me, right?
Speaker 0: And then by buying that merch from me, I will spend like two minutes or so talking to you.
Speaker 0: So it's not just hi, sign, goodbye, right?
Speaker 0: And if you're, I can tell after two minutes talking to you, if you're actually a fan or if you're just some eBay schmuck or whatever.
Speaker 0: And if you're just some eBay schmuck, I just won't sign your shit.
Speaker 0: You know, you bought my merch and you got your two minutes with me.
Speaker 0: That's what you're paying for.
Speaker 0: The autograph is just if I like you, right?
Speaker 0: So there's no guarantee of the autograph, right?
Speaker 0: It's just, you know, you're paying for merch and talking to me.
Speaker 0: So fans will be thrilled because their merch and talking to me is worth a million times more than my name on a stupid piece of paper.
Speaker 0: eBay dudes will hate me.
Speaker 0: They won't get my autograph, right?
Speaker 0: But I'll still, if a fan is an awesome fan, which I'll figure out from talking to them, I will sign something which is not part of, it's not something they purchase.
Speaker 0: The autograph is just me doing it because I want to.
Speaker 1: So what's going to be the going rate at Oticon to get two minutes with Scott?
Speaker 0: Well, it's just the cost of whatever my merch is.
Speaker 0: So if my book is 15 bucks, my book is 15 bucks.
Speaker 1: I don't know, whatever.
Speaker 0: You know, the Geek Nights box set, whatever I'm selling, you just pay, you know, if the t-shirt's 10 bucks, the t-shirt's 10 bucks.
Speaker 1: Hey, remember when we were going to make that Geek Nights box set and we discovered how many- We discovered, well, you know what?
Speaker 0: We could do a Blu-ray.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we could.
Speaker 1: And it wasn't feasible back then.
Speaker 1: It is now.
Speaker 0: It was not feasible to do.
Speaker 0: You know, we could also do USB stick because, I mean, I just bought an eight gigabyte USB stick for $30.
Speaker 0: So we could get 16 gigabyte, like SD cards and use those.
Speaker 0: We'd have to charge a lot of money, but we could do it anyway.
Speaker 1: So one last piece of information, and this is why Oticon always kind of takes the cake.
Speaker 1: Oticon, for the most part, always does the right thing.
Speaker 1: They're setting up a special booth on Thursday.
Speaker 1: No details yet for people who are going to the concert to be able to pick up their badges early so they don't miss the badge pickup in the evening while they're at the concert.
Speaker 0: That is bad ass.
Speaker 1: I'm really, I'm looking forward to this because I know that Hyde had a great time in Baltimore and I know that he is- Oticon makes sure that all those people have a great time in Baltimore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is primarily Jim Bowles being like the god of guest relations.
Speaker 1: That got like, if you think anyone has ever been good at guest relations, you need to meet Jim.
Speaker 1: That guy.
Speaker 0: But anyway.
Speaker 0: All right, so we got to move along here.
Speaker 0: We took way too much time talking about Shoes and Oticon.
Speaker 1: Shoes, oh my gosh.
Speaker 1: So last bit of news.
Speaker 1: We are going to be at Kineticon.
Speaker 1: We hadn't said anything about it yet for reasons that we're not going to get into yet to save time.
Speaker 1: But July 31st to August 2nd, Kineticon.
Speaker 1: It's a video game, webcomic, anime.
Speaker 0: It's the week before or after Oticon?
Speaker 0: I think it's- Two weeks after.
Speaker 1: I think it's Oticon, then we have the week of awesome.
Speaker 1: There's one weekend off and then Kineticon.
Speaker 1: One thing led to another and Kineticon is the first convention to take us up on the give Geek Knights a room to schedule as we see fit for the entire con.
Speaker 0: So you don't have to be like, you know, hey, when are your panels?
Speaker 0: What room are they in?
Speaker 0: There is one panel room.
Speaker 0: It belongs to us.
Speaker 0: It is the Geek Knights room.
Speaker 0: You can just spend the whole convention with us in this room and we will be doing things the whole convention in this room.
Speaker 1: However, we will actually have a secondary room in addition where we will have Luke Crane and all of our game masters from the front row crew and occasionally us running games.
Speaker 0: Is that a separate room?
Speaker 0: I think it's just some tables in a room.
Speaker 1: Well, it's in the tabletop gaming area.
Speaker 0: Yes, we will have a room of panels that is always constantly on as well as some tables in the gaming area that we own.
Speaker 1: So here's why I bring this up.
Speaker 1: Obviously, Kineticon is pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: We always have a good time there, especially for the gaming content, but the anime isn't too bad.
Speaker 1: But here's the deal.
Speaker 1: We have a couple of slots that we haven't finalized filling yet.
Speaker 1: So I'm not now.
Speaker 1: Don't get me wrong.
Speaker 1: We are not saying, hey, send us your panel and we'll get you into Kineticon.
Speaker 1: What I'm saying is that if you think you have a bad ass panel, if you think that you can impress us and you have the best thing you've got and you want to do it at Kineticon, tell us by Saturday.
Speaker 1: You don't have much time this Saturday.
Speaker 1: You know, it's Wednesday, June 17th.
Speaker 1: You have until Saturday, June 20th.
Speaker 1: And we probably will say no.
Speaker 1: But if you put up a good front, there's a chance we will schedule you for a panel at Kineticon.
Speaker 0: And you also have to be going to Kineticon.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It's not hard to go.
Speaker 1: The hotels are not sold out.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And, you know, I guess there is a free badge opportunity, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah.
Speaker 1: Plus Kineticon.
Speaker 1: We haven't.
Speaker 1: you know, we're going to risk.
Speaker 1: Scott and I will personally be doing like at least nine or 10 of the panels.
Speaker 1: Good God.
Speaker 0: So maybe we shouldn't do any together.
Speaker 0: That way we can, you know, spread it out.
Speaker 1: So if you want to see all of our experimental stuff that we haven't done at other cons yet, it's all going to be a Kineticon.
Speaker 0: And lots of reruns because you need to fill in this time.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: One more news.
Speaker 1: One more.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: On the comic book order form this month, which it is current.
Speaker 1: DCVS?
Speaker 0: Well, it's the.
Speaker 0: you know, it's the it's.
Speaker 0: everyone uses the same comic book order form.
Speaker 0: But if you use DCVS, it's also this month.
Speaker 0: So it's June.
Speaker 0: So July, August.
Speaker 0: So coming out in August, Fantagraphics is putting out an Usagi Yojimbo collection.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: It is a hardcover slip case collection of the first seven volumes, 1200 pages of the beginning of Usagi Yojimbo and a fancy hardcover slip case.
Speaker 0: And at DCVS with a discount, it is fifty dollars.
Speaker 1: There's really no excuse.
Speaker 0: This is like, I mean, think about the Hellboy library.
Speaker 0: editions are like thirty something on Amazon.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So this is this is big time action here, you know.
Speaker 0: So how can you not?
Speaker 0: You can't.
Speaker 0: So go get it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And also one last thing, just because it is noteworthy.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to talk about it, obviously, but Hayao Miyazaki is going to be in the U.S.
Speaker 1: in California on July 28th.
Speaker 0: The rumor is he's going to make a secret appearance in Anime Expo, but I don't think so.
Speaker 1: I highly doubt that.
Speaker 1: But John Lasseter is going to be there, too.
Speaker 1: And basically this is remember how Satoshi Kon got that retrospective in New York City.
Speaker 1: And then he was like, well, I hope I get another one because I feel like I'm just getting started.
Speaker 1: This is pretty much that times a million for Miyazaki.
Speaker 0: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: But anyway, before we get to it, things of the day, how long has the episode been already?
Speaker 1: Not that long.
Speaker 1: OK, we've gone on longer.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: About less.
Speaker 1: But chipmunks and Star Wars, I'm not exactly sure what the deal is, but is it like Alvin Simon Theodore?
Speaker 0: Does Darth Vader, Luke?
Speaker 1: and basically as far as I can tell, this guy had wild chipmunks living near him and he bribed them with almonds and then surrounded them with various Star Wars figures and took pictures of them and reacting to the Star Wars figures.
Speaker 0: I think I saw one of these because I saw a stormtrooper riding on a chip.
Speaker 1: That is, in fact, the first picture I'm looking at.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: All that picture.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The one in the end is pretty good.
Speaker 1: It's an Ewok taking a spear to the chipmunk and the chipmunks got his mouth open like, ah, no, it's a good one.
Speaker 1: There's only seven of them.
Speaker 1: This isn't that much of a deal, but I'm sick of using videos from College Humor as things of the day.
Speaker 1: So for once, a non College Humor video thing of the day.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day is a webcomic that I discovered, but I haven't read it.
Speaker 0: So don't blame me if it's no good.
Speaker 0: But I looked at it and it looks really good.
Speaker 1: I can pick things of the day if I don't even know what they are.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: Is the webcomic.
Speaker 0: It's called Marsh Rocket M.A.R.S.H.
Speaker 0: Like a bog or a swamp, a marsh, you know, a dank, spooky marsh and rocket like into outer space.
Speaker 0: Marsh Rocket.
Speaker 0: It's a webcomic.
Speaker 0: It looks cool.
Speaker 0: It looks sort of like a sci fi anime of awesome with some pretty interesting coloring going on.
Speaker 0: And I will read it and then I will know if it's actually written well or not.
Speaker 0: But in the meantime, you got none better to do.
Speaker 0: read webcomic.
Speaker 1: So usually we cover this right after we go.
Speaker 1: But you know, we're on the alternate alternating schedule now.
Speaker 1: But we were at the MOCA in New York City.
Speaker 0: Well, not at the MOCA at the MOCA Arts Festival, which is a once a year event.
Speaker 0: And for the MOCA, it is their primary fundraising event.
Speaker 0: And it is pretty much the best comic convention in New York City.
Speaker 0: Take that in your account.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it pretty much is a snap.
Speaker 0: So we've done shows about it in the past.
Speaker 0: You know, do you really want to spend a lot of time talking about what the MOCA was?
Speaker 1: I just want to get right into it because we got some good stuff.
Speaker 0: We did get some good stuff, you know, actually.
Speaker 0: So we went to the MOCA and the first thing I got there was like a print, actually, which is sort of out of usually I just get, you know, comics there and I don't really buy arts, but I forget who it was and they didn't give me their they didn't put their business card in with the poster.
Speaker 0: So that was sort of side.
Speaker 0: I remember them.
Speaker 0: Sorry.
Speaker 0: But it was like this awesome print where it was like it was all red.
Speaker 0: And then there was like this big pile of blue junk in the in the corner.
Speaker 0: And this person was sort of falling out of it.
Speaker 0: It's pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: So maybe I'll try to find it and post a link in the forum.
Speaker 1: Don't forget.
Speaker 1: I can find out who did it.
Speaker 1: We also got the futurism print.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes.
Speaker 0: That we be quickly soon after made a stop at the Wondermark table, which the Wondermark table is always wonderful.
Speaker 1: Every year I buy something.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: So this year did not disappoint.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I was disappointing, though, that the he's usually Sherry at the Puck building.
Speaker 0: I first of all was in a new building this year.
Speaker 0: It was in an armory as opposed to used to be at the Puck building.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But the armory was it was instead of being separate rooms, it was just one big room.
Speaker 0: So.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: One big room has advantages and disadvantages, lost a little bit of charm, gained a little bit of efficiency, but it was really hot in the armory.
Speaker 0: Really hot.
Speaker 0: I mean, the Puck building was hot, but the armory was real hot.
Speaker 1: Well, what really got me was I remember standing there and I'm sweating and I'm feeling just just overwhelmed.
Speaker 1: And then I look up and I realized that in the sky there are eleven burning sons of death.
Speaker 0: And well, they would have turned it off.
Speaker 0: It would have been pitch black.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, maybe a third of those lights were actually on.
Speaker 1: I can't imagine.
Speaker 0: I remember I walked into the to the festival and I smelled some nasty B.O.
Speaker 0: and I was like, whoa, I didn't know this is.
Speaker 0: I thought this, you know, this isn't usually a fanboy convention.
Speaker 0: It's usually, you know, cool hip indie type people.
Speaker 0: And it is cool hip indie type people.
Speaker 0: But it was just so warm sooner within some minutes.
Speaker 0: I had the
Speaker 0: B.O.,
Speaker 0: even though I had deodorant, it was just that hot in there.
Speaker 0: Everyone was.
Speaker 1: We also met up with two awesome listeners, friends, Phil and Timo.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Timo, all the way from the Finland.
Speaker 0: Totally awesome.
Speaker 1: Who was also in Boston.
Speaker 0: He was in Boston because he's a physicist and he was doing some physics action.
Speaker 1: But he took some time away from the physics to take the Chinatown bus all the way to New York just to go to the MOCA.
Speaker 0: And he showed us some really good comics from the northern Europe.
Speaker 0: So totally sweet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll talk about those.
Speaker 1: I think we should just get right into all the individual things we got.
Speaker 0: So here the first thing I'll talk about is, oh, the Wondermark we were talking about at the Wondermark booth.
Speaker 0: We bought both of his posters.
Speaker 0: He was selling both of them for fifteen dollars.
Speaker 0: So it was fifteen dollars to get to.
Speaker 0: usually it's ten dollars each, I think.
Speaker 0: So we got the Futurism poster and also the Hierarchy of Beards poster.
Speaker 0: Highly recommended posters for your wall.
Speaker 0: Very stylish.
Speaker 1: I've been planning to buy that Hierarchy of Beards for a while and it was there.
Speaker 1: So I got it.
Speaker 0: And that Futurism one, it's like five bucks extra.
Speaker 0: And it's totally my style.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So here I got this is a book.
Speaker 0: I actually didn't buy at the MOCA.
Speaker 0: It is Ace Face, the mod with the metal arms by Mike Dawson.
Speaker 0: I haven't read it yet, so I can't tell you if it's good or bad.
Speaker 0: But Mike Dawson, if you remember, he did the Freddie and Me book, which is totally awesome in a million ways.
Speaker 1: Scott got something very special from him.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: You see, I had my pirate sketchbook, you see, which, you know, I always sort of you know, I think I'm just going to give this to everyone, get a million sketches in it.
Speaker 0: But, you know, I think it's better to just get a few at a time, one or two at each convention.
Speaker 0: And then over the years it will build up and build up, you know, rather than, you know, just doing hardcore on it.
Speaker 0: So the only, you know, pirate sketch I got at the convention was for Mike Dawson.
Speaker 0: And usually I just tell people, draw whatever you want.
Speaker 0: That's piratey, you know, anything that you want, but has to be piratey in some way.
Speaker 0: But instead, I told Mike Dawson to draw pirate Freddie Mercury and draw pirate Freddie Mercury.
Speaker 0: He did.
Speaker 0: And that's all there is to say about that.
Speaker 1: It was it was quite.
Speaker 0: And this is his new book.
Speaker 0: And I'm sure it is awesome because it is made by someone who draws pirate Freddie Mercury.
Speaker 1: So Lamar Abrams has put out a comic called Remake.
Speaker 0: Man, like I seen I saw the cover of this comic around you like I had seen it and I recognized it when I saw it.
Speaker 0: But then we actually got to the table and we saw Lamar Abrams and he was totally cool.
Speaker 0: Like he was an awesome dude and actually flipped through his comic.
Speaker 0: And I was like, oh, wow, this is this is more than what I thought it was going to be.
Speaker 1: And I read it and I liked it, too.
Speaker 0: It's it's sort of Astro Boy.
Speaker 0: Well, it's sort of Mega Man, but really what it is, I think it's Astro Boy the jerk.
Speaker 1: Well, there's also there's a little bit of Scott Pilgrim, just a little in the dialog, I think it's a dialog.
Speaker 1: And also in the way characters will kind of look almost make the Internet face to look up and away and smile a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, you're right.
Speaker 1: But there's also a tiny bit of Tekkon King Crete almost just in the way the characters present themselves and the sudden jumps to extreme and needless violence.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but no, I really think that the summary of this book I would give to someone it's Astro Boy the jerk.
Speaker 0: You know, he's totally Astro Boy, but he's not nice and he's not evil.
Speaker 0: He's not a bad guy.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But he's just an asshole.
Speaker 0: The people just like he'll just like break shit or like, you know, go to sleep.
Speaker 0: But he's supposed to be doing something.
Speaker 0: And so it's it was.
Speaker 0: it was really funny.
Speaker 0: I like this book a lot.
Speaker 1: I haven't read it all yet, but the two best parts so far is I like the girl with the drill hands.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And I like the cat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the cat's good.
Speaker 1: I really like the cat.
Speaker 0: The girl with the drill hands.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that's one of my favorite parts, too.
Speaker 1: We need more of her.
Speaker 1: She needs her own comic.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, just drill hands, girl.
Speaker 0: And, you know, at the end is some Pluto inspired action towards the end there.
Speaker 1: Well, it's funny because I interviewed him a little bit and he basically said, yeah, this is inspired by.
Speaker 1: and then the list of things that we said.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, Lamar Abrams, totally cool.
Speaker 0: I'm you know what I want to see.
Speaker 0: I'm really looking for.
Speaker 0: it's like he's got to do something else.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Or maybe he has something else.
Speaker 0: I got to go look at his website, you know, has quite a bit because if he made this, he made some other awesome stuff or is going to make some other awesome stuff that I want.
Speaker 0: Probably even more.
Speaker 0: You know, so Lamar Abrams for the win.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So what do you got?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So at the drawing and quarterly table.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: First of all, they had some.
Speaker 0: they had some very nice deals on some Yoji Hero Tatsumi.
Speaker 0: It was like by drifting life and get one of the other Tatsumi books cheap or free.
Speaker 0: It was there were some good deals going on, but I already had all them Tatsumi books.
Speaker 0: So I just had another deal going on.
Speaker 0: They had Adrian Tomine's 32 stories, the complete optic nerve mini comics.
Speaker 0: And if you bought that, you would also get another Adrian Tomine book.
Speaker 0: So I got shortcomings.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So basically I got both of these was a combo.
Speaker 0: I saved like 10 bucks.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, I haven't read either of these yet, so I'm not going to say much about them.
Speaker 0: But Adrian Tomine is 32 stories.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's a little cardboard box.
Speaker 0: It's like a brown cardboard and you slip the box open and inside is a cardboard box that actually contains like all eight mini comics, all separate.
Speaker 0: It was a box full of mini comics.
Speaker 0: It wasn't like a trade paperback that had all the same pages as the mini comics reprinted.
Speaker 0: No, it's actually the eight mini comics in a box.
Speaker 0: And I just I thought that was really cool.
Speaker 0: It's it's.
Speaker 0: it's a very nice production.
Speaker 0: And that was that alone was totally worth it.
Speaker 0: And of course, you know, this is much hyped and much critically acclaimed.
Speaker 0: And I know that Tomine is an appreciator of Tatsumi.
Speaker 0: So he knows good comics and he's, you know, comic creator himself is has to be good.
Speaker 0: It's a guaranteed lock.
Speaker 0: That's why I bought it.
Speaker 1: Pretty much the first thing I saw, though, when I walked in and I had to buy it and I think I'm going to have to buy the rest of these forever.
Speaker 1: Tim Raglin made this series of gigantic children's picture books.
Speaker 1: Well, now they're in the style at least of a children's picture book, Scott and West, A Complete Story Adventure, Volume One, The Curse of Cat Uncommon.
Speaker 1: It's basically a Scotty dog and another dog and cats, and it's just anthropomorphize dogs and cats on old Sherlock Holmes style action adventure.
Speaker 1: It's hard.
Speaker 1: I can't do.
Speaker 0: what was that other book he had there?
Speaker 0: It was like Uncle So-and-so Christmas.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: He had several.
Speaker 1: I only bought one, but I plan to buy the rest.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I hope the only reason I only bought one was that I didn't want to carry these gigantic books around the entire mocha.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the back will give you an idea.
Speaker 1: Presenting The Curse of Cat Uncommon, being the legacy of an ancient cat, most uncommon international adventure mystery and a seasoning of intrigue for little misses and masters extensively embellished with colored engravings, sure to delight and improve children of every age.
Speaker 1: These books are beauties to behold.
Speaker 1: And to get a sense of how big this is, it is the size and shape of Scott's monitor.
Speaker 1: It is the same aspect ratio.
Speaker 0: In fact, it's a. it's a pretty big book.
Speaker 1: I got to tell you, this is the kind of thing that I would give to a child or put in my library on the top of my shelves with a little like tripod.
Speaker 1: It's a display book.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So you should definitely better look out for these.
Speaker 0: I noticed recently this sort of been, you know, a greater interest in like sort of like these high end children's picture books that are sort of comic sort of, you know, it's like there's a line between what's an illustrated book and what's a comic.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And, you know, there's a lot of stuff like The Arrival, you know, by by Chantin.
Speaker 0: You know, stuff like that is sort of really sort of making a push into the comic scene.
Speaker 0: And, you know, it's not just sort of staying in the children's illustrated book scene.
Speaker 0: And this I noticed the illustrations in these type of things are just absolutely stunning.
Speaker 0: And who cares if it's not technically a comic, it's not paneled, it's not sequential art.
Speaker 0: Who gives a fuck?
Speaker 0: It's this amazing illustration.
Speaker 0: I'll buy it.
Speaker 0: I'll buy a print of one picture.
Speaker 0: I'll buy a book full of awesome pictures on every page.
Speaker 1: Plus, he gave me, along with the book, a giant sticker of Dr.
Speaker 1: Mu Manchu.
Speaker 1: It's just these are so wonderful.
Speaker 0: We could turn we should turn Dr.
Speaker 0: Mu Manchu into an Internet meme.
Speaker 1: I'm sure we could.
Speaker 0: I mean, he's already ready.
Speaker 0: He's it's already primed to pull the trigger.
Speaker 0: All right, so I sort of have a problem when I go to the mocha, right, is sort of I tell myself, first of all, I tell myself spend like crazy, right, because you're not going to see this stuff for anywhere else.
Speaker 0: Just go nuts.
Speaker 0: Don't hold back.
Speaker 0: If you have a slight feeling about something, just buy it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Of course, this one thing that holds me back is that rim buys stuff.
Speaker 0: He's going to buy it.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to buy it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Another thing that holds me back is sort of, you know, I'm always sort of like, OK, I'll see something that might be, you know, I'll judge it by its cover, but I won't have a lot of confidence that it's actually good.
Speaker 0: It's like I'll say I'll see something really cute, but I don't actually have a lot of confidence that it's actually any good.
Speaker 0: It's just really cute, you know, so I sort of feel like I want to buy it for the cuteness, but that I don't want to buy it.
Speaker 0: So I sort of limit myself on cute things.
Speaker 0: I'll be like only buy one or two things in the cute category.
Speaker 0: So I bought one thing in the cute category, which is Cooking with Food Volume one by Evan Palmer.
Speaker 0: And so I see this book sitting there and on the cover.
Speaker 0: It's a mini comic.
Speaker 0: There's all these different foods, an apple, potato, an onion, some pepper.
Speaker 1: That tomato wasn't looking so good.
Speaker 0: The tomato doesn't think he has some problems biting his tongue.
Speaker 0: He's not happy.
Speaker 0: You know, a lemon, an avocado, a pickle, garlic.
Speaker 0: And there's a knife and a spatula, but they're not anthropomorphized in any way.
Speaker 0: or vegeta more legume.
Speaker 1: Well, they're definitely anthropomorphized.
Speaker 1: They talk and walk around.
Speaker 1: the vegetables are, but the spatula and the avocado is said that those two mooks don't know anything about.
Speaker 0: So I bought this because it was so ridiculously cute with the with the vegetables, with different cool faces and expressions on them.
Speaker 0: I got home and I actually read that.
Speaker 0: I actually read this on the train home.
Speaker 0: It was actually like so awesome, like a hundred times awesome and not just in its cuteness, but in the fact that, A, you're getting real recipes and B, it's actually well written and like the vegetables are all great characters.
Speaker 0: And it's it's.
Speaker 0: it's totally sweet.
Speaker 0: And I'm like I'm just like waiting to go to mocha next year, hoping I can get volume two and get more cooking with.
Speaker 0: it's called cooking with food.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's like just to give you an example.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The first page, he's sitting there.
Speaker 0: He's about to cut this potato.
Speaker 0: Suddenly the potato has eyeballs.
Speaker 1: Then the potatoes have eyeballs to begin with.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Then the potato says, hey, Evan.
Speaker 0: So he stops cutting the potato.
Speaker 0: He's like, yes, potato.
Speaker 0: And it goes from there.
Speaker 0: So cooking with food by Evan Palmer is one hundred times the win.
Speaker 1: I think he had a bunch of other little things.
Speaker 0: So Evan Palmer comics dot com.
Speaker 0: There he goes.
Speaker 0: It's on the back of this book.
Speaker 0: So I am looking forward to more cooking with food and more Evan Palmer.
Speaker 1: Speaking of little things, I should.
Speaker 0: that teaches me a lesson.
Speaker 0: Don't hold back just because it's cute.
Speaker 1: I did pick up number two of the Diary of Diaries.
Speaker 0: Diary of Diaries.
Speaker 1: I very much enjoyed them on the same level that I enjoyed that other comic that I couldn't find anymore.
Speaker 1: The prison stories.
Speaker 0: That was a good one.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I like more than killing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's weird.
Speaker 0: It's like this autobiographical comics, you know, but then there is sort of these that they're comics that are like true tales.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like it'll just be sort of a bunch of true stories that are all really short.
Speaker 0: You know, the kind of story you'll tell someone like, hey, one time, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 0: So someone draws up that short little story and like a few pages of comic and you do about 10 of those and you slap them together in a book and you got yourself, you know, a nice comic.
Speaker 0: That's and I really like that genre, whatever genre that is.
Speaker 0: And I see quite a few of them at MOCA every year.
Speaker 0: They catch my eye.
Speaker 1: But, you know, in particular, it is always easy to draw me into something with bums, prison or poop.
Speaker 1: The more of those are in the same comic, the better.
Speaker 0: That's Rims.
Speaker 0: If you want to sell comics to Rims, make them about bums who get into prison and then have poop fight.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, it can't just be normal bums.
Speaker 1: It has to be dapper bums.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course.
Speaker 1: They have the more dapper, the better.
Speaker 1: A dapper poop.
Speaker 1: I don't know what to do.
Speaker 0: They're not a stab and hobo.
Speaker 0: They're a poop and hobo.
Speaker 1: Poop jokes and top hats.
Speaker 0: That was that was the Wondermark.
Speaker 1: That's why I read Wondermark.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I thought the comic was called that for a long time until I finally looked at it.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But the Diary of Diaries is always fun because they're basically true stories from this guy who has had many misadventures in pooping.
Speaker 0: I mean, I have sometimes Bali problems.
Speaker 0: This guy, he's got real Bali problems, but he basically told me that it is.
Speaker 1: it is surprisingly cathartic to just not try to hide it and just to tell these stories.
Speaker 1: And even though he went through everything in these stories, the fact that someone else can get a laugh off it makes him feel a lot better about it.
Speaker 1: But issue number two is all close calls.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, because I mean, you know, even if you have bowel problems that are pretty serious, you're not going to be shit in your pants that much.
Speaker 0: You're right.
Speaker 0: Well, so, you know, you'd only so many stories you've got of that are true, you know, so he sort of I think, you know, he's used a lot of stories in volume one, like four or five stories of poop in volume one.
Speaker 0: So, of course, volume two had to be the close call stories.
Speaker 0: But that does not diminish the quality of these stories in any way.
Speaker 0: In fact, some of these stories are even more epic than the volume one, because, you know, it's got that whole.
Speaker 0: holding it in action is really the power in the diary of diaries.
Speaker 0: is the suspense of.
Speaker 0: is he going to make it?
Speaker 0: How's he going to make it?
Speaker 0: What's he going to do?
Speaker 0: Is he going to actually find in a bathroom?
Speaker 0: Is he going to poop in the woods?
Speaker 1: You know, I just realized I got to email him and point out, don't shit your pants.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, I'm sure you love it.
Speaker 1: He's a cool guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 0: That'd be awesome.
Speaker 1: I point him out because I don't want to talk about all the things like this.
Speaker 1: But this is an example of the kind of, you know, anyone can publish an indie comic and anyone can present at the MOCA.
Speaker 0: This guy's not the best.
Speaker 0: You know, it doesn't someone draw it for him?
Speaker 1: These are eight and a half by eleven pieces of paper with black and white, basically Xerox stapled together with a color paper wrapper.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: And hold it in half with a staple.
Speaker 1: And yet here they are.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: I enjoy them.
Speaker 0: I enjoy them very much.
Speaker 0: And if it wasn't for the MOCA, I'd probably never get them or see them or know about them or anything.
Speaker 1: So I also have in front of me another small one.
Speaker 1: And I did pick this up.
Speaker 1: And Scott also picked it up the next day.
Speaker 0: I have to let me let me let me cover this cover.
Speaker 1: Paul, sorry.
Speaker 0: So Rim was standing at this table talking to someone else about the Gilgamesh table, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I was interviewing that.
Speaker 0: So he's standing there talking to this person and I'm just sort of hanging out, you know, looking around and on the table in front of me, I see this book, Don't Trust Evil Knievel.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, OK.
Speaker 0: And on the cover, there's a sort of a sketchy drawing of a character, a cartoon character of Evil Knievel.
Speaker 0: You sort of only see his helmet.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like he looks like the Stig with stars all over him, basically.
Speaker 0: And it says on the cover, Evil Knievel is saying, buy this book.
Speaker 0: And then every page of this book is pretty much the right hand side of the page.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Says, don't trust Evil Knievel in some font.
Speaker 0: And on the left side, there's a picture of Evil Knievel.
Speaker 0: And he has one speech bubble.
Speaker 1: So let me read to you some of these that they're all bet it all.
Speaker 0: And it's safe to pet a lion as much as you want after it's eaten the gazelle.
Speaker 1: They want you to be up on stage.
Speaker 0: You can jump that far easy.
Speaker 1: I'm sure that's how it's spelled.
Speaker 0: Whatever's in that giant mouse hole can't be that big.
Speaker 1: The roller coaster is supposed to do that.
Speaker 0: Lightning can only strike you once.
Speaker 1: I never miss that.
Speaker 0: They they just go.
Speaker 0: roller coaster is supposed to do that.
Speaker 1: I said that one.
Speaker 0: Oh, you don't need your shoes for this.
Speaker 0: This is you should have one more.
Speaker 1: There is definitely a genre, a kind of comic where it's almost the concept comic.
Speaker 1: And there were a lot of these.
Speaker 1: We picked up another one, the wolf cried boy.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about that in a little bit.
Speaker 1: But it was pretty much just a concept, but it was amusing enough to where I picked it up.
Speaker 1: Is the kind of thing that you read once it's amusing and then you give it to someone.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But, you know, this is the kind of thing where it's like, you don't sit down and read this book.
Speaker 0: You know, you just leave it lying somewhere, maybe the bathroom.
Speaker 0: And, you know, if you just need something to read, like during the two minutes while you're eating your cereal or whatever in the morning, you know, you could just open it up, pick any random page and maybe you'll get a laugh.
Speaker 0: You know, it's sort of, you know, and it's it's.
Speaker 0: it's pretty funny.
Speaker 0: And I mean, you know, at first I looked at it when I was standing at the table and I was kind of like, eh, you know, but then I open it and started reading it and I was actually laughing.
Speaker 0: So I was like, oh, my gosh.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, all right.
Speaker 0: I laughed at your book.
Speaker 0: Here's my money.
Speaker 1: I think part of what made it funny is that individually nothing in here was that funny.
Speaker 1: But the repetition, like it's one of those things where people try to do something clever with the form of a media or work as opposed to the content.
Speaker 1: And usually it falls flat on its face.
Speaker 1: But here just the don't trust Evil Knievel in a different font on every single splash page made it funnier because it's kind of like it.
Speaker 0: It's almost like a like a Photoshop thread, like, you know, it's like there's a common there's a common theme, but each, you know, and everyone sort of gives their own spin.
Speaker 0: So each of these pages has a different line of dialogue.
Speaker 0: It's almost like one of those caption contests, you know, it's like caption this image.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, that's what this book is.
Speaker 0: It's a caption contest one guy had with himself.
Speaker 1: I rather enjoyed it.
Speaker 1: But while Scott was picking this up and then I was picking it up later, I was talking to Kent and Kevin Dixon.
Speaker 1: And, you know, I walk up and I see this comic and it looks interesting.
Speaker 1: It's Gilgamesh.
Speaker 1: Gilgamesh!
Speaker 0: Misused in many anime.
Speaker 1: Also, apparently it's a 4chan thing now.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: I'm not sure what the deal is, but someone made a joke on Fark and then someone else explained that it was a 4chan thing.
Speaker 1: But apparently people just post a picture of someone and type Gilgamesh underneath it.
Speaker 1: And I don't I don't know what it's referring to.
Speaker 1: But what this is and, you know, I was interested and I start talking to the guy and I put the microphone in his face like, hey, you want to give me a few words?
Speaker 1: He's like, you should wait until the artist comes back.
Speaker 1: I'm like, OK.
Speaker 1: And the guy's like, yeah, the artist is my son.
Speaker 1: And I start talking to him.
Speaker 1: Then his son comes back.
Speaker 1: I did a short interview.
Speaker 1: But basically the father would read mythological tales, you know, Greek mythology and Gilgamesh and things like that to his son when they were young.
Speaker 0: And three messenger fans.
Speaker 0: Getting
Speaker 1: older to get his son to do something, he decided to make his own rendition, you know, which is basically you take a rendition is when you take multiple different translations of a work and synthesize them along with some of your own original translation work into a new kind of interpretation of the work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because, you know, a lot of these old stories are either a oral tradition, so there is no official version, right, or be they're originally written in some language of old, you know, Greek or even older than that.
Speaker 0: So there's not.
Speaker 0: it's very difficult to know the exact story or even if there is such a thing as the exact correct story.
Speaker 0: So there's just sort of like these common, you know, things you know, it's like, OK, if it's going to be a you know, this story, then it has these characters.
Speaker 0: And this is the basic story and then fill in the details around it however you want.
Speaker 1: But it's not just that.
Speaker 1: I mean, even if you have one original work that is translated multiple times, if it's especially older languages, you can translate things in different ways.
Speaker 1: And there are different interpretations of what was actually being written.
Speaker 1: So the father put that together and the son illustrated it.
Speaker 1: And it is a very direct retelling of the epic of Gilgamesh in comic form.
Speaker 1: And the story there alone was interesting.
Speaker 1: And when he signed it, he actually wrote something in Cuneiform, which I think it's Cuneiform.
Speaker 1: I have heard it pronounced both ways by people who had enough clout for me to trust them.
Speaker 1: So I don't know.
Speaker 0: We defer.
Speaker 1: I defer to the Internet.
Speaker 0: I'm actually interested to read this because I don't know very much about, you know, the story of Gilgamesh.
Speaker 0: And it is referenced quite often.
Speaker 0: So I feel, you know, I'm never going to be able to read like, you know, the full, big on hardcore mythology in my life.
Speaker 0: But I'll probably be able to read this comic very quickly.
Speaker 1: The comic is also it's told in a very direct and literal form.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So now when there's all sorts of Gilgamesh references and novels and anime and who knows what, I will totally get them instead of being illiterate.
Speaker 1: I note that a character someone posted for the Burning Wheel game we're playing this weekend, Enkidu, you should learn who that is.
Speaker 0: I've heard of Enkidu before.
Speaker 1: Well, all will be made clear when you read this.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: And I got to put up the interview at some point because these two, this father son duo was.
Speaker 1: it was there was something cool to be there at a table and to meet a father and son who collaborated on this like comic.
Speaker 1: They're not comic artists or anything special.
Speaker 1: They just got together, did it, got it printed, set up at the MOCA.
Speaker 1: And there they were with their with their epic.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: You know, we did a bunch of interviews in the MOCA.
Speaker 0: Most of them were very short, you know, sort of like, you know, hey, who are you?
Speaker 0: Tell us about your comic kind of things.
Speaker 0: But, you know, last year we sprinkled those throughout the episode itself.
Speaker 0: I think we should do is we should take them all, just string them together into like one audio file and put it up as like an extra, maybe in the experimental feed or the something like that.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It'll be up at some point.
Speaker 1: I just I didn't want to extend this episode any longer.
Speaker 0: And we didn't want to spend a lot of time editing tonight.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And normally I do this stuff like on the train.
Speaker 1: But anyway, I didn't get to it.
Speaker 1: And some of these people are really cool stuff to say.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So the next book I have here is Top of the Heap by Keith McCleary.
Speaker 0: You might remember Keith McCleary from last year because he did.
Speaker 0: Oh, what's the name of the book?
Speaker 1: Yeah, he did Killing Tree Quarterly.
Speaker 0: See, I had the cover was in my mind, but the name of the book just wasn't coming because we talked about that last year.
Speaker 1: And he like he found our episode later and emailed us and he's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: And I liked Killing Tree Quarterly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Killing Tree Quarterly is pretty good because it was sort of like, you know, the the the mixed racial western sort of story.
Speaker 0: It was totally cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Plus he he is definitely improving as time goes on.
Speaker 0: So yeah.
Speaker 0: So Top of the Heap is new because we saw Killing Tree Quarterly and like, hey, we know this table.
Speaker 0: Let's see if there anything new.
Speaker 0: And sure enough, there was Top of the Heap, an animal story by Keith McCleary.
Speaker 0: Now, the first thing I noticed when I look at this.
Speaker 0: Well, of course, I know this is an animal story, but this book is like really amazing looking.
Speaker 0: Like every page is like like a full color, shiny printed painted image from like the all covering every single, you know, spot on the paper from edge to edge.
Speaker 0: There isn't really, you know, panels going on.
Speaker 0: And the images are just stunning, like absolutely stunning.
Speaker 1: I believe originally when he did Killing Tree, he used, I think, Poser or something like it with 3D models to kind of set the scenes.
Speaker 1: And then he made it from there.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So this is it's really amazing.
Speaker 0: It looks like, you know, every page is like a full on painting, you know, and it's a story that involves a circus and some animals.
Speaker 0: And I'm not going to spoil it for you.
Speaker 0: And apparently he also told us that there is a there is a crossover in a way between this and Killing Tree Quarterly, if you have read them both.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: He said it's something clever.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: So Top of the Heap is totally awesome.
Speaker 0: And how could you not?
Speaker 0: I mean, it's just, you know, it's a nice little comic book with like this, you know, incredible artwork on every single page.
Speaker 0: I'm just going to see you looking at it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you keep you keep doing so.
Speaker 1: Speaking of something little Leslie and Mackenzie Stein, that's either one person or two people.
Speaker 1: I think it's two people.
Speaker 1: But these are the basically we found this table and that this gigantic spread of laminated pages with cutouts of paper in it and base South Park style.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: And South Park style is how they make these comics.
Speaker 1: And it was a pretty cool concept of how they put it together.
Speaker 1: And I picked up one of their works.
Speaker 1: I think it was the first or one of the earlier ones that they had on the table.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 1: And while I don't it's clearly this comic is some sort of not necessarily an inside joke, but definitely an inside story like it is a story from their lives or from someone's life that is completely in media res with no context whatsoever.
Speaker 1: So it doesn't really give you any resolution necessarily or any context.
Speaker 1: But I don't know.
Speaker 1: I was a neat little comic.
Speaker 1: I just I really like the style.
Speaker 1: I obviously don't want to talk about what it's about because I'll spoil it.
Speaker 1: It's so short.
Speaker 1: But the series of drawings done by Jim Morrison after she wakes up from her drunken band.
Speaker 0: That was the best part is when she wakes up from being drunk and the dude just tells her what happened while she was drunk.
Speaker 1: That was like that right there.
Speaker 1: And also just her being drunk and just the style.
Speaker 1: And I don't know, this wasn't necessarily a great work in and of itself, but I feel like good things are going to come out of these people.
Speaker 0: But she had that whole new book was sitting, right?
Speaker 0: She talked about how, like with this one, they said, yeah, it is.
Speaker 0: They scanned it in.
Speaker 0: But that with the next book, the one that was sitting on the table, like she had the actual see the one we the copy of.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is that we have is just, you know, the scanned in and then printed out book, right?
Speaker 0: But the new book, she actually had all the pages with the actual, you know, she used the scissors and cut out the paper and pasted it together.
Speaker 0: You know, she had the actual thing there on the table.
Speaker 0: And that looked like something really amazing.
Speaker 0: And I can't wait to get that.
Speaker 0: But she says she's going to for that one, she's going to actually take photographs of all the pages instead of scanning, you know, to sort of get like some shadows going on and all that sort of good stuff.
Speaker 0: So I can't wait for that book, whatever it's called anymore.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes, I have two more.
Speaker 0: You have a lot to I get like seven because you get you spent all the money and I didn't.
Speaker 0: So this is a book that I actually knew about before I went to the mocha and I had planned to buy it a few times and I planned to buy it.
Speaker 0: But then I saw it there.
Speaker 0: And, you know, you see something at the mocha that you thought of buying before you're going to buy it.
Speaker 0: It's called The Bizarre Comics of Booty Rogers.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: And I read some of that on the train home.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so basically this dude was this awesome dude way back in the day who just his name was Booty Rogers.
Speaker 0: That was his real name.
Speaker 0: And, you know, he wrote, you know, those comics that he wrote were in the first ever comic book.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: That's how old school and awesome this guy is and his sort of style of comics.
Speaker 0: You know, it's it's a very old style, of course, you know, art wise, but it's actually even though it's really old.
Speaker 0: I mean, sort of the art is better than like Superman, if you ask me.
Speaker 0: And it's just so wacky.
Speaker 0: I mean, not that there's nothing else in the world that's wacky, but this sort of uniquely wacky in many ways, like a lot of the creatures and the people and the way things are drawn.
Speaker 0: And it's like, you know, like, you know, the stories about, like, you know, getting swallowed by a hippo and then, you know, the hippo has an armchair on its back.
Speaker 0: And it's just it's totally and completely off the wall kind of shit.
Speaker 0: And actually, I really, I really like it.
Speaker 0: Actually, it's still even though it's like this incredibly old humor, it's actually like so old.
Speaker 0: It's funny again.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I'm totally digging it.
Speaker 0: And also the book itself, actually, someone named Craig Yo sort of, you know, took sort of, you know, these works of, you know, Booty and he compiled them into this book.
Speaker 0: And it's from who's the publisher wasting time.
Speaker 0: That's all right.
Speaker 0: You should buy.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's a fan of graphics book.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: Who else would print out something?
Speaker 0: So who else?
Speaker 1: about Fanta graphics?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Fanta graphics is it's a twenty dollar book.
Speaker 0: You can definitely see this on, you know, the Amazon or wherever you need to get it.
Speaker 0: But you should just go and look for the cover of this book, right?
Speaker 0: It doesn't cost you anything to see the cover on Amazon.
Speaker 0: The bizarre comics of Booty Rogers.
Speaker 0: And if you'll see where this is going, you see that cover and you like what you see, then you know what kind of business you're in.
Speaker 1: So Timo went over and eventually directed us to the large Scandinavian presence at the MOCA this year.
Speaker 1: Many Scandinavian artists were there, many Scandinavian comics, and one that I picked up that he highly recommended.
Speaker 1: And I can see why.
Speaker 1: Kha or the ring by Titu Takalo.
Speaker 0: I got to read that.
Speaker 1: Which is a Finnish comic.
Speaker 1: And apparently Titu is a very up and coming comic artist.
Speaker 1: But this is not available in English.
Speaker 1: So I actually have the Finnish version and included with it is an English translation on a separate little book.
Speaker 0: Oh, how nice.
Speaker 1: The art is amazing.
Speaker 1: It's about this boxer.
Speaker 1: And I don't want to say any more than that.
Speaker 1: Other than that, this is pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: And it reminds me again how much I love a lot of comics that never make it into the English language.
Speaker 1: I mean, remember at the New York Comic Con two years ago, all those French comics, it was just every comic.
Speaker 1: There was awesome.
Speaker 1: And they were all in French and none of them were in America.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And I feel like Scandinavia has a slightly better chance because it seems like they're trying a lot harder.
Speaker 1: And they're really getting these artists out here.
Speaker 0: And they definitely, you know, I don't know what it is, but they definitely make a push at the MOCA.
Speaker 0: You know, the north, the, you know, the Norway, the Sweden, the Finland, you know, they really do push at the MOCA, at least if nowhere else.
Speaker 0: You know, their comics to the to the United States market.
Speaker 0: And, you know, I mean, you know, you look at Jason has made some pretty good progress.
Speaker 0: So it's, you know, if he can if he can make some progress, so can the other ones, because, you know, I definitely am seeing a lot of stuff at that table that is, you know, just as good as Jason.
Speaker 0: So I'm excited.
Speaker 1: But this was awesome.
Speaker 1: So you should I can't say check it out.
Speaker 1: It might not be that easy to get just yet, but keep an eye out for to talk alone.
Speaker 1: I'm sure I'm pronouncing this name incorrectly.
Speaker 0: I'm sure Timo also pointed out this book by Tom Gauld called The Gigantic Robot.
Speaker 0: And I'd seen rumblings about this book online.
Speaker 0: So, you know, when Timo, you know, said, hey, you got to go check this book out, it's amazing.
Speaker 0: And I saw the book in person.
Speaker 0: I was like, OK, I'll buy that.
Speaker 1: The fact that he took.
Speaker 1: he held it in front of me and read it to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So let me let me read a little bit to you.
Speaker 0: Of course, it doesn't really work at all without the illustration.
Speaker 1: It is primarily illustration.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: So pretty much it's this big cardboard book.
Speaker 0: Actually, it's like these big, nice, thick cardboard pages.
Speaker 0: And all the left hand pages have words and all the right hand pages at pictures.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So page one, the war rages on page two.
Speaker 0: A site is chosen for the secret project.
Speaker 0: Page three, a mysterious structure structure is erected.
Speaker 0: Work continues day and night.
Speaker 1: Each one of these is illustrated just an entire page.
Speaker 0: The structure is dismantled.
Speaker 0: The gigantic robot is revealed.
Speaker 0: And then it goes from there.
Speaker 0: This book, I mean, you get it only takes a few minutes to read it, but I actually spent like a good 10, 15 minutes, like really looking at it.
Speaker 0: And even though I know the whole story, you know, it's just one sentence per page and one illustration per page.
Speaker 0: Like, you can just keep looking at it over and over again, just because it's so.
Speaker 0: it's very powerful and it's one of the better giant robot stories I've seen and it involves no giant robot fighting, which is kind of interesting.
Speaker 0: The thing is, it also sort of works as a flip book.
Speaker 1: It's it's.
Speaker 1: it's very poignant and very.
Speaker 1: I liked it a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can learn a lot from it.
Speaker 0: In fact, you can learn a whole lot about a great many things.
Speaker 0: Oh, let me read what it says on the back.
Speaker 0: A perfect little book by Tom Gold turns futility, decay and eternity into sheer comic wonder.
Speaker 0: His black humor makes Beckett look timid at.
Speaker 0: the gigantic robot is a rye fable concerning the production of an impressive secret weapon whose promise goes unfulfilled.
Speaker 0: There you go.
Speaker 0: Buena Ventura Press, Tom Gold, the gigantic robot.
Speaker 1: So the gigantic robot was something that tried to do something with the form and did it very well.
Speaker 1: Now, there were two independent comics not related to each other called the Wolf Cried Boy.
Speaker 0: One of them was by the Cat in Common guy, right?
Speaker 1: One.
Speaker 1: Yes, I believe so.
Speaker 1: And the other one was by Paul Frederick.
Speaker 1: And I picked that one up just kind of randomly and not so impressed, to be honest.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm giving a bad review to a mocha book.
Speaker 0: You're so mean.
Speaker 1: But Paul Frederick, the same guy who did Don't Trust Evil Knievel, does the Wolf Cried Boy.
Speaker 1: And it's you'll see you read it and he's trying to go somewhere with it.
Speaker 1: It's obvious what he's doing.
Speaker 1: And at the end, you get it.
Speaker 1: But it just repeats far, far too many times.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If he would just repeat it, you know, because the boy who cried wolf is a story about repetition.
Speaker 0: You know, it's as well.
Speaker 0: If there's a wolf, no, there isn't.
Speaker 0: There's a wolf.
Speaker 0: No, there isn't.
Speaker 0: You know, so is that the repeating part and then the finishing part.
Speaker 0: And this book, you know, does that story, of course, is the wolf who cried boy.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But it repeats the beginning part too many times.
Speaker 0: I think if you would have just repeated the beginning part three times or two times, it would actually worked pretty well as a nice mini comic.
Speaker 0: But he repeats it like five or six times.
Speaker 0: And it's literally an exact repetition.
Speaker 0: Like he's just literally drew some pages and copied and pasted them in order so many times.
Speaker 0: At least that's what it looks like.
Speaker 0: So, you know, that repetition is sort of like you flip through to get to the end.
Speaker 0: And the end is, you know, it's it's.
Speaker 0: it's the expected kind of good end of the comic.
Speaker 0: I just, you know, it makes a point.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: I think it could have made its point a lot better than it just cut out.
Speaker 0: I could just take a scissor and make the book perfect by cutting out, you know, I would have left the repetition in, but I would have made it slightly crooked every time.
Speaker 1: That's also a good alternative.
Speaker 1: The fact that it wasn't slightly crooks pushed it beyond brilliant and into inane for me.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If the repetition was either fewer or each repetition was slightly different from the others, that would have been, you know, but I have to talk about bone sharps, cowboys and thunder live lizards.
Speaker 1: How could you not buy a book with that tale of Edward Drinker Cope and the Nathaniel Charles Marsh and the Gilded Age of Paleontology, the Gilded Age of Paleontology.
Speaker 1: It's set in the Gilded Age and it's just the early days of the discovery of dinosaurs and paleontologists.
Speaker 1: And it's just.
Speaker 1: it's some good old fashioned scientist paleontologist drama.
Speaker 0: So that's not what the cover looks like.
Speaker 1: Well, that's what it is, quote, The Wild West provided the setting for some of the famous battles, but the gunfight at the OK Corral can't hold a candle to the bone war.
Speaker 1: In the late eighteen hundreds, the newly reunited states dug, tunneled and blasted his way to the Pacific Ocean, exposing rock that hadn't seen the light of day for millions of years.
Speaker 1: Nor had the bones buried in those rocks.
Speaker 1: Born sharps, cowboys and thunder lizards of the story of Edward Drinker Cope and Nathaniel Charles Marsh, two scientists who found and fought for those bones and the artist Charles R. Knight, who almost single handedly brought dinosaurs back to life for an awestruck public.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that second part there, the dinosaurs back to life, awestruck public aspect.
Speaker 1: Well, as in by taking by drawing pictures of them, there are not rampaging dinosaurs.
Speaker 0: This is a tale of scientists because the front cover makes it look as if there are rampaging dinosaurs.
Speaker 1: Well, the front cover you see is doing something cool and clever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I enjoyed it.
Speaker 0: I thought I had not read the book and I saw that cover and I had assumed, perhaps wrongly, that the interior of the book was, you know, going to be a literal exposition of what I had seen on the cover.
Speaker 1: No, no, it is much more straight up.
Speaker 0: OK, that's cool.
Speaker 0: I actually now want to read it more.
Speaker 1: Knowing that you have any more or am I in the end run here?
Speaker 0: You're on the end run.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I picked up a whole bunch more.
Speaker 1: I'll talk about one more because this really stands out.
Speaker 1: Swallow Me Whole by Nate.
Speaker 0: That's some top shelf, right?
Speaker 0: Addison Tyler bought that so fast.
Speaker 0: If you didn't buy it.
Speaker 1: I have not read this yet, but several people in the crew did over the course of the last week.
Speaker 1: And every one of them has told me unabashedly and without any reservation that it is amazing.
Speaker 1: As far as I can tell, I'm trying to avoid knowing much about it, but it is a tale of a family just going through their daily life.
Speaker 1: But the grandmother is dying of a terminal illness.
Speaker 1: And the two kind of main characters both have some mental illness.
Speaker 1: Each one of them has a different mental illness.
Speaker 1: And the story basically just kind of follows their lives from the perspective.
Speaker 1: It kind of really illustrates what it is like to live in the real world as a real person with a real actual mental illness like schizophrenia.
Speaker 1: And it portrays it in this loose panel kind of pseudo realism.
Speaker 1: It's hard to describe, but it looks absolutely amazing.
Speaker 1: And from the brief interview I did with Nate Powell, who wrote it, he based it is not based on a true story, but a lot of the experiences and a lot of the visuals are based on the fact that he works with people who have these mental illnesses and he knows a great deal about what it is that they experience literally through their senses on a daily basis.
Speaker 1: It does not look like it is a happy read.
Speaker 0: I really think you think it's going to be.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: it's a romp.
Speaker 1: I will put it is a comedy romp now, but the illustrations are amazing.
Speaker 1: The panel structure is all over the place and the production values.
Speaker 1: This is a hardcover book of the highest quality.
Speaker 0: I think it's a top shelf, you know, limited kind of thing.
Speaker 0: I think the actual one is if you buy it on Amazon, be softcover, I assume usually they don't do the hardcovers like that for the it could be.
Speaker 1: I could be wrong to quote one of the reviewers, because I obviously haven't reviewed this yet or read it, quote in the belly of Swallow Me Hole.
Speaker 1: There are dangling conversations, flying pills, final moments, front stoop haircuts, classroom assaults, waves of pain, loss and paranoia, and a few of what Dave Eggers would call heartbreaking tableau of staggering genius.
Speaker 0: So actually, I don't have any more books in my pile here, but I do have a couple of the things we saw that I would like to discuss.
Speaker 1: I have my instant mustache.
Speaker 0: There's one cool people.
Speaker 0: They had instant mustache.
Speaker 0: I think it was Joe Anarchy.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's a good name.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, I saw at the vertigo table, they had Jeff Lemire's original new original graphic novel, Jeff Lemire.
Speaker 1: He's the one who did Essex County.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They're actually, you know, what they're coming out with complete Essex County whole thing in one book.
Speaker 1: Oh, I should just buy that anyway.
Speaker 0: Well, I have the separate books.
Speaker 1: Why would you just to own give to someone else?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: My dad, I should.
Speaker 1: That's like a good gift for a dad.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm going to get you.
Speaker 0: I can get you one.
Speaker 0: I can order it now.
Speaker 0: Get discount.
Speaker 1: Yeah, get it.
Speaker 1: I'll give it to someone.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: The what's it called?
Speaker 0: So I saw his new book there.
Speaker 0: One of his new books is he's doing two new books.
Speaker 0: He's got original graphic novel.
Speaker 0: Then he's also doing an ongoing series.
Speaker 0: He's starting.
Speaker 0: I forget the names of them right now, but I flip through it.
Speaker 0: And Jeff Lemire is like the new hotness, as we said.
Speaker 0: There is no doubt about it.
Speaker 0: His name is basically the stamp of gold.
Speaker 0: If this is if you have his name with a price under it, you that's the amount of money that's escaping your wallet unless you suck.
Speaker 1: Oh, I did pick this up.
Speaker 1: I didn't know who wrote it or anything, but I will bite you.
Speaker 1: Oh, yes.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I got it solely because it's basically an inside joke for the front row crew.
Speaker 1: As far as I can tell, the moon comes down to the sky and bite some kid.
Speaker 0: And that's all.
Speaker 0: I mean, that meteor hit some kid in Russia recently, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Meteorite.
Speaker 1: There was so much bite.
Speaker 1: There was so much more we could talk about at the MOCA.
Speaker 1: I missed a million things.
Speaker 0: I do want to talk about.
Speaker 0: the girl had the the silhouette picture frame.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: And the Victorian soaps shaped like guns.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Those silhouettes were brilliant because I didn't notice it first.
Speaker 1: And she was like, do you like these?
Speaker 1: I was like, yeah, they're OK.
Speaker 1: And she's like, did you really look at them?
Speaker 1: And I'm like, I'm about to.
Speaker 1: And then I realized what they were.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Like you see this table and she's got some cool stuff there.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it's like, oh, man, that's good stuff.
Speaker 0: That's good stuff.
Speaker 0: And it's like soap in the shape of a gun.
Speaker 0: What did it say on the?
Speaker 0: on the?
Speaker 0: she had like a clever saying on the soap.
Speaker 1: She did.
Speaker 1: I forget.
Speaker 0: I feel so bad.
Speaker 0: But the there were these like little picture frames.
Speaker 0: And I was just sort of ignoring them because they weren't sort of.
Speaker 0: it's like if you walk by a table quickly, you know, and there's something that's small and subtly humorous, you won't notice it.
Speaker 0: You have to actually stop and look closely and examine.
Speaker 0: And then you will see the humor.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So actually, these are kind of a good thing, like maybe hang on the wall somewhere, these silhouette picture frames, because like anyone who looks from far away, just looks like a classy, tiny picture frame.
Speaker 0: But if you get close, it's epic.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: Epic, epic lols of what's in the picture frames.
Speaker 0: Totally epic.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Times a billion.
Speaker 1: Oh, and we didn't actually get to see her.
Speaker 1: But Kate Deaton was there, you know, fat Napoleon and all.
Speaker 0: Oh, we also talked to Randall Monroe of XCD.
Speaker 1: Oh, yes, we did.
Speaker 0: He was very.
Speaker 0: it was weird because at the one hand, he was like, you know, basically it was a lot of other people at MOCA are always walking around, moving around.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: He was sitting in his one spot.
Speaker 0: He had the longest line of almost anyone.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: His line was blocking off the adjacent tables and he basically had his head down and was drawing, you know, XCD sketches pretty much the whole time.
Speaker 0: So when he got up to him and we're like, all right, we'll give him a break.
Speaker 0: You know, we just chatted with him a bit.
Speaker 0: You know, we had a mutual friend, you know, so we use that as a way to introduce ourselves.
Speaker 1: And now, but I was like, hey, you want to give us a short interview?
Speaker 1: And he's like, I'm really awkward.
Speaker 0: And it would be awkward.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 0: He said he was awkward.
Speaker 0: And he said, you know, that he felt really awkward right then and there.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, like in our short couple minute conversation, he said two or three things that were like epically hilarious and awesome.
Speaker 1: Now, I probably won't do anything with this, but New York State, you realize, is a one party consent state.
Speaker 1: And I happen to leave the microphone on because I have the.
Speaker 0: how well did it record, though, if you were holding it all near your body?
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: Well, I'm not.
Speaker 1: I don't think I'm going to put it on the show, but I do have an entire recording of the entire conversation we had.
Speaker 0: Well, it wasn't like an interview conversation, though.
Speaker 0: It was just sort of a person to person real conversation.
Speaker 1: So it's not too useful, but it's always at the same time more interesting.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But anyway, we thought Randall, he was never at MOCA before.
Speaker 0: So it was really interesting and exciting to see him there and see just how many people were lining up to get XKCD.
Speaker 1: It makes me happy that XKCD is so popular because I love XKCD.
Speaker 1: It is one of my favorite comics.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, and it's you know, if he went to like, you know, New York Comic Con, no one to be paying attention to his.
Speaker 1: Well, no, because they they're there for the silver age Spider-Man and nothing more.
Speaker 0: You know, but at the MOCA, XKCD is like, you know, longest line.
Speaker 1: I think we'll have to wrap it up here.
Speaker 1: But shout outs, obviously, to all the cool people we met at the MOCA.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people who a lot of listeners stopped up and said hi.
Speaker 1: If you want one group of kids, they they walked out with this giant pile of comics and they're like, you're probably going to review all these.
Speaker 1: But we figured by them anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, so who was it?
Speaker 0: We saw I saw Ian Levenstein there.
Speaker 0: We saw Ananth and George there.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Oh, I did buy an awesome to awesome.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, we should talk about that.
Speaker 0: I didn't read it yet.
Speaker 0: So Indy Spinnerak.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Charlie Doe and those Mr.
Speaker 0: Phil and those awesome guys over at the Indy Spinnerak podcast.
Speaker 0: They put out a book a year ago or so called Awesome.
Speaker 0: The Awesome Anthology.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So I bought it because, you know, I love those guys and I'm totally cool with them.
Speaker 0: And it's basically just.
Speaker 0: they just got a bunch of their artists, you know, that they know.
Speaker 0: Comic artists to sort of contribute a few pages, you know, a short little bits.
Speaker 0: And they made this anthology book called The Awesome Anthology, and they sold it.
Speaker 0: And, you know, with the money, they were able to support Indy Spinnerak, of course.
Speaker 0: And two, they set up a scholarship to send someone to the Center for Cartoon Studies in Vermont and actually the Center for Cartoon Studies at a table there.
Speaker 0: So they decided, hey, let's do awesome to awesomer.
Speaker 1: So it's three going to be awesomest and then that's it?
Speaker 0: I have no idea, but they did awesome to awesomer and it's awesomer in many ways.
Speaker 0: First of all, it's bigger and better.
Speaker 0: Second of all, they're still doing the, you know, donation to a scholarship to go to the Center for Cartoon Studies and it is published by Top Shelf.
Speaker 0: So it's like 100 times awesome in all directions.
Speaker 0: And because it's published by Top Shelf, it'll actually be a lot easier for normal people to buy it than was awesome one.
Speaker 0: So if you can go and look for awesome to awesomer and it is worth pretty much everything.
Speaker 0: And it has a Jeff Smith cover.
Speaker 0: Jeff Smith of Bone.
Speaker 0: That's that.
Speaker 0: Jeff Smith did the cover for this book and that alone means you should buy it.
Speaker 0: I mean, I preordered it and I made him buy another one anyway.
Speaker 1: Ah, and I think that wraps it up, though, breaking little news for us.
Speaker 1: You know, we did all the convention stuff early, but we have scheduled.
Speaker 1: we have finally set in stone the schedule for the first of our possibly numerous panels at PAX West this year.
Speaker 0: Oh, shit.
Speaker 1: Friday, September 4th at eleven thirty a.m.
Speaker 1: to twelve thirty p.m.
Speaker 1: in the way one time eleven a.m.
Speaker 1: to twelve thirty.
Speaker 0: that interferes with any sort of keynote action.
Speaker 0: I swear to God.
Speaker 1: In the Raven Theater, we will be doing Beyond Candy Land.
Speaker 0: No, really?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Oh, snap.
Speaker 0: I didn't think we got that.
Speaker 0: We get that one accepted.
Speaker 1: Neither did I. I thought we were doing the other three.
Speaker 0: So sweet.
Speaker 0: But if that interferes with the freaking keynote, I swear to God, the thing is, at least we've seen one.
Speaker 1: We've already moved on to doing big things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I don't want it says the thing.
Speaker 0: Pax, unlike the other conventions, has the big events that everyone goes to.
Speaker 0: And I really don't want to be set.
Speaker 0: There's so much time that is not opposite them.
Speaker 0: I feel like they shouldn't even put anything opposite them except for, you know, the the always open stuff like the, you know, here anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it'll work out.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Is that it?
Speaker 0: That's the only thing that's scheduled for now that I'm just now like right now getting all the emails to put Beyond Candy Land on the kinetic on schedule.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Easily done.
Speaker 1: OK, this has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to D.J.
Speaker 1: Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.
Speaker 0: dot.
Speaker 0: front road crew dot com, where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our rapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays we have video games, board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front road crew dot.
Speaker 0: com, or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution, non-commercial, share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.