Speaker 1: Hey, it's Wednesday September 16th.
Speaker 1: I'm Ram.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: Pokemon adventures the manga.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: You realize other than one day on Wednesday after PAX I have not been back to my office since we went to PAX.
Speaker 0: You're gonna have to go to back to the office eventually if you want monies.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: No I'm working from home.
Speaker 0: It's the best thing ever except aren't you working the night shift from home?
Speaker 1: well I am but last week I was working the day shift from home, and I got to say working the day shift from home is perhaps The greatest thing in the world.
Speaker 1: I mean you know I used to have a very sure no It's been all.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: it's a lot greater.
Speaker 0: not working and just traveling wherever the hell you want Yeah, but I have to work right now at least though.
Speaker 1: I think I have enough money I could quit and live for a while before I eventually starve to death.
Speaker 0: the thing is I've been thinking lately.
Speaker 0: It's like hey, let's say I don't know.
Speaker 0: I went to the doctor, and they told me I had like a year to live.
Speaker 0: right What would I do?
Speaker 0: I travel the world for you be like whatever?
Speaker 0: But I could.
Speaker 0: that means that if I could do that you could do that anyway.
Speaker 1: I could do that anyway.
Speaker 1: at the end of that you'll have no assets.
Speaker 1: It'll be indigent.
Speaker 0: What's indigent me?
Speaker 1: no no assets?
Speaker 1: What do I do then?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: starve in the street.
Speaker 0: There's no way to unindigent get some money.
Speaker 0: I have skills.
Speaker 1: I mean you'll probably have a bunch of debt chasing you because obviously if you you know if you were going to die You're gonna travel the world.
Speaker 0: Credit cards pay for everything all right, so what if I travel the world and then I get back and the doctors like oh wait Actually, you're not gonna die.
Speaker 1: that has happened.
Speaker 1: And there was a case.
Speaker 1: it was on FARC a couple years ago where a guy was told that he had like a year to Live terminal illness.
Speaker 1: so he like sold his house and spent all his money and like lived the life of his dream.
Speaker 0: And then he was a homeless bum.
Speaker 1: He sued the doctor an idea.
Speaker 0: doctors got money.
Speaker 1: I don't I don't know what came of it.
Speaker 0: Hopefully you just get the doctor to pay off the debt.
Speaker 0: Then you can get a job.
Speaker 1: me here's the problem.
Speaker 1: if he got all of it taken care of You realize the obvious scam is you work with a doctor?
Speaker 1: To diagnose you and then you guys have a party.
Speaker 0: Anyway, no you know why you wouldn't do that because what would have you know what it happens, then it's now insurance fraud.
Speaker 1: Yeah, insurance fraud is very lucrative.
Speaker 0: I guess Unless you're uninsured.
Speaker 0: But then who are you gonna get money from?
Speaker 1: well if you're uninsured by definition you cannot be party to insurance fraud I know.
Speaker 0: but then you also cannot be party to a bunch of money to help you go around the world Unless you are the guy who sets the house on fire to precipitate the insurance fraud.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, then you get paid and you're.
Speaker 0: then you're an arsonist.
Speaker 1: You'll be good at arson.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but having all this free time I've been working European banking hours this week, and I've been doing it from home.
Speaker 1: He's a bank holiday I would have but there weren't any bank holidays while I was doing the European shift.
Speaker 0: is it?
Speaker 0: is it all of Europe or just UK or what?
Speaker 1: well it's complicated.
Speaker 1: You know our our operation is based in bank holidays.
Speaker 0: They're only in London's.
Speaker 1: I think well no, but the stock UK?
Speaker 1: The complicated answer is that there was a bank holiday.
Speaker 1: that happened.
Speaker 1: that was only UK so our people took the day off But the rest of the European markets were active, so it was this complicated.
Speaker 1: We're still figuring out how to handle that mmm, but working from home a lot of free time.
Speaker 1: What am I doing?
Speaker 1: I'm watching the space train.
Speaker 0: Oh space train already finished I'm you know I ever think about it.
Speaker 0: space trains like a hundred and what 17 episodes something like that.
Speaker 0: There aren't too many people in the history of the universe who have seen the whole thing.
Speaker 0: I've said this probably hundreds of people who've seen the whole thing and I'm one of them.
Speaker 0: every single episode.
Speaker 1: Holy shit You know watch every lazy Matsumoto everything.
Speaker 0: That's just impossible.
Speaker 0: Like zero people who've done that.
Speaker 0: Samoto is among the zero people.
Speaker 1: man at some point has to die and as long as he dies before you you could Theoretically watch it all.
Speaker 0: yeah, I guess it takes less time to watch and it takes to make.
Speaker 0: and they made it all.
Speaker 1: so Yeah, but one thing I got to say you know I watch like the whole beginning And I watched like all these rent like 20 or so episodes all through the middle And now I'm watching like the last 15 episodes.
Speaker 1: and one thing I got to say you know Matsumoto lays on the melodrama pretty thick but as we always say he's the only man in the world Who can do it with a straight face?
Speaker 1: But he's really laying it on thick like that episode where there are two Galaxy Express three nines I was a good Mattel's and two well one Tetsuro and one other guy.
Speaker 0: And then they don't even let you know if the mix-up was actually a mix-up or not.
Speaker 0: They're just like yeah It's alright bitches ah and they throw in in that episode.
Speaker 1: They throw that whole side story of yeah There's also a world with the cyborgs of the good guys.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's a good one.
Speaker 1: But there's like this five-minute scene of people saying goodbye to each other and that was like the most melodrama in the whole series As far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: I know captain Harlock.
Speaker 0: He can lay it out.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty heavy.
Speaker 0: well that series I mean it was an episode with captain heart.
Speaker 0: it was but that's actually a three-parter.
Speaker 1: But that three-parter couldn't be nearly as melodramatic as Arcadia.
Speaker 0: Did you not watch the three-parter?
Speaker 1: I did not.
Speaker 0: I'll have to tell you which episodes those are.
Speaker 1: I'll go back and watch that shit.
Speaker 1: I love me some Harlock all right, but we'll probably review Galaxy Express.
Speaker 1: We just have to watch the movie again, and I have to finish watching the end of the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah it needs to be a big movie showing going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe Sunday after the game.
Speaker 1: We're playing you know burning wheel this weekend.
Speaker 0: I don't know about Sunday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the problem is we started like 10.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right We'll see anyway.
Speaker 1: What do you got for me?
Speaker 0: What do I have for you?
Speaker 0: Well, you know there isn't really news.
Speaker 0: well actually there is one big news.
Speaker 1: There's the obligatory.
Speaker 0: There's no more anime industry blah blah blah blah, but yeah, and you know comic news is usually pretty uninteresting.
Speaker 0: It's usually like a new series from so-and-so or you know up so-and-so canceled.
Speaker 0: It's not like this big happenings too often in the world of comics.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna continue my trend of doing geek bites in the Wednesday news slot And I'll continue this trend with this book here.
Speaker 0: It's Marvel 1985. it's let's see it's $20.
Speaker 0: I didn't pay $20 And I don't.
Speaker 0: it's not really thick enough to be $20 worth, but anyway This is uh you remember the Marvel 1602 by Neil Gaiman.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that was actually pretty good.
Speaker 0: That was actually very good.
Speaker 1: I liked it.
Speaker 0: This is not as good But it's okay.
Speaker 0: basically the deal is right.
Speaker 0: is is 1985 in the United States.
Speaker 0: I forget exactly where maybe, California.
Speaker 0: I forget it's basically a suburban Somewhat rural type of place and as a kid with divorced parents and he goes to live with his dad or whatever and There's a weird house in the woods that you know something's going on there.
Speaker 0: I'm basically you know the kid thinks he's insane.
Speaker 0: cuz like he sees dr.
Speaker 0: Doom at the house and You know sure enough right the kid.
Speaker 0: You know at first.
Speaker 1: It's not insane and dr.
Speaker 0: Doom is at the house yeah, and so pretty much all the Marvel bad guys are at this house and They're totally real just hanging out playing poker.
Speaker 0: no eventually they just start devastating everything on purpose in a smart way.
Speaker 1: man Look at dr.
Speaker 1: Doom.
Speaker 1: He's devastating everyone.
Speaker 0: They just kept like they were going out in a radius from this house just fucking everything up.
Speaker 0: And why?
Speaker 0: why are they working together for take they want to take over the world like hey There's no heroes in this world.
Speaker 1: Let's just take it over, but I don't know Devin Devastating everything is not the same as taking everything over.
Speaker 0: I know it's a reign of terror kind of situation.
Speaker 0: You know sort of like The all hail Megatron exactly.
Speaker 0: that's not to say you know but again that all hail.
Speaker 1: Megatron fell short Primarily because it did such like the superficial.
Speaker 1: He's in charge now didn't go into all the cool stuff They could have done.
Speaker 0: yeah We need to really make one or bad guys are really actually smart like full-on smart and this one Sort of gets there a little bit.
Speaker 0: really what this is all about is sort of like the flavor like the art is not what?
Speaker 0: You would normally expect from you know Marvel superhero comic, and it's got all sorts of 80s nostalgia going on And it's pretty cool, and I liked it anyway It was.
Speaker 0: you know it's not like.
Speaker 0: oh man everyone rush out and buy Marvel 1985 Holy shit, but it's sort of like hey.
Speaker 0: This is pretty fun.
Speaker 0: You know little kid Galactus shows up.
Speaker 0: It's crazy time you probably want to read.
Speaker 1: you know what.
Speaker 1: I take that back.
Speaker 1: You want to read this before you read 1602 because it's a roller coaster syndrome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not really related to 1602 except for the fact that there's a year in the title.
Speaker 1: Oh, I know the title is mostly for the same problem that the first Batman comic I ever actually read was Dark Knight Returns.
Speaker 1: No every other Batman comic Just doesn't live up.
Speaker 0: I should get some of the other ones that people say are also great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but everyone agrees.
Speaker 1: They're not as good.
Speaker 1: They're good, but they're not as good anyway.
Speaker 0: So yeah, if you haven't read 1602 you should definitely go and get that instead.
Speaker 0: You want to do a whole show on it.
Speaker 1: I think we could do.
Speaker 0: I gotta read it again.
Speaker 1: All right pretty much anything.
Speaker 0: I got the hardcover that bitch.
Speaker 1: You know I Superheroes aside Thor has about plus 10 to my liking of anything.
Speaker 0: Why don't you?
Speaker 0: why didn't you could read Thor every month if you wanted to?
Speaker 0: why don't you?
Speaker 1: because that you realize Thor the comic?
Speaker 1: Has a total score of 10.
Speaker 1: So anyway was actually some big news in the anime con comic-con circuit And they all come together every year.
Speaker 1: we go to the New York comic-con and the New York anime festival.
Speaker 0: Okay festivals in two weeks.
Speaker 1: Yes, and we'll talk about that during the meta bit.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna push it off But the New York comic-con and the New York anime festival starting in 2010 at least once and Probably forever after this as long as this doesn't like explode are going to be confined into one convention.
Speaker 1: They're gonna take over the whole Javits.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be like the biggest craziest thing ever.
Speaker 1: I think in the long run It's going to eclipse some of those West Coast shows.
Speaker 0: wow that's it's pretty crazy.
Speaker 1: Anime festival gets a ton of people like it's one of the bigger anime cons.
Speaker 1: the New York comic-con is like the biggest thing outside Of STCC yeah, and now that they're putting both in the same building in New York City I think they realize it's cheaper to do one big convention than two right.
Speaker 0: and also you know New York anime festival It's pretty great But it's not really you know super great.
Speaker 0: and the New York comic-con like needs a little bit more to get near to San Diego's Level.
Speaker 0: it's like you know.
Speaker 0: combining them was a really really great strategy.
Speaker 0: However, I hope they realize you know they're gonna.
Speaker 0: You know obviously they'll be able to sell more tickets because they have the whole job at once.
Speaker 1: I think what I know.
Speaker 1: they know this.
Speaker 1: I know they know it.
Speaker 1: I don't know what they're going to do about it.
Speaker 1: But the I mean while notice how a lot of anime people go to the New York comic-con just because they like convention.
Speaker 1: So it's not like.
Speaker 1: they're not from.
Speaker 1: the people who go to the New York comic-con are not familiar with The anime kids and what they do at cons like they're used to that.
Speaker 1: It's there.
Speaker 1: But the New York comic-con like here's example the dealers room is.
Speaker 1: the dealer area is basically just like here's the row of Silver Age comics, and here's the row of Gold Age comics.
Speaker 1: and the dealers room at an anime con is here's the row of swords Here's the row of manga.
Speaker 1: I don't know how they're going to coexist.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be really really interesting.
Speaker 0: I think the thing is actually I kind of really like this because you know We're definitely gonna be doing stuff at it.
Speaker 0: No matter what my god.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: We're already taught We're.
Speaker 1: the thing is I'm a bigger audience is better right.
Speaker 0: and second of all you know the New York And a festival was really a one-day con.
Speaker 0: you would go walk around for a day looking at stuff And that'd be it and then your comic-con was a one-day con.
Speaker 0: you walked around looking at the exhibition hall And that was it.
Speaker 0: and they're really the panels.
Speaker 0: not that exciting except our panels right.
Speaker 0: if they These two this is gonna be a three-day full-on do everything you can at this con.
Speaker 0: get the full action.
Speaker 1: So I know many of you have seen us at the New York comic-con or anime festival for and we're usually like well usually like Breeze in do like our panels and disappear, and then we'll like interview some people and we're gone like we're ghosts.
Speaker 0: I might just for the one year.
Speaker 0: We had a table.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I might just get a hotel room and just stay in the city for the whole weekend.
Speaker 0: I'm.
Speaker 0: hopefully we'll be living in the city by October of 2010.
Speaker 0: If I actually gonna call a guy tomorrow, I saw some nice apart.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: cuz.
Speaker 1: maybe we'll fast forward to that time.
Speaker 1: you'll be living in like one of the five bedrooms in my house.
Speaker 0: I don't know about that.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: my house is pretty nice.
Speaker 0: if I get it No, and if I'm living in your house, then you can go live in somewhere else.
Speaker 1: But anyway that the other.
Speaker 1: the one issue I see too is with the artist alley.
Speaker 1: I mean near anime festival.
Speaker 1: artist alley is a artist alley like anime cons have New York.
Speaker 1: comic-con.
Speaker 1: artist alley is mostly big-name people.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like.
Speaker 0: how are they going to really shouldn't be in an artist alley?
Speaker 0: How?
Speaker 1: because I think the artist alley is a different thing at a comic-con.
Speaker 0: I think what they're gonna do.
Speaker 0: This is my prediction.
Speaker 0: You're ready.
Speaker 1: All right, cuz I have a prediction too.
Speaker 0: Let's see if they're the same you go Okay, so the New York comic-con last year, right?
Speaker 0: It took up right the big area the main area of the Javits the entire main area Right.
Speaker 0: the New York anime festival took up the whole downstairs area of the Javits, you know, it wasn't in the upstairs It was in the downstairs.
Speaker 0: I think That what they're gonna do is they're not gonna merge them like physically.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be the New York comic-con upstairs new kind of festival downstairs at the same time and one ticket will get you into both.
Speaker 0: So that I think you know A lot of comic people won't even go downstairs.
Speaker 0: a lot of enemy people won't even go upstairs.
Speaker 1: But I don't will.
Speaker 1: I disagree on that point.
Speaker 1: if they do it that way I think the comic people are going to stay in the comic area, but the anime people will be everywhere.
Speaker 0: It's possible.
Speaker 0: They'll definitely be cross mixing of kinds.
Speaker 1: I just think there'll be a lot.
Speaker 0: I think there will be less cross mixing than you would think.
Speaker 1: No I think there's gonna be a very disparate cross mixing.
Speaker 1: a lot more anime people are gonna check out comic stuff than vice-versa.
Speaker 1: It's possible because you know just everything is the question.
Speaker 0: I remember
Speaker 1: every anime con we go to like people are into a lot of things but Every comic-con we go to like half the people who run into are literally like with no exaggeration Telling us things like I'm here to buy Silver Age spider-man and that is the only reason I'm here.
Speaker 0: I know how about this right?
Speaker 0: Let's say you're a dealer and there's two dealer rooms.
Speaker 0: Obviously if you're like an anime dealer, you know which one to go in and if you're like a guy who's selling Silver Age comics You know where to go.
Speaker 1: What if you're the sword dealer, right?
Speaker 0: Well, what if you're like vertical comics, right?
Speaker 0: They would get a booth at both conventions.
Speaker 0: They would get you know, vertical incorporated.
Speaker 0: They would get a booth at the anime and they get a booth.
Speaker 1: I don't think they're gonna do it that way.
Speaker 1: I think it's gonna be more integrated.
Speaker 1: I think more integrated, but I think like I think the artist alley will be tiered.
Speaker 1: They'll be like multiple Sections of the artist alley that are basically the same but a lot of different titles.
Speaker 0: They got it.
Speaker 0: It'll be definitely.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be really really really really interesting But it's a long way off so they have a lot of time to get it right or at least to figure things out.
Speaker 1: But that's my prediction.
Speaker 1: They're gonna have like the artist alley will have like the big name section and the normal section.
Speaker 0: I think it would actually be better if they mix them up like the big names and the small names to fix the traffic problems In the New York comic-con artist alley.
Speaker 0: You know because the comic-con artist alley is big problems.
Speaker 0: all those big names if they put all the anime people mixed in Shuffle it up.
Speaker 0: You can really help the traffic out.
Speaker 1: No, then you get the life old situation where the penny arcade line just goes past them and no one ever sees the table.
Speaker 0: Yeah But it helps the traffic gives the lines to hand maybe maybe and then you know what all those people standing in line.
Speaker 0: We'll look at their shit.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna do it that way though.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: they're just gonna have areas with different titles like different designations and the same thing.
Speaker 1: in the dealers room They're probably gonna have like the comic area of people just selling comics and like different areas of different kinds of dealers But I'm gonna have like the same.
Speaker 0: Like how many panel rooms are they gonna be like?
Speaker 0: are you gonna have like a problem?
Speaker 0: We're like there's an anime panel you want to go to but there's a comic-con panel at the same time.
Speaker 0: It's just like ah, what do I see?
Speaker 1: most definitely?
Speaker 1: There's gonna be a lot of panels you have to deal with.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be crazy crazy shit.
Speaker 1: I'm excited me.
Speaker 0: a three-day deal.
Speaker 1: The main reason I'm excited is that normally, you know, we'd only do panels.
Speaker 1: the New York Anime Festival we were just now because the comic-con is branching more and more into gaming.
Speaker 1: We really want to bring our gaming content to the New York comic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was a lot of gaming like companies at the New York comic-con last year.
Speaker 0: Remember we talked to like upper deck with their Warcraft minis and stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was that whole table that had all those board games.
Speaker 1: if they unify them It's the best of both worlds.
Speaker 1: because remember when we brought up beyond D&D to Otacon and it was like this You know like thousand people in the room standing room.
Speaker 1: only crazy thing.
Speaker 1: Now we have the excuse to do panels like that at a comic-con anime festival Daryl Surratt Non-withstanding.
Speaker 0: no Anyway, yeah, it's gonna be a very interesting con.
Speaker 0: It's a long way off and I'm actually you know, it's like I wasn't really looking forward to New York anime festival comic-con.
Speaker 0: It was just sort of like alright here they come again, you know What am I gonna do?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna talk to like David Peterson again.
Speaker 0: I know it's like.
Speaker 0: it's much better for me because now I've got another.
Speaker 0: I like to have fewer cons that are More powerful and have lots of air cons that take up a lot of time and a lot of energy, but aren't that great?
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day, so I have a non video here.
Speaker 1: Usually it's like videos from College Humor, but I'm trying to avoid that because seriously you were looking at a few considering I was.
Speaker 1: but seriously half my things of the day are from College Humor.
Speaker 1: You should just go to College Humor and watch their video.
Speaker 0: college humor comm slash videos Yes, but any rims.
Speaker 0: things of the day.
Speaker 1: So this guy This guy has been a fan of Mad Max for 27 years.
Speaker 1: Mad Max is like the greatest movie in the world.
Speaker 1: to him There's a fan of everything.
Speaker 1: so what he has done is first he recreated the car the Mad Max interceptor.
Speaker 0: That's pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: And he has a blue healer named dog All right.
Speaker 1: And he moved to the Australian outback to make a Mad Max museum and live as much as possible the life of Mad Max.
Speaker 0: Two men enter one man leave he.
Speaker 0: what if I entered?
Speaker 0: when he doesn't leave what happens?
Speaker 0: then?
Speaker 1: there's this town.
Speaker 1: I think it's called Silverton in Australia, and I think they actually filmed Mad Max out in that area.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a lot of the.
Speaker 1: a lot of the extras and stuntmen live right there, and they think this guy is totally awesome.
Speaker 1: He's opening a Mad Max Museum.
Speaker 1: He dresses like the Mad Max guy.
Speaker 1: is just the story behind This is cool enough and Mad Max is cool enough to where I think it warrants the thing of the day.
Speaker 0: What does Melvin gibstein think about this?
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: I will say here's a quote from the article.
Speaker 1: one of the locals says quote Matt.
Speaker 1: mr.
Speaker 1: Burnett is a fair dinkum wonderful bloke fair dinkum who lives and breathes Mad Max.
Speaker 0: There's someone who lives and breathes everything.
Speaker 0: You know we're just talking about Pokemon, but there's a lot of Pokemaniacs out there.
Speaker 1: here is an example.
Speaker 1: We always talk about the difference between a geek and a nerd.
Speaker 1: this guy is a nerd.
Speaker 1: He's a big-time nerd.
Speaker 1: He's a Mad Max nerd.
Speaker 1: Joe a Mad Max geek will probably watch fist of the North Star and think yeah, that was pretty cool This guy fits the North Star.
Speaker 1: oh my god It's not a bad idea you wash.
Speaker 1: ah I'll see if I can get a contact info and I'll send it to like you know.
Speaker 0: Like Silverton, Australia, right?
Speaker 1: There's like pendulettes old thing.
Speaker 1: he was like.
Speaker 1: just address a letter to me in Vegas and see if it comes to me.
Speaker 1: no dress Mmm, and it worked.
Speaker 1: a lot of the letters got to him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think this guy would like fist of the North Star.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just put like the first as many episodes you can fit on a DVD right.
Speaker 0: make it a region-free You know.
Speaker 0: put a little letter in there like hey I read about you on whatever website was what website?
Speaker 1: is it some news site?
Speaker 0: right about you?
Speaker 0: in the newspaper Times online I read about you in the times, and I you know I heard you're a fan of Mad Max.
Speaker 0: Here is a you know a Japanese animated cartoon from the olden days that I think you might enjoy it.
Speaker 0: It's very similar to mad.
Speaker 1: Wow Silverton all right.
Speaker 1: It's out in the Outback.
Speaker 1: It is 800 miles west of Sydney.
Speaker 0: That's in the middle of nowhere.
Speaker 1: It has a population of 51 Including him.
Speaker 1: so he was the 51st person to move.
Speaker 0: so if you address it to you know I'm sure it'll get there.
Speaker 0: you watch a painting posted.
Speaker 1: They're like three other people named that.
Speaker 0: I wonder how often they get mail out there.
Speaker 0: I don't know they got to have met.
Speaker 0: this is not stare must be man.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing.
Speaker 1: I want to send something to this town now because think there's only 51 people in the town.
Speaker 1: if a DVD Shows up in the mail you will probably have everyone in that town watching it.
Speaker 0: I'm sure that they can buy things on Amazon.
Speaker 0: They probably get DVDs all the time.
Speaker 1: I will probably make more fans of fist of the North Star by mailing a DVD to this remote Mad Max town than I ever Would talking about it on geek nights possible.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I got thing of the day.
Speaker 0: It's more appropriate for a Tuesday But I wanted to spread this love to the Wednesday because I think the Tuesday would already know about this kind of thing.
Speaker 0: all right You know we like Cthulhu.
Speaker 0: who doesn't like Cthulhu right?
Speaker 0: ah no though tap I think he actually likes it.
Speaker 1: It's hard to say.
Speaker 0: I mean he's always praying to anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but um and you know we like battle tech.
Speaker 0: right two great gaming classics.
Speaker 0: You know the battle tech and the call of Cthulhu, right?
Speaker 0: How about Cthulhu tech?
Speaker 1: Is this like poke through Lou?
Speaker 0: no, it's totally.
Speaker 0: this is actually a legit game.
Speaker 0: It actually has to expand.
Speaker 1: is poke through Lou was the legit game?
Speaker 0: No, this is a super legit game like holy crap.
Speaker 0: So selling a rule book in PDF for like 70 bucks is this literally just max versus Cthulhu?
Speaker 0: I'm it's.
Speaker 0: it's fucking Cthulhu tag and it's for real and it actually won a lot of awards for being a good game.
Speaker 1: Let's get it.
Speaker 0: It's like 70 bucks.
Speaker 0: by thinking gonna pay for it anyway I might pay and I get a PDF immediately.
Speaker 0: so and then the full book will come later.
Speaker 0: And then if we play it if we actually play it then I'll buy some of the expansion bits.
Speaker 0: The one expansion allows for like minor cults to enter the game.
Speaker 0: ah And I didn't read what the other one did.
Speaker 0: but yeah Cthulhu tech is totally for reals.
Speaker 1: I've sounded up our alley in a big way.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: even if it's a bad you know I can't.
Speaker 0: it's won a lot of awards.
Speaker 0: I mean come on even if it's shitty.
Speaker 1: it'll go on the shelf next to all the other really expensive though.
Speaker 1: It'll go next to all the other RPGs and board games that aren't good, but we bought anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah like Twilight Struggle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I spent.
Speaker 0: I spent more money five dollars more on battle lore.
Speaker 1: so yeah I see I told you battle or is a bad.
Speaker 0: sell that battle or anyone want a battle lore?
Speaker 0: It's yeah It's a full set.
Speaker 0: hardly ever played a battle or and I actually have an extra board so you can play with a board That's twice as big.
Speaker 0: yeah, and I'll try.
Speaker 0: you know I paid like a total of like 85 something $90 for both parts, so if you you know I'll sell it for a lot less than that.
Speaker 0: 50 bucks 40 bucks whatever battle or comes like a million miniatures.
Speaker 0: They're all unpainted.
Speaker 1: So anyway before we get on to the main bit and our Pokemon adventure stylings This is where we do the meta bits.
Speaker 1: now It's a new bit on geek nights where we try to keep all of our meta crap out of the rest of the show and put It right here.
Speaker 1: You know met all the stuff about geek nights.
Speaker 1: that is not relevant unless you are a fan of geek nights directly and in our community.
Speaker 0: yes, so Meta note number one the ad contest is still ongoing.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna give it another week or so.
Speaker 0: it Basically we want to purchase ads on other websites to advertise geek nights.
Speaker 0: however to do this We need images.
Speaker 0: that are the ads themselves.
Speaker 0: if you go to the forum forum dot front recruit I come and you go.
Speaker 0: there is a thread.
Speaker 0: It's it says ad contest.
Speaker 0: you know there are all the instructions there how big to make the images and such and such.
Speaker 0: Send the images by email or post them in the forum.
Speaker 0: We'll pick a winner and you'll win all six volumes of the Akira manga a very awesome prize that is worth a lot of money.
Speaker 0: It's like $180 worth of manga, so you want to enter if you have any Photoshop or design skills whatsoever.
Speaker 1: So metabit number two we are going to be at the New York anime festival And I've got our schedule here for you.
Speaker 1: finally.
Speaker 1: I just I had to go dig it up.
Speaker 1: I you know this was settled like four months ago So I had to go find like this old email to figure out what we're doing now.
Speaker 1: So perhaps the last New York anime festival the New York anime festival is next weekend for the 25th 26th and 27th of September in the Jacob Javits Center in New York City.
Speaker 1: We are going to be there Friday and Saturday Friday evening 730 in Panel room 3. we were doing know your creators the same panel.
Speaker 1: We did a note account.
Speaker 1: so if you saw the note account the last time we're gonna do that panel We're gonna revamp it.
Speaker 1: We're basically we're gonna drop it and do a similar panel.
Speaker 1: That's very different, but accomplishes the same purpose.
Speaker 1: So this is the last running of it.
Speaker 1: if you really want to say it check it out and on Saturday at 7 45 p.m.
Speaker 1: also in panel 3 and Anime every fan should see colon cover your bases.
Speaker 1: That's basically an amalgamation of every different title.
Speaker 1: We've given this panel in the last Two panels only two panels.
Speaker 1: It's pretty easy Friday and Saturday and Saturday.
Speaker 0: They're both nighttime panels.
Speaker 0: So during Saturday during the day, maybe we can go look at apartments or something.
Speaker 1: I think it's Saturday during the day.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna do some stuff in the city for sure.
Speaker 0: we should go look at apartments.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or maybe we'll do a listener meetup.
Speaker 0: anyone who's going?
Speaker 0: oh, not a bad idea.
Speaker 1: Let us know and Saturday we'll try to schedule something like we can say hi, or maybe we'll take you guys out.
Speaker 0: So I'll make a thread in the forum for like yeah 09 listener meetup.
Speaker 0: and if anyone listening to this is going to the nyaf then post there, and so if there's no more nyaf It's just the nyaf Nick.
Speaker 0: I think well.
Speaker 0: I mean there.
Speaker 0: start the read exhibitions.
Speaker 0: right they got this show in Chicago the c2e2.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's basically gonna be an everything con.
Speaker 0: get you know everything nerdy right.
Speaker 0: so I think what they're doing is They realize that New York Comic Con combine it with nyaf.
Speaker 0: They can sort of make it more like the c2e2 and basically what they'll end up doing is saving a lot of resources and run Basically the same show twice.
Speaker 1: I'm honestly getting more and more excited about read doing these geek conventions because they're you see every year like they.
Speaker 1: you know They're a professional business, and you know I work with a lot of the people.
Speaker 0: You know it's.
Speaker 0: it's taken a while.
Speaker 0: They started out doing the shows the same way they did their normal business II shows.
Speaker 0: But now I think they've realized geek shows make a lot more money.
Speaker 0: They get a lot more press they're a lot more exciting and they're learning how to do them with time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you need more than just a room full of booze and as far as I can tell the staff like they're getting into it More and more.
Speaker 1: they're really enjoying well.
Speaker 0: They're hiring a lot of people who are nerdy to handle that kind of shit.
Speaker 1: Yep, but the other cool thing is that remember they're doing.
Speaker 1: they're handling all the logistics for PAX East - so read one.
Speaker 1: They spend all this time like analyzing their conventions and figuring out how to do them better And they have professional resources to throw at that sort of thing - by managing PAX East and All these different comic and anime cons they basically are in a position to learn from like the things that all these different kinds of cons do well and Amalgamate them into what could be in the end like the generic uber geek con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's definitely.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: their cons You know are good, but they're not like oh super amazing.
Speaker 0: But they're definitely you can see they're clearly improving and learning and I think they're gonna you know Eventually, they're just gonna be like the masters of the geek con plus.
Speaker 1: I will say as a meta aside You're like we do.
Speaker 1: we're staff on Connecticut We're the heads of panels and we do stuff like Otacon and everything and anime.
Speaker 1: Boston's fun But it's not really relevant to a lot of you.
Speaker 1: You know you go to these cons as an attendee you want to enjoy the panels do all the stuff.
Speaker 1: but from our perspective the meta perspective as like performers as Lecturers as staff is all this stuff.
Speaker 1: The professional cons and the ones run by read are just so much nicer to work with and so much easier to deal with.
Speaker 0: They actually email you back.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much the only difference.
Speaker 0: I mean.
Speaker 1: if you guys saw like all the bullshit and hurdles we have to go through at some of these fan conventions to do That like just to do a panel.
Speaker 0: It's mostly cuz.
Speaker 0: just people don't email us back.
Speaker 0: That's really the only problem It's.
Speaker 1: but I mean more and more.
Speaker 1: I don't want to turn my back on the fan run cons because I like them and for attendees I still think in a lot of ways they're better.
Speaker 1: like Otacon and anime Boston have a lot going for them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then of course Pax West is like the ultimate of that.
Speaker 1: Yep, but while I don't want to turn my back on these fan cons Personally, it's just so much easier to go to the professional con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think our con schedule for the foreseeable future is anime Boston Otacon Pax East-West Connecticut.
Speaker 0: yeah, New York Comic Con Connecticut, and I think that's it right.
Speaker 1: yep And you know the little ancillary things like Zenkai con because that you know our friends Rob.
Speaker 0: are we doing that yeah?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're doing some of our good gaming panels and actually that that thing's picking up.
Speaker 1: I could see it going places not very good.
Speaker 1: I don't know if we'll ever have time to do Torah con again.
Speaker 1: I like Torah con.
Speaker 1: It's just it's too far away.
Speaker 0: I can't go back to Rochester.
Speaker 0: Maybe if I'm got like mad extra vacation days and mad extra money's I could use the jet blue.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just more and more.
Speaker 1: all my reasons to go back to Rochester.
Speaker 1: I've moved away from Rochester.
Speaker 0: Yep Okay, so main bit Pokemon adventures.
Speaker 0: Oh snap Gotta catch them all bitches.
Speaker 1: It's real simple, but I learned something.
Speaker 1: I learned something that has changed everything.
Speaker 1: But I'll get to that in a second.
Speaker 1: if you liked the Pokemon games the actual games on Nintendo.
Speaker 0: Yep, not not like any of those other Pokemon.
Speaker 0: You know it's weird.
Speaker 0: Pokemon is a strange thing in that there's sort of like this core right.
Speaker 0: the core is the original Series of games for the Gameboy slash DS.
Speaker 0: You know Pokemon red blue green the ones that are just colors.
Speaker 0: You know not Pokemon snap not Pokemon troze a Pokemon pinball not Pokemon mystery dungeon Just plain old Pokemon color any color.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: that main series of games is like the core and it's great and a lot of that extra stuff is sort of nay right and You know with the Pokemon anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever right okay?
Speaker 0: It has some aspects that are good, but really eh right and you know most Pokemon manga is bleh.
Speaker 1: well I'm not even gonna say bleh.
Speaker 1: I think it's more simple.
Speaker 1: It's all very different from the core of Pokemon exactly like it's kind of like all those Carcassonne expansions.
Speaker 1: You just tacked down around the side of this completely separate original thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Pokemon is a strange thing because you expect Pokemon to be like this kitty sort of thing And you know what it is.
Speaker 0: all that tacked on stuff is exactly the stereotype of what you would think Pokemon is.
Speaker 0: but the core Pokemon stuff the core series of video games and This manga which is pretty much the only other thing that I consider to be in the Pokemon core are the real deal Not just silly kitty stuff.
Speaker 1: I mean basically if you enjoy the Pokemon games you should read this manga.
Speaker 1: make sure you get the right one.
Speaker 0: Pokemon Adventures, that's it.
Speaker 0: It's not called Pokemon color.
Speaker 0: It's not called anything else.
Speaker 0: It's just Pokemon adventures.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: That's the.
Speaker 0: that's how you know it's the right one and Viz recently reprinted.
Speaker 0: It's he back in the day right back in like the early 2000s I think.
Speaker 0: Viz printed this in the US and they printed in these big books.
Speaker 0: They were like full-size there, but they were thin.
Speaker 0: it was like one chapter and one trade paper.
Speaker 1: I remember Luke had them all at RIT.
Speaker 1: That's how we read it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Luke is like oh my god You got to read this Pokemon manga, and we're like what?
Speaker 0: And we read it and we're like oh shit.
Speaker 0: But it was published sort of like as almost like a coloring book.
Speaker 0: so we're like what the fuck You know is with this printing format.
Speaker 0: Yeah And then eventually right now like as of like a month or two ago Viz finally reprinting this original Pokemon adventures manga in the you know Manga digest format, so it's actually in an accessible book.
Speaker 0: It's only eight dollars per book.
Speaker 0: and let's see this book has volume two.
Speaker 0: How many pages are in this guy for eight bucks and try to find a page number?
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of freaking pages at least 200 something more than 200 pages of manga for $8.
Speaker 0: That's a good deal right there.
Speaker 1: Well depends on the manga, but for this one.
Speaker 0: definitely this one is definitely the real deal now.
Speaker 1: It was originally put up by Shogakukan and in the not I think 1996 1997.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's an old manga.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 1: We're so old.
Speaker 1: so oh my god.
Speaker 0: That's actually kind of interesting because I mean we were reading it in the US.
Speaker 0: and what like oh 102. so it took less than like you know five years for it to get over.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is interesting how this.
Speaker 1: there's the weird nostalgia factor where?
Speaker 1: Pokemon is both a lot older than you think and yet not nearly as old as original Pokemon was for the original Gameboy.
Speaker 1: But it's weird.
Speaker 1: not even Gameboy color just Gameboy my whole like.
Speaker 1: I think of what I cannot Consider or imagine or remember the point at which I became aware of Pokemon.
Speaker 0: I do I remember exactly what I feel as though.
Speaker 1: I was always aware of Pokemon and the Pokemon always existed.
Speaker 0: No, I remember exactly when because I was reading my game Pro magazines, right?
Speaker 0: There was you know suddenly there was all this stuff about Pokemon, and I was like.
Speaker 0: I was like Why are they pushing this kid's game Pokemon?
Speaker 0: whatever?
Speaker 0: right and I kept skipping over all the Pokemon stuff.
Speaker 0: Just be like whatever whatever and eventually of course my brother who had the Nintendo power right.
Speaker 0: he got the Pokemon for his Gameboy Pocket.
Speaker 0: Gameboy Pocket, but you don't remember that guy.
Speaker 0: I remember that guy.
Speaker 0: Gameboy Pocket was great.
Speaker 1: You know I didn't buy that shit.
Speaker 1: at a game gear was already in color.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Gameboy Pocket wasn't in color wasn't but it had that it had a much better screen.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 0: my pocket was basically original Gameboy only Smaller had more battery life with two triple-a batteries instead of four double is.
Speaker 0: the screen was green was bigger And the device was smaller.
Speaker 1: also not only was the screen bigger.
Speaker 1: That wasn't the biggest deal.
Speaker 1: It was high contrast And white.
Speaker 0: yeah think about the Gameboy Micro, that's what the Gameboy Pocket was.
Speaker 0: it was like that only worth it.
Speaker 1: I mean the Gameboy Pocket like I. As a kid I remember dismissing it until a friend of mine had it And I saw it and I realized that you could have colors other than drab lime to darker drab lime.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, so my brother got the Pokemon for the Gameboy Pocket And then I had the Gameboy Color soon after and I was just like our.
Speaker 0: I saw the Pokemon.
Speaker 0: I was like oh wow That's actually like oh That's what that.
Speaker 0: oh, oh I thought it was some kiddie thing all along like whatever.
Speaker 0: I just dismissed it and skipped over it didn't read about it.
Speaker 0: once I saw what it was I was like oh fuck me now.
Speaker 1: We got the Pokemon.
Speaker 1: We keep saying it's the real deal.
Speaker 1: But there is solid evidence for this to the point that the quote is like all over the internet.
Speaker 1: It's on Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: They're like a million citations for it, but Satoshi Tajiri the guy who created Pokemon mm-hmm He said and I quote Boku got to tie a takata.
Speaker 1: Seki no moto mocha Kai manga desk, huh?
Speaker 1: This is the comic that most resembles the world.
Speaker 1: I was trying to convey.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if you look right at say I only said the Japanese because they pointedly put the Japanese in the Wikipedia To make sure that no one argues about the translation or anything.
Speaker 0: Wow so anyway if you look at the original Pokemon Gameboy game right that that was the first ever Pokemon ever was that Gameboy game.
Speaker 0: There was no Pokemon before that.
Speaker 0: that was it.
Speaker 0: then look at say the anime for example right and compare that to the original video Game.
Speaker 0: there's a lot of big differences.
Speaker 0: I mean like Pikachu's his first Pokemon It's like no in the Gameboy game.
Speaker 0: He gets you know either You know Charmander Squirtle or Bulbasaur.
Speaker 0: first Pikachu comes later And that's only if you get one.
Speaker 0: you don't have to get a peek at you if you don't want to.
Speaker 0: it's kind of hard To skip it though.
Speaker 0: You know and there's like the story, and he's not ash Ketchum He's you.
Speaker 0: you name him, but the default name is red.
Speaker 0: cuz he's the red guy and the right There's a rival and his default name is blue.
Speaker 1: There's also yellow the yellow Caballero.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the fucking man.
Speaker 0: yellow caviar rocks at the house, but it's like you know.
Speaker 0: Brock and misty don't follow you around Right you know you just fight them once and that gets the end of them.
Speaker 0: also in them in this manga misty Badass and Team Rocket in the ma in the Gameboy game Badass scary dudes.
Speaker 0: in the anime you got like that Jesse and James.
Speaker 0: silly nonsense going on.
Speaker 0: So you know the anime.
Speaker 0: while it has many similarities with the original you know Gameboy game It is you know very much a diversion.
Speaker 0: right actually interesting thing.
Speaker 0: right in The anime right the main characters name in the u.s.. Is ash Ketchum right and the rival is what Gary?
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 1: yep well the thing is I know you're going with this.
Speaker 1: in the original Japanese the names were actually Shigeru and Satoshi.
Speaker 1: you know the names of Miyamoto and the guy who created Pokemon.
Speaker 0: That's in the anime though in the Gameboy game.
Speaker 0: It was red and blue.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep, so yeah That's that was sort of interesting to find that out.
Speaker 1: Now anyway I talked earlier about something that blew my mind and like this is like one of those puzzle pieces that fell out into my lap from the internet, and it looks legit and It answers every like question.
Speaker 1: everything fell into focus.
Speaker 1: I now understand Everything there is to understand about Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Yep, the guy who created Pokemon Satoshi Tajiri, so when he was a kid as a young boy He lived in Mashida near Tokyo, and he liked to collect bugs.
Speaker 1: all right.
Speaker 1: He just collected bugs Yep.
Speaker 1: So eventually all the places he used to go to collect bugs were paved over and turned into apartments And he was sad.
Speaker 1: so he eventually wanted to make a game where people could relive that and collect bugs.
Speaker 1: He succeeded much in the same way that Miyamoto.
Speaker 1: You know what was Legend of Zelda.
Speaker 1: he used to wander through the woods as a kid And he wanted to recreate that sense of exploration and wonder.
Speaker 0: I had a great idea.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you after the show, but anyway I'll wait to leave listeners hanging.
Speaker 0: so what it rim?
Speaker 0: Tell me what was there something you did as a kid that you now want to recreate and recapture?
Speaker 1: uh play DOS games.
Speaker 1: I Installed fucking tie fighter.
Speaker 0: You know we should do.
Speaker 0: we should make a video game that sort of recreates the experience of installing and uninstalling games in DOS.
Speaker 0: That's a good idea.
Speaker 0: And that's all it is.
Speaker 0: is like you know just as you pretend to install and uninstall games to keep your DOS disk We can make it in the don't shit your pants style.
Speaker 1: Then you have to make boot disks and everything instead of don't shit your pants It's don't break your computer and make tie fighter work now.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the piece of the puzzle where it all came together Nintendo.
Speaker 1: he was called.
Speaker 1: the guy was called reclusive and eccentric by people at Nintendo, but very creative Turns out.
Speaker 1: the creator of Pokemon had Asperger's.
Speaker 0: Oh really.
Speaker 0: That's a surprise now.
Speaker 0: So the OCD also.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure but suddenly Everything tamale.
Speaker 1: you know everything about Pokemon makes sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, absolutely everything anyway.
Speaker 0: Well, we're talking about Pokemon adventures this manga Which is written by he didn't or a kusaka and the art is by motto.
Speaker 0: I guess a person with one name like sting.
Speaker 1: I read that just the coloring was done by motto.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh well That's the I'm really I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at the front of the cover of the viz volume 2 Which is story by he didn't or a kusaka art by motto.
Speaker 0: so take from that what you will.
Speaker 0: Satoshi Yamamoto this manga.
Speaker 1: Basically as someone who has played I see what happened motto did the first nine volumes and then other people took over after that.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh as someone who has played the video games and read this manga This manga is basically a manga version of the video game.
Speaker 0: like it is so dead-on You know in the in the way it feels the way the story goes and everything and so the thing is.
Speaker 0: of course It's more fleshed out because the video game you know Doesn't have a lot of filler in it in terms of lots and lots of text.
Speaker 0: you know it only has a little bit when you talk to people.
Speaker 0: so this sort of takes the shell of the story of the Video game and keeps everything that's in there in there And then just sort of fills in the gaps.
Speaker 0: it adds a little bit to like.
Speaker 0: there's a new character green Who's the girl who's totally awesome, and there's a couple other slight differences?
Speaker 0: But they fit in.
Speaker 0: they don't like stand out as like you know being out of place like the way ash Ketchum does you know?
Speaker 0: This is totally right.
Speaker 0: along with you know the feel and how those games go.
Speaker 0: It's totally great.
Speaker 0: The thing that I like about it the most I think is that you know an Earthsea right the Wizard of Earthsea.
Speaker 0: It's like you read book one It's about Ged right and then like you read the rest of the books and get is sort of like becomes this legendary figure And he's not really around.
Speaker 0: I mean he's kind of around, but he's not really really around.
Speaker 0: he's become this legendary figure.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: these Pokemon books go the same way.
Speaker 0: the first few volumes are about red the original Pokemon guy
Speaker 1: and
Speaker 0: then you read yellow Caballero which comes after that and Red is now sort of like this mysterious legendary figure But you know all about him because you read those other volumes, but now he's all legendary and mysterious, and it's totally awesome.
Speaker 0: I love that shit.
Speaker 0: You know I think that other stories need to do more.
Speaker 0: that like you know you read Lord of the Rings and Merlin is sort Of he's there, but he's still sort of mysterious, right?
Speaker 0: They should have had the story of Merlin first and then do the Lord of the Rings where Merlin's all mysterious.
Speaker 0: that way You get that same feeling you get in Pokemon Earthsea.
Speaker 1: Well regardless.
Speaker 1: I just The game and the comic give me the same feeling actually that earthbound does.
Speaker 1: there's this very.
Speaker 1: you know Earthbound is very Pokemon it is But just the idea the journey of the child through the adult world through the eyes of a child and with the priorities of a child.
Speaker 1: But yet, it's an adult world that the child is traveling through and that Mystique to a child.
Speaker 1: I think that is what made Pokemon and earthbound while mother just so amazingly Transcendently popular among kids.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what else is pretty great about this Pokemon?
Speaker 0: Right is that you look at some of the other Pokemon.
Speaker 0: things like especially Pokemon movies concentrate a lot on the Pokemon themselves.
Speaker 0: You know on the monsters and catching them all.
Speaker 1: he's got Gyarados.
Speaker 1: well I have squirtles and I'll do the blah.
Speaker 0: or even like you'll see scenes where it's just Pokemon.
Speaker 0: There's no people around.
Speaker 0: this is all about the people.
Speaker 0: the Pokemon are just sort of there.
Speaker 0: You know it's sort of like.
Speaker 0: you know I don't know, but it's that it's about the trainers.
Speaker 0: It's all about the trainers the trainers of the main characters.
Speaker 0: It's all about them and the people they talk to.
Speaker 0: the Pokemon are there and they are characters But they're not the primary characters.
Speaker 0: They're always like off to the side a little bit, and they'll do awesome stuff with the Pokemon You know, but they're really.
Speaker 0: they sort of take the place of the cute pet You know like Akumako or something like that.
Speaker 0: You know where they have.
Speaker 0: you know hilarious scenes when they do something and they say funny things and do funny things But they're not the characters.
Speaker 0: you're not like following the adventure of Pikachu.
Speaker 0: It's the adventure of red.
Speaker 0: It's about red.
Speaker 0: It's about the yellow Caballero.
Speaker 0: It's about green and Gary and Professor Oak and those people and You know that's what I want to see is I want to see a story about people.
Speaker 0: I don't want to see story about.
Speaker 0: you know cute monsters right, but you know the cute monsters.
Speaker 0: They're still there, and they still provide awesome moments and a rim loves his Bulbasaur.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, Bulbasaur is just.
Speaker 1: I don't think you guys understand how hardcore Bulbasaur is.
Speaker 0: yeah and you know there's all sorts of like funny situations like when they're Pokemon get mixed up or Like you know and like yes the ride on the Gyrodos or whatever and he goes in the water And he's like oh shit.
Speaker 0: Oh shit surf.
Speaker 0: Oh crap.
Speaker 1: Probably my favorite parts though are all toward the end.
Speaker 1: You know Team Rocket is a serious scary Pseudoterrorist organization.
Speaker 0: yeah, that's what I love that.
Speaker 1: and Giovanni is one scary badass motherfucker.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Jesus.
Speaker 0: He actually appears here in volume two.
Speaker 0: is it great?
Speaker 0: because he goes and he talks to our red And he just sort of walks around with red like all normal like pretending to be friendly.
Speaker 0: it reminds Hard.
Speaker 0: yeah, then after red walks away He sort of like pulls his coat back, and you can see the letter R on his vest.
Speaker 0: It's all stylish, and it's like oh shit.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: He's Team Rocket Oh, but the fact that Team Rocket is more like this mafia organization like this evil That's the thing seriously evil.
Speaker 0: if you look to Team Rocket in the original video game You know you didn't know much about them other than that they were bad guys and what they looked like and they all looked Like bad guys.
Speaker 0: they would wear black You know evil kind of suits, and they'd be up to no good.
Speaker 0: and in the manga They're even more evil and up to even more.
Speaker 1: no, but they're up to realistic.
Speaker 1: No good They're trying to do.
Speaker 1: you know the kinds of things that mafias do just in a world where they're a Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they want to get Pokemon and make them all powerful And and you know do all sorts of evil stuff with them take over towns and smash things and threaten people and you know all That sort of evil stuff.
Speaker 0: They have an evil corporation.
Speaker 0: That's a front for their mafia.
Speaker 1: miss yep This manga is at least the beginning of it The story of red and his you know youthful idealism and him fighting against Team Rocket And it culminates in the like the whole story.
Speaker 0: He's just trying to become like you know like the.
Speaker 0: you know this great Pokemon train.
Speaker 0: Yes, but he gets embroiled get all the badges, but then you know along the way He can't help but keep bumping into Team Rocket And then Team Rocket's coming after him at the same time and so it's a big mess.
Speaker 1: it just I like the whole the first Saga how that all ends with Giovanni and him and everything is just amazing.
Speaker 0: It's very me.
Speaker 1: This is a good manga, and I shall just read it.
Speaker 0: I mean it's Viz kids right, but don't be put off.
Speaker 0: I mean it is appropriate for kids obviously, but don't be thinking.
Speaker 0: It's kiddie.
Speaker 0: I mean there's shit going down in here like people's getting arms get chopped off or like Pokemon get cut up And they bite people and it's it's friggin hard dangerous world.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean friggin.
Speaker 0: as a giant Pokemon.
Speaker 0: if it steps on you You're dead, but the thing is don't be fooled.
Speaker 1: You know when you've just start reading the manga the first volume it starts out on the same level I'd say as that Legend of Zelda manga like it's kind of light-hearted, and it is kind of kiddie at first And it it's also of his kids title.
Speaker 1: yeah But it definitely progresses and progresses and gets darker and more serious and more cool as time goes on.
Speaker 1: and By the end of the first story arc with red and then when you move on to yellow You'll see what we're talking about.
Speaker 1: you'll see why we like this so much.
Speaker 0: the other thing is that plot wise it skips over a Lot of sort of like the fiddly BS that like other Pokemon things will pay attention to right like you.
Speaker 0: don't see him catch every single freaking Pokemon.
Speaker 0: You know it's like they'll sort of skip ahead.
Speaker 0: He's like.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, this you know I you know There'll be one chapter.
Speaker 0: He's got like three Pokemon.
Speaker 0: the next chapter have like eight and you'll see ones that weren't there.
Speaker 0: You just sort of assume that he caught them in the meantime, and he did.
Speaker 0: and that's that you don't need to see that.
Speaker 0: You know what's the what's the deal?
Speaker 0: You know it moves in a very nice pace as a result as opposed to getting bogged up And you know where you watch him throw a bokeh ball.
Speaker 0: It didn't work.
Speaker 0: Pokeball didn't work.
Speaker 0: You know you don't have that sort of stuff going on.
Speaker 0: So yeah Pokemon adventures don't get the wrong one.
Speaker 0: Pokemon adventures, let's see the ISBN of volume 2 is 1 3 9 7 8 1 4 2 1. oh doesn't start with 1 3 9 7 8 1 4 2 1 5 3 0 5 5 0. so You know I'll post some Amazon links in the show notes, so you get the exact right volumes.
Speaker 0: You don't get the wrong thing.
Speaker 0: How about that?
Speaker 0: sound good good Pokemon adventures.
Speaker 1: this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various ranks And tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: you can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: Don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.