Speaker 0: Hey, it's Monday June 15th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: The pain of my existence the bane of my existence.
Speaker 0: ticketing systems.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I get to my building this morning You know going into work, and they finally completed the construction on the facade, but it's not.
Speaker 1: It's still got a scaffold going.
Speaker 0: the word Lincoln has been excised from every possible place in this building.
Speaker 0: Wow The statue is gone.
Speaker 0: all the quotes that were in like bronze on the walls are gone.
Speaker 0: There are these plates these gilded plates and every every elevator every hallway.
Speaker 0: the word Lincoln is gone from all of them And now they have renamed it one grand central place Grand central place.
Speaker 1: yep, is that an actual address?
Speaker 1: now it is Where's grand central place?
Speaker 0: directly in front of grand central.
Speaker 0: since when it's right now?
Speaker 1: What Street is that?
Speaker 0: 42nd Street.
Speaker 1: Grand 42nd Street is not grand central place.
Speaker 1: It is the second Street.
Speaker 0: No, 60 East 42nd Street is now one grand central place.
Speaker 1: What the fuck.
Speaker 1: you can't just be like.
Speaker 1: I mean it's one thing right like if you live on a street And you want to change your number and no one else has the number you want to use.
Speaker 1: you don't like the number you got.
Speaker 1: But and you know let's say you're on the corner of say.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: fifth and 45th right.
Speaker 1: so maybe your address is like something 5th Avenue.
Speaker 1: You could change it as something 45th Street if you know.
Speaker 0: there are addresses.
Speaker 0: I mean there there's something places and something squares which are on a street.
Speaker 0: But the place or the square name which is a legitimate address includes neither Street at the cross-section.
Speaker 1: They basically made up a street grand central place.
Speaker 1: There is no road that is called grand central place.
Speaker 0: there are many addresses all over American cities that don't have the name of the street.
Speaker 0: They're actually on in them places and plazas and all sorts of stuff like that.
Speaker 1: No, because most of the ones I know of anyway There are plenty that aren't it exists.
Speaker 1: look like for example Apple is one infinity loop, but Infinity loop is the name of the street that's in their private campus there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it doesn't have to be the real Street.
Speaker 0: in a lot of places RIT it's law.
Speaker 1: Memorial Drive is the actual road that's RIT owns is the private road that they got it.
Speaker 1: I'm saying it's bullshit.
Speaker 1: You can't just make up a new street.
Speaker 0: They do it all the time.
Speaker 1: actually I've never seen it.
Speaker 0: Okay, and you can't even name one besides Scott.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: You've never seen it.
Speaker 0: It happened here.
Speaker 0: I can.
Speaker 1: yeah, that's why I'm saying it's bullshit.
Speaker 1: It shouldn't be allowed to.
Speaker 0: Okay, the city actually was all for it and the post office already accepts the address.
Speaker 1: They're stupid.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: She put me in charge.
Speaker 1: I would said no, okay.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's all I got this morning.
Speaker 0: You just had all this righteous indignation.
Speaker 1: So, why do they actually?
Speaker 1: why they didn't do this?
Speaker 1: just for no reason?
Speaker 1: I mean it cost money to change the facade on a building.
Speaker 1: Why did they spend all that money?
Speaker 0: for it's a much more memorable Name, it makes it kind of a trophy address and all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 1: Were they trying?
Speaker 1: are they like having trouble selling space in the building?
Speaker 0: actually much of New York City is right now, really?
Speaker 0: Yeah real estate in the city for commercial purposes is pretty cheap.
Speaker 1: turn it into apartments, baby.
Speaker 0: No, because apartments can't be in those places and don't work in those buildings.
Speaker 1: There are buildings that have residential and commercial space in them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is possible to make it happen.
Speaker 0: This is one of those pre-war buildings.
Speaker 0: They cannot retrofit it that easily.
Speaker 0: They have enough trouble getting water to the bathrooms.
Speaker 1: You know the pre-war buildings are sort of problematic but when they do these so called gut renovation to them and put in the nice new appliances they Are very desirable.
Speaker 1: and you know, in fact, you know, I'm not a fan of like the exposed brick But many people are they like that.
Speaker 0: actually, you know, though There's not enough incentive to do that because it would cost so much to gut a building like that.
Speaker 1: Spend money to change the address that cost almost nothing.
Speaker 1: You're not making money with the empty space.
Speaker 1: That's sure.
Speaker 0: I mean changing the address the facades all together cost almost nothing.
Speaker 1: I would live in office space if they let me they should okay.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I just I just put a shower in there Alright, so there's like a bajillion bajillion tech news.
Speaker 1: We haven't done a Monday show in like forever and there was palm pre and there was iPhone and there was fuck fuck Everything in the universe.
Speaker 1: So in order to cover it all we'd have to do a tech news roundup.
Speaker 1: But you know what?
Speaker 0: I think most of these stories have already been covered Extensively, that's just not Scott's excuse for not wanting to actually look into these any further.
Speaker 1: I've looked into all of them extensively because I've myself listened to and read much of the coverage that you can also Listen to Henry.
Speaker 0: I found most of it lacking.
Speaker 0: I mean, I listen to GD GT's roundtable about the pre and it was garbage.
Speaker 0: They basically said nothing interesting and they talked a lot about the business.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I did.
Speaker 1: I did listen to that today and I was sort of disappointed.
Speaker 1: They didn't talk about like the specifics like, you know, how does the synergy syncing thing work?
Speaker 1: How many things can you say?
Speaker 0: Palm the company Web OS something in the future, but no specifics.
Speaker 0: No detail.
Speaker 1: It's like I need to know.
Speaker 1: I want to know like, you know, okay the web browser on the phone How fast is it?
Speaker 1: Does it?
Speaker 0: Basically did was speculate the exact same things that I personally could have speculated.
Speaker 0: They didn't give me anything I didn't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we really need some sort of you know in you know.
Speaker 1: Give it to you because I don't have the phone.
Speaker 0: but best review I found so far is still the end gadget one from before The phone was out.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So anyway, there is one story though that I think is the.
Speaker 1: it's been covered But it's not being covered enough or in depth enough anywhere I've seen and that is the fact that the next version of Apple's OS X the snow leopard because the current one is the leopard.
Speaker 1: I kind of hate how they did it.
Speaker 1: They did tiger leopard snow leopard.
Speaker 1: It's like come on.
Speaker 1: There's another cat.
Speaker 1: you can use Lion yet.
Speaker 0: It's a slight update there.
Speaker 0: They did that to kind of link the two together especially with the news you're about to talk about.
Speaker 1: yeah, but the snow leopard.
Speaker 1: the big news is that the From everywhere.
Speaker 1: I've read there weren't like explicit details But it would seem that if you want to upgrade from leopard to snow leopard it will only cost you $29 and perhaps 99 additional cents.
Speaker 1: To upgrade from tiger to snow leopard apparently is gonna cost a hundred and thirty dollars as usual, right?
Speaker 1: Now the thing about this news is first of all one That's great for me because I got a Mac at work and which while I have many problems with it The snow leopard actually adds a lot of features.
Speaker 1: I want to use at work like I was after using a Mac at work.
Speaker 1: I would never buy one for my house or for myself except for the TV the Mac mini, but They're adding exchange support to like the built-in the mat the Mac mail and calendar and such and right now I'm using a virtual machine with Windows and Outlook.
Speaker 1: So that's a huge boost.
Speaker 1: So I'm and the fact that it's $30 means I'm pretty much guaranteed to get it.
Speaker 1: So that's good news for me.
Speaker 1: but the two things I think that's most important about this is that Apple makes all their money right?
Speaker 1: or they make money from selling hardware and such right and some other things, you know They also make plenty of money from the software.
Speaker 1: They do make plenty of money from the software.
Speaker 0: but I mean who can get away with that sort of upgrade model?
Speaker 0: It's very expensive.
Speaker 0: Well, it was very expensive to upgrade OS X but people kept doing it because they kept needing the new features.
Speaker 1: Yep, but the fact that they're doing it for $30, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they could have done it.
Speaker 1: They could have just had it be 130 like it was before right?
Speaker 1: In fact, they've got another thing Let's see.
Speaker 1: You've got a family and everyone in your house has max for 50 bucks.
Speaker 1: You can upgrade like your whole family right.
Speaker 1: the details of that I have not seen either like exactly how many can you upgrade?
Speaker 1: because I mean What if I can upgrade infinity?
Speaker 1: I'll just buy one and upgrade the whole company, you know, it's like But you know, they're basically letting people upgrade very very cheaply.
Speaker 1: So they're losing a bunch of money on that because they could charge the full 130 They've been charging.
Speaker 0: losing money is a relative term.
Speaker 1: They're they're Could make they could make more money is what I'm saying, right?
Speaker 1: The thing is I think that putting the price at $30 is gonna benefit them in two ways way.
Speaker 1: number one is That basically by having all the leopard people move to snow leopard They're gonna save a lot of money.
Speaker 1: Are they gonna get?
Speaker 1: they're gonna save some money and not having to deal with leopard anymore, you know I mean well not even just leopard but pre.
Speaker 0: I mean people.
Speaker 0: even you know They might.
Speaker 1: people might leapfrog and jump and I still I think it's gonna cost though the full 130 to get out of Tigerland.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they might know I don't think anyone's using any pre tiger anything.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of people there really a lot of people.
Speaker 0: I just I see people out there using the oldest oldest OS that just because they can't afford to upgrade.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I mean you can pirate the upgrade but and I could see people upgrading out of Tigerland Even if it's expensive just so then they can get the cheap upgrade.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, I don't know if the upgrade is gonna be cheap, you know, you'd have to pay.
Speaker 1: I guess I think it would cost 130. just go directly from Tiger to snow leopard.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm guessing from what people have said.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the the thing is right.
Speaker 1: Microsoft has had a lot of trouble with Windows because they've had to maintain this backwards compatibility.
Speaker 1: People are still using Windows 98 still using Windows 2000, right?
Speaker 1: And I think that making the upgrade $30 is gonna be a long-term benefit for Apple getting all these people out of leopard.
Speaker 1: So they're gonna be able to abandon these older OS X's right in the long run, but to If you notice, you know Apple they got a lot of.
Speaker 1: it's sort of weird because you look at the big tech companies You know and Microsoft the Google the Apple right and they all sort of overlap in certain areas and don't overlap in other areas Right.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know Google and Microsoft sort of overlap and you know this web space But they don't overlap in the operating system space, you know.
Speaker 1: And then like Microsoft and Apple overlap in the operating system space and you know.
Speaker 1: But they don't overlap and say the game console space, you know, it's it's sort of everyone's doing a different mix.
Speaker 1: But Apple just seems to love taking shots at Microsoft That's the person that they target the most and making the OS upgrade.
Speaker 1: 30 bucks is a huge broadside on Windows 7 because Windows 7 is gonna come out right and Microsoft isn't gonna make money selling hardware with Windows 7 on it.
Speaker 1: Dell makes that money.
Speaker 1: Microsoft has to sell Windows 7 and make money from the sale of Windows 7 directly So they can't afford to drop the price way down, right?
Speaker 1: So what?
Speaker 0: at the same time though remember Microsoft is still gonna make a lot of its money from corporate accounts.
Speaker 1: If they upgrade they might just keep sticking with 2000 XP as they've been doing now.
Speaker 0: They won't become.
Speaker 0: as far as I've seen the enterprise world Always eventually upgrades and they just they tend to stay one full version behind but they always upgrade.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's gonna be a big enough move.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna be a full-on move to 7 like it was a full-on move to 2k XP.
Speaker 0: Actually, I'm seeing rumblings more and more than a lot of people are going to Upgrade all the way up to 7 because they skipped a lot of incremental ones along the way really.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean we're right now.
Speaker 0: we're moving on to 2008 server.
Speaker 1: It's one thing Apple does not make a lot of Corporate licenses on OS X not nearly as many as my whole company.
Speaker 0: We bought one airbook just because we could when they first came out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it just sits there.
Speaker 0: No one likes it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but It's a huge broadside though Because people are gonna go and they're gonna look and the Mac which is typically perceived as expensive Right and the PC which is typically perceived as a better value, which is a better value.
Speaker 1: It's hardware and price wise for the stuff, right?
Speaker 1: When they see the $30 OS upgrade on one side and the Windows 7 $200 who knows what it's gonna cost?
Speaker 1: Right, it's gonna look real bad for Windows 7.
Speaker 1: So any money that you know Apple could have potentially made by pricing up to 1/3 the full 130 on the OS upgrade Instead by say basically they're spending $100 per upgrade to basically fire a big old cannonball at Microsoft and Windows 7 It's gonna make them look real bad unless Windows 7 gets really cheap.
Speaker 1: But if they make Windows 7 really cheap That's gonna hurt them a hell of a lot because it cost them a hell a lot of money to make it.
Speaker 0: the other thing I've seen it open up is a lot of speculation as to the eventual release of some sort of Apple netbook and the idea that this is a sort of a test and if people embrace it maybe they'll release a netbook specific version of OS 10 that's really really cheap and maybe release some ultra marked-up hardware.
Speaker 0: That's basically a netbook.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know the thing is it's like on the one hand, right?
Speaker 1: Apple has to play this weird game, right?
Speaker 1: Because the here's the one thing at Apple is that they they have a hole in their product line, right?
Speaker 1: There's the Mac Mini.
Speaker 1: There's the laptops.
Speaker 1: They got the full spread of laptops, right?
Speaker 1: Except the netbook.
Speaker 1: They've got the iMac and they got the Mac Pro.
Speaker 1: They the Mac Pro is the only Mac only Mac that you can open and do stuff inside of right?
Speaker 1: You can't open the iMac.
Speaker 1: You can't really open the Mac Mini, you know, you have a putty knife, right?
Speaker 1: You're not supposed to write.
Speaker 1: The Mac Pro is the only one you're supposed to open right.
Speaker 1: yet There's a big hole and sort of the non ridiculous desktop that you can open right.
Speaker 1: they used to have that.
Speaker 1: remember You know, there was like the g3 towers.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah It was sort of the normal.
Speaker 1: It was just a normal tower computer, but you could open it, right?
Speaker 1: They don't make a tower computer that you can open and muss with.
Speaker 1: that isn't ridiculously expensive Mac.
Speaker 0: Oh, do you need to muss with it though?
Speaker 1: There are a lot of people who would buy that, you know They're though compare I mean compared to the number of people who don't care they I think it's a product that would sell big-time.
Speaker 0: It's I think it would sell big-time Relative to what a lot of other people expect.
Speaker 1: I don't think it would be big enough for them to bother with because there's a Lot of people they want something with like iMac horsepower, but they don't want the built-in monitor.
Speaker 1: They want to use their Dell monitor mouse keyboard.
Speaker 1: They've already got.
Speaker 1: but a Mac Pro is way beyond and many is not enough.
Speaker 1: The high-end Mac Mini is real powerful It is but not enough.
Speaker 1: and you can't like add internal drives to it and it you know.
Speaker 0: But Mac people more and more I see they don't want the internal drive.
Speaker 1: Actually Mac they get the external drive because they have to.
Speaker 0: they don't realize Mac people have jumped ahead to what I see a lot of Linux and Windows people Suddenly realizing works very well.
Speaker 0: You have the hard drive on your PC.
Speaker 0: That is not the storage of everything you have It is just kind of the workspace.
Speaker 0: Well, that was.
Speaker 1: that's why they were selling the time machine and such or the time capsule, but that's his time.
Speaker 0: That's really the way to go.
Speaker 1: if you're a professional it is a good way to go.
Speaker 0: But regardless right the Mac here is a hole in the product line And also, I don't think it's a big enough hole for them to justify filling it.
Speaker 0: It's a hole I know because I think if they leave the hole People who are going to buy a Mac are not going to not buy a Mac in enough numbers for them to care.
Speaker 0: Basically, they're pushing those people the majority of them in one of the two directions Around the sides of the hole and thus economy of scale makes them more money.
Speaker 1: Look how many people would have bought like the size star if it wasn't all bootleg and crappy.
Speaker 0: How many really would have outside of the tinkerers and the nerds?
Speaker 1: I think a lot of people.
Speaker 0: I don't think that many I think A lot anyway, we don't.
Speaker 1: if you look in the past like, you know before they got rid of that product You know some of the best-selling Macs were like that g3 tower a lot more sold a lot more than the regular old iMac.
Speaker 1: You know the first one with the color see.
Speaker 0: but back then the iMac was like it fit a very different role from what it Does now.
Speaker 0: the iMac was like the baby computer.
Speaker 0: baby Mac is a bad-ass piece of.
Speaker 0: like the iMac.
Speaker 0: still.
Speaker 0: the new iMac and the Mac mini are some of the best industrial design I've seen in a while.
Speaker 1: Yeah, too bad.
Speaker 1: It's ridiculously overpriced.
Speaker 0: inside thing is it's almost worth it.
Speaker 1: I mean our Mac Mac mini is only worth it because you want Something in your room with your TV to be quiet and there's no other home theater PCs that are as quiet.
Speaker 1: for a desk free Actual desk, I would never buy any Mac Now that I've used one at work.
Speaker 1: I would never.
Speaker 1: it depends unless the price is way down and such.
Speaker 0: Of course, you know moving into a house.
Speaker 0: My big plan is to have no computer in my room whatsoever.
Speaker 0: That's not caring.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is right.
Speaker 1: my Apple with this hole in their product line, right?
Speaker 1: They sort of had to balance right on the one hand, right?
Speaker 1: They could sort of keep going along their cart route where they make a ton of money selling this overpriced hardware, right?
Speaker 1: And with the huge markups on it, you know, they sell or stick around.
Speaker 1: that's 20 bucks for 100 bucks, right?
Speaker 1: They make shit tons of money over there.
Speaker 1: But as people are going to the netbook they're price-conscious and such and such right and that stops working for them at any point Right.
Speaker 1: what they could do is they could just sell OS X that works on pretty much any computer, right?
Speaker 1: And They can make a whole ton of money just selling copies OS X. you can run any normal computers.
Speaker 1: and then what's Microsoft gonna do?
Speaker 1: No, if you can go and buy, you know, you know Frickin snow leopard for less for a hundred bucks or less and just install it on your PC instead of Windows 7 Who's gonna buy Windows 7?
Speaker 1: I mean I wouldn't because I mean I wouldn't buy the OS X because I've learned that I don't like it at work but pretty much everyone else is gonna.
Speaker 1: just about Who's not gonna?
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm even considering upgrading our tiny little Mac mini as old and slow as it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course part of the reason it's old and slow as we realized recently that that thing still only has 500 12 megabytes of RAM.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and see that's the thing, right?
Speaker 1: That's the reason I was discussing the hole in the product line because like people would buy Copies of OS X on their own to install on their desktops.
Speaker 1: But if that product if that hole in the product line is filled the demand to install OS X on your own desktop Computer really goes away because now Apple has the you know piece of hardware that matches that which they don't have right now.
Speaker 0: So that would.
Speaker 0: that was what you thought was the most the biggest or most Important bit of tech new.
Speaker 0: I think it was an extremely important news that was very overlooked and not covered nearly enough because I think much more important is the fact that Iran may or may not be on the cusp of a student democratic revolution.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that is only partially a tech news.
Speaker 0: This is the thing is it's one.
Speaker 0: I think it is relevant enough to where it is.
Speaker 0: It would deserve mention regardless but we're gonna hold off on discussing anything but the technical aspects of it until next Thursday because by then We'll have a much clearer picture of what happened and where this is going and we'll have a lot more commentary.
Speaker 0: but Technologically this I think is actually a groundbreaking event because the first time we really saw what happened here happen Was during the New Orleans disaster in the United States where the regular news media basically?
Speaker 0: Could not cover a story due to infrastructural problems and due to just slowness of response and all sorts of reasons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they were trying to get you know, like news people in there But like the news people couldn't get there was dangerous and such and such right?
Speaker 1: It's hard to drive or get a car or a helicopter into a place that's flooded.
Speaker 0: but it was the first time where we really relied on citizen journalism and citizen journalism for the most part pulled through him.
Speaker 1: and if you wanted coverage of the nor there was that one dude who had a Webcam pointing out his window at the street and that was the dude.
Speaker 0: Well, it wasn't just him.
Speaker 0: actually a lot of the covered a lot of the people in New Orleans who were Farkers.
Speaker 1: We're just on Fark posting the blow-by-blow and cool I mean that it wasn't just Fark it was all sorts of places that you know had dead internet people Congregated.
Speaker 1: both.
Speaker 0: Park was the primary place partly remember.
Speaker 0: even you know If we want to go a step back earlier during that is Craigslist action a lot of it.
Speaker 0: I would still argue that the bulk of it was on Fark.
Speaker 1: No, that's you.
Speaker 1: I think you're just saying that cuz you're on Fark It was just as much going on and all sorts of other internet places.
Speaker 0: Anyway, while I disagree with you If you look before during the 9/11 attacks when most of the major news sites Basically went down right away due to the load the places that stayed up and disseminated information were slashdot and Fark.
Speaker 0: But we've seen this evolution from 9/11 to New Orleans to now and This is I think the big turning point in kind of what it's not just the media and getting the word out But one.
Speaker 0: this is the time where it wasn't just that we found out about it before the regular news covered.
Speaker 0: it Was that the internet found out about it in depth and knew exactly to a good degree what was going on Before CNN even mentioned like even had a blip about what was going.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean CNN.
Speaker 1: Leo Laporte said that CNN was showing like reruns of some Larry King interviewing some bikers While all these tweets are going down.
Speaker 1: Well,
Speaker 0: the best part was that the thousands and thousands of tweets with the hash CNN fail on Saturday night and Sunday morning Mm-hmm and the rest of the news media really wasn't covering it either and you really would have no idea this was going on Unless you either got lucky Or you happen to be on one of the plate You know happened to be listening to the people on Twitter who talked about it happened to be reading Fark Happened to be reading the Drudge Report.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know this actually This I got to watch.
Speaker 1: this is Daily Show thing Apparently where they interviewed the New York Times and people have been talking about it.
Speaker 1: We got to watch it after the show.
Speaker 1: They said that apparently they went to the New York Times and they were like, so show me something in your newspaper.
Speaker 1: that happened today And there isn't anything.
Speaker 1: it all happened yesterday at the latest, you know, and that's exactly what's going on.
Speaker 1: is you have You know, you've got newspapers and you got 24-hour news networks.
Speaker 1: And even those are too slow now They're so slow.
Speaker 0: think about way back.
Speaker 0: I mean, I think I've told the story on the show a long time ago, but way way back when I played MMOs And I was on the realm the first MMO and I was hanging out in there and You know my family's in the other room watching the news or whatever and some guy comes into the guild hall and says Princess Diana just died in a car accident.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And I was like what.
Speaker 0: and he's like, yeah, seriously I'm like, he must have heard about it on some news.
Speaker 1: That was fast.
Speaker 0: No, he's like.
Speaker 0: I just got home Like he was nearby really so we posed is really nearby.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he says this and everyone starts, you know talking about it in the realm.
Speaker 0: So I go to my parents.
Speaker 0: I'm like, hey Princess Diana just died and they didn't believe me.
Speaker 0: and they're like, what do you mean?
Speaker 0: How could you possibly know that?
Speaker 0: don't stop making stuff up.
Speaker 0: and then like four hours later the news broke.
Speaker 1: No, did they?
Speaker 1: what did they say then?
Speaker 0: they basically the response was how did you know?
Speaker 0: and the explanation of oh one of my guild members told me Guild members, you know online the Harpers right, but This is not a new phenomenon But this is like right now.
Speaker 0: This was the biggest instance of it ever and it's not just the media getting out.
Speaker 0: What I really am interested in is that one the Iranian government as far as we can tell has been doing its best to shut down communications to prevent more information from getting out and also Twitter and SMS are allowing the protesters to form effectively flash mobs and Almost it's almost to the point to where they can react Faster than the reactionary forces can put them down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, definitely because what there is?
Speaker 1: no government?
Speaker 1: I think that's another thing.
Speaker 1: No government on earth, right is Technological as technologically sophisticated as the citizens.
Speaker 1: none zero.
Speaker 1: There is not one that exists.
Speaker 1: not Japan not Korea not nobody.
Speaker 0: It's tricky because North Korea has such a monopoly over what the citizens can get that they can effectively.
Speaker 1: Okay, but I'm saying is there's no government.
Speaker 1: I'm not talking about its citizens per se but just citizens in general.
Speaker 1: You know just people like us.
Speaker 1: there is no government.
Speaker 1: We have more sophisticated technology in this podcast that any government has in the entire world in terms of you know Communications and media and that's not you know, they have better weapons technology, obviously.
Speaker 1: But in terms of this sort of Internet's web technology No government on earth is more powerful than you and me in this room and there are people Even more powerful than us who are not governments, right?
Speaker 0: But I think if this Sparks into the revolution if this is the tide changing in Iran if this is it This could only have happened and I feel dirty saying this because of Twitter now Not necessarily Twitter itself But just flash mobs using SMS and the Internet and whatever technologies they can to Massively and quickly mobilize and react to an emergent situation in a manner That is not just able not just the reaction but a matter of record Everyone in Iran who gets a tweet out saying, you know, I am here Even if the government silences them.
Speaker 0: that message got out and can't be deleted.
Speaker 1: I also think it's it's you know Something's going on because the meta story is as big as the story story.
Speaker 0: I mean this.
Speaker 0: I think this weekend and the next week or so are going to be some of the more like.
Speaker 0: we're living through Very historic times right now.
Speaker 0: Yep, and you can follow it all on Twitter.
Speaker 1: The thing is the only thing you know, the thing that bothers me just a little bit right is you know a lot.
Speaker 1: There's a big push right to have like proxy servers set up for like Iranian people to get out to the Internet's you know And such which is all great.
Speaker 1: It's totally awesome, right?
Speaker 1: We need more proxy servers for people who are trapped behind evil firewalls and such right?
Speaker 1: but right, but First of all, you're setting up all these proxy servers now where?
Speaker 1: where have you been, you know for China?
Speaker 0: I mean there have been enough Scott I do disagree with this point because we discussed this earlier.
Speaker 0: that one unlike China, which is a relatively stable situation and It it's a situation to where one more proxy is not going to immediately make a change and Announcing proxies very openly also makes it very easy to stop them.
Speaker 0: So it's a much slower kind of constant effort.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you announce a proxy on Twitter.
Speaker 0: No, the government's not sophisticated enough to see that They're so stupid, but at the same time it doing like doing it that rapidly for China does not help.
Speaker 0: It's not an emergent situation.
Speaker 0: People aren't dying right now.
Speaker 1: I'm not talking about the tweeting of the proxy servers and talking about the setting up.
Speaker 0: There's a difference between the emerge.
Speaker 1: I mean there are.
Speaker 1: there are proxy servers for Chinese people to use.
Speaker 1: they exist but you know There hasn't been like this, you know, there should have been this huge push for proxy servers a long time ago.
Speaker 1: There's not enough Tor nodes at all.
Speaker 1: We should have been doing this before right?
Speaker 0: I just I still disagree.
Speaker 0: It's it's more the point that there's an emergent situation and that drives people to action because it's right now It's not just I know.
Speaker 1: that is why people are suddenly setting up a bunch.
Speaker 1: Why weren't they setting them up before?
Speaker 1: You know, it's it's sort of like.
Speaker 1: yeah, where were you?
Speaker 1: we were doing this shit like, you know years ago setting up proxies Suddenly.
Speaker 0: now you're interested and I don't think it's that big of a deal.
Speaker 1: All right, and second of all, right, you know, a lot of people are tweeting out.
Speaker 1: You know, the IP is the proxy servers, which is totally great, right?
Speaker 1: You know, we should totally be doing that.
Speaker 1: but if no one in Iran is following you Why are you tweeting out proxy servers?
Speaker 0: Well at the same time just spamming not necessarily What if you I mean depends on the hashtags you're using and certain hashtags for could include all the time.
Speaker 0: I mean, obviously some people are doing it wrong, but you can't hurt.
Speaker 1: No, it can't.
Speaker 0: don't follow anyone on Twitter hardly So.
Speaker 1: that's why I hate.
Speaker 1: that's why it doesn't bother you.
Speaker 0: I don't care if people spam and if someone does spam I just stop following them forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is it's like I'll see us I'll see a some proxy server listings come out from like the Craigslist, you know Craig of Craigslist, right?
Speaker 1: And then I'll see a retweet from like some dude I know who obviously is like, you know, barely any followers and it's like, okay, really?
Speaker 1: You're not helping you just spamming, dude.
Speaker 0: Okay That's the same situation after 9/11 when everyone tried to give blood even though it got to the point to where there was.
Speaker 0: no That's so true because people they they care.
Speaker 0: I mean, these are people who you know all they knew like to feel like they're helping but they're not helping.
Speaker 0: They knew about Iran.
Speaker 0: They did care now.
Speaker 0: It is like it is a I'm not doubting anyone's caring.
Speaker 0: Now it's like air.
Speaker 0: now it's an emergent situation and there are people dying.
Speaker 0: it is now like Like the desire to take action and to be altruistic is overpowering and if you are powerless I'd never begrudge anyone even if they're helping ineffectively if they want to help and they try not begrudging them if they want to help.
Speaker 1: But I'm saying is maybe we need a way to channel these want to help energies in a way that actually helps You know because right now it's like, you know what?
Speaker 1: We've managed to jet.
Speaker 1: it's like we've managed to generate all this electricity.
Speaker 1: We're losing it all as heat You know, we got a. we got to send the wire the right way.
Speaker 0: Maybe just go to the park or follow the right things on Twitter and there are people organizing very massive Units, there are people there are groups of people that all they're doing is gathering every picture They can and getting them all over the world as much as possible.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So if you want to help right don't just sort of do a retweet of something uselessly actually think about what you're doing and Try hard to do something that actually means something.
Speaker 1: if you you know If you're one of these people that actually cares instead of you know Just spamming on Twitter.
Speaker 0: my simple idea my tiny little thing and I see I saw some other people doing something like this Because the symbol of this right now is green like people are wearing green.
Speaker 0: That's kind of the solidarity symbol already.
Speaker 0: Just get all your friends together put on green armbands or something.
Speaker 0: Take a picture and put it out there and hope that Iranians see Americans, you know American kids standing beside them.
Speaker 1: It's that helps more than spamming.
Speaker 0: It's a. I mean it seems so little but imagine someone in Iran seeing people that are nominally You know a country that has always been kind of at odds with them and the youth of that country standing by them Mmm.
Speaker 0: Now it gave me a much more interesting idea.
Speaker 1: You can send them cookies.
Speaker 0: I Like the idea of police are so busy dealing with protests.
Speaker 1: They won't notice our cookies putting together.
Speaker 0: Imagine this What if we made a device and all it does is if you give it power it?
Speaker 0: Creates and a wireless network a y-max as big as it can.
Speaker 1: now we wanted to do this forever.
Speaker 0: But and it also know but I realized the way to make this effective and it'll seek it You know, it'll communicate with any other near nodes nearby any access points anything you can find.
Speaker 0: Maybe it even has a web cracker in it just to be sure.
Speaker 0: And but it should be entirely autonomous, but to it should have to know two inputs for power.
Speaker 0: you know positive negative and it should be able to take just about any power source with the idea that You just drop them batteries.
Speaker 0: No, you drop them over a country Just everywhere and the idea is that all you have to do is steal a car battery Plug this into a car battery and leave it somewhere.
Speaker 1: Well, you could all see his actual batteries, too.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but a car battery is the pretty the most ubiquitous Long-term source of cars everywhere in the world have the same kind of car battery except for stupid Britain.
Speaker 0: Now the plus or minus is the first with their stupid positive ground.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was the worst idea ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, I mean, you know, we've always you know the internet really, you know while the the web on the high level The internet is a mesh and a web and a grid, you know and such right on the art and the infrastructural level The internet is still a hierarchy on one end and then sort of like, you
Speaker 0: know Imagine if we were getting, you know smuggling into a country where there is discontent little nodes that together with simple power that a non-technical person can plug in and get to work would create an unstoppable mesh.
Speaker 1: Well, imagine if the whole internet was that always then no one you wouldn't know would be no point of control for anybody to even Think about blocking it.
Speaker 1: It would just always be that that's a ways out.
Speaker 0: baby steps here.
Speaker 1: Well, if you can do the thing is if you can do what you want to do Then we could just make the whole internet like that.
Speaker 1: Well, we would just sell those nodes at the at the Best Buy.
Speaker 0: Well, we could.
Speaker 0: we could make something like that and sell it and use those Profits to create more that you then airlift over countries like Iran.
Speaker 1: That's not a bad idea.
Speaker 0: The only problem with using my SPs would be so pissed.
Speaker 0: the only real problem other than that is that you'll run afoul of FCC regulations and Latency would be really high so people couldn't game with it.
Speaker 1: Well, when one thing that you would definitely do with it though is you definitely go ipv6 with the multicast You're basically making a new network.
Speaker 0: Well, you would also have the well with ad hoc.
Speaker 0: that becomes much more difficult You.
Speaker 0: the more important thing is to have some sort of store and forward or store and repeat broadcast.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is right.
Speaker 1: any of these things you could load it up with like the full open source package You know, you could have a DNS cache and a and a squid frog.
Speaker 1: you could do the whole setup in there.
Speaker 1: So there would be like almost nothing to stop you from.
Speaker 1: you know, whatever you needed, you know Like let's say it was connect to the internet and someone got some info.
Speaker 1: but now the Internet's out But the note is still there and someone Wi-Fi is to it with their phone.
Speaker 1: They can still see the cache pages because you're just that awesome.
Speaker 1: But
Speaker 0: anyway just watch the situation and watch what's going on on the internet because this this has the potential to be a big turning point in terms of how we Get media and communicate with each other and the fact that I even saw a lot of hints of anonymous Attacking Iranian servers.
Speaker 1: very nice Here if you want to.
Speaker 1: you know, I mean obviously you're not going to Iran.
Speaker 1: So you're you know, unless you're in Iran go you Your odds of actually doing something that's really really meaningful and helpful is pretty low unless you're very rich or something, right?
Speaker 1: So what I think what you can to get the most out of this right?
Speaker 1: What you should do is you should watch closely and see what is done right and what is done wrong So that you can replicate it elsewhere when it is needed.
Speaker 1: That is what you should do.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: You know what I realized, you know that picture that gets circulated periodically.
Speaker 0: It says I forget the exact but if all else fails vote from the rooftops and it's a picture of a sniper rifle.
Speaker 0: Yep, replace the sniper rifle with some sort of y-max device.
Speaker 0: It's a cantata But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: so I didn't actually know this existed and the story is fascinating.
Speaker 0: I'll let you read the fullness of it, but Suffice it to say in the 20s Henry Ford Saw that the cost of rubber in making tires for his cars was pretty high.
Speaker 0: yep, and he decided the best way around this was to create a colony in Brazil and make a factory to mass-produce rubber from rubber plantations Mm-hmm, so he basically tried to make a little Midwestern factory in the rainforests of Brazil didn't work Did it?
Speaker 0: it failed in a catastrophic way?
Speaker 0: That is epic to a degree.
Speaker 0: That is laughable.
Speaker 1: saw that coming.
Speaker 0: There's a quote.
Speaker 0: Let me where was the quote?
Speaker 0: bla bla bla bla.
Speaker 0: I mean there were riots and knife fights.
Speaker 1: Quote in 19 so bad you wish I know cut you some.
Speaker 0: in 1930 the native workers revolted against the managers Many of whom fled into the jungle for a few days until the Brazilian army arrived and the revolt ended Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It did not go very well, but the legacy of Ford Landia lives.
Speaker 0: Okay, and there's a cool NPR thing about it, too.
Speaker 0: I did not know about this.
Speaker 1: is it is the factory?
Speaker 1: did actually anything get built.
Speaker 0: Yes, actually this is still there.
Speaker 0: Ruins of it as far as I can tell other pictures.
Speaker 0: I found a few pictures, right?
Speaker 0: This is pretty neat mmm.
Speaker 0: I don't have a lot else to say other than that Henry Ford You didn't think you're clever plan through and even if it had worked They came up with synthetic rubber pretty much right away after this.
Speaker 1: yeah It's actually sort of interesting.
Speaker 1: just a quick aside is like you look at stuff like Formula One where they're very advanced tire technology and They're always trying out like new materials for the tires, you know and in different mixes of rubbers and all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 1: Are they basically?
Speaker 1: you know, there's a whole lot of trial and error going on But like some of the materials they use are in such ridiculously short supplies.
Speaker 1: So it's like even if they find something great like they might run out and then they'll have to come with something else.
Speaker 0: It's pretty crazy, um, so what do you have for me?
Speaker 1: so After the iPhone, you know, which is probably like the number one way to make money with a little game these days If you want to make a lot of money with a cute little game your best bet right now is probably flash Because you know, there's quite a few companies out there that all they do is make a whole bunch of flash games And they put them on the internet.
Speaker 1: They let them spread around they put ads all over them and they they're making it.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know desktop tower defense was making like five figures a week.
Speaker 0: at one point I heard I played it for a while.
Speaker 0: Remember the forum was all into it.
Speaker 0: We played it like I would be playing it while I was doing the show and congregate.com seems to be doing all right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there doesn't seem like they're doing too poorly.
Speaker 1: so flash games are definitely a way to go.
Speaker 1: the one thing about flash that is the major problem with flash is Not only are the usual problems with the plug-in and you can't search inside of a flash thing and all that business.
Speaker 1: Really do 3d which is gonna die cuz HTML 5 is coming on which is awesome.
Speaker 1: But I'll talk about that some other.
Speaker 0: we got to do a whole show on that.
Speaker 0: Yeah Actually, we should do a whole show on the history of HTML.
Speaker 1: No, so To make anything with flash you need to buy flash right and it's not like say Photoshop.
Speaker 1: We're like, okay sure Photoshop's a bajillion dollars, but there's the gimp, you know, it's like well this flash.
Speaker 1: It's a bajillion dollars.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: You want to make a flash game.
Speaker 1: you got by this.
Speaker 1: it's a lot of money So it's not it's not the greatest.
Speaker 1: Well some guy he went and he He made something called flicks.
Speaker 1: all right and what?
Speaker 1: this is a flash game engine for games That are all pixel styling, right?
Speaker 1: so if you want to make a pixel style in game you get this flicks all thing.
Speaker 1: and then you can get either Flex Builder, which is $250 or you can get flash develop which is free or you can get MX MLC, which is also free and Combined with this download of flicks all that he's got you can make a flash game Without giving any money to Adobe at all.
Speaker 1: zero without any money whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Actually, and you still have to write, you know in the action script and I guess you have to draw your own pixel arts And all that kind of business, but you know It's a. it's a game engine for making flash games without flash and that is pretty freakin useful.
Speaker 1: and I've put a lot of great pixelated flash games like Dino run.
Speaker 0: Oh Dino run I think so.
Speaker 1: You can now make Dino run without paying any money and you can make some bank Go for it.
Speaker 0: the real I mean flash.
Speaker 0: everyone uses it as a game development platform, but it's really a much more generic Development platform, which is really meant for Animations and sort of vector arts and these sorts of things.
Speaker 0: as was noted in our interview with
Speaker 1: video part of it is really sort Of tacked
Speaker 0: on as it was noted in our interview with Alex and Emily, you know with Muse games It's if you're without using a game platform Like it basically doubles and triples the amount of work you have to do to develop a game.
Speaker 0: Yep, so things like this, you know an actual game development platform that itself is based on a more generic platform are the way to go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is like he's actually got like a little tiny engine here a little framework for you to work with.
Speaker 1: So, you know you a lot of the the work of making a pixelated flash game is somewhat done for you And you only have to do your actual game part and then you're good to go.
Speaker 0: So tonight we're gonna talk about a topic that hopefully is not too dry But it's one that's very near and dear to my heart.
Speaker 0: everyone.
Speaker 0: Stop listening I am basically the head of our project to have a universal ticketing system in our company right now But Ticketing is a concept that is one misunderstood by almost everyone Yeah and two.
Speaker 0: I have never in my life seen it implemented in anything that I even call a close facsimile of something even Yeah on a scale of one to ten ten being perfect and zero being poop, right?
Speaker 1: I've never seen anything above like a five and five is some hot shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know, some of the fives are real expensive.
Speaker 1: So just we should talk about a ticketing system.
Speaker 1: right is usually used for support and help desks Right.
Speaker 1: So it's usually like hey, there's somebody sitting at their desk who's I don't know an editor.
Speaker 1: They do some job at the company.
Speaker 1: They sit at a computer all day.
Speaker 1: Who knows right?
Speaker 1: They're not a technical person though, and they have a problem.
Speaker 1: Maybe their Microsoft Word won't open.
Speaker 1: They double click on Microsoft Word and it won't open.
Speaker 1: So they you know if they go and up to the IT office and say hey I got a problem with my computer.
Speaker 1: That's not very good.
Speaker 1: Why is that not good?
Speaker 1: because you know the IT people, you know, they need to be able to manage their time.
Speaker 1: They can't just get up everyone time someone, you know immediately every time someone comes over to the help desk, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they've got to figure out all the problems and sort of prioritize them and pick which people to help first.
Speaker 1: You know, maybe they can just help people by sending them an email, right?
Speaker 0: Well, there's more to it than that - yes even I mean a lot of people.
Speaker 0: The way they manage that is you know Send them an email and you get all these emails in your phone calls and you queue them all up and some sort of human Driven business process.
Speaker 1: It's a lot of extra work.
Speaker 0: Well, then you have the problem where things get lost.
Speaker 0: I mean, alright, I've received two emails today.
Speaker 0: So by the end of the day, I've responded to both of them and fix their problems.
Speaker 0: But then a week later the guy from the second email emails me back saying hey It's not working again, and I've gotten ten more emails and I responded to eight.
Speaker 0: I missed one and I didn't actually respond to the ninth guy Even though I fixed his problem.
Speaker 0: and sudden, you know things email doesn't really help you keep track of that very well at all.
Speaker 1: Which already has red and unread and maybe it has star or flag or something.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: If you're using outlook you at least have all the colored flags.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I live by those really.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just live by the automatic sort into folders bits.
Speaker 1: I don't use the colored flag I use.
Speaker 1: well, I use a kind of use the stars in Gmail though, but I don't use the multicolored stars.
Speaker 1: I just I stopped using those.
Speaker 0: I started using the superstars.
Speaker 1: I just I went back to using the regular star.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you've seen I have like 30 different folders Labels.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I use the labels a lot too.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so Here's already the problem.
Speaker 0: the majority of organizations that I found both small and large Seem to use just email and call that a business process.
Speaker 1: It's not good right.
Speaker 1: you lose in plus you want to document these things that later on you can look and see.
Speaker 1: how good are We at fixing things.
Speaker 1: maybe like someone had the same problem before and you want to look it up Searching your email doesn't help right?
Speaker 1: Maybe there's two tech support guys.
Speaker 1: me and rim rim solved the problem for one guy rims not at work today.
Speaker 1: Now the guy comes to me with the problem.
Speaker 1: I don't know what he did, but the problems in rims email.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know we I solved a problem once.
Speaker 0: so if I have a ticketing system, you know, I categorize it.
Speaker 0: I say ticket number 9009 was this problem and I fixed it by doing this.
Speaker 0: that is now the official solution for that problem.
Speaker 0: So when a thousand people call in with that problem for the next five years The text go blah blah blah, you know, they talk to the person on the phone they type in the description They hit a search that ticket comes up.
Speaker 0: They see the resolution procedure that I already typed in.
Speaker 0: they say, oh, okay They click.
Speaker 0: this was the problem and I solved it.
Speaker 0: They give the person the solution.
Speaker 0: They close the ticket.
Speaker 1: Yep, very easy now.
Speaker 0: so ticketing systems go much further beyond that in terms of what the real purpose is because The idea all you're basically doing is kind of serializing or providing unique Identifiers for things.
Speaker 0: that you have done is that you can find them later.
Speaker 0: It's basically just a relational database and The the ability to have a number a ticket number You know seven and that tracks something from the beginning to the end of a business process.
Speaker 0: That is where the real gold is and that is where most people fail miserably.
Speaker 1: Yep, I mean basically when someone's at their desk and they have a problem right you want them to submit a ticket.
Speaker 1: You don't do anything else, right?
Speaker 1: So as soon as they make that new ticket.
Speaker 1: now you have something like to attach to.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: You can say, you know, it comes into the system.
Speaker 1: You'll based on its severity the right people get notified.
Speaker 1: based on the category the right people get notified, you know You can go to the web page for it or just look at it.
Speaker 1: if you're using some desktop application ticket system You know, you can read what the person wrote in there and since they're typing right?
Speaker 1: You don't have to sit there on the phone while they go blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: They've typed in their whole problem usually poorly but you know, it's something right.
Speaker 1: you can maybe you know You can sort of figure out what the deal is.
Speaker 1: you can you know, you can assign it to someone.
Speaker 1: you can mark It was resolved.
Speaker 1: You can mark it as redundant.
Speaker 1: You can close underestimate.
Speaker 0: I mean assigning to someone.
Speaker 0: that sounds really simple But that like to understand the savings.
Speaker 0: there say problems are coming in.
Speaker 0: So you've got emails and somehow notifications are coming in that they're different problems.
Speaker 0: Say you've got a team of four people who all respond.
Speaker 0: Who responds to what?
Speaker 0: do you have to waste time telling people what you're responding to?
Speaker 1: Yeah, Dean in a fifth person whose job it is to pick who does what?
Speaker 1: I mean, that's that's inefficient.
Speaker 0: I mean, what do you got?
Speaker 0: four people?
Speaker 0: I see an email so I look alright and I start looking at it.
Speaker 0: So I can respond and say yeah, I'm working on this.
Speaker 0: Here's what I found so far.
Speaker 0: I'll follow up later.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, someone else respond saying yeah, I'm looking at this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you definitely get to.
Speaker 1: you can be ability to say okay I think it comes in and you say aha rim knows about this shit.
Speaker 1: you assign it to rim.
Speaker 0: now It's rims responsibility a clever ticketing system.
Speaker 0: So you have categories.
Speaker 0: So there's a category blah blah blah NTP.
Speaker 0: now if someone's someone takes its call and they say oh, this is an NTP problem and they say this is an NTP problem This is an automatically says.
Speaker 0: All right, the only people that know how to fix that are rim and God I'm gonna randomly assign it to either rim or God.
Speaker 1: Think of it this way, right?
Speaker 1: Let's say your job is to fix anyone's computer problems, right worst-case scenario People are basically constantly emailing you calling you and coming up to your office with all their problems.
Speaker 1: That's what a ticket system solves the perfect ticket system.
Speaker 1: What would it be like?
Speaker 0: It would be like right let.
Speaker 1: it would be a lot like you're playing some MMO and you go in and there's all these quests And you have to do all the quests.
Speaker 1: That's your job.
Speaker 1: do every single quest and you can either do them yourself you can you know, maybe they're already done and it's just a suit the quest is stupid or You can say ah rim you do this quest.
Speaker 1: Ah God you do this quest and that's what a ticket system does I like.
Speaker 0: how you never even questioned my likening of myself unto God.
Speaker 1: Well, no, I was saying that you know.
Speaker 1: Actually, I did not interpret that as you likening yourself unto God.
Speaker 0: I did in that I made a subtle linguistic equivalency and I let it stand uncontested.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I thought you just implied that you know, God was sort of hanging out there and I guess he could be knew how to fix computers.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but it gets so much more complex at this night.
Speaker 0: But I mean ticketing in itself is kind of like this overarching category.
Speaker 0: I mean problem management, you know Tracking these resolution of problems through a business process or through developers or whatever Bug tracking which is technically also ticketing.
Speaker 0: but that's you know, I've got a program that Scott's working on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, identify a bug.
Speaker 0: He says alright, I will call that bug number 4008.
Speaker 1: and Tracking and ticketing systems overlap in a lot of ways and if they integrate with each other that in an intelligent way That's actually really you know.
Speaker 0: What I would say is that ticketing is the overarching category because all that is is something.
Speaker 1: bugs are a part of ticketing.
Speaker 1: I think there's.
Speaker 0: I think there are parts of bug tracking that do not Ticketing is is the assigning of unique identifiers to incidents of some kind.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: and then be under that you have all the different kinds of tickets or incidents.
Speaker 0: I mean there there is problem management.
Speaker 0: where you're you're tracking Problem resolution from an end-user standpoint or something like that Which may involve development effort.
Speaker 0: if you run into a bug in software that is bug tracking.
Speaker 0: Sometimes both will be under the ticketing the same ticketing system.
Speaker 0: Sometimes not like a good example is in my company.
Speaker 0: We use one product to track problems and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: But once it gets to the point to where the production support team says we have identified the cause of the problem The customer saw it is this bug in the software.
Speaker 0: We then open a problem ticket with the developers who track this problem as a bug and their own bug tracking software Which follows a different internal business process because bug tracking is very different from problem tracking.
Speaker 0: I mean bug tracking includes all the stuff like identified in release X tentatively fixed.
Speaker 0: in release Y QA confirmed that release Z does not have the problem, you know that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: These libraries are involved.
Speaker 0: these aren't stuff like that stuff that the customer doesn't give one shit about.
Speaker 1: it's all this.
Speaker 1: It's a lot of metadata, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, the primary data is you know, the number the identifier of the ticket.
Speaker 1: You know the text that describes what's going on and you know the status and maybe the assignee.
Speaker 1: But every ticket system, you know, whether it's for bugs or for IT problems or something else and even at different companies there's a whole bunch of extra information as attached to every ticket.
Speaker 1: that and You know which particular fields you need depends on who you are and what you're doing also.
Speaker 1: But that is where all the important stuff that no one gets right is, you know Every ticket system ever used always has like, you know metadata fields that are Unnecessary.
Speaker 1: or the people need a field that's not available Or they need an option for a field that's not available or I feel there's too many option.
Speaker 0: I'm all that up.
Speaker 0: the primary problem with almost every ticketing solution Anyone's ever come up with is that even if they they nominally work pretty well They're never semantically consistent.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they're not you know, perfectly integrated with your exact business process.
Speaker 1: They're always sort of you know, if you get one off the shelf, it's for like this generic business process.
Speaker 1: You either have to adapt your process to the system or hack the system until it matches your business And a lot of people just right out the ass to get one custom-built.
Speaker 0: a lot of people write their own system Which never really ends.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, the problem with writing your own system right is sure.
Speaker 1: It's very tuned for what you do, but unless you really invest a lot into it a lot of work or a lot of money You're not gonna get a lot of these basic features.
Speaker 1: You're gonna have to reinvent the wheel a whole bunch, you know.
Speaker 1: You know features that no other ticket systems off the shelf already have.
Speaker 0: yeah
Speaker 1: And you know to invest that much money and something that is not directly profit generating
Speaker 0: never a revenue generator
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's something that's very difficult for any business to actually do unless it's got money to burn
Speaker 0: And you know just to get to illustrate the complexities, you know bug tracking.
Speaker 0: What about release tracking completely separate thing?
Speaker 0: You know release one five eight contains all these bug fixes.
Speaker 0: It has been signed off on by this QA person in this QA person.
Speaker 0: Now the production team has to sign off on it before we actually roll it out to customers stuff like that.
Speaker 0: What about Change management, which is a separate thing all together.
Speaker 0: What about compliance?
Speaker 0: What about HR processes?
Speaker 0: Like it gets crazy.
Speaker 0: It's not just technology but Every day here's every ticketing system out there.
Speaker 0: It's not just that they're poorly written They're shitty.
Speaker 0: Like they're really bad and they're really really really expensive.
Speaker 0: I mean service desk Express like magic solution Which is basically remedy light Cost tens and tens and tens of thousands of dollars and out of the box does jack all.
Speaker 1: and there's a lot of open source Ones out there.
Speaker 1: They suck - OS ticket is I mean at least at least they're open source.
Speaker 1: So if you hack at them, you can you know Theoretically get them to be what you want them to be over the course of be what you were meant to be.
Speaker 0: I installed about 30 different ticketing systems open and closed source and tried them out and of the open source ones.
Speaker 0: I can say that only three I tied I tried worked if I followed the instructions.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of them out there that are sort of they're like web service ones, you know.
Speaker 1: So it's like someone hosts something and you pay them.
Speaker 0: I don't trust that for shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like base That's the 37 signals base camp, you know company.
Speaker 1: That's what they're up to.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well like gyre It wasn't John.
Speaker 0: I forget which ones which but I try era that's one I hate use.
Speaker 0: I've used Jira I'm gonna tell you right now terrible That was some crap that I tried to install.
Speaker 0: I talked I talked to the support team on the phone when I installed their demo And it just didn't work and I was like it just doesn't work.
Speaker 1: and they were like, yeah Yeah, Jira is not so great.
Speaker 1: The other thing is that like there's a lot of features that are sort of like they should be standard But they're not right.
Speaker 1: like for example Most people in your company right don't are never.
Speaker 1: you're never gonna be able to teach them use the ticket system ever and they don't Need to write.
Speaker 1: all you want them to do is send an email to like help at company.
Speaker 1: You know get help a lot of ticket systems don't have the ability to read to.
Speaker 1: you know Read from the email server and import emails as tickets.
Speaker 1: That's sort of necessary.
Speaker 1: So if you don't have that you're just disqualified right away.
Speaker 0: Do you realize how few ticketing systems have any concept of escalations?
Speaker 0: I know right SLA?
Speaker 1: Yeah, think about this when you call up like a real data center, right?
Speaker 1: They sort of have this escalation system, right?
Speaker 1: Your problem is at this level you get so they assign you to like some low-level support guy Who's gonna take his sweet-ass time?
Speaker 1: Your problem is super serious.
Speaker 1: We're sending you to the knock.
Speaker 0: You go to the Network Escalation say I want to set up to where my boss assigns me something to do.
Speaker 0: You know some instant and it's assigned to me and say I don't update it for a couple of days.
Speaker 0: Based on the priority of this ticket, which is defined in the system.
Speaker 0: Say I want it to email me and remind me after three days.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was a normal priority ticket.
Speaker 0: Do anything.
Speaker 0: now it emails me again and warns me that it's gonna email my manager if I don't do anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah And then it emails my manager.
Speaker 0: and if I don't do anything and my manager doesn't do anything.
Speaker 0: It emails my manager's manager with the pissed-off email.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and also, you know if the if the email is like low priority Maybe it never sends an email.
Speaker 1: But if the email is critical and you don't fix it with like in an hour It starts bothering people because they need to know.
Speaker 1: plus, you know that way like even if I get this critical ticket.
Speaker 1: So I start working on it, but I'm sucking and I'm not able to fix it right away.
Speaker 1: But I'm so concentrated on fixing it that you know No one else sort of realizes that this thing is broken because it was just assigned to me.
Speaker 1: I got an email and I'm working on it.
Speaker 1: After an hour or two this critical thing is still busted.
Speaker 1: other people need to start knowing that I'm you know Failing over here to help me out because it's critical.
Speaker 0: Oh shit Yep, but I mean to go into a lot of specifics would require a lot of shows.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna go into super specifics on any of these.
Speaker 0: one thing I am series, you know.
Speaker 0: I've spent a lot of my professional career working and dealing with ticketing systems at the enterprise level and The conclusions I have come to is that they all suck.
Speaker 0: They're all either expensive in time or expensive in money.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm And I have never in any company ever Seen a ticketing system that was implemented in any good way at all like even bad ticketing systems.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I figure you could get them to a workable state.
Speaker 0: I have never interacted with the ticketing system that worked and every company I have ever seen has the ticketing system that works Kinda, but all the techs kind of know the problems and work around it on their own.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so is anyone out there ever encountered a ticketing system that worked?
Speaker 1: Well, I imagine right that the companies at which see the one thing right is off-the-shelf ticketing systems.
Speaker 1: either a they're built to match the ticketing process at the company that made them or Be the company that made them doesn't actually use any ticketing systems at all.
Speaker 1: They're just making one for what they think, you know for maybe what the employees at that company learned from wherever they worked before You know.
Speaker 1: So it's never gonna match your business and what you need to do is you need to come up Before you even look at the systems right.
Speaker 1: come up with your ideal ticketing process regardless of any system that manages it.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: come up with all the things you'd like to your ticketing system to do just on paper, right and then Go and look for a system.
Speaker 1: You can find one that comes close.
Speaker 1: You can if you can.
Speaker 1: now
Speaker 0: you can't you
Speaker 1: probably can't but if you can Take it and modify it and if you can't I Think it actually is sort of worth the time and money in the long run depending on how much time and money you have You know depending on the size of your company and a lot of other things, you know to just make it.
Speaker 1: And the thing is if you make it and it doesn't suck for your company and it actually matches your business process Then you know even though you wasted a lot of time and money making this thing a Your business helped a great deal in a long run by having the system in place and working and be.
Speaker 1: Maybe you can turn around and sell that and it won't suck and you'll make money that way.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean think about a lot of stuff these days Right a lot of the big things you see.
Speaker 1: I mean, do you remember what was that?
Speaker 1: Flicker came out of this these people that made this game that I played it wasn't even really a game was like a chat room With the shit attached to it and forget what it was called, but it was like this weird thing.
Speaker 1: But flicker came out of that right?
Speaker 1: They didn't go out.
Speaker 1: They didn't seek out to make flicker.
Speaker 1: They made this other thing and flicker came from it.
Speaker 1: Twitter came out while they were making Odeo, right same dudes You know as a whole bunch of stuff these days that mean like look they made unreal.
Speaker 1: But now unreal doesn't make the money.
Speaker 1: the unreal engine makes the money.
Speaker 1: You know the tools you make to do your primary business end up Becoming a primary business in and of themselves.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we've seen this time and time again.
Speaker 1: So it's very very worthwhile.
Speaker 1: if you have a business right that is hopefully successful You should always at work on at least one business tool that you plan to turn into.
Speaker 1: Alright, don't plan to turn it into a product.
Speaker 1: Just make some tool that your business needs make it in-house and make it perfect and then maybe Probably if it's good, it will become its own product.
Speaker 1: on natural
Speaker 0: But in terms of specific ticketing systems, you know I'm sure many of you out there are listening to this because you're tasked with this or you're interacting with this in some way in a company or You're you have some young fawn out of college and you're gonna get into some business soon.
Speaker 0: You're gonna have to deal with this.
Speaker 0: my advice to you is one be somewhat idle compliance ITIL that in your business process because that will save you a lot of headaches.
Speaker 0: and Basically what that means to summarize is that don't just have an urge like a priority of your tickets.
Speaker 0: have a Priority.
Speaker 0: that itself is a matrix of the relationship between two other attributes on a ticket urgency and impact.
Speaker 0: who does this affect and how quickly does it need to be resolved?
Speaker 0: and the priority should be a derivation of those two fields.
Speaker 0: That alone will make your business process much better.
Speaker 1: Yes Email this market high priority, right or it's like?
Speaker 1: I remember someone told the story of how from North America Had a ticket system right and the ticket system didn't have priorities at all.
Speaker 1: So they added right an urgent button.
Speaker 1: right now notice how Newegg has like the rush service button.
Speaker 1: But that rush service button costs like $2 to $3, you know, they're urgent button didn't cost anything.
Speaker 1: You know anyone can make any ticket urgent very quickly.
Speaker 1: Every ticket was urgent every single one.
Speaker 0: Same fundamental problem with QoS if you let end users determine a QoS on a network that you don't control fully.
Speaker 0: Everyone will set the maximum possible priority for all of their packets exactly and then the QoS doesn't exist effectively.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So For priorities on the tickets, you don't want to just set like, you know Urgent critical high medium low, right?
Speaker 1: You're never gonna you know, what you want to have is you want to have like, you know something that's actually Quantifiable right not something subjective that people just you know will be full of themselves and pick critical, right?
Speaker 1: You want to have them be like, all right, how quickly do you need this done?
Speaker 1: Or maybe you don't even pick.
Speaker 1: what will happen if this is not done.
Speaker 0: No, maybe you set up check boxes.
Speaker 0: for example Say you're a stock market II company and you have a bunch of check boxes on the ticket that say You check.
Speaker 0: all the following affects a customer Affects the execution of a trade, you know, there you go.
Speaker 0: Thanks the production system Execution of a trade.
Speaker 1: that's specific to your business and no other business and that's you know.
Speaker 1: That's really the problem is so, you know, so many of these Ticket systems suck ass.
Speaker 0: Well, no all of them suck as so many of these ticketing systems are geared towards solving Technological problems and as opposed to solving generic business process problems.
Speaker 1: or they're so generic That they're not specific enough to handle anything smoothly or they're so specific They only handle one business and no other business in the world.
Speaker 0: The other primary problem is that while the good ticketing systems are very customizable and that's the point It's been a lot of time customized.
Speaker 0: No, it's the fact that the customization interfaces are shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah Oh good god, you're not gonna find a user interface.
Speaker 1: That's not shit.
Speaker 1: What enterprise anything has a good use of your interface and getting system or otherwise?
Speaker 1: Oh my god, nothing But my.
Speaker 0: my other piece of advice to you is that do not conform your business Process to a ticketing system that already exists.
Speaker 0: Yes Conform the ticketing system to your business process and if at any point you find yourself Having to change the way you do business because of the way your ticketing system handles processes change the system.
Speaker 0: Otherwise you're going down a road that does not end anywhere.
Speaker 0: you want to be Mm-hmm, and I'm really hungry.
Speaker 0: So let's just stop right there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's end this.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.