Speaker 0: It's Thursday June 11th.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We're gonna talk about losing stuff But it doesn't really go anywhere.
Speaker 0: I'll be honest Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I realized that I start almost every show with the word so.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I was listening to old episodes to start with the word knit instead or perhaps weave.
Speaker 0: so anyway yesterday was.
Speaker 0: It is rare, you know, usually when I have some sort of task before me some sort of journey I have to take some sort of thing I have to do.
Speaker 0: that requires a lot of coordination has a lot of variables.
Speaker 0: I plan it very meticulously and It always works out.
Speaker 0: Okay, but every now and then you run into the situation where you plan with allowances.
Speaker 1: That's why you were home like not yesterday.
Speaker 0: This is why I didn't get home until like 1045 last night Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: I thought I was mistaken.
Speaker 1: I thought we had to do a show yesterday, but I was wrong.
Speaker 0: No, but then today you're like We don't have to do a show today.
Speaker 0: The last year we did was on Tuesday and today's Thursday.
Speaker 0: So I was in a situation where I allowed for error at each step of the way which we do.
Speaker 0: I mean anytime we're going to a con and the maximum error occurred at each step.
Speaker 0: the maximum possible error occurred at every Possible step of this journey.
Speaker 1: I just get to the point.
Speaker 0: So Here's the task set before rim I had to meet with my lawyer whose office is in White Plains.
Speaker 0: Well actually Technically it is in Tarrytown Directly equidistant between the White Plains train station on the Harlem line and the Tarrytown train station on the Hudson line.
Speaker 1: So you did you.
Speaker 1: obviously you tried to take a train and then a cab or what?
Speaker 0: So beyond that I needed to when I arrived at this lawyer have a cashier's check for some $20,000 Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: No big deal.
Speaker 0: I come into the city.
Speaker 0: I'm like, all right I can't go to the bank in Beacon because it opens it like eight and closes it like four.
Speaker 0: And I think all right, there's got to be a branch in the city.
Speaker 0: I get to work.
Speaker 1: I'm doing stuff around 830 branches in the city.
Speaker 0: The nearest branch is in like Yonkers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz you have a fuck bank.
Speaker 0: Actually.
Speaker 0: I have one of the biggest banks.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it's not in the city not in the city, but it's everywhere out.
Speaker 1: Foreign banks in the city, but not yours.
Speaker 0: So I Look and I see sure enough within a mile of the train station in White Plains and I've been there.
Speaker 0: He's to work over near that area.
Speaker 0: In fact, that's the mall right there where I bought the iMac Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So my bank has a branch there that is open not until 4 but until 7.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so my whole plan comes together.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna leave work at 4 catch the 420 Harlem line train to White Plains.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna take a leisurely walk get some food go to this bank get a cashier's check.
Speaker 0: I assume that there's gonna be trouble and that's gonna take a half hour.
Speaker 1: I would have assumed an hour.
Speaker 0: No as in from the moment.
Speaker 0: I say I would like a cashier's check.
Speaker 0: I expected a half hour of BS.
Speaker 0: Okay, no No, the walk everything was accounted for.
Speaker 0: then I was gonna walk back to the train station pick up one of those cabs.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna take the cab to the lawyer's office.
Speaker 0: I'm either gonna tell the cab to wait cab couldn't find the lawyer's office.
Speaker 0: That was a bad idea or I lined up to have another cab meet me there after I'm done with the lawyer.
Speaker 1: The cab is never gonna know how to get to the lawyer's office.
Speaker 1: You need to get the lawyer to come get you.
Speaker 0: I knew where the lawyers office was.
Speaker 0: I could point them out.
Speaker 0: Like I I drove.
Speaker 0: I drove past that like every day when I used to work over there.
Speaker 0: I knew exactly where all this stuff was.
Speaker 0: I was totally set.
Speaker 0: I Start to go.
Speaker 0: I get on the train I go up.
Speaker 0: I Can't find the bank.
Speaker 0: I realize it's inside of the stop-and-shop and I go in there.
Speaker 0: There it is the bank in the stop-and-shop.
Speaker 1: This is bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's fine.
Speaker 0: So I walk up and I'm like hi I'd like a cashier's check and they're like, oh, yeah for how much?
Speaker 0: and I tell him we go back and forth and then they go when they come back and they're like We're out of cashier's checks.
Speaker 1: real so they could have done it, but they didn't have any.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: you're out of cashier's checks?
Speaker 0: You're a bank.
Speaker 1: you print them.
Speaker 1: They have a printer.
Speaker 0: I was like fine Can I have a certified check?
Speaker 0: I'll just pay the difference.
Speaker 0: They're like, yeah, we're out of those two.
Speaker 0: So after a dumbfounded minute, I asked is there any way I can get this money?
Speaker 0: and they're like, well you could withdraw it.
Speaker 0: You just have to fill out a government form.
Speaker 0: and for a second I considered this till I realized that that's incredibly stupid.
Speaker 0: I did not want to be taking a cab in White Plains and then walking to a train station with $20,000 in hundreds in a briefcase.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a bad idea.
Speaker 0: They offered to give me a briefcase too Really?
Speaker 0: They apologized.
Speaker 0: They were so nice.
Speaker 0: But fuck that bank.
Speaker 1: They'd give you a brief.
Speaker 1: It was a stop-and-shop bank.
Speaker 1: It's not an actual branch.
Speaker 1: It's a convenience brand.
Speaker 0: It was an actual branch.
Speaker 0: really in a stop-and-shop It's a full branch.
Speaker 1: Usually the branches in the stop-and-shop are just convenience branch.
Speaker 0: Actually no, from what I can tell the branches in the stop-and-shops are better than normal branches because they're open a lot later.
Speaker 1: Well, they do have better hours But they're mostly just for people to line up and deposit their checks.
Speaker 0: You realize that At least for good banks if any branch can do all the services of the bank except for very special services.
Speaker 0: So if it says branch you can do what you need to do.
Speaker 0: I could have gone and applied for a mortgage there.
Speaker 0: So after talking to them for a little while and determining that they're useless and they at some point they're like well How about this if we give you a new account and transfer all your money into that?
Speaker 0: Then we can give you starter checks and then you can write a starter check.
Speaker 0: and I was like Do you think the lawyer that is going to take this and give it to another lawyer to put in escrow is going to take A starter check number one for twenty thousand dollars?
Speaker 0: and she was like, yeah, that probably wouldn't work.
Speaker 0: So I was like fine.
Speaker 0: Never mind.
Speaker 0: Fuck it.
Speaker 0: I'll sort this out.
Speaker 0: Later.
Speaker 0: I walked back to the terror town train station.
Speaker 0: All right, I walk up to a cab like art.
Speaker 0: I'll just go to the lawyer.
Speaker 0: Anyway deal with the rest of it.
Speaker 0: I'll wire in the money or something later.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I walk as I walk up to the cabbie.
Speaker 0: I remember the task that I did not complete at the bank because I was so vexed.
Speaker 0: I did not withdraw money.
Speaker 0: No regular money because you see independently.
Speaker 1: Well, this is this is your fault here.
Speaker 0: independently of all this my ATM card, which is also a debit card expired.
Speaker 0: Oh, right has never happened to me in my life.
Speaker 0: So I didn't expect it and I asked my bank and they mailed me a new one.
Speaker 0: They're like, yeah, we had no money for this cab.
Speaker 0: I had I had $33.
Speaker 1: that's enough for the cab.
Speaker 0: All right, but I have no way to get more cash at all.
Speaker 1: after you get to the lawyer You can get some cash.
Speaker 0: Well, I could ask the lawyer to front me some money.
Speaker 1: You're giving a 20,000 he can front.
Speaker 1: he's a lawyer.
Speaker 1: He's got.
Speaker 0: I was giving him money to put into escrow.
Speaker 0: I wasn't giving him money.
Speaker 1: You're gonna give him money also.
Speaker 1: All right, he's Knows you're gonna pay him back.
Speaker 1: And if you don't he knows how to come after you.
Speaker 0: imagine this.
Speaker 0: Here's my $20,000 check to buy this house.
Speaker 0: and yeah, can I borrow 50 bucks to get on the train to take a cab?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm sure the lawyer you being such a good customer should get a car for you.
Speaker 0: No, so I walk up to the cab, you know There's a million cabs lined up and I'm like if you can't take credit and the guy just starts laughing.
Speaker 0: So I was like how much to this address?
Speaker 0: and he's like, where is that?
Speaker 0: So I'm like, I know exactly where it is.
Speaker 0: I tell him he's like 15 bucks.
Speaker 0: All right, so I'm like Okay, I can probably do this mmm-hmm, however, okay, whatever.
Speaker 0: so I get to there the lawyers running late.
Speaker 0: I don't actually talk to him until like 7 which is fine cuz I didn't get there to like 645.
Speaker 1: No, the banks closed now.
Speaker 0: No, it was too late to get money.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I know I'd given up on that.
Speaker 0: I had already resigned Called the lawyer and then went home now because I had to sign the contracts.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I can wire him the money.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm contract was the important part.
Speaker 0: we go over that.
Speaker 0: He's great.
Speaker 0: I might talk to him about our the stuff we need for geek nights, too.
Speaker 0: Cuz he knows some people but he's far away.
Speaker 1: Not really Well, if we got to go see him we're driving.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's actually a really easy drive.
Speaker 0: I only didn't drive because I would have had to pull such shenanigans like drive to Tarrytown in the morning park.
Speaker 0: They're going to the city is an idea.
Speaker 1: Just don't go to work that day.
Speaker 0: I had to go to work because I have important work schedule the shit for another day.
Speaker 0: I had to do it right away For other reasons, so I take care of this.
Speaker 0: I'm all set.
Speaker 0: I leave.
Speaker 0: I Call the number of the cab service that I looked up before I went there.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: No answer.
Speaker 0: So I walk to the Marriott next door and I'm like, alright Can I get a cab and pay for it with a credit card?
Speaker 0: They were like, yeah, probably not.
Speaker 0: I was like fine And I just get a cab and they're like sure.
Speaker 0: they give me a bunch of numbers.
Speaker 0: I call a cab and he's like, yeah 15 bucks.
Speaker 0: How long will it take for you to get here?
Speaker 0: I can pick you up in 45 minutes.
Speaker 0: I look at when the next train is.
Speaker 0: I realized that if he picks me up in 45 minutes I will miss it.
Speaker 0: It will be faster to walk the two and a half miles at the train station than a way for the stupid cab.
Speaker 1: Yeah, oh two and a half miles is not bad.
Speaker 0: So I start walking down a sidewalk-less freeway Completely in the dark in the middle of nowhere across white plains and Tarrytown.
Speaker 0: All right in a suit and wearing dress shoes.
Speaker 0: All right, that was.
Speaker 0: that took a while.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's fun.
Speaker 0: It took me about 40 minutes to walk that partly because of the boots and the resulting blister Also because of the fact that I didn't actually get dinner because I was in a hurry.
Speaker 1: This is a Harlem train that was taking you back to Grand Central.
Speaker 0: No, no, no No, I took the Harlem train up.
Speaker 0: Then I was gonna walk the rest of the way to Tarrytown and take that train home.
Speaker 0: Okay, so I don't walk to that train and then the rest of my trip was fine.
Speaker 0: But you know, it takes an hour to get home from there.
Speaker 1: That was it.
Speaker 0: That was it.
Speaker 0: Nothing crazy happened.
Speaker 0: I ran into some strange people walking to the train station, you know I'm a guy in a suit walking in the dark and People wonder what's up with that?
Speaker 0: So a lot of people pulled their car over and asked me stuff, but no one was willing to give me a ride.
Speaker 1: What do they ask you?
Speaker 0: one guy was like, what are you doing out at night?
Speaker 0: Someone's gonna break your?
Speaker 0: do something something.
Speaker 0: and they drove off in Tarrytown.
Speaker 1: who's gonna break your?
Speaker 1: what it's?
Speaker 0: Terry I was.
Speaker 0: I was actually on the border between Tarrytown and white plains.
Speaker 0: It's fine.
Speaker 1: I don't know who's gonna break anything.
Speaker 0: People basically pulled over and yelled weird stuff at me and kept driving.
Speaker 0: All right, it was weird.
Speaker 0: What can I say?
Speaker 0: why would someone do that?
Speaker 0: I don't know they're weird.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: It was just fail every step of the way.
Speaker 1: That wasn't such fail.
Speaker 1: You mean mid homes?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I succeeded.
Speaker 1: I also I would have driven Yeah, but that introduced extra complications, but it would have helped with the cab situation Yeah, but it would have avoided all that bullshit.
Speaker 1: you probably could have driven to a further away Bank You could have done all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 0: Well one white play you realize the traffic and white planes around that time You basically can't drive.
Speaker 1: No, but you could have you know parked and and got.
Speaker 1: you could have gotten to a place to park that was close and then Walked and you know, nah anyway That's all I got.
Speaker 1: Yeah, is it?
Speaker 1: we're not good to news?
Speaker 1: I don't think there's not.
Speaker 1: all the news is all sorts of tech gaming.
Speaker 0: news For the proper days is all the rhetoric about how the new the drugs are.
Speaker 0: said we're gonna end the war on drugs But then Obama made clear that no that doesn't mean legalize.
Speaker 1: So oh So we'll still keep it illegal, but we'll just stop enforcing make it.
Speaker 0: No, basically we'll make it slightly less illegal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's not stopping the war on drugs
Speaker 0: to a degree because if you stop the quote-unquote war I guess that basically just means stop all the rhetoric stop funding all the programs that don't work like dare and I don't know lower the minimum sentences or get rid of them.
Speaker 1: I Mean, you know every little bit is good.
Speaker 0: But I guess I'm just always disappointed that every time I see news that's like Obama administration does something crazy.
Speaker 0: Awesome, if I read the articles like they basically completely backpedal to almost where they started by the end of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah But who?
Speaker 0: I don't know who to blame more?
Speaker 0: I can't really blame the administration so much as the media for lying to me through headlines yet again.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Well, you know, they got to boil everything down, you know to its simplest, you know, what levels of discourse episode I think we talked about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Let's just get right on with it.
Speaker 1: Okay, so you want to just do things today?
Speaker 0: I think so.
Speaker 0: So then moving right along here Tomorrow is an auspicious day.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you all know that by the time you listen to this The Red Wings will have won the Stanley Cup again.
Speaker 0: who?
Speaker 1: what if they didn't?
Speaker 1: I am so sure that Game sevens are basically a coin toss.
Speaker 0: I am Absolutely.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: I guarantee a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: The Red Wings are going to win.
Speaker 1: It's totally 50/50.
Speaker 0: No, they're not even close.
Speaker 1: So so what if they don't?
Speaker 1: what do you do?
Speaker 0: There's no possibility.
Speaker 1: Well, you have a guarantee which means a guarantee means that if it doesn't happen then you have to somehow.
Speaker 0: Well, you know one I reference the movie Tommy Boy and two it doesn't matter because they're gonna win.
Speaker 0: Ah, the Red Wings are absolutely going to win the Stanley.
Speaker 0: In fact, you can effectively say that they already have won it for 2009.
Speaker 1: Yes My thing today is the Red Wings winning the Stanley Cup in 2008 against the same team The same team which is now You know, which was a young team and is now older and more experienced.
Speaker 1: Then the Red Wings is now.
Speaker 1: They were old last year and experienced.
Speaker 1: now They are just old.
Speaker 1: old but because that's the penguins are only getting it better.
Speaker 1: The Red Wings are only getting it worse.
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: It's a young team versus an old team.
Speaker 1: That's how it is.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 0: Welcome to the world, but the Red Wings are just so good.
Speaker 0: They just keep getting better.
Speaker 1: No, in fact, they're worse than they were last year.
Speaker 1: That's why they're in game seven.
Speaker 1: last year They won well before game seven.
Speaker 0: No, that was just flukes.
Speaker 0: They see I'm gonna say I'm not gonna back this up at all that they pushed it to game seven.
Speaker 1: How many hockey games did you even watch this year?
Speaker 0: To make it more fun?
Speaker 0: Anyway, they're definitely gonna win.
Speaker 0: So my alternate thing of the day is this old NHL.
Speaker 0: I don't know how old it is But it's an animation of the raising of the cup comprised of cup raisings from past Stanley Cup championships.
Speaker 1: Yeah I just want to point out though that ESPN people's think the Penguins are gonna win just so ESPN's wrong because they are.
Speaker 1: they're the what they're because here here is the.
Speaker 1: here's the argument for why the penguins are gonna win.
Speaker 0: I can see one argument.
Speaker 0: they could make the argument.
Speaker 0: That was the same reason why the Red Wings won in 96.
Speaker 1: No Here's the correct argument.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: The Penguins this year beat the Capitals away in game seven.
Speaker 1: They're gonna do the same thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah But I got it down.
Speaker 0: I've read a lot of articles in the past talking about how the Joe Luce arena is Statistically the most inhospitable away team arena there is.
Speaker 1: I don't think it matters.
Speaker 0: I think it does.
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: Anyway, they're gonna win so it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: How could it possibly be more inhospitable than the freakin capitals where every single human being is wearing red and screaming?
Speaker 1: The entire game I point doesn't get more inhospitable than that.
Speaker 0: I point out that the Red Wings Actually used to cheat and their bench for the opposing team was shorter and the door was hard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're no longer cheating.
Speaker 0: So I'm sure they're cheating in some other way.
Speaker 0: Anyway, plus Joe Lewis's fist is right there.
Speaker 1: It's outside where you can't punch you.
Speaker 0: It's right next door.
Speaker 0: Just waiting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you go outside, it'll punch you but it can't punch you while you're ice skating.
Speaker 1: So I was reading on Boing Boing that apparently it's illegal to possess Anything that belongs to an eagle.
Speaker 0: so what I knock off his car.
Speaker 0: What not like?
Speaker 1: if you have an eagle feather you can get in serious trouble like $10,000 fines and worse.
Speaker 1: Right, and that's that's pretty rough.
Speaker 1: Obviously, it's the stop eagle poaching, but I think it has a side effect on oh shit An eagle feather landed in my yard and now I'm in trouble, right?
Speaker 1: Also, it was pretty interesting because people were talking about how like at the veterinary places with it to take care of Eagles They have to take all of these sort of Eagle refuse and send it to this place that the government runs and then if Native Americans want said Eagle refuse like feathers for their kinds of stuff that they need it for.
Speaker 1: Then they have to make like these bureaucratic requests that made that you know are very stringent and can be denied and such.
Speaker 1: So yeah, so anyway in the comments of this post on Boing Boing talking all about owning Eagle bits Someone posted a link to a video and they said this guy's in serious trouble.
Speaker 1: And this guy is some dude and it looks like he has an airport or something in the backyard.
Speaker 1: I can't tell but he had 30 bald eagles in the backyard and His kids were playing with the bald eagles in the backyard.
Speaker 1: and the reason that the Eagles were there was because they attracted them With the red seven.
Speaker 0: Ah, the red salmon would attract me as well.
Speaker 1: Yes, so they had the red salmon and like 30 bald eagles in the backyard and they weren't hunting them They were just having them in the backyard going on my hands.
Speaker 1: Look at that 30 bald eagles and put it on youtubes and such.
Speaker 0: but They're actually not super endangered anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so as I said, it used to be wicked endangered, but because they were protected so much they're only kind of sort of endangered.
Speaker 0: Well, actually there there is a sliding scale and they are a least concern.
Speaker 0: It is the.
Speaker 0: it is the least endangered you can be and still be on the endangered list Exactly.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, they're not like say seagulls or pigeons to where it's like who the fuck cares.
Speaker 1: There's a bajillion of them.
Speaker 1: There's probably too many.
Speaker 1: but they're also not like say Pandas where it's like fuck this five.
Speaker 1: I Think there's more than five pandas, but you know, there's at least seven.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a lot more than that I think but there's still not.
Speaker 1: not a whole lot anyway.
Speaker 1: so 30 bald eagles in the backyard video pretty cool.
Speaker 1: So Today's episode I want to.
Speaker 0: well tonight's tonight's episode.
Speaker 1: You're correct.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: We're going to talk about Losing things because everyone in their life loses things, you know physical things, you know, they they disappear.
Speaker 1: and You know, I lost something recently and it's sort of obvious and inevitable and foreshadowed years in advance.
Speaker 1: Do you know what?
Speaker 0: I lost you lost those expensive sunglasses?
Speaker 0: Absolutely.
Speaker 0: I can't believe it.
Speaker 1: So Uh, so basically I realized not only did I lose them but I have determined scientifically why I lost them.
Speaker 0: All right, I'm curious because I'd I you know, everyone's different about this, but I'm actually I rarely lose things.
Speaker 1: See I used to but I'll tell you my losing history.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So back in the day back Back in the day, right?
Speaker 1: I would lose shit and it was all I would never lose like completely normal shit Like oh I lost a pencil I would always lose the expensive thing, right?
Speaker 1: And the reason was this number one If I had an expensive thing like say a fancy pen, right?
Speaker 1: I'd want to use it a lot.
Speaker 1: So I'd be bringing it all around thus increasing the chances of losing it Multifold right and also because it was such a special thing I would always be you know Treating it precariously and differently from other things putting it in special places and such and such Preteriously?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: That's that's quite an adjective there.
Speaker 1: Yes, and thus Also increasing his chances of being lost, right?
Speaker 1: If I would have just kept it in the pencil box with all the other pencils, it would have been just fine You know, but no I had to put it in a special place.
Speaker 1: So we didn't get all messed up by all those regular pencils in the pencil box.
Speaker 1: Of course it got lost, right?
Speaker 1: I would also often lose watches wristwatches and I'm pretty sure if I still wore wristwatches I would still lose them because Number one right the wristwatch.
Speaker 0: How could you lose it?
Speaker 0: It's on your wrist.
Speaker 1: Okay, so here's the thing Right the wristwatch while you're wearing it.
Speaker 1: It's not a problem and if you get a waterproof one it's even better because you can bring it in the pool and such.
Speaker 1: so it's even.
Speaker 1: you know, you're hardly ever gonna lose it but They're sort of uncomfortable.
Speaker 1: So I never liked.
Speaker 1: actually I liked having them Wet, you know in the days before cell phones so I could tell the time but I never.
Speaker 1: they were never comfortable on my arm.
Speaker 1: I always used to get a Timex You know the kind that had the two big buttons on the front.
Speaker 0: You gotta get the nice one with some sort of leather strap.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I hate more comfortable.
Speaker 1: Even though it's still uncomfortable to me.
Speaker 1: I can't.
Speaker 1: I hate a wristwatch anyway So it was always uncomfortable.
Speaker 1: So for example, I would take it off when I went to bed or take it off for a shower.
Speaker 1: or you know I would take it off and put it on adjusted adjusted, you know such and such.
Speaker 1: maybe if I was like timing something Rather than like poke at the buttons while it was on my wrist I would take it off and hold it in one hand to get more accurate.
Speaker 1: Stop watching activity, right and Because of this constant maneuvering of the watch it was inevitable that I would lose track of it Especially since you know, I might not wear it every day.
Speaker 1: So then it's like you don't remember if you're wearing it or if you're not wearing it or whatnot, right?
Speaker 1: So the sunglasses, right?
Speaker 1: So my whole life I've always bought cheap sunglasses because a I would lose them and B I would break them.
Speaker 1: So I figured hey, I'm better off buying cheap ones.
Speaker 1: That way I can break them and lose them and just buy another one.
Speaker 0: see now that's the opposite of my philosophy Which is buy the best possible and keep them forever.
Speaker 1: and I changed my strategy to that very strategy.
Speaker 1: Yet all the whole time.
Speaker 1: I was still thinking I'm going to fucking lose these things I'm gonna break them.
Speaker 1: who knows what the fuck?
Speaker 1: in fact, actually they were made of plastic as opposed to metal Which is sort of like hey, I paid $200 for these like a plastic instead of metal.
Speaker 1: But actually that's better because it doesn't change in shape like metal ones.
Speaker 0: bend right and then well Well, I mean if you get nice titanium ones, they don't they just bend right back.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: But you know the plastic ones they just stay in the same nice shape.
Speaker 1: and the polarized lenses?
Speaker 1: I was just so much better than the regular lenses and they were more comfortable.
Speaker 1: The only complaint I really had with them is that my hair got caught in them, which is annoying and hurt.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so I was very careful not to lose them.
Speaker 1: But losing them was inevitable and the reason is thus number one Sunglasses don't stay on your face all the time.
Speaker 1: You got to take them off when it's not sunny or if you're inside or who knows what right?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: number two There is not when you take them off.
Speaker 1: There isn't really a secure place to put them right.
Speaker 1: that is consistent.
Speaker 1: Like for example, Mike I used to lose wallets occasionally not too often.
Speaker 1: I've lost I think two wallets, but I wouldn't lose them often because a I would always keep them in the same exact secure place front right pocket.
Speaker 1: It was never in a different place.
Speaker 1: front pocket, of course.
Speaker 1: Whoa Rear pocket fucks up the way you sit.
Speaker 1: I don't know why people put it in the rear pocket.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: I've never understood that because all the pants I have Where the rear pocket is is slightly away from where the tailbone is or where the butt bone is.
Speaker 0: So it doesn't in any way affect how I say.
Speaker 1: it's like sitting on a lump.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 0: it's a pain in the ass pants that it does get in the way.
Speaker 0: I can't deal with.
Speaker 1: no Anyway, I've never used the rear pocket wallet.
Speaker 0: You want to hear something crazy?
Speaker 0: I knew a guy in middle school who wore his keys in his back pocket.
Speaker 1: Whoa Didn't that poke him in the butt?
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I would marvel at this kid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, you know what?
Speaker 1: I would consistently put the wallet in the front right pocket and whenever I sat down at a desk I would take it out and put on the desk.
Speaker 1: But whenever I left the desk I put it back in that front right pocket where it was secure.
Speaker 1: I couldn't fall out.
Speaker 0: Why would you take it out?
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 0: why would you take it out?
Speaker 1: Because when I'm at a desk usually with the computer I might often need the credit card for typing in.
Speaker 0: I only get the wallet out.
Speaker 0: see.
Speaker 1: Also, I hate sitting with a wallet in the pocket.
Speaker 1: It's annoying even in the front pocket.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing.
Speaker 0: the real way to wear a wallet as I've always attested and as I now fortunately with my job get to do all the time if You're wearing a suit jacket or a blazer on the inside pocket put it in the blazer pocket.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't wear those though.
Speaker 1: But when I do I was always.
Speaker 1: I always feel rather dapper when I'm buying something at a store and it looks like you're gonna pull out a gun But then you pull out money, which is far more dangerous.
Speaker 0: not just reaching into the front pocket always feels very dapper.
Speaker 1: Yes, I also enjoy the front pocket, but I do not have the front pocket in my club anyway.
Speaker 1: So the wallet right and the keys and the cell phone are the same situation right.
Speaker 1: I do.
Speaker 1: I always put them in the same secure place I always take them out in the same manner and I always put them back in right.
Speaker 1: so wallet phone keys is a lock.
Speaker 0: see now I think The issue with that it and in one hand creates a situation where you will very likely not ever lose it because you don't know Where it is, it's where you always put it exactly.
Speaker 0: But at the other time if anything disrupts your schedule you are fucked.
Speaker 0: If you like if something happens like your pants get you on fire.
Speaker 0: you will never see any of those things again.
Speaker 0: Even if you get them out of the pants, you're not gonna remember where you put them anyway.
Speaker 1: That so the sunglasses right.
Speaker 1: mistake number one.
Speaker 1: I wore them on.
Speaker 1: yeah two days ago when it was raining I thought it was gonna get sunny.
Speaker 1: So I wore him even though I usually wouldn't have.
Speaker 0: that's another thing.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: the wallet every day no matter what.
Speaker 1: the cell phone iPod no matter what every day.
Speaker 1: the keys no matter what.
Speaker 1: every day Right the sunglasses not every day.
Speaker 0: So what other thing?
Speaker 0: what now that I carry the messenger bag?
Speaker 0: Sunglasses are in there.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 1: Well, you have the clip beyond sunglasses that can go in your bag.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: I thought you did.
Speaker 0: I had those a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I I have very nice custom-made sunglasses.
Speaker 1: How do you get them in the messenger bag though?
Speaker 1: Because like when you fold up the Oakley's right?
Speaker 1: They're sort of blob you list.
Speaker 1: They don't really go in the messenger bag.
Speaker 1: It's like they're gonna get crushed in there.
Speaker 0: I have a metal case.
Speaker 0: That is the exact minimum size and shape to hold these custom sunglasses.
Speaker 1: Oh, see the case.
Speaker 1: the Oakley's coming is a giant blob that is not good for you know Carrying around in a messenger bag.
Speaker 0: Well, it fits in my messenger bag in the slot right next to my DS.
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah, see these do not fit So I think I could not put them in the messenger.
Speaker 0: if I carry them in the messenger bag You know what?
Speaker 0: I can't put in the messenger bag, but books.
Speaker 0: But what I could put would be a Kindle.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I really need a Kindle or the equivalent.
Speaker 1: Yep So anyway, I could not put these in the messenger bag because they are big and blah and they would get crushed.
Speaker 0: Why don't you get a special case for him and then put it on the clippy on the outside of the messenger?
Speaker 1: Well, I was going to say that but I'm going to do now is of course I'm going to buy the expensive sunglasses again.
Speaker 1: You need the bandolier on that bang and then I'm going to invent something which gives me the consistent and secure Storage place.
Speaker 1: Okay, Scott Use that consistent and secure storage place even in the fucking winter that way to create the consistency necessary not to lose them.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem.
Speaker 0: Now you're gonna be out somewhere with the sunglasses on.
Speaker 0: You'll be in a situation where you can't put it back into that exact configuration right then and it suddenly gets dark.
Speaker 0: You'll never see him again.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you'll set him like on top of your car.
Speaker 1: So basically here's what happened.
Speaker 1: right is that this is?
Speaker 1: I sort of have this vague memory, right?
Speaker 1: Which is the problem?
Speaker 1: if I had a clear memory of it, I would have found them.
Speaker 0: But it's always that way if you ever lose anything you can always think back to like.
Speaker 0: well I got home So I had the wallet when I got on the train.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like first of all I couldn't remember if I wore them or not because like I was think I remember thinking in the morning Like should I wear them or shouldn't I wear them?
Speaker 1: and I remember deciding yes, and I also remember deciding though I have two memories.
Speaker 1: They're probably from different days.
Speaker 1: They're both equally valid though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're both equally valid memories.
Speaker 1: It is, you know from different days.
Speaker 1: I don't know which one went with which day But obviously the memory of wearing them went with that day because they weren't still in the case when I got home Unless someone came in the house and stole them out of the case.
Speaker 1: That's not where they were.
Speaker 1: so memory too I have was when I got out of the car at the beacon train station, and it was raining.
Speaker 1: I sort of remember Maybe putting them on my head or maybe putting them down low I don't remember, but they were not anywhere at the beacon train station.
Speaker 1: and then I had another memory of At the Grand Central Station when I got out of the terminal onto the street in the city I remember putting my hood on because it was raining.
Speaker 1: and I remember thinking ah Because putting the hood on when the sunglasses on your head it sucks, right?
Speaker 1: So I have two different memories of that.
Speaker 1: one memory is I'm glad I didn't bring my sunglasses today.
Speaker 1: putting on my head Hood is so comfortable.
Speaker 1: and the other memory I have is uh, why are my sunglasses with the hood?
Speaker 1: I hate this It sucks.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna take my sunglasses off and put them down low somewhere and then I don't remember where they went.
Speaker 1: and then basically from then on the next memory was leaving work where I got up to leave my desk at work and I Examine the desk to make sure didn't leave anything there and there were no sunglasses.
Speaker 0: No, it's like fuck fuck fuck fuck fuck.
Speaker 1: And I was like did I bring them?
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: are they really not around here?
Speaker 0: fuck?
Speaker 1: and then it was like They're gonna be on my up.
Speaker 1: I guess I didn't bring them.
Speaker 1: they're on my desk at home.
Speaker 1: get home not there.
Speaker 1: Fuck again, that's the worst cuz.
Speaker 0: now you're the whole day.
Speaker 0: now You're thinking gotta get home to see.
Speaker 0: if they're there gotta go home to see.
Speaker 1: well It was as I left work at five o'clock the whole day nothing.
Speaker 1: Nah while I was working didn't even think.
Speaker 1: not, you know completely out of mind.
Speaker 0: see at least I read in recent.
Speaker 0: I have not lost anything really at all recently, but I have had a few close calls.
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: I did a send a report to the Grand Central lost and found which is a 60% return rate.
Speaker 1: But you know, that's assuming I love to make Grand Central or the train.
Speaker 0: Yep, and someone didn't just go.
Speaker 1: Hey sunglasses Yeah, I mean if I would have seen those on the street out of it like fuck.
Speaker 1: Yes, like I sort of had this a fantasy of.
Speaker 1: maybe I'll see a homeless guy, right?
Speaker 1: Who's wearing them?
Speaker 1: and they're obviously mine cuz they're custom.
Speaker 1: so I can.
Speaker 1: there's no way that the odds of identical ones are extremely low.
Speaker 1: and I just be like.
Speaker 1: I Imagine that if the homeless guy admitted that they were mine, I would have let him keep them.
Speaker 0: That's very Ultima quest of the Avatar exactly.
Speaker 1: But if he would have been all indignant homeless guy would have gotten a cop and tried to get him back.
Speaker 1: But I don't know what I could have done.
Speaker 1: What kind of recourse is there in that case?
Speaker 1: You could probably I mean I can prove that I bought ones that were that color.
Speaker 1: Cuz I have the I can go get the receipt and they're custom.
Speaker 1: So that's sort of almost Reasonable doubt that those are mine.
Speaker 1: But it's you know, I mean there could sadly very sadly because the way because the guy's homeless I'd probably just get him back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that that's what I was about to say.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well now wouldn't it suck if that guy saved up the money actually bought the exact same custom.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah How do you feel about that?
Speaker 1: The thing is I figured this way right.
Speaker 0: and what if his name was like Sam?
Speaker 0: Robin-stein?
Speaker 1: so No, I just had the polar the default inscription on there because I wasn't gonna pay extra for that film monogram.
Speaker 1: No, but I figure right I'm gonna buy another one if I lose the second pair game over fuck it That's right, cuz you know, but I figure hey worst case I'm back to square one, but I have an extra carrying case and an extra cleaning cloth and You know what?
Speaker 1: I've spent more on less in my life, right?
Speaker 1: I've lost worse Like five $50 time X's.
Speaker 1: that's more money than the one sunglass.
Speaker 0: You know the feeling where you lose something and it's entirely or just you screw something up It's entirely your fault and you can point at the exact monetary damage you cause to yourself.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you have that feeling of.
Speaker 1: but if you but if you if you feel bad over it You're basically just doing more damage.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep, but there's still that feeling and you can't a hundred percent escape it, right?
Speaker 1: But I mean if I lose the second pair, that's it.
Speaker 1: I'm back to the $20 sunglasses.
Speaker 1: We're done, right?
Speaker 1: But I'm gonna get the second pair and I'm also going to invent a way to not lose them.
Speaker 0: You know what I've Only the only time I've ever lost a pair of sunglasses.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is you're a glasses kneading person So it's completely different for you if I needed to wear them not because one clip-ons which I used to use There's no need for that.
Speaker 0: It's just sunglasses.
Speaker 0: It's like putting them on.
Speaker 0: you don't think to use them They're not.
Speaker 0: you know, it's the same deal.
Speaker 0: You don't have a sunglasses instinct separate from the glasses instinct.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean your sunglasses are prescription and you would if you wear them you just hang on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they are, you know There was a time when I use clip-ons instead in which case those are easy to lose.
Speaker 0: But the only time I ever lost them was when I left them in a diner Right when we graduated from our IT.
Speaker 0: I As I walked out I went oh crap my sunglasses.
Speaker 0: I walked back in.
Speaker 0: there was another family there and they they.
Speaker 0: I am so sure that they just took them.
Speaker 1: Oh, I remember this.
Speaker 0: I'm absolutely sure I remember this story.
Speaker 0: We forgot about the waiters like yes, I'm there and the waiters like yes I'm there to the family.
Speaker 0: The family's like we didn't see nothing.
Speaker 1: You should have gotten the police then.
Speaker 0: it wasn't where it did take.
Speaker 0: You know what.
Speaker 0: as much as I enjoy watching the righteously indignant or people of that ilk squirm Especially then you had no money.
Speaker 0: It is so.
Speaker 0: no then I had a decent bit of money.
Speaker 0: Okay, cuz remember I was working at IBM.
Speaker 0: I drove back to our IT to quote-unquote.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I thought this is pre.
Speaker 1: This is the okay.
Speaker 0: No, that was.
Speaker 0: that was when I had so much money.
Speaker 0: I didn't care anymore.
Speaker 0: All right, but The only time I really like I've had a lot of close calls Mostly with keys or wallet was he is a thing right.
Speaker 1: losing something is not the same as a close call And it's not the same as leaving something somewhere.
Speaker 1: like sometimes you might leave something at someone's house or you get something behind.
Speaker 1: It's not the same as losing it right like for example.
Speaker 1: But I've left things in hotels and then later called the hotel and had the mail it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's the same situation because recently when I actually lost something that mattered I lost my keys while I went out for a run.
Speaker 0: Oh shit because there was a hole in my pocket.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: I went for a run.
Speaker 0: I get home.
Speaker 0: I go open the door doors locked.
Speaker 0: I'm like, let me just get my there's a hole in my pocket.
Speaker 0: Ah And I'm thinking I'm picturing my keys.
Speaker 0: and when I'm picturing my keys, I'm thinking keys to my car.
Speaker 0: Well, I got to get a new set of those.
Speaker 0: He's to Emily's car.
Speaker 1: Well Yubikey great, yeah RSA key fuck I Got some more Yubikeys in the in the room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I convinced my coworker to buy one.
Speaker 0: He's loving it.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So what do I do?
Speaker 0: I spend the next hour?
Speaker 0: Retracing my steps in the dark with a flashlight.
Speaker 1: you find them.
Speaker 0: I found them a mile and a half away from the house on the sidewalk.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 0: I was very pleased with that.
Speaker 1: That's not losing though.
Speaker 0: Yeah Losing.
Speaker 0: I almost always have close calls, but it's rare that I lose something.
Speaker 0: that matters Yeah, but the one time I did the one time was in middle school.
Speaker 0: Well, there wasn't middle school.
Speaker 0: No, it was high school.
Speaker 0: It was definitely high school because I have a driver's license.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I was biking and I was wearing my trench coat.
Speaker 0: because I wore my trench coat everywhere.
Speaker 0: Remember I even wore that thing at RIT like all the time along with that cowboy hat yeah, and I used to always keep my keys and wallet in these unsecured.
Speaker 0: Don't zip up front pockets that were like four inches deep.
Speaker 1: You had all those inside pockets.
Speaker 1: They didn't use those.
Speaker 1: use the outside one.
Speaker 0: Well, they were.
Speaker 0: they were inside really, but they didn't have anything securing items in them at all.
Speaker 0: So and you know and I think back it was inevitable that I would have lost anything I ever put in those pockets.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like they're in the fact that I did you put like cans of coke in there and shit.
Speaker 0: I remember proving at RIT when Greg didn't believe me that I could fit an Entire 12-pack of soda in that trench coat with no visible bulges.
Speaker 0: You did and walk not very fast mind you but I could walk.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, why was it?
Speaker 1: I don't understand why that was so unbelievable.
Speaker 1: people store like like three shotguns in a coat.
Speaker 0: Like you remember that video with the kid?
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean, it's like if you can put three shotguns in a coat, you can put six cans of coke in a coat.
Speaker 0: I think it was primarily remember way back when we were all at RIT.
Speaker 0: I think it was.
Speaker 0: I think it was actually very similar or in the same era of when we watched that one episode of Malcolm in the middle with the peeps.
Speaker 1: peeps.
Speaker 0: You can't eat a hundred peeps.
Speaker 0: I lost both my keys and my wallet Keys and wallet both same day.
Speaker 0: they gone gone gone forever.
Speaker 0: and the worst thing is the keys.
Speaker 0: I was really bummed because the keys had a key fob on them.
Speaker 0: That was a pewter dragon pocket watch Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: It was so cool.
Speaker 0: I love that thing.
Speaker 1: It's gone now.
Speaker 0: Yep, and the wallet was well my wallet And that was one, you know, I went home like mom.
Speaker 0: I lost my keys and she's like I was like and my wallet she was like.
Speaker 1: ah Thing is I've lost walls before.
Speaker 1: it's not a real big in people like oh my god I mean, I basically just went to the credit card website disabled the car.
Speaker 1: They sent me a new one.
Speaker 1: It took one click.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 1: see it's much like to the DMV the new driver's license one click.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's so easy.
Speaker 0: back then, you know and up until very recently wallet losing wouldn't have been a big deal.
Speaker 0: But now I would have two credit cards ATM card like for insurance cards car insurance car registration Driver's license my insurance and registration in my car.
Speaker 0: Yes, I also carry my insurance and registration in the wallet.
Speaker 1: I did not.
Speaker 0: everyone else in the world does that at least everyone else in the country?
Speaker 1: I do not.
Speaker 0: New York's all weird with the registration like taped to the window.
Speaker 0: I never got used to that.
Speaker 1: That's how it is in Connecticut.
Speaker 0: I know it's weird.
Speaker 1: And also Connecticut also does a sticker on the license plate that has just the date.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Michigan used to that way.
Speaker 1: cops can see from afar if you're up to date Yep, and actually they mail you that sticker in the mail.
Speaker 0: But most importantly now train ticket because here's here's the situation in the city.
Speaker 0: Lose wallet.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I can't get any money.
Speaker 0: I don't have any money.
Speaker 0: I don't have a train ticket home.
Speaker 0: I've lost the time to buy the train ticket.
Speaker 1: I lost the training one.
Speaker 0: I don't have the ID to give the conductor to pay him later.
Speaker 1: I lost the train ticket once because I bought basically a web ticket which is flimsy ass piece of paper.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I lost it halfway through the.
Speaker 0: what do you do?
Speaker 0: You're about to leave work.
Speaker 0: You don't have your wallet.
Speaker 0: You basically have to go to the conductor and at his mercy be like look I lost my wallet.
Speaker 0: I don't have any collateral to give you.
Speaker 0: I guess I could give you my DS And then you get home.
Speaker 0: you still have to get a new train ticket, yep Train tickets are like cash man.
Speaker 1: That's the thing, right?
Speaker 1: That's why Galaxy Express is.
Speaker 1: I can identify with it so much because the pass the pass ooh the Galaxy Express ticket is such this point of drama and like half the episodes because basically If you don't have it, you can't get on the train.
Speaker 1: Otherwise they kill you this penalty of death right if someone takes your ticket.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: they're on the train and you're not right and like you have to basically get off the train and all these stops and you pretty much have to like hold on to that thing For dear life and people are constantly trying to steal it and it cost a bajillion dollars And such and such.
Speaker 1: and you only have one and it's like oh my gosh.
Speaker 1: And it's like wow, it's exactly the same as all my train tickets and wallets and whatnot, you know.
Speaker 1: And it's so.
Speaker 1: it's just so true.
Speaker 0: Yep But I actually the way I handle this pretty much as I just have a shoebox a really nice one that I put out And I put all my items of note that would be decanted from my pockets when I come home there.
Speaker 0: So I have a spot to put all my change spot to put all my bills and a little thing to put my cell phone.
Speaker 1: I can't on to my desk and then I decant off of the desk.
Speaker 1: So the the desk itself is the.
Speaker 0: well the problem with that is that I need my keys which have my RSA key Whenever I need to do work stuff or log into the VPN and I need the YubiKey.
Speaker 0: So I need these when I'm at the computer pretty often.
Speaker 0: now I need my cell phone around a lot because I'm making a lot of calls.
Speaker 0: No doing this house stuff.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Plus.
Speaker 0: I got to charge the stupid thing.
Speaker 0: I don't have my pre yet.
Speaker 1: with my touchstone You're gonna get the stupid touchstone.
Speaker 0: Probably not I. I'm actually 50/50 right now between the pre and the new iPhone.
Speaker 1: I would wait for the pre roundtable podcast to make a decision.
Speaker 0: Well, I can't buy one until the 30th which is when my contract expires.
Speaker 1: The roundtable should be out in a couple in a day or two.
Speaker 0: So maybe it's even out now, but right now I'm ambivalent one of the other.
Speaker 0: Yep Okay, yeah, I wish I could get.
Speaker 0: I mean I lost my cell phone a bunch of times.
Speaker 0: Never lost a cell phone or an iPod.
Speaker 0: well Kate I remember she lost her cell phone somewhere on RIT's campus in the winter and She came back the next day.
Speaker 0: She's like I lost my cell phone.
Speaker 0: So I just took our landline and had the redial and while I was playing a game I just kept hitting redial while she watered her on RIT's campus and like an hour later She found the phone ringing buried in snow and it was fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was pretty cool.
Speaker 1: But now did you see how Apple actually on the new iPhone?
Speaker 1: Mobile me right if you have mobile me, you can find your iPhone You can delete it or disable it remotely etc.
Speaker 0: It said now the pre should just offer that for free.
Speaker 1: yeah, well, yeah, first of all every phone has to offer that now every phone with the GPS right.
Speaker 1: and Second of all, I think we need to start having a way to like.
Speaker 1: why can't I GPS them sunglasses, right?
Speaker 1: I mean it does.
Speaker 0: You would need to have some sort of GPS device on the sunglasses.
Speaker 1: Well, that's true Howard.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: Also also able also a cell device so it can communicate its location.
Speaker 0: GPS is not to way No, but it could be.
Speaker 1: so we need we should invent what it's sort of like an RFID of GPS Where the device itself has no GPS abilities, but it can be located by a GPS.
Speaker 1: That's looking for it.
Speaker 0: that's not feasible really.
Speaker 0: just by the way the technologies work.
Speaker 0: the best you could do is have a transponder.
Speaker 1: That's why we need to invent it.
Speaker 0: What do you mean invented?
Speaker 0: How are you going to do that?
Speaker 1: Invent something new?
Speaker 0: But Scott, all right, so it's gonna figure out its location with GPS.
Speaker 1: No, it's not figure out its location It's just it has some sort of powerless thing attached to it such that it can be located Electronically by something else.
Speaker 0: Okay, so stop saying GPS.
Speaker 0: that has nothing to do with it.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying I know has nothing to do with GPS, but you know what I'm saying?
Speaker 0: It's called RFID.
Speaker 1: The problem is you would you would have to Imagine the RF it would take to find the sunglasses from space ID on them like burn a hole right through the earth disintegrating the sunglasses.
Speaker 0: I think it is technologically infeasible within the next 15 or 20 years Yeah, I don't know 15 maybe you know sort of some sort of mesh network and then some sort of shizuma device to put in It to power it.
Speaker 1: I'm just you know, it's something to think about for all those inventors out there.
Speaker 1: Yes, wait a way to tag things such that they can be found.
Speaker 1: You know, it doesn't even have to be like find it from space, right?
Speaker 1: It could be like I know I left it maybe at you know I would have maybe either at this train station or the next one or whatever.
Speaker 1: So maybe here's the problem a hundred foot radius.
Speaker 0: Here's why this is so infeasible.
Speaker 0: if it if it has to get its power from the thing that is going to find it you're really stuck with RF or something at the equivalent or Something that has not been invented yet.
Speaker 0: No, you either have to transmit the power to it somehow or it has to already have the power Or it could be like, you know Like what?
Speaker 1: like a metal detector where you can just sort of like detect it just needs to be detectable Scott You know how metal detectors work, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, yeah If you lose something metal About the totes I could have found the $20 plus sunglasses that were made of metal But not the plastic ones.
Speaker 1: Actually, they're not plastic.
Speaker 1: They're made of unobtainium.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually you see that new element.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have a name yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think they should caught.
Speaker 1: they should call it on a nun a nun a nun a millennium.
Speaker 0: I like those names.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same time I like it when you give them a cool name Nubian.
Speaker 1: the thing is you already have rubinium.
Speaker 0: Just make it Nubian.
Speaker 1: So I'm done.
Speaker 1: We're good, we got it.
Speaker 1: You got.
Speaker 1: thanks Jay coverage.
Speaker 1: Notice how they don't have to cost ernium.
Speaker 0: That's common.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm waiting for the you ready for number 500.
Speaker 0: I'm waiting for the next island of stability.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Plus what about a lyrium?
Speaker 0: Uh, but you're not a leer you All right, this is kind of Peter.
Speaker 0: not I don't know.
Speaker 0: we really had to say anything else.
Speaker 1: that has been lost I don't know.
Speaker 1: lost and founds are cool.
Speaker 1: You should make use of them.
Speaker 0: Remember remember way back I lost that.
Speaker 0: basically I had that brazier cell phone forever Mm-hmm, and then I lost it that one day and I called it and a dude answered and then I got my phone back.
Speaker 1: Oh, right.
Speaker 0: Yeah overnighted it to me.
Speaker 1: You find some other dudes.
Speaker 1: blackberry never give it back to him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I kept meaning to like.
Speaker 0: I found like.
Speaker 0: I looked into it I found all the email addresses in it.
Speaker 0: So I just emailed all of them and I was like I found this blackberry and it's this guy's name.
Speaker 0: Tell him and I'll give it to him.
Speaker 0: Here's my contact info.
Speaker 0: No one ever responded.
Speaker 0: Eventually, the blackberry ran out of battery.
Speaker 0: Then I put it in a drawer.
Speaker 0: I forgot about it for like two years.
Speaker 1: Just sell it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I found it later and I was like, whoa too little too late I Don't know.
Speaker 0: I should just turn.
Speaker 0: I just like lose it in Grand Central.
Speaker 0: Yeah donated somewhere.
Speaker 0: I don't know when you work to the hospital.
Speaker 1: Didn't you have the incredibly old-school blackberry?
Speaker 0: No, I had a pager One way.
Speaker 1: but the original blackberry was effectively a pager wasn't it?
Speaker 1: Like you just had some.
Speaker 0: but no I had an alphanumeric pager at the hospital.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I lost that right?
Speaker 0: I lost that like a week after I got there and No one ever paged me anyway, so it didn't matter.
Speaker 0: and when I quit I was like, yeah I lost that pager and they're like, oh you're gonna have to pay for it.
Speaker 0: And I said sure how much and they couldn't figure out how much and they never asked me again.
Speaker 0: Good The thing was worth about five bucks.
Speaker 0: Yep, it took double A's.
Speaker 1: so either I'm gonna have one sunglass that cost twice as much but came with extra accessories or Maybe someone will find it at Grand Central and I'll have to.
Speaker 0: ah That'd be crazy only two at twice the price.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right, this Peter dad.
Speaker 0: I think we're done.
Speaker 1: We're done.
Speaker 0: We'll pick up next week with mocha coverage, which will be a good episode and a crazy episode.
Speaker 1: might it to be extra long?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Monday, there's so much tech news.
Speaker 0: Well, we got some stuff.
Speaker 1: It might just round it up even though I don't wanna.
Speaker 1: No, we got we'll see.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.