Speaker 0: Hey, it's Tuesday October 6th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight late to the party We talked about Castle Crashers on the Xbox.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So rim when we moved into this apartment here this one in Beacon How many keys were given to us upon least signing?
Speaker 0: well two, but there was only one door that had a key, right?
Speaker 1: So it was two keys But they were exactly the same key right up, and there are two of us And it's a pretty bits of house right as a back door in the front door.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it was a weird like back sliding doors.
Speaker 0: You couldn't really lock it from the out of the lock on.
Speaker 1: it didn't really work at all.
Speaker 1: He's a wooden stick the lock.
Speaker 0: that's what you do.
Speaker 0: if you have a sliding door And you don't have a stick you're making a mistake.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so regardless right we got one key for where we live now effectively To this day.
Speaker 0: It's still weird to me like I I remember as a kid.
Speaker 0: You know our house had like four different like every house All these different like exterior doors and every night There was the ritual of like check all the doors and this house.
Speaker 0: like I come downstairs I look at the one door.
Speaker 0: I see it's locked and I just kind of feel like huh Yeah, only one way out.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also You know like even people today who have like a front door and a back door just have one key for both.
Speaker 1: You know they make sure they get the same compatible locks on all the different doors front door back door.
Speaker 0: You know it's cool in Detroit.
Speaker 0: all the houses outside doors Door and the head door on the garage also door directly into the basement from the outside.
Speaker 0: that's old school.
Speaker 1: That's old school anyway, so I'm moving to this apartment.
Speaker 1: You know I didn't actually move in yet I'm gonna move in slow and comfortable like not this big rush of course.
Speaker 1: I realized It's still a pain in the ass It's it.
Speaker 1: I mean I don't have to deal with that day where you carry a shit ton of furniture cuz base.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna get all new furniture Carried anything with that house.
Speaker 0: I'm buying like.
Speaker 0: I'm just so glad that we're not.
Speaker 0: you know We have money and an extra month of rent, it's just so such a luxury yeah, but anyway It's still a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: I guess look at a bunch of shit to do.
Speaker 1: but today.
Speaker 1: I got the keys.
Speaker 1: Guess how it's.
Speaker 1: this is a small apartment, right?
Speaker 1: it's it's bet it's not even the size of just the upstairs of our current place right and It's just one person in one apartment in this in this building.
Speaker 1: Guess how many keys they gave me.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna guess three open exterior door key.
Speaker 0: Interior door key mail trash key.
Speaker 1: all right, so I got here one two three four six different keys Three of which I have doubles for for a total of nine keys.
Speaker 1: nine keys nine keys.
Speaker 0: so boomerangs take those bastards.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, no, there's actually ten ten keys.
Speaker 1: So here the first key is a fanatical devotion to the Pope right.
Speaker 1: so the first key is just this little metal stick And that's used for.
Speaker 1: you know if you get the bathroom or the bedroom blocks.
Speaker 1: You know the interior doors.
Speaker 1: It's like oh shit.
Speaker 1: You locked yourself out of the bedroom.
Speaker 1: Just poke this into the middle.
Speaker 1: you know those locks that just have the time.
Speaker 1: Anything will work in that capacity right even like I usually always use a skewer from the kitchen to open those Usually use a tiny screwdriver, that's the first quote key also good for getting CD roms out that are broken.
Speaker 1: the next key is The key to get into the trash room.
Speaker 1: you see on each floor of the building There is a trash room Which is basically the cement room that you put your trash in and the guy told me all about what trash to do and apparently He says take all the trash and throw it down the incinerator whatever it is.
Speaker 1: I don't know if there's actually an incinerator compactor or whatever is at the bottom, but Willie Walker incinerator right?
Speaker 1: Whatever's at the bottom is is something that takes care of the trash, but Recycling just leave it in the room just on the floor in a bag and also if it's like you know raw food Just leave it on the floor in a bag in that room.
Speaker 1: Don't send it down the trap.
Speaker 1: So the next key is a key to open that trap.
Speaker 1: You know the the incinerator shoot compressor thing Compactor thing the thing is he just says he leaves that thing open But I have the key to open it just in case it gets locked.
Speaker 1: then I got two identical keys to open my mailbox Two identical keys to open the front door of the building two identical keys to open my apartment one key to open that trash room and then another key that I think is Probably the key to open the back door of the building, but I have to test that out.
Speaker 1: Maybe it's a laundry room key?
Speaker 1: I'm not exactly sure.
Speaker 1: I don't remember the laundry room being locked, but regardless is one more key.
Speaker 1: It's the mystery key The mystery key.
Speaker 1: cuz I got to say when we there's a lot of freaking keys here I need like I gotta just split them up and put them on separate key chains like I thought to put the trash key.
Speaker 1: I'm like good by Oscar the grouch.
Speaker 1: You know what you could buy that.
Speaker 0: I know that those are the trash keys because when I was at IBM We had all these PCs And you know we didn't want the users like open them up and messing with it.
Speaker 1: one of those lockers that you put all the Keys in.
Speaker 0: we had a tiny key locker Actually was a gigantic.
Speaker 1: I think I'm just gonna get a key hanging bit and hang the keys But make sure to put key chains on them so you know which are which.
Speaker 0: but the mystery key That's a lot like you know.
Speaker 1: when I moved into I'll put a question mark keychain on that one.
Speaker 1: You know maybe a Riddler keychain.
Speaker 0: We moved from one part of downtown Detroit to another part of downtown Detroit a little less downtown closer to see just put a gun on all your keychain Gun pointed all the doors.
Speaker 0: yeah now But in the basement like one the basement had an uneven floor because I think there was a sub basement that was filled in Mm-hmm, but sub sub basement.
Speaker 0: There was no sub sub basement.
Speaker 0: Oh my god I wonder if anyone will even realize what we're talking about now anyway.
Speaker 0: Why did they?
Speaker 0: why is the acid still there?
Speaker 0: They open it, and they're like don't watch out.
Speaker 0: That's acid and you know it's like Chekhov's acid.
Speaker 1: It's totally check out.
Speaker 1: why leave the acid there?
Speaker 1: Well how did it get there?
Speaker 1: well you put it there?
Speaker 1: And why did they leave it there?
Speaker 1: and why did they leave the hatch open?
Speaker 1: if they if I knew there was ass and I?
Speaker 1: Couldn't get rid of it close the hatch and never open it.
Speaker 0: the hatch was closed asshole open.
Speaker 0: She's like look at that.
Speaker 0: That's acid.
Speaker 1: check it out Close it the fuck up and never open that again.
Speaker 1: Yeah And if he tries to open it again throw him in the acid and close it.
Speaker 0: never open it again if the bones keep coming Up.
Speaker 0: well you got bigger problems.
Speaker 0: I know right anyway.
Speaker 0: So in the basement of that house that had the scary stuff filled in all the heads and crew that I was always Kind of as a kid.
Speaker 0: I always basically assumed that bodies were down there, and that's why it was filled in with cement.
Speaker 0: duh Yeah, but there was this light switch coming out of the ground like I don't like you know one of those two like pipes and it just came out of the ground in like a totally unrelated part of the basement and There was just this switch on it and the wires went down.
Speaker 0: We could never figure out where it went or what it did.
Speaker 1: Why are you speaking about bodies and cement?
Speaker 1: right you know there's that old story.
Speaker 1: the Jimmy Hoffa is in the cement of giant stadium.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the 50-yard line.
Speaker 0: everyone knows that right.
Speaker 1: well Yeah, they're.
Speaker 1: you know next year the new giant stadium is gonna be done.
Speaker 0: They got to move the body.
Speaker 1: obviously they're gonna take the old one apart.
Speaker 1: Maybe they'll find his body.
Speaker 0: You know I would not put the odds that low on them finding a body In there.
Speaker 0: however, I would guess that it is a hobo body.
Speaker 1: hobo body hobo Jimmy Hoffa.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: so another item of small note.
Speaker 1: So I basically spent lunch at work going to the apartment getting the keys whatever But I came back.
Speaker 1: my co-workers my tech co-workers are raving about this thing like a cookie or something Cookie.
Speaker 1: yeah, so they went out again because they were.
Speaker 0: apparently it was so great Because actually as an aside I had the best cupcake.
Speaker 0: what one of the best cupcakes I've ever eaten in my life today.
Speaker 1: Where'd you get it from?
Speaker 0: some co-worker made him?
Speaker 1: Oh, okay?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so You know they're talking about this thing and they're like oh you go back.
Speaker 1: So they wanted to go back to it right so I came back from Astoria.
Speaker 1: We went down you know to this thing and you know what the thing was.
Speaker 1: Well, you know when you're on the street, and you want to get food.
Speaker 1: It's the street meat.
Speaker 1: There was this truck street cupcake the street sweets.
Speaker 0: Was it called street sweets?
Speaker 0: Yes?
Speaker 1: It's this big truck.
Speaker 1: this dude owned it and he in the truck He had an oven in which he baked baked goods like you know brownies and cupcakes Keishas and eclairs and did he have one brownie that was like $100 more than all the other brownies?
Speaker 1: No He had a bunch of brownies so and he had coffee and his whole menus online.
Speaker 1: now this dude Let me tell you this dude knows what the fuck is up right.
Speaker 1: number one.
Speaker 1: his truck was really big and had awesome Graphic design all over it.
Speaker 1: right all his marketing materials have awesome graphic design.
Speaker 1: I have here a card that gets a stamp every time I buy a suite and if I get ten stamps Gain ten pounds.
Speaker 1: I'm on easy Street.
Speaker 1: the next one's on them.
Speaker 1: So I don't know what the next one is but I assume it's one of anything to boot to the head.
Speaker 1: all right He tweets where the truck is.
Speaker 1: so this dude never has to worry about the location location location problem.
Speaker 1: He just drives to the good location right and you know he's at every day.
Speaker 0: the dumpling truck does the same thing.
Speaker 0: they tweet And the only reason I don't follow them is that I'm nowhere near any of the places they go anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is this is a block away from my office.
Speaker 1: today.
Speaker 0: I only get to eat all those cool foods when I'm like at training.
Speaker 0: cuz I'm gonna get training.
Speaker 0: It's like down a wall street or something.
Speaker 1: also the dude was an awesome, dude.
Speaker 1: I think his wife was in the truck too.
Speaker 1: They were totally awesome.
Speaker 1: Basically they have a cool website.
Speaker 1: you get the menu on a PDF.
Speaker 1: their sweets were really sweet And you could tell looking at the truck like I'm really close to inspection how well they've thought this out right.
Speaker 1: they got lights On the outside of the truck on the side of the the you know the window so that he can open the truck at night.
Speaker 1: He took the truck to like Yankee Stadium during a game.
Speaker 1: You know for big It's not stupid.
Speaker 1: he's like a really smart much smarter than the ice-cream men.
Speaker 1: right he's this on the outside of the truck There's a camera like you could tell.
Speaker 1: it's a security camera looking.
Speaker 1: so if you try to rob the street sweets He'll get you right.
Speaker 1: He's got like this whole thing like pimped out to the max, and there's a website.
Speaker 1: the website is Street sweets.
Speaker 1: and why calm.
Speaker 1: and it was wasn't like the greatest brownie entire universe.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I was dying, but it was a damn good chewy brownie much better than any I could make so well worth.
Speaker 1: What did I pay like 250 for this brownie?
Speaker 1: That was kind of big?
Speaker 1: That's not bad not bad at all for getting on the street at street sweets and a stamp Working one thing to the way towards another.
Speaker 0: you know that there's no more beard poppa in Midtown.
Speaker 0: I pretty much I'm stuck with like the melon pie.
Speaker 1: Yeah So I said I recommend following the street sweets on Twitter if you're in New York and you'll know where the street sweets truck is And if it's near you you can go and get a street sweet.
Speaker 1: that day I'm really.
Speaker 1: there's another truck that sometimes is near my work the Jamaican duchy.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna try that.
Speaker 1: It's on my list Jamaican duchy.
Speaker 0: oh yeah that somehow all I can think of is elephant castle apparently get some jerk chicken from him.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, oh shit the jerk store called.
Speaker 0: So you know Scott and I usually like Scott will ever tell me what he's what his stupid news is gonna be.
Speaker 0: that's right.
Speaker 0: But we usually have to at least make sure we're not doing the same news.
Speaker 1: otherwise what the fuck happens in the middle of the Show and you realize I don't have a news.
Speaker 0: I will just note that it is that you can always tell when we're both on the same page about some news or Something or just a zeitgeist of geek nights when we both end up picking the same news.
Speaker 0: So we got to talk about epic Mickey right.
Speaker 1: so the deal here is that you know it basically leaked out because some magazines Got the exclusive wait wait no no no no lee lee Right some magazines we're gonna come out with this.
Speaker 1: But then of course the magazines themselves got on the Internet's before they got to print or whatever.
Speaker 1: so everyone knows Warren Specter who I guess is a famous video game guy.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry.
Speaker 1: I don't know what he made.
Speaker 1: I just know he's a famous video game guy.
Speaker 1: his name is on the Internet's all the time.
Speaker 1: He is somehow involved in making a game called epic Mickey.
Speaker 1: I don't even it's a Wii game exclusive.
Speaker 1: and what this game is all about is you can tell from the imagery.
Speaker 1: It looks totally awesome because it's like this.
Speaker 1: you know it's Mickey Mouse But like a dark evil castle, and it's got all that sort of Kingdom Hearts only even more.
Speaker 1: badass Cuz there's no Square Enix involvement.
Speaker 1: well thing is it's just dark Disney.
Speaker 0: straight up.
Speaker 0: this is the kind of picture where even if you know nothing about it you see this picture and you think Badass.
Speaker 0: I mean Mickey Mouse has the badass posture.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah But you know what it reminds me of a little bit.
Speaker 0: remember that that Mickey game on the NES Which one were you and many versus you.
Speaker 0: we got a fine me.
Speaker 0: And then you like in people try to kidnap or got to go through.
Speaker 0: I forget the exactly what the name of the game was.
Speaker 1: There's quite a few of them I don't remember.
Speaker 1: There is one that I remember that it was I liked and the other ones in the one word like.
Speaker 0: the first level was kind Of a like Icarus a kid Icarus like dungeon style thing.
Speaker 0: and then level two was like a side scroller.
Speaker 0: Level three was a dungeon thing.
Speaker 1: again I don't think I remember one.
Speaker 1: level one was kid Icarus.
Speaker 1: ish But I was never able to beat level one so that game was hard as balls.
Speaker 0: It was great though you fight beat the pirate.
Speaker 0: yeah, Minnie Mouse always get kidnapped by these jerks And you have to save her.
Speaker 1: and yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: It's a good game.
Speaker 1: I'll have to go try it out again.
Speaker 0: on the Emily - that's what I feel when I look at this picture.
Speaker 0: Cuz that game was great, and it was kind of dark and scary in parts.
Speaker 1: this game It looks real dark and scary.
Speaker 1: the thing about this game is - we exclusive game?
Speaker 1: because apparently what the game is about is all These like forgotten disgruntled Disney characters who like got no respect You know and no one even knows about really anymore Who's never wrong but always right who'd never dream of starting a fight.
Speaker 0: you don't remember the Donald Duck song?
Speaker 0: no But they're gonna talk with all the.
Speaker 1: I don't think they're talking about Donald Duck one.
Speaker 1: They're talking about.
Speaker 1: you know Disney characters that no one even knows.
Speaker 1: you know that are from the ancient times That probably in like one or two cartoons if that Are coming back to get revenge on Mickey Mouse for you know being so you know the head of Disney or whatever.
Speaker 1: so The way you play this game apparently is Mickey.
Speaker 1: you're Mickey Mouse or you're helping Mickey.
Speaker 1: Mickey Mouse is clearly made of ink and has a paintbrush And you're using the paintbrush that we mote to paint on the screen and do stuff.
Speaker 1: now the thing is my prediction for this game.
Speaker 1: I don't know for sure.
Speaker 1: I can't pass judgment.
Speaker 0: I can sum it up in one word.
Speaker 1: Okay right here scribble knots yeah, that's pretty much what I'm seeing is that it's one of those games Where you know on paper?
Speaker 1: It's probably got all this stuff going on, but in reality.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be Cuz they know that's my prediction.
Speaker 1: Gonna pass the judgment before playing it.
Speaker 0: But that's it's the problem And I've had this my whole life where you see like a picture for a game.
Speaker 0: or you have the idea like What if you did mother, but and then you have like the twist that makes it awesome And it used to be that no one ever made the game like that.
Speaker 0: So you'd always like how.
Speaker 0: what if they just made tie fighter moves versus?
Speaker 0: and if you're about to say they made x-wing versus tie Fighter fuck you that didn't exist.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was I have no son.
Speaker 0: But then it's like the industry realized that people want the mashup like them.
Speaker 0: the unexpected Usually like take something light.
Speaker 1: you can sell a video game based on style alone without any substance whatsoever.
Speaker 0: If you made a Hello Kitty like I don't know murder game Like some sort of dark.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have to be good.
Speaker 0: I'll put it this way Hello Kitty, right?
Speaker 0: I'll make it I'll make a real good idea.
Speaker 0: It's all Sanrio.
Speaker 0: Hello Kitty styling.
Speaker 0: Hello Kitty is a 1920s era private eye going after the serial killer bottom are Shit, and it's all like black and white, but it's still Sanrio like right.
Speaker 1: It's like if you got people who are experts in say animation or movies or writing, right?
Speaker 1: You can do all those things and put them into a video game and make the video game basically Poop, like just a generic platform or even or a point-and-click adventure or something like that.
Speaker 1: And as long as you have all those other things together Or if you have some like novelty trick like scribble knots does you don't actually need any game substance to get big sales.
Speaker 1: You can have absolutely no game substance whatsoever and get big sales.
Speaker 1: And that's what's happening.
Speaker 1: a lot is this is the lesson that these companies have learned is Don't bother trying to actually make the game like a quality awesome game.
Speaker 1: just have the contest itself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean look Kingdom Hearts.
Speaker 1: I mean in all honesty.
Speaker 1: It's just a walk around and hit things.
Speaker 1: game.
Speaker 1: You know, there's not too much game going on.
Speaker 1: It's generic action.
Speaker 0: Are I the dope-ass Disney train?
Speaker 1: It's an action RPG.
Speaker 1: Not too much novelty not too much, you know innovative gameplay.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's something just a Final Fantasy plus Disney aspects, which you know sell it big time.
Speaker 0: There's something to be said.
Speaker 0: you could have done like.
Speaker 0: you can make an action RPG game like that because and make it good Or different.
Speaker 1: I mean, I mean, it's still a good action RPG, but it's not like say Mario 64 a world-changing game.
Speaker 0: But I'm saying you could.
Speaker 0: it's not NS What is otherwise a fairly standard game using you know tried-and-true game mechanics.
Speaker 0: don't do anything innovative or special But use the mechanic of because you're playing the character and because you're immersed in the game.
Speaker 0: The story as a whole is more immersive than a movie and all that.
Speaker 0: But even gay games that have the good story and the good styling Still just don't pull that off to the point that it's worth it.
Speaker 0: They were still.
Speaker 0: they would have been better off making a movie.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Kingdom Hearts would have been a better movie than a game.
Speaker 0: I'm straight up and I feel this is the same way.
Speaker 0: Why isn't this a movie?
Speaker 0: Why is this that if what?
Speaker 0: if you saw this and it was a movie trailer poster as opposed to a shit?
Speaker 1: It Mickey Mouse movie.
Speaker 1: It's been how long holy shit.
Speaker 1: I would be.
Speaker 1: I would like buy it on DVD.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, but imagine if the movie were this.
Speaker 0: it's the same situation As that that x-men poster.
Speaker 0: that was not anything but a poster.
Speaker 1: No, that's some guy may just cuz you wanted to.
Speaker 0: yes, that needs to be a movie.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that needs to be fucking every x-men comic.
Speaker 0: Yeah my god, but look no, this is just scribble notch.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be the situation where they come up with a concept that they know will sell and they don't have to back it Up, they just have to back it up enough to where the reviews are not bad right away.
Speaker 0: And that's it.
Speaker 0: They make all their money.
Speaker 0: They're done.
Speaker 1: It's the same thing with the Sonic Unleashed.
Speaker 1: Remember that?
Speaker 0: Oh my god Game.
Speaker 1: that was half Sonic the Hedgehog in 3d, but it looks like it's awesome like the old Sonics But the other half of the game is like freakin werewolf.
Speaker 1: Who knows what stretchy werewolf?
Speaker 0: Yeah, like why?
Speaker 1: It's like the game looked like it was gonna be the shit but in reality No, everyone says it's poop even though I never played it.
Speaker 1: So I don't like the difference between chocolate and shit chocolate and shit.
Speaker 0: So I want to talk a little bit about this article about strain gamers and strangers and testosterone.
Speaker 0: But very briefly I would like to point out I had no idea This was even an issue and this is kind of a neat glimpse into the world of hardware hacking.
Speaker 0: But the Game Boy Color boot ROM was a mystery to everyone but Nintendo Until very recently apparently no one actually knew what the firmware was on this chip because the IO Like the the IO pins on the outside were not really interlinked with the control pin.
Speaker 0: So once it booted there was really no way to dump it.
Speaker 0: It's not like it's software.
Speaker 0: there was no interface for it and Usually in the past what people would do is they do something called decafing where all right.
Speaker 0: Just crack the chip open and look at what's connect to what.
Speaker 0: but that didn't help here apparently and there's this cool story of How after ten years they finally dumped it and ten years good god.
Speaker 1: I bought a Game Boy Color.
Speaker 1: the day came out I skipped it.
Speaker 0: I remember I had the Game Boy and the Game Gear and the Game Gear with the screen was just so much better That I basically said fuck you to every portable thing that came soon.
Speaker 1: I basically I didn't have a Game Boy because everyone else had one and I just played theirs.
Speaker 1: and then my brother had a Game Boy Pocket and then I had a job.
Speaker 1: It was like, you know, and I had a job and the Game Boy Color came out.
Speaker 0: So I was like yoink and that was that I got at the Pokemon I looked at the Game Boy Color and then I look back at my Game Gear and I was like what the hell.
Speaker 0: and It wasn't until the Game Boy Advance when suddenly that was a revolution.
Speaker 1: Is the Game Boy Color Sort of got skipped over because the Game Boy Advance came too soon and that blew everything away.
Speaker 0: The Game Boy Advance was just such a transcendent piece of hardware.
Speaker 1: No shit.
Speaker 1: But the Game Boy Color had a lot of games for it that are sort of like, you know Lost like.
Speaker 1: there was Super Mario Brothers Deluxe, which is pretty much the best portable version of Super Mario Brothers one that exists is it straight up?
Speaker 0: and it looks like Mario one is not some rescan or anything.
Speaker 1: There was a later release of Super Mario Brothers period for the GBA on one of those expensive $20 cartridges But Mario Brothers Deluxe actually had all this extra shit in it.
Speaker 1: It even had like the Lost Worlds, you know.
Speaker 1: so it was like totally a sweet deal compared to the you know, straight up re-release of Mario Brothers for the GBA.
Speaker 0: so Aside from the coolness of this one of the ramifications one You can now perfectly Recreate the Game Boy logo and then the cling sound that it makes All right, and -
Speaker 1: couldn't we do that before with regular Game Boy boot ROMs as opposed to Game Boy Color boot ROMs?
Speaker 0: It wasn't the exact same one apparently, uh-huh But - now emulation will be perfect because there were some color things that apparently Couldn't be done perfectly because we didn't know what was in.
Speaker 1: yet I suggest if you're interested and you know, well what games are for the Game Boy Color?
Speaker 1: Go get Zelda Oracle of Agents and Zelda Oracle of Seasons.
Speaker 0: I forget which one I liked.
Speaker 0: I liked one a lot more than the other.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter get both of them And basically it's actually it's two Zelda games or the Zelda games that have probably been least played by human beings.
Speaker 1: You can play one then play the other Then you can take like the passwords from one and put them in the other one and vice versa and it's actually like four Zelda games in one.
Speaker 0: But also if you play it on a Game Boy Advance, there's special stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can play it in a Game Boy Advance.
Speaker 0: And you can buy the Game Boy Advance ring.
Speaker 0: You know what it does?
Speaker 0: Nothing!
Speaker 1: Also Wario 2.
Speaker 1: Wario Land 2.
Speaker 1: One of the best platform games ever.
Speaker 0: Not only that you want to steal from the Forgotten Masters Just steal from Wario 2.
Speaker 1: Tell it totally.
Speaker 0: Bad game.
Speaker 0: Actually all the Wario games were great.
Speaker 1: Wario 2 though is clearly the best Wario.
Speaker 0: 3 was pretty good though.
Speaker 1: Y'all 3 was just sort of more 2 but a little bit less.
Speaker 1: Wario Land 2 is just above and beyond.
Speaker 1: All I got to say about Wario 2 is defeat the giant spearmen.
Speaker 0: But there's this interesting article linked to from Slashdot.
Speaker 0: I'd recommend you read it.
Speaker 0: But the title is gamers are more aggressive to strangers and it's from new scientists.
Speaker 0: But they talk about.
Speaker 0: if you study gamers and people who play games One you get a testosterone rush if you beat someone But only if you beat someone who is either anonymous to you or if you know who they are.
Speaker 0: They're not in your like in-group uh-huh, and There's a lot of speculation as to why.
Speaker 0: and the one obvious speculation is maybe it's like, you know Within a social group you want to kind of have a united front against the outside world and you'll fight Internally for dominance and control and all these things.
Speaker 0: But it's very bad if two lions fight and like they kill each other because then you know They're kind of weakened.
Speaker 0: if a bunch of humans all fight internally It's tough for them to fight the external threats or the humans that are more together.
Speaker 0: But at the same time if you're fighting an external thread, you want to bite their neck and rip it out.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean that's sort of you know, whenever there's like, you know throughout history, right?
Speaker 1: You try to make war with someone you have to label the other guys as the other.
Speaker 1: if you fail to make sure this bad Guys are other then, you know people feel bad killing them.
Speaker 1: They don't wanna.
Speaker 0: but there's a lot of interesting research not just here But about this sort of related thing.
Speaker 0: Like I read an article and we talked about a lot of work actually a couple years ago about how there was a pretty strong link between testosterone levels in the blood and Good performance among stock traders.
Speaker 0: Mmm, and the only Argument like the only link that people could really actually make was that to increase Testosterone tends to cause increased risk-taking behavior and by and large people who have high risk-taking behavior Tend to succeed more often than people who don't.
Speaker 0: however when they fail they fail awesomely.
Speaker 0: Mmm, it's just a really neat article.
Speaker 0: I don't want to talk about it much more because I have to keep this in mind.
Speaker 1: Like if I'm playing a game against a stranger like can say a tournament or something I have to keep in mind to like, you know, like keep them a stranger and be vicious.
Speaker 1: Well, no, it's like.
Speaker 1: should I have to evaluate like do I make riskier moves in the games or not?
Speaker 1: You know, I got to make sure I make the right move to win.
Speaker 0: No, I'm gonna use it more along the lines of when I'm playing against strangers I will expect high risk-taking and I will expect vicious behavior from them and I will play the Conservative play the conservative counter-attack game where you hold back and then you strike.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what I'm thinking also to when I play against friends.
Speaker 0: I have to very pointedly increase the aggression in games Because even you know fighting games like Soul Calibur I don't usually give it my all when we're all playing Soul Calibur and it's not just an excuse like yeah You know, I wasn't really playing a hundred percent, but you really you don't.
Speaker 0: but when you're at like packs And you're playing a game against a stranger.
Speaker 0: You just feel this desire to win.
Speaker 1: Huh, you know, but the thing is like I've noticed that you know, depending on the game You know that we play and depending on the situation like
Speaker 0: depending on the game We're playing
Speaker 1: like something like Mario Tennis like I'm fucking giving it everything, you know, cuz I can't lose it.
Speaker 1: No Mario Tennis.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but like we played Dominion the other day.
Speaker 0: It's just like yeah Dominion, you know Maybe it's the lack of direct attacks or Directed attacks.
Speaker 1: It's I don't know what it is.
Speaker 0: You know, we have to you'd have to study this more and seed You know different game mechanics.
Speaker 0: I don't think they did anything like that.
Speaker 0: I mean look at all the different board games where they're direct attacks versus indirect attacks versus no attacks all that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: I'll bet that plays a big role because I think when there isn't a direct attack Maybe you don't get the surge until you win the game.
Speaker 0: Hmm, but maybe if you play multiple games against strangers you get the surge Mmm, so maybe you let the person win the first round They get the surge and then you take advantage of their increased risk-taking behavior in the second round.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'll be in you know be an interesting way to study this.
Speaker 1: if we we can look at two different sports That would really help us out.
Speaker 1: You can look at tennis and golf the individual sports and you could compare right.
Speaker 1: for example Let's say someone's buddy buddy with say Tiger Woods and he's playing with Tiger Woods.
Speaker 1: You know like on a certain day how they perform in their testosterone levels versus say You know two guys who like are complete strangers playing golf in the same You know foursome or whatever.
Speaker 1: and the same thing with tennis like aha you're playing tennis against a guy You've never met before.
Speaker 1: or you're playing tennis against a guy, you know, you know, you're at a certain match.
Speaker 1: You know and how they how the games go and how the sets go whatever.
Speaker 0: also think about this.
Speaker 0: I mean this specific study.
Speaker 0: there's a surge of testosterone when you win against a stranger.
Speaker 0: There is a drop when you win against a friend Mmm, so maybe you have.
Speaker 0: you have to take into account the surge of winning specifically.
Speaker 0: so maybe games that have Junctures where there's like a scoring ground in the middle like hacienda or you can win a sub game but lose the overall.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz look at like, you know like golf you can win a hole or in tennis You can win a game or a set, you know And that's sort of like a wins.
Speaker 1: you can get your toss toss thrown up during the game.
Speaker 1: But in something like I don't know what's a game where like this is a surprise score at the end Maybe it actually Dominion is sort of surprise score.
Speaker 1: Yes, you know who's winning them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Tikal has that to a degree.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like surprise at the end See who's winning right and there's not any chance during the game to know and get your testosterone up before the end.
Speaker 0: You know, all I can think this whole time is I'll preposter own.
Speaker 0: It's neat.
Speaker 0: but also, you know as an aside I Wonder how this plays into gender stuff too because it's hard to tell how much is actually Physical versus how much is just societal in terms of the clear Differences on average and how girls approach games as opposed to how guys approach games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's and it's really like.
Speaker 0: I don't know how much of it is just cultural versus you know hormonal and I wonder if they See, I don't know if that I didn't read the full study I don't know if they did men and women and all I don't know.
Speaker 1: but as games become more and more Important in our society, you know, not that they've all never been in, you know, not been important But now they're even there.
Speaker 1: it's like they were crazy important and now they're double crazy important and they're gonna be triple crazy important.
Speaker 1: We definitely need a lot more study into these sorts of areas.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean look at the the keynote at PAX that they keep.
Speaker 0: one of the big points was that we're really the first generation For whom there was never a point in our lives where video games did not exist in mass.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean my mom was playing Atari When I was in the.
Speaker 1: you know, the woo she's playing the breakout.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean people who were born like a couple years before me.
Speaker 1: Okay, there was still Atari But we're the couple years before that there was nothing and not only are we the first generation really.
Speaker 0: where you know gaming has always Existed fully in a relatively modern form but gaming is the one of the first new media to appear.
Speaker 1: Man, there are kids who grew up with like ps2 instead of NES.
Speaker 0: I know and I wonder what the future holds for them.
Speaker 1: I'm lack of skills and not knowing where the door charges are in Zelda 1.
Speaker 1: Not being able to beat Megaman 2 so easily Not even coming close to being able to beat Megaman 1. that's what the future holds.
Speaker 0: No Human can beat Megaman not even knowing how to play Donkey Kong.
Speaker 0: thing about this.
Speaker 0: Maybe you'll get to this point to where there are these lost skills.
Speaker 0: Maybe in the far future, they'll be kids.
Speaker 0: They'll find like this relic.
Speaker 1: They'll find like a nice invaders and they'll have no idea how to get past level one.
Speaker 0: They find Megaman.
Speaker 0: They're like.
Speaker 0: you mean Megaman for they're like, no, it just says Megaman.
Speaker 0: There's never been a game without a number before And then it's trying to play it.
Speaker 0: they can't beat it.
Speaker 0: But they finally could be one level find like an old video of some Prehuman like some pre whatever they are, you know, they're coordinators the new types or whatever and they're like that guy's beaten it.
Speaker 0: So things of the day, you know our friends Emily and Alex front row crew people work from use games and they they made a game Elementia and it was pretty good and it didn't really show off though Like what they're capable of is a game studio and nor did it show off the plug-in, you know They're using unity this 3d like game development framework web browser thing and the game didn't really show off What's that cape what that's capable of?
Speaker 0: they have a new game.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much done and they released the trailer for it and I recommend you check this out.
Speaker 0: I'm for a three month development cycle.
Speaker 0: This is a pretty fucking slick game.
Speaker 0: I Yeah, one thing I'll say this game is basically there's the seed of a of a long-term like you could take this and make like The biggest MMO awesome game ever.
Speaker 1: Well, I think a good idea.
Speaker 1: right if they can turn around something like this, right?
Speaker 1: This game is pretty much the shooting and the repairing right and that's it.
Speaker 1: If you can take a game like this Right every three months turn something out in this in this sort of fashion You get some sort of some way.
Speaker 1: combine them all together right, and that's that's where you can actually make some action right.
Speaker 1: look at like Like that Neopets thing isn't it?
Speaker 1: I think isn't Neopets a Scientology thing.
Speaker 0: I don't even remember but There's I believe someone there's some link or like someone bought that I'll look it up.
Speaker 0: You keep talking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, regardless the Neopets I don't even remember like the details of it But it's like they have a bunch of different games in there that you can use to like Upgrade your pets or whatever.
Speaker 1: the how the fuck it works I don't even know but it's basically a collection of unrelated games together Somehow form a thing greater than you know the the sum of the parts and you can make Voltron if you can make a game every three months right.
Speaker 1: that you know is is On this level and you just keep doing it.
Speaker 1: eventually You're gonna have something that is greater than the sum of the parts, you know, as long as you keep it up.
Speaker 0: But check out this trailer.
Speaker 0: It's a game our friends made straight up and it's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So my thing of the day, what was it?
Speaker 0: Good game.
Speaker 0: Here we go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I remember now this dude went to Japan.
Speaker 1: he went to some sort of urban design center.
Speaker 1: It was udck urban design center kashiwa, right and he went there and he was thirsty.
Speaker 1: So he goes to get a drink at this cafe and the cafe has a weird sign out front, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's in like some weird language.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: He goes to the cafe and he goes up and he orders orange juice.
Speaker 1: The lady gives him Something else I forget what and he's like what the hell?
Speaker 1: Apparently, this is a special cafe.
Speaker 1: the specialness of this cafe is you order something and You pay for what you order, but you get what the person before you ordered.
Speaker 1: Huh now the thing right.
Speaker 1: so the next he said he's like, huh?
Speaker 1: He sits down with what he didn't want.
Speaker 1: I don't even remember if he wanted it or not.
Speaker 1: The next person comes up and it's some lady and she orders orange juice and she gets orange juice.
Speaker 1: She's like yay.
Speaker 1: And the thing is you can't go up and order twice in a row.
Speaker 0: That's not allowed right and I'd go in with a friend.
Speaker 1: Yeah Regardless right, you know, there's all these rules so you can't be stupid about it.
Speaker 0: It's a cool idea.
Speaker 0: So what I want to make?
Speaker 0: I want to take this and make a game based on that concept.
Speaker 1: Oh snap So what the dude?
Speaker 1: oh shit you a bidding game would be really good.
Speaker 1: like, you know what the previous order was?
Speaker 1: It's like if you want there to be a big order it's like you have to make a big order pay for it and then like Everyone goes again and it's you and everyone else bidding for what you just or what you just picked.
Speaker 0: There's some there's some magic there.
Speaker 0: We got a figure regardless.
Speaker 1: So the dude's like hey So he goes and he basically orders like a ton of shit like a whole bunch of candy and everything right and then he goes and hides around the corner and the next people come up and they're like, you know, uh soda or something and the lady just starts giving him all this stuff and the tooth the lady and her kid who came up and got all this free stuff for like Whoever ordered this.
Speaker 0: Oh my gosh Think about this.
Speaker 0: look at he was driven.
Speaker 0: There's some mechanism design there.
Speaker 0: He was driven to buy all this stuff He normally wouldn't have bought.
Speaker 0: he wouldn't have just bought this stuff for a stranger randomly.
Speaker 0: But because there was this little game this little mechanism design He got this at a strange utility of buying more stuff and the store probably sells a lot more than they would if they were Just like a normal shop.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it would be.
Speaker 1: you know, I don't know how this kind of cafe would work in the United States Somewhere but it's definitely it feels like a Japanese thing.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of thing you gotta put at like if you've got us.
Speaker 0: if you're at a college and you have like a student fair Or something.
Speaker 0: that is what you need to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a good place for it.
Speaker 1: But yeah, cool idea cool pictures cool cafe, Japan Japan.
Speaker 1: Okay, so the meta minute.
Speaker 1: metamoment the metamucil.
Speaker 1: we don't want to forget the metamoment.
Speaker 1: So the ad contest.
Speaker 1: we have received zero submissions since we have started doing the metamoment So it's completely useless to keep announcing it regardless.
Speaker 1: I've decided just end it and pick a winner.
Speaker 0: pick a winner.
Speaker 1: I have picked pretty much the entry.
Speaker 1: That was the most polished and photoshopped.
Speaker 1: Clearly someone has Photoshop skills.
Speaker 1: So they are the winner.
Speaker 1: the winner is the forum name Particulates.
Speaker 1: I found out through five minutes of research.
Speaker 1: you ready for this.
Speaker 0: I'm ready.
Speaker 1: I didn't realize this when I picked the winner.
Speaker 1: The guy's name is Chase Gordon.
Speaker 1: I think he's the dude who does that comic in which there was the old Rochester whiskey.
Speaker 0: Oh, where we?
Speaker 1: oh, yes, so the creator of Rim and Scott's old Rochester whiskey is now the proud owner of six volumes of the Akira manga Which is the whole thing.
Speaker 1: I will mail you these six volumes when a you send me your address and B. I'm done moving
Speaker 0: Which is
Speaker 1: probably a month from now But I promise I will send them because I already have them and I have plenty of boxes in which to mail them And I will be living much closer to a post office And we'll have much easier access to it and more time in the day to go to it.
Speaker 1: So Will you?
Speaker 1: really?
Speaker 1: definitely there's a post office like right down the street from here I know so I go to it off an X out.
Speaker 1: I mailed out all those things to sold on Amazon.
Speaker 0: So you're gonna be living closer to one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's one like right next door in Queens.
Speaker 1: I'm not.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure there's one very close regardless.
Speaker 1: I will definitely mail these to you.
Speaker 1: So particulates chase Gordon dude with the awesome comic who you know with the rim and Scott joke Email us geek nights at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm.
Speaker 0: with your mailing address You realize we're gonna get at least won't like five emails from other people saying no because he has his domain for his webcomic.
Speaker 1: I'll pimp him out.
Speaker 1: I think it's like release.
Speaker 1: you go to Google and search for particulates comic and you'll find his comic.
Speaker 1: I hope you'll find his comic and So I'll know because his email address will hopefully be like at particulates something calm.
Speaker 1: so I'll know it's him.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, dude you won the contest.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna start after I'm done moving buying ads with your ad and also You know sending you manga.
Speaker 1: So awesome awesome for you, dude.
Speaker 1: You're awesome.
Speaker 0: So I got another aside.
Speaker 0: I want to talk a little bit a tiny bit about Kinetic on and I want to talk about it on a Tuesday because you know, we're the heads of panels for Kinetic on.
Speaker 0: now It's kind of a generic on like, you know anime and game any kind is not an anime con or a gaming con.
Speaker 1: It's an all geek God.
Speaker 1: Yes, but it's geeky.
Speaker 1: We got it and we're really up in the geekiness.
Speaker 0: You know, there's a lot of anime content added and there's also a lot of webcomic.
Speaker 0: I mean really really really want to have a lot more gaming content and a lot more Unrelated to any of this content like crazy stuff.
Speaker 1: want to get some tech in there if we can.
Speaker 0: so I mentioned it.
Speaker 0: You know, it's in Hartford, Connecticut.
Speaker 0: It's going to be next summer probably near the end of summer.
Speaker 0: We don't have all the details on that yet.
Speaker 0: what I want to say is that if you have a gaming related panel and youth or you want to give a lecture or you have a cool idea for what we should do in a Panel room before between one and five hundred people in the room, you know, the con is like six or seven thousand people.
Speaker 0: Email us geek nights the front row crew calm and you know Talk to me.
Speaker 0: one of us will respond.
Speaker 0: and we're doing the kind of pre.
Speaker 0: We're feeling out all the super awesome people and trying to get all the super awesome people scheduled before we open it up to the masses.
Speaker 1: So send us your sort of quirky ideas, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz we've got stuff on here.
Speaker 1: We got like parkour We got belly dancing the sci-fi stuff going on Right, so if you've got something that's really really clever or something that would just be like, yeah, totally awesome You know, let us know.
Speaker 0: even if you don't think you can't run it you live in like Albion or something.
Speaker 0: Just you know, tell us your cool idea and we if we can we'll do it.
Speaker 0: We're it.
Speaker 0: the buck stops at us.
Speaker 1: We'll try to find someone else who can do it.
Speaker 0: Maybe do I mean if the panels there aren't awesome It's our fault and we'll just blame you.
Speaker 1: So yeah Passing the buck.
Speaker 0: All right, so I bought an Xbox.
Speaker 1: I bought an Xbox 360. now.
Speaker 1: The reason that we did not buy an Xbox 360 for the longest time is a few reasons.
Speaker 1: number one it cost money Numbers not a reason.
Speaker 0: number two.
Speaker 1: I was under the impression that really without an HDTV It wasn't worth it, which is sort of true in a little bit.
Speaker 1: which right?
Speaker 1: reason.
Speaker 1: number three I already have more video games than I have time to play.
Speaker 1: I have a pile of unbeaten video games, right?
Speaker 1: So why would I buy a console to get more video games that I have time to play?
Speaker 1: Well, I bought one.
Speaker 1: finally and here's the reasons why I bought one number one I'm getting HDTV because I'm moving and a big TV isn't gonna really fit.
Speaker 1: so I gotta buy a flat one and Flat one's gonna be HD.
Speaker 1: So there you go.
Speaker 1: Number two the price dropped like a rock.
Speaker 1: I was able to get the elite the elite 360 the greatest one with the biggest hard drive the you know It's black.
Speaker 1: It's amazing for the price of $300.
Speaker 1: but there was a $50 mail-in rebate $250 for an elite Xbox 360, how about that?
Speaker 1: That's the same price I paid for the Wii on launch day and this is for the elite not for the regular or the premium Or whatever.
Speaker 1: so hells.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm gonna pay that.
Speaker 1: Reason number three.
Speaker 1: I already had these Xbox 360 controllers and wireless headsets that I was using with my PC for some PC gaming.
Speaker 1: So I didn't have to buy any extra controllers or headsets for the 360 really.
Speaker 1: so You know, it was a total, you know, I already paid for these controllers.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna get more use out of them.
Speaker 1: So it's actually enhancing the value of things I already owned by buying the 360.
Speaker 1: So I bought one and the things I realized when I got it were you know I I thought that you know over these years I kept seeing all these news is about all these great like Xbox Live arcade games and I always wanted some of them that they were just like these awesome indie games.
Speaker 1: Now that I've got it.
Speaker 1: There's a lot fewer of those that I Remember.
Speaker 1: they're being over the years.
Speaker 1: I remember seeing news about over the years.
Speaker 1: I thought they wanted to be like so many.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't know what to do with but really there aren't.
Speaker 1: and the thing is I look at the list of 360 games out there that are I want and A lot of them are games.
Speaker 1: I already have on Steam.
Speaker 1: like the braid game already got it on Steam.
Speaker 1: You know all the valve games got him on Steam and you know what.
Speaker 1: if a new game comes out and it's available on Steam And on the 360, I'm gonna pick it on Steam before I pick it on the 360.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean it depends actually on the kind of game.
Speaker 1: if it's a game I'm gonna play with the controller.
Speaker 1: I might pick the 360 version.
Speaker 0: I guess what really bothers me about that?
Speaker 0: It's a mouse keyboard game.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna pick the PC, you know, we're playing Castle Crashers, which we're gonna talk about in a second and There's no reason it shouldn't just be on the PC.
Speaker 0: There's no reason at all for it to be a console only game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's no reason for it to be 360 exclusive.
Speaker 1: I mean the guys who made it who have the source code could probably just push a button and Spit out a PC version that would run on Steam, but they didn't.
Speaker 1: so there you have it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the two games that I've got are occupying my time our shadow complex Which I'll talk about in the future needless to say by that game.
Speaker 1: It's it's totally awesome and worth every dollar.
Speaker 1: And the other game is Castle Crashers Which we have both been playing which is why we can do a show on it because he both been playing it Whereas I've been the only one playing shadow complex.
Speaker 1: Yep So Castle Crashers Castle Crashers is River City Ransom plus Ninja Turtles 2.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: it's a little bit of Final Fight.
Speaker 1: There's a little bit of Final Fight Streets of Rage, but not much.
Speaker 1: You know what it has awesome music like Streets of Rage what it also has a lot of and as choose your character Pirate baby cabana battle.
Speaker 1: it has some of that going on - it has Playing.
Speaker 0: it feels like watching pirate baby cabana battle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically it's a side-scrolling beat-em-up game that has leveling up and money like River City Ransom does.
Speaker 1: it's got totally awesome styling and character like River City Ransom and You know Pirate baby cabana battle do.
Speaker 1: it has awesome music like Streets of Rage.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, the music in this game is some of the best music I've heard in a game in a long time.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: But the thing is the actual play of the game like, you know The parts you're standing on an animal.
Speaker 1: the part where there's an elevator the part, right?
Speaker 0: Where the other literally get on this platform, I think it's in the.
Speaker 0: we keep calling it the techno palace But it's the industrial castle right where it's just totally teams with Ninja Turtles.
Speaker 1: It's Ninja Turtles the arcade game and there's there's also parts where it's golden axe.
Speaker 1: also, you know Like the thieves are stealing stuff, you know as golden axe straight up.
Speaker 0: So rarely has a game so well stolen from the Forgotten Masters.
Speaker 1: Oh indeed indeed I mean really I mean this.
Speaker 1: it's not really like there's nothing this game does.
Speaker 1: it's incredibly innovative Exciting and really it's just a straight-up walk sideways beat him up.
Speaker 0: It's not like a highbrow game I mean, it's got a good set of combos, but pretty rapidly You'll min-max it and I've got like.
Speaker 1: I put all my points into magic and defense.
Speaker 0: I put all mine into strength and agility.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have infinite air combos that just kill anyone.
Speaker 1: I just stand there casting like magic splash attacks that hit every bad guy and do a ton of damage to all of them and then poison them and continue to damage them over time even if I dodge them and then My defense makes it some really hard to kill except for really dangerous bosses.
Speaker 1: But yeah, this game just steal it's.
Speaker 1: it's a side-scrolling beat-em-up.
Speaker 1: But they've taken the best of all the great side-scrolling beat-em-ups over time and made basically the ultimate Side-scrolling beat-em-up game to end all well side-scrolling beat-em-up games.
Speaker 0: Well, it does in the sense.
Speaker 0: in the sense of a normal, you know, this kind of beat-em-up.
Speaker 0: We're not talking about the hardcore beat-em-ups.
Speaker 0: This is no God hand.
Speaker 1: No, it's not a God hand It's clearly River City Ransom.
Speaker 1: yeah, you Jam the buttons to beat up the bad guys and try to dodge the attacks that they occasionally throw at you and the bosses are Sometimes interesting and have a pattern that you have to follow.
Speaker 0: admit though The majority of the fun I get from the game is the fact that it's a well executed game that simultaneously just has Great pirate baby cabana battle stylin to where like the watching and the listening and the playing are all equally good and the three together.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I have no interest in playing this.
Speaker 1: for example You can tell when you're playing this game that like you can level up big-time and you know You can do all sorts of crazy attack.
Speaker 0: They're like, you know any different fucking characters to unlock and you have to like be really 30.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can be like the Saracen and the fire elementally alien and the conehead.
Speaker 0: Oh, I didn't know that beekeeper.
Speaker 0: Oh shit, the way to unlock them all is such grindy bullshit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's like a million weapons in the game and there's also animals that you can get in the year in your arc.
Speaker 1: You know animal companions.
Speaker 0: the leveling up is fun But the fact that I can't just pick a level is Incredibly annoying primarily because you know we Scott and I played through a lot of the game And then we wanted to show it to Alex.
Speaker 0: So we sit down and we basically all had to be level one or else it just sucked.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean Alex could have been level one while we were very high level.
Speaker 0: that would have been great for him, right?
Speaker 1: That would have been great for him.
Speaker 1: Just getting completely owned by all the bad guys.
Speaker 0: Also the fact that level clearly matters significantly.
Speaker 0: I mean Scott played a little bit and was higher level than me and until I caught up He was just better than me completely and I didn't even need to be there.
Speaker 1: Yeah So yeah that leveling.
Speaker 0: the leveling is fun, but why like the grindy bullshit?
Speaker 0: wise They should have made it more like I have all this achievement II grindy bullshit stuck onto an otherwise good game.
Speaker 1: They should have made it just like River City ransom where it's money that matters.
Speaker 1: you can get Techniques and things like.
Speaker 1: you go buy a combo you got buy an animal, but it doesn't actually level you.
Speaker 0: It does in River City ransom, that's why you level up.
Speaker 0: you go buy the food.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 1: The staff forgot about yeah And that that was.
Speaker 0: that was fun because you only you would only play it with like one person all the way through.
Speaker 0: But this is more a game where I might just pick it up with my friends.
Speaker 0: the fact that oh I gotta level up my guy to catch up with my friends.
Speaker 1: Yeah, your friends can't join it You know, the thing is it does allow you to play online with friends.
Speaker 1: So like if I level up myself and my friend levels up we can join together.
Speaker 1: Or if like my friend who has the game at his house comes over He can log into his Xbox Live on the and then we can he can bring his characters up.
Speaker 1: I think I'm not a hundred percent sure about that, but I hope it looks like you're able to.
Speaker 1: I don't know about that For sure.
Speaker 0: I just I don't like the fact that I have to level up all these characters and like we unlock some characters I gotta level them up separately.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just to play them.
Speaker 0: No, I want to play it right because I only care about the style.
Speaker 0: I don't care about anything else.
Speaker 1: It's definitely the kind of game where after I beat all the levels and all the bosses I'm gonna be done with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also the fact that you could buy some of this content with the DLC for real Can you really?
Speaker 0: I didn't know that some of the weapons are like the king's pack.
Speaker 1: Oh I Was unaware not happening.
Speaker 1: Nope, not cool not paying for that.
Speaker 1: Sorry Yeah, other than that.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, it's it's got a lot of funny bits in it You know, like.
Speaker 0: there's the part where the deer is rocket poop the rocket poop and there's a lot of Ren and Stimpy styling But not always that and there's also a lot of it.
Speaker 1: There's also a lot of parts of the game That are like they mix up the gameplay the same way Ninja Turtles the arcade did like.
Speaker 1: there's a sequence of the game where you ride Animals while you're running away from this big monster.
Speaker 1: It's also the right and you stop doing.
Speaker 1: you know beat them up and you do like a sort of dodgy Side-scrolling game almost like dodgy in the American almost not the British sense.
Speaker 1: It's almost like the racing part in Chrono Trigger kind of.
Speaker 1: you know, I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's almost like that.
Speaker 1: So it's not just a side-scrolling beat-em-up, which though, you know what?
Speaker 1: It's actually a lot like Battletoads in that sense.
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 1: It's almost like the motorcycle part in Battletoads.
Speaker 0: I'm surprised that hasn't been remade recently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I actually wish the game had more Battletoads kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: It has a little bit but that's another book.
Speaker 1: beat him up that it's.
Speaker 0: there is one part when we were fighting the the techno King.
Speaker 0: Yeah, where I just I expected it to be that Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles or Battletoads thing.
Speaker 0: I expected to be like throwing stuff at the screen, but that didn't really happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, but you know, we're only we're not even all the way through the game.
Speaker 1: We got to go across the river to the rest of the game.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there's all kinds of exciting stuff over there.
Speaker 0: there is but the fact that there's so much like a lot of people who are playing that are getting really really into the DLC and the unlocking and the leveling in the ground That's I mean, how else can you make big money off a game like this?
Speaker 1: If you don't do that kind of stuff You're only gonna make a little money off it and that's why this game probably didn't cost them anything to make at all.
Speaker 1: Yet they found a way to market and design the game to basically Get tons of money from people on a huge high margin and that's why they're raking it in.
Speaker 0: so it's a fun game though It is.
Speaker 1: it's definitely it's a good game.
Speaker 1: I mean, they wouldn't be make be able to get DLC people to pay for DLC if the core game was poop.
Speaker 0: The thing is it's like we said, it's a fun pirate baby cabana battle.
Speaker 0: It's not a it's no NS.
Speaker 1: I mean I I was playing NS today and Yesterday, yeah This is heavily game where you buy it you play it till completion and then you put it back on the shelf never to be picked Up again, maybe like years later.
Speaker 0: You'll play it through again with some friends.
Speaker 1: Maybe I forget maybe you know.
Speaker 1: what happened is, you know Some other friends will come over haven't played it and they'll play it together while you're doing something else.
Speaker 1: That's definitely gonna happen.
Speaker 1: It's a game that like the same way that mean like we've beaten River City ransom But we'll pick it up and play through a level or two from time to time.
Speaker 0: It's one of those games where other people can be playing it and I get almost the same enjoyment watching other people play as I Get playing.
Speaker 1: so I could do something Especially like, you know when they see the jokes in the game that you've seen already But you can see them laugh at the joke.
Speaker 0: Didn't we talk about this last Wednesday?
Speaker 1: We talked about this.
Speaker 0: I think we need to do a Tuesday on replaying cuz there's different stuff to say You think so?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't think this different.
Speaker 1: It's it's mostly the same.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's some different though a little bit a little bit.
Speaker 0: if we broaden it to be replayability.
Speaker 0: Maybe why can I play NS and tie fighter over over again?
Speaker 0: But I can't play castle crashes again cuz cash crashes again is the same thing.
Speaker 0: again It's the same but I thought is the same.
Speaker 1: but NS again.
Speaker 1: each game of NS is a different experience.
Speaker 1: It's it's you're creating.
Speaker 1: It's the same reason.
Speaker 1: you can play dwarf fortress actually if you like.
Speaker 1: it has infinite replayability.
Speaker 0: The exact same game again.
Speaker 0: Why can I play it again so easily?
Speaker 0: Because tie fighter you think is.
Speaker 0: I think it's just because there aren't enough of those games.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's kind of like if I'm if I'm dying of scurvy something that has a little bit of vitamin C in it I will eat that forever cuz I need it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if someone gives me oranges, I don't need it anymore.
Speaker 0: Basically, there's.
Speaker 1: I should walk to the gas station get some oranges.
Speaker 1: We don't have any.
Speaker 0: they're the only sources left of vitamin tie fighter.
Speaker 1: our tie fighter and x-wing alliance vitamin tie fighter Come over and over again.
Speaker 1: The only source of vitamin X calm is X calm?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I mean there's the jagged Alliance.
Speaker 1: whatever whatever.
Speaker 1: it's not.
Speaker 1: Nothing is the same as that X calm alien.
Speaker 0: whatever tribes - there's even a penny arcade.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right Vitamin tribes.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I'm so deficient in that.
Speaker 0: I think I'm gonna die.
Speaker 1: Die of tribes Scurv scurv drive.
Speaker 0: try V tribes II.
Speaker 1: I don't know we're gonna have to come up with diseases for this.
Speaker 0: I think we're winding down here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know, I guess just in summary right castle crashers.
Speaker 1: It's got sort of this cool.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's basically a medieval styling.
Speaker 1: side scroll II beat him up game great music Good gameplay, you know, but it sort of mixes it up with all sorts of you know, aliens and animals and as bears shitting themselves right big monsters Dragon, I don't I really have any dragons yet.
Speaker 0: I really like that techno King though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's cool because it combines like sort of technology.
Speaker 1: There's aliens, but this medieval, you know, you get the pirates They got they got everything coming in all the cool themes rolled into one.
Speaker 1: So, you know, it's it's totally geeking out, but it's a game.
Speaker 0: don't buy an egg You couldn't buy it.
Speaker 0: really good controls for this game.
Speaker 0: No, you have an Xbox.
Speaker 0: You're 300.
Speaker 1: It's not a $300 game.
Speaker 0: If you don't have if you have an Xbox already, you're stupid.
Speaker 0: if you don't have this game That's right But it should be on the PC.
Speaker 1: Maybe someday will be yep, you know Especially because it's playable online game could basically be on the DS game could be on the Wii Game could be on everything, you know, no reason to make it 360 Pacific.
Speaker 1: Yeah Oh, I do want to say one thing though.
Speaker 1: Is that you know, I originally thought that you know You need an HDTV or else the 360 isn't worth it.
Speaker 1: And I realize that's only partially true, right?
Speaker 1: We're playing these games on a non HDTV with the 360 and it's just fine.
Speaker 1: The thing is there are obviously Some few aspects where an HDTV would significantly help right like in the shadow complex game.
Speaker 1: There's some things that are just sort of small and difficult for me to see, you know even with my excellent eyesight just because the TV is not HD.
Speaker 1: and also in Castle Crashers like there's small details like When you're looking the wet go into the weapons frog and you look at like the stats and different weapons.
Speaker 1: They're like just like they're a little bit pixley and you can't really tell.
Speaker 1: like is that plus four magic?
Speaker 1: or is that plus four?
Speaker 1: strength and with an HDTV you could totally tell right away and the screen might actually be a little wider which would help a lot to so What you know.
Speaker 1: if you know if you don't have an HDTV and you want a 360 don't let that stop you But an HDTV is recommended.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Speaker 1: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.