Speaker 0: It's Monday January 5th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight the humble netbook.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: I can't believe there's only one more year of the knots.
Speaker 0: I guess.
Speaker 1: What do they call like you know?
Speaker 1: thing is you don't have anything for them to call the nod.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they called it on eight back in the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what do you call the tens?
Speaker 0: We were not gonna worry about that teens that they're not all teens.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna worry about that.
Speaker 1: that's even harder to name.
Speaker 1: But then we get to the 20s will be all good for the rest of our lives like ah you know what I think it'll Happen.
Speaker 0: because when I listen to old people talk they say aught up to 19 aught 9 or aught 9 And then they say for all the tens they just say like 1911 1919 and then we hit 20. they say the 20s Mmm.
Speaker 0: I think that's what we have to do.
Speaker 0: There is no other reasonable option.
Speaker 1: Let's just change English so that they're all teens.
Speaker 1: It's 10 teen 11 teen 12 teen 13 teen.
Speaker 1: We'll be good.
Speaker 1: we'll come the teens.
Speaker 0: I was an advocate of that curse when I was a little kid.
Speaker 0: I remember I used to argue very much that English originally used base 12 because 11 and 12 were such weird numbers, and it made so much sense.
Speaker 0: Good job, and then when I was an omology when I was like seventh grade my teacher was like that's clever, but wrong Of course.
Speaker 0: then he went on to agree with me that base 12 is much more useful, and we should have used that.
Speaker 1: I Guess if you like four three two and six you got so many factors in there.
Speaker 1: What do you need?
Speaker 1: the factors for most people can't factor for anything so I don't know.
Speaker 0: you know it's more useful For people like me.
Speaker 0: maybe less useful for people who can't read or write.
Speaker 1: I don't know who know.
Speaker 0: I don't care But we'll probably do a show about the the New Year's extravaganza because we basically had the front row crew Up in beacon or down in beacon depending on you know which people for about a week.
Speaker 1: It was a good time.
Speaker 0: It was kind of awesome though we actually had by all.
Speaker 0: we almost missed the new year because Scott and a bunch of people were upstairs playing Agricola and The game was running long, and I walked upstairs, and I'm looking at them And I'm counting up like who's gonna win, and I walk downstairs, and I look and it's like 1158
Speaker 1: yeah,
Speaker 0: and I'm like popping the champagne and trying to pour and all the I'm trying to make like 25 glasses of champagne And get everything ready.
Speaker 0: we all run downstairs.
Speaker 0: I couldn't even get the NIST clock up in time.
Speaker 1: you suck you going for the NIST clock.
Speaker 1: you got to go for time Gov it's much faster.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I went for the NIST clock I use at work because you're stupid.
Speaker 1: time.
Speaker 0: gov has been trusty every year, but luckily we made it because of that extra leap.
Speaker 0: second Not really we made it.
Speaker 1: we said no people like looking at the cell phones like oh, we missed it.
Speaker 1: It's not really that important.
Speaker 1: - oh yes It is at some exact an arbitrary moment in time Which is no different than this exact moment in time.
Speaker 0: I point out that I'm a person who celebrated the millennium on the proper year.
Speaker 0: All right, I did.
Speaker 1: Oh no an arbitrary You know calendar thing whoo you know what.
Speaker 1: if it wasn't for Gregor it would be a totally different date that you would do this.
Speaker 0: okay, but anyway We sang all Lang sign, and then it odd yesterday the last of the stragglers left our house.
Speaker 1: Oh Wow, it was yesterday.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It was yesterday.
Speaker 1: Ah Well the house is like we cleaned it up surprisingly well.
Speaker 0: We clean the house up faster than we used to after some D&D games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's still got some cleaning to do, but it's not too bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think part of it was that in the New Year's party because so much like people went out of their way to pick up after themselves as opposed to D&D where I would find like a Half full glass of something under the couch undisturbed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also a lot of people were at other people's houses for sleeping.
Speaker 1: that helped.
Speaker 0: Oh my god Did that help including me?
Speaker 0: I actually just kind of slept somewhere else and let people use my bed the whole week.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, I wasn't about to do that.
Speaker 1: I need my bed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the nice thing was I could wake up to quietude.
Speaker 0: I could take a shower immediately Without having to worry about anyone else taking showers.
Speaker 1: I just showered it weird at different times that way to be hot water.
Speaker 0: I kind of like a shower right away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'd like to but it's not necessary.
Speaker 0: But anyway, we'll talk about all that some Thursday.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you're interested because if nothing else Saturday night Really felt like college suddenly like we'd all been around long enough to where we all Slipped back into the college lifestyle and that was one hell of a night as a result.
Speaker 0: All right So so not enthusiastic.
Speaker 0: what's up with you?
Speaker 1: I'm tired.
Speaker 0: Mr.
Speaker 0: How could you be tired?
Speaker 0: We went to bed at like 8 yesterday.
Speaker 1: I want to bed at 10.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 0: because what were you doing?
Speaker 0: Were you just surfing the internet?
Speaker 0: no, it's no better than playing.
Speaker 1: Wow, I wasn't doing that either.
Speaker 0: You're playing Fallout a single-player.
Speaker 1: I stopped playing that at like 7 or 8.
Speaker 0: Good game anyway.
Speaker 0: Tech news Monday, whatever.
Speaker 0: We're back new year.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: What do you got in the news?
Speaker 1: All right, so, you know Amazon s3, right I May.
Speaker 1: basically it's Amazon's.
Speaker 1: is it simple storage solution?
Speaker 1: I think they call it.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: We're thinking about switching to it already.
Speaker 1: I'm already using it for a bunch of stuff.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna use it even more after we learn that Libsyn is just using that and then charging us more than they charge them.
Speaker 1: Well, it may or may not be charging us more than they charge them.
Speaker 1: right but check this is how this works, right?
Speaker 1: Let's say, you know you get some hosting right from some company for I don't know a website, right?
Speaker 1: Okay, so then they usually give you a bandwidth limit.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: for example, our hosting is 200 gigabits a month.
Speaker 1: So if I put a 1 gigabyte video file 1 gigabit video file so it's 2 billion 1 billion bits of video and 200 people download that video then they cut me off and the website will be down until The next month right when it will come back up or I can pay them extra money on a per gigabit basis Which is expensive.
Speaker 1: so if you have things that are high in bandwidth that people are downloading or Maybe you just want to like have a safe place on the internet to put stuff You know, like you want to back up your computer But you don't want to back it up to just a hard drive in your house.
Speaker 1: You want to back it up somewhere serious where you know, it's safe.
Speaker 1: You can just store stuff on Amazon's very very trusty servers and your stuff there is very safe and you can make it encrypted and secure if you want to and If you want you can give other people access to it so that you know I could put a video up there and then everyone in the world could download it.
Speaker 1: and it's.
Speaker 1: you know it's not the fastest thing in the universe, but it'll work because it's Amazon servers and It's not free though, you know.
Speaker 1: They charge you based on how much you upload and how much is downloaded even if someone else is doing the downloading That's not you.
Speaker 1: So the result of that, you know Is that I get like a bill from Amazon every month for like a dollar and change because that's really how cheap it is.
Speaker 1: now What they did is they just added a feature Which is a very interesting feature in that Let's say I put some files up there and I make them publicly accessible or at least accessible to the other people besides myself.
Speaker 1: Now I can charge those people the cost of them getting the file.
Speaker 1: So So if it cost two cents if it would have cost me two cents for them to download the video I can now charge them two cents.
Speaker 1: In fact, I can also charge them more than two cents if I want to and you can actually now very easily set up Some stuff where you put data online and then charge people for downloading it.
Speaker 0: I wonder very very easily.
Speaker 0: I wonder if all those shady for-profit podcasts and things are gonna move to this.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: you might see some of that.
Speaker 1: You might see like some people putting like wares and then you have to pay them like a dollar to get it.
Speaker 0: I don't know about that because you're pretty easily tracked to yourself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but who's looking at these?
Speaker 1: and you know, it could be just some encrypted file Mmm, you know that has a key along with it.
Speaker 1: No one knows Could put all kinds of crazy shit up there.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be.
Speaker 1: it's gonna be very interesting the result of this.
Speaker 1: but the question that it mostly raises is you know Who is supposed to pay?
Speaker 1: Right because it's like right now the way the internet works.
Speaker 1: as long as things are net neutral.
Speaker 1: It's like everyone just pays for a connection that has some speed and then they use as much as they want.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: It's kind of like look at anime conventions versus comic conventions.
Speaker 0: Like it's exactly the same thing.
Speaker 0: I mean if you go to an anime con you pay, you know You're 50 bucks or whatever to get in But then everything in the con is covered by that.
Speaker 0: like you want to go to a concert go to the cosplay Go to the panels watch show whatever you want to do you pay for a badge and then that badge gets you into everything Everything in the world, but you go to comic cons and it's like alright I paid my 50 bucks to get in and I can walk around this little room in this little room.
Speaker 0: But hey, I want to go see Kevin Smith up.
Speaker 0: That's another five bucks.
Speaker 0: Want to go get something signed by Stan Lee?
Speaker 0: That's another 50.
Speaker 1: Yeah, kind of like that I guess I. just the question is like if you're hosting some files on the internet, right and you want people to you know Look at those things.
Speaker 1: It's like who is supposed to pair you supposed to pay or it's like it caused Google money every time I go to google.com.
Speaker 1: That's why they make that site as low bandwidth as possible.
Speaker 1: It's like this tiny piece of HTML.
Speaker 1: That's why it says privacy instead of privacy policy because it would cost them that much more Right.
Speaker 1: So right now Google pays when I visit google.com.
Speaker 1: But should I pay because I'm the one who's benefiting by visiting google.com?
Speaker 0: I think no because if if we get into that world where it's pay for content and not just paying for bandwidth But also paying for the contents bandwidth not just your own bandwidth.
Speaker 0: I One I feel like bandwidth is so cheap that anything that actually What makes you pay for the bandwidth you spend to get it will immediately be subverted by something free Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I mean one.
Speaker 0: I would never pay for bandwidth for crap I would.
Speaker 0: I can't conceive of a situation where I would pay for the privilege of looking at something.
Speaker 0: I would just pirate it at that point.
Speaker 1: I think what we should really happen right is when you look at it Everyone is sort of it's even all around, you know, sure I caused Google a lot of money But I have a website and people visit that and it sort of evens out in the end on all sides.
Speaker 1: See, so the only people who really should have to spend a lot of money I think are the people who have a a huge disparity of you know one side or the other.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is if you look at most people, I mean what 90% of people just consume they don't have a website Mmm, maybe they have a myspace but they're not paying for that.
Speaker 1: No, they're not paying for that.
Speaker 1: Oh Whatever.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's interesting though It is maybe people at least like because one thing is people don't realize it's very difficult even today to set up like quality e-commerce, especially if you have any sort of special needs or If you want it to be shiny and cool, you know It's.
Speaker 1: you're either going to pay a lot of money or you're going to do a lot of hard work Or you're going to have something crappy.
Speaker 1: You really can't get a high-quality thing for free.
Speaker 1: That's exactly what you want.
Speaker 1: That's also good.
Speaker 1: It's just it does doesn't exist.
Speaker 1: but you know things like this and Amazon checkout or Amazon payments Google checkout and stuff and It's gonna make it real easy for people to make like, you know, say a site where you know They you download videos and pay for them or something because YouTube doesn't offer that shit.
Speaker 0: It definitely pays the way for micro payments.
Speaker 0: Like it's the first Viable does everyone will it be able to use Amazon?
Speaker 0: It'll just work automatically.
Speaker 1: Yep, basically sign it to Amazon download a bunch of stuff and then at the end of the month they charge you like three bucks.
Speaker 0: Yep, so, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Will this be the beginning of like webcomics and videos and things be having micro payments.
Speaker 1: I Was gonna be real interesting just to see like who uses this and for what.
Speaker 1: yes I'm very.
Speaker 1: I'm very curious to see what happens.
Speaker 0: I've got a guess.
Speaker 0: I've got a hard.
Speaker 0: maybe The thing is it's difficult to say because pornography is pretty much free on the internet.
Speaker 0: But then again, that's because it's all pirated and the porn people fight to ought to get their stuff off the pirate network.
Speaker 1: That's a big problem with the porn right?
Speaker 1: Is that like, you know, you got a porn site and you charge money for the porn But you want people to come to it.
Speaker 1: So you take some porn and you put it out there for free.
Speaker 0: that has your logo all over it But that's probably enough for that says enough for most people.
Speaker 1: so they never come and pay.
Speaker 0: so Scott they come they just don't pay.
Speaker 1: if you don't put any porn out there for free No one will ever come to your site to pay for anything because they won't even know it exists.
Speaker 0: I can't believe I'm at a cum joke on the air.
Speaker 1: Hey great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not on any air or on wires.
Speaker 0: No, we're on air.
Speaker 0: Okay, we can be on air.
Speaker 0: There's wireless routers of me.
Speaker 0: You have to pay for them anyway, so apparently Twitter is dead.
Speaker 0: It is no longer innocent.
Speaker 1: live Twitter.
Speaker 0: It's the end of the internet.
Speaker 0: It's the end of micro blogs.
Speaker 0: They've destroyed it because someone fished on Twitter.
Speaker 0: Yes, I'm gonna quote from the person who put this on slashdot Culture crash blogger blah blah.
Speaker 0: blah says this is the end of Twitter's innocence.
Speaker 0: will tweets become like email with two out of every three just worthless spam?
Speaker 0: wait a minute on One hand.
Speaker 0: no Twitter and things like Twitter can't become like that for one simple reason You only see the tweets that you subscribe to the people you were friends with.
Speaker 0: It's a white list by default system as opposed to email, which is a blacklist by default system.
Speaker 1: Yep, so even if there are mad spammers on Twitter if you don't follow them You will never see their spam ever.
Speaker 0: only get spammed on Twitter if you follow idiots Follow spammers or are an idiot.
Speaker 0: Yep So in this guy mean basically all that happened here was someone Started compromised someone's account and started sending, you know private tweets to a whole bunch of people and a private, you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's a good way to do it.
Speaker 0: those tweets looked legitimate even though I don't think I could be fooled by.
Speaker 0: why would someone send me a tweet with a link to The login to Twitter and why would I follow that login which has clearly the wrong URL Type in my credentials and then not worry about it when it doesn't work?
Speaker 0: hmm but apparently a bunch of people did and those people's accounts got compromised and It spread all over the place and people are losing their shit over this and one.
Speaker 0: The internet was not terribly innocent to begin with.
Speaker 0: it was just that in the old day.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like in the early days of the internet.
Speaker 0: There was the AOL like walled garden.
Speaker 0: That was kind of like the Byzantine Empire with their walls around them hiding from the bar.
Speaker 0: Dark Ages around them.
Speaker 0: Except was the opposite.
Speaker 0: They'd walled the Dark Ages in and wouldn't let him out.
Speaker 0: But then everyone in the real internet was like the Wild West in the early days.
Speaker 0: They all had guns and didn't trust each other for shit.
Speaker 0: It's still how it is Except now a lot of people are wandering out into the Wild West with their little carpet bags And they're going into the saloon and they give a put $100 in on the bar And they're like how much for a whiskey partner.
Speaker 1: and then someone comes and blows their brains out and takes their money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the internet was never innocent and Twitter was never innocent.
Speaker 1: But if you want to walk around in this wasteland, you better know Hokuto no Ken or know somebody does.
Speaker 0: But or else I don't see how this is news.
Speaker 0: anyone could have done this.
Speaker 0: It's it's not you know, this is only news Because it happened over Twitter, which I notice and the internet cares about.
Speaker 1: that's something I've noticed a lot in just in tech news lately.
Speaker 1: Is that?
Speaker 1: What is actually news?
Speaker 1: doesn't make the news.
Speaker 1: the only things that make news are if you have an important word for example, like Something that is like the stupidest story in the universe But has the word Apple in it will be like at the top or has the word Google in it or the word Microsoft in it or if it has a big word in it then it gets to the top even if it's a worthless news.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile, very very important news that does not have any of those big words and it will not rise to the top.
Speaker 1: And so basically this is a piece of crap.
Speaker 1: news.
Speaker 1: fishing Fishing isn't news.
Speaker 1: fishing has been around everything is being fished banks are being fished Everything in the world is being fished and idiots still fall for it.
Speaker 1: It's not news, but the word Twitter's in it's always at the top of the news.
Speaker 0: big deal Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Twitter Apple tweet Apple.
Speaker 0: Twitter jobs to it tweet Twitter.
Speaker 0: Yep Of course this brings up another issue that I Guess Twitter is starting to become more mainstream Because I've never met a competent technologist who could ever be fooled by fishing Like it.
Speaker 0: just you can't be fooled unless the site you were going to is already compromised directly.
Speaker 0: You really Really have to go out of your way to get fished.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's pretty hard It's sort of like.
Speaker 1: I mean I could sort of understand, you know people falling for fake medicine You know because a lot of them are really deceptive with their you know, fake medicine ads that are just outright.
Speaker 0: But if I go to Geico dot co.
Speaker 0: dot uz And it has a green Geico logo and like a red misspelled login.
Speaker 0: I don't think that's gonna get me.
Speaker 1: No, besides why would someone want to log into your car insurance?
Speaker 0: Well, my car insurance is also my credit card.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even though it's actually on a separate site.
Speaker 0: but yeah.
Speaker 0: But anyway, actually plus it's trivial to prevent fishing.
Speaker 0: if you're a big institution like all my banks and my credit cards and everything When I log in one it asks me for my username.
Speaker 0: All right, I type that in and then it prompts me for something.
Speaker 0: It's not just something I know, you know.
Speaker 0: get the factors of security something I have something I know something I am.
Speaker 0: it also has something, you know You know, I log into my bank and first it shows me a picture of something I'm not gonna tell you what it is clearly and then it asks me a question.
Speaker 0: So not only does the bank make me prove who I am before it lets me in but it makes itself prove to me Who it is.
Speaker 1: Yep So it's like, you know You're going a fishing is when you go to a website and you think that website is your bank's website But it's not your bank's website.
Speaker 1: It's some other website.
Speaker 1: So how do you prove to your bank that you're you?
Speaker 1: That's how you get into your account.
Speaker 1: is you give them your name and password?
Speaker 1: But your bank has to prove to you that it's your bank and isn't some fake website.
Speaker 1: So it shows you this picture and stuff and websites need to do this.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean the only other option is like a secure ID open ID kind of thing all those RSA style keys.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much unbreakable.
Speaker 0: But again, all those things can be brought around.
Speaker 1: I got to order those YubiKey thing.
Speaker 1: Yes, you do.
Speaker 1: So I got away with it.
Speaker 0: And I kind of I kind of want to.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to convince my work.
Speaker 0: Basically, they said if I get it working for like local stuff and I show to them they might be willing to dump the RSA.
Speaker 1: You might have to code something for it, but you don't have to pay for the RSA server anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah the cost of RSA Minus the cost of all the development time it would take to set up everything to use this instead.
Speaker 0: I mean, I even have this crazy idea of giving it to clients like they can get premium secure service.
Speaker 0: Oh Crazy idea, but I got a. I got to sell it to people.
Speaker 0: So I got a. I got to get YubiKeys and make sure they actually no one will log into your pipeline and trade stock in your name Even though it's pretty much impossible to do that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I know I know But you know people.
Speaker 1: if you charge like a small fee for people but will pay for it World of Warcraft did it and it Works brilliantly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those are RSA keys, aren't they?
Speaker 0: I think so I don't know pretty sure.
Speaker 0: while made a deal well blizzard made a deal with RSA.
Speaker 1: I don't know who's RSA or someone else?
Speaker 0: Yeah, all I know is that the people who buy them are people whose accounts were actually Compromised usually due to no shady action on their part.
Speaker 1: Right makes.
Speaker 1: the vast majority of compromised accounts on things like myspace or Facebook or Wow are people who have stupid Guessable passwords and their friends guess them or they tell someone their path.
Speaker 0: Oh the other I think the other half equally valid are people who use the same login ID and password for everything that too and Then they make an account on something shady or poorly maintained.
Speaker 0: Mmm, you compromise that you've compromised everything.
Speaker 0: Yep, but I feel like if Blizzard has such an easily breakable system I mean, it depends on how they're being compromised and then Blizzard offers you the ability to pay Protection money.
Speaker 0: No, that's kind of shady.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I got one more quick news I want to.
Speaker 0: I want to point this out.
Speaker 0: I'd like to do a whole.
Speaker 0: I realize this should be turned in kind of a whole show about electricity power grids not the game internet and all this sort of stuff, but There's this article on slashdot about distributed nuclear batteries as the new like electrical grid infrastructure.
Speaker 0: The idea is that you bury Nuclear batteries in quotes.
Speaker 0: I'll get to that in like every little neighborhood and then have all these like small entry points into the grid.
Speaker 1: Wouldn't it be more efficient to just have nuclear power plants?
Speaker 1: Yes, I Mean centralized is always more efficient than distributed as long as you're not losing more over the power lines than you're gaining by Being more efficient at the generation.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I didn't read the whole article yet But they test the man you have to do there.
Speaker 0: The real issue here is that they say batteries.
Speaker 0: But if you read the article, they're not actually nuclear batteries.
Speaker 0: Those are a real thing that exists.
Speaker 0: They're kind of awesome.
Speaker 0: I wish civilians could get their hands on them.
Speaker 0: I would kill for a nuclear power laptop.
Speaker 1: They're really heavy.
Speaker 0: They are really heavy, but you know what if my laptop weighed 10 pounds, but I only had to charge it once every 10 years?
Speaker 1: Okay, I'd rather have it weigh five pounds in five years, you know what I'd be happy with a year.
Speaker 0: But these aren't actually nuclear batteries.
Speaker 0: they're basically small Self-contained nuclear reactors much like the kinds we're trying to use in Africa.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're pretty cool for that purpose.
Speaker 0: They are but I don't feel like this is a good idea yet because we haven't even got Yucca Mountain up and running.
Speaker 0: So we're still gonna have to do something with these things and there's a lot of issues with transporting nuclear quote-unquote waste across state Lines, I said there's something about nuclear waste.
Speaker 1: I still understand right.
Speaker 1: if it's if it's dangerous That means it's still radioactive right?
Speaker 1: There's this nasty shit coming out of it Nasty shit coming out of it.
Speaker 1: then it can generate electricity somehow because there's energy being released.
Speaker 1: Let me make this even more confusing because all right If there is no energy being released of it from it in the form of radio radioactivity, then it's not dangerous.
Speaker 0: Let me make this even more confusing for you.
Speaker 0: Think about it this way the more radioactive something is the more alpha beta or gamma or whatever radiation Photon something are coming out of it.
Speaker 0: Yep, the more and so more energy and or mass is being emitted from it Mm-hmm, the faster it's giving that up the shorter its half-life is.
Speaker 0: The shorter its half-life is the less time it spends being dangerous.
Speaker 0: Yep So nuclear radiation and nuclear waste is kind of a self-limiting thing and You can also usually get power out of it and you know what?
Speaker 0: The answer is in France and in civilized countries where they continue to build nuclear power plants.
Speaker 0: They have power plants that are designed to use refined nuclear waste to generate further energy and make less dangerous ways.
Speaker 1: Yes modern technology.
Speaker 1: Well, we won't see that for 50 years even better.
Speaker 1: for anyone who's unaware I mean look how long it took us to get the cell phone from the Japanese.
Speaker 0: the majority of nuclear waste is Generated by a nuclear facility is what's termed low-grade nuclear waste.
Speaker 0: you know things like gloves and suits and detectors and construction materials and those things are Barely radioactive and it doesn't even take them that long to be no longer dangerous.
Speaker 1: So then it's just goop and rocks.
Speaker 0: Well, no, it's mostly gloves and things.
Speaker 0: It's basically the stuff that you have to store for you know, 10 20 years and then dump it in a landfill or recycle it Or whatever.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm
Speaker 0: I think this is an interesting article because one thing I could see is that this would be a good kind of backup solution or a kind of intermediary solution for you know We do have the problem now that there are a small number of very big points of failure in the US power grid.
Speaker 0: I mean remember the Northeast blackout.
Speaker 1: I think it would just be cool to just we should just make a bunch of them just have them on hand and then you Know if there's an emergency or something just drive the trucks out.
Speaker 1: or even better Take them or put one in a truck and drive it somewhere then plug it in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or why don't we use these this technology more widely in places like Africa?
Speaker 1: that well We are I guess trying.
Speaker 1: someone's trying.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we should do it more instead of using them here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Don't know.
Speaker 0: It's an interesting article I didn't I?
Speaker 0: I would have a lot more to say about it than I can fit into a little news bit.
Speaker 0: So I wanted to point it out.
Speaker 0: I want you all to read about this stuff and some Monday We'll do a show about the power grid.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna try to find some expert to correct us when we're wrong.
Speaker 1: Good luck with that.
Speaker 0: but anyway things of the day and speaking of electronics or electricity or the power grid Have you ever when I was a kid like one thing my parents gave me was this giant set of electrical components.
Speaker 0: It was like transformers and plugs like extension cords and light bulbs and adapters and fuses and it wasn't ever intended.
Speaker 0: I could never make anything out of it because I wasn't allowed to plug it all in.
Speaker 0: but I had all these things.
Speaker 0: And when I was really really young what I was obsessed with Was plugging something into an outlet and then plugging the other end of that somehow into another outlet.
Speaker 0: really I didn't know what it would do.
Speaker 0: I was like five But I thought it would be a cool idea and this was like the goal of many of my young experiment.
Speaker 1: I never thought that was a good idea.
Speaker 0: So I would like.
Speaker 0: I was trying to make like little adapters and I was trying to do all this stuff and of course because I didn't have a soldering iron, you know, I was five there was no configuration I could put together that would allow this to come to pass Which was lucky because I would often plug my things in when no one was looking And then my parents would come and unplug it and tell me not to do that.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but it turns out I as a five-year-old was about as smart as a lot of 30 40 year olds because apparently a Certain department store.
Speaker 0: Well, not a department store hardware store got so many requests for a dual headed Power-card or power adapter.
Speaker 1: What would you possibly need one for that?
Speaker 0: They put up a sign saying hey assholes No There's a picture of this.
Speaker 0: you got to see this thing.
Speaker 0: apparently the primary reason people want these is that They have poorly thought-out their Christmas light plans and have ended up with two Backends of Christmas light strands facing each other and want a nice easy adapter to plug them in.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: wait a minute now, that's not possible.
Speaker 0: Oh, it is possible, but I will say this.
Speaker 1: How is it possible?
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: How is that possible?
Speaker 0: How is that not possible?
Speaker 1: I mean Christmas light All Christmas light.
Speaker 0: well most Christmas lives except for the triple long strands.
Speaker 0: We'll have that Shoddy looking thing that plugs into the wall that has the adapter in the front of it to plug something else into the outlet
Speaker 1: yeah,
Speaker 0: and at the other end of the strand will have the Female adapter into which to plug in a second strand of lights,
Speaker 1: correct?
Speaker 0: so people would plug this male adapter in.
Speaker 0: now I point out that if they plug the male adapter in and They've already got the Christmas lights plugged in.
Speaker 0: They just made a deadly weapon right there.
Speaker 0: if they survive this They've already made it further than I would expect.
Speaker 0: Yeah But then they could plug that end into the next strand of Christmas lights and power them from the rear.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I Just want to point out if you end up plugging, you know You haven't died yet and you plug the other end of this into another outlet somehow or if the other end of this Which is also a lethal weapon touches anything?
Speaker 0: Well, uh not gonna end.
Speaker 0: Well, I can't believe this sign was necessary.
Speaker 0: I feel like basic electronics much like.
Speaker 1: I don't know Electronics here, we're not even at electricity here.
Speaker 1: We're at plugging something in.
Speaker 1: You don't know how to plug things in.
Speaker 1: but the holes Jerry the holes, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I feel more and more like public high schools.
Speaker 0: You should be able to opt out of these classes Like if you take a test.
Speaker 0: But if you can't pass a test, I feel like there should be a class in high school called how to not suck at Life after high school and it should teach you this should be elementary school how to plug things.
Speaker 1: No,
Speaker 0: it's got to be high school because otherwise people will forget
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 0: It's got to be like how to plug stuff in what a checkbook is and how to use it What a savings account is not to use it what a credit card is and why you shouldn't have one if you're in this class.
Speaker 0: No, I'm gonna turn on a gas stove without killing yourself.
Speaker 1: Yeah Man, I had to put that like class in a bunker somewhere.
Speaker 1: That's safe You know people go turn on the gas stove.
Speaker 0: Oh, I just imagine the practicum at the onion.
Speaker 0: before you graduate your senior Water they lock you in a room.
Speaker 0: They shut the door.
Speaker 0: There is a Bunsen burner a lighter and a beaker and if you can boil the water without dying you get to go to college.
Speaker 1: All right, you get to go to community college Hall Road high.
Speaker 0: So what do you have for me?
Speaker 1: It's just a funny song by one of our favorite funny song bands the arrogant worms.
Speaker 1: But someone made a little animated video to it.
Speaker 1: It's funny.
Speaker 0: Which one is this?
Speaker 1: This is the the song of assumptions.
Speaker 0: Oh, I almost used that as my thing of the day before I saw this gem.
Speaker 0: That was my thing at the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the song.
Speaker 1: you get a lot of assumptions when you listen to the song, but your assumptions are not correct.
Speaker 0: Ra Ra Ri kick him in the knee.
Speaker 1: Ra Ra Ras kick him in the other knee in the ass.
Speaker 0: No, I Just remember that one RT hockey game.
Speaker 0: We're doing the Ra Ra Ri dead thing and a guy was like Ra Ra Ri Kick him in the knee and the whole crowd's yelling.
Speaker 0: and there was Ra Ra Ras and the really loud guy.
Speaker 0: You know just kick him in the and the loud guy yells as loud and long as possible.
Speaker 1: It's a good one.
Speaker 0: so uh We couldn't come up with what to do the show on.
Speaker 1: No, we suck.
Speaker 0: We had like ten ideas, but they're all like think about it a little bit have a have a plan and then do the show Episode ideas.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so even though I guess a lot of people have discussed this already We've discussed it in the forums a whole bunch.
Speaker 1: It's a kind of a hot topic lately.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should talk about the netbooks Kind at least somewhat.
Speaker 0: it Amazes me to this day that it took as long as it did for a product like that to be made and sold in quantity.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean well think about this.
Speaker 1: right you had computers and computers kept getting faster and better and stronger with more see faster CPUs more RAM more hard drive space more everything Right.
Speaker 1: and every aspect of computing got more powerful.
Speaker 1: and you know the prices kept going down.
Speaker 1: So you can always get more power for the same amount of money.
Speaker 1: and as that went on consumer level Applications because you know real applications always need more power.
Speaker 1: but consumer level applications Always needed more, you know, these games are too slow, you know these 3d games It's you know, even just saving this Word document takes a while, you know, it just everything, you know It need to get faster.
Speaker 1: the Internet's too slow.
Speaker 1: Look it takes me like 10 minutes to sign into AOL.
Speaker 1: This sucks and things got better and better and better.
Speaker 1: and Then eventually sometime like, you know a couple years ago ish maybe two or three years ago, you know cable modems DSL We're everywhere, you know, we had Pentium fours AMD Use around that time.
Speaker 0: like Wi-Fi started to become completely ubiquitous.
Speaker 0: I mean right now they're like six access points within range of our house.
Speaker 1: Yeah, everyone's got laptops with Wi-Fi, right?
Speaker 1: people didn't really need More horsepower than they had.
Speaker 1: I mean people.
Speaker 1: what do they do?
Speaker 1: They go to YouTube they go to Facebook They go to myspace.
Speaker 1: they brought.
Speaker 1: most of the stuff people do is in the web browser.
Speaker 1: So if you were computer can run Firefox or Internet Explorer Can run flash right in the web browser.
Speaker 0: I use links and can play.
Speaker 1: it can play videos and music.
Speaker 1: and You know PC games, you know, everyone talks about the crisis, right?
Speaker 1: But no one really plays that most people play, you know Even Wow has barely any system requirements.
Speaker 1: half-life 2 portal these sorts of games have barely any system requirements.
Speaker 1: So Even if you're a gamer if you're not super crazy into the very high You know system requirement games, you don't even need that much horsepower.
Speaker 1: So most people the vast majority of people using computers no longer need Faster computers than what they've got and they won't for a while
Speaker 0: but not even just that look specifically at portable devices because the the scope of what people will do on the go is Far lower far smaller than what they will do at home.
Speaker 0: I mean when you're in Starbucks, what are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: You want to check your email go to Google Maps and find a restaurant?
Speaker 0: Email, you know get on Twitter and tell people that you're about to go take a shit and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna sit down and play, you know NS in a Starbucks.
Speaker 0: I did that.
Speaker 1: some people play like that recently, you know, you might play like Wow for a minute or two But even then system requirements not too high.
Speaker 0: Well Wow doesn't run so well on the netbooks.
Speaker 1: No, it doesn't.
Speaker 0: but but there's.
Speaker 0: they're kind of like.
Speaker 1: this depends on the netbook.
Speaker 1: Actually, you might get it to go for a little bit.
Speaker 1: You won't be able to do like a. you know a huge thing, but maybe you can sign in and yeah, they're Wow mail.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah the time as time went on and as time is going on there's been more and more like the.
Speaker 0: the technology gap between high-end on-the-go use and average on-the-go use has broadened to the point that we have $400 little Netbooks that have three hour batteries and do everything the average person will ever want to do in Starbucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because see here's what happened right.
Speaker 1: there were always well almost always tiny laptops But they were ultra portables like the ones we have or like the ones you know Cool people have.
Speaker 1: and what an ultra portable is.
Speaker 1: it's when you take an incredibly powerful laptop like a full power laptop We're talking core to duo full-on, right?
Speaker 1: But you shrink all the parts you should make everything really small and you put it in a tiny package and You put like two batteries in there.
Speaker 1: So the battery lasts forever and the screen is small but the screen is very high resolution.
Speaker 1: It's a high quality screen.
Speaker 1: So basically you get the best stuff in the world and you make it real in this but also the smallest stuff.
Speaker 1: So you get a long battery life high horsepower?
Speaker 1: Low weight laptop and the result is something that costs like $2,000 and maybe even $3,000.
Speaker 1: The other way you can go is you can just get some piece-of-shit computer parts and don't even bother miniaturizing them.
Speaker 1: They're so shitty that it doesn't take any effort to put them in a tiny package.
Speaker 1: and they're so shitty and slow.
Speaker 1: They don't use that much electricity.
Speaker 1: So you don't need to put two batteries in there.
Speaker 1: just put one normal shitty battery in there to last forever because it's barely using the battery and You know who cares.
Speaker 1: the screen is high resolution, it's like 800 by 600. that's good enough for freaking people.
Speaker 1: they don't you know, no high resolution from what.
Speaker 1: and You know people bought into it and it does what most people do.
Speaker 1: and it's surprising because I look at a netbook.
Speaker 1: It's like I couldn't live off of one but a lot of people can plus.
Speaker 0: honestly if I hadn't bought an ultra portable like if I if I didn't make as much money as I do and I wasn't And I wasn't doing the things on the computer that I do.
Speaker 0: But I needed more than a netbook like.
Speaker 0: I needed a real computer.
Speaker 0: I'd either have like the super powerful Desktop and the netbook what I carry on the train and around the city in my pocket basically in my tiny little bag Yeah, or I'd have you know, my PC at home I'd have the you know moderately priced powerful laptop that I bring like on trips or like when I'm going somewhere big.
Speaker 0: But then I'd have the netbook that I carry with me everywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because the normal laptop plus netbook is far cheaper than Actual.
Speaker 0: good small, you know ultra portable I mean you can get.
Speaker 1: I bought my parents like a Dell 15-inch full-on laptop as good as it You know a full desktop computer basically.
Speaker 1: But in a laptop and it was like $800 and a netbook is like $200 and my laptop That's an ultra portable is $2,000.
Speaker 1: so I can get for two netbooks and two normal laptops or one ultra portable.
Speaker 0: Yep, now, of course the ultra portable really does serve all the purposes like it is the best possible laptop Unless you were one of those people who travels all the time and needs to do complex 3d rendering on the go.
Speaker 0: Then you need one of those big, you know, like 17 inch honking laptops, which I really don't see too many people doing.
Speaker 1: that I mean Really?
Speaker 0: I do For the like the game 3 or 3d rendering when you were at home I can see the use for the gaming laptop.
Speaker 0: to what if I went to a whole ton of land parties.
Speaker 1: You know, it's a whole ton of land parties.
Speaker 1: But even then if I went to that many land parties like you buy a dedicated land box exactly.
Speaker 1: I would get like a high-powered box in a high-powered desktop.
Speaker 1: But in this very small box like micro ATX or something, you got to carry the screen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I want that screen because see the main thing about a lot for gaming right is the fact that when you have a Laptop, even a gaming laptop the screen is attached to the computer.
Speaker 1: So you can't have the keyboard.
Speaker 1: when you move the keyboard you're moving the monitor.
Speaker 1: You say I don't move the keyboard when I'm playing a game, but you're forced to have it in this particular orientation.
Speaker 1: Also a laptop keyboard is really bad.
Speaker 0: You know what I can say this.
Speaker 0: I did actually play NS in a Starbucks not that long ago because it runs just fine on my ultra portable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 0: It was great.
Speaker 1: Did you have a big?
Speaker 1: did you plug the mouse into it?
Speaker 0: Yes I plugged a mouse into it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you guys you got it.
Speaker 0: I've been using the geek night's mouse.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you also, you know a set an external keyboard would help a lot too.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah I'm thinking about buying a little Bluetooth mouse just for my laptop for when I'm on the go.
Speaker 0: but at the same time when I'm on the go and I need A mouse I just bring the geek night's mouse.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even so the thing is that they do make like computers that are sort of you know The in-between desk like you can go buy from Dell like these things that like sort of fold up computers that are like their desktops Yeah, but then like the monitor comes out and separates a bit and they make things like that.
Speaker 1: I think Sony makes one, too.
Speaker 0: But I mean there there are some uses for those things.
Speaker 0: but in the end I see like most techie people I know They need an ultra portable and they either can't afford one or aren't or real or will not spend the money on one.
Speaker 0: even they Can't afford it.
Speaker 0: But otherwise Like netbooks are awesome and I feel like more and more people are gonna buy them.
Speaker 0: and I don't think the argument I've been seeing in the media that netbooks are taking off because the economy is poor is true.
Speaker 1: No, it's not because if you look, you know things like the XO PC and that stuff, right?
Speaker 1: That was they were trying to make laptops, you know for like, you know the poor parts of the world where there are countries that do not have high quality economies to begin with.
Speaker 1: and Then they sort of realized in doing that that regular old people want this too.
Speaker 1: and it was actually They.
Speaker 1: people have wanted this kind of thing.
Speaker 1: It's one of those things or people want it, but they didn't know.
Speaker 1: they wanted it right because they were ultra portables.
Speaker 1: But no one except nerds bought ultra portables.
Speaker 1: No one even knew about them.
Speaker 1: They'd see your laptop and go holy shit that small because they never seen anything so small because it was never marketed to them.
Speaker 1: and the idea of having an incredibly small laptop didn't even occur to people because they just sort of Laptops are about 15 inches.
Speaker 1: That's the size.
Speaker 1: They are, you know, they didn't think about these things.
Speaker 1: They didn't realize that they really wanted a small, you know laptop that was light and had long battery life.
Speaker 1: They you know, so when they went to the store and they looked they were like, well, these are all big That one's got a big ol impressive screen.
Speaker 1: I'll get that one not really thinking about it.
Speaker 0: Well think if you don't know it's not obvious that ultra portables exist.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because I mean like how did I buy my Fujitsu?
Speaker 0: I had to go to the Fujitsu website and buy it from them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the only ultra portables you're gonna see are like it may be a Dell maybe The MacBook Air which is still a little big inches wise even though it's thin.
Speaker 0: It's also really heavy.
Speaker 1: Is it really that heavy?
Speaker 0: Yeah, we got one at work.
Speaker 1: I thought it was supposed to be light.
Speaker 0: It's really heavy for how small it is Like.
Speaker 1: ah, I think my laptop weighs less and you'll see some Sony ones, which are not so great.
Speaker 1: But you know, you're not gonna and the prices are gonna be way high.
Speaker 1: you're not gonna consider them and they don't look impressive next to the other ones because You have to actually know what you're doing to realize that it's fucking awesome because it's a whole lot of power in a little package.
Speaker 1: So the fact that now right you got the netbooks, right?
Speaker 1: Not only the netbooks cheap which draws anyone's eye no matter what the economy is, right?
Speaker 1: But they put them in the stores where everyone can see them.
Speaker 1: they market the hell out of them and they're actually like Cheaper than any desktop.
Speaker 1: You're gonna see that the cheapest computer you can get period.
Speaker 1: you know It's like if they can make a netbook for two hundred three and three hundred dollars.
Speaker 1: Where's the $100 desktop, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the MacBook Air weighs a little over three pounds.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow Yeah, so I'm still wondering like the hundred dollar desktops are because I think that a lot of people would go for those as well.
Speaker 0: I think the reason there are no hundred dollar desktops it's the same reason why hard drives don't really get cheaper.
Speaker 0: because if people always think hey if I can buy a 500 gigabyte drive for a hundred bucks How come I can't buy a hundred gigabyte drive for five bucks?
Speaker 0: is it's still made of metal because it costs this?
Speaker 0: like Physically, it's pretty much the same.
Speaker 0: So once they make a process to make bigger drives if I make a 500 gigabyte drive It doesn't cost any more to make than a 100 gigabyte.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like even a. you know, the cheapest shittiest desktop computer still comes in a case Right with a motherboard and manufacturing time on a factory line and metal and soldering and all that business.
Speaker 1: Oh that business that the price is not really.
Speaker 1: you can't push it down that much just because using you know cheapo parts.
Speaker 1: That's also
Speaker 0: the reason why used computers never really come down in price so much because used computers are either unreliable Or take more time to make reasonably reliable then like the time it takes to put them back together by someone who knows Costs more than just buying a new cheap computer.
Speaker 1: That's why you see already faster.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's why you see a lot of these places that you just bring your old computers to and then they take the working parts build new working computers of all the spare parts from broken old ones and then install Linux on them and given to poor people because There's really nothing else you could do with them.
Speaker 0: Do we have anything else?
Speaker 0: We have anything at all?
Speaker 1: I Don't know.
Speaker 1: I think that it's just kind of weird how it took so long for netbooks to come around and it's strange that you know For the first time we don't have software pushing hardware as much.
Speaker 1: I mean even in like the console gaming department right where it's always been this race and race and race.
Speaker 1: We're now gonna see we're probably gonna see a lot longer lifecycle on the current generation than any previous gaming generation.
Speaker 0: and well because we're kind of hitting a lot of limits where things Like a lot of gameplay things got to the point where more technology does not really make for more game experience.
Speaker 1: It's like you have a 4d game.
Speaker 1: not really It's like right.
Speaker 1: It's it's really hard to push things farther than we've got them at least software wise You know.
Speaker 1: and it's it's.
Speaker 1: and even so it doesn't make a significant difference when you do audio software like audition.
Speaker 0: Audition doesn't really do much more than cool.
Speaker 0: Edit did in the year 2000.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like 2000 2001 like it does more.
Speaker 0: this technology has advanced But it's advanced so little that you're never gonna have like audio applications for editing audio that are pushing the limit of computers.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: I mean it's got to the point where I can do like real-time Britney Spears a fine And all right, what am I gonna do beyond that with audio?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's kind.
Speaker 1: It's like You reach a limit where it's like any.
Speaker 1: Our imaginations are.
Speaker 1: what's limiting us, you know, we can't think of another thing to do.
Speaker 1: It's not that we can't do.
Speaker 1: it is we don't know what to do and the only things that we can think to do Right are like supercomputer things that supercomputers are doing, you know, like simulating all the weather on the entire earth.
Speaker 1: It's like all right.
Speaker 1: What next simulate the entire universe?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Well, we're sort of done then What are you gonna do beyond that?
Speaker 0: Uh, well, well I don't want to get into the simulation argument because if it's possible to simulate the entire universe, did you create the another universe?
Speaker 0: Yes Haha Luckily though the way out of that paradox for anyone who knows, you know Really like thinks about that paradox The way out is that it is possible that to simulate the entire universe Takes the amount of energy that it takes to run the entire universe.
Speaker 1: Also in simulating an entire universe you'd have to simulate a simulation of the entire universe which would fail.
Speaker 0: Maybe anyway, I think we're done.
Speaker 0: I Was thinking of leaving the hospital.
Speaker 0: I I applied to a whole bunch of jobs and I was like I looked at different things and I even considered just like getting out of IT entirely.
Speaker 0: and I started looking at a lot of Tech journalism and I like I started sending my resume to newspapers and people like that and for a lot of places They would ask me to send a writing sample on the condition that I would relinquish my rights to the writing sample And then they could publish it if they wanted.
Speaker 0: Yeah Actually a little over a year ago wrote an article for and a certain I can't reveal who Outfit about how netbooks are the future.
Speaker 0: the first person to make one is gonna be so freaking rich like that.
Speaker 0: is it?
Speaker 0: netbooks are everything and they're coming and I'm gonna look after the show and see if I can find if someone actually ever published that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that'd be pretty cool.
Speaker 0: They never even called me back after I sent it in.
Speaker 1: now They're probably just looking for some free stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were.
Speaker 0: they were kind of kind of shady and low-end anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like most tech journalism is if it's not on I guess the one or two sites.
Speaker 0: I actually go to yeah Yeah, all right.
Speaker 0: I think we're done.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got nothing.
Speaker 1: Let's go to bed go to bed.
Speaker 0: But but shouldn't we be all arrested from our week and a half of vacation and New Year's and Xmas and all that?
Speaker 0: No This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 0: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 0: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.