Speaker 1: Hey, it's Monday July 27th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: privacy security SSL and private keys.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: what Scott was warm today?
Speaker 1: about froze.
Speaker 0: mom Actually was warmer yesterday.
Speaker 0: Yes, it was so warm about melted my Today slightly less warm Still you know is the words today like work was just blah.
Speaker 0: everything sucked right.
Speaker 1: sudden random thunderstorm around lunchtime.
Speaker 0: No, no I like actually that part lunch was cool because they felt sorry for us at work being all Blair.
Speaker 0: So someone went out and got us some lunch with company monies, and they got me some.
Speaker 0: pancake is very nice pancake Yeah, lunch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, huh?
Speaker 0: Yeah it were really good pancakes - came with butter and syrup and everything.
Speaker 0: but No, and then you know I left work at 6 instead of a 5.
Speaker 0: I walk outside.
Speaker 0: I didn't think it was gonna rain today.
Speaker 0: Right it was warm And it started drizzling a bit when I walked out the door and I didn't have an umbrella or a hood.
Speaker 0: Usually I have one of the other you know and as long as I had the umbrella.
Speaker 0: I'm totally cool But if I have the hoodie it's like a but I'm least I'm alright.
Speaker 1: that didn't run in any rain But I was basically.
Speaker 0: the office is immediately started raining, and then it rained harder and harder.
Speaker 0: as I walk towards the train I was just like fuck man.
Speaker 1: I was already.
Speaker 0: they work late, and then you rain on me.
Speaker 1: I was already like home by then.
Speaker 1: there was no rain.
Speaker 0: I know right.
Speaker 1: the funny thing is that crazy thunderstorm rolled through the city right.
Speaker 1: so I have my phone out.
Speaker 1: Everyone's looking out the window cuz the lightning like struck near our buildings or super loud.
Speaker 1: So I look on like the weather radar And there's basically this tiny dot of red over New York City and nothing anywhere else.
Speaker 0: yep Alright, I guess that's it for today's BS.
Speaker 1: But you know for anyone who is wondering what's going on here You know you might have seen us at Otacon where he did some amazing panels.
Speaker 1: geek nights is four nights a week.
Speaker 1: This is Monday night Which is science and tech and neck beards and links and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: so if you're looking for our coverage of Otacon or our Upcoming coverage of Kinetic on or upcoming coverage of packs Otacon will be this Wednesday.
Speaker 1: packs will be some Tuesday in the future after you know after packs happens and You can listen if you want to.
Speaker 1: but this is Monday night.
Speaker 1: We talked about neck beards and Linux.
Speaker 0: I'm curious as to where the neck beard meme started because you know did Darryl Surratt actually start that?
Speaker 1: The thing is that wasn't me.
Speaker 0: was it some or did he get it from somewhere?
Speaker 1: that was definitely.
Speaker 0: I heard neck beards on twit recently.
Speaker 1: really I wonder if it's spreading again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, actually John C Dvorak said throat beard and then switched it up to neck beard broke beard.
Speaker 1: that is clearly someone who heard it Didn't know?
Speaker 0: apparently people in the chat room in the Twitter chat room during the Twitter show or telling them throat beard neck beard.
Speaker 0: So, huh Yeah, I definitely some you know.
Speaker 0: Awo geek nice listeners.
Speaker 1: I recall very distinctly hearing the term at our IT long before geek night.
Speaker 0: really I never did.
Speaker 1: I heard it more than once.
Speaker 1: in fact someone pointed out to me that I had grown a neck beard because I Had in fact yeah, I'm talking about in relation to Linux users.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: I was at our IT, and I was the Linux user.
Speaker 0: Well my headphones just started working a lot more than they were a second ago, that's strange all right.
Speaker 1: So you're gonna just throw that in there where I can't easily edit it out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's fine Okay, it's good for the show, but anyway.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's not protecting us.
Speaker 0: It's tech news tech stuff, but So long since we did any shows There's like just a bajillion.
Speaker 0: news is about everything.
Speaker 1: a very interesting anecdote from work actually of all things all right relation to tech because you know when you get back from a long vacation and you know we haven't done a geek nights in like a week and a half.
Speaker 1: but Yeah, I show back up at work And you always have that kind of conversation with the co-workers of yeah, so were there any disasters while I was gone?
Speaker 1: And there was but I can't get in all the details But the kind of thing that only happens in like a lab practical in college happened at my work while I was gone.
Speaker 1: Wow Imagine a situation.
Speaker 1: we have three environments You know like a UAT environment a research environment and a production environment.
Speaker 1: the exact same problem the same symptom Happens in all three environments simultaneously, and the end result is that all three were Unrelated to one another despite the fact that at the level one and level two analysis They appeared to be the exact same problem and in fact there was an unrelated fourth error that was non Impacting in two of the three environments that was unrelated to either of the problems, huh?
Speaker 1: This was like the kind of thing like in a class on the exam.
Speaker 1: They'd be like what if blah happens and blah happens.
Speaker 1: What do you do?
Speaker 1: What could it possibly be, but it was in the real world to see you investigate and eventually figure it out.
Speaker 1: Well, they did well yes, because we're very smart, but this was one of those situations to where well I don't think most people could have solved it.
Speaker 0: It was solved it with enough time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we had to solve it before the market opens better than our problem at work.
Speaker 0: We're.
Speaker 0: basically it's like well.
Speaker 0: This is fixable with lots and lots and lots of working.
Speaker 0: There's no like answer that we can't solve.
Speaker 0: it's like we know exactly what's wrong.
Speaker 0: It would just take incredible amounts of time and work to fix it, but this is what we do.
Speaker 1: This is like the equivalent of Imagine if images stopped working on like your outbound webs like your web server to the public on all your websites And it turned out that every website you run had its images broken independently by an unrelated problem.
Speaker 1: Yep, that was basically the equivalent of what we had to deal with.
Speaker 0: it's like you think it must be you But it's not you.
Speaker 0: every website out there had its images broke.
Speaker 0: Yes, all right, so Tech news right I guess we should talk about.
Speaker 0: you know there's like a bit of bajillion tech news over the past week or whatever.
Speaker 0: But I think an actual one of the most pressing ones is very recent and that is the most obviously the flame war rific AT&T blocking a 4chan.
Speaker 1: now I don't know who said it first.
Speaker 1: I think it actually might have come from fast karate But someone equated AT&T fighting with 4chan as a t-rex fighting a massive bacterial infection.
Speaker 0: Yeah, someone wrote that somewhere on the Internet's.
Speaker 0: Basically the situation it seems like now that all the information is out it goes something like this right AT&T is an internet service provider.
Speaker 0: Apparently there was a DDoS tech coming from within from AT&T ISP Subscribers to one particular 4chan server.
Speaker 1: I think it was the image server Which is as far as I can tell it's B, and I don't know what else.
Speaker 0: yeah bad stuff It's you know B.
Speaker 1: Definitely stands for bad.
Speaker 0: Yes, so AT&T saw this DDoS attack emerging from their network, so they blocked that.
Speaker 1: right of course what they blocked was you know I guess HTTP gets outgoing to that 4chan server or something like that now as far as I can tell it's more likely that they blocked that IP which just hosted the images for a couple of the boards on fortune.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so anyone people are trying to go to 4chan who used AT&T as their ISP, and they couldn't get there.
Speaker 0: It wouldn't work, and you know brings up all sorts of net neutrality.
Speaker 0: It's like hey AT&T is not up to you to decide what sites I go to.
Speaker 0: and it's like even if there was a DDoS is it really up to AT&T to protect 4chan server?
Speaker 0: I mean it's 4chans problem.
Speaker 1: Well that more likely say they saw a DDoS arising from this and maybe just to protect their network They blocked it at the pairing level.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: It's true, but you know it's like.
Speaker 1: I mean, what do you do?
Speaker 1: you you're caught between a brick and another.
Speaker 0: you couldn't you block it in another way?
Speaker 0: That would not prevent regular legitimate users from going to 4chan.
Speaker 1: That's the nature of DDoS that because of the fact basically a proper like well-executed DDoS is indistinguishable from popularity.
Speaker 0: It's true absolutely 100% indistinguishable.
Speaker 1: There is no way to know.
Speaker 0: I mean remember Google said when they go to the Michael Jackson searches they thought it was DDoS.
Speaker 1: Yes And this is becoming more and more of a problem as the use of the internet and the use of media Democratizes and people become more tech savvy but sources of information are still confined to a very relatively small number of web sites and Data flows are confined to relatively small number of peers and small number of IPs and small number of aggregation points.
Speaker 1: People think that the internet is like this you know end to end But really it's very tiny endpoints connecting to very large endpoints through very small pipes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now the thing is though.
Speaker 0: even though it is true that a very well properly executed DDoS is indistinguishable from popularity The reality I think is that most DDoS is are not very well done And if you actually spend some time and closely inspect them you know like you look at the packet You know below just the destination.
Speaker 0: You know that the head on deep packet inspection is incredibly costly.
Speaker 0: It is incredibly costly.
Speaker 0: however Even like I'm not talking about actual deep packet inspection by the server I'm talking about by a human being just look at it in your you know your Wireshark or whatever.
Speaker 1: That's the thing is that the amount of time that adds to your response Basically makes you already a non actor in the situation.
Speaker 0: I mean you could look and you can see aha everything this DDoS is sending out.
Speaker 0: the packets all look exactly like this right and These normal people sending out packets look you know different.
Speaker 1: so even most often That's not the case because what are they sending?
Speaker 1: a get well you know who knows what they could be sending plus I mean even on like a local level.
Speaker 1: I mean within a corporate internet or something Let's say like someone's using up all your internet.
Speaker 1: It's not that trivial to figure out right away.
Speaker 1: I mean you might have some sort of proxy that logs stuff, but that gives you a huge performance hit.
Speaker 1: So what?
Speaker 1: maybe you turn on IP accounting?
Speaker 1: That's also a huge performance hit just to see who's talking the most and then figuring out what's going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could also just sort of have.
Speaker 0: you know just generic throttling.
Speaker 0: you know slow it down.
Speaker 0: So it doesn't kill you, but still let it go.
Speaker 1: slow it down.
Speaker 1: slow What down.
Speaker 1: and does slowing down mean queuing up pack?
Speaker 1: that means it means a QoS type?
Speaker 1: Yes, QoS Scott basically means drop packets randomly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that doesn't often doesn't end.
Speaker 0: well Yeah, be good like QoS.
Speaker 0: Just the 4chan packets.
Speaker 0: You know something like that Yeah, but even then that's not so easy.
Speaker 1: and when you're an ISP 4chan is no less legitimate.
Speaker 1: Then I don't know my porn dot org net.
Speaker 0: yeah But if I was an ISP I would definitely have advanced tools and people to deal with that.
Speaker 1: what advanced tools though?
Speaker 1: There's nothing terribly good for that.
Speaker 1: and my giant brain I mean it basically comes down to these kind of fuzzy statistical analysis and no matter what you do You're gonna piss someone off and as attacks to get more sophisticated.
Speaker 1: There's absolutely no way to determine a DDoS versus legitimate use.
Speaker 0: Yep, at the very least you know that this you know the.
Speaker 0: you could do like you could like call 4chan and like talk to Him.
Speaker 0: you know like if I saw DDoS going at someone's server, and I was an ISP Regardless of how I dealt with it on my network You know whatever decision I made I would call the person with the server and notify them.
Speaker 0: I'd be like you know if I notice it was yours like Google I would call Google on the phone.
Speaker 0: be like hey Google.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is ISP number three.
Speaker 0: all right point.
Speaker 1: the first point to the first Scott.
Speaker 1: Have you ever tried calling someone based on like some company?
Speaker 1: you know there should be no.
Speaker 1: try calling Google.
Speaker 1: There's no red phone.
Speaker 0: There should be you know a place to call for that specific problem.
Speaker 1: It's per service all right Google.
Speaker 1: Maybe Google has a red phone one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how many people are gonna be calling that for BS?
Speaker 0: I know, but I think you know.
Speaker 0: the fact is everyone has sort of like.
Speaker 0: there is sort of like these standards a little bit Right and that you're supposed to have like an email address.
Speaker 0: That's like abuse at and another one you know.
Speaker 0: so I think we need Scott.
Speaker 1: Here's the problem.
Speaker 1: They're sort of standard for I don't think we can because the signal-to-noise ratio is so high already That if you have a standard people will just hit it with their BS all the time.
Speaker 0: No, we just need a standard.
Speaker 0: you know in between network people's not for normal people's just for network people's to You know contact each other all right.
Speaker 1: so the Internet, so who would AT&T have contacted?
Speaker 1: because it's not another network?
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess they could contact what the ISP.
Speaker 0: Google is a network.
Speaker 0: All right, I guess they would probably call someone at Akamai.
Speaker 1: actually because Google's all Akamai Yes, so then what they have so much to deal with anyway, or what about this 4chan situation?
Speaker 1: Who do you call?
Speaker 1: the ISP that hosts them.
Speaker 1: you got to figure out who that is?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you probably just call their hosting company.
Speaker 1: all right.
Speaker 1: You got to figure out who that is.
Speaker 1: you called their generic number.
Speaker 1: It's like an 800 number.
Speaker 1: now what?
Speaker 0: Well they should have a number for calling with network problems with the network people all right.
Speaker 1: now Now they have to staff that number with humans.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's it's you know in the Network Operations Center.
Speaker 0: where then they already have for telephone?
Speaker 1: is that cost money?
Speaker 1: It costs a lot of money.
Speaker 1: They have to pass.
Speaker 0: yeah But everyone it'll be an equal cost for everyone because everyone will have you know the phone.
Speaker 1: It's got that reason.
Speaker 1: that raises the cost of everyone.
Speaker 1: so then I offer an eye But it'll make everything better for everyone also because it's got.
Speaker 1: it's the tragedy of the comments.
Speaker 1: everyone offers it great I make an ISP.
Speaker 1: I don't offer it.
Speaker 0: I'm now cheaper than everyone else and therefore better And make it a require you should regulate it.
Speaker 1: Oh wait regulation now that opens a whole extra can of worms in favor of that one regulation that it's got.
Speaker 1: so what I mean?
Speaker 1: Where do you draw the line?
Speaker 1: I mean, what if the problem is coming from 4chan itself?
Speaker 1: whose responsibility?
Speaker 1: Is it to cut off that server.
Speaker 0: whoever owns a server all right?
Speaker 1: So how do I determine?
Speaker 1: so anyone who owns a server?
Speaker 1: That is in any way on the internet in any capacity has to pay to have a 24 by 7 hotline For people to call.
Speaker 1: that is public.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we've got to have a hotline.
Speaker 0: someone can call your cell phone line out owns our our server.
Speaker 0: We don't own it line ode.
Speaker 1: so the colo company has to do it.
Speaker 0: They're not a colo company They're hosting company.
Speaker 1: alright, so hosting companies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what defines hosting company?
Speaker 1: I mean I can have a web server through our dynamic DNS out to the internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so now do I have to do this?
Speaker 1: How do I?
Speaker 1: how do I regulate that?
Speaker 0: If there's a problem and someone looks up your phone number.
Speaker 0: They can't find you then you know you gotta maintain this look-up.
Speaker 0: It's in who is put in.
Speaker 0: the who is do where the abuse and all the other email addresses are the thing.
Speaker 1: that's basically completely Useless and unreliable as it stands.
Speaker 0: I think the who is.
Speaker 0: I should.
Speaker 0: I think the I can should be more better about enforcing.
Speaker 0: Who's gonna pay for that who were already paying for the.
Speaker 0: I can might as well pay more.
Speaker 0: it sucks as it is.
Speaker 1: I don't think regulation is the answer.
Speaker 0: I think I think there's a small amount of regulation would be good.
Speaker 0: People on the Internet's major network players need to have some way of just communicating with each other when shit goes down.
Speaker 1: Yes, and defining who a major network player is is already effectively impossible.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of obvious.
Speaker 1: look at how many times even at the high level where the to to like level two ISPs will stop pairing with each other over some bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: How are you going to regulate that?
Speaker 1: What if they just hang up on you, and then they say yeah the phone didn't work?
Speaker 1: or what if they just?
Speaker 1: They say you know all right.
Speaker 1: Here's the situation.
Speaker 1: Let's say I as like you know a company call level three or cogent or someone because I have a problem.
Speaker 1: I'm singing DDoS and it's coming from their network.
Speaker 1: You know how long it's going to take me to get through Them to show them what the problem is such that they can deal with it.
Speaker 1: It is much faster for me to simply block it thus saving myself the problem and by acting in my own self-interest.
Speaker 1: It is not in my interest to work with anyone in any good faith.
Speaker 1: It is in my interest to cut them the fuck off.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but blocking is it's.
Speaker 0: you know It's bad for all sorts of other reasons is it?
Speaker 1: But what if you identified something that is coming through your network that is substantially degrading the entirety of your network And you have reason to believe may be substantially degrading the behavior of other people's networks And you have the capability right now to temporarily stop it and sort it out?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but what if you were wrong and it was actually people searching for Michael Jackson after he died?
Speaker 1: well Here's the other problem, you know, there's the whole simulac.
Speaker 0: I think it's better safe than sorry.
Speaker 1: No safe than sorry in what direction?
Speaker 1: Here's the other simulac or situation.
Speaker 1: if you cannot tell the difference between legitimate traffic and a DDoS They are effectively the same thing and blocking them has the same effect because legitimate traffic and illegitimate traffic are basically indistinguishable.
Speaker 1: So the Michael Jackson searches are equally useless and causing an equal problem to the 4chan DDoS.
Speaker 0: Well, one of them is censorship and one of them is you know protection.
Speaker 1: But is it censorship to block something that is basically preventing your network from functioning properly?
Speaker 0: if your network isn't Functioning when there is legitimate activity occurring then your network is just not capable of doing what needs to do.
Speaker 1: It's got.
Speaker 1: no network is capable because we've gotten to the point to where there is more data people want to send than there will Ever be capacity and the fundamental problem is exposed.
Speaker 1: Well, the fundamental problem is that there's no way to distinguish there's no regulatory way to solve it And currently there's no technological way to solve it other than being very very very very very smart.
Speaker 0: Well, you know the thing is despite all those things you just said there aren't DDoS is just going around killing everyone.
Speaker 0: Everything's got to work still.
Speaker 1: part of that is because people are.
Speaker 1: Networks are actually fairly proactive and stopping these sorts of things.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh Let us let us continue to another news and let us hope that the 4chan people You know don't ruin the Internet's.
Speaker 1: so remember a while ago.
Speaker 1: There was that whole brouhaha where oh shit, huh?
Speaker 1: Yes They deleted all these books from people's Kindles remotely.
Speaker 1: Oh, you want to talk about this BS like George Arwell's 1984 over the horror the irony.
Speaker 0: I think it would have been more ironic though if they deleted Fahrenheit 451.
Speaker 1: I believe someone reported that they also deleted that.
Speaker 0: that was just some.
Speaker 0: probably gotta be a joke.
Speaker 0: Well, the whole situation is that would have been the headline over the 1984 headline.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the deal as far as I can tell basically One people are angry about the fact that they have the ability to delete content that you bought.
Speaker 1: This is kind of.
Speaker 1: this is the thing that people who are advocating their own has it?
Speaker 1: This is the thing people were advocating DRM said would never happen.
Speaker 1: and here it is.
Speaker 1: This is like the like the most egregious.
Speaker 1: here it is you bought something.
Speaker 1: they just delete it with a big fuck you Mm-hmm, but it's a little more complicated than that because what they deleted was 1984 which was being sold through their store by someone who had no legal right to sell it.
Speaker 0: Well, actually it's kind of weird because that book is in the public domain elsewhere in the world But it's not in the public domain in the US.
Speaker 1: Well, thus the other problem of the public domain and we've talked a lot about this in our forum.
Speaker 1: We haven't really brought it up in the show, but I'm pretty sure we have not in any great detail.
Speaker 1: We're getting to this point to where I feel like the public domain as an institution is Almost over broad and inconsistent and I feel like usually I am of the mind that we need to reduce Creators rights in order for the public good.
Speaker 1: This is one situation where I feel like we need to increase Creators rights and I think the public domain really needs to be replaced by some sort of you.
Speaker 1: I think an artist has a perpetual right to Notability and a perpetual right to attribution.
Speaker 0: Well, no one's come no one's complaining about attribution.
Speaker 0: People are complaining about you know, the ability to just use the frickin.
Speaker 0: Yes, but the fact that the Okay, they don't want to change the name on the book to say 1984 by Scott Reuben They just read it they can.
Speaker 1: but the problem is that the public domain is both over broad in one way and yet So far out into the future and so inconsistent that it's useless anyway.
Speaker 1: So the whole thing's moot to begin with.
Speaker 0: yeah, well, I think one interesting thing about the situation right?
Speaker 0: is we usually you know We talk about you know.
Speaker 0: Aha, well, you know a regular book, you know, just you know photo.
Speaker 0: if I steal a regular book from you now You don't have the book right?
Speaker 0: We're always comparing the digital reality to the physical, you know manufactured reality.
Speaker 1: But then there's the meta argument.
Speaker 0: The thing is right with the physical book, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say I illegally printed up copies of 1984 and sold one to you Right, and then I go to jail or I get sued or whatever happens to me for my illegal, right?
Speaker 0: They're never gonna come and take the book away.
Speaker 1: Well you and they perfectly legally can because the receipt of stolen property is itself something that can be remedied.
Speaker 1: So if you get stolen property, the police can just take it from you with no compensation.
Speaker 0: They never will.
Speaker 0: they're gonna have that book, you know, how many you get bootleg CD?
Speaker 0: They're not gonna come and get it.
Speaker 1: is they can.
Speaker 1: and in a lot of cases like if you buy a car and it turns Out the car was stolen.
Speaker 1: You're just out of luck Uh-huh, so then if that is the person who sold it to you, but they're probably in jail and indigent at this point Anyway, so if that's the case, right the you know, the the stolen property, right?
Speaker 0: Then this is a situation where if you want to if you want to talk about it that way Then these people got off easy by getting a refund and having the book taken away.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing.
Speaker 1: I Have my take is that they were technically in the right.
Speaker 1: They were technically correct the best kind of correct, but There was probably a better way to go about it.
Speaker 1: that wouldn't have generated all this bad Press and would have made everyone happier.
Speaker 0: Yeah well, I mean they were first of all, they were negligent in making sure that people who selling books on the Kindle had the right to it right.
Speaker 0: and Second of all, right now this is what happens when you have a closed platform Right is you look at something like, you know The Kindle or the Apple Store right?
Speaker 0: if you actually want to have some sort of control over what?
Speaker 0: Content shows up in your you know, what books are on Kindle.
Speaker 0: then you're now responsible for a books are on Kindle.
Speaker 0: Amazon was responsible for that book being there.
Speaker 0: That wasn't supposed to be there.
Speaker 0: if they would just be cool and let anyone put whatever the fuck book they want on the Kindle Right without interfering or anything then Amazon would have no responsibility And it would be up to that person who illegally put the book there to go get in trouble.
Speaker 1: Well, that is I would still have responsibility if someone bamboozled them and sold something through their store.
Speaker 0: But yes, but no it's not Amazon's responsive if Amazon just let anyone put any book on the Kindle right without You know making a yes or no decision then Amazon's got nothing to do with it.
Speaker 1: No, because what if?
Speaker 1: what?
Speaker 1: if they set up for Amazon, you know You can put whatever book you want on the Kindle trivially and it'll just work.
Speaker 1: But they also have their store which you pay for them to get a book from it.
Speaker 0: No No, I'm talking about there's a store and anyone can put anything in the store and that's it.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about that.
Speaker 1: you still run into legal trouble in that situation by facilitating the sale.
Speaker 0: No, cuz that's what the DMCA does.
Speaker 0: the DMCA says if you're making a platform for distribution and you're not, you know Controlling it editorially got the damage.
Speaker 1: You're not responsible for you know To a degree as far as I've read the DMCA only protects you in certain specific situations.
Speaker 1: You're still confronted to trouble.
Speaker 1: I think.
Speaker 0: no actually that's.
Speaker 0: it's a specific thing.
Speaker 0: is that it's that you know.
Speaker 1: Situation where the law encourages something that in the end is actually in more bad faith toward the authors.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but no that's you know, why Google was so genius with YouTube, right?
Speaker 0: Google doesn't say this can go on YouTube.
Speaker 0: this can unless it's you know illegal child.
Speaker 1: Notice how they still have to take things down.
Speaker 0: Oh, they don't take it down, right?
Speaker 0: Google doesn't take it down.
Speaker 1: the copyright holders are doing the police copyright order holder does all the policing but once the copyright holder makes A legitimate request Google has to follow her and take it down Doesn't take it down?
Speaker 0: the copyright holders have an interface through which they do the taking down.
Speaker 1: Yes, but Google created that to comply with the law.
Speaker 0: No, they didn't do to complain with the law.
Speaker 1: They did it to you know, keep those copyright holders from you know Bitching and mode Oh Scott because if Google had not created that interface for them to do it directly Then Google would have had to do it.
Speaker 1: No, they wouldn't have in response to a complaint.
Speaker 0: They would have No in respite.
Speaker 0: Oh if they yeah then the DMCA.
Speaker 1: if someone makes a complaint to them then they would have to respond.
Speaker 1: their genius was making a system to where They don't have to actually ever Themselves deal with the complaints.
Speaker 1: the complaints are dealt with directly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is you don't have to you know respond to the complaints unless someone actually comes and you know sues you or whatever.
Speaker 1: Well, no if someone responds the safe harbor thing is basically that if someone makes a complaint then you have.
Speaker 1: you know You have to take it down.
Speaker 0: You don't have to take it down until they you know prove just making it take.
Speaker 0: sending a takedown notice isn't enough unless you know.
Speaker 0: That's basically the nice thing you can do.
Speaker 0: is you know, take it down.
Speaker 0: if you know someone sends you a takedown notice They still have to go to.
Speaker 0: you know, if you say no, they have to go to court and prove that they actually own it.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the thing you don't want.
Speaker 1: as far as I'm aware and I'm pretty sure I'm more right on this than you if someone issues you a takedown out of the DMCA and You don't there's certain things you have to do in good faith or else you lose the safe harbor provision.
Speaker 0: No, I'm pretty.
Speaker 0: no They have to go You know, you can just be like whatever and completely ignore it and they have to go and prove that they actually own it You know to make you take it down, but the takedown notice just sort of an a nice thing.
Speaker 0: It's like hey before you know, we go to court.
Speaker 0: Yeah I just want to let you know and if you're pretty sure that you know you they own it and you don't want to deal With that bullshit, then you take it down.
Speaker 1: So 30 seconds of googling proves that I'm right.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't Doesn't?
Speaker 1: alright?
Speaker 1: in order to have an allegedly Infringing website removed from a service providers network or to have access to an allegedly infringing website Disabled the copyright owner must provide and then they give this list of things you have to provide Which is you know the name and address of the complaint the material in question a statement under penalty of perjury that you're accurate in Your claim and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: now once notice is given to a service provider or the service provider discovers them infringing material itself They are required to expeditiously remove or disable access to the material.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the point is is that you you know.
Speaker 0: The original point was that if you you know If you are not editing your content, even just letting people post whatever they want.
Speaker 0: You have a safe harbor Still says that.
Speaker 1: and remember It gets tricky when their commercial interests involved, especially if you facilitate the transaction.
Speaker 1: But when it comes to the safe harbor specifically if you're given a takedown notice, you have to take it down Immediately and then the person that's.
Speaker 0: if the takedown notice is legitimate what it you know It says.
Speaker 0: if they have to you know say that they're definitely the people who oh, yes It's not difficult to make a legitimate one.
Speaker 1: There are very few criteria.
Speaker 1: You have to meet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know there's plenty you know, well I could just make up takedown notices for nothing and send them in.
Speaker 1: Yes, you can and if you do you know what.
Speaker 1: the people you send them to have to take the stuff down at first.
Speaker 0: But what am I sending stuff for?
Speaker 0: like someone else's shit, you know?
Speaker 1: However, you doing that is illegal and then the person who stuff was taken down can file a counterclaim and then they could basically sue You for perjury, but it's basically more.
Speaker 0: it's basically they've made.
Speaker 0: it's a situation where it's less work to just take all the shit down.
Speaker 1: It's not just less work.
Speaker 1: It's that if if the ISP the person who is providing the place where the stuff is Does not immediately respond and take it down.
Speaker 1: They're responsible So they'll just take it down no matter what and then it is your responsibility As the person who put the stuff up in the first place to file a counterclaim and get it back.
Speaker 0: The point is that if they just let anyone who wanted to post books to Amazon They would still have to take down things based on infringement notices immediately.
Speaker 0: Perhaps they would have to take it down, but there is nothing in there that says they would have to remove it from all the Kindles.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is that I could see situation because remember safe harbor.
Speaker 1: All it does is protect you from being sued Mm-hmm, but you still at the same time distributed what could be classified as stolen materials.
Speaker 0: I didn't distribute it.
Speaker 0: the responsibility for that distribution goes to the person who posted it.
Speaker 1: I said me but I'm safe only if you don't have the means to remove it Because if you do have the means then you're not safe.
Speaker 1: Harbor doesn't give you protection from that sort of thing or from remedies.
Speaker 1: It only protects you from monetary damages.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can't sue me.
Speaker 0: someone else puts that you know copyright infringing video on YouTube and then it was taken down.
Speaker 0: and now Um, you know, even though someone out there might have downloaded that video from YouTube and saved it and kept it around We don't make them from their computer.
Speaker 1: right now I can show in a court of law that you have the ability to trivially remove it from everyone's computers who download.
Speaker 0: well See that see that's the thing is.
Speaker 0: I think it was a big mistake was even putting that ability in in the first place By using the same DRM, right that you were attempting to use to you know, prevent copy protection You know to prevent, you know copyright infringing activities.
Speaker 0: You've actually sort of screwed yourself.
Speaker 1: well Scott is it's a cash 22 because I have a feeling that very few publishers would have agreed to even be on the Kindle in The first place or through their store at all if they didn't have this ability.
Speaker 1: and this DRM It's.
Speaker 0: so I can't believe it's.
Speaker 0: it's one thing that astonishes me right?
Speaker 0: is that you think about this right copyright copyright copy.
Speaker 0: We've been talking about this for how long over a decade.
Speaker 0: It's the year 2009 Scott.
Speaker 0: This is an issue since the late 90s.
Speaker 0: I know where you're going.
Speaker 1: there's a trivial answers to why one.
Speaker 1: the majority of the population of the world doesn't care.
Speaker 1: a very small subset of people even know it's an issue and That's it No one cares.
Speaker 1: so it'll never get changed.
Speaker 0: and Even after over a decade the record companies have figured out that DRM is completely stupid and their sales Really haven't gone down since getting rid of DRM.
Speaker 0: and in fact recently an RA person was like DRM is dead.
Speaker 0: Hello, welcome to you know, 2009.
Speaker 0: It's like I'm like hello.
Speaker 0: Welcome to 1999.
Speaker 0: Yet the people with books the people with movies They still haven't learned the same exact lesson in over a decade because I'm pretty much like well If you're that slow to learn your lesson just fuck you.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna steal all your.
Speaker 1: well No, it's got part of it.
Speaker 1: I think is that with music they were basically damned.
Speaker 1: They didn't end if they didn't so they went with the damned if they didn't but I don't think they're really any better off.
Speaker 1: Either way, and when it comes to everything else, there's no incentive.
Speaker 1: There's absolutely no incentive to drop it because it's one of those tragedy of the common situations.
Speaker 1: If one person drops it Then all the publishers will go to the people who still have it.
Speaker 1: Everyone has to drop it at the same time or the people who drop it lose out from the publishers and the publishers don't care.
Speaker 1: And the people don't care.
Speaker 1: so nothing changes.
Speaker 0: I think I think the thing is they underestimate how much the people do care.
Speaker 1: And no, I think it's an echo chamber.
Speaker 1: nerds care.
Speaker 1: No one else does.
Speaker 1: no one else even realizes There's a problem.
Speaker 0: well see that's the thing is I think people don't realize there's a problem But then as soon as until it gets in their face people don't realize didn't realize iTunes DRM was a problem until they tried to You know authorize that fifth computer, or you know they.
Speaker 0: they tried to redownload something.
Speaker 0: They got deleted when their hard drive crashed.
Speaker 0: people don't realize the Kindle DRM is even there at all.
Speaker 0: It's not an issue to them until the book they paid for gets deleted.
Speaker 0: Then suddenly they wake up to DRM.
Speaker 0: And I think over time more and more people wake up to DRM.
Speaker 0: and in each Individual arena in music it already enough people woke up in music to get rid of it.
Speaker 0: I think it's only a matter of time before Enough people wake up to it in movies and wake up to it in ebooks.
Speaker 0: And now you have to get rid of it too, and it's just you know.
Speaker 0: you wait for these people.
Speaker 1: It's a matter of time, but the fact is that right now.
Speaker 1: We're nowhere near that.
Speaker 1: so nothing's going to change.
Speaker 0: I think it's gonna change.
Speaker 1: I don't think it is because one how few people own kindles.
Speaker 1: anyway It's a relatively small.
Speaker 0: and the other thing that there's so retard is that look Anyone who's gonna buy books is gonna You know for you there kindle is gonna buy them whether this DRM or not and anyone who's gonna Pirate them is gonna pirate them whether this DRM or not.
Speaker 1: It's just no because there isn't as nearly as wide of a piracy network for books because only nerds care.
Speaker 1: No one else does think about it.
Speaker 1: most people don't even like things like kindles because they have the stigma against reading things on a Piece of paper.
Speaker 0: yeah, the kindles actually sound really well though, so it is selling really well.
Speaker 0: But I do want to point out that they had to drop the price on it.
Speaker 0: perhaps It's not selling as well as they expect.
Speaker 1: It's got wallet selling really well.
Speaker 1: the majority of people don't care.
Speaker 1: don't want any device like this.
Speaker 0: story is all over the news so It's already out of the news.
Speaker 1: It's only in the tech news now.
Speaker 1: No one cares anymore.
Speaker 0: It was on the regular news.
Speaker 1: yeah for a brief flash and people have already got.
Speaker 1: people care more about New Jersey than they ever Will about this.
Speaker 0: oh, New Jersey, that's something to talk about.
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: So you know that apocryphal tale about how when NASA was trying to figure out a way that's to write In space on the space shuttle in the Apollo program They came up with a multi-million dollar program to make the space pen and the Russians just use a pencil and how.
Speaker 1: that was completely Apocryphal and not true, but it's a very resonant story.
Speaker 0: It is an apocryphal story.
Speaker 0: however I do want to point out this space pen does exist.
Speaker 1: it does, but we did invent that well for that reason.
Speaker 1: But it has its uses.
Speaker 1: I can write upside down continuously great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is great.
Speaker 1: Not really that is okay, but anyway here is basically the same story But it's not apocryphal.
Speaker 1: so if you want that sort of story to tell us an anecdote here.
Speaker 1: We go in China.
Speaker 1: There was some regulation saying that buses have to have Devices to allow you to break a window in the event of an emergency and escape.
Speaker 1: and you've seen these things are like a specialized Little hammer with like the pointy bit.
Speaker 0: Why don't they just have the removable windows where you like pull the clamp off the side of the window and push it out?
Speaker 1: Well one those are a lot more expensive than you know what is on existing buses.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay, yeah, and to even in the u.s.
Speaker 1: A lot of buses that have those windows also have the hammers somewhere.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh because you know the window might be in the wrong place.
Speaker 1: They can't make all the windows that way.
Speaker 1: yeah Yeah, and also, it's China.
Speaker 1: You know not everybody.
Speaker 0: they have the school bus rear exit action.
Speaker 1: You can but that's not enough.
Speaker 0: I mean US school buses.
Speaker 0: they have the.
Speaker 0: you can push out the window also.
Speaker 1: you basically need the rear exit the side exit the Top exit yep, so they have this regulation to save lives because obviously there's a lot of crappy old buses.
Speaker 0: Oh wait lots of crappy old buzz.
Speaker 1: think about it.
Speaker 1: a simple solution is to Require that all buses have means of egress in the case of an emergency.
Speaker 1: And you could have kind of the last resort regulatory option of the special little hammer to break the window and get out.
Speaker 1: Well it turns out those little hammers are being stolen in every single bus.
Speaker 1: They put him in because you steal a hammer.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 1: it's there.
Speaker 1: It's trivial to grab.
Speaker 1: It's a relatively useful tool.
Speaker 1: It's basically like this pick and China's relatively poor especially in the more rural.
Speaker 0: Why don't you put the hammer in like you know the little glass case?
Speaker 0: This is breaking case of emergency.
Speaker 1: just break it and take the hammer and also that's more expensive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and think all right someone breaks it and take the camera.
Speaker 1: great now I have to replace the hammer and the glass but the alarm goes off and you arrest them for stealing.
Speaker 1: now I also have to pay for an alarm.
Speaker 0: It's just a little teeny teeny teeny.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's got that.
Speaker 1: that that's a lot said.
Speaker 0: when you multiply it by number Maybe China can buy their own crappy You know bell ringy things instead of selling them to us.
Speaker 1: so it's got multiply that by number of buses in China.
Speaker 1: You have a problem.
Speaker 1: so some enterprising bus companies took bricks painted them yellow put the Chinese characters on them to be you know in case of emergency and These 100% met the regulatory requirement.
Speaker 1: and as the bus company said no one's going to steal a brick.
Speaker 0: I Would it would be cool brick?
Speaker 0: I would take one.
Speaker 1: Are you gonna carry this brick around?
Speaker 1: We're gonna do it.
Speaker 1: We stole a brick at RIT.
Speaker 1: You know what.
Speaker 1: we put it back.
Speaker 1: that brick was more of a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: But this brick is yellow and his cool Chinese writing on it.
Speaker 1: That would be like a souvenir when I got back to the old Chinese writing in China is the equivalent of stealing a brick that Says like BD on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah BD is cool No, but when if I'm not Chinese, I'd steal it.
Speaker 0: Chinese people don't want the bricks, but US people would watch.
Speaker 1: Yes, and how many US people are gonna ride some podunk bus in the middle of China?
Speaker 0: I would well why else go to China?
Speaker 0: I want to get the real experience.
Speaker 1: anyway if you want that tail, and you don't want it to be apocryphal here you go And there's a good picture of the brick.
Speaker 0: well You know how you were just talking about.
Speaker 0: you know Russians using a pencil.
Speaker 0: yep, you know.
Speaker 0: and we made a space pen Which isn't true, but anyway right.
Speaker 0: well You know we made you know IBM computers.
Speaker 0: You know Russians made BIM computers, I don't know what they.
Speaker 0: you know they made Russian computers.
Speaker 1: And if you know China tried to make computers to that the dragon project back in the day.
Speaker 0: You know that was.
Speaker 0: that was more recently that was a while ago.
Speaker 1: They tried to make their own chips not X.
Speaker 0: it was less than a decade ago.
Speaker 0: these Russian computers Let's talk decade a decade less than a decade even less than a decade.
Speaker 1: What was the world like in?
Speaker 1: 2002?
Speaker 0: not bad these computers by the Russians are made in the 50s and mostly the 60s.
Speaker 0: I mean you think about it right and it's it.
Speaker 0: there's this whole thing that goes on with Soviet stuff because they were cut off from the world.
Speaker 0: so it's like they didn't have.
Speaker 0: you know it's like you look around the world Today right it's like okay if I go to say Japan or China or Australia or Europe right we generally have a lot of the same stuff.
Speaker 0: You know maybe their exact model of DVD player be a little different.
Speaker 0: Maybe there's some you know unique local stylings, but in general.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: Oh look a Sony TV.
Speaker 0: You know it does not a lot of it's not that kind of.
Speaker 0: you know like.
Speaker 0: there's not some electronics company That is exclusive to say France.
Speaker 0: You know you can't see that stuff anywhere.
Speaker 0: You know maybe there's you know car models that are only sold in other countries, but you know it's it's getting very globalized.
Speaker 0: But when the world was cut by the Cold War Russia had all this shit that no one else had and we had all this shit that Russia didn't have.
Speaker 0: so When you look at the Russian computers like wow you know they didn't have no univacs or anything like that, so They got all this cool stuff.
Speaker 0: and one interesting.
Speaker 0: There's a big article here with a few pictures.
Speaker 0: one interesting thing from the article was that you know Early on of course they were trying to you know basically out.
Speaker 0: invent the United States in terms of computer technology right, but eventually They just told the Russian computer scientists like give up just copy everything IBM does and then try to improve on it.
Speaker 0: stop trying to beat them by developing from scratch.
Speaker 0: I Thought that was that was pretty humorous.
Speaker 0: well.
Speaker 1: I recall way back in the day playing Aerobiz and Aerobiz supersonic on the SNES and I always play like a European country or America or something And I'd always see that I can the Eastern Bloc.
Speaker 1: there'd be these plane companies other than Boeing and Airbus and such McDonnell Douglas, but I can never buy the planes.
Speaker 1: whenever I tried to send a representative there They'd be like we can't buy Eastern Bloc planes.
Speaker 1: I was there was always this mystique about them.
Speaker 1: so one day I played as the Russians and said and I could buy Eastern Bloc planes.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you those Tupolev and Ilyushin planes were the biggest pieces of shit.
Speaker 1: They were more expensive and worse.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's totally how it works over there.
Speaker 0: so if you want to see some more expensive and worse computers from Russia from the 60s the likes of which you've probably Never seen.
Speaker 0: this is a good article for reading and looking at the pictures.
Speaker 1: It's weird though how as much as you know the Soviet Union was basically this economic disaster But the styling of the Eastern Bloc in my opinion for whatever reason was pretty damn cool.
Speaker 0: I know you look at these things right and I mean univax pretty cool.
Speaker 0: But these things they look like they belong in like some awesome like sci-fi movie like Soviet Bloc apartments and Soviet car There's.
Speaker 1: there's this mystique about cool.
Speaker 0: They have right.
Speaker 0: the ones where it's like just vacuum tubes and the vacuum tubes have numbers in them And it looks like some sort of crazy Frankenstein thing love those things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got to get one of those, but you know they just had like this great style to it.
Speaker 0: I don't know like why the style is great.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: is it as the aesthetics of the stuff itself?
Speaker 0: Or is it the fact that you know we didn't see stuff like that in this side of the world?
Speaker 0: Yeah I wish I could figure out what it is about it.
Speaker 0: that makes it so awesome in the way it looks.
Speaker 0: at least It's like the fact that it came from a terrible situation.
Speaker 1: So SSL there was an article about self-signed certificate and all that stuff on Is it?
Speaker 0: will we get in trouble if I just call it a racket?
Speaker 0: ah?
Speaker 1: Racketeering is a word.
Speaker 1: I may or may not have used.
Speaker 0: let me let me explain the situation here.
Speaker 0: So people know what this is about.
Speaker 0: right you know how.
Speaker 0: sometimes you go to a website And you want to buy something.
Speaker 0: usually when you're buying something But also for other situations, and you know this lock appears in your web browser Or maybe your web browser turns green and it says you know you are secure and safe right you know That's.
Speaker 0: that's what SSL is.
Speaker 0: now What SSL does?
Speaker 0: is it does two things.
Speaker 0: probably does a lot of things but does primarily two things.
Speaker 0: the first thing?
Speaker 0: It does is it guarantees that the website you think you're at is the website you are.
Speaker 0: So let's say I'm at amazon.com, and it turns green.
Speaker 0: that means I know I am at amazon.com and none of this information I'm typing in to the form on the website is going to say Google or Who knows who else unless Amazon gives it to them on the back end right the?
Speaker 0: Communications between me and that web server are just between me and that web server.
Speaker 0: There's no one snooping on it or anything like that and the number two thing.
Speaker 0: so it's anti-phishing right.
Speaker 0: the number two thing It does is it has some sort of symmetric encryption right.
Speaker 0: so if someone is just like snooping the packets They just see this garbledy garbledy garbledy, and they can't see.
Speaker 0: you know what I'm typing in and spy on it.
Speaker 0: Right and that's what SSL is supposed to do.
Speaker 0: and that's why if you are engaging in a secure transaction online You know typing in your credit card number your social security number anything along those lines You want to make sure that you send a little lock up in the you know location bar of your web browser.
Speaker 0: But also you want to make sure that the URL in the location bar is the website you think you're dealing with.
Speaker 0: you know Even if it's secure.
Speaker 0: if you send your shit to some shady site well You know I mean I could give a secret encoded message to some.
Speaker 0: you know Criminal on the street, and I still gave it to.
Speaker 0: you know it doesn't help me.
Speaker 0: No one else got it, but the criminal, but hey That's how things go.
Speaker 1: so here's the problem with the way SSL really works.
Speaker 1: is that to get that certificate You basically just have to pay some arbitrary person enough money, and then they give it to you.
Speaker 0: yep See let's say I mean there's nothing preventing me from just making a certificate and setting it up.
Speaker 1: They're called self-signed certificates.
Speaker 1: I make the certificate and I sign.
Speaker 1: that is legitimate.
Speaker 1: But web browsers because of the way the internet is Basically like you know those locks are the special things that they'll show.
Speaker 1: like Firefox now has that nice like blue Bar that appears next to the URL to show they have a lock and they have an extra special lock.
Speaker 0: It's like the double lock.
Speaker 1: basically you can't get that unless you pay one of these companies for their Certificate or get them to sign your certificate.
Speaker 0: Yes, basically it doesn't cause them any money to do it all they do.
Speaker 0: It's just like you're paying for a rubber stamp a lot of money for a rubber stamp And you have to pay for it over and over again because your rubber stamp expires And they charge a lot for it now And it's technologically No Different at all from your own rubber stamp that you can.
Speaker 0: just I could spit out like a million of these things in a second With like a shell script.
Speaker 0: right now the thing is right.
Speaker 0: if I rubber stamp my own certificate right.
Speaker 0: well How do you know that you know it's really me.
Speaker 0: I could just use it on whatever freaking website.
Speaker 0: I want Right there's no guarantee that you know the certificate is actually for reals.
Speaker 0: It is totally safe.
Speaker 0: You're basically these rubber stamps from these companies are basically you know okay?
Speaker 0: We are Verisign and we guarantee that this is really Scott Rubin, and it's really front row crew calm stamp.
Speaker 0: So it's basically you know if you see a certificate of my site that I side is.
Speaker 0: basically you have to decide.
Speaker 0: Do you trust me?
Speaker 0: But you know if you trust Verisign this company with rubber stamps Then you don't need to worry about whether you trust me or not because you know the Verisign is trustworthy.
Speaker 0: So really it's sort of like this trust in Economic network.
Speaker 0: in a way you're paying for trust and you're trusting people who pay money.
Speaker 1: Now the real.
Speaker 1: this wasn't a problem until relatively recently in general because pretty much It was the kind of this cost of doing business and the only people who really use this sort of thing were Businesses that had we're collecting credit card information or something like that
Speaker 0: And the only people doing real e-commerce cared about it and anyone who's doing real e-commerce is making money because they're selling stuff And they could afford to have
Speaker 1: this dual problem of people using shoddy certificates and bad Urls to get people or you know fall you know spurious domains like amazon dot
Speaker 0: com.
Speaker 0: You know you ever go to a website, and it says like the certificate has expired the certificate may be fake.
Speaker 0: That's because someone doesn't want to pay up, or they're legit.
Speaker 0: They're actually you know crooks, and they're trying to or they're incompetent.
Speaker 1: There's all sorts of reasons.
Speaker 0: There's all sorts of reasons.
Speaker 1: the problem really is that one there's so many issues that this is kind of just like This show is basically just.
Speaker 1: I was kind of getting all the issues out there.
Speaker 1: We can't really talk about any of them in super depth because each one deserves an entire Monday show in and of itself.
Speaker 0: basically also Just you know.
Speaker 0: to sum up the episode in case you don't listen anymore We're pissed because we have to pay a whole fucking ton of money if we want to have one of these things.
Speaker 1: It's not that much money.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of money.
Speaker 0: It's like hundreds of dollars.
Speaker 1: There are a place like anything start SSL, which will actually give you one for free.
Speaker 0: really That's nice, and they're just really work in all the browsers.
Speaker 1: it works in most browsers.
Speaker 1: They're pretty well trusted.
Speaker 0: and can I get the double plus lock or just the regular lock?
Speaker 1: probably just the regular lock.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I want the double plus lock.
Speaker 1: that one cost more.
Speaker 1: Because and they're always like that to pay money to make a symbol appear in a web browser at the same time It's only it's this kind of barrier to entry the old keep the riffraff out to where only legitimate kind of legitimate businesses can get them.
Speaker 0: But yeah think about the cost of this to Amazon is basically zero compared to what they add the money they actually have.
Speaker 0: but the cost of it to someone like me who's you know just running a little old website is Enormous compared to my hosting cost now.
Speaker 1: It's tricky because on one hand.
Speaker 1: It's a little anti-competitive It's kind of this downward pressure against startups but the other hand it really stops a lot of the very trivial attacks that would bring the whole system down.
Speaker 1: because To get that lock cost so much money that if you're making a million spoofers spam domains You can't afford to do that because the margins on scamming already so low.
Speaker 1: yep So but the one of the real issues here is that because it's kind of this You know it's not a scarce supply anymore.
Speaker 1: I feel like the solution is that don't registrar should basically give Certificates to whoever buys a domain from them, and that's the end of it.
Speaker 0: yes I agree.
Speaker 0: however the problem is you know if a domain changes hands or if a domain expires they have to revoke.
Speaker 1: the Certificate should automatically expire at the intervals of the domain expiring yep And they issue new ones.
Speaker 1: as they are they should expire.
Speaker 0: I completely agree.
Speaker 0: You should just get a perfect SSL certificate with the domain And then it's up to you the person who runs the website not to like share the certificate around or do it the wrong way.
Speaker 1: But there's this whole extra problem on the side of that.
Speaker 1: in the old days if the certificate was self-signed either It would just accept it or pop up a little warning.
Speaker 1: you click ok.
Speaker 1: But Most of the time a self-signed certificate or a shoddy certificate means either you're at Amazon instead of Amazon Or you're on a corporate internet that didn't want to pay for a certificate And or you're on some guy's website who just wanted to have like e-commerce now.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing though.
Speaker 0: Let's say we give a certificate to everyone right couldn't we just make the whole web as is L Like everything.
Speaker 1: there is a performance hit.
Speaker 0: there is a performance hit and there's no reason to.
Speaker 0: the other problem with it I think is that let's say everyone gets one of these and everyone makes everything secure, right?
Speaker 0: Well, then it's like well the lock is always locked.
Speaker 0: So how do I?
Speaker 0: there's no safe and unsafe situation?
Speaker 1: Well, it also gets a lot of the power down to the point of.
Speaker 1: did I type the URL, right?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a lot of power in the SSL now and that most of the time you're browsing the web It's not there, but it's not so when you're safe.
Speaker 1: It's like aha there's the law but the root problem is it's never gonna actually be security because doing this Will always end up being security through credit card as opposed to security through obscurity.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, you don't want security through obscurity or credit card.
Speaker 0: You want security through fucking real security.
Speaker 1: The thing is security through credit card works pretty well in this situation.
Speaker 1: It really does work.
Speaker 0: It works better than nothing.
Speaker 0: That's for sure.
Speaker 1: The problem is this whole separate problem.
Speaker 1: There's an article in slash shot that this study shows that pretty much everyone just fucking ignores This and like they don't even know what that lock means.
Speaker 1: They just ignore it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean web browsers, you know have been trying to do a better job of.
Speaker 0: you know Changing the user interface of the security like ie if there's a bad ticket will like make the whole location bar red.
Speaker 0: You know like Firefox is a lot bigger.
Speaker 0: Firefox is like I mean Netscape used to be this little tiny lock icon in the bottom right.
Speaker 0: that would appear and disappear and now It's nice.
Speaker 1: now will be your face.
Speaker 1: Hey This movie is bad and it gives you an error and you have to click on like four different things That are in different places to get past it.
Speaker 0: Yep,
Speaker 1: and it seems like the majority of people will just click on anything they can and keep clicking and keep clicking until they get Through because
Speaker 0: that goes back to something that we talked about all the time Which is that most people use computers don't read, you know, there's.
Speaker 0: if there's words on the screen They will not read them whatsoever.
Speaker 0: No matter what the words are.
Speaker 0: It could say warning.
Speaker 0: You're going to die.
Speaker 0: The computer will explode.
Speaker 0: they don't read it.
Speaker 0: All they do is if anything pops up at all.
Speaker 0: All they do is click and click and click and click until it goes away.
Speaker 0: They don't read anything They don't think about right.
Speaker 0: so No amount of popping up or visual cues or anything is ever going to get through to people who don't read.
Speaker 0: See you what?
Speaker 0: the only way to actually make SSL work would be to actively say this website is insecure.
Speaker 0: Sorry, you can't go here no matter what by and just not let them go no matter what they do.
Speaker 1: But then that basically prevents your web browser from being used on most corporate internets.
Speaker 0: Well, what I would do actually is that's a good.
Speaker 0: that's a good point.
Speaker 0: You brought up about the corporate internets right for a home user.
Speaker 0: maybe doing that is not so necessary but if I had a company I would set up the computers such that no one would be able to visit any site that had an expired or That.
Speaker 1: that basically unsolved the problem of how do I?
Speaker 0: well it keeps my company safe for my employees.
Speaker 1: You don't read but you don't need that.
Speaker 1: The problem here is that normal people in their normal homes need to know whether or not they're actually on Amazon.
Speaker 0: Well, they don't pay attention anyway, so does it really matter?
Speaker 0: they're gonna get fucked no matter what we set up.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know what to do about it because here's the situation where - if you give them the information.
Speaker 1: Even if they read the pop-up with stuff like certificate They have no idea what it means and there's no way to really explain it.
Speaker 1: because if you give the actual explanation No one's gonna understand what a certificate is or what it means.
Speaker 1: and if you give a dumb explanation you dumb it down.
Speaker 1: They'll just say what do you mean?
Speaker 1: I can't go here.
Speaker 1: It's Amazon.
Speaker 0: Fuck you What I would do is I would put up a series of questions.
Speaker 0: Right and the questions would be like are you a hundred percent sure that you're actually Firefox?
Speaker 1: basically does that?
Speaker 1: It doesn't work.
Speaker 0: people just keep the way it words.
Speaker 0: It is not that plain.
Speaker 1: It says there is an error.
Speaker 1: do not continue.
Speaker 1: and if you and if you just look and you click on like the nice-looking Answer, it doesn't let you go You have to go back and click on the scary-looking X and even then you have to go then it you have to say yes I understand you have to get the certificate.
Speaker 0: So you say are you saying that since people will go through the trouble of visiting the site even with a bad certificate We don't need to pay for the thing.
Speaker 0: We can just use the signed one the self-signed.
Speaker 1: We probably could.
Speaker 0: The problem is it's unprofessional and it is it is very unprofessional.
Speaker 1: It's also a situation where it's your website the system works well enough to where security through credit card Is still pretty viable and if you're gonna do e-commerce today, you should pay for one of these certificates.
Speaker 0: Well, I do think though that Well, you know while what we have is okay, and even though we should still try to find a better solution I think that there should be sort of an iron monkey pricing system.
Speaker 0: You remember an iron monkey when he's sitting there right and as a rich man who comes to get some medicine and as a homeless Poor man, right and he gives the poor man the free medicine.
Speaker 0: and there he tells the rich man It's like 30 tells or whatever.
Speaker 0: right and he's like he got the same medicine for free What the fuck.
Speaker 0: and he's like, you know, hey rich man, maybe you can't afford it.
Speaker 0: and he's like, oh shit He was too proud not to be you know, so he paid him up.
Speaker 0: I think that you know, the SSL should cost more for Amazon than it cost for me.
Speaker 1: But then do we differentiate on the user side the difference on the user side?
Speaker 1: Because if you do we're in the same boat.
Speaker 1: We're in now doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: This is exactly the same as it is now And if we don't differentiate then I pay zero because I have this, you know, I don't make any money.
Speaker 1: I'm just some guy for Amazon and then I proceed proceed to scan people and make all this money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we're in this situation to where the system still works now and is going to continue to work for the foreseeable future and Relatively few people are affected by this.
Speaker 0: It's basically a big old glass house, but the system is someday going to.
Speaker 0: it's a big old Tower made of cars someday.
Speaker 1: This is basically going to break down Catastrophically balsa wood bridge and I don't know what to do about it.
Speaker 0: What do you know?
Speaker 1: also independently aside from all that it is not trivial to set this shit up in Apache.
Speaker 0: It's moderately Troublesome, I mean, it's only a little bit difficult.
Speaker 1: I know how to do it, but even I have run into problems like I had to set up a chain certificate Which I didn't know even know.
Speaker 1: So I had to basically set up our certificate this root certificate and then a chain of authority that went all the way down to my certificates.
Speaker 1: I had these multiple certificates to set up and
Speaker 0: though that's the worst thing is if you got subdomains It's like sometimes you need to get more certificates sometimes you need to get like broader certificates and like if we want to have a different certificate for like forum dot front recruit calm and front row crew calm.
Speaker 1: and also the situation of some.
Speaker 0: we gotta pay again and again and again.
Speaker 1: some people who sell certificates are More or less reliable and maybe a browser will stop trusting one certificate authority because they're bad.
Speaker 0: And yeah, like, you know fire for the people you and that's the thing.
Speaker 0: It's like the browsers really need to do something about it.
Speaker 0: Like, you know, if the browser let's say I'm Mozilla, right?
Speaker 0: I decide the Verisign is trustworthy, right?
Speaker 0: So any certificates that are signed by Verisign are gonna get the green flag in Firefox, right?
Speaker 0: Well, you know, why can't me Scott Rubin why can't I write a letter to Mozilla?
Speaker 0: They should have someone whose job this is right to handle this.
Speaker 0: and I can be like, hey go look at my website.
Speaker 0: Here's my certificate that I made, you know and trust me because you see my website and you approve it even though I didn't pay Verisign any money.
Speaker 0: and they should have a person if they want to be deciding who to trust and who not to in place of the user then I should be able to apply for trust as A person with the website and a certificate to the browser as opposed to to this, you know.
Speaker 1: What would be nice is if a certificate authority basically like did all this investigation and hired like private investigators and basically what they did is verify based on P eyes and like spying on you and all sorts of craziness that yes, I certified that the person I gave this certificate to is the person they say they are.
Speaker 0: But then once they do you are now trusted and inside and then you can make as many certificates as you want.
Speaker 1: They have to continue to watch you Revoke that certificate.
Speaker 1: the second you fuck up, right?
Speaker 0: You'll have a private key that you can use the sign all your certificates.
Speaker 1: that would cost a lot of money.
Speaker 1: And again, no one can pay for that but the rich people.
Speaker 0: that's something else to think about right is Right.
Speaker 0: Imagine if you know, I saw it.
Speaker 0: Let's pretend it's like some magical fantasy land, right?
Speaker 0: I sign all my certificates.
Speaker 0: you sign all yours.
Speaker 0: Joe signs.
Speaker 1: Oh the way PGP is supposed to work, right?
Speaker 0: Everyone signs their own certificates, right?
Speaker 0: And you know, everyone is sort of individually trusted now, right?
Speaker 0: So that means let's say something crazy happens and someone breaks my private key.
Speaker 0: Well only my certificates are in trouble right now.
Speaker 0: if I get like the Verisign private key I can fucking make certificates or fucking at all.
Speaker 0: The internet is fucked totally fucked and it's only one private key just one Right for like a lot a lot of certificates.
Speaker 0: It would be much more secure if we had lots of different private keys for lots of different certificates from everybody in terms of encryption You know side of the thing.
Speaker 1: Well, here's another.
Speaker 1: what if we had trust through consensus to where everyone has their own private key and You can sign or trust other people's keys.
Speaker 1: So my private key, I trust the real Amazon certificate.
Speaker 1: So the real Amazon certificate has you know, 10 million people have trusted it.
Speaker 1: Amazon has the 500 people in the small botnet trusting it.
Speaker 0: Oh, that wouldn't be bad like because most people, you know, most internet people wouldn't bother it, right?
Speaker 0: But all of the web people would go around Trusting certificates like they'd be like walking around with petitions like hey dude from this other website.
Speaker 0: I know you know, trust me.
Speaker 0: Hey all my listeners to this podcast.
Speaker 1: Now you need you to sign our certificate and trust us System to where you signing has weight depending on how many people have signed yours in this kind of clusterfuck.
Speaker 1: Yeah The problem with that is that who where do my root certificates come from?
Speaker 0: Basically, whoever has the most Twitter followers against the most security?
Speaker 1: not only that but alright.
Speaker 1: So I write a spam bot that just generates a billion certificates that all sign each other.
Speaker 1: So that doesn't yeah.
Speaker 0: But the thing is that wouldn't be attached to anyone in your web of trust.
Speaker 0: So your trust level for it would be zero because you had have no connections to that insular network.
Speaker 0: See, it's it's a whole trust network situation.
Speaker 1: The thing is they we can't really get into it.
Speaker 1: But the logistics of that and then math of that is I could I could make that in my laboratory.
Speaker 0: Don't ask me to make it for the Internet.
Speaker 1: So that would be one of those like everyone bands together for peace and prosperity.
Speaker 0: I can make it in my laboratory and it would be like.
Speaker 0: that would be the kind of thing you would give someone is Like a CS project in college.
Speaker 0: It would not be something that you would actually be able to make happen in the world.
Speaker 0: It'd be like, you know, it'd be a good like question like here's the web of trust.
Speaker 0: how much should Joe trust Jake?
Speaker 0: You know, he's like, well Joe should just shake three three trust three trust.
Speaker 0: Much you know Mary.
Speaker 0: trust, you know Jake.
Speaker 0: now that Jay, you know, Joe doesn't trust Jake anymore zero trust.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like one other way.
Speaker 1: The you know.
Speaker 1: again what this really comes down to is identity.
Speaker 1: and way back and open everything.
Speaker 1: New York City.
Speaker 1: Was it 2008 was 2009?
Speaker 1: It was eight because it was still warm out.
Speaker 1: was it or was it not that long ago?
Speaker 1: And I'm just.
Speaker 1: and maybe it was spring.
Speaker 0: I think it was spring.
Speaker 1: I don't already don't remember.
Speaker 0: I'll say all nine.
Speaker 1: I was wearing the shirt like yesterday.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the first open everything, New York City.
Speaker 1: one of the things that I brought up and talked about a great deal was the idea that In the future going forward the most important thing to solve on the internet and in the world is identity and the most important commodity in the world is being able to prove reliably who you are and What it really comes down to is when everyone is born.
Speaker 1: They need to be given a USB key that has their private key.
Speaker 0: What about are you doing USBs done?
Speaker 1: Well, you know when I say USB key I mean whatever technology.
Speaker 1: at the time we implant a chip in you out.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: You have to have scaling technology to where everyone is issued a private key.
Speaker 1: That is used the way social security numbers are now and you sign things with that And if you lose it you have to report it to the government.
Speaker 1: then they revoke it and then they give you a new One.
Speaker 1: maybe you have to reapply for it every ten years the same way to your driver's license And it expires.
Speaker 1: and all that sort of business.
Speaker 1: and until we have some sort of thing like that There's basically no way to solve this or a thousand other internet problems, you know.
Speaker 0: And in fact, actually if you think about it, right if the government set up some sort of private key system for every citizen You know, it had all the public keys in this giant database and everyone had their own private key in some secure fashion The government a lot of the government's other work would go away
Speaker 1: You know
Speaker 0: like to be a lot of things these wouldn't have to do if they could set that up and make it work Like a lot of other things.
Speaker 0: they wouldn't have to do so much.
Speaker 0: They would just be really easy because you just use the private keys and public keys for it like the mail.
Speaker 0: He's just.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: private keys send mail, you know, Oh driver's licenses.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't need a driver's license ID You know, oh, you know, you know everyone, you know signing things.
Speaker 0: notaries wouldn't need.
Speaker 0: him wouldn't need the whole notary thing at all.
Speaker 0: I forget his notarize everything themselves by digitally signing it.
Speaker 1: If you did it with an issued private key that was hashed with some security wouldn't need some biometric.
Speaker 1: Then you eliminate pretty much every Bay, oh great.
Speaker 1: We've solved everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't need some security cards We don't.
Speaker 0: you know taxes got to fill out all these tax forms.
Speaker 0: I mean when you fill out taxes today, you still need to write down name address, right?
Speaker 0: Imagine you just did your taxes and you just you know, signed it with your private key and then the you know The IRS, you know took a public key and set up.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: This was definitely written.
Speaker 1: How bullshit is it that I signed something with my pen and Fax it and it's more reliable than like a PGP signature because people in court don't understand signatures and contracts.
Speaker 0: Everything would be easy because if you signed a contract Provable that you signed it and I was digging around in my trash They found some mail that was thrown away and they applied for a credit card in my name.
Speaker 0: If they don't have my private key, how could they sign it?
Speaker 0: They can't Right, you know all these problems just go away if they would do this one thing.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: However, then people worried about like, you know government ID systems and all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: Basically, all we're doing is give everyone everyone a number that you hold on to and never have to show to anyone In fact never should show to anyone and should never be.
Speaker 0: well under no circumstances Ever be forced to show it to anyone.
Speaker 0: court judge police government official Nobody will you ever have to show that number?
Speaker 0: All you will ever be required to do is sign things with the number then hand over the signed Thing which can then be verified with the public key.
Speaker 0: you will and you know And in fact, you'll be strongly encouraged never to show the private key to anyone not even family members Not even your own mother and nobody zero
Speaker 1: and in fact,
Speaker 0: so it's not like, you know
Speaker 1: Obviously, we can't have the midwife every time a cat child is born give them their key and then kill them.
Speaker 1: So
Speaker 0: now you'd have to have some sort of system where like, you know Eventually, you're not gonna need this number when you're in say elementary school, you know, maybe right We'll have some sort of system where you know, you go into a booth and it you know It's a sealed booth and the machine generates the key puts the private public key in a database Prints out the private key somehow to give to you onto a device or a Piece of paper who knows what and then erases it from its memory and then you step out of the booth.
Speaker 0: It's that simple.
Speaker 0: There you go done And you could use that to sign your SSL search on your website and people would know, you know That was definitely signed by this person.
Speaker 0: If there's a discrepancy they could look up in the government and you know.
Speaker 0: Well, you are.
Speaker 1: we've solved the problem that for the first time on gig nights.
Speaker 1: We solved it.
Speaker 1: It's done.
Speaker 1: Thanks, yeah, thanks for listening.
Speaker 0: there's never gonna happen.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share a like 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit.
Speaker 0: don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.