Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, May 26th.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: We're back from Anime Boston, and we talk about two board games, Oshii and Tsuru.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I woke up this morning, and the sun was coming in the windows, and like, I was feeling pretty awake, and it was, you know, I heard stuff going on outside, and I was like, "Oh, what time is
Speaker 0: it?".
Speaker 0: It's probably like six something, right?
Speaker 0: I'll get get up and get ready, right?
Speaker 0: So I look at the iPhone.
Speaker 1: All right, it was either way earlier than you expected or way later.
Speaker 0: It was 5 30, but it felt like 6 30, so I was like, "Spring ahead, fall
Speaker 0: back.".
Speaker 1: It's not that day.
Speaker 0: It's not that.
Speaker 0: I'm like, "What the
Speaker 0: fuck?".
Speaker 0: And it was literally 5 30, but it felt like 6 30, which can only mean, I don't know, but I felt awake, and it was sort of fucked up.
Speaker 1: Were you traveling at the speed of light?
Speaker 0: Not this again, yeah.
Speaker 0: It may have been, and it was weird because I went to bed kind of late after playing some Awesome Left 4 Dead last night, so I don't know what was up with that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you did, because I came home and went straight to bed, because I was wrecked from the con, and I couldn't even talk.
Speaker 0: You know, midnight-ish.
Speaker 0: So to only sleep five and a half hours, to feel really awake.
Speaker 0: You know, every now and then, though.
Speaker 0: And for it to look like 6 30 outside.
Speaker 1: Every now and then, like, it's weird.
Speaker 1: I'll have certain, I used to call them, like, magic nights.
Speaker 1: Like, sometimes you stay up.
Speaker 0: Magic night.
Speaker 1: Magic night, right here.
Speaker 1: You stay up way late, or you're tired, or it's one of those nights where you really want to be well-rested the next day, and you know you're not going to be, but for some reason, the night lasts forever.
Speaker 1: Like, you fall asleep, and you kind of, like, wake up, and you feel like you've slept for a whole night, and it's only been, like, a half hour, and you go, "Ahh," and go back to bed.
Speaker 0: Well, see, I think it may have had something to do with the fact, right, that the previous night, you know, I guess, I woke up on Monday at, like, 9 something, which is, like, for the past long time, when I've, you know, had a chance to sleep as much as I wanted, I've always woken up at, like, 8 something, you know?
Speaker 0: So, to wake up at 9 was weird, and I think, you know, that was probably because we had just returned from the Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Not just that, but Anime Boston, we, I don't know, we handled it differently from the way we've handled most conventions we've been to in recent memory.
Speaker 0: Well, whenever we go without a whole bunch of people, it's always different.
Speaker 1: It felt a lot more like PAX, partly because the convention center is almost, like, very similar to the one in Seattle.
Speaker 0: Oh, with the escalators, yeah.
Speaker 1: With, like, the middle column of escalators, and the multi-levels, and the...
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the back walls.
Speaker 1: And the separate building with the gaming in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we should, like, you know how they study, like, you know, there's different designers of stadiums, and there's different designers of golf courses, and designers of racetracks.
Speaker 0: There's probably designers of convention centers.
Speaker 0: We should find out who they are.
Speaker 1: Their names were all on the wall by the open of the front.
Speaker 0: Oh, we gotta look at that shit.
Speaker 0: They're probably just, like, you know, it's important, like, looking at rollercoaster designers.
Speaker 1: It was cool.
Speaker 1: It was this old, like, marble, you know, cast thing with, like, everything carved into it, like, the names of all the architects.
Speaker 0: Sure, it didn't just say, like, mayor of Boston, and governor who provided the money.
Speaker 1: I'm sure, because it listed the architects, and the designers, and all these people, and at the bottom, carved into marble, it said HVAC, and then the name of the company that did the HVAC.
Speaker 0: You know, I should get myself a freaking chisel.
Speaker 1: For a second, no, I looked at the bottom, and I was, like, H. The fuck number is H.
Speaker 0: Oh, you were looking for the Roman numerals.
Speaker 1: And then I was, like, oh.
Speaker 0: I should get a chisel, and learn how to chisel the way that, you know, those things are done, and get mad skilled at it, and then, like, chisel my name into things in a way that no one will recognize that it's out of place.
Speaker 1: That is very similar to one of my favorite pranks of all time.
Speaker 1: This guy went into a mall, right?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And it had, like, they had this restaurant, like, one of those mall restaurants, and the sign had, like, these bronze, like, an apple, and a banana, and some grapes, like, around the side.
Speaker 1: So we went in at night.
Speaker 0: Oh, and he added a different fruit, yeah.
Speaker 1: He took out the banana, and he put, like, a watermelon, and then he kept changing the fruits, like, every month, and eventually someone noticed.
Speaker 0: Oh.
Speaker 1: I gotta find that and make it a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: It was pretty cool.
Speaker 0: That's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: But yeah, we will talk about Anime Boston more tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Welcome, welcome, welcome to, uh, Cake Nights, not Zombocom.
Speaker 0: No, not Zombocom.
Speaker 1: All the people we met in Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: I know there were a ton of you.
Speaker 1: Tomorrow night is Wednesday night.
Speaker 1: We talk about anime and all that stuff, and we will have coverage of Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: We will also have uploaded the slides from Cover Your Bases, aka Anime.
Speaker 1: You Should See, and Know Your Creators, because a lot of you were asking for them.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: But tonight is not Wednesday, it is Tuesday, and we're talking not about anime, but about video games.
Speaker 0: That's alright, because there were lots of games going on in Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So, if you're in Anime Boston, you're probably a gamer type.
Speaker 0: I hope so, anyway.
Speaker 1: In fact, I was very proud of those punk kids that we played Magic with.
Speaker 0: We didn't play Magic with them.
Speaker 0: They were playing Magic.
Speaker 0: We played Blockus with them.
Speaker 1: They wanted to play Magic.
Speaker 1: They had their Magic cards, and we tricked them into playing Blockus, and they proved that some punk kids who play Magic can also appreciate a real game.
Speaker 0: I like how one of the kids had played it in math class, and he thought it was cool.
Speaker 0: You know that's nerds right there.
Speaker 0: There's no way.
Speaker 1: Those kids were exactly like I was when I was 14.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's what I was gonna say.
Speaker 0: It was like, "Wow, you're me when I was 14,
Speaker 0: kid.".
Speaker 0: However, I cannot- Look into our future!
Speaker 1: I cannot any more tell what age anyone younger than me is.
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 0: So, for all I know, they were anywhere between- It was pretty much high school and middle school.
Speaker 0: That's all I can tell.
Speaker 1: They were anywhere between 11 and 18, as far as I was concerned.
Speaker 0: I can tell high school or middle school usually, and that's about it.
Speaker 1: The thing that really strikes me is you ever go into an elementary school, go to the second grade room, and you look at those desks, and they're like the size of your shoes.
Speaker 0: I know, right?
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: So, there is actually- You ever sit on a school bus?
Speaker 0: I sat on one recently, because last year they were using it to shuttle you from the parking lot to the giant stadium.
Speaker 1: Scott, you, me, and Emily went to a Mets game, and we took a school bus from the parking lot.
Speaker 0: It was better than the giant stadium one.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, when I used to be living in Poquay, they shut down all the trains for some construction, so they would take me from Southeast up to Poquay in a school bus.
Speaker 0: Not like a normal city bus?
Speaker 1: No, it was like a school bus.
Speaker 1: So, it'd be like me and all these fancily dressed people who went into the city to see a show, and they'd just be sitting on the bus like, "Oh, I'll choir into
Speaker 1: funds.".
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So, Starfy, one of the few games, I don't know, in a long time I've for some ungodly reason been excited about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I really like puzzle platforming games, and it seems like what Starfy is, right?
Speaker 1: Starfy also has that kind of curvy feel to it, just the graphic design, but a little bit of Mega Man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, and I got, you know, a Henry Hatsworth puzzling adventure, and that is, I assumed it was going to be a puzzle platformer, but a puzzle platformer it is not.
Speaker 0: It is a puzzler and a platformer that are barely attached at the hip, that are not merged.
Speaker 1: Way back when we saw videos of Starfy, which is properly known as Densetsu no Starfy, Taiketsu, Daru, Kaizo Dukan.
Speaker 0: Even a cute game.
Speaker 1: Kaizo Kudan.
Speaker 0: Even a cute game in Japanese can be made to sound non-cute if you don't know what it means and you say it in a Yakuza voice.
Speaker 1: I don't know, though, because the translation is Legendary Starfy Confrontation, Dire Pirate Squad.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: Maybe it's supposed to sound all Yakuza.
Speaker 1: But watch the video if you don't know what we're talking about.
Speaker 1: This game looks pretty badass, I guess.
Speaker 0: So a game is coming out, that's the news?
Speaker 1: We assumed, everyone who saw these videos immediately assumed, yeah, that game's never going to be in the US.
Speaker 1: This is a game we're going to have to import.
Speaker 0: I didn't even know about it until they announced it was coming in the US.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, I saw videos of it way back, and I just felt, oh, we're never going to see this.
Speaker 1: It is actually coming out in the second week in June, June 7th.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's actually really soon.
Speaker 1: But the story here, what I find interesting, is that according to Kotaku, themselves, according to Hitoshi Yamagami, who is the producer of the game, said that the game was not going to come out in America, despite the fact that the developers really wanted it to.
Speaker 1: They wanted it to be overseas.
Speaker 1: But Nintendo of America said it was, quote, "too Japanese," unquote, and vetoed it.
Speaker 1: So I don't know what circumstance caused this game to come out in America anyway, but I'm excited.
Speaker 0: Well, here is my guess.
Speaker 0: Number one, Nintendo of Japan overrules Nintendo of America, because it's the boss versus the worker, right?
Speaker 1: Well, now, Nintendo of America seemed to have a lot more say a long time ago, in the NES days, with all the censorship and whatnot.
Speaker 0: Really, Nintendo of America, first of all, remember, they sort of closed out, and they moved all the people, they shrunk the office and everything.
Speaker 0: And basically, all they really do is sell the stuff the Japanese people make in the US.
Speaker 0: And they also do the adaptations and those sorts of things, but they don't really make anything.
Speaker 1: Well, remember Square versus Squaresoft?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know, right?
Speaker 0: The thing is, being in America, we think about Nintendo of America as if they do more, but really, they don't make, do they?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure they don't make any games.
Speaker 1: I'm not actually 100% sure, to be honest.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so also, I think what happened here is, number one, it's a case where the Japanese and the Americans are both right, right?
Speaker 0: Japanese Nintendo was right.
Speaker 0: If I had Reggie's job, I could have sold Starfy and made it a big hit.
Speaker 0: I guarantee it.
Speaker 0: But on the other hand, Nintendo of America is right.
Speaker 0: Starfy is probably not going to sell very well, because they're not going to do what I would do, which is be really risky and push it real hard to the right demographics in the right way.
Speaker 1: Of course, then again, look at what Nintendo did with the first Layton.
Speaker 1: They pushed that at anime and gaming conventions as hard as they could.
Speaker 0: Wrong choice.
Speaker 1: All right, who do you push that at?
Speaker 0: My mom.
Speaker 1: So how do you market that to your mom?
Speaker 0: Lots of money, put it on the daytime soaps.
Speaker 1: Your mom watches daytime soaps?
Speaker 0: No, but some other moms do.
Speaker 1: So how do you get your mom, the mom who's going to like this, as opposed to your daytime soap mom?
Speaker 0: Involve longer burger baskets in some way.
Speaker 0: My mom collects these stupid baskets.
Speaker 1: What are these baskets?
Speaker 0: I'm not going to explain the longer burger basket.
Speaker 0: You can go look it up on Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: Wait, as in a burger that's long?
Speaker 0: No, that's just the name of the company.
Speaker 1: But longer burger?
Speaker 0: That's correct.
Speaker 1: Is that just a hot dog?
Speaker 0: Well, I think it's B-E-R-G-E-R.
Speaker 1: What if you made a hot dog?
Speaker 1: If you just rolled up a hamburger into the shape of a hot dog, cook that and put it on a hot dog bun.
Speaker 0: My mom might think it was a funny joke if you called it a longer burger, but that's about it.
Speaker 1: I would probably eat it.
Speaker 0: I would also eat it.
Speaker 1: Starfies coming out in the US.
Speaker 1: I'm going to tell you all to buy the game, but I don't know if it'll be good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If you don't know if the game's going to be good, right?
Speaker 0: It's a platformer, so you probably don't need to know so much Japanese.
Speaker 0: You could probably pirate it and test it out and not buy it at all.
Speaker 1: Not longer burger, it's longa burger.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's it.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, I see what they do here.
Speaker 1: Your mom is basically a member of a cult.
Speaker 0: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: They have a big factory shaped like a basket.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: The thing is she only went to the basket factory like once or twice.
Speaker 0: She has a friend who's even more crazy that goes to the basket factory and like an annual pilgrimage.
Speaker 1: These are just beanie babies.
Speaker 0: Pretty much, yeah.
Speaker 0: Except she actually uses the baskets.
Speaker 1: They set you up just like Tupperware.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 1: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: She uses like, she's got one bag.
Speaker 0: She's the thing is, right?
Speaker 0: She uses the baskets.
Speaker 0: She actually uses them, which is good, right?
Speaker 0: But it's bad because like one basket could serve.
Speaker 1: If I host a longer burger basket event, I will get 500 longer burger dollars.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And I don't host his dollars and free shipping and handling and bonus offers.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Good gobs.
Speaker 0: But if you, I'm not collecting the baskets.
Speaker 0: What are you looking at me?
Speaker 0: She's got a different basket for each thing.
Speaker 0: So she has a specific basket for candy corn on Halloween and another specific basket, like for...
Speaker 1: Scott, there are baskets that are the shapes of all pre-existing bowls.
Speaker 1: And you take the bowl you have and put it in the basket.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: Don't ask me why.
Speaker 1: The bowl already serves the purpose.
Speaker 0: What are you asking me for?
Speaker 0: I agree with you.
Speaker 0: I'm not wasting my money on baskets.
Speaker 1: I can design my own basket.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you can also, if you go there, you can make your own basket.
Speaker 1: I'm making my own basket right now.
Speaker 1: So what's your news?
Speaker 0: So my news is also a similar...
Speaker 1: Oh, it's going to be a berry basket.
Speaker 0: It's a similar US to Japan situation.
Speaker 0: A game that really no one ever expected to come out in the US is probably coming out in the US, the Tatsunoko versus Capcom.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That's really coming out in the US?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: I can't act surprised.
Speaker 1: This was mentioned at Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: So I think this is important for two reasons.
Speaker 0: Number one, it shows that Capcom is still the company that knows what's up.
Speaker 0: They got on top of their game a while ago when they made Mega Man 9 and Bionic Commander Rearmed, and they are still on top.
Speaker 0: Capcom is still sitting in the number one game maker's seat for the time being.
Speaker 1: Oh, I can add a paw print to my basket.
Speaker 1: And number two, I'm a hockey player.
Speaker 1: There's a hockey player right there.
Speaker 0: Number two, that's for carrying the pucks out onto the ice and off the ice after practice.
Speaker 0: And I'm pretty sure there was not a battle between Capcom, Japan, and if they have a separate US branch over whether or not to bring it out here.
Speaker 0: But I wonder, right, you know, this game will probably sell really well with the people who care about this sort of thing and perhaps also with some fighting game fans.
Speaker 0: But I mean, really, what kind of sales do they think this is going to have?
Speaker 0: People like Tatsunoko, what the fuck?
Speaker 0: All those sorts of games that sold well in the US were the Marvel versus Capcom or, you know, the ones where people are X, you know, the ones that were.
Speaker 0: people knew the characters when they tried to bring over like, you know, SNK versus Capcom.
Speaker 0: Only fighting game fanboys bought.
Speaker 1: Yes, but maybe they realize maybe they're doing the same thing that superhero comics in the US do.
Speaker 1: They know that they have a fairly large, insane fan base.
Speaker 1: I mean, the people who play SNK versus whatever and are good at it and play all those games, they will buy any of those games, especially because they're going to play in the tournaments.
Speaker 1: And you know that the convention circuit now is going to have this game be like the tournament.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, if you look at it, though, in the way I just described, you got to think, A Capcom versus SNK, I guess it did well enough, right?
Speaker 0: Sold to only the fighting game fanboys.
Speaker 0: This will sell to fighting game fanboys and anime fanboys.
Speaker 0: Double play.
Speaker 0: It's not going to be huge, but that's better than right.
Speaker 0: Maybe, maybe, maybe, maybe.
Speaker 0: I don't know why.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They don't just make Capcom versus SNK versus Marvel versus Tatsunoko.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 1: They will.
Speaker 0: Why don't they just do it?
Speaker 1: Here's the way to do it.
Speaker 0: There should be a million.
Speaker 0: There should be like 100 screens full of characters that no one can even figure it out.
Speaker 1: That's how I make one game and sell it once when you can break that into 10 games and I'll tell you why.
Speaker 0: I will tell you why.
Speaker 0: Here's what they should do.
Speaker 0: I have if my idea was the idea to make things the best possible way for the fan.
Speaker 1: Wait, because I have an idea.
Speaker 1: Are you ready for it?
Speaker 1: Modularly.
Speaker 0: I was about to tell you the way to make the most money is to sell a fighting game that only has the Street Fighter two characters.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then sell packs of 10 characters for like five dollars and everyone has to download all the packs or five bucks each.
Speaker 1: You got to rate it.
Speaker 1: You got to rank the prices differently.
Speaker 1: For example, much like you could probably sell a guitar.
Speaker 0: It costs ten dollars to get the characters who are cheap.
Speaker 1: Much like you could sell one dollar to get the losers.
Speaker 1: No one likes you make of all equally powerful or you sell like Dolly outfits for him too.
Speaker 1: But much like you could sell Guitar Hero Stairway Edition for like fifty bucks on its own and people would probably buy it.
Speaker 1: You sell Wolverine for ten bucks by himself.
Speaker 1: No, but then for another dollar for another dollar, you get the clause.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think I think that's taken a little bit too far.
Speaker 0: But yeah, the obvious way to make the most money is to sell just like Street Fighter two and then so all these character packs actually put it on the Street Fighter four engine.
Speaker 0: That would do it.
Speaker 0: Street Fighter four engine.
Speaker 0: All the characters sell the characters and packs of 10 done.
Speaker 0: Big money.
Speaker 0: Capcom wins.
Speaker 1: But anyway, in things of the day, I've got a story from North America.
Speaker 0: No snaps.
Speaker 1: So at Anime Boston, we attended the much lauded Anime Hell.
Speaker 0: We had known about the Anime Hell for quite some time, but never attended.
Speaker 1: Not at least in fullness.
Speaker 1: But we went and it anime hell things like that in anime conventions are basically you go and people show you weird stuff that you've probably never seen before.
Speaker 1: And of course, this is a lot more difficult now that YouTube makes everything available.
Speaker 1: And yeah, I mean, there are a lot of people who try to do events like this, but you show up and those are all on CollegeHumor last week.
Speaker 0: I fully expected that most of the things would not be things I had seen, but I was actually, you know, even though I expected it, I was still surprised that I had not seen 90% of what I was shown.
Speaker 1: But this animation far, far above and beyond anything I've seen in recent memory, partly because it was late, partly because it was unexpectedly bizarre, and partly because the song has just been stuck in my head since Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Fuck this song.
Speaker 1: What if it did?
Speaker 1: What if it didn't?
Speaker 1: What if the world was made of pudding?
Speaker 1: This is indescribable and you all need to watch it and show it to other people.
Speaker 1: I warn you, the song will be stuck in your head.
Speaker 1: And two, I don't know, the body language, the posture, the way that that father enters that child's room is more frightening than anything I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: It's very aggressive.
Speaker 1: It's the most aggressive possible body posture.
Speaker 0: It reminds the dad.
Speaker 0: The style of the dad reminds me a lot of the Ren and Stimpy guy, Cricka Flusi.
Speaker 0: How do you, I don't even know how to say his name.
Speaker 0: Just look at the way he's standing in the room.
Speaker 1: It's like he's about to murder and rape the child.
Speaker 0: What's your favorite part?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: What if he did?
Speaker 1: What if he didn't?
Speaker 1: And when the spider kills the kid.
Speaker 0: When the spider, no, I like it.
Speaker 0: when the spider has like the knife to the kid's throat.
Speaker 1: That's a good part, but not as good.
Speaker 1: I think is when the spider just kills the kid with the poking in the face, just the stab in the eye.
Speaker 0: That's a good part too.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Just the song.
Speaker 1: I listened to it last night before I went to sleep.
Speaker 0: So I've been like, you know, I've been subscribing to video podcasts now with my iPhone.
Speaker 0: You know, I started with the Onion News video, which is far superior to the Onion News radio.
Speaker 0: And then I moved on to the, uh, the Ted talks, you know, which is, so now I can just watch all of them without having to go to the website or anything.
Speaker 0: And actually, um, old Jews telling jokes has one now also.
Speaker 0: So I'm going to watch, I'm going to watch that.
Speaker 1: And also video podcasts that really, like it started petering out after the first several.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, everyone told all the good jokes right away, but there's a whole bunch I haven't seen yet.
Speaker 0: So I'm going to see if there's any gems in there and I will filter them out for you.
Speaker 1: It has to beat the dropkin fart.
Speaker 0: I don't know if we can beat the dropkin fart, but you can get close.
Speaker 0: Anyway, um, so there's a Ted talk.
Speaker 0: I watched today and I, you know, I think what happened to Ted, I think they just wanted to get so many speakers in that a lot of them are like doing shorter bits.
Speaker 0: So this guy did like a three or four minute bit and you know, it didn't directly have anything to do with gaming whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Well, neither did rims thing of the day, but I think this indirectly applies to things, uh, gaming related, at least things the way I think about them.
Speaker 0: And, uh, it's a bit of a stretch, but whatever.
Speaker 0: So in this video, this, uh, guy explains how they took these kids and they gave them, they're like four year olds, six year olds, whatever.
Speaker 0: And they gave them a marshmallow, but they told them, you're going to wait here with this marshmallow for 15 minutes and we're going to leave.
Speaker 0: And if we come back in 15 minutes and the marshmallow is still there, we will give you another marshmallow and then you will have two marshmallows.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And he explained how quite shockingly, right?
Speaker 0: Two out of three kids ate the marshmallow.
Speaker 1: Is it really that shocking?
Speaker 0: No, it's a four year old.
Speaker 0: The shocking part comes next.
Speaker 1: It's not even a five year old.
Speaker 0: shocking part comes next.
Speaker 1: It's not even at the point of the five year old.
Speaker 0: And one third of the kids sort of resisted the marshmallow and then got two marshmallows.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The shocking part is that they came back years later and found those same kids.
Speaker 0: Cause when you do a study on kids, you rattle the names down and then you can go find them later.
Speaker 0: So they found them later and they found out that, you know, 100%, 100%, that's the shocking number of the kids who resisted the marshmallow were successful by the general definition, you know, good grades in school, et cetera, et cetera.
Speaker 0: And not 100%, but a large percentage of the two thirds that did eat the marshmallow were not as successful by that general standard of good grades in school, money, jobs, et cetera, et cetera.
Speaker 1: The guy basically sums it up in the video as people who have the ability to delay gratification for a greater reward later will succeed almost universally.
Speaker 0: And the way this relates to gaming in my eyes, I may be stretching it, but whatever, because I'm curious where you're going to go with this because there's the, I guess what road I'm going down.
Speaker 1: Well, there are two roads to go down.
Speaker 1: There's the prescriptive, you know, you can either go down the road that, you know, you can use this principle to make better games or that's a good, I didn't think of that one.
Speaker 1: I know that's the one I figured that you didn't think of, but the one you're probably thinking of is that you can use games or the popularity of certain games to determine whether or not people are going to be successful.
Speaker 0: Well, that was one thing I was thinking.
Speaker 1: The marshmallow game worked pretty well and a world of Warcraft so far works pretty well.
Speaker 0: And you've hit where exactly where I was headed, right?
Speaker 0: Perhaps the reason that people like us do not like the world of Warcraft is this world of Warcraft is a game of instant and constant gratification.
Speaker 0: It's basically a game that keeps putting mushrooms, uh, marshmallows in front of you and you keep eating them and you keep getting more.
Speaker 0: So people who are the type that will just eat the marshmallow, the unsuccessful types will play world of Warcraft and just eat all these marshmallows and have a grand old time.
Speaker 0: Whereas we prefer games that most people hate hard games, games that suck games, games that have a lot of, you know, strategies and such, and are only rewarding if you actually win and suffer a great deal to get to the end.
Speaker 0: Those are the games that we like being successful.
Speaker 1: marshmallow resistors would not say that German board games are only fun if you win.
Speaker 0: I would not say that either, but you just did perhaps.
Speaker 0: But did I say the word German board games?
Speaker 0: No, I said hard games.
Speaker 0: There are easy German boards.
Speaker 1: There are even games that we don't like.
Speaker 0: There are many games we don't like.
Speaker 1: I respect age of steam.
Speaker 1: That is a good game.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I don't like.
Speaker 0: go enjoy playing.
Speaker 1: age of steam.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I said it was a stretch and I am obviously generalizing and thus in, you know, introducing a lots of falsities on the fringes and the extreme cases and the not so extreme cases.
Speaker 0: However, I do think that, but I make a point.
Speaker 1: Nonetheless, I do think that use it as a player in a game who wants to win.
Speaker 1: This principle is very important because a lot of games unintentionally thinking of it that way.
Speaker 1: That's no, that's the third way games either intentionally or not.
Speaker 1: Mostly the fourth way is the moon game, right?
Speaker 1: But intentionally or not, a lot of games have mechanics where you can get an immediate reward now.
Speaker 1: Like in, Oh, she, we're going to talk about a little bit.
Speaker 1: I can push your one off right now.
Speaker 1: Instant gratification, or I can not push him off, leave him threatened and use that as leverage to go after your two and three pieces.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, but in terms of, you know, and also you could, what about mechanisms design of mechanism design, make games that encourage implicitly the holding off and get kids to play them to teach them this principle if they don't already have it.
Speaker 1: That's a good one.
Speaker 1: Because the very fascinating thing about this video is that they went at four year olds.
Speaker 1: I wonder what the factor is that will cause a child to be able to do this or not.
Speaker 0: I am very interested in that as well.
Speaker 1: Is it genetic?
Speaker 0: He said that they were teaching kids to resist gratification in South Korea.
Speaker 0: So I wonder exactly how they're doing that teaching.
Speaker 1: Because the interesting thing is, is that going to work?
Speaker 0: He said they made like a book, like a marshmallow book.
Speaker 1: Or is that just a bandaid over a deeper behavioral thing?
Speaker 0: I also won.
Speaker 0: It was only four minutes, so he did not have time to tell us more information.
Speaker 1: I mean, the example I would use is that someone who was born autistic cannot be not autistic anymore, but you can use, if they have like very severe autism, you can use behavioral training to give them a better chance of integrating into society.
Speaker 1: It doesn't actually make the autism better.
Speaker 1: It just makes the appearance and the interaction better.
Speaker 1: It makes it as a result easier on the person.
Speaker 1: And while the net benefit is definitely there, it may not be as much of a benefit as some people think who don't study it more thoroughly.
Speaker 1: I think with this, it could be the same thing.
Speaker 1: I mean, maybe there is a don't eat the marshmallow gene.
Speaker 0: Maybe here's my final angle on this, right?
Speaker 0: If you want to make a video game that sells a fuck ton and everyone loves, basically the games you just keep giving your marshmallows the whole way through.
Speaker 0: That way, those two thirds of people who are marshmallow eaters will love it.
Speaker 0: And the game should also give you twice as many marshmallows if you don't eat the marshmallows along the way.
Speaker 0: So the one third and then everyone will love the game.
Speaker 0: It'll be psychologically fulfilling to all.
Speaker 1: If you could add that, if you could somehow add greater reward for delayed gratification to World of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: That might be bad.
Speaker 0: Hey, you know, hey, if you don't grind and you don't, it's like, don't pick up all the it's like you get some loot.
Speaker 0: If you don't pick it up and keep not picking it up and keep not doing what leveling up, then eventually you'll get even better than what you would have gotten because you know what will happen, what will happen with World of Warcraft players.
Speaker 1: They will grind one character all the way and then they'll have another account and I'll have that other character not grind and they'll do both at the same time.
Speaker 1: Effectively, you're still grinding.
Speaker 1: Perhaps as someone who played the realm a lot back in the day, I would have done something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But you see the point that I think the more interesting tech is to look at this concept and try to make games that do.
Speaker 1: I mean, the carrot stick model is pretty solid.
Speaker 1: World of Warcraft is perfect.
Speaker 0: Instead of carrots and sticks, we should move to marshmallows.
Speaker 1: No, marshmallow management.
Speaker 1: Maybe there are models of carrot stick that we haven't explored yet or ratios we haven't explored yet.
Speaker 1: that might in the end to make more rewarding games.
Speaker 0: Perhaps there are many also areas in which I could explore this marshmallow idea outside of the gaming realm, but it's Tuesday, so that will be held up.
Speaker 1: I do note, Scott, that if we play Advance Wars, you have no capacity to not immediately eat the marshmallow.
Speaker 0: That is true.
Speaker 0: But there are other games where I will not eat the marshmallow ever.
Speaker 0: In fact, it will get to the end of the game.
Speaker 0: I'll get a pile of marshmallows and still not eat any.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 1: Then there are games like OSHI where you'll basically choke yourself on marshmallows.
Speaker 0: It's totally game dependent, so who knows?
Speaker 1: At Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: I'm successful, so whatever.
Speaker 1: Well, that's debatable.
Speaker 0: Well, by his definitions of good grades, jobs, etc.
Speaker 1: In the university.
Speaker 1: Good grades?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but grades didn't really matter.
Speaker 1: Maybe that was a delayed gratification.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'm the girl who ate the inside of the marshmallow and is going to be successful, but should not work at the bank.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: That girl was like convulsing like an addict.
Speaker 1: She reminded me of Shall I warm, sirs, crack pile.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: At Anime Boston, you know, we're friends with like all the people who are in Connecticut and they had a booth set up and, you know, board games were for sale at Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: And it just so happened that two games that we had known about did not own had did not play, didn't know anything about other than that.
Speaker 1: They were made by whiz kids.
Speaker 0: I knew about one of the games, which is no more because I had played it at the.
Speaker 0: basically the story begins when I went to the NYC nerd gaming night with Alex.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And some coworker, Brian, I think his name was and whatever.
Speaker 0: We played a game called.
Speaker 0: we played a game of Vinci, but we also played a game of Tsuro, which is a game I had seen many times in stores right on shelves.
Speaker 0: But I never played it, but I recognized it like I've seen that game around all over the place.
Speaker 0: It was made by whiz kids.
Speaker 0: The people who made Mage Knight and Hero clicks and et cetera, et cetera, gone, they're gone.
Speaker 0: And the only successful thing I think they had was the hero clicks.
Speaker 0: I think everything else was a bust.
Speaker 0: And, you know, they got shut down by now.
Speaker 0: we were a division of tops and tops closed them out.
Speaker 1: We talked at length at Anime Boston with some other gamer people and the head of Anime Kineticon about why these kids went under and how they could have.
Speaker 1: they could have been like one of the biggest game companies should have just stuck with the hero clicks only.
Speaker 0: And they should have made.
Speaker 0: if all of their clicks games work together properly, they probably would have done all right.
Speaker 1: But instead, we got things like Mech Warrior, Mage Knight.
Speaker 0: And that game was bad.
Speaker 0: They had a thing about this tops closed whiz kids, a subdivision of whiz kids, even right, like even lower on the totem pole had was doing all the classic battle tech.
Speaker 0: So I'm pretty sure that's all dead now, too.
Speaker 1: So anyway, they had both these games.
Speaker 1: So we know we were bored hanging out.
Speaker 1: So we asked Matt to teach us how to play oshi.
Speaker 1: And he basically point at it and said, read the book.
Speaker 1: So we sit down and read the book.
Speaker 1: And now it takes like two seconds to learn how to play oshi.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the rule book is a piece of cardboard.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And then we just we just we bought oshi and suro right then and then.
Speaker 0: Because, you know, I had learned at, you know, at that game night that, you know, I played suro and discovered that it was an awesome game for two to eight players.
Speaker 0: that, you know, worked great with two to eight players.
Speaker 0: It was very easy to learn, easy to play, but also very good.
Speaker 0: You know, I played it a few times and had a lot of fun, has a dragon in it, has a dragon in it.
Speaker 0: And, you know, but they said it was out of print.
Speaker 0: So I went to.
Speaker 0: I went to Boston and we saw it in the dealer's room there at the Kineticon table.
Speaker 0: They had eight copies and I knew it was out of print and I had played it and liked it.
Speaker 0: So how can I not buy it?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Lately, I have more and more of this thing for getting out of print games, even if they're not good, just because they're out of print.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's kind of a collector mentality, but at the same time, our copy dooms real good.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: I got used on eBay.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I want to get a copy of the expansion.
Speaker 0: There's oh, there's an expansion.
Speaker 0: There are several expansions.
Speaker 0: Oh, shit.
Speaker 1: One one has burning wheel kind of combat.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: When leaders fight like it gets it's intense.
Speaker 0: It's cool.
Speaker 0: I actually like that better than the straight up win with the, you know, reveals.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If you could actually use the kind of feels are good, though.
Speaker 1: It's good game theory stuff, but it is anyway.
Speaker 1: Let's talk about Suro first, because I have less to say about it, even though it's a very good game.
Speaker 0: OK, the way Suro works right is everyone has a dude, right?
Speaker 0: It is the game of the path.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Everyone has a dude and you put your dude on the edge of the board somewhere and you can put them pretty much anywhere you want.
Speaker 0: that isn't taken already.
Speaker 0: And then on your turn, you take you have a hand of three tiles and you take a tile and put it in front of you.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And every tile is a square and every tile has two connections on each side.
Speaker 0: So there is no arrangement of tiles that will not fit.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Every edge of the board has two spots and every tile has two spots in each side.
Speaker 0: So you can always every tile fits in every spot.
Speaker 0: It's not like Carcassonne where you're going like doesn't fit there, doesn't fit.
Speaker 0: It always fits right.
Speaker 0: Your guy starts in the edge of the board, which means you can never make a loop, because if you made a loop, you would go right back where you came from.
Speaker 0: And that's not possible.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it's impossible to make a loop and you just keep playing tiles.
Speaker 0: And on your turn, all you do is put a tile in front of your guy and then slide your guy down the path until he reaches another edge until he can't go anymore.
Speaker 0: And then your next turn, you put another tile in front of you and you keep moving.
Speaker 1: Now, the game's really simple.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much whoever's on the board last wins.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Now, think about what this means.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Number one, the game really is, you know, you could say whoever's on the board last wins, but it's also whoever plays the most tiles wins.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, every turn you have to play a tile.
Speaker 0: So whoever plays the most tiles is on the board the longest.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Also, if two players are on the edge of the same square, one of them is going to go before the other one, which means you get to control the other person's movements.
Speaker 0: You really don't want to end up right in front of someone if it's, you know, their turn.
Speaker 1: But if you cause the death of another player, they go off the board, then you get a little bit of a boon.
Speaker 1: You get to pick like some of their tiles.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Like, you know, in the course of playing all these tiles, there's going to be a lot of paths that are created that are unused.
Speaker 0: Some of those paths can be used on purpose to get your guy over to like an unused area of the board.
Speaker 1: However, most of them are dead.
Speaker 0: Yes, most of them are dead.
Speaker 0: But occasionally you can use.
Speaker 0: you can go across the already existing tiles and take a big long roundabout route, because really the goal is to get your guy into a position where there's lots of empty spaces in front of him.
Speaker 0: You know, it's sort of like get to the unpaved road so I can pave it.
Speaker 0: If you're stuck in an area that doesn't have a lot of paved roads in it, you know, unpaved spots, you're pretty much going to die no matter what tiles you're in your hand, because you got nowhere to go.
Speaker 0: You have to keep paving.
Speaker 0: So getting your guy in a good position is just as important as, you know, putting the right tiles in front of you.
Speaker 1: But the really cool thing about the game is that each piece is either unique or nearly so like the pieces are all completely crazy.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Some of them are.
Speaker 0: some of them are better, though, because they give you more options.
Speaker 1: Well, you have.
Speaker 1: you have this sort of weak drafting element where you'll have three in your hand and you play one draw once.
Speaker 1: you always have a choice of three.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Except toward the end of the game when you're running out of tiles.
Speaker 1: But then you want the only way to switch up tiles is to kill someone else.
Speaker 0: Eventually, when the tiles run out, everyone stops drawing tiles and just has to use what they got.
Speaker 0: And by then, everyone's dying all over the place anyway.
Speaker 1: So it's not a big deal, you know, there's not much more else to say about the game, except that it scales really well.
Speaker 1: And if you want a game to get other people into gaming or a good social game to play, like at home, like bring all your friends over, just play like 10 games of it in a row for like 15 minutes.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I mean, it doesn't take long to play.
Speaker 0: It works well with two, three, four, five, six, seven or eight players.
Speaker 0: It's really fun with eight players because this stiff competition for territory right away, it gets crazy right off the bat and it's easy to learn.
Speaker 0: And it's also a good game, strategically speaking, even though there's also some randomness and I just got shit tiles.
Speaker 0: I got nothing to do.
Speaker 0: Oh, well.
Speaker 0: But it's not really a problem because you're going to play again in two seconds anyway.
Speaker 0: So whatever.
Speaker 1: It's also a great game to just like bring to a con and whip out.
Speaker 0: It's out of print, but it's not too difficult to find at the moment.
Speaker 0: But if you wait too long, it probably will become more difficult to find.
Speaker 0: So the game is Tsuro, T-S-U-R-O from WizKids who are out of business and it comes in a nice little box.
Speaker 1: Now, the second game that is much more interesting.
Speaker 1: Oh, she the game of influence.
Speaker 0: O-S-H-I.
Speaker 0: These games both have Asian themes to them.
Speaker 0: One is sort of like an Asian temple house, castle theme, and the other one sort of has a dragon theme.
Speaker 0: But I just thought that was interesting.
Speaker 1: This is a really simple, symmetric, perfect information to play a game like chess.
Speaker 0: You see, everyone puts the pieces on the board and moves them around.
Speaker 1: Basically, you'll have all these all these pieces on board.
Speaker 1: Some are one high, some are too high, some are three high.
Speaker 1: They're all like pagodas.
Speaker 0: And all right.
Speaker 0: Pagoda.
Speaker 0: That's the word.
Speaker 1: If you have one high piece can move one space in any orthogonal direction and can push up to one piece of yours or the enemy's.
Speaker 1: Yes, in one orthogonal direction, a two piece can put can move up to two and can push up to two pieces up to two spaces.
Speaker 1: A three can push or move up to three spaces.
Speaker 1: Now, the interesting thing here is that as a result, a three piece is strong in the offensive because it can push up to three pieces no matter what.
Speaker 1: But being a three piece is not a defense because you can be pushed just as far as a one piece.
Speaker 0: A one piece can push a three piece, one space, a three piece, a three piece can push three one pieces, three space.
Speaker 0: The whole game is you just take turns and you turn, you move one of your pieces and you try to knock the other guy's pieces off the board that literally you start to push them off the board.
Speaker 0: It comes with a little push them off the back, the front or the side.
Speaker 1: A little shoddily put together glued piece of wood.
Speaker 0: Well, that sort of that sort of annoyed me, right?
Speaker 0: Is that, you know, I mean, game production is sort of is important when you're paying a lot of money for a German board game.
Speaker 0: If you buy a set of Scrabble for ten bucks, do you really care if you get plastic pieces instead of wooden?
Speaker 0: No, not really.
Speaker 0: But if you pay, you know, like 20, perhaps, you know, some German board games like a lot of money, right?
Speaker 1: You spend what?
Speaker 1: Seventy five bucks on stupid Twilight Struggle, right?
Speaker 0: You want high quality production values, right?
Speaker 0: Or lots of pieces, even if they're lower quality.
Speaker 0: So, you know, this game, the we played a demo unit at at the con that the Connecticut people had, and their board was a solid piece of wood.
Speaker 0: I you know, but our board was like two pieces of wood glued to each other.
Speaker 1: They're not even the same wood.
Speaker 0: They're not even the same wood.
Speaker 0: And I feel like it's the board is going to snap in half and I'm going to have to make a board, which is not a big deal to make.
Speaker 1: But it's still annoying.
Speaker 0: I paid for this piece of wood and it feels like it's going to break.
Speaker 0: And I want a board game geek.
Speaker 0: And someone else also had, you know, a piece of wood that was glued together and was probably going to break solid wood.
Speaker 0: Some people are broken wood.
Speaker 1: The game was is not high production values.
Speaker 0: The plastic pieces are nice.
Speaker 1: The game.
Speaker 1: They're OK.
Speaker 1: They have glue marks on them.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: But the game itself is pretty complex.
Speaker 1: The rules are really simple.
Speaker 1: It's not really fiddly.
Speaker 1: It's got a simple anti stalemate stalemate mechanism.
Speaker 0: I like the anti stalemate mechanism.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty good mechanism, but it is still possible to generate a recursive stalemate.
Speaker 0: it is.
Speaker 0: But it's pretty obvious whoever has the upper hand in such a recursive stalemate.
Speaker 0: And as we have seen, what you think might be a recursive stalemate might actually not be because it might go on for a little bit.
Speaker 0: You'll go to one end of the board, then go back to the other end of the board.
Speaker 0: But then you'll be in a configuration where suddenly one of the other pieces on the board comes into play and busted up.
Speaker 0: Well, well, it's not always true, but it happened a couple of times.
Speaker 1: My warning to you is to not take advice from Scott on this game.
Speaker 0: I'm not.
Speaker 1: I'm one to trash talk pretty mercilessly.
Speaker 1: But in this case, it's just funny.
Speaker 1: We got the game.
Speaker 0: I can't stop laughing.
Speaker 1: We played it twice at the con and I won the first game and Scott won the second game and it was really cool.
Speaker 1: So we just bought it and that was it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: We got home after anime Boston.
Speaker 1: We're hanging out and I proceeded to win like 15 in a row.
Speaker 1: You went a lot in a row and then Scott won one.
Speaker 1: But then he accused me of letting him win, which is kind of true.
Speaker 1: And then I won like another whole bunch.
Speaker 1: And then Scott Johnson came over.
Speaker 1: I played against him once.
Speaker 0: He beat me, but I was.
Speaker 0: I was giving Scott Johnson advice, which sometimes he accepted and sometimes did not.
Speaker 1: So then you're like, wait a minute.
Speaker 1: I know what to do now.
Speaker 1: And you play against me and I got dominated.
Speaker 1: 15 more games.
Speaker 0: I won one of those.
Speaker 0: I think you did win one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Scott just can't play this game.
Speaker 0: I don't know what's going on?
Speaker 0: because like when I was helping Scott was I was watching Scott Johnson play.
Speaker 0: I like saw what to do and ended up working because Scott Johnson won like what I saw.
Speaker 0: I saw it play out.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But when I was when I was playing, it's like I was seeing something completely different.
Speaker 0: I just got hosed.
Speaker 1: So I got to figure out I got to I got to do something really, really cool thing about this game is that one is almost straight up pattern recognition.
Speaker 1: Like all you have to do is recognize the patterns and you'll see immediately where each recursive kind of set of moves will end up at the end.
Speaker 1: And then you don't have to think about that anymore.
Speaker 1: You just enact the pattern knowing where it will end and then push the guy off the edge.
Speaker 1: What the game really is analogous to.
Speaker 1: And if you can conceptualize this in your mind, you will win this game almost all the time.
Speaker 1: There's that old game.
Speaker 1: I used to play it a ton in like middle school and elementary school.
Speaker 1: And I taught everyone in the crew how to play it.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what it's called, but it's like the stick game where you draw like four sticks, three sticks and two sticks or five sticks, four sticks and two sticks.
Speaker 1: There are different variations and everyone takes turns picking up a number of sticks and whoever picks up the last stick loses.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's a really simple game.
Speaker 0: For example, I'll cross off all four, then rim will cross off like two of the threes that I'll cross off one of the threes.
Speaker 0: I'll cross off the two at the bottom and then rim is left with just the one remaining stick in the middle and then he's done.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But those that is still a game where if you can recognize patterns where like you don't have to get the game into a state where the other person picks up the last stick, you have to get the game into a state where the only possible option 10 moves later is for him to pick up the last stick.
Speaker 1: Oh, she is exactly like that.
Speaker 1: And the math behind that is really cool.
Speaker 1: The game, the board basically alternates between stable and unstable states.
Speaker 1: I would define stable as there is no possible move that can cause one color to push another, any piece of another color off the board.
Speaker 1: And there's an unstable board to where one color or both colors, it doesn't matter which can push a piece of the other color off the board.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And there are degrees of stability.
Speaker 1: The more pieces that can be pushed off, the more unstable the game is.
Speaker 1: And all you do is alternate the board between stable and unstable states iterating through these patterns until someone wins.
Speaker 0: Basically what sort of happens, right?
Speaker 0: Is you'll be, you'll, you start moving your pieces out right from the starting positions and then suddenly someone is in a position where they're going to lose a piece, right?
Speaker 0: So the beginning choice that you might do is to take that piece that's going to get killed and move it out of the way.
Speaker 0: So now it can't be killed, right?
Speaker 0: But it's actually because the way the game works, really difficult to run away from death, because usually it's like a three piece threatening a one piece.
Speaker 0: And it's probably, you know, one piece just can't get away.
Speaker 0: If it's too close to the edge of the board, it's, it's, it's doomed, right?
Speaker 0: So what you have to do instead is in the one piece is never going to run away.
Speaker 0: And if you spend all your actions running away, you're just going to lose a whole bunch of points all over the place.
Speaker 0: Instead, take one of your pieces and threaten elsewhere.
Speaker 0: So he's going to kill your one.
Speaker 0: So put his two, instead of moving the one out of the way, move your three into a position where it's going to kill his two.
Speaker 0: So now it's like, all right, you can't waste your turn killing my one.
Speaker 0: I'll kill your two.
Speaker 0: And it sort of stacks up all over the place.
Speaker 1: And well, that's actually very similar to the patterns you see in chess.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But it's, it's a little bit different in that, um, you know, it's much, much simpler.
Speaker 1: It's trivial to plan 10 or 15 moves in advance, even if you're not an expert at the game.
Speaker 1: Uh, you just win it all the time.
Speaker 0: No, but, well, you know, it has a lot fewer pieces, a lot, you know, simpler patterns, a lot smaller board, all sorts of things.
Speaker 0: You know, there's, you'll, you'll be in a position where there's a lot, it's obvious, you know, what all the options are.
Speaker 0: You know, you only need, you don't need to kill like, you know, any specific piece.
Speaker 0: You just need to kill seven points worth.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Also the way to win against unskilled players, if you guys pick this game up and you want to play it against a friend is think about the stable, unstable mechanic I talked about and just constantly put the game into an as unstable a position as possible, just push the stability crazily off balance.
Speaker 1: And the other person will get kind of found it.
Speaker 1: And then you'll just win.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You always, if you're not on the offensive, you know, putting his guys in a position where they're going to get killed constantly, then as soon as you're on the run, we're like a bunch or a lot more of your guys are in a position to die than his guys are in a position to die.
Speaker 0: You're pretty much done.
Speaker 0: It's very difficult to run away unless you have a really clever setup where like, with a, with like a one move, you can, you know, turn the tables.
Speaker 1: Now the, of course, the only significant drawback to the game is that like all small, perfect information game, eventually figure it out.
Speaker 1: The game is, is eminently solvable.
Speaker 1: And I think mathematically, I don't think it would be that difficult to mathematically solve it.
Speaker 0: And then, no, I mean, they've solved checkers.
Speaker 0: You know, you could easily write a computer program.
Speaker 1: checkers is a little bit because pieces all have, there are only two possible kinds of pieces and the number, the kinds of moves are simple.
Speaker 1: And also checkers has compelled moves.
Speaker 0: No, that's true.
Speaker 0: Compelled.
Speaker 1: There are no compelled moves here.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But even so, I think it would be not very difficult to, you know, make a computer program that would know the optimal move for any possible board configuration.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I, I would wager, I feel like because there are so many opportunities for stalemate, that the end game is perfect stalemate.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The stalemate, you know, rules sort of, uh, basically the stalemate rule.
Speaker 0: I don't think we said what it was.
Speaker 0: is it's not that, you know, if there's a stalemate, blah, it's, if you move it, if a piece was in, let's say a piece was that position, you cannot move one of your pieces to a position that it resided on, on the beginning of your previous term, right?
Speaker 0: So if my two piece was two pieces up from right, and then it got moved two pieces down, I can't just move it two spaces back up to where it used to be.
Speaker 0: I have to move it somewhere else.
Speaker 1: This, however, is a very elegant rule because it very succinctly prevents almost all of the possible stalemates and problems because you can push a piece.
Speaker 1: Like I can take a second piece and push the first piece to where it was before.
Speaker 1: I can do all sorts of interesting things with my other pieces or with that piece.
Speaker 1: It prevents the very specific scenario of I push you back three spaces.
Speaker 1: You can't push me back three spaces.
Speaker 1: And furthermore, it gives the offender the advantage.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean, think about it, though, right?
Speaker 0: I push you three so you can only push me back to.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: But then right then I can't push you back, you know, that I could push three.
Speaker 0: But that you to see how it goes.
Speaker 1: Well, yes, but it always gives the offense the advantage because it'll always put the defender.
Speaker 1: If you let someone else push you three, you will always have to be reacting or avoiding and you can play games.
Speaker 1: Well, I'll push two, but then you're going to be pushed back even further.
Speaker 1: And there's other than having other pieces to leverage or running away, you will always be an advantage if you attack fully.
Speaker 1: The game is really fun and I highly recommend it to just about anyone.
Speaker 1: It's a good addition to your household.
Speaker 0: It's also a rare, good two player game that doesn't take very long and is not, you know, just rock, paper, scissors or, you know, chess.
Speaker 0: Well, it is chess, but it doesn't take as long as chess.
Speaker 1: Not right away because chess is just rock, paper, scissors.
Speaker 0: That's also true.
Speaker 1: But, you know, you see the point.
Speaker 1: It's iterated rock, paper, scissors.
Speaker 1: However, because the game is out of print, if you can't find it, just make it.
Speaker 1: It's trivial to make.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it's true.
Speaker 1: This is four or five, six, seven.
Speaker 1: It's a nine by nine grid and you need two, three pieces to two pieces and for one pieces for each side.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: And then get the rules of board game.
Speaker 0: We dot com.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: You're done.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You can make this game.
Speaker 0: So, you know, try to buy it, though.
Speaker 0: I guess if you're lucky enough to get the solid piece of wood, that's nice.
Speaker 0: Hey, maybe we should make a copy of this game because we should.
Speaker 0: because I mean, I can go buy a piece of wood, polish it up, you know, I'll get some ox blood, take a wood burner, burn a wood grid onto it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Then get all sorts of nice stain, make it a nice color.
Speaker 1: You got to have the ox blood or it's not.
Speaker 0: you can really just use a go board, right?
Speaker 0: You don't even really need to make it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, you can play.
Speaker 1: You got to get little pieces to fit in the squares of the go board.
Speaker 0: I think it might be interesting to see if you could, you know, you could extend the life of this game by putting the pieces in different configurations or having bigger boards with more pieces, et cetera, et cetera.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the problem with bigger boards is that a game like this, you would have to have more stalemate rules or you'll have just long stalemates that might not even be obvious.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it'll be the same game, just bigger.
Speaker 1: Because the game is just pattern recognition.
Speaker 1: I mean, how many times, Scott, did we play where we do the four opening moves and we're in the exact same position we were in for the last eight games?
Speaker 0: Yup, exactly.
Speaker 0: And I took me like, it's like, wait, if I go first and I do this, does it turn out like that or does it turn out like the other way?
Speaker 0: Oh, no, it turned out the same way.
Speaker 0: So I have to do the other move when I go first to make it turn out the different way.
Speaker 1: All right, let's play some oshi and then go to bed.
Speaker 1: I think we're done here.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week covering four different geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays we have video games, board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an Odeo on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share-a-like 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money and share it in kind.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.