Speaker 0: It's Wednesday, May 27th.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, our coverage of Anime Boston 2009.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Hello everyone from Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: We're home.
Speaker 1: Oh snap.
Speaker 0: We made it.
Speaker 1: We made it a couple days ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but this is our first, you know, anime show after Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: And because we skipped Katsu-Kan this year, Anime Boston was really the beginning of the Kan season for us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it totally, I think we're gonna replace Katsu-Kan with Anime Boston, which is good because it saves us some traveling.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean Anime Boston, we'd never been before and it, many of you at the Kan heard this story.
Speaker 0: And I know many of you were new and people who listen to the show know a lot of our previous coverages of Anime Boston's.
Speaker 0: But we ended up going for the first time and it wasn't that we tried to avoid Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: I always, every year, wanted to go to Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: It just always came at like the wrong time.
Speaker 1: Why don't we save the Anime Boston talk for the Anime Boston portion of the show?
Speaker 0: Okay, but for all of you who are new, this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: I assume you're an anime fan since we did primarily anime panels.
Speaker 1: However... We did one gaming panel.
Speaker 0: We did one gaming panel, Beyond Dungeons and Dragons, and if you found this episode first, Tuesday nights of gaming.
Speaker 0: And if you don't care about anime and you care about Burning Wheel and D&D, well, Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: Tuesdays.
Speaker 0: Mondays are Linux neckbeard stuff.
Speaker 1: Which you probably really don't care about.
Speaker 0: I don't know, we met some neckbeard-y people at that Kan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they were outside the Kan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were in the city.
Speaker 0: I think that's close enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cause MIT's across the river, that's why.
Speaker 0: But before we talk about Anime Boston, our full review that I know many of you have been waiting for.
Speaker 0: And also we'll have a link to the Anime.
Speaker 0: You Should See slides that everyone's been freaking asking for.
Speaker 0: But anyway, a little bit of news.
Speaker 0: We are, in fact, we hadn't announced anything yet, going to be attending Otacon, like we always do.
Speaker 0: Like we have every year since 2002.
Speaker 0: And we are going to be doing, sadly, they didn't want us to do any of our new panels, so you'll have to wait until, I guess, the New York Anime Festival, or maybe, maybe, Connecticut to see Tales from the Anime Club.
Speaker 0: But we're doing Cover Your Bases, which is a little hint.
Speaker 0: That's just anime you should see with a different name.
Speaker 1: Oh, shit.
Speaker 0: And Know Your Creators.
Speaker 1: I hope people don't think it's a baseball panel about baseball manga.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, well the description will at least set them straight.
Speaker 1: People don't read the description, they look at the title only.
Speaker 0: See, the problem is, anyone who goes to a panel on baseball anime has already seen a lot of anime.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: Not many people start on like Princess 9.
Speaker 0: And we're doing Beyond Dungeons and Dragons.
Speaker 1: Which has nothing to do with Otacon.
Speaker 0: Except for the fact that the crossover between anime and video games and board games and all that stuff is effectively infinite at this point.
Speaker 0: I mean, the Venn diagram is so close.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: It's just saying.
Speaker 1: It's so sad though.
Speaker 1: It's like we go to this anime convention for Otaku Generation and we say, "Here's a bunch of
Speaker 1: stuff."
Speaker 1: And they say, "Yeah, we want the same old, same
Speaker 1: old.".
Speaker 1: It's like, "Really?
Speaker 1: If I was a panel picker, I would never pick the same panel to repeat unless it was opening
Speaker 1: ceremonies.".
Speaker 0: See, Scott, I would say just the opposite.
Speaker 0: There are certain panels or types of panels that at large conventions you pretty much need every year because so many people come every year.
Speaker 0: There's so many new fans.
Speaker 0: I mean, the panel that tells people who don't know what anime to watch, who just got into anime, what anime to watch is an important panel.
Speaker 0: The, you know, how to run an anime club panel is an important panel.
Speaker 0: There's all these kind of basic panels that you pretty much have to run every year and you'll always have people who have never seen it and need to see it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but quite often those are the people who do not come to that panel.
Speaker 0: They will.
Speaker 0: I mean, look at Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: How many people came to anime you should see?
Speaker 1: That was a lot of people, but, you know, many of them had seen anime.
Speaker 1: judging by, you know, about half the people there were, you know, grown in and...
Speaker 0: See, while you say that, half the people there had never seen Cowboy Bebop.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 1: It's scary.
Speaker 1: It's like half the people, like, knew it and half the people didn't know it.
Speaker 1: And I really wondered, like, why the half the people who knew it were there.
Speaker 0: But even those people, they hadn't seen half the other stuff.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone, maybe like four people out of the 800 in that room...
Speaker 1: Are we in that much of a minority?
Speaker 1: Are we the only people who've seen the stuff?
Speaker 0: Well, remember when there was that someone posted in a forum thread a list of, like, the 100 greatest anime, and I remember going through the list, I had seen, like, 96 of them all the way through, and I knew what 100 of them were.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It made me almost a little bit sad for myself.
Speaker 1: Well, there's not, you know, it shows you that there's, you know, there's a lot of anime, but it's not really so much that it's like, you can never watch it all, but you can surmount it, you know, such that, you know, you have a sufficient knowledge of a great deal of the work.
Speaker 1: It's like, you can never read all the books, but if you spent your life reading, like, sci-fi books, you could conquer enough of them, you know.
Speaker 1: Someone giving you a list of the greatest ones is like, yeah, I got that.
Speaker 0: But at least for OdaKan, for these sorts of panels, I have this feeling that we're gonna be running Anime.
Speaker 0: You Should See and Know Your Creators in some capacity at most anime conventions that we attend from now on.
Speaker 1: Well, even if you agree with the argument that those panels should be run at every convention, you know, over and over again, let's get someone else to run those and do something different.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: I enjoy doing it.
Speaker 0: Plus, we've changed it up every time, and we got Daryl Surratt, and I think he added a lot to Anime You Should See.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but also, you know, he came from Florida, so I felt bad that if he came here and didn't do anything, that would be sort of like a waste of his trip.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he had a lot to do on his own.
Speaker 0: I mean, we'll talk about the random awesomeness of that vile specter of Moe panel, but the other thing is that if you saw Anime You Should See at Anime Boston, do not come to see it at OdaKan.
Speaker 0: It is going to be the exact same panel.
Speaker 0: Like, exactly.
Speaker 0: Anime for anime, almost word for word.
Speaker 0: Just leave it be.
Speaker 0: However, Know Your Creators is basically going to be completely different, so go ahead and go to that one.
Speaker 0: I say this primarily because every con we go to, Anime You Should See is like standing room only, like people lined up outside, they have to turn a bunch of people away.
Speaker 0: Know Your Creators never fills the room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's kinda sad.
Speaker 1: Because really, Know Your Creators is the one that probably should get more people.
Speaker 0: But in other OdaKan news, I do want to bring this up before we get...
Speaker 1: Maybe we should change the name to Creators You Should Know.
Speaker 0: I kinda want to change it to like, Six Grades or something about six, and then every time we do it...
Speaker 1: Why do you pick six?
Speaker 0: That way we can give ten minutes per creator.
Speaker 1: I guess, but you're forgetting the time it takes for the intro and the outro.
Speaker 0: Well, ten minutes per creator, but there's some overlap.
Speaker 0: Like, if I do Oshii and Shiro, there's going to be about five minutes of overlap between the two.
Speaker 0: Which leaves them with only fifteen minutes total.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but OdaKan, other news, OdaKan's coming up, you know, we said we're going to go, and they opened up the Artist Alley, as they always do.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it was a record this year, but I applied for the Geek Nights Artist Alley table within a couple hours of them announcing registration.
Speaker 0: And I am so far down the waiting list that there's no point.
Speaker 0: And this is a problem every year, and I can't blame OdaKan or any convention that has this problem, because what do you do?
Speaker 0: You have a very limited supply of Artist Alley tables, and an order of magnitude more people who want Artist Alley tables.
Speaker 0: And any method you come up with to decide who gets them and who doesn't is going to be unfair to someone as opposed to someone else.
Speaker 0: Or is going to cause some problem over another problem.
Speaker 1: One thing I would like to say, right, is that the room the Artist Alley is in is a very large room, yes?
Speaker 1: There is a significant portion of that room that is relatively empty.
Speaker 0: I think part of it is that there are rules about how much of the room can be filled with stuff.
Speaker 1: I agree that there are rules about how much of the room can be filled with stuff.
Speaker 1: However, I would also like to point out they have that area that is like, I guess, nominally for CCGs that no one uses at all.
Speaker 1: And everyone just uses it to eat lunch, right?
Speaker 0: Here's how I feel about that area.
Speaker 0: The New York Anime Festival has it right.
Speaker 0: They just turned it into a maid cafe and didn't even pretend.
Speaker 0: Or what OdaKan can do, either drop the tabletop gaming or get us to run it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Either make that a real area and beef it up or turn it into Artist Alley tables.
Speaker 1: And two, right, the art show really has not held up so much.
Speaker 1: And I think, you know...
Speaker 0: Wait, wait, are you proposing to get rid of the art show?
Speaker 0: Because it always fills up.
Speaker 1: I am proposing they reduce the art show slightly.
Speaker 0: How so?
Speaker 1: By reducing the available space and, you know, having some sort of quality filtration.
Speaker 0: See, that's the problem.
Speaker 0: Quality filtration.
Speaker 1: There are always a few empty things, you know, that no one hangs up on.
Speaker 0: Why even bother?
Speaker 0: Because the amount of space you'll save by cutting like four of those partitions out of there is not going to affect anything else in that room at all.
Speaker 0: There is no way to reduce the art show enough to make an impact without ruining the art show.
Speaker 0: And you'll just make more people unhappy.
Speaker 0: The art show, I think, should stay the way it is.
Speaker 1: Also, I've heard complaints from artists who put things in the art show about the... They made a change to the way, you know, the finances of the art show for artists.
Speaker 1: And it's actually a very bad deal for the artists.
Speaker 1: Unless you can sell something that's really good for a large amount of money.
Speaker 1: So I think the art show...
Speaker 0: What were the changes?
Speaker 1: I forget exactly, but many artists were complaining.
Speaker 0: Yes, but Scott...
Speaker 1: Basically, it's not worth it financially unless you sell something for a shit ton of money.
Speaker 1: In which case, if they want to keep that financial arrangement, they should pretty much only allow things that are going to sell for a shit ton of money.
Speaker 0: Wait, but Scott, I mean, what are even the changes?
Speaker 0: You don't even know.
Speaker 0: And how often do the artists at like an artist's alley or something complain about nothing violently?
Speaker 1: Well, Nuri was complaining, so I trust what she said.
Speaker 0: Alright, well, I'll look it up.
Speaker 0: if you're going to bring this up without any references or citations other than hearsay.
Speaker 1: It's not hearsay.
Speaker 1: I'm referencing a person who complained.
Speaker 0: Yes, that's hearsay.
Speaker 0: That's the definition of hearsay.
Speaker 1: They changed something anyway.
Speaker 0: Regardless, even if you cut it in half, that'll have no impact on any other part of the room.
Speaker 1: Well, the whole area behind the art show is always empty.
Speaker 1: Like, just a big empty space.
Speaker 0: But if it's empty anyway, then you could...
Speaker 1: Fill it with tables.
Speaker 0: No, you can't most likely.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they should.
Speaker 1: They probably can't.
Speaker 1: Find a way.
Speaker 1: At the very least, you could spread out the existing tables.
Speaker 0: No, the problem I realized, I didn't think of until recently, was that doing it the way they do... I mean, there's no safe or fair way to dole out the artist's alley tables.
Speaker 0: But doing it first come, first serve, I'm starting to feel, is the worst possible way.
Speaker 1: It is the worst possible way.
Speaker 0: Not because it rewards the most obsessive people or anything like that.
Speaker 0: Because that probably is better than just giving it out randomly to reward the people who care the most.
Speaker 0: The problem is that it doesn't necessarily reward the people who care the most.
Speaker 0: It basically will create this sort of meme propagation to where as soon as one person in a group of friends gets a table, they have called all of their friends on the phone immediately, and those people have all gotten tables.
Speaker 0: So the people who start getting tables, the people who find out that it opened and get the first submissions in, are all friends with each other in this long chain of friendship.
Speaker 1: Well, there might be a few trees, because anyone who discovers it on their own quickly enough is like a beginning node.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the point remains that you'll have generally very strong lineages of people that are all related to each other, and you'll kind of get a lot of samey-ness in the artist's alley as a result.
Speaker 1: Well, the artist's alley at all the conventions have been very samey.
Speaker 0: Well, I would argue that Anime Boston wasn't at all.
Speaker 1: No, I see a whole bunch of the tables in Anime Boston were tables I had seen previously and previously and previously.
Speaker 0: I'd say about a third, maybe a quarter.
Speaker 1: That's a lot.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's that big of a deal.
Speaker 1: It's not a big deal, I'm just saying it's a lot.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of people who are just in that artist's alley community, they're in the artist's alley at every con, you always see them.
Speaker 0: See, but the point is that the samey-ness at Otacon would be vastly mitigated if the cliques of artists who all know each other weren't practically guaranteed to either all get in or none of them get in.
Speaker 0: Because that, I think, contributes to a lot of the samey-ness.
Speaker 0: Never mind the people who scammed Otacon last year.
Speaker 0: Those people were at Anime Boston and they had two sets of tables.
Speaker 0: It was, I don't know what to do about those people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: But, I mean, look at last year, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, we didn't do anything like that, but the front row crew, because I happened to be awake and I called all of our friends when the artist's alley opened up last year, we had 14 tables.
Speaker 0: Everyone in the front row crew had an artist's alley table just about.
Speaker 1: It wasn't 14 tables, it was like one.
Speaker 0: We had 14 originally and we dropped several of them because we didn't fill them up.
Speaker 1: I was trying to count.
Speaker 1: We only had like 10.
Speaker 0: We had 14 tables when we started.
Speaker 0: We dropped it down to, I believe, 12 at the end.
Speaker 0: And this year, zero.
Speaker 1: Oh well.
Speaker 1: I didn't really want to sit in the artist's alley anyway.
Speaker 0: Oh no, I was going to hire someone to sit at an artist's alley table.
Speaker 1: I didn't even know why you applied for a table because I thought we had decided not to get one.
Speaker 0: I was going to apply anyway.
Speaker 0: I was going to basically sublet it to the best artist I could find who didn't get a table.
Speaker 0: That was my plan.
Speaker 0: And then in return, in the corner of the table, they was there to sell some Geek Night t-shirts.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: That's a good idea.
Speaker 1: if that could have happened.
Speaker 0: Alright, so you're all down and everything would have gotten in the news.
Speaker 1: What do I have in the news?
Speaker 1: Well, there is a thing called, for many, many years now, I have known of a thing called the Guin Saga.
Speaker 1: If you would have come up to me and said Guin Saga, I'd be like, "Yeah, I heard of that, but I have no idea what it
Speaker 1: is.".
Speaker 1: And in more recent years, I have come to learn what it is.
Speaker 1: It's an epic fantasy story.
Speaker 1: It was originally in a bunch of actual books with some illustrations, like 126 volumes worth.
Speaker 1: There was a manga that told some side story that came out from Vertical that I read.
Speaker 1: that's like three volumes.
Speaker 1: And there's a brand new anime series, which I'm watching and is pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: And it's about this guy and he has a leopard for a head and he doesn't know why.
Speaker 1: And he's in his fantasy world and there's all sorts of kings and princes and war and all that typical fantasy stuff and wizards and whatnot.
Speaker 1: Well, it is very sad news, but Kaworu Kurimoto, the original creator of the Guin Saga, has passed away from, was it pancreatic cancer?
Speaker 1: At the age of 50-something, 53 I think.
Speaker 1: I don't have my laptop in front of me, so I don't remember the very specific details.
Speaker 1: So this leaves me, number one, it's sort of like, "Wow, that's pretty
Speaker 1: big.".
Speaker 1: Pretty much the number two fantasy series in all of history after The Lord of the Rings.
Speaker 1: It's done, right?
Speaker 1: And 126 volumes, it's like, "Is it over?
Speaker 1: Was she working on more?
Speaker 1: What's the situation going to be
Speaker 1: there?".
Speaker 1: People were freaking out about the Robert Jordan situation, the Guin Saga situation could be a billion times worse than that.
Speaker 1: And it's like, just as I was starting to get into it, as soon as I really figured out what it was and started liking it and started trying to read it, then this goes on.
Speaker 1: It's like, "Oh,
Speaker 1: God.".
Speaker 1: So that is a sad news for the world.
Speaker 0: That indeed.
Speaker 0: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 0: Now, we were at Anime Boston, and one of the highlights of Anime Boston was the Calafina concert.
Speaker 0: I'm a big fan of that.
Speaker 1: You sure it's not Calafina?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've heard Calafina from just about everyone.
Speaker 1: I was just trying to be silly.
Speaker 0: But I did eat at Chipotle for lunch today.
Speaker 1: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: Chipotle.
Speaker 0: But, in case you don't know who Calafina was, I'm linking to some Calafina videos on YouTube that probably won't be taken down in the near term.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just sort of hate linking to anything that I know is going to be taken down.
Speaker 0: It may or may not be taken down.
Speaker 0: I mean, copyright law in the U.S.
Speaker 0: is all weird.
Speaker 1: It's true.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Is that it?
Speaker 1: That's all you got?
Speaker 0: There's nothing else on the internet.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So my thing of the day is a very small thing of the day.
Speaker 1: In fact, we're going to include, for the first time ever, the entire thing of the day in this show.
Speaker 1: So you do not, if you want to hear, it's an audio thing of the day, right?
Speaker 1: If you want to hear this thing of the day, you do not need to go to the website or click on the link.
Speaker 0: Should we just play it without explaining what it is?
Speaker 1: Just play it right now.
Speaker 1: Alright, so, for those of you who, we should have played it a few times, actually, so people can, you know, hear it over and over.
Speaker 1: Maybe we'll play it again after I'm done talking.
Speaker 1: What that was, was a correct pronunciation of...
Speaker 0: Mjölnir.
Speaker 1: No, not Mjölnir.
Speaker 0: Well, it was the correct pronunciation of Mjölnir, just like Nobunaga is the correct pronunciation of Nobunga.
Speaker 1: Yes, you see, Mjölnir is the name of Thor's hammer, a very important geek artifact in both the land of comic books, but also the land of Norse mythology.
Speaker 0: So what's the name of Odin's horse?
Speaker 1: Fuck you.
Speaker 0: How about the name of the Rainbow Bridge?
Speaker 1: Rainbow Bridge.
Speaker 0: Or the guy who guards it.
Speaker 1: I forget.
Speaker 0: Or the place where the gods dwell.
Speaker 0: Or the place where you don't know anything but the Marvel stuff.
Speaker 1: You're making me think too quickly.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: I just wanted to point out that you said, you know, Marvel and Norse mythology, when you really meant Marvel.
Speaker 0: Mjölnir.
Speaker 1: Well, no, because Norse mythology on its own is not important enough to geekery.
Speaker 0: I think it is.
Speaker 1: It is Thor the superhero that creates the extra impetus of geeky importance.
Speaker 0: Are you really sure?
Speaker 0: Because I know that in middle school and high school, being doing like quiz bowl and stuff, every nerd knew everything there was to know about Norse mythology above and beyond every other mythology.
Speaker 1: In order for your evidence, your anecdotal evidence to be valid in this argument, your anecdotal evidence would have to be from a time before Thor the Marvel superhero existed.
Speaker 1: Would it be?
Speaker 0: Because of all those people, no one I knew read comic books.
Speaker 0: That did not matter.
Speaker 1: The geeky interest was ancillary.
Speaker 0: See, I don't think it was because Thor is pretty badass.
Speaker 0: Can you prove it wasn't?
Speaker 0: However, I have an equally plausible supposition.
Speaker 1: The point is that we now know how to correctly pronounce Mjölnir.
Speaker 1: And the way you spell it is M-J-O-2-dots-L-N-I-R.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I have the equally valid or possible plausible supposition.
Speaker 0: We know why you have plausible suppositions here.
Speaker 0: The interest in Norse mythology among geeks comes primarily from metal.
Speaker 1: Mjölnir.
Speaker 1: Alright, if you don't shut up, I'll hit you with Mjölnir.
Speaker 0: But anyway, Anime Boston 2009, the short version, in case you want to listen to all of this, is that it was badass and we were coming to every Anime Boston again forever.
Speaker 1: Unless it goes down the tubes.
Speaker 1: I mean, we said Kazukan was badass.
Speaker 0: Kazukan was badass.
Speaker 1: It may be badass again.
Speaker 1: It could be possible that Anime Boston, a few years from now, will say Anime Boston was badass, but I hope not.
Speaker 0: I can at least say, Anime Boston is now in the permanent Geek Nights con rotation.
Speaker 0: It is now among the likes of Otakon, the New York Anime Festival, the New York Comic Con, PAX East, PAX West.
Speaker 1: So let me just sum up the story.
Speaker 1: We had never been to Anime Boston because of who knows why.
Speaker 0: Usually situations like, "Hey, you guys should go to Anime
Speaker 0: Boston.".
Speaker 0: Rim saying, "Anime Boston?
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's go.
Speaker 0: When is it?
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, last
Speaker 0: week.".
Speaker 1: Right, so we actually finally went because Dragon Master Lu is awesome and he's the man.
Speaker 1: Oh, right.
Speaker 1: We also, last year on Geek Nights, we didn't go to Anime Boston, obviously, because this was our first time going.
Speaker 1: But we heard from people that the registration at Anime Boston was horrendously bad.
Speaker 1: And it was.
Speaker 0: It was bad enough to where?
Speaker 0: had I gone to the previous year's Anime Boston, I probably would have backcharged the credit card.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: So, we went this year.
Speaker 1: And, you know, we walk up and we're, you know, cautious.
Speaker 1: Cautiously optimistic as we are, right?
Speaker 0: Anytime we go to a new con, I mean, remember the first time we were doing panels at Kinetic Con?
Speaker 0: We show up like, there's always, you know, being people like us going to any convention, there's always the, "Is this convention going to have our badges for
Speaker 0: us?".
Speaker 1: Even at PAX, we were cautious for the first five minutes.
Speaker 0: Like, are they going to know who we are?
Speaker 1: Until we met that first enforcer who hooked us up.
Speaker 0: Are they going to give us what we need?
Speaker 0: Is it going to, I'm not going to name cons, but are we going to have to find a schedule, fake our way in to get badges, then look on the schedule to figure out where our panels were scheduled?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: So, we go to Anime Boston and at first, we're a little bit.
Speaker 1: eh, a little bit, right?
Speaker 1: You know, we're not, we don't know our way around this convention center so much.
Speaker 0: I want to say so much eh, is that we walk in.
Speaker 1: We're only a little bit eh.
Speaker 0: And we ask one of the staffers walking by, "Excuse me, good sir, where can we go to get panelist badges if we are a featured
Speaker 0: panelist?".
Speaker 0: And they say, "Registration is that
Speaker 0: way.".
Speaker 1: And we're like, because we had thought that because of the email, right, which Rym did not have.
Speaker 0: Uh, Scott, the email said exactly go to the customer service desk, as I said at the con.
Speaker 1: You were not so sure about that.
Speaker 0: I was 100% sure.
Speaker 1: No, that's not what you said.
Speaker 1: You were like, "Yeah, the email said to go somewhere special,
Speaker 1: eh.".
Speaker 0: Yep, it said go to customer service.
Speaker 1: In fact, I think in the car you said information desk.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point was we were not 100% sure where to go and the person said to go to.
Speaker 0: I was 100% sure.
Speaker 1: No, you were not.
Speaker 1: Not at all.
Speaker 1: You're basically lying.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: So anyway, you know, we get in line and there's a little bit of a line.
Speaker 0: The only complaint, this is like the only complaint I have about all of Anime Boston, is that they make the same mistake Otacon does with registration.
Speaker 0: They have all these booths set up for pre-registration and ad-con registration and they have one booth on the end for special cases.
Speaker 0: Anyone who has a problem, their registration wasn't there, their badge was wrong, they need a special badge.
Speaker 0: Anyone who has something weird going on has to go to this one booth.
Speaker 0: So as a result, in the time it takes a normal booth to process like 100 people, the special booth processes one person.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: It took us like a half hour to stand in a line with like seven people in front of us to get our badge.
Speaker 1: You do need to have A, a separate booth for the, you know, you can't have the same booth servicing people with problems and panelists and guests getting badges.
Speaker 1: There needs to be two booths.
Speaker 1: And secondly, the problem booth, right?
Speaker 1: It could be just one booth for the problem people.
Speaker 1: But the thing is, if someone's got a problem, you really need like an excellent staffer there because these are people who are going to like that.
Speaker 1: Their whole convention is going to be determined by their experience at that booth because they have a problem.
Speaker 1: And how elegantly it is solved is pretty much going to change their whole attitude.
Speaker 0: The only reason I complain about this is that Otacon had the exact same problem.
Speaker 0: And to actually get our panelists badges, we had to stand in a line that took longer than the entire normal registration line.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So what you need to do is at the one booth for special case people, right?
Speaker 1: You need to have like two or three of like your best freaking staffers there.
Speaker 1: Like until that line is empty or, you know, just to make sure, because that's pretty much you, you found that you have a clever opportunity.
Speaker 1: It's like your only golden opportunity to put all the problem people at the con in one spot and then kick them out the door and then help.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And fix them.
Speaker 1: So don't squander that opportunity.
Speaker 1: Put the big staffers there and keep them there until it's fixed.
Speaker 0: But anyway, we finally get up to the front.
Speaker 0: And this is the moment of truth, because every con may like the quality we experience we have as like panelists or guests or whatever really is always indicated by whether or not they actually have our badges ready for us.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, oh, I'm rim and there's a Scott and we're here and they're like, here's your badges.
Speaker 1: And from then on, everything is great.
Speaker 0: And they handed us our badges and like everything was just brilliant from that point forward.
Speaker 1: The only other, the only negative thing to say, in fact, there's only two other negative things to say about the con and they're not very negative.
Speaker 1: Number one, the registration was infinity times better than the registration the previous year, which, you know, I only know about from hearsay, but it was bad.
Speaker 0: However, however, does it twice as good.
Speaker 0: But not to not to talk about Otacon, Pax, like I thought Otacon, I always looked at Otacon as like the best con in the world for handing registration.
Speaker 0: They they take that crazy line on Thursday and it is gone like right away.
Speaker 0: Like they're so fast.
Speaker 0: But then we went to Pax and there was no line because they mailed everyone their badges.
Speaker 0: Now it's interesting because every anime con like Otacon, Anime Boston, Katsucon, Kineticon, every con, they say, no, it's impossible to mail out the badges.
Speaker 0: But Pax just does it and it just works.
Speaker 1: And I think it's when they worry about, oh, somebody is going to forge the badges.
Speaker 1: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: So we can't mail them out.
Speaker 1: Then again, the New York Comic Cons and the New York Anime Festival, that badge is such an easily forged badge.
Speaker 1: It's the same exact thing as like the Anime Boston Otacon badges.
Speaker 1: It's a piece of paper and a piece of plastic with a hologram on it.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They mail them out.
Speaker 1: They have no problem.
Speaker 1: They don't care.
Speaker 1: And their tickets are a lot more money.
Speaker 1: In fact, you could probably you can forge a badge.
Speaker 1: The New York Comic Con, that could be like a five hundred dollar badge that lets you see Stan Lee trivial to forge.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They just mail it to you.
Speaker 1: They don't care.
Speaker 1: They don't force you to get it at con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel like Pax showed me the light in that regard that just hire a company, mail out badges.
Speaker 1: I'm done with the excuses of not mailing out badges at conventions.
Speaker 1: You mail them out.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Because while the badge, the registration situation at Anime Boston was satisfactory and it was infinitely superior than previous year, that line still was too long.
Speaker 1: Our friend came for a Saturday only badge.
Speaker 1: He bought it at door and he had to wait over an hour.
Speaker 1: And that is too long.
Speaker 1: You know, it's significantly better, but too long.
Speaker 1: And that's the only.
Speaker 1: that's one negative thing.
Speaker 1: And the only other negative thing was that, you know, you have a board at each door to every room in the con.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: Tiny font, tiny font.
Speaker 1: You have to basically, you know, it's like the outside panel room.
Speaker 1: A you have a piece of cardboard on an easel and it has the schedule for panel A. It's on a little tiny eight and a half by 11 piece of paper or like a 14 point font.
Speaker 1: So you need to walk up to it and basically squint at it to read what the schedule is.
Speaker 1: It should be in big, big letters that you can see it just walking down the hallway.
Speaker 1: And other than that, anime Boston was pretty much perfect for what it was.
Speaker 0: We figured we'd get the all the negatives out of the way first, because otherwise we do like other years coverage of other conventions where we end on all the bad stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Everything else.
Speaker 1: I mean, Boston was perfect.
Speaker 1: Perfect.
Speaker 1: No, no, no complaints.
Speaker 1: Nothing was wrong.
Speaker 0: The panels were amazing.
Speaker 0: We'll just take it where we will go chronologically.
Speaker 0: I don't think you need the minute by minute account of this.
Speaker 1: I mean, do we really need to like review all of our panels that we gave?
Speaker 1: It's not really.
Speaker 0: We should talk about what happened each of the panels, because I think they're all noteworthy in some way.
Speaker 0: I mean, we basically got to the count.
Speaker 0: We walked around and then our first panel on Friday was of all things beyond Dungeons and Dragons.
Speaker 0: And there were a little there between two and three hundred people in that room.
Speaker 1: It was it was pretty crowded.
Speaker 1: Did you notice that people like to sit adjacent to the aisle in the middle?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: What was that?
Speaker 1: You know, it was weird because it's a bit I did too.
Speaker 0: When I went into rooms, I always sat like right there.
Speaker 1: I didn't sit there.
Speaker 0: I did.
Speaker 1: I sat more in the middle of one of the sides.
Speaker 1: That's where I like to sit anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But in terms of panel rooms, anime Boston, outside of packs, had the best panel rooms I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: Because even Otakon, even all the other big anime conventions, they usually have one set of speakers at the front of the room and the microphones and everything.
Speaker 0: And the average two pretty good tech guys and every count union tech guys.
Speaker 0: But anime Boston's panel rooms and showing rooms, I point out one had dedicated staff in every panel room and showing room for the entirety of the con that knew their stuff like they were perfect.
Speaker 1: They that guy in Ballroom A, he helped us out.
Speaker 1: What's up?
Speaker 0: Ballroom A guy was so great.
Speaker 0: Like we're standing there.
Speaker 0: We're like, oh, if only that like wireless mics and he hands us to wireless mics like he ninjas behind us.
Speaker 1: And they worked.
Speaker 1: They worked.
Speaker 1: That's not often they have wireless mics that work.
Speaker 0: They had one better projectors, gigantic projectors that also work.
Speaker 0: And the panel rooms were gigantic.
Speaker 0: I mean, Ballroom A seated, I think seven hundred and twenty people.
Speaker 1: And most importantly, in that giant room, there were six speakers, two in the front, two sort of halfway and two in the middle so that everyone throughout the entire room could hear what was coming out the microphone.
Speaker 0: Even if you were sitting way in the back, you didn't have that situation in most other counts where the front of the room is crazy loud in the back of the room.
Speaker 0: You can't hear anything.
Speaker 0: And it made for a much more dynamic, much more into it, much more focused panels.
Speaker 0: People were enjoying a more.
Speaker 0: just in general, the panel set of Anime Boston beats the crap out of pretty much every other convention we go to.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, it was, you know, fewer larger rooms for the panels.
Speaker 1: That's one thing.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And the other thing was that, you know, there were stretches of the con where there weren't any panels to go to.
Speaker 1: that like we were interested in.
Speaker 1: But there were always things going on.
Speaker 1: You know, it was just for us, it sort of felt like, you know, at points where we had nothing to do.
Speaker 1: Like Saturday morning, for example, was sort of like, OK, right.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But then again, I mean, what do I do at a con?
Speaker 0: I tend to go to about half events and then I tend to hang out with people and have fun for the other half.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 0: I mean, you need time to go and eat and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: And plus, I would say, looking at the schedule, there was something to do at that con.
Speaker 1: Just not for us.
Speaker 0: At pretty much any point in the con.
Speaker 0: I would have gone and played some DDR.
Speaker 0: You didn't really want to.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't want to play DDR in that smelly room.
Speaker 0: The room wasn't smelly until Saturday night.
Speaker 1: Well, it was smelly up by the DDR real close.
Speaker 0: Not on Friday.
Speaker 1: Maybe not Friday.
Speaker 0: Only it wasn't until Saturday night that that room smelled.
Speaker 1: I really wanted to play GoGo 13 slot machine, but there were.
Speaker 1: no I didn't know how to make it work.
Speaker 0: Put a quarter in.
Speaker 1: I wasn't going to put my quarter in someone else's slot machine.
Speaker 0: What if it won?
Speaker 1: I didn't know that.
Speaker 1: I couldn't trust that there were quarters in it.
Speaker 1: It was not, you know, it was not a license.
Speaker 0: You weren't willing to spend a quarter to see the Duke Togo do whatever he does on that machine.
Speaker 1: I don't gamble unless there is a gambling commission keeping it straight.
Speaker 1: Not that they keep it straight.
Speaker 1: Well, plus, you know, I know I could have put that quarter in that machine and Duke Togo would like blow my brains out.
Speaker 0: I would have bet on Duke Togo because a man who will shoot a guy on his way down.
Speaker 1: Well, that's the thing is you're not betting on Duke Togo.
Speaker 1: You're betting against Duke Togo.
Speaker 1: You're trying to get his money.
Speaker 0: Are you?
Speaker 0: Are you really?
Speaker 0: What if your quarter is paying him to take out that slot machine?
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: He's in the slot machine coming out.
Speaker 1: Not the advice.
Speaker 0: He's got a gun pointed right out the slot.
Speaker 1: It would only be betting for him if you were Duke Togo using the slot machine.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 0: But, you know, Beyond D&D got a lot of people and it was pretty interesting to see all these anime people who were also really into role playing games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was actually kind of, I didn't think the turnout was going to be that much, what it was.
Speaker 1: But one thing that I think we, it's something I knew we needed to fix with that panel and I thought we did fix it, but I guess not.
Speaker 1: Is that, you know, the way we deliver that panel is we use D&D as the example all the time because everyone knows D&D.
Speaker 1: So that's what you, you know, you're going to be saying D&D a lot.
Speaker 1: And the result is it sort of comes off in the panel as if we're bashing on D&D, which we are not.
Speaker 0: Nevermind the fact that we began the panel with a five minute explanation of.
Speaker 0: we love D&D.
Speaker 0: D&D is awesome.
Speaker 0: It's important.
Speaker 0: We play it.
Speaker 0: It's great.
Speaker 0: D&D is awesome and do not think that we are in any way disparaging D&D.
Speaker 1: That doesn't help, right?
Speaker 1: So I do think we need to basically re-, just not use the word D&D or Dungeons & Dragons as much.
Speaker 1: One thing
Speaker 0: I did notice at this panel that has never happened to us at another convention before, and I don't know if just because of the crowd or the nature of the room or what, but in all the panels we did, people in the audience would like just start interrupting and yelling stuff at us.
Speaker 0: Like in every panel, like say, say something and someone in the back of the room would just start yelling like a comment like, but you guys forgot about going to guys work, the blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 1: And you just don't say, don't acknowledge them.
Speaker 1: Otherwise you're going to lose control of your panel.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But it was interesting that this happened.
Speaker 0: Like it happened a lot at Anime Boston and it's never happened at any other con except once at Kineticon.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: And it wasn't just our panels.
Speaker 0: Pretty much every panel I went to had people in the audience interrupting.
Speaker 0: And it was actually the same, as far as I could tell, like the same people.
Speaker 0: Like there were like 50 or 60 people who seemed to be the ones who kept doing it.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, there was this one panel we went to, it was these two girls and they gave a panel about murder mystery manga.
Speaker 1: And you know, it was an average panel, you know, and they had a very good list of murder mystery manga.
Speaker 0: I learned about two murder mystery manga I did not know about.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: I also I took the hands out on a nice piece of paper that had a list of all the manga they were talking about, which is very nice.
Speaker 1: Their slides had a really good design, but they had a lot of text on them and, you know, a lot of text on slides is not so good.
Speaker 1: But anyway, you know, so I learned about good murder mystery manga.
Speaker 1: So it's worth my time to sit in that panel, but like someone just blurted out a question and then they answered it.
Speaker 1: And it's sort of like, no, you're supposed to make them wait to the end and raise their hand and such and such.
Speaker 0: I'm curious as to what the phenomenon was.
Speaker 0: It wasn't really a detriment.
Speaker 0: It was just really interesting because some of the people who would yell stuff out did have really interesting things to say.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And I feel like I feel as a result, Anime Boston could host some panels that we don't even try to run at other conventions.
Speaker 0: We could host some serious like roundtable discussion style panels.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I feel like, though, either A, we need to make like the Beyond D&D panel shorter, like remove some content from it, or we need to get more time for it so we can take questions.
Speaker 0: Because pretty much the problem with doing a panel that says controversial things is that I mean, it was weird looking around the audience.
Speaker 0: I'd say half the people like I'd say something and the audience, like people, they'd be like nodding like seriously.
Speaker 0: Oh, I get it.
Speaker 0: But there'd be an equal number of people going, those guys are wrong.
Speaker 0: And they'd raise their hand like, I got to say something.
Speaker 1: I got to say something.
Speaker 1: Or there's the people out there like, you know, there are people who know more about animes and mangas and stuff than we do.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: We are not the know it alls.
Speaker 1: That's why we had to throw out with us.
Speaker 1: So, you know, there are people out in the audience who know more than you and they might have something to add.
Speaker 1: that is, you know, new information.
Speaker 1: But sometimes they're not so eloquent.
Speaker 1: Sometimes they are right.
Speaker 1: Some, you know, et cetera.
Speaker 1: There's a whole bunch of variables there.
Speaker 1: And it's sort of like, you know, I want to hear what they got to say because it's obviously something I don't know.
Speaker 1: But if they can't say it concisely and well, I don't want them to talk during my panel.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing, though, and be if they do, if they're that smart and they know these things, they should have their own panel.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing that's really interesting about anime Boston with all of that, more so than at any other convention.
Speaker 0: And this is partly because the panels were all the ones I went to, like every panel I went to was pretty damn good.
Speaker 0: Like the weakest panel I saw was well above average for anime cons.
Speaker 0: And I saw some really good panels, too.
Speaker 0: But after every panel, like, you know, at Otakon or Katsucon or something, there'll be like 20 or 30 people who come up to the front of the room and want to talk to the people given the panel afterward.
Speaker 0: But at this con, like mobs would come to the front of the room and not want to leave.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was sort of we had to like, you know, move people along.
Speaker 0: And again, it wasn't just us.
Speaker 0: A lot of people had this problem.
Speaker 1: And I think every panel was very punctual in the ending and starting times.
Speaker 0: Yes, yes, they were.
Speaker 0: But I think the way to solve this is to schedule panels the way Pax does, where every room needs a half hour period between each panel.
Speaker 1: Fifteen minutes.
Speaker 0: Well, no, a half hour and you dedicate, you know, the first 15 minutes of that to Q&A, wind the crowd down while the other people set up.
Speaker 0: And then you clear out the room and have another 15 minutes of silence.
Speaker 1: That's all right.
Speaker 0: Because the 15 minutes, knowing that there's that buffer, you can get all that kind of bustle of.
Speaker 0: I want to talk to the panelists, oh, my God, out of the way.
Speaker 1: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: The other option would be to have allow some.
Speaker 1: if you're going to do the half hour, though, you need to have, you know, remember, they had fewer, bigger panel rooms.
Speaker 1: that made Boston.
Speaker 1: So having these half hour gaps, that's a lot of content you're losing.
Speaker 1: If you have, say, four panel rooms instead of, you know, you have more of them, you can stagger the scheduling and then the half hour emptiness won't matter.
Speaker 0: Now, normally here in most kinds, here's where I'd say, yeah, we'll get rid of the video showing rooms and do and do that instead.
Speaker 0: But anime Boston had better anime showings than pretty much.
Speaker 1: You could see the subtitles.
Speaker 1: It was nice and quiet.
Speaker 1: In fact, they were in.
Speaker 1: one of them was in this hotel that was attached to the convention center.
Speaker 1: It was like a movie theater because you went in one door and then there was a little lobby area and then there was another set of doors.
Speaker 1: So there was no way that the hallway traffic could interfere with the quiet, dark video showing room.
Speaker 1: It was like an actual movie theater is awesome, but really interesting.
Speaker 1: Now, that is, you know, I can't dis other conventions for not having that because that's just a, you know, luck of the way the hotel is arranged, you know, the the architecture of it.
Speaker 1: But, you know, you could sort of get close by doing sort of like, you know, curtains on sticks situation.
Speaker 0: But the really cool thing, I walked in and I watched like 15 minutes of innocence, that whole golem scene.
Speaker 0: I just watched that again.
Speaker 0: It happened to be on.
Speaker 0: But in these rooms, there were a ton of people watching anime, like a ton in all the video rooms they had.
Speaker 0: And looking at the schedule, they didn't fall into the trap that a lot of other anime cons do where they'll show like, you know, episodes five through 11 of some TV show or like long stretches of some anime TV show.
Speaker 0: A lot of the showings were movies, one offs or like the beginnings of shows.
Speaker 0: And in general, like if you're going to do anime video rooms, either don't do them because they're a bad idea the way most people do them, or at least do them the way Anime Boston did, or have the live action violence like Chinese, Japanese, Korean movies, the Filipino stuff and all that cool thing, all the stuff in video five.
Speaker 1: They didn't have that, but you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: But the video rooms were good enough to where I wouldn't say get rid of them and make more panel groups.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So the artist's alley at Anime Boston was actually pretty big.
Speaker 1: It was like maybe half, a little less than half the size of the Otacon.
Speaker 0: I'd say a quarter.
Speaker 1: Quarter and maybe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was still very, very large, much larger than I thought it would be.
Speaker 1: There was maybe 100 tables, if not more, maybe 150 tables.
Speaker 0: It was it was it was still small.
Speaker 0: I mean, compared to Otacon, clearly, but it was a sizable artist's alley.
Speaker 0: The quality was it was the best artist's alley I've ever seen outside of Otacon.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, there was a large variety of different things that were very, very awesome.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean, you had crafts, you had arts, you had fan arts, original arts.
Speaker 1: There was an indie comics guy.
Speaker 1: Oh, that was right.
Speaker 1: We talked to this awesome indie comic guy.
Speaker 1: You got his card over there?
Speaker 0: I got his card.
Speaker 0: We'll talk about him later.
Speaker 0: We're going to interview him and stuff in the future.
Speaker 1: I just wanted to give him a prop.
Speaker 1: Basically, he was talking about how, you know, he tries to sell his indie comic at the comic cons and people will talk to him, but they won't buy his stuff because, like, they only buy Spider-Man for the Silver Age.
Speaker 1: But at the anime cons, he says, like, this is awesome.
Speaker 1: Everyone's buying my shit.
Speaker 1: So that was pretty cool.
Speaker 0: He basically this is his first anime con.
Speaker 0: And he's like, I'm never going back to comic cons.
Speaker 0: Like every anime con I can now.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know, and his stuff wasn't even anime.
Speaker 1: He was just an indie comics dude.
Speaker 1: And he had his, you know, little mini comics and he was going to make a trade.
Speaker 1: And I was like, dude, when you have a trade, I'm so buying it just because you're awesome.
Speaker 1: So, you know, that's the kind of shit that was going down the, you know, the anime Boston artist alley.
Speaker 1: It was totally great.
Speaker 0: Well, the cool thing was it looked like a lot of fun.
Speaker 1: People sat at their tables the whole time.
Speaker 0: I'd say the room was about 60, 70 percent crafty or social currency kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: And then the rest was art, like straight up art.
Speaker 0: It wasn't.
Speaker 0: there weren't that many people selling prints and everything.
Speaker 0: It was mostly people selling crafts and interesting stuff.
Speaker 0: that wasn't just.
Speaker 0: there was some good sushi pillows in the corner.
Speaker 1: There was some good origamis.
Speaker 0: There were a lot of crafty plushy things like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: it was a pretty happening artist alley.
Speaker 1: I spent some times in there.
Speaker 1: Good times.
Speaker 0: Dealers room was surprising because there was one big dealers room and it was.
Speaker 0: it was one of the better dealers rooms I've seen.
Speaker 1: You know what it reminded me of?
Speaker 1: It reminded me of that anime next dealers room only twice as big.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is, we walk around the whole room and everyone's like, yeah, there's a second section.
Speaker 0: So we finish and we're like, oh, let's go to the second section, then leave.
Speaker 0: And it looks like it's just like this tiny alcove.
Speaker 0: So we walk over there and just around the corner in the alcove is basically an entire other dealers room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was just a big room that happened to have a separator that couldn't be moved, you know, which had bathrooms and stuff in it.
Speaker 0: But notes from the dealers room one, the people selling cells were there and they had like they had one guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's at Otacon, too.
Speaker 0: And I got.
Speaker 0: I almost bought a cell.
Speaker 1: He has the legitimate posters, the legitimate wall scrolls in the cells, and he just shows up at all the cons trying to sell him.
Speaker 1: He's totally old school and I see him all the time.
Speaker 1: And I bought my Galaxy Express poster from a while ago.
Speaker 1: I got to still frame that shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but notes of import.
Speaker 0: The ATV table was pretty sad.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The ATV is looking.
Speaker 1: it was looking worse than the CPM booth was looking.
Speaker 1: And what happened to CPM?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, CPM booth was two years ago.
Speaker 0: We bought all that anime for like one.
Speaker 1: One interesting thing from the ATV booth.
Speaker 1: They had 14 volumes of the five star stories, manga for two hundred dollars, all bundled up.
Speaker 1: And I was like, oh, man, but I wasn't going to pay two hundred for it, you know, but I was.
Speaker 1: I was going to go back at two thirty and like offer him like one hundred and maybe settle for one fifty, you know, which would have been ten bucks.
Speaker 1: Per book.
Speaker 1: But I didn't.
Speaker 1: I just, you know, I'll still.
Speaker 1: no one bought it, obviously, because no one else wanted it there but me.
Speaker 1: But I'll I'll get him at Otacon.
Speaker 0: But a comic copia.
Speaker 0: They had all of Phoenix for one hundred bucks.
Speaker 0: Ninety bucks.
Speaker 1: Alex, actually, Alex leave it.
Speaker 1: But volume six through the end.
Speaker 1: So they only have one through five still.
Speaker 1: But they're actually the harder ones to get.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: And I was very happy that I got the first 15 volumes.
Speaker 0: I don't know if that's all of it or not of Dr.
Speaker 0: Slum.
Speaker 1: Let me look that up for fifty two dollars.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, comic copia, if you know, is an awesome comic store.
Speaker 1: in is 18 volumes of the manga.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So I have to get three.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Maybe they're still coming out.
Speaker 1: I'll look at them on the preorder list for you.
Speaker 0: I don't own all of Dr.
Speaker 0: Slump.
Speaker 0: It is vaguely continuously amusing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And we also happen to talk about it at our know your creators.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we did.
Speaker 0: And that's part of the reason why I had to buy it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no.
Speaker 1: But like there were actually some pretty good deals on mangas and you could actually find, you know, because they these you know, we bought a volume of Eagle for ten five bucks.
Speaker 1: that we found, you know, volume four.
Speaker 0: Oh, the best was I forget what booth we're at, but they had the cat eyed boy and it was twenty five dollars.
Speaker 0: And I think ten or fifteen percent off.
Speaker 0: Maybe he's even twenty five percent off.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, hey, I should buy it.
Speaker 0: This guy says wait.
Speaker 0: And he pulls out his iPhone and it looks Amazon.
Speaker 0: It's cheaper on Amazon.
Speaker 0: And he tells me this.
Speaker 0: The guy running the booth says, how much cheaper?
Speaker 1: And we're like, I just said it's like.
Speaker 1: I just said like it's twenty three on Amazon.
Speaker 0: I was a little bit.
Speaker 0: Then he's like, I'll give it to you for fifteen.
Speaker 1: I don't I remember it more like.
Speaker 1: I was just looking it up.
Speaker 1: And I just remember saying it's twenty three on Amazon.
Speaker 1: And the guy just popped out and was like, I'll sell zero.
Speaker 1: I never fifteen.
Speaker 0: And he was standing there and he stands there for a minute and he like he says, give me it.
Speaker 0: And I hand it to him and he holds it and he flips it over and he looks at the back.
Speaker 0: He flips it over again.
Speaker 0: And then he hands it back and says, I'll give it to you for fifteen.
Speaker 1: Oh, I think that's right.
Speaker 0: I think his appraisal was no one else is going to buy this.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No one's going to buy cat eyed boy.
Speaker 0: Cat eyed boy is pretty badass, though.
Speaker 0: It's very key.
Speaker 0: Taro slash bug boy.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got to read that.
Speaker 1: That's my alley.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 0: It is very much your alley.
Speaker 0: I read the first half already.
Speaker 0: It's really good.
Speaker 1: I'm taking it.
Speaker 0: But dealers room aside, the last thing I want to point out is that our friend Luke is a dealer.
Speaker 0: For Hammer Girl.
Speaker 0: And he goes to a lot of cons.
Speaker 0: He really should have been at this kind of the one kind we're at that he doesn't go to.
Speaker 0: He sells all the stuff that like no other dealer at this conference salad would have made bank.
Speaker 1: One more thing about the artist's alley is, I think, not the artist's alley, the dealer's room.
Speaker 1: I think Gundam models might be making a slight comeback because there were a lot more of them for sale there than there had been previous.
Speaker 1: You know, I saw like dealers there who I see at every single convention.
Speaker 1: you see, you know, but they stay.
Speaker 1: They obviously stocked up on models and I saw a lot more people buying them.
Speaker 1: I also think Princess Tutu is making a comeback.
Speaker 0: That was so weird.
Speaker 0: Like at first an anime you should see.
Speaker 0: We're like we have the whole section of anime you probably wouldn't watch unless someone told you to or tricked you into it, but are actually good.
Speaker 0: And the first example is Princess Tutu.
Speaker 0: There were like four independent groups of Princess Tutu cosplayers at this car.
Speaker 0: There were like two tables in the artist's alley with Princess Tutu art and there was Princess Tutu art in the art show.
Speaker 1: So people, I would be on the lookout for a slight resurgence in American anime fandom in Gundam models and also Princess Tutu.
Speaker 1: Don't expect there to be a boom, but a slight surge is what you can expect.
Speaker 0: Maybe a counter-attack.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, so speak, we'll talk about this now.
Speaker 1: I was just about to bring up the same thing.
Speaker 0: There was an artist alley and there was a dealer's room.
Speaker 0: There was also a swap meet.
Speaker 1: This is so awesome, right?
Speaker 1: Because you're not allowed to sell things unless you're a dealer, right?
Speaker 1: Because you got to deal with taxes and all that crap, but there's no rule you can't swap things.
Speaker 1: So on Friday and on Saturday they do it twice.
Speaker 1: Anime Boston has a swap meet.
Speaker 1: Basically people come and they bring all this junk they don't want.
Speaker 1: Old mangas, old DVDs, old toys.
Speaker 0: Plastic Halloween masks of Gundam characters.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: They lay them out on it.
Speaker 1: They have a room full of tables.
Speaker 1: They just set their stuff up on a table and you sit there and people walk around looking at your stuff.
Speaker 1: And they, you know, they offer to trade you and people trade all their anime stuff.
Speaker 1: And it's, I'm just not, I use selling a whole bunch of stuff on like Amazon, like comics and stuff, like one piece volumes they didn't want and such.
Speaker 1: Screw that.
Speaker 1: I'm saving all my stuff, all my comics now for Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: Thing is, I feel like what no one did, but I would do is I got, you got to dress up like the merchant from secret of Mata and not set up on the table, but put a rug down on the ground.
Speaker 1: I'm going to get a turban, a rug, a vase, a plastic snake, and the whole, you know, a purple vest, you know, with a white poofy shirt under it and the whole, the whole thing.
Speaker 0: And that's what I, and what about your idea of taking my trench coat and hanging everything on the inside?
Speaker 1: Two swap meets one Friday, one Saturday, I can do both on Friday.
Speaker 1: I'll lay out the rug and on Saturday I'll come with a trench coat.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And I'll walk around and be like, I got manga.
Speaker 0: People had some crazy stuff at this.
Speaker 1: Well, one dude had like really crazy stuff.
Speaker 1: It's like the Tetris board game.
Speaker 1: He had a Dr.
Speaker 1: Chaos cartridge.
Speaker 1: It was, it was pretty out of control.
Speaker 0: One girl had two gold box.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Most people just had like, you know, old manga.
Speaker 1: They didn't want to read anymore.
Speaker 1: You know, like the same Tokyo pops you see going for a dollar in a dealer's room, but there was some good stuff to be had.
Speaker 1: You know, one guy was trying to like, you know, pawn off his cowboy bebop box, but everyone else had already seen it.
Speaker 1: So they didn't want it.
Speaker 0: So Friday night we went to something we've never really gone to in fullness before we went to and fully attended Daryl Surratt and Mike tool performing anime hell.
Speaker 1: Oh, the third guy was there.
Speaker 1: The Kaiju guy.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah.
Speaker 0: The Kaiju guy.
Speaker 0: What was his name?
Speaker 0: Cause he's all horn.
Speaker 0: Cause he's awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anime hell.
Speaker 0: If you haven't been to it, you should go to at least once.
Speaker 1: I knew what it was.
Speaker 1: I knew of it.
Speaker 1: I understood it, but I had not attended it.
Speaker 0: It is one of those things where you really need to experience it to understand.
Speaker 0: And if you don't understand, check out my thing of the day from yesterday.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: What I like about anime hell is it brings me back to that, you know, two in the morning, alone in the dark, Cartoon Network, Space Ghost kind of action.
Speaker 1: That's that's what it is.
Speaker 0: Plus this one was in 3D.
Speaker 1: And Ivan the Red was there.
Speaker 0: Ivan the Red was okay.
Speaker 1: I liked Ivan the Red.
Speaker 0: I don't know, 3D Bollywood and stories from North America.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Those are good too.
Speaker 1: Also those little clips of the Jesus crap taken out of context.
Speaker 1: Come with me kid.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: That was fun stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And I was also happy that we basically stayed Friday night at anime Boston in the convention center until it closed.
Speaker 0: I have not stayed at a convention until it closed since like, it's been like three years.
Speaker 0: I'm too old for that shit.
Speaker 0: And somehow I did it at anime Boston.
Speaker 0: Twice.
Speaker 0: I was so pleased with myself.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I try to remember what all we did, the anime squares, which is OK.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we were going to.
Speaker 0: we were guest squares.
Speaker 0: We were the bottom left square on anime square.
Speaker 1: Nobody picked us.
Speaker 0: Well, the bottom left square is like the bastard stepchild of square.
Speaker 1: The other problem is that, you know, they really they need to have nine microphones for the nine squares.
Speaker 1: That way we could talk at any time.
Speaker 1: And also, oh, the way they set up the squares is very interesting, though.
Speaker 0: It's like sit on the people sitting in chairs.
Speaker 0: They would people like up on the stage.
Speaker 0: There were people sitting on the table above them.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So it's like there was a table on the stage for the top three squares, the stage for the middle three and the floor for the bottom three.
Speaker 0: You know what I would have done instead of having the computer screen, give everyone big X's nose to hold up.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's a good idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's good.
Speaker 1: Very good.
Speaker 1: Also, the guy reading the questions, he didn't read them very eloquently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 0: Elegant or eloquent.
Speaker 0: You could go either way.
Speaker 1: That's exactly my point.
Speaker 1: It was it was sometimes hard to get the question out of him.
Speaker 0: It was OK.
Speaker 1: It was all right.
Speaker 1: It could it could have been a lot worse, but it was good.
Speaker 1: People were entertained by it greatly.
Speaker 1: And in fact, you know, at that panel, I think that the you know, usually on a game show, it's the the hosts and such and the content of the game show has to carry, you know, the load.
Speaker 1: But in the anime squares, the contestants carried the load of all the entertainment, which is awesome.
Speaker 0: Well, it was.
Speaker 1: it was not often that you have such great contestants.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I mean, usually we do like the anime match game and we'll have awesome guests and we'll be doing it.
Speaker 0: And the people we actually get from the audience have like never seen an anime in their lives.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Like they did.
Speaker 0: They have no idea.
Speaker 0: But random dude from the audience knew more than like anyone we've had on our shows.
Speaker 1: But he didn't have to know a lot for the anime squares.
Speaker 1: It wasn't an anime trivia kind of thing.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, those people were making some anime jokes.
Speaker 1: They were indeed making some anime jokes and they were dressed up as various shapes and sizes.
Speaker 1: But Saturday, we went to the California concert and first it was a video games orchestra concert.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: They scheduled it wrong.
Speaker 0: They said California concert and they scheduled it.
Speaker 0: The entirety of what they scheduled was the video game concert.
Speaker 0: And then after that, not on the schedule was the California concert.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: They basically the schedule said California concert 90 minutes.
Speaker 1: Ha ha ha ha ha ha.
Speaker 1: It was video games orchestra concert 90 minutes, followed by California concert very long.
Speaker 0: The video game orchestra concert was pretty damn bad ass.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: I mean, it was only, you know, a chamber.
Speaker 1: It wasn't, you know, a whole orchestra.
Speaker 1: But, you know, that's not it doesn't mean much.
Speaker 1: It was fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: And Calafina, if you don't know, Calafina are three vocalists and Yuki Kajira.
Speaker 0: They did the music for such terrible shows as Dot Hack, Noir, the Cabolet.
Speaker 0: What was that show?
Speaker 1: El Cazador de la Bruja.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Basically amazing, amazing music that will trick you into watching a bad show far longer than you otherwise would.
Speaker 0: I watched 13 episodes.
Speaker 1: Black Butler.
Speaker 0: 13 episodes of Dot Hack before I realized it was bad because the music was so good.
Speaker 0: I couldn't tell.
Speaker 1: Exactly right.
Speaker 1: So they do basically this amazing sort of operatic almost kind of singing.
Speaker 1: And they can really sing.
Speaker 1: I heard them sing in person.
Speaker 1: So it wasn't digital effects.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, there is a such thing as live digital manipulation.
Speaker 1: Possibly.
Speaker 1: But for three people at once, it's not easy.
Speaker 0: They can freaking sing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And the video games orchestra can fucking play.
Speaker 1: But we because the concert was scheduled as such, we could not stay for the whole thing.
Speaker 1: We had to leave before the very final bit because we had to go and get ready for our panel.
Speaker 1: So that was kind of sad.
Speaker 0: We saw the whole concert except the encore bit, which apparently is when Yuki herself came out and performed with them.
Speaker 0: I could have cried.
Speaker 1: And someone said that she was all elegant, like wicked, elegant.
Speaker 0: I think it was like she went on.
Speaker 0: She went at length to describe the degree to which this woman is elegant.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So I sort of grace.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And of course, during the video games orchestra.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: They were totally willing to let you photograph and whatever, which means everyone could bring their camera in.
Speaker 1: But during the California, you couldn't photograph or whatever, even though everyone had the cameras on them.
Speaker 0: Still, you know, Japanese guests, that's the way it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: One other thing is that while everyone was standing there waiting for the video games orchestra concert.
Speaker 1: to begin, they had a pre-show in which they had video content on the screen that had audio that had audience participation thingies.
Speaker 0: Stage.
Speaker 0: All I have to say about that is that one brilliant.
Speaker 1: It was indeed brilliant and effective.
Speaker 1: It worked very well.
Speaker 1: It was the ultimate crowd control.
Speaker 0: It was exactly the same.
Speaker 1: The only thing I question is, are they going to keep?
Speaker 1: are they going?
Speaker 1: They can't reuse the same one next year.
Speaker 1: They have to make a new one just like it.
Speaker 0: They should sell the ones they use to other convention.
Speaker 1: They should make a company that makes those for any convention, any events, any event.
Speaker 0: We will make these things for stadiums, because at most anime conventions or like, you know, art animal club stuff back in the day, we would have to do this manually.
Speaker 0: Like when the crowd was waiting for a music night to start or a tournament to start or something, like someone like me would have to get up.
Speaker 0: And we had this list of like these BS games we would play with the audience just to keep them occupied.
Speaker 1: Like the one of our panels, I think an anime you should see.
Speaker 1: I made the.
Speaker 1: I did the wave with the whole panel room because there were like seven hundred and fifty people in that room.
Speaker 1: I did the way from the front to the back.
Speaker 1: It was awesome.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Anime, you should say the last thing about the king of the wave, the space that the concert is in for Anime Boston in the Heinz Convention Center is very Pax-esque.
Speaker 0: It lacks only the lack of chairs.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: And I'd even had like an upper deck, too, on both sides.
Speaker 1: That was on.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: And I point out that Pax East Coast there, I think is going to work really better.
Speaker 1: Use that upper deck.
Speaker 1: I want to go up God because that I think about it right.
Speaker 1: I've been to the concerts at Pax last year.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So they're probably going to be very similar on the East Coast.
Speaker 0: But then again, East Coast, they're probably going to get some East Coast acts.
Speaker 1: Possibly.
Speaker 1: But anyway, you know, standing there was great and all being right with the concert.
Speaker 1: But it's like I feel like to do it again, I would want to sit back and that upper deck would be so great.
Speaker 0: You are old.
Speaker 1: Maybe we're older than all the other people there.
Speaker 1: That's for sure.
Speaker 0: Though I feel the average age of anime Boston was not high, but it was higher than other anime.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 1: But I think that's only.
Speaker 1: I think I don't think that's a result of it being actual higher.
Speaker 1: I think it's a result of the con goers aging.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's the same people got a year older.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's actually, you know, that older people are, you know, coming.
Speaker 0: No, but that that that means there's a significant trend because before it was this boom of kids a certain age.
Speaker 0: So we had this constant influx every year of younger and younger people.
Speaker 0: If those whatever percentage of those people continue to go to cons as they get older are the ones who start watching more anime.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: And we'll have to do a separate show on that.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the concert was great.
Speaker 0: But speaking of Scott doing the wave, our anime, you should see panel was.
Speaker 0: This is the reason why I think we need to do this at every convention forever now.
Speaker 0: Or in the very least, after we do it for a few years, like pass the baton to someone else.
Speaker 1: It needs to be some time passing or at least swap it up.
Speaker 0: Like maybe we'll always do it, but we'll always get a special guest on.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's Daryl Surratt added a lot to it.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to do it with Gerald instead at Otacon just to have a different person.
Speaker 1: You know, he's going to tell him to watch bad shows.
Speaker 0: He'll tell him to watch, right, man?
Speaker 1: No, he'll tell him to watch, like, I don't know, desert punk.
Speaker 0: Nodgica.
Speaker 1: Nodgica.
Speaker 0: But anime, you should see, like it was crazy how many people were there, especially because that room is bigger than most other cons panel rooms.
Speaker 0: And the fact that people were still turned away.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I don't know what else I can say.
Speaker 0: Other than that, the crowd really liked it.
Speaker 0: And we will upload these slides.
Speaker 0: Everyone's asking for them.
Speaker 0: I think at Otacon, we're just going to have to print out a one page thing and give it to everyone.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Let's see, what other panels did we go to?
Speaker 1: We went to, we sat there for Alex Leavitt's panel about Shinichiro Watanabe.
Speaker 1: That was pretty good.
Speaker 0: It was.
Speaker 0: We also went to, well, we'll save the Vile Specter of Moai for last because something special happened there.
Speaker 1: Of course, something very special happened there.
Speaker 0: We'll tell that after we talk about the late show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we went to the worst of Tezuka panel.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And that was that was pretty great.
Speaker 0: I've seen some of what they showed, but I had not seen all.
Speaker 1: I had not seen that Cleopatra.
Speaker 1: Oh, my, I, I, I, I theoretically live action Astro Boy.
Speaker 0: I theoretically knew how bad that Cleopatra was.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm in the same boat, but seeing it, actually seeing it was like, and actually that Phoenix movie.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to watch.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to Otacon's got to get a hold of that and show it.
Speaker 0: Oh, shit.
Speaker 0: Like video five.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: I'm all over that.
Speaker 0: But we you know, we did our panels and anime you should see was like crazy, despite the fact that ninety nine percent of the audience never even heard of Escaflowne.
Speaker 0: Or like more than half the audience never seen Ghost in the Shell.
Speaker 0: Hardly anyone had seen Ava.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we had to resist asking for every single anime how many people had seen it because then it would get really stupid because maybe we should make a panel.
Speaker 1: How many have you seen it?
Speaker 1: And it would just be here.
Speaker 1: Who's seen it?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know that the whole panel.
Speaker 0: how we could turn that into a pseudo game show where you you narrow the crowd down.
Speaker 0: You know, have you seen it?
Speaker 0: Have you seen it until there's only a few people left.
Speaker 0: But then if they say yes, you randomly grill them to make sure they're not lying.
Speaker 1: Of course, when you get down to the low numbers right when you got like one or two dudes left, you bring them up and you grill them on every single one of the shows to make sure.
Speaker 0: So you say you've seen Evangelion.
Speaker 0: name any character from it.
Speaker 1: Misati.
Speaker 1: Fail.
Speaker 1: Know your creators.
Speaker 0: Tanaka fail.
Speaker 0: We run it differently every time.
Speaker 0: And I think we finally figured out how to run it.
Speaker 0: So if you've seen our panels at other conventions, particularly anime, you should see don't go to our panels.
Speaker 0: But go to know your creators, because it'll be very, very different.
Speaker 0: We only got like 200 people.
Speaker 0: I know your creators, but more people were shuffling in toward the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was sort of weird the way the panels are scheduled.
Speaker 1: They weren't scheduled evenly.
Speaker 1: Some were big, some were small.
Speaker 1: Some had space, but for some had empty space before or after them.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: So it wasn't really consistent.
Speaker 1: Like sometimes you'd start up a panel and an empty room and you'd have to fill it up with the power of your panel.
Speaker 1: But sometimes you'd get someone's leavings from the previous panel and you'd be able to hold onto them and drag in some more.
Speaker 1: Sometimes you would leave some people left over after a panel, but sometimes your panel be over to clear out.
Speaker 1: And it was, you know, it sort of mixed it up and it was interesting, but I think consistency is better.
Speaker 0: So in all honesty, we did Saturday night, the late show, late night anime Boston.
Speaker 0: This was kind of a test.
Speaker 0: We were seeing how this would work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we learned a lot from trying this at Katsu.
Speaker 0: I think we did a really good job, actually.
Speaker 0: All things considered at Katsu Con.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: At Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay.
Speaker 1: Basically we, you know, we didn't, we weren't able to do like a professional actual late show format or anything.
Speaker 0: Because we didn't bring like any of the crew.
Speaker 0: It was basically just me and Scott doing this entirely with force of will.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And the room was not that crowded.
Speaker 1: It was across from the rave, but the doors were closed and the rave did not interfere with us.
Speaker 1: And we only had competition.
Speaker 1: The only competition we had was porn and sleeping and rave.
Speaker 0: So, you know, there were, there were between 50 and 70 people in the room when it started.
Speaker 1: That was about right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And the cool thing was it wasn't even in the con book.
Speaker 0: So people showed up and no one knew what it was.
Speaker 1: It was like in the, in the schedule, I said late show, but in the con book, it didn't say anything about it.
Speaker 1: So it was just like late show.
Speaker 1: What's that?
Speaker 1: And everyone asked us, what's the late show?
Speaker 1: And I was like, you know, it's technically a late show, like, you know, Letterman or whatever, but anime, but you know what?
Speaker 1: We're just going to sit up there and BS.
Speaker 1: And we just, we tell, we told the joke of the only other things scheduled right now are porn about 10 times.
Speaker 1: And then we dropped it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Then we dropped it, moved on to other jokes.
Speaker 0: But if any, if there's any gauge, I forget what, what joke someone told, but there was a point at which someone said something and the audience just freaking lost it.
Speaker 0: Like more so than any other joke.
Speaker 0: It looks like everyone there had a good time between me.
Speaker 1: You know, it was just me, you, Daryl and, uh, it was just us sort of shooting the shit, you know, at the audience, having a nice discussion, saying funny stuff, showing, uh, we, we did the, um, the Harris bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: We ended with the hope.
Speaker 1: Don't know Ken.
Speaker 1: Oh no bit.
Speaker 0: Oh my.
Speaker 0: The thing is because Daryl, like he, he's seen that clip as many times as we have seen that clip.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I've seen that clip a lot of times, but when we finally showed at the end, it's basically me, Daryl, Lou and Scott looking at my laptop, watching.
Speaker 1: I was looking at the big screen.
Speaker 0: We're looking at the laptop and we're just giggling because we all know how it goes.
Speaker 0: And like we couldn't control it.
Speaker 0: So Daryl's just sitting there like, it's a hilarious clip.
Speaker 0: How can you, we also did the bit of the openers and closers to anime in Germany.
Speaker 1: Oh yeah.
Speaker 1: I think that went over actually really well.
Speaker 1: People, people like that Italian one piece.
Speaker 0: Italian one piece is better than real one piece.
Speaker 1: Italian one piece is better.
Speaker 1: And we also had fun torturing the audience with English one piece, which is just as good for, as the enjoying of the Italian one piece.
Speaker 0: I think it was really fun.
Speaker 0: And if Anime Boston will let us do it, uh, we were, we were, we were going to do this.
Speaker 1: I want to do a panel of just the foreign opener.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm already working on that.
Speaker 1: We should throw in like, you know, the DuckTales and stuff.
Speaker 0: Anime Boston gave me like more ideas for panels than the last year of trying to come up with panels.
Speaker 0: gave me for panels.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Basically took bits from other panels and expand them into panels themselves.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: But the Late Show went really well.
Speaker 0: And we originally were going to do this at KatsuCon, but we're kind of dropping KatsuCon for now, at least until they get their act together more.
Speaker 0: But if Anime Boston will have us, I think we're going to up the ante and do the full on Late Show.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: We're going to need to do something to get more people in there though.
Speaker 1: And we're also going to need some more help on the backend.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Basically if we're going to do the Late Show, we're going to need to bring like our staff.
Speaker 0: We're going to need to bring like four or five crew people.
Speaker 0: And we're going to need to get at least one or two voice actor guests.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I think, I really think we should stick to the one voice actor guest.
Speaker 1: That way we can fill half the Late Show with like our content and such, and then we can fill the other half with the interviewing a guest bit and then end with some, our content.
Speaker 0: Plus, you know, like real Late Shows, you have the kind of two bit guests, you know, the Daryl Surratt, the Lou, not really two bit, but two bit in the sense of, you know, if you've got Vic and you've got Daryl, the audience wants to see Vic.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: But the Late Show, I think like it was super fun to do and we had a great time, but then afterward we stayed because there was a panel that Daryl Surratt was going to be on with someone else.
Speaker 1: The someone else.
Speaker 0: Well, the panel was the Vile Specter of Moet and it was, and I wanted to know about the Vile Specter of Moet.
Speaker 0: And I knew a lot of this, like Emily had taught me a lot of this and like we knew a lot of the basics.
Speaker 1: I still learn things I didn't know.
Speaker 0: This panel was so well researched and so together and it was, it was amazing.
Speaker 0: I look at Otaku in an entirely different light.
Speaker 1: And you know, it's like, I always forget like, you know, the bad Miyazaki, you know, it's like, I know of him, like, you know, they posted his picture and I'm like, Oh yeah, that guy.
Speaker 1: But I always forget like how significant that dude was in Otaku history.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like.
Speaker 1: I needed that reminder, you know, and it really, you know, changes the whole perspective.
Speaker 0: Plus, I didn't know about the early post-war usage of Otaku.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I knew that it meant house, right?
Speaker 0: But I didn't know the other, like why the panel was really interesting.
Speaker 0: And we're going to make sure any con where we have influence, he is going to come and do that panel again.
Speaker 0: because the person doing the panel.
Speaker 0: I walk up and I'm like, Hey, this looks like a good panel.
Speaker 0: I shake the guy's hand and he's like, do you know who I am?
Speaker 1: Well, he's like, you guys stole my club and we're like, what the fuck?
Speaker 1: And his, his badge says Christian daily.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, I don't know anyone named Christian daily.
Speaker 1: And it's like, wait a minute, wait a minute.
Speaker 0: And I said, we suddenly realized that this dude was one of the original RIT anime club presidents.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: This guy, there's a continuous.
Speaker 1: See, when you are an anime club, see if you're probably the anime club president, like if you're in the anime club at RIT now, you probably hear these names like rim Scott Johnson, Luke, Christian, the other Scott.
Speaker 1: It wasn't, there was another.
Speaker 1: Scott is president, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Scott Meeker and Jason what's his name?
Speaker 1: or Saudi and Greg young.
Speaker 0: And especially, you know, there are some anime clubs that aren't that big, but there are like old school anime clubs where like being the president of that club in that school is a big deal.
Speaker 0: Like it's, it's, it's like on the level of it's like if Utena were real to a tiny, tiny degree.
Speaker 1: So you just, when we were in the anime club during the course of those years, we heard these names, Christian, something, something Scott Meeker, something, right.
Speaker 1: We just heard these names.
Speaker 1: We didn't really know these people.
Speaker 1: And occasionally like at a convention like Scott Johnson would say, Hey, that's Scott Meeker.
Speaker 1: What's up for like five minutes.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: At Otacon, I think it was two years ago, we had five years of anime club presidents at the same time at the same time.
Speaker 1: That was pretty good.
Speaker 0: That was crazy.
Speaker 1: So when we saw the badge was Christian and he said club, we're like, Oh shit, this dude was like anime club president, like before you're even at RIT, like we're getting the point now to where like he was graduated when we got there.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 0: And he, it's interesting because like our era at the anime club, like from Luke, Scott Johnson, me, Lisa, like this, there's this progression where there were huge changes.
Speaker 0: Like everything exploded in good ways.
Speaker 0: And Christian was president during a similar explosion.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The perhaps the original explosion.
Speaker 1: He was talking about how when he was in the club, like technically this girl was president who didn't do anything.
Speaker 0: It's funny how the exact same thing happened with Scott Johnson later.
Speaker 0: Good times.
Speaker 0: But as a result, we, we, we met like one of the classic people of our own personal history and at the same time saw an awesome panel.
Speaker 0: So Christian Daley, you are going to be at every freaking con we can get you into.
Speaker 0: Good God.
Speaker 1: Any con he wants to go to that he can go to.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So, uh, what else is there to say about the anime of Austin?
Speaker 0: Sunday was Sunday.
Speaker 0: We didn't do a lot of the con.
Speaker 0: We kind of just hung out.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, you know, the schedule was not jam packed on Sunday.
Speaker 1: We could have gone to the open and closing ceremonies.
Speaker 0: We, uh, we kind of skipped out on like Saturday evening at the con to go get dinner with friends outside the con.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's not to be covered by this episode to be covered another time up.
Speaker 0: the area around the convention center is actually great for a convention.
Speaker 0: You walk one block in any direction and it's very nice restaurant.
Speaker 0: There are a million nice restaurants and no con people.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Zero.
Speaker 0: Also, there's a salad place because the cool thing is anime.
Speaker 0: Boston could not fit in the Heinz.
Speaker 1: Like if it were just the Heinz, it's actually that the Heinz is a convention center is attached to a mall, a yuppie mall, which is attached to this hotel and is also attached to the Prudential tower.
Speaker 1: It's like all these things are physically joined at the hip and that's necessary because all those con goers are going to that mall to get that caught food court.
Speaker 0: You walk into that mall, like entering the mall.
Speaker 0: The mall is as crowded with nothing but con people as like a hallway in Otakon is.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: That hotel attachment allows them to have the later night programming that a convention could not, a convention con alone could not have.
Speaker 0: Case in point.
Speaker 0: Anime Boston had two video gaming rooms, one in the convention center, one in the hotel.
Speaker 0: They also had tabletop gaming run by this awesome dude in the hotel table.
Speaker 0: So I could go late.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Tabletop gaming at Kinetic Kinetic Con.
Speaker 0: Anime Boston was like a mini Kinetic Con.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was not as good as Kinetic Con, but it was actually going like it was a room about the size of the UberCon room.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And they had games there.
Speaker 1: Most of it was people playing Magic, Yu-Gi-Oh, etc.
Speaker 1: A lot of people were playing this monster Godzilla Kaiju miniatures game.
Speaker 0: There were a ton of German board games.
Speaker 1: And they had a table that pretty much just had like one of every good German board game on it.
Speaker 1: And you could just pick them up and play without checking them out or anything.
Speaker 0: And no one stole anything like the back right of the room.
Speaker 0: There were two tables running like D&D and role playing games all weekend.
Speaker 1: Shadowrun and Vezum and the titles of these games were those around one half role playing game.
Speaker 0: It was obvious that these were the fun convention style D&D role playing.
Speaker 1: So I mean, usually right, like at Katsucon, you know, there's this.
Speaker 1: I guess there's nominally a tabletop gaming or like Otacon, but nobody.
Speaker 0: hard gaming area.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But no one uses it except for the LARP.
Speaker 1: And they had there was a LARP area at the in that room.
Speaker 1: But I don't.
Speaker 1: I didn't really see too much action in the LARP.
Speaker 1: It might it might have moved around.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: But there was actually significant action in the tabletop CCG board game role playing game department, you know, enough that we spent some time in there and played some games and had some fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: We talked to people how to play games.
Speaker 0: We played a bunch of games.
Speaker 0: We learned we found about a game that was fun, but not worth buying.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Might be worth buying.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't buy that game.
Speaker 0: I might buy it for cheap.
Speaker 0: It's a good game to play it like cons with other people.
Speaker 1: It's a game for you to buy.
Speaker 1: Not for me to buy.
Speaker 0: I'll put it next to Twilight Struggle.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: And Hellas.
Speaker 0: They had a DDR machine and an in the groove machine.
Speaker 1: They also had some pads hooked up to a PlayStation.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The rave was not the kind of music I want to dance to.
Speaker 0: Nothing is ever beaten.
Speaker 0: The first katsukan.
Speaker 0: I went to that.
Speaker 0: That was like the best anime dance I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: But they are twice as good in the music department as Otacon because Otacon is just boom, boom, boom, boom for like three or four hours.
Speaker 1: I went into the rave room as they were picking up all of the dance floor tiles and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: And it was looking like a pretty well laid out room.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And they had two different areas with two different kinds of music.
Speaker 0: And the music was not like great dance music.
Speaker 0: But it had like four more elements other than just boom, boom, boom.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It was almost danceable.
Speaker 0: I was very pleased with it.
Speaker 1: So let's see.
Speaker 1: I feel like there's something we're missing here.
Speaker 0: Something we're missing.
Speaker 0: We hung out with Daryl Surratt a lot.
Speaker 1: The panels we did, the panels we went to.
Speaker 0: We have a lot of shout outs for cool people we met or hung out with at the con in general.
Speaker 0: I mean, Vega was there.
Speaker 0: We hung out with her a whole bunch.
Speaker 0: Water's Poison.
Speaker 1: Oh, right.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Water's Poison's girlfriend.
Speaker 1: She went to this plushie making panel.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: I wanted to go to that.
Speaker 1: And she came out and like she was she like had a half made plushie of, you know, major Kusanagi.
Speaker 0: And I was like, oh, that was not big enough.
Speaker 0: But I don't think they had enough stuffing in that room to make the bubble.
Speaker 0: But it depends, though, is it manga version?
Speaker 0: Is it later?
Speaker 1: No, but it's like she had this little dolly and she had like, you know, a little purple hair, a little black coat.
Speaker 1: And it's like she was going to.
Speaker 1: you know, it was looking like, hey, that could be pretty good when it's ready.
Speaker 1: So that was, you know, I didn't go to the panel, but it looked good enough by the judging by the results to me.
Speaker 0: Who else was there?
Speaker 0: was Naito was there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we were just lots of people.
Speaker 0: We ran into a ton of you farmers and front row crew people.
Speaker 0: So let us know if you were here.
Speaker 0: And we forgot to mention you because we I got like a pile of business cards.
Speaker 1: Ian Levenstein and his girlfriend were there.
Speaker 1: And I didn't realize that his girlfriend works with a Pokemon company until just now.
Speaker 1: So I'm going to.
Speaker 1: I'm going to get some hookups in that department.
Speaker 1: Stay tuned.
Speaker 0: The coolest thing, though, before anime, you should see, you know, we're like we're kind of standing outside the room getting ready to go in and this big group of kids walk up to it.
Speaker 0: And they're like, oh, my God, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 0: We saw you guys.
Speaker 0: And I don't remember if it was Katsu Kahn or Otacon.
Speaker 0: And you showed us that gag manga thing.
Speaker 0: And I was like the best thing ever.
Speaker 1: We only show we had to be Katsu Kahn.
Speaker 1: It had to be.
Speaker 0: We've shown it in other places where I'm trying to remember it had to be Katsu Kahn.
Speaker 1: We guarantee it was Katsu Kahn.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we they basically said we will watch anything that you ever tell us about again forever.
Speaker 0: And then they sat through our animation and they took notes.
Speaker 0: They took note.
Speaker 0: They sat there and they were like, hey, watch this.
Speaker 0: Be watch this.
Speaker 1: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: Those kids are going to turn out all right.
Speaker 1: We also in the game tabletop gaming room, there were some kids who were all magic, the gathering types, but we got them to play some block.
Speaker 1: And those kids are all right.
Speaker 1: They are going to turn out just fine.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Boston was bad ass.
Speaker 1: It was a definite win.
Speaker 0: The cool thing is, like from this meta perspective, as a con goer, you know, like I don't want I can't go to a lot of other detail because I didn't really pay attention.
Speaker 0: But there was nothing obviously wrong with the convention at all.
Speaker 0: Like there was no significant problem.
Speaker 0: Nothing got in the way of my enjoyment.
Speaker 0: But most importantly, I wasn't enjoying anime cons or just cons in general for a while now, because like last OdaCon, we did like six panels because, you know, we were helping them out and filling in some extra panel space.
Speaker 0: And like we've been doing a million million panels and artists and all this stuff.
Speaker 0: And I never had time to just do stuff at the convention proper for a while now.
Speaker 0: This con we only did like we did three panels.
Speaker 0: And then like the anime squares, we just kind of we were guests on it.
Speaker 0: That was the same as doing a panel.
Speaker 0: Got to spend a lot of time hanging out with people and going to panels and doing all the stuff that I like doing.
Speaker 0: The reason I used to go to anime cons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's sort of weird.
Speaker 1: It's like I thought that, you know, because I had been to so many anime cons that like there was no more excitement in dealers rooms or artists alleys or panels because I had seen so many and been to so many that I was just like, well, if I'm not doing I'm not having fun.
Speaker 1: The thing was right, is that at these conventions, I was having fun when I was doing panels and I wasn't having fun when I wasn't doing them.
Speaker 1: because I didn't I wasn't really actually able to do anything because I wasn't doing the panel last year.
Speaker 0: We were just exhausted and wrecked managing like a 14 artist alley tables and like all the stuff.
Speaker 1: And I was spending all my time sitting in an artist's alley, not doing anything, not going to panels, not going and checking stuff out.
Speaker 0: Plus, we had to like go and get our stuff for all these panels we were doing.
Speaker 0: And we scraped the bottom of the barrel like we did that Advanced Wars panel.
Speaker 1: Exactly.
Speaker 1: It was terrible.
Speaker 0: Thing is, a ton of people came to that panel and they loved it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But yeah, so actually doing stuff at the con, you know, and especially because there were so many people there that we sort of knew, you know, that we didn't get to see very often, you know, convention friends, Boston friends.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: We hung out with Kat.
Speaker 0: She was that artist's alley table.
Speaker 0: We didn't get to hang out with her more.
Speaker 0: And like we were going to go to dinner with some people, but we lost like half the group.
Speaker 0: So we didn't actually get to eat dinner with Vega and all them.
Speaker 1: It's like I was going to call up my former coworker who was up in Boston, but I got his voicemail so we didn't get to eat dinner with him, you know?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But Anime Boston kind of, I realized to strike the balance, we're in all cons from now on.
Speaker 0: Fewer, more focused panels and nothing else other than hanging out and having fun.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I mean, think about New York Anime Festival.
Speaker 1: You pretty much walked in, did our panels and walked out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, seriously.
Speaker 0: It was last year.
Speaker 0: We walked in Saturday morning.
Speaker 0: We did panel, panel, panel and we left.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean, New York Anime Festival is a little different because it's mostly is just a big room without a lot of, you know, stuff.
Speaker 1: But I mean, we didn't see anyone else's panels or anything.
Speaker 1: And it was probably something to see.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was.
Speaker 0: But my love of anime cons is rekindled and I'm looking forward to Otacon more than I've looked forward to any Otacon in years.
Speaker 0: Just because, one, we're only doing three panels and it's the same three stupid panels.
Speaker 0: I don't have to do crap except rewrite the Know Your Creators panel.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I think we're going to turn it into a clip panel, right?
Speaker 1: We got more videos.
Speaker 0: Wait till you see.
Speaker 0: I already, you should see.
Speaker 1: Because I think our panels, right, tend to be panels where we just talk and talk and talk.
Speaker 1: And we have some slides that would have pictures on them to support talking.
Speaker 0: And that works well for certain things like anime.
Speaker 0: you should see.
Speaker 0: Any other format would either have to be two hours long or you're going to cut off like a hat.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: But like you look at say like Daryl Surratt likes to do these clip panels where he just shows a whole bunch of video and he'll talk over it.
Speaker 1: I think we need to, we're going to do the in between panel where we have the talking, but then we have a significant number of supporting video clips.
Speaker 1: I think that's what we have to go for.
Speaker 0: Plus I've already made the shirotasm scale.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: I like just from left to right.
Speaker 0: And I've got these like shiro heads that show you how shirotastic something is.
Speaker 1: How many shiro heads?
Speaker 1: No one knows who it looks like.
Speaker 0: I made one up.
Speaker 0: I found something on the internet.
Speaker 1: Just use the major's head and grow it.
Speaker 0: I'll have to use the different versions of the major.
Speaker 1: That's a good one.
Speaker 0: But that, the shirotasm scale will let you know what Know Your Creators is going to be like.
Speaker 0: I'm excited about this.
Speaker 0: And the panels we're going to be running at Anime Boston next year are going to be interesting.
Speaker 0: Suffice it to say.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So Anime Boston was awesome.
Speaker 1: There's probably something about Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: we forgot, but that's all right because I think we talked about the awesomeness enough to cover the base.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Go, if you are feeling down about anime cons or you're looking for an anime con to go to and you can't get to Otacon.
Speaker 1: Oh, here's the one thing you got to say about Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: It's very, very smart.
Speaker 1: They separated the masquerade feedback from the con feedback.
Speaker 0: Oh my God.
Speaker 0: I almost forgot about that.
Speaker 0: There was a feedback session and a masquerade feedback session.
Speaker 0: Weren't they at the same time too?
Speaker 1: No, they were different times.
Speaker 0: Regardless, they should be at the same time because as we've noticed at every anime con ever, if you go to the feedback session, there'll be one person who has legitimate feedback.
Speaker 0: 99 cosplayers complaining about the masquerade.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: It was brilliant.
Speaker 0: Why didn't I ever think of that?
Speaker 0: I feel stupid.
Speaker 1: I also felt stupid, but when I saw that on the schedule, I was like, genius.
Speaker 1: Genius.
Speaker 0: Otacon, take a page.
Speaker 0: because seriously, Anime Boston, the best way I can describe it, kind of in the vague terms, it feels like Otacon, but it's closer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it does.
Speaker 1: It didn't have the numbers that Otacon had, but it had a very large number.
Speaker 0: And while it doesn't have the crazy Lark on CL concert, California was a crazy, badass concert.
Speaker 1: The production quality of it was just as good.
Speaker 1: And the feel of the convention was an Otacon feel.
Speaker 0: It felt just like Otacon.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you go to Anime Boston, Otacon is the same thing with more people.
Speaker 1: It's bigger.
Speaker 0: Take everything that Anime Boston has and make it bigger, except the panel of rooms.
Speaker 0: make them smaller.
Speaker 1: Right, but there's more of them.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: This has been Geek Nights with Rem and Scott.
Speaker 0: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com, where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 0: We say feeds plural because Geek Nights airs four nights a week, covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 0: Mondays are science and technology, Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs, Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 1: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com, or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Speaker 1: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Speaker 0: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 0: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution, non-commercial, share-alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 1: This means you can do whatever you want with it, as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Speaker 1: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.