Speaker 1: Hey, it's Monday April 6th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We have a bunch of different topics in tech.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So this morning I went to a place.
Speaker 1: I very rarely enter these days.
Speaker 1: I uh, I went into the Dunkin Donuts outside of my work.
Speaker 0: Oh That one the place that's combined that right next to the TGI Fridays Yeah, the one that said.
Speaker 0: so that's like the tiniest and worst Dunkin Donuts the one that is also a KFC Space.
Speaker 1: I went in because you know, there's a big roll out of work.
Speaker 1: So a bunch of people were showing up early from the sales team and the customer support team and I'm the morning guy anyway.
Speaker 1: So I wasn't actually gonna show up early.
Speaker 1: I told all them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll be here early I'll help you out, but I'm always there that early they could they don't know.
Speaker 1: So I even said you know what and I'll bring in some doughnuts.
Speaker 1: So I went in and usually I stop it like Starbucks, but instead well Starbucks can't give you done.
Speaker 1: It's in quantity like So normally I go to Starbucks and get coffee But instead I went to Dunkin Donuts just to get like a bunch of Timbits, you know There's gonna be like a million people in that Dunkin Donuts.
Speaker 1: It's it's 7 in the morning.
Speaker 1: Well like 645 There's no one there.
Speaker 1: There was.
Speaker 1: there were like two people in front of me in line and one guy walked in after.
Speaker 1: so Normally when I stand in line at the Starbucks I mean What's the stereotype of a Starbucks coffee buyer versus like a Dunkin Donuts or McDonald's coffee buyer?
Speaker 1: The Starbucks guys the one who walks in they're like, yeah I want a double soy light latte with that extra this and not enough this and all this sort.
Speaker 1: They have these really weird donuts.
Speaker 0: you get coffee.
Speaker 1: It's actually the exact opposite.
Speaker 1: every time I go to Starbucks.
Speaker 1: It's just one after another.
Speaker 1: people walk up.
Speaker 1: They're like tall black coffee or latte.
Speaker 1: like they order very simple quick specific things.
Speaker 1: They're prepared immediately.
Speaker 1: They're not fussy if they get the wrong thing.
Speaker 1: They're usually like whatever and they just kind of deal with it.
Speaker 1: Meanwhile at the Dunkin Donuts press a where it's like an order of magnitude cheaper like the coffee cost nothing.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, every single person in that line was giving these outrageous orders like hey Could you only fill the cup three quarters the way full and then fill the rest with like half-and-half?
Speaker 1: But then at the top put a little bit of vanilla from that thing.
Speaker 1: you got over there and then stir it with one ice Cube.
Speaker 0: maybe they were like Starbucks II people but they were at the Dunkin Donuts.
Speaker 1: No, no because the the guy says, you know the usual.
Speaker 1: And the next guy left and the clerks talked to him.
Speaker 1: They go to that Dunkin Donuts every day.
Speaker 1: And as I stood there waiting for my donuts apparently Shoveling donuts from the donut dispenser into my bin took longer than getting like 10 people coffee.
Speaker 1: Every single person in this Dunkin Donuts ordered like this like everyone had this.
Speaker 1: I would use the word outrageous order Like the.
Speaker 1: the level of fussiness and the level of expectation for their 98 cent coffee There should really just be like.
Speaker 0: you should go in the restaurant and be like, you know We don't do anything.
Speaker 0: that isn't on the menu.
Speaker 0: So if you want coffee say coffee you have no, you know, you mean like.
Speaker 0: you can tell me, you know Dark or not so dark.
Speaker 0: You can tell me yes milk or no milk You can tell me right but you can't tell me how much you can't tell me.
Speaker 0: You know if you want it you do it yourself, you know, fuck we don't do that.
Speaker 1: What amazed me was that the stereotype was kind of reversed that the P the people getting the crappy coffee were the most Demanding and the people getting the more expensive coffee were generally less caring.
Speaker 0: It's all anecdotal anyway.
Speaker 0: Well, the problem is it is something that could be studied.
Speaker 1: It's a weird situation because it is the Dunkin Donuts on 42nd Street But at the same time there are eight Starbucks within a two-minute walk of that place.
Speaker 0: Yeah The thing is, you know, they could be people trying to save money but are also fussy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, but I I have this general feeling I'm going solely on nothing here.
Speaker 1: I'm pulling this out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: I feel like if you did study this the less on average the less people pay For things the more not necessarily expectations, but the more demands they may make.
Speaker 1: and I'll bet it's a cultural thing.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: You got a.
Speaker 1: I'm basing this entirely on my experiences at this Dunkin Donuts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this one is one morning.
Speaker 0: Why don't you go to Dunkin Donuts next to us?
Speaker 0: That's actually nice for a Dunkin Donuts.
Speaker 1: Actually, the same thing happens at that Dunkin Donuts if you ever go into it.
Speaker 0: I never went into it.
Speaker 0: Well often that much.
Speaker 1: I'll often stop there when I go for a run and grab like a doughnut just to get some sugar before I go.
Speaker 1: hmm Anyway, that was my morning.
Speaker 1: That's that's what I got.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's so exciting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's thrilling.
Speaker 0: Oh Hi, do you have any I guess technology news of some sort?
Speaker 1: Oh, I gotta go into news a bit.
Speaker 1: Well, I've realized more and more that in terms of commuting New Yorkers really have it better than everyone else.
Speaker 1: our our commuter Infrastructure is amazing compared to pretty much everywhere else in America, America.
Speaker 1: That's an important qualification.
Speaker 1: forget the rest of the world.
Speaker 1: We got nothing on that Of course, uh, I think we beat those Indian trains.
Speaker 1: No, yeah What was that video where the people are jumping onto the moving train just to get a seat?
Speaker 1: Yep But I didn't realize, you know, I've never been to Boston.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go to Boston for the first time for anime Boston and then again for PAX East.
Speaker 0: But I've been to Boston so many times just not in a while.
Speaker 1: But yeah, well, I mean what I grew up in the Midwest.
Speaker 1: my vacations were like down to Florida or to see your point of Florida also or to Chicago, but I think we didn't go out east to those eastern places the good places.
Speaker 1: Is really that good in Boston.
Speaker 0: Boston's pretty nice.
Speaker 0: It's also.
Speaker 0: it's also real colonial except like you think it's colonial like around here.
Speaker 0: You go to Boston.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know, it's not so nice in Boston the MTBA.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna read an excerpt from the beginning of this article because it's kind of interesting and I Think this illustrates more than anything Why commuter rail or generally a lot of publicly funded things have issues quote?
Speaker 1: It's been documented before.
Speaker 1: the commuter rail service in Massachusetts is among the tardiest in the country with trains showing up late more than 20% of the time.
Speaker 1: hmm, but the official NT MTBA numbers tell only part of the sad commuting story.
Speaker 1: according to a globe analysis the rush-hour trains the ones most people take are actually late 6% more often.
Speaker 0: that are indicated by the official statistics Because the other the non rush-hour trains show up on time enough.
Speaker 0: well, so they only look at the total numbers.
Speaker 1: That's the thing.
Speaker 0: They should do it by person.
Speaker 0: People get on a late train.
Speaker 0: That's how you figure it out,
Speaker 1: but it turns out that they very pointedly and specifically aggregate the numbers from the entire day for their statistics and in fact They make a point of not tracking commuter versus non commuter so that no one can use those statistics to do anything.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm They obfuscate the data and I think what bothers me the most if there's a quote an official quote from the one of the guys like the head of all this and the MTBA and he says From a service perspective.
Speaker 1: I don't want to be saying that one train is more important than another Which either Belies his intelligence or
Speaker 0: I think that yeah
Speaker 1: or or more more likely It proves that he realizes that numbers would make him and his department look bad and thus covers them up The most expedient way possible.
Speaker 0: Well, what they should do is really I mean Metro North does the same thing, right?
Speaker 0: They just give you the total lateness numbers They don't give you the you know times really do the same time.
Speaker 1: But one thing I can point.
Speaker 0: I think they might actually split peak and off peak I don't.
Speaker 1: one thing I can point out about Metro North is that in all my years of commuting on it It's mostly on time.
Speaker 1: The rush hour trains are pretty much never late.
Speaker 1: And if anything is late, it's the off-peak trains No one cares about.
Speaker 0: yeah What they should do is they shouldn't say how many trains are late.
Speaker 0: they should say how many passengers Arrived at their destination late.
Speaker 0: Well, that's what they should calculate is what percentage of passengers or when you know what they could do.
Speaker 0: Here's the most accurate number.
Speaker 0: you could use Total passenger late minutes.
Speaker 0: So if I miss if I'm late for my stop for five minutes and there are a hundred people on that train that adds 500 late minutes.
Speaker 0: you see and that's how they should figure it out.
Speaker 0: Just total late minutes.
Speaker 1: But no, here's the more important point.
Speaker 1: Think about this.
Speaker 1: How come the trains that are used the most are so much more late.
Speaker 1: There's clearly yeah, either These schedules are bad and because the train has to stop at the station longer.
Speaker 1: No, that's not the problem.
Speaker 1: That's that doesn't even factor into this.
Speaker 1: if the rush hour trains are consistently that late What jackass is making?
Speaker 1: the schedules say that they'll make it at these times that they clearly can't make?
Speaker 0: that's also true.
Speaker 1: That is the fundamental problem that they're holding themselves to a standard that they clearly can't make and then they're making that standard by lying Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Now the other thing is they really it's.
Speaker 1: it seems like they haven't actually investigated what the specific causes are because it it does break down pretty simply either.
Speaker 1: it's People getting out and getting off because you see this Metro North trains.
Speaker 1: it takes like five sometimes six or seven minutes for the beacon train to fill out just because Everyone's stupid and they all get into the front car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it takes them all this time.
Speaker 0: just get off the train you're just sitting there and well people get off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but also maybe there's something to do with you know cascade effects.
Speaker 1: one train is late And then all the other trains don't have any leeway that there could be a million things.
Speaker 1: But it seems like very trivially if they just track to this data instead of trying to lie about it or cover it up.
Speaker 0: But that require doing actual work.
Speaker 1: but they're already tracking the trains but then they aggregate the data and get rid of the Specific data, all they would have to do is add that data is like, you know, not even like correctly.
Speaker 1: What's even worse?
Speaker 1: apparently their policy the way it works internally is that they find the train operator if his train is late and it wasn't due to something he had control or it was due to something he had control over.
Speaker 1: but When would a train operator ever make a train late?
Speaker 1: on purpose or within their control?
Speaker 0: I guess you could mess up right like you could you know mess up going through the signals or you know Something sudden along those lines, you know, you could.
Speaker 0: you know, not you could like, you know not mess up something I don't know.
Speaker 0: It
Speaker 1: seems like that is not the best way to go about fixing this Because one that only encourages people to lie or cover up when they've made a mistake or say if they're late due to an error Maybe they'll speed to catch up and turn off the safeties because they don't want to get.
Speaker 1: fine.
Speaker 0: It's also that's a tear.
Speaker 1: I mean there was even a TED talk about that.
Speaker 1: That's the exact wrong way to incentivize people to do their job better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right but it's such a simple solution, but I don't think there's any way to force a Proper because anyone who's smart enough to manage the trains right is this remember?
Speaker 0: This is like a government job.
Speaker 0: This is like a job that's all union e and seniority, right and not meritocracy.
Speaker 0: Someone who's smart enough to manage the trains is never gonna have that job and that job will never pay enough or be pleasant enough For someone who is that smart to ever want that job.
Speaker 0: So there you go.
Speaker 1: The best part is.
Speaker 1: apparently they just had a big rate hike and a lot of that money went into Putting in new turnstiles and stuff that don't work as opposed to fixing the trains.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, at least the MTA.
Speaker 1: every time they get a bunch of money suddenly everything gets a lot nicer.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, there's a problem with doing a meritocracy as your government.
Speaker 0: We haven't figured that one out yet, but there is no problem doing a meritocracy And a place of employment because we have very real rubrics and metrics for measuring someone's job performance and a lot of these.
Speaker 1: Interestingly enough because I'm Randomly, I've been reading a lot about the napoleonic error again.
Speaker 1: I got all these books from when I was gonna run this burning wheel game that I never got around to.
Speaker 1: it's so far Down in the hopper.
Speaker 0: She's talking so much.
Speaker 1: It's in the hopper.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh Yeah, it's a deep hopper.
Speaker 1: My hopper is deeper than you can possibly imagine, but I was reading this stuff again and I Lot of historians have made the very interesting point that two Surprising meritocracies that did exist and did work functionally and properly to a large degree where the British Navy during that whole era and the military of France during the early part of the napoleonic era Mm-hmm, and there was a. there's a whole chapter in one of these books on why these like why these were meritocracies And why they worked and then at the same time why eventually they broke down and we're no longer meritocracies.
Speaker 1: But I feel like we can apply a lot of those policies to things we have now.
Speaker 0: Well, we got to watch out for that why they broke down part.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yes Yes, we also have to watch out for captain laudanum who invariably makes his way in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a problem.
Speaker 0: Well, I think most remember those are both militaries which has sort of like the the sort of side Factor of people without merit.
Speaker 0: just there's lots of death.
Speaker 0: So you just lose lots of people that way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well like if you're a bad ship captain either you're gonna get course mark cart marshal and hung or hanged I guess is the technical term or your ship's gonna get stumped.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it says, you know, but that doesn't really happen so much.
Speaker 0: I mean unless you're a really really really really bad train operator Your trains not gonna crash like the guy who crashed the train because he was busy playing with teenagers and text messaging everyone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's that's super rare.
Speaker 1: So here's where this gets really interesting our Chan Fung and I think that's one of the coolest names.
Speaker 1: I've ever seen a Quote.
Speaker 1: political scientist who is part of Harvard's transparency policy project Argues that the T and other public organizations should make all of their data available to the public over the internet in raw form Of course, so customers can quote him.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess I'm quoting again.
Speaker 1: There's a meta quote here.
Speaker 1: mash it up.
Speaker 1: He thinks that in general if you just take like if instead of aggregating the data and publishing this specific data that you know Like these are our times or whatever What if they just made an API and just put out
Speaker 0: all they're not smart enough to fix a train schedule.
Speaker 0: You think they're smart enough to make like a cool web API.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing.
Speaker 1: even know what that is.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: if they said sure That Harvard could put together a team of IT people and CS people to make it So in like a couple weeks, yeah, they could do it.
Speaker 0: But the thing is they'd need to basically get full access.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, they wouldn't be able to be.
Speaker 0: it'd be that situation where you're sitting there Just waiting for the stupid person to give you what you're asking for and then they give it to you and it's not what you Asked for.
Speaker 0: yeah, but and you're sitting there waiting for this email and you're not doing anything.
Speaker 1: I think it could be done pretty readily if only Politicians could force the MTBA to open up their data.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it would take a law and be and they had a bunch of grad students.
Speaker 0: It would take a lie.
Speaker 0: There's so much stupidity in the way.
Speaker 1: All it would take is one law and like ten grad student.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it's a lot.
Speaker 0: You know a law is a lot to ask.
Speaker 0: I know I know I know and then you actually think that people are gonna execute the law like properly.
Speaker 1: But I do like the idea, you know politics aside that any public organization unless the data they have is Politically like is sensitive in a way that could cause direct harm to people should just be completely open to.
Speaker 1: Even if they can't make a web API I Should be able to mail them and pay some nominal pittance and just get it all in text format on like a CD.
Speaker 0: That's what the FOI is supposed to be for except half the time.
Speaker 1: It's all secret.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah It's you know, and they're trying to work on it.
Speaker 0: I think but that it's really the results so far have been unimpressive.
Speaker 1: Of course the thing is scarily, you know, who's some of the biggest pushers of the FOI?
Speaker 1: a stuff are UFO people of course and then they always claim it's not working because the government's like fine.
Speaker 1: Here's the data.
Speaker 0: We didn't find any stupid UFO like, you know, FYA when I was in high school or whatever to get whatever.
Speaker 0: they sent me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I read it all and it was basically a whole bunch of nothing and there was some stuff blacked out But it was barely anything.
Speaker 0: and like, okay There was some stuff blacked out.
Speaker 0: right if I if I anything that could possibly have fit where those words were Would not have met their aliens actually remember that there was nothing you could have written That would have made sense in those black spaces.
Speaker 0: that would have you know blown the lid off the roof.
Speaker 0: It was probably most of the stuff was probably like people's names.
Speaker 1: Remember way back.
Speaker 1: not not the thing where you could just turn off the redactions in Adobe documents But that guy who made the statistical analysis program where you could figure out with a reasonable degree of certainty What was redacted just by the context of the sentences?
Speaker 0: Yep And also, you know the stuff where it was printed but then gone over with a marker.
Speaker 0: They would use a scanner to see it again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty trivial.
Speaker 1: Actually we could do that at home.
Speaker 0: Yep, you can actually do it just like a shiny light and your eyeballs sometimes anyway.
Speaker 1: I think I think this is an interesting article because it raises a lot of issues that are interesting And it proposes all the solutions we need.
Speaker 1: but it's one of those things where we know the problem We know the solution we have the means to put forth the solution, but it will never happen.
Speaker 1: And I I don't know what to do about the same problem as everything else.
Speaker 1: But but again, I don't know what to do about it.
Speaker 0: You got to kill all the stupid people You could do.
Speaker 1: I don't think that's a solution either.
Speaker 0: Well, you know get rid not killed literally, you know, just get you know It's it's the battle against stupidity.
Speaker 0: It is never-ending and give up.
Speaker 0: So this is a this is sort of a sad story, but it sort of got my mind on a tangent, right?
Speaker 0: You know when you install adblock plus it asks you to choose to subscribe to a filter Yeah, and there's different filters for different countries, you know and such and you always pick the the easy list, right?
Speaker 0: Cuz it's the u.s.
Speaker 0: One right.
Speaker 1: Yes, yeah, yeah, I do.
Speaker 0: I have to keep backing you yeah, so the the guy who maintained the easy list He died.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, well, so, you know, that's that's sad that this guy died.
Speaker 0: and You know some people were saying oh no is the easy list still gonna be around.
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah It's gonna be fine.
Speaker 0: Don't don't worry You know worry more about the guy dying than worrying about the ad block continuing to work, right?
Speaker 1: That's all people worry about.
Speaker 1: right riser.
Speaker 1: What did anyone talk about on slashdot?
Speaker 1: So what's happening to the file system, right?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So the thing is that that I thought was interesting as I started thinking Hey, you know even adblock plus the greatest ad block system in the world, right?
Speaker 0: Basically has a human maintainer.
Speaker 0: There's a guy who goes out there and finds ads and then comes up with the regular expressions that block them.
Speaker 0: It's it's not automatic, you know.
Speaker 0: Look like blocking ads like a DVR here.
Speaker 0: I mean sure sometimes It can sort of like oh, aha.
Speaker 0: There was a fade-out and a fade-in.
Speaker 0: I'll skip that but sometimes there's a show with a fade-out or in a faded or a movie or something in it.
Speaker 0: You know, it's an or it's not precise and you need a person to actually fast forward and you know Or cut the ad out in some video editor to put it on bit toward her.
Speaker 1: Well South Park did it pretty well where they did by accident.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we forgot to put the ads into that episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was pretty good.
Speaker 1: so literally we're watching South Park commercial break comes and there's just a minute and 30 seconds of a blank screen.
Speaker 1: Yep, it was actually kind of pleasant.
Speaker 1: It was a nice intermission.
Speaker 0: I kind of like that.
Speaker 0: tell you they gotta bring intermission back to the movie theaters.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I just you know, it got me started thinking about like how all these adblock systems are still human systems.
Speaker 0: It's and there is no automatic ad blocking really so much.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it's always people, you know deciding what are ads and what are not ads.
Speaker 0: and this really, you know.
Speaker 0: And it's it's sort of a subjective thing there and it's also sort of there's no no There's no way it could possibly be done, you know Like what could you possibly do to have a computer at the same time?
Speaker 1: This is almost the same issue as the MBTA thing where by we have we have People's brains who are very smart and able to do crazy things.
Speaker 1: Computers are nowhere near and won't be for a long time.
Speaker 1: crowdsourcing can solve amazing problems in amazing amounts of time But at the same time very few people who like the people who need this the most don't leverage it.
Speaker 1: so we only get it for things like ad blocking and things where geeks are the ones who care about the problem and Geeks are the ones who can implement the solution.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: We never get it for anything else.
Speaker 0: That's why we're just.
Speaker 0: that's why it's gotten to the point where the geek world is just another world from you know because all the things that geeks care about and geeks have control over are basically in the future and everything else is Really no different than it used to be.
Speaker 0: because you know, there hasn't been you know, any sort of geek action there.
Speaker 1: I mean look normal people Hulu is like this cool thing that they use on their computer to watch some TV with ads But they still watch cable geeks computer hooked up to the TV and a hacked boxy.
Speaker 1: Yep They don't like they don't even think about it.
Speaker 1: Nope, but yet normal people have no access to that.
Speaker 1: Nope So what do we do about this?
Speaker 1: Do we just continue to break away further and further from the society around us?
Speaker 0: Oh, what are you gonna go and give up?
Speaker 0: Why are you geekiness and live slowly?
Speaker 1: I can be like that Neo primitivist that Emily knew in college.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're gonna be like that the guy who get.
Speaker 1: he got rid of all his furniture in his dorm room Clothes and he kept his Mac book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz he had to blog about his a neo-primitivist lifestyle.
Speaker 0: I know right?
Speaker 1: I Don't know.
Speaker 1: Well, I wonder if maybe I feel like some speculation is due as to what?
Speaker 1: Problems this schism is going to cause ten years from now Ten years from now.
Speaker 0: I mean the same problems you have now only worse.
Speaker 0: cuz what's gonna happen is, you know You're already seeing it now.
Speaker 0: It's the situation of oh, no, the newspapers are going to add business.
Speaker 0: What's the normal person gonna do who doesn't know how to use a computer and it's like, you know, you had your transition period.
Speaker 0: It's been over a decade since the Internet's.
Speaker 0: you've had a long time to get you know to move ahead.
Speaker 0: If you still haven't moved ahead, there's not a newspaper anymore.
Speaker 0: You have no choice.
Speaker 0: if you don't like ebooks, you know or computer.
Speaker 1: I think it's going to be reading on a screen.
Speaker 1: I think it's going to be far more sinister than that because as long as there are people who can't use these technologies There will be a market in catering to them.
Speaker 1: But at the same time these are the people who will just buy.
Speaker 1: the nature of the media They consume and the way they consume it will have the least control over what they get.
Speaker 1: so they'll be more and more Scarily controlled by the very people who use the technology to give them their information in their old methods.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but their numbers will be so small that they won't be able to do anything.
Speaker 0: It'll just be a very, you know, they'll be the crazies.
Speaker 1: Will they really though?
Speaker 1: How small will they be?
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't know big at first and then decreasing over time at the same time.
Speaker 0: I don't know if the person also mostly be old people who go away.
Speaker 0: You know the first ones to go.
Speaker 1: for every 4chan kid.
Speaker 1: There are still 10 kids who don't really use the internet and still read newspapers either.
Speaker 1: They don't read.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but kids don't read.
Speaker 0: we don't wear.
Speaker 0: the old people don't worry about they read.
Speaker 1: now I'm not I'm more worried about the kids.
Speaker 0: Well that kids not reading is a different problem than old people reading paper But I think it's getting.
Speaker 1: it's getting to the point more and more where I have very little ways to Communicate with the people around me like in my neighborhood.
Speaker 1: I would have almost no way to communicate with anyone in my neighborhood Like I if I found their first and last name, I'd have to go find a phone book, I guess.
Speaker 0: Yeah He's Google phone book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that doesn't always work so well.
Speaker 0: Maybe I could just shout into the street going to someone's door and knocking on it.
Speaker 0: It's like the olden days.
Speaker 0: he could do that nowadays.
Speaker 0: He can't do that so much.
Speaker 1: I guess you could but I have not knocked on a stranger's door in almost a decade.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean, you know, nope, nope one not that long ago.
Speaker 1: I knocked on the wrong door.
Speaker 0: People will think you're a Jehovah's Witness or something You know, you're only knock at a door if you have actual business, you know I'm a UPS guy or I'm I'm coming to fix your water heater or I'm your friend or you know You know a stranger knocking on the door to talk about something that a is not a business Transaction and B is not a sales pitch from a religious person.
Speaker 1: that Knocking on my door is the equivalent of pinging my secure ports.
Speaker 1: It's like what are you doing?
Speaker 1: Why are you trying that that ports not for you?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's so.
Speaker 1: it's like There's an API right?
Speaker 1: There's that mailbox.
Speaker 0: I mean, maybe we could you know, I mean there's nothing wrong with it.
Speaker 0: But it just you know, it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not what it used to be This old gray mare.
Speaker 1: It's a you know, like remember that Hitchcock We were watching where those two guys just walk into the guy's house and hang out in his living room waiting for him to come Home.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that used to be totally cool.
Speaker 0: I'd like to live in a place where that was totally cool But that's not the way it is.
Speaker 0: But
Speaker 1: I think the schism like even at my work like I work in an incredibly high-powered IT and CS environment Like I really honestly think I work in one of the most technologically proficient companies in America like I Don't want to brag but the like people are smart to the point that I often feel very dumb and very inadequate at the place I work.
Speaker 1: and for someone with my ego, I think that says something.
Speaker 1: and yet at the same time There was a conversation today at one of our big meetings.
Speaker 1: I am the only person Possibly in the company who uses Twitter at all and I barely use it because I'm a curmudgeon.
Speaker 1: Think about that.
Speaker 0: So you're not working at a very high-powered Technologically advanced place.
Speaker 1: I think I am though.
Speaker 0: No, but no one uses Twitter.
Speaker 0: Compare yourself to the company where everyone uses Twitter already that you go you got but at the same time What are they doing?
Speaker 1: What kind of big iron do they have running?
Speaker 0: There are places that you all use Twitter and have big iron.
Speaker 0: dig digs got big iron.
Speaker 1: Do you even know what big iron means?
Speaker 1: Yeah But anyway, I got.
Speaker 1: I got a good thing of the day here.
Speaker 1: I found this out of nowhere Like it was oh shit.
Speaker 0: I forgot my thing today.
Speaker 0: What was that?
Speaker 1: But I'll talk about mine and maybe you'll remember yours, but Out of the blue we were talking about peeing because I think I had a. I had a particularly long Pee session the other day to the point that it woke Scott up in his room.
Speaker 1: So, you know, he comes to me the next day.
Speaker 1: He's like rim.
Speaker 1: That was quite a pee ahead this morning.
Speaker 1: You shouldn't pee that loud and then my response as I often do I kind of respond in the real world The way I would respond to someone if I were on FARC.
Speaker 1: Is that just went to my computer went on YouTube and search for that scene?
Speaker 1: From a league of their own where Tom Hanks just pees forever.
Speaker 1: And I found it.
Speaker 1: but then there are all these other scenes and I realized that this video was a collection of All the times.
Speaker 1: Tom Hanks has had an extended peeing scene in a movie and you know what?
Speaker 1: there are a lot of them like a Surprising number.
Speaker 1: Tom Hanks is now typecast as the guy what pees on screen for longer than is comfortable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean a league of their own.
Speaker 1: the Green Mile Apollo 13 the castaway movie.
Speaker 1: There were like four more.
Speaker 1: it was crazy.
Speaker 0: He does a lot of peeing.
Speaker 0: I mean if I me if I'm making a movie which I'm probably never gonna do really but And I need someone to pee.
Speaker 0: I know who to call.
Speaker 1: I Think a league of their own has the longest one.
Speaker 0: But yeah, so I forgot my thing of the day But I remembered an alternative thing of the day.
Speaker 0: So I don't have to get up and pause the show.
Speaker 0: All right, so You know that there's a webcomic that's pretty old and actually hasn't been updated in a long time called Shabbat six thousand.
Speaker 1: Oh, I love Shabbat Shabot dot com.
Speaker 0: six thousand dot com.
Speaker 1: get a link to that flash of the one.
Speaker 1: I forget what holiday it is.
Speaker 0: Well, he's got a few flashes.
Speaker 0: But anyway Basically, it's a funny comic where you have a robot living with a rabbi and the robot learns about Jewishness And he's always being like, you know misbehaving You know, at least Jewish misbehaving, you know, it's like, you know on Yom Kippur, you know to help me get through the fast.
Speaker 0: You know, sometimes I eat a little.
Speaker 0: So That guy apparently a year ago made this video 20 things to do with matzah and that thing sort of became popular on the Internet's this year.
Speaker 0: Took a year, you know that to the next Passover.
Speaker 0: so it's a fun video of this guy and a girl singing a song about 20 things to do with matzah.
Speaker 0: and Passover is a Wednesday, so it's relevant.
Speaker 0: There's another flash video where It's a. it's a the rabbi the robot and 50 cent are Rapping about the ten players.
Speaker 0: That's a good one, too.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So, uh, what were we doing?
Speaker 1: this show on?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: a whole bunch of stuff got it all written down.
Speaker 0: some of it I mean basically what happened was is people started giving us ideas for the show
Speaker 1: and
Speaker 0: all of the ideas either a required preparation right and the problem with a preparation show is not that we have to do preparation because we have time to do some preparation.
Speaker 0: Reparation is that if we do a show about something we don't know about like and have an actual experience with then our preparation Consists of internet research and the show becomes read Wikipedia Or effectively read Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: in which case what's the point of us doing a show right?
Speaker 0: We're gonna do a show?
Speaker 0: It's either it's because we have personal experience with something and we can provide Knowledge or insight that is not available on the Internet's already with your Google searches, right?
Speaker 0: So the other problem is sometimes we get a show topic But the show topic is so minimal that it would only be like five minutes of talking.
Speaker 0: and that's it You know, oh we talked about it and well, we're done.
Speaker 0: There's nothing else to say about that topic so that we can't really use that for a show because we need like 20 minutes At least of talking.
Speaker 0: so we decided hey, what if we combine a bunch of those five-minute shows into a 20-minute show and?
Speaker 0: That might work.
Speaker 0: So it's not a tech news roundup.
Speaker 0: It's like a tech show roundup.
Speaker 1: I'll kick it right off with a short one because I think I mentioned this a little bit earlier but we had our live stream and it went really well.
Speaker 1: the audio for that will be up this Thursday because we're gonna try to Do a full week of shows this week.
Speaker 1: try because you know Scott's going out of town Wednesday stuff.
Speaker 1: But I'll probably put about Olivia a bunch of extra stuff up in the feed this week.
Speaker 1: But you know we recorded this and we did it on you stream and things were going fine.
Speaker 1: And then a little way through suddenly the shit cockery began Suddenly and like a lot more than I would have expected.
Speaker 0: Well, I think what it really started happening I mean you know there were some people who were sort of you know gig nights fans or a little bit shit cocky You know, but they were you know sort of relevantly shit cocky.
Speaker 1: But then we got featured on the front page.
Speaker 0: yes if you get enough people in your channel You'll get to the front page of you stream And then random people who just come to you stream TV will click on you or just get thrown into your channel You know.
Speaker 0: so you get those people and those people the shit cockers.
Speaker 1: now I have to preface this because I mean we're both technological people Scott and I are both aware fully of the nature of the legion of like the hordes of the Internet.
Speaker 0: The John Gabriel's internet fuckwad theory is not news to us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we have been playing the.
Speaker 0: you know the FPS is on the Internet's.
Speaker 1: for since you know last century millennium I mean I remember when I would play quake one I would log on to a server and I would be killed by a man named fuck Jesus who is saying your mother Repeatedly in the chat faster than he was shooting me.
Speaker 0: And then would you know after he killed everyone on the map would go to your corpse and crouch many times Man good times and anyway draw a giant penis and that you know.
Speaker 0: who knows what else would happen.
Speaker 1: or like you know look I'd
Speaker 0: go into an AOL chat room and someone would put in an ASCII art of like naked something and Like fuck fuck motherfuck
Speaker 1: I mean or the idea that It's kind of like in a city if there's any space where you can write something on it and no one can stop you The word fuck appears yeah,
Speaker 0: and it's anonymous.
Speaker 0: Yes, I mean you know we know the theory anonymity plus.
Speaker 0: you know audience equals shit.
Speaker 0: cuck right yep.
Speaker 1: But our YouTube comments, they're just.
Speaker 1: they're a place people can scribble so they scribble horrifying things.
Speaker 1: And I knew this.
Speaker 1: I knew this on an intellectual level.
Speaker 1: I knew it on a practical level.
Speaker 1: I used filters like slashdot and Farken places to where I don't interact with these things.
Speaker 1: It's just noise.
Speaker 1: It's no more than static to me like I don't even recognize it.
Speaker 0: I mean sometimes you encounter it, but it doesn't.
Speaker 0: you know it doesn't get it through.
Speaker 0: cuz you know we know it's there We knows the problem, and we know how to deal with.
Speaker 0: we've dealt with it for a decade.
Speaker 1: I mean the internet is the Wild West and I carry a gun and I shoot anyone who looks at me cross-eyed.
Speaker 1: yep, but I Guess I didn't really know it.
Speaker 1: on a visceral level it's one of those things where you knew it, but at the same time you didn't really.
Speaker 0: because Suddenly like like imagine if you just said you lived in a coastal town And you had a bat.
Speaker 0: you weren't like New Orleans.
Speaker 0: you actually had a real levee that worked and you just after a century You forgot that there were floods and then the levee broke.
Speaker 1: the rapidity with which the Not just the rapidity the rapidity and the numerousness of the people who came into this chat room Spouting the most vile garbage imaginable at the drop of a hat to like.
Speaker 1: there is no Explanation other than the fact that they went to ustream continuously.
Speaker 1: there was a sea of people Constantly hitting the front page of ustream being immediately directed into whatever was featured there no matter what it was With just everything ready to go Like they were it it.
Speaker 1: it gets to the point where it's a matter of premeditation.
Speaker 1: It's not like someone just sees a message board and thinks hey, and they go in and type shit fuck fuck fuck fuck shit shit shit shit fuck.
Speaker 1: It was that these people are like going to these sites with the specific intent of doing this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know if it's intent right.
Speaker 0: I think what it is.
Speaker 0: this is a box to type in and they got to type in something right and Basically the third their minds are just so shit cock that that's just.
Speaker 0: that's just what just sort of comes out.
Speaker 0: It's a completely unthinking.
Speaker 0: It's completely, but think it's as reflexive as a drunken guy going.
Speaker 1: But think of this as a chat room.
Speaker 0: It's like I fuck fuck fuck get within negative.
Speaker 1: ten seconds of us being on the front page like 10/15 of these people just start appearing one by one spouting it off.
Speaker 1: That means that for no matter what as long as anything is on the front page of that There's a constant stream of people being directed into it saying these things.
Speaker 1: There's a constant stream of people constantly trying to get into places to shit cock.
Speaker 1: I I Wonder.
Speaker 1: I want to write like a treatise on this.
Speaker 1: I want to figure out really why we know what we don't really know why.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we don't know why in a psychology sense.
Speaker 0: There should be like an actual book about it.
Speaker 0: I mean we know we have so far.
Speaker 0: We have a webcomic that explains it really well.
Speaker 0: But we don't know the real brain working because I'll and societal workings that result in this and you'll admit to you feel that urge.
Speaker 1: Everyone feels it.
Speaker 1: every now and then that little that little tinge is kind of like you're walking down the street and you see like Someone drops their wallet and you think for a second I could just grab it and you don't you don't you like you don't even consider grabbing it, but part of your brain says you could and Sorry already started weighing the odds of getting away with it, but you don't do it.
Speaker 1: You're a good person You don't even think about it, but on the internet with things like this, you know I don't really think about taking the wallet as much as I think about like.
Speaker 0: should I ignore it or should I give it back?
Speaker 0: I don't even think.
Speaker 0: should I take it?
Speaker 0: It's should I ignore it or should I give it back?
Speaker 1: I don't think.
Speaker 1: should I take it?
Speaker 1: but there's definitely that that the part of the brain I think is always Calculating whether or not you can get away with things.
Speaker 1: but on the internet There's no moral ambiguity because you're not you're not.
Speaker 1: all you're doing is saying something You're not doing anything.
Speaker 1: and I'll admit when I was in that the anonymous your chat with a stranger and Scott was over my shoulder.
Speaker 1: We're in there and we're typing and I talked to the stranger.
Speaker 1: I type two lines and I immediately feel this slight urge to just type your mom.
Speaker 0: I don't have that.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, your mom is sort of just become a reflexive say So it wasn't it wasn't a shit cocking urge.
Speaker 0: I don't really have that.
Speaker 1: but is if your mom is still a lesser degree of Shit cocking.
Speaker 1: I don't know Talking to a stranger.
Speaker 1: Hi, how are you your mom?
Speaker 0: Well that you know the content of it, but with knowing that who we are It's not.
Speaker 0: maybe maybe we knew who those people were.
Speaker 0: Maybe they're shit cocking is actually the same way.
Speaker 0: Your mom is for us.
Speaker 1: Is it really though?
Speaker 1: Which would I?
Speaker 1: join a chat with you and type a racial slur hundreds of times per second until you banned me?
Speaker 0: No only to come in with a different name and type a different racial slur But I mean like, you know I used to hang out with some Jews back in the day and we'd be like what up my kikes Yo, and it would be.
Speaker 0: you know, it's a funny thing.
Speaker 0: But if you said that someone else it'd be like, oh shit You know, but like if I say it online I could go into a chat room and I'm like, you know A Jewish chat room like what up my kikes.
Speaker 0: it would be like shit cocking But if they would have known me and known our friends and had the context it wouldn't have been shit cocking.
Speaker 0: So there is I think I'm not gonna say that, you know, all shit cocking is just out of context.
Speaker 0: non shit cocking but what I will say is I think there is a portion of shit cocking of People who have things that they say in the context of their friends and closer social groups Set that are bringing those things, you know sort of out of bounds, you know They're taking their in jokes taking them out into the chat rooms of public world where they are Taken out of context and those viewed as shit cocking.
Speaker 0: and that is a portion of shit cocking perhaps a very small portion But it is but it is there.
Speaker 1: it does exist, but at least in those cases, it's still.
Speaker 1: there's an expectation of communication.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not a hundred racial slurs in a flood.
Speaker 0: It's like one-liner plus.
Speaker 1: even then there's an Expectation of a response.
Speaker 1: notice how.
Speaker 1: I think that the real line between shit cock and not not in shit cock Specifically is whether or not you actually expect a response.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz flamers expect a response Response, you know trolls expect a response.
Speaker 0: Shitcockers are just putting bad words in a flood and that's it.
Speaker 0: They don't expect a response.
Speaker 0: They're not gonna talk to you.
Speaker 0: They're just Spitting out lots of bad words.
Speaker 0: Maybe
Speaker 1: I wonder some
Speaker 0: of it is is definitely like, you know, the same way as like the little kid is not allowed to say bad Words, it's like oh my god, I can say bad words
Speaker 1: But there are so many of them and there are so many other places they could do this.
Speaker 1: the fact that they're doing it everywhere Simultaneously in real time 24/7 all the time.
Speaker 0: I don't know what they're doing.
Speaker 0: 24.
Speaker 1: I think that we have to try this.
Speaker 1: we have if we did a geek nights you stream or and got enough people in on Christmas no, is it the same person all day?
Speaker 0: I mean, it's a rotating.
Speaker 1: I'm saying that at any second there is like in any public space that is big enough to warrant notice.
Speaker 1: There are people trying to shit cock there.
Speaker 1: Mmm, kind of like how on the internet if you have a cable modem and no net someone is hitting all your ports all the time.
Speaker 1: Yep, except on the internet, you know, literally it's just people typing fuck at all your ports all the time, right?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So moving on.
Speaker 0: Oh, so let's you want to talk about.
Speaker 0: I had this problem today, right?
Speaker 0: What I wanted to do?
Speaker 0: As I'm on you stream, right and I'm sitting there and I want to teach some people some computer stuff, right?
Speaker 0: So what could I do?
Speaker 0: I could point my webcam at my screen.
Speaker 0: not good.
Speaker 0: I could get a big whiteboard but rim didn't order it yet, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah I got a big Amazon order in the queue.
Speaker 0: I could or I could go and find something that would basically take my screen and stream what's on my screen, right and their decks Huh?
Speaker 1: Webex does it really?
Speaker 0: Well, well, but see the thing is a commercial product though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a commercial product, right?
Speaker 0: There's something else webcam max also commercial product.
Speaker 0: There are a bunch of free ones.
Speaker 0: They all suck.
Speaker 0: There are some that do it like, you know a go-to meeting or something like or like a VNC kind of thing.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: the problem with those is that they're not.
Speaker 0: you know They're not like web-based video streams like YouTube like you stream.
Speaker 0: They're like, you know, you connect to my computer kind of.
Speaker 0: you know remote desktop things.
Speaker 0: It's completely different and Really there wasn't a solution there.
Speaker 0: just there just wasn't like everything out there like.
Speaker 0: there were some Some almost solutions, but everything was pooped.
Speaker 0: There was like no way to take what was on my screen Stream it over streaming video in a web page.
Speaker 0: I'll allow you stream with good enough resolution for people to see what was in my terminal Right and have it be really accessible to the viewer so that lots of people could watch but also have the communication Mechanisms integrate, you know the chat room and me talking to them and the whole right.
Speaker 0: It's like I could have done this separate from the you stream.
Speaker 0: But then people would I join the you stream and then also join that and also get a piece of software.
Speaker 0: It was like so much work, you know just to make this happen where it should have been really easy.
Speaker 0: And I think the best solution that I came up with was get a webcam Bust it open take out the camera Get some sort of device that has a VGA cable in one end and then connects to the camera spot on the webcam on the Other end.
Speaker 0: so it's basically VGA to USB.
Speaker 0: So if it coming out of your video card into a device into your USB hole and thus it your computer treats Um, you know You duplicate the monitors using clone and then your computer would think the second monitor was also a webcam and would thus be able To stream it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I couldn't find anything better than that.
Speaker 1: See now I feel like the the market here right now.
Speaker 1: in the short term if you stream just had an option to Share a desktop they do but it's it's you have to get the stupid program that caused money If you stream could just do it without doing that.
Speaker 0: Yeah The problem is on Windows right because the way Windows works the only that.
Speaker 1: what I was about to say is that if you just Share it as video that's still.
Speaker 1: that's a lot of bandwidth and it's gonna be really lossy and terrible compared to doing it.
Speaker 1: You know like with the MSTC exactly but MSTC is not set up by default - like you can't just use that through something like ustream Yep an x-forwarding.
Speaker 0: But yeah It's like.
Speaker 0: the way to do it right with the video part is you have to basically put a driver in Windows in between.
Speaker 0: You're like the mod is to be a webcam driver that picks up on.
Speaker 0: you know The video out and that's totally the wrong way to do it.
Speaker 0: But because of the architecture of Windows that's the way it has to be done.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was something called like webcam studio for Linux.
Speaker 0: I couldn't even get it to work on Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: It just didn't install and I didn't have time for that shit.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of solutions that required a lot of work and I wasn't about to deal with them.
Speaker 1: I had that problem just looking for a screen scraper for my own desktop just to make some a way back.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of solutions to record your desk.
Speaker 1: Oh there are but even then in Linux many of them either don't work or are really shitty.
Speaker 0: Well xvidcap is fine.
Speaker 0: It's okay, but just the thing is you have to do the encoding yourself.
Speaker 0: afterwards It makes a gigantic full res AVI.
Speaker 0: Yeah You know, but at least it doesn't destroy your performance like some of the other ones do that cuz they encode while they're going along.
Speaker 0: So it's like your performance goes to shit and you can't work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course, I got two cores.
Speaker 1: I could live with that.
Speaker 1: but now xvidcap worked pretty well, but it wasn't optimal.
Speaker 1: It was just the best one and it doesn't.
Speaker 0: dogs.
Speaker 0: vidcap also, right?
Speaker 0: It might record the your screen.
Speaker 0: It doesn't record the audio so you have to do.
Speaker 0: you have to dub it later Yeah, or I mean or you push record in audacity at the same time Yeah, but that's nice still gets out of sync.
Speaker 1: You're gonna have trouble.
Speaker 0: Yeah You need to.
Speaker 0: you need to record that Audio dub it in a program that also takes the video into account.
Speaker 0: so the dubbing is you know timed properly?
Speaker 1: Maybe our answer is just to have a big whiteboard and a camera.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I also think having a computer where the VGA cable goes into you know Like a capture card or something would also Be like the correct solution that would work properly, you know It's still it just it really sucks because you shouldn't need hardware to do it, but I think we do
Speaker 1: All right, you got more.
Speaker 1: I I only remember the one I brought up.
Speaker 0: so, okay Someone wanted us to do a show about regular expressions and I was sort of like, you know Why should we do a show on regular expressions?
Speaker 0: I mean first of all regular expressions are a very visual thing.
Speaker 0: if you're gonna teach them to someone you need like terminals and things, you know open and text editors that you can, you know, visually show what's all about and Also everything I've learned about regular expressions.
Speaker 0: I've learned from the internet.
Speaker 0: So this is also a web.
Speaker 0: There's one website.
Speaker 0: You'll know if you find it.
Speaker 0: It's very high up on Google if you do searches for regular expressions.
Speaker 0: It's sort of orange ish and Yep, I've used that because that website has really everything you need to know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because even you know, I use I use them on a daily basis constantly.
Speaker 1: But every now all the time I'll forget some obscure syntax or I'll try to think of a like.
Speaker 1: I do something But it's kind of it.
Speaker 0: I pretty much need them as the need like a reference all the time.
Speaker 0: Cuz I don't remember hardly any of the syntax.
Speaker 1: I remember all the more like.
Speaker 0: I'll come up with a regular expression, but I'll need.
Speaker 0: I'll hate it because it's not perfectly optimal.
Speaker 1: So I'll have to go search around like get it optimized or half the time I'll end up I'll use like a reg X. that gets the job half done and Then my output gets pipe set off something to get my real output or Grant pipe grant pipe grab when I could have done it with one red egg reg X.
Speaker 0: Yep, just cuz you're not that good with the right.
Speaker 0: You're not a reg X wizard You just sort of know enough to get them to go.
Speaker 0: few people are few people are indeed mostly pearl people.
Speaker 0: are reg X wizards.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I stare at command lines all day.
Speaker 1: All I do is parse logs and other logs and track stuff through logs and I use reg X is constantly like I don't know About 50 an hour.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'm trying to come up with a met.
Speaker 0: I mean Django is in.
Speaker 0: you know you're doing web stuff.
Speaker 0: URL is all about URLs.
Speaker 0: parsing URLs and Verifying form fields is all regular expressions.
Speaker 0: but
Speaker 1: for the layman if you're wondering what we're talking about if you a regular expression is a way to is a syntactical way to Parse text and generate an output that is transformed based on your rules so you can search through text Find what you're looking for in a very specific order.
Speaker 0: So so there's two parts.
Speaker 0: There's the matching right of text and there's also the parsing of text, right?
Speaker 0: So the matching goes something like this Let's say I have a regular expression that is like, you know You know, I I'm not gonna actually speak in the syntax of regular expressions cuz that won't.
Speaker 0: it'll just confuse the hell.
Speaker 1: It'll sound like DCS.
Speaker 0: But let's say let's say I'm looking for a phone number, right?
Speaker 0: I'm looking for a phone number.
Speaker 0: I want to know what the person typed in is a phone number.
Speaker 0: So we've I say three digits followed by a hyphen followed by three digits followed by a hyphen followed by four digits, right?
Speaker 0: So there's a language where I can type in.
Speaker 0: it would be something like, you know Backslash D curly brace 3 - backslash D curly brace 3 - backslash D curly brace 4 Right and what that would say is three digits followed by - Bob, right?
Speaker 0: So then I can tell the computer Here's my regular expression the shit with all the curly braces.
Speaker 0: Here's here's the part the thing the person typed in.
Speaker 0: Does it match?
Speaker 0: and if the person typed in a phone number meaning three digits followed by a hyphen and so on?
Speaker 0: It'll give me a yes thumbs up.
Speaker 0: And if what they typed in has like letters in it or has four digits followed by three digits followed by a slash It'll say thumbs down.
Speaker 0: So that's the first thing you can do with regular expressions.
Speaker 0: is you say does this match thus?
Speaker 0: You can take some unknown input that is text right or numbers and symbols and Determine if it matches this format that you're looking for.
Speaker 1: now to it.
Speaker 1: Just just to give you an idea of how powerful this is.
Speaker 1: just on this front part You could trivially write a rule that also, you know It could look for this three digits that may or may not be surrounded by parentheses followed by either a space or a hyphen or the parentheses from before and then four digits and Actually and then three more digits and then four digits with or without that whole first section so you could Find out like you could look for almost any format.
Speaker 1: Someone could type a phone number in.
Speaker 0: Yeah go online and look for something.
Speaker 0: go do searches for like Email address regular expressions and they'll people will have all these different crazy regular expressions that match like they match anything that could possibly be an email address and Don't match things that are not email addresses and it gets pretty crazy.
Speaker 0: But it's it's ridiculously powerful and it you know, it has lots and lots of applications.
Speaker 0: Like I said, let's say you're making a website and you have people typing things into the boxes on the website And you want to make sure that what they typed in is correct.
Speaker 0: You could use the regular expression.
Speaker 0: Let's say you've got a big file full of I don't know Like like data right and you want to look and it's just a text file.
Speaker 0: It's not in a nice spreadsheet or anything and you want to look for people who live in New York.
Speaker 0: So you can you know do a regular expression looking for and why capital with spaces around it?
Speaker 0: You know all sorts of you know different combinations of things that that will result in that being a you know And you could say give me any line in this file.
Speaker 0: This is what grep the program grep does.
Speaker 0: you'd be like give me any line in this file where you see the letters NY And it will only spit out those lines in the file and not spit out the other lines.
Speaker 1: Yep, and they're great for looking through log files, you know I want to see every message that were sent to or from this list of three clients.
Speaker 1: that involves a timeout on this thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've got this big old file full of all the logs everything that the web server has done for the past hour.
Speaker 0: Give me every line in this file that has the word error in it so I can just see the errors Or you can use them programmatically for things like log channels like say you write complex programs or demons.
Speaker 1: So say you have every log line start with an integer from 1 to 9 and then a space and then the line.
Speaker 1: so you could designate say that Channel 1 is major errors channel 2 is minor errors channel 4 is debug channel 9 is like infer events No one cares about and you can have a log Masker that uses regular expressions that will basically say if the log line I'm about to write is in channel 4, you know, it begins with an integer for then write it.
Speaker 1: Otherwise don't unless I change the log mask.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So there are lots and lots of ways to just use the matching Capabilities of regular expressions.
Speaker 0: We haven't even scratched the surface on that, right?
Speaker 0: I mean you use something like awk.
Speaker 0: you're going way you can.
Speaker 0: it's crazy powerful crazy powerful But you think that's powerful.
Speaker 0: regular expressions have one other function and that is the you know the parsing Functionality.
Speaker 0: so what you can do is you can say let's say I'm do I'll use the phone number again, right?
Speaker 0: So I'm doing the phone number and the phone number.
Speaker 0: has you know that area code at the beginning, right?
Speaker 0: So I can say match a phone number three digits followed by whatever followed by three digits followed by four right four digits.
Speaker 0: But I put some parentheses around those first three digits.
Speaker 0: Now I can say all right look at this whole big file Find anything that matches a phone number and then spit out just the just the area code part.
Speaker 0: Give me that area code part so you can extract parts of what you have matched, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I could match Email addresses and I can just pull out just the domain part, you know I could like just give me all the domains and I could see like how many Yahoo.com email addresses are in here how many gmail.com email addresses are in here?
Speaker 0: You know, I could go in and you could you know, so by pulling out different parts You can actually start to do some really crazy stuff.
Speaker 0: Like I have a script I wrote that will rename.
Speaker 0: You know, you download an anime fan sub right and the file name is this crazy fucked up thing, right?
Speaker 0: You've got and people do it all different ways You know and they've got.
Speaker 0: they put in like the name of the fan sub are in there.
Speaker 0: You got the episode number in there.
Speaker 0: You got the file extension in there, right?
Speaker 0: You got all this junk in there.
Speaker 0: So I'll wrote this program that basically it checks to see if you know This, you know file.
Speaker 0: it looks at all the file names in the folder and it says does this file name match?
Speaker 0: You know, is it a anime fan sub?
Speaker 0: All right, so it mostly looks for like an MKV or a VI file extension.
Speaker 0: Right, then it says if it is Extract out right the name of the show and extract out the episode number, right?
Speaker 0: Get rid of the rest of the shit and rename it to Name of show space - space episode number dot file extension.
Speaker 1: You could even really set it up to where.
Speaker 1: if you can't parse it properly Like you can set up the expression to where.
Speaker 1: if it doesn't fit any of your cases Flag it with like, you know four X's at the beginning and then I'll go through and sort those manual.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could you know and then I can you know.
Speaker 0: Once I see that that case didn't match I can then go back and modify my regular expression to match that case in the future.
Speaker 0: So, you know, it's the regular expressions are you know an evolving thing sometimes when you don't have, you know consistency.
Speaker 0: It's like when you have some consistently structured textual data.
Speaker 0: They're very useful because you can process large quantities very easily and very reliably.
Speaker 0: But when you have small amounts of inconsistent data or even large amounts of inconsistent data They're equally powerful because it's the only thing you can do to search inconsistent data is a regular expression.
Speaker 0: There's no way to search something that's all fucked up, you know with an with an actual search function because you know something that's more straightforward because you're not gonna find anything and That's that's what regular expressions are all about.
Speaker 0: And if you have to deal, you know with text or matching or searching or finding and replacing or Renaming or verifying or anything along those lines, you know in computers regular expressions is something you should learn And I think as you know, there really isn't going to be a replacement for them.
Speaker 0: They're pretty much it, you know, and they're gonna be it for quite a long time.
Speaker 0: I mean, we'll still be using regular expressions probably 10 if not 20 years from now that there's really nothing else we can do about it.
Speaker 1: We'll be using them until we have semantic computing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much so.
Speaker 0: It's worth your while to learn them and to learn how to use them and to learn to write simple scripty programs that utilize them.
Speaker 0: Because that you know.
Speaker 0: learn, you know, there are two the main things you have to learn, you know You can learn said which is like this straightforward regular expression tool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can learn auk which is a super powerful regular expression tool.
Speaker 1: You can and you can learn simple way to remember say grant is a stream editor.
Speaker 1: So you can basically take a file pipe it into said and then the output will be transformed by whatever expression you build.
Speaker 1: So you could say replace the letter a with the letter F on every file on my hard drive.
Speaker 0: yep, said can do that right.
Speaker 0: auk is basically.
Speaker 0: you put something into auk and you give auk a bunch of expressions and you say auk whenever you see this expression.
Speaker 0: do this So it can go through a file or whatever you give to it and whenever it sees a certain expression that it's looking for It does something right.
Speaker 0: so you that's in ridiculously powerful.
Speaker 0: Once you learn how to use it You can use grep which is pretty much search for something.
Speaker 0: So you got a folder full of files and you want to look, you know through those files.
Speaker 0: Let's say you're working on a program and there's a function called fubar and you don't know which file the fubar function is in.
Speaker 0: Well grep is the winner.
Speaker 0: and lastly, you know in your programming language of choice Python Ruby Perl bash Whatever you can learn how to use the regular expression tools Provided by that programming language to write full-on programs that can use regular expressions for searching replacing verifying matching whatever PHP whatever.
Speaker 0: it's all good.
Speaker 1: All right, we've actually gone on pretty well and maybe we can end there.
Speaker 0: You don't want to.
Speaker 0: you want to do another one or that's it.
Speaker 1: It's been a while.
Speaker 1: I think we can stop for now.
Speaker 1: I think I think it was a good proof of concept and it killed a Monday.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Yes This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Speaker 0: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.