Speaker 0: It's Thursday January 7th 2010.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott I'm rim, and this is geek night tonight our triumphant return of questioning and answering.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Holy crap we're back.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: We're not.
Speaker 1: no never mind, okay?
Speaker 1: It's been a while it.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: we did geek nights for so freaking long that it got to the point almost to where I Felt.
Speaker 1: I wasn't tired of doing the show But it was like a time to do the show.
Speaker 1: it was kind of this job I was doing especially back when it was still four nights a week every week.
Speaker 0: Well, I think another part of the thing is that you know we're not like a news show like say twit where they can just Look at the news every week and do a show.
Speaker 0: or you know we're not a show on one particular Topic where we can just you know look at the internet and get a feed of things come in.
Speaker 0: I guess the thing of the day.
Speaker 1: we can do that, but basically for our show we need to Build things up within ourselves in order to create shows and after you know since 2005 of doing this some 700 episodes including the the famous I feel like I'd run out of mana.
Speaker 1: So I don't we had to back up and let the mana recharge slowly like in those shitty old games.
Speaker 0: You know I'm playing one of those shitty games that torchlight game.
Speaker 0: right now It's basically Diablo click click click.
Speaker 1: You know I'll say this I almost bought it because it was so cheap.
Speaker 1: I was like I'd pay five bucks Like it is a stupid clicky game.
Speaker 0: right, but the price of five bucks the production value of this game Is obviously at least a $20 game, so it's pretty right, but the thing is it's you know to make the Diablo torchlight joke.
Speaker 0: Basically we did not bring enough mana potions, so we had to use the town portal.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well more.
Speaker 1: it was like Final Fantasy 1 when I was trying to save up money for a silver sword.
Speaker 1: So I wouldn't go to that in until I had like one guy left, and he was almost dead.
Speaker 0: yeah So long to walk back and out again And you'd waste money on the inn and it was so much more efficient to stay out in the field as long as possible.
Speaker 1: of Course one time I remember wasn't me was my little brother.
Speaker 1: He was doing something like that, and he stayed out too long.
Speaker 1: He got hit by some ghouls.
Speaker 1: They paralyzed his last guy, and he died.
Speaker 0: that's the one thing I hate is like you stay out there, but you're like.
Speaker 0: okay I could go back now But maybe I could stay out for one more.
Speaker 0: But on the way back after I fight one more will there be a random encounter before I actually get in the town?
Speaker 0: So you know what you do.
Speaker 0: you just walk around the town in a circle, so you're always one away from it.
Speaker 1: Yep, y'all back and forth the two squares in front of canaria.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Welcome to canaria.
Speaker 1: Wow, I've read that in a while.
Speaker 0: I've been reading it all the time.
Speaker 0: Snow cones, okay, I'm like a year behind on that, but I actually added some new web comics.
Speaker 1: We had the commute and we had all that stuff.
Speaker 1: so basically we're getting to the point to where we needed time off to set Our lives straight.
Speaker 1: and the lives are straight.
Speaker 1: the geek night studio is now in Long Island City right next to Manhattan.
Speaker 0: in fact We can see nothing else in this.
Speaker 0: behind this apartment is straight.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: I don't have any.
Speaker 1: you realize our apartment we have a bed and Boxes everywhere and the only room that is put together is the studio.
Speaker 0: my apartment is on that.
Speaker 1: You've been living in yours longer.
Speaker 0: It didn't take me that long to get it all set up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well we got more stuff.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: plus I had to build the stupid studio, and now I got to build a new computer.
Speaker 0: I got rid of my stuff.
Speaker 1: But you know we always talk about the late show.
Speaker 1: you get like the background And it's always like some fake cityscape, or you get like a green screen.
Speaker 1: you show Manhattan.
Speaker 0: well Well, we're David Letterman who like records the show like 9 in the morning You know.
Speaker 0: so it's like and he's not even like high up, so he just puts like a fake cityscape behind.
Speaker 0: We are actually capable of Producing a nighttime show with a real cityscape out the window.
Speaker 1: in fact the only reason I can't see Manhattan right now is because I have the shades down.
Speaker 0: yep Well actually from your sitting position you wouldn't not be able to see Manhattan.
Speaker 1: I could were I to put a mirror up.
Speaker 0: you could see like Queens and maybe some Brooklyn.
Speaker 0: Yes, a mirror perhaps would allow you to see Manhattan's.
Speaker 1: well Yes, however one thing I'm gonna do get a new boom and I'm gonna face the other way the boom.
Speaker 1: I'm getting a boom.
Speaker 1: get the big bottle boom But I own a multi pass now in a New Yorker.
Speaker 0: No, it's more like a single pass you had.
Speaker 0: I had the multi pass before when it was Metro north and Metro still a multi pass.
Speaker 1: Metro north train not metronome.
Speaker 0: It doesn't let you get on train.
Speaker 1: Let's begin on subway trains and Buses.
Speaker 0: that's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's two things.
Speaker 0: Okay, multi sure You get on the path train or the air train.
Speaker 1: It's weird how much I was looking forward to you in the show to be honest like it When we first I was always like really excited about geek night because I had a lot to say.
Speaker 1: and as time went on It was I don't know.
Speaker 1: I wasn't as excited about the show as I am right now.
Speaker 0: Well, that's because basically you didn't have you know, it's like it's like a glass half empty half full situation, right?
Speaker 0: So basically our glass of stuff to do shows with our material was running low.
Speaker 0: So doing a show meant you had to like scrape the bottom of the barrel.
Speaker 0: But then we just didn't do shows and it rained and it poured.
Speaker 0: So now I like the cup overflow with.
Speaker 0: so you're like, yeah, we'll do a show.
Speaker 0: Look, I can just sort of hit this water fucking everywhere.
Speaker 0: It's easy.
Speaker 1: What really did it I think was.
Speaker 1: there were the pre geek nights days when Scott and I had that house and beacon.
Speaker 1: We both had jobs and nothing else to do at all.
Speaker 1: We would come home from work and like watch two movies play video games for like three hours Play a board game and then be bored for an hour.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we also filled up the cups mightily with the you know, five years of colleges Yep, so it was like six years of cup filling.
Speaker 0: So, you know, and then we were able to empty six years of Material in like four years of geek nights.
Speaker 0: So now we've had like a month or and change of filling.
Speaker 0: I think we'll be alright.
Speaker 1: But as Emily pointed out there were the pre geek nights days where we still had the big commutes.
Speaker 1: We didn't have anything else to do.
Speaker 1: then we had geek nights and the big commutes.
Speaker 1: now We have geek nights and no big commute.
Speaker 0: So we basically get those cup days and geek nights Sort of, you know We definitely are going to be able to this.
Speaker 1: last week the one day I came home and didn't like go shopping or like go To Home Depot or do house stuff.
Speaker 1: I came home and it's like I like seven hours before I have to go to bed.
Speaker 0: I watched all of master Keaton.
Speaker 0: I've watched all of.
Speaker 0: I've watched a lot more various anime series.
Speaker 1: I watched most of season 2 of Dexter and I read a lot of comic books.
Speaker 0: Oh, I need the photons.
Speaker 1: Give me I'm gonna watch it first.
Speaker 0: I need something.
Speaker 0: Just I might have to go back to Hokuto.
Speaker 0: no can if I don't get something.
Speaker 1: we got to review these shows that we're watching Before we forget.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically, I've been able to get a lot, you know, and because it can be saving so much time No commuting I'll be able to.
Speaker 0: the cup will not run out as quickly because I'll be able to Continuously fill it with things because I have basically two hours a day that I did not have before.
Speaker 1: Sadly, what am I watching primarily right now goes to Michelle standalone complex again?
Speaker 1: Are you telling me if it was not here right now you wouldn't just watch it instead of anything else?
Speaker 0: It also just so happens that you know, like we now we've also got like moving stories.
Speaker 0: We've got like holiday stories.
Speaker 0: We've got New York stories.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: We've got some.
Speaker 0: you know, there's a lot.
Speaker 0: CES is happening right as you record this.
Speaker 0: So there's a lot of technology gadget stories, you know There's all sorts of gaming stuff going on because it was the holiday season and I think the e3 is coming relatively soon.
Speaker 0: So babe is basically crazy.
Speaker 1: stuff has happened.
Speaker 1: I mean I joined the Otacon staff.
Speaker 1: So did Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm going to the Otacon general staff meeting like in a couple weeks.
Speaker 1: I'm not going.
Speaker 1: I gotta get a plane ticket.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of stuff happened.
Speaker 0: So we had a lot of things to make shows of.
Speaker 1: so expect craziness.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do a lot of changes to geek nights, too But I don't want to get into all that.
Speaker 1: I don't want to sit here and be like we're gonna add this and add this and take out this.
Speaker 1: just listen to the show.
Speaker 1: You'll see things changing for the next couple weeks.
Speaker 1: We might not still do the full day like our regular schedule.
Speaker 1: We might miss an episode do double episode as we kind of get back into the swing of things.
Speaker 1: We got a review giant robo before we forget about it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: This is another one I watched.
Speaker 0: look how much I'm able to do with without having to go on a train all day.
Speaker 0: so much.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow.
Speaker 1: I haven't heard that music in a while.
Speaker 0: You didn't hear that music?
Speaker 1: No, I didn't thanks to the magic of automatic editing and the Scott completely destroying the illusion.
Speaker 0: No one hears that music but you geek nights is all about destroying illusions.
Speaker 0: All right, that's that's.
Speaker 1: maybe that should be the theme of our TED talk our TEDx talk The theme of TEDx destroying illusions and ruining your childhood.
Speaker 1: Yeah But things of the day.
Speaker 1: and what could be more fitting because it is actually this weekend and I know you know Usually geek nights like maybe half of you guys listen the night it comes out and I see like this trail for two weeks The people downloading the episodes later.
Speaker 1: I know most of you are listening to this episode on Thursday night considering how much crap We've been getting about, you know, when are you gonna do a show?
Speaker 1: When's geek nights coming out games?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: They didn't say so much about guns But it is this Sunday so you have time to prepare.
Speaker 1: it is my second favorite holiday in the world.
Speaker 1: It is that improv everything group and they're doing no pants day.
Speaker 0: Do they realize like the NFL playoff starts and ride the subway with no pants?
Speaker 1: now There are some very important rules about this thing.
Speaker 0: one is you have to wear underwear But this is I don't know if your underwear accounts for him.
Speaker 0: It's basically a string.
Speaker 1: Well, see I have experience with this in my past.
Speaker 1: You know how you get away with wearing underwear in public.
Speaker 1: you wear whitey tighties or tighty whiteies Depending on where you're from on the bottom and then you are boxers over that thus preventing any chance of peekage or leakage.
Speaker 0: Leakage Because it rhymed Yeah, sure rim has no leakage, uh-huh Okay, but the the other rules are.
Speaker 1: you must be willing to take your pants off on public transit in public and to you Must be able to do this while maintaining a straight face.
Speaker 0: I can do that if it wasn't zero degrees out So fucking Oh God, it's so cold.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: woman woman woman I mean, it's not that woman today But there are so many days that have passed or we didn't do shows when we came where it was So woman we came back from freaking Albany.
Speaker 0: I thought I was in space.
Speaker 0: I thought I was in double space Emily and I came back.
Speaker 1: I know Judith and Natalie's car.
Speaker 1: So they drove us for our tower place.
Speaker 1: We had to park like three blocks up and you probably parked on that street that goes to the the bridge the Queensborough Bridge.
Speaker 1: There's like a wind tunnel there.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: not only was it like one degree but there was the solar anti woman wind coming at us the whole Woman, I was pro woman when it was anti man.
Speaker 0: as I boys wind If it froze the boys first the boys women off as space does.
Speaker 1: My love for you is deathless.
Speaker 0: Too bad for this omnipotent wind.
Speaker 1: But I am.
Speaker 1: if I go out on Sunday I will participate in this.
Speaker 1: I will take at least one picture of myself if you go out.
Speaker 0: No, I think the idea is that you're supposed to go get on the subway at two o'clock on purpose Depends on how cold it is.
Speaker 0: But the thing is what you can do is you can just get on the subway right and ride it like into Manhattan.
Speaker 0: Well, I might man time it such that like you're you're in Manhattan like downtown around two o'clock.
Speaker 1: Well one thing I might have to go up to Beacon to deal with my car in which case that's road north.
Speaker 0: I don't think you want to take your pants off on Metro north.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: It's a lot more strict.
Speaker 1: It's there's no law against it.
Speaker 0: No, I guess not.
Speaker 1: There's no rule against either The rule.
Speaker 0: there is a rule about going to jail for seven years if you fuck with the conductor.
Speaker 0: No, if you hit the conductor, yes, if you hit him with well, I guess that's true.
Speaker 1: I mean Do I do I hit him with my junk?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, that's the thing It's like, you know I just remembered that your penis is so small that you wouldn't have a problem accidentally hitting the conductor if you took your pants off.
Speaker 1: Well, see the problem with Metro north is that it really wouldn't fit in those seats.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'd have to at least get the three across but the trains so crowded.
Speaker 0: Well, I would just you know, basically stay in the four-seater, you know both directions at once.
Speaker 0: Maybe you have to open up the vestibule door the whole time, but it'd be alright.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the problem is the trains that go up to Beacon on the weekends don't have enough cars.
Speaker 1: I Just remember the one time I was on the train.
Speaker 1: I think I was going to the Bronx for some reason because I'm gonna back when I worked there and this old man is Complaining the conductor.
Speaker 1: He's like, I'm an old man.
Speaker 1: I don't have to pay the peak fare.
Speaker 1: blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: The connectors like peak train.
Speaker 1: Everyone's got to pay the peak fare.
Speaker 1: There's no way around either.
Speaker 1: get off the train I'm gonna throw you off.
Speaker 1: and the guy was like You try and throw me off this train and he raises his cane Like he's gonna hit the conductor and the conductor just looks at him says go for it.
Speaker 0: I Man, I wish there was some law that was like if you hit Scott you go to jail for seven years.
Speaker 0: cuz I would just Be like, come on hit me.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: There is a trap if you become a conductor.
Speaker 0: I know maybe I think is conductor.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: conductor make as much money as I do know.
Speaker 0: God no, and it doesn't look like that fun.
Speaker 1: But some of the people I found that one Jamaican guy has fun.
Speaker 1: that's true that's true Yeah But some of the people obviously do not enjoy their jobs.
Speaker 1: probably the guy taking the train like from Poughkeepsie to Manhattan at 11 at night on a Sunday.
Speaker 0: that somehow a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah pants.
Speaker 0: All right No pants, so I'm just gonna start off, you know, I'm gonna ease back into the things that I've got So many great ones piled up, but I did not prepare any of them for the show.
Speaker 0: So I'd have to go, you know, look at my my backlog.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna ease into the quality things of the day So as not to overload your senses with something too amazing after you know You being you know cold turkey on hilariousness for so long the secret.
Speaker 1: just go to College Humor 90%.
Speaker 0: I'm going to give you a College Humor video of the never-ending rooster.
Speaker 0: It is a rooster that crows for a very long time and that is it I could.
Speaker 1: I can imagine that the other roosters They're sitting there and they're like he starts to crow and they're like, who's this guy?
Speaker 0: I don't think there are any other roosters that he's pretty well.
Speaker 0: Obviously this rooster has eaten the rest of them You know and all the hands were just sort of like.
Speaker 1: Well, they're probably like shut up We know.
Speaker 1: So we figured we start this all off with questions because you guys love these question episodes and we wanted to try out Google moderator.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I got a few things to say here, right?
Speaker 0: So first of all, right people love the question show Even though I sort of don't think the question show is that great because it gets very meta.
Speaker 0: not so good for the new listener Alright.
Speaker 0: second of all, you know in the question shows of the past We have selected the questions on our own and the thing when we select the questions.
Speaker 0: It's a good thing because a if we don't have a lot of things to say For a question like we don't have a good answer we can just skip it.
Speaker 0: if the questions stupid We can just skip it without having to make fun of the person who asked it.
Speaker 0: If there's like one person asking a hundred questions, we can just answer one per person.
Speaker 1: So it's spread out evenly across many different questioners But at the same time it causes the kind of echo chamber where I pick all the questions that are like Why do you like Horatio Nelson so much rim, right?
Speaker 0: So the thing is this time we try to use Google moderator.
Speaker 0: Google moderator is a tool that allows basically it moms a tool, right?
Speaker 0: it's designed for like if you're going to have a conference or a speech or a lecture and People can ask questions beforehand or during the lecture if they have computers and internet connections or mobile phones or whatever and then Not only can they ask questions, but they can vote questions up or down.
Speaker 0: You know that other people have asked instead of being redundant right and thus the questions that most of the people want asked will be the ones that get answered as opposed to like You know the old lineup system where like whoever gets in line first is the person who asked their question.
Speaker 0: Even if they're a stupid question, everyone goes boo sit down sit down, right?
Speaker 1: I kind of like the idea.
Speaker 1: maybe at Connecticut I was thinking about this because we're gonna run like the one big panel room.
Speaker 1: we should set this up and have someone with a laptop who takes all the questions from people during the course of the lecture and Just types the good ones then just so we have a nice way to display them on the screen while we answer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you still need the voting of the.
Speaker 0: you know It only works if the people in the audience are in you know.
Speaker 1: Well, we could use it just as an easy way for the person in the audience to answer the questions regardless.
Speaker 0: as an experiment We use this tool as you know to control the questioning for this episode and we got a hundred people Asking a hundred and twenty four questions with six thousand one hundred and fifty six votes Which if you think about the math is actually there should be 12,400 votes if everyone of all hundred people voted on every question.
Speaker 0: So basically About either half the people voted on all the questions or all the people voted on half the questions or somewhere in between And we're just gonna answer them in order if they all happen to be from the same person or if they're stupid or Whatever.
Speaker 0: We're just going to have to deal with that as we go until we're done and that will be this episode.
Speaker 1: I do want to give some thanks to the form I formerly known as your Lord Yupa who doesn't want to use that name But I feel like I should use it anyway, because that's the way we roll.
Speaker 0: Isn't that the guy from?
Speaker 0: Nasca is Lord Yupa.
Speaker 1: I Don't remember.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yes Anyway, but he actually went and grabbed all the questions people had typed into other places in the past and got them in here.
Speaker 1: It's kind of a set of seed.
Speaker 0: So if there is a question from him and it's stupid It might not actually be his question, but he did a lot of help here.
Speaker 0: So I gotta give props to him and so I yeah, I have to warn you in advance.
Speaker 0: We haven't done this in question episodes of the past, but we may make fun of your question.
Speaker 1: Yes So start out right away because a lot we're gonna do it in order skipping nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah that and cuz everyone can see this page.
Speaker 0: So if we skip something or do anything everyone will know.
Speaker 1: so we cannot avoid Unless they continue to vote on them after we do the episode, I guess.
Speaker 0: but basically let's just go in order.
Speaker 1: All right, you want to start or shall I all right?
Speaker 0: We just have to read it.
Speaker 0: It says It's from Naito or at least that's.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna read the name that's there Even though that's not necessarily the person who actually asked and he says do you think that your life would have been?
Speaker 0: Significantly different if you hadn't met each other.
Speaker 0: I assume he means me meeting you and vice versa.
Speaker 1: Well, if I hadn't met Naito, I mean I wouldn't have decided.
Speaker 1: You know, it's weird because there's two aspects to that.
Speaker 1: There's the rim and Scott meeting and then there's the like the whole front row crew coming together.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that it's actually sort of a self-answering question.
Speaker 0: It's like would your life be different if your life was different?
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: yes, yes it would.
Speaker 0: but
Speaker 1: then again some things are subtly different like had I on the morning of January 8th 2001 had pineapple juice instead of mango juice Probably not gonna matter so much in any scope of my life no matter how far out into the future Mmm, or like going to RIT versus going to Arizona State would have been a huge difference.
Speaker 1: Going to RIT and joining the anime club and our wag Versus going to RIT and joining the anime club our wag and CS house.
Speaker 1: Maybe not as big of a difference.
Speaker 0: Yep So, I mean, yeah, I mean, you know, there were other big decisions and I think that you know who you meet and such is Largely more a consequence than a than a cause.
Speaker 1: but at the same time Even if myself and Scott had not met but the front row crew had formed either without me or without Scott I could see the crew being very similar because it seems like The thing that changed all of our lives was really just the formation of the front row crew.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean mean pretty much no matter what.
Speaker 0: if I had gone to any college, right?
Speaker 0: I mean it was.
Speaker 0: I was already gonna go to a nerdy place, you know I was gonna meet a bunch of nerds, you know worst-case scenario None of those nerds are like really strong enough friends to still be friends after college.
Speaker 0: So what would have happened?
Speaker 0: I would have moved somewhere like New York City Anyway to get a tech job or San Francisco or something and it would add some nerd friends there, you know.
Speaker 1: Yes, it's really.
Speaker 1: it's not a matter of friends.
Speaker 1: It's a matter of the front row crew.
Speaker 1: it was I think the moment when like all of us as a group our lives really changed and became like kind of the I Was about to say like the force of righteousness and justice.
Speaker 1: but that doesn't really.
Speaker 0: but I'm saying if you pick the point at which we met as sort of like a branching point in a in a you know, you know a Probability matrix tree, you know decision-making branching whatever if you pick that point is the point of diversion.
Speaker 0: The the resulting, you know, like pad life paths that were in front of me were not too dissimilar.
Speaker 0: You know short of you know me deciding to go and do something crazy Which is within me and has nothing to do with our meetings.
Speaker 1: Yeah I would disagree on one front that the crew like the front row crew really There was that moment like after the first year of college when everyone was like gonna go back home for the summer and do that stuff.
Speaker 1: We all kind of stood around together and it kind of clicked that the front row crew wasn't just like all the other people at RIT who had like their group of friends that was gonna break up after they all left college.
Speaker 1: the front row crew kind of became Family And I think that is influenced If not myself and Scott specifically then the crew as a whole has influenced the crew as a whole in a kind of self replicating manner.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean but that you know that happens if you have any people that you you know Stay close to for a long time.
Speaker 0: That's just.
Speaker 1: that's what it seems like.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 1: the rule out of college is that most people I've known don't seem to maintain a large group of their college friends.
Speaker 0: I think those are the people who have maintained their high school friends.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, like in community the guy with the the letter jacket.
Speaker 1: hmm anyway, so Where do you see the show and crew in the next five years taking into account the last five years from the head blood?
Speaker 0: That's a well.
Speaker 0: I think it's vampire hunter deep blood.
Speaker 1: I know but it's spelled for head blood.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: I think he's making a false assumption that the last five years Have an effect on the forward future five years in some.
Speaker 1: well They do in the sense that they're predictive.
Speaker 1: you can see you know what trends happen.
Speaker 1: I mean what happened the last five years.
Speaker 1: the crew that had formed that got really really close left our IT and went out into the real world and we spread out all over the place and then bit by bit we all Reconverged back on each other.
Speaker 1: everyone kind of moved far away and kind of said this sucks, and we all move back together.
Speaker 0: Let's see so five years.
Speaker 0: Let me 2015.
Speaker 0: I'll probably not moving for a while because I've got a. you know I paid a big fee to get the apartment.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna keep the lease for a bunch of years to get the most out.
Speaker 0: You know because the longer I stay the more I get my money's worth for that fee.
Speaker 1: Yep, unless they build another building directly in front of this building.
Speaker 1: I don't see myself moving.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my job seems to be you know pretty good It's.
Speaker 0: it's probably not gonna fall apart like previous job.
Speaker 1: job wise it is not out of the realm But I'll be a millionaire by the end of five years.
Speaker 1: It's not that out of the far out of the realm.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty much confident.
Speaker 1: They'll be able to retire by the time I'm 45.
Speaker 0: That's that.
Speaker 0: well 45 isn't unreasonable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's some decent Millionaire in five years, then you could retire when you're like 30 something.
Speaker 1: yeah, yeah, that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: It's about any.
Speaker 0: if I had any number of millions I would retire immediately.
Speaker 1: it is not out of the realm and it is surprisingly possible.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying it's that likely, but it is more possible than I would have expected five years ago.
Speaker 0: And I don't know what.
Speaker 1: well I mean let's we got to break it up the show and the crew.
Speaker 1: that's like asking about what?
Speaker 1: Your family gonna be like in five years, and what's your job gonna be like?
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: well You could all decide to send us a bunch of money So we can do this full-time if you really want to.
Speaker 0: you know it's up to you.
Speaker 1: well our maintenance costs increase Dramatically.
Speaker 1: this studio space per square foot is a lot more money than the studio space and beacon.
Speaker 0: that is true You know.
Speaker 0: I Don't know what else is gonna change.
Speaker 0: I mean I sort of you know.
Speaker 0: I really want to like you know start doing some more traveling action.
Speaker 0: So that will definitely occur.
Speaker 1: yep Well actually within five years I plan to take Three to six months off of work on sabbatical and go on a crazy journey.
Speaker 0: the convention schedule will probably sort of go into a summer Holding pattern you know doing less more powerful.
Speaker 1: We pretty much solidified.
Speaker 1: We're not adding any conventions except for possibly tech and gaming conventions that are really easy to do.
Speaker 0: I think the big the.
Speaker 0: I think the most difference That's gonna be in the next five years.
Speaker 0: is that because I'm not commuting There's gonna be a lot less shit talking and I'm gonna make a lot of things.
Speaker 0: and maybe there is a small Probability very small that one of those things could you know lead down an unexpected path?
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: But that's really.
Speaker 0: you know what else.
Speaker 0: what else is gonna happen?
Speaker 0: short of like I don't know a lottery win because I don't buy tickets.
Speaker 0: That could happen.
Speaker 1: well, I mean in terms of the crew you can find a lottery ticket on the ground.
Speaker 0: It's already a winner.
Speaker 1: in the last five years you know the crew kind of ballooned out and then came back together.
Speaker 1: and Just recently especially more and more the front row crew has been centering around, New York City.
Speaker 1: We've had a bunch of people like.
Speaker 1: we had friends in DC who moved up to Brooklyn.
Speaker 1: We had friends in the south who moved out to a lot white planes.
Speaker 1: Everyone's kind of converging.
Speaker 1: New York City is pretty much the center of the crew right now And then we have a couple people in Albany help people in Philly.
Speaker 1: But it's all like the radius is New York City and I foresee it getting closer and closer as opposed to further and further.
Speaker 0: hmm Okay, the next question.
Speaker 0: Is it weird not living together anymore?
Speaker 0: miss anything.
Speaker 1: I don't miss having a bathroom Entirely covered in pubic hair.
Speaker 0: I don't miss you know having all hair Absolutely everywhere.
Speaker 1: I don't miss pee on the floor.
Speaker 0: You're the one who peed on the floor.
Speaker 1: Whose apartment has pee on the floor I have?
Speaker 0: first of all my apartment does not have pee on the floor.
Speaker 1: I was like it does.
Speaker 0: and second of all I would like to point out right that my apartment had no pee on the floor And then you stayed over like two times.
Speaker 0: then there was pee on the floor and I cleaned it.
Speaker 1: I thought you just said there was no pee on the floor.
Speaker 0: I cleaned it and there has not been pee on the floor since you have been there.
Speaker 0: You came and peed on my floor.
Speaker 1: So you say that but how come?
Speaker 0: there's no pee on my house and there is no pee on my floor since I cleaned it And I've been the only one there.
Speaker 0: It is only when you were there that pee was deposited.
Speaker 0: I don't believe you.
Speaker 1: We'll have to go to your apartment and look at the pee.
Speaker 0: I cleaned it and there is no pee anywhere.
Speaker 1: It's wait a week.
Speaker 1: I cleaned.
Speaker 0: it comes back.
Speaker 0: I cleaned it like a week ago.
Speaker 0: It's been a week already.
Speaker 0: Cleaned it two weeks ago.
Speaker 0: Honestly.
Speaker 1: I don't think you guys understand.
Speaker 1: We live a couple of subway stops away from each other.
Speaker 1: We're basically next-door neighbors.
Speaker 0: the major difference is that when I see something awesome on the internet I have no one to tell immediately Yep, and I can't just walk into the other room be like hey check out this funny video You never walked into the other room.
Speaker 1: I'd be working on my computer and I hear hey rim rim Rim blah blah.
Speaker 0: see yes, blah blah brim or or even better.
Speaker 1: I'd be sitting there and I hear Until I finally yell, what's so funny?
Speaker 0: This funny thing that you must see immediately and stop doing whatever you are doing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's part of the reason why I took so long to edit the show back in the day Like as soon as we stopped the show, I'd like start to edit.
Speaker 1: I'm listening to the show and then next to me I have Scott basically doing another show.
Speaker 1: Yep Really it's not that different It's just.
Speaker 1: it's kind of like we live in this gigantic Apartment building where we're like in the like.
Speaker 1: it takes almost no time for me to go to Scott's place.
Speaker 1: It's got to go to our place.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: It's not yeah, it's really I don't know what city live in.
Speaker 1: It's kind of just this modular lifestyle.
Speaker 1: Yeah What do you think are your greatest personal weaknesses and how have they manifested?
Speaker 1: by the way that previous question was Vega and this Question is from Nery.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Well, I'm really just too awesome.
Speaker 1: And that is really prevented me from being not as awesome as I should be.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm just too smart for my own good.
Speaker 1: So You know, it's just actually I was thinking about this question and it actually gave me quite a bit of insight into all my successes By looking at them in the light of weaknesses like a personal weakness because I do have two very very important weaknesses.
Speaker 1: Scott has one peeing on the floor But weakness the first.
Speaker 0: weakness number one Rims peak is my.
Speaker 0: my floor is very.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: rims pee is super effective against my bathroom floor.
Speaker 1: It's plus one against Scott floor.
Speaker 1: Yeah But my one weakness I have and this is the only one that's detrimental to me is that I'm incredibly Dangerously absent-minded like I will be sitting there and I'll be like, oh I have to pay this bill And then I will immediately forget like why I'm looking at my credit
Speaker 0: card rim.
Speaker 0: Here is a check mail this Oh, yeah I'll just hide it under the stairs under a pile of crap and then the landlord will come and ask for the rent is and Rim will say he mailed it when he clearly did not.
Speaker 1: Or I'll be like, yeah, I'll build that e-commerce by next week.
Speaker 0: Yeah by never.
Speaker 1: yeah, I just forget.
Speaker 1: I forget everything.
Speaker 1: I just I leave stuff everywhere and I forget everything.
Speaker 0: you also Don't do simple things like.
Speaker 0: there'll be something that will take two seconds and rim just I'll say do it now.
Speaker 1: No No, no, it takes two seconds.
Speaker 1: Do it every time Scott tells me to do something that he says is simple It's always something really annoying.
Speaker 1: Good always be like our Google search or something.
Speaker 1: I don't care about and I have no intention of doing do it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's gotta be like rim.
Speaker 1: You got a Google this article and read it.
Speaker 1: I'm like now.
Speaker 1: Do it right now.
Speaker 1: I don't care or I got to point out half the time.
Speaker 1: What do you do?
Speaker 1: that is because I'm like, I'm editing the show.
Speaker 1: I am listening in my headphones to the show I'll find the part where I cough and in my and my other ear I hear rim blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah Blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: It'll take two seconds blah.
Speaker 1: And then I keep.
Speaker 1: don't you notice?
Speaker 1: I keep rewinding what I'm doing because I can't hear it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just pause pause button Open up the tab window.
Speaker 1: But I this made me realize something interesting because my other biggest weakness is that I procrastinate on Everything until the last possible second.
Speaker 1: I don't do shit until someone has a gun to my head.
Speaker 1: But I realized when I really thought about it that you know procrastinate at work.
Speaker 1: Yeah I Procrastinate like crazy at work and I'm always working on stuff.
Speaker 1: But like I don't work on any particular thing until like five minutes before it's due or before it's becoming a problem Oh, good job, but it's more than in life.
Speaker 1: I always defer decisions to the last possible minute and I realized that this is very much given me the ability to capitalize on Circumstance in a huge degree because I never play my hand My hand is always kind of in my pocket and I forget about it and then suddenly someone's like rim.
Speaker 1: You got to play a card like oh shit.
Speaker 1: But by then everyone else has played their cards and I just play the person are.
Speaker 0: so meanwhile You know the oh shit on the e-commerce was like six months ago.
Speaker 0: What the fuck?
Speaker 0: Where is it?
Speaker 1: Oh that didn't benefit me in any way.
Speaker 1: Oh, yes but I'm saying that all of my great successes have come out of the fact that I deferred decisions to a dangerous degree and As a result was able to capitalize on.
Speaker 1: crazy Circumstance that came up that I could not have capitalized on had I been more proactive.
Speaker 0: So not doing the?
Speaker 0: what did you know?
Speaker 0: not doing the e-commerce what benefit?
Speaker 1: oh that didn't benefit me.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying.
Speaker 1: I'm saying it's a weakness because it does not often benefit me.
Speaker 1: However, the few times it has benefited me It has benefited me into in ways that have significantly altered my life for the better.
Speaker 1: It's this weird situation where our weakness kind of made me who I am today made everything awesome But makes a lot of non important things somewhat more problematic.
Speaker 0: Hmm I think my weakness is that is silver silver.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: dragons vain.
Speaker 0: Is that if someone tells me to do something?
Speaker 0: I don't want to do it like even if I would have done it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, like if I'm gonna get in the grocery store and I'm gonna buy honey nut Cheerio and someone says Scott You should totally get honey nut Cheerios because of blah now.
Speaker 0: I don't want to get him I just won't get him.
Speaker 0: just cuz someone told me to I don't see me not want to do it.
Speaker 0: and then Right, like if I come back to get honey Like I actually did want the honey nut Cheerios if I come back and get the next day to get the honey nut Cheerios I have to hide the honey nut Cheers, so they don't see that.
Speaker 0: I got it.
Speaker 0: I can't do anything that someone tells me to do it.
Speaker 1: Actually, you know Scott don't give me five bucks.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna happen Because now there's nobody in my apartment.
Speaker 0: I can do things that people told me to do that I could not do when they were always watching, huh?
Speaker 1: You know, I kind of feel that a little bit.
Speaker 1: There's this.
Speaker 1: I guess I can see that weakness like I can understand it.
Speaker 1: It's kind of this whenever someone gives me advisor tells me to do something even if it's good advice I think for a second.
Speaker 1: how stupid am I that I didn't think to do this and I think they're not better than me?
Speaker 0: No, it has nothing to do with that.
Speaker 0: It's just I don't want to do what anyone tells me to do at all.
Speaker 0: No, even if it's really good advice, I don't give a shit.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter if it's good or bad advice.
Speaker 0: So what do you?
Speaker 0: someone tells me to do it?
Speaker 0: I don't want to.
Speaker 1: what are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: If you ever want to go to like a financial advisor That's a weird thing.
Speaker 0: it's like if I'm at work I have no problem doing what I'm telling to do Because they're paying you.
Speaker 0: I think it's just.
Speaker 0: you know, I don't know what it is.
Speaker 0: But if someone tells me what to do It's weird.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, it's someone asked me to do something.
Speaker 0: I might say yes, I might say no It's you know, but if someone tells me what to do, I just don't want to do it.
Speaker 1: Oh, I also have all the obvious weaknesses, you know bullets knives Poison boobs.
Speaker 1: Yeah Not so much.
Speaker 1: I would say that that weakness boils down to cute art girls.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I have a desperate weakness for cute art girls.
Speaker 1: Did I get her or Arthur?
Speaker 1: They are.
Speaker 0: did I do the last one or did you I did?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Scott not take the next question.
Speaker 0: There is always of talk.
Speaker 0: Okay, Zandro is the asker of this question.
Speaker 0: Zandro your grammar is fail Grammar.
Speaker 0: your fail is there is always of talk of smart people on the show.
Speaker 0: What is your definition of smart?
Speaker 0: someone who is intelligent and thinks for themselves or someone who agrees with you?
Speaker 0: Um, neither.
Speaker 1: Well, I would say you want to go first.
Speaker 0: Yes, there are many things which make a smart person but I think the number one thing that makes a smart person is a a display of critical thinking ability.
Speaker 0: if someone can display You know and improve and demonstrate that they are capable of critical thinking Then they are well on the road to being a smart person and if they do not have that odds are very high.
Speaker 0: They are not what I would consider a smart person.
Speaker 1: I'll back it up to a slightly more Universal statement.
Speaker 1: I'd say I believe very strongly that The definition of intelligent people is that if you have a group of people a large group of people and they all have access to The same information on a given problem and they all agree on the same high-level goals Related to whatever.
Speaker 1: the problem is that the intelligent people will all agree with each other on the path forward or they will disagree Not on the best way to achieve the goal But they will disagree on whether or not the goal should be achieved in the first place.
Speaker 1: I guess to boil it down all if everyone is equally informed and equally willing to critically think and examine data and Willing to be unbiased then all intelligent people will generally agree on most things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean you could put a bunch of stupid people in a room, and they might all agree on something.
Speaker 0: That's totally wrong.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I'm saying that that's not a very good measurement at all.
Speaker 1: I didn't say it was a measurement.
Speaker 1: I said it's just.
Speaker 1: it's a state.
Speaker 1: I feel that intelligent people will agree.
Speaker 0: so the definition of a smart person is someone who agrees.
Speaker 0: That's not really.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: my definition of a smart person is some you know.
Speaker 0: at the very least a smart person displays.
Speaker 0: You know you know very strong critical thinking.
Speaker 1: what is critical thinking?
Speaker 1: I mean really just comes down to the ability to think critically.
Speaker 1: is there a goal?
Speaker 1: if there is a goal.
Speaker 1: Are you able to understand the information that exists and able to make an intelligent decision regarding the achievement of said goal?
Speaker 0: Hmm yeah, but it's not all.
Speaker 0: but you know not everything in the world is is you know like achieving a goal?
Speaker 0: You know or or looking at information and coming up with an answer to something You know a lot of times.
Speaker 0: It's isn't it though.
Speaker 0: No a lot of time a situation.
Speaker 0: Well that isn't well because you know you don't have information.
Speaker 0: It's sometimes it's the ability to observe and acquire information.
Speaker 0: a lot of people you know we'll look at something like.
Speaker 0: you know how many people sit in front of a computer right and You know I also look at that computer, and they don't know what.
Speaker 0: they can't figure out the problem.
Speaker 0: But I can.
Speaker 0: and why?
Speaker 0: because I read the screen and they don't.
Speaker 0: we have the same information available to us.
Speaker 0: They just don't read it right so they lack.
Speaker 0: It's not about making a decision based upon information It's.
Speaker 0: they don't even have the.
Speaker 1: you know the the but they have made a decision.
Speaker 1: in that case They've.
Speaker 1: the decision they've made is that information has been presented to them.
Speaker 1: that is pretty verifiable and objective Or at least it is information that everyone else who is solving the problem or everyone else who was in the same situation Also receives and they choose to ignore this extent information thereby belying their own intelligence.
Speaker 0: Whatever you're getting?
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah, I'm getting.
Speaker 0: what about critical thinking ability?
Speaker 0: if they can if someone can figure something out Then you know.
Speaker 0: if they have figuring out abilities, then they are probably smart.
Speaker 0: But I just as an aside I do feel that in there's nothing to do with like the amount of knowledge You know you have in your brain, or you know what particular area that knowledge might may or may not be in.
Speaker 0: You know or anything like that.
Speaker 0: It's your your ability You know your potential to figure things out when you know they are in front of you.
Speaker 1: yep So what is one habit you wish to break from Kate monster?
Speaker 1: Uh-huh I stopped looking at the internet all the time.
Speaker 1: that was my only one.
Speaker 0: really I also don't look at the internet all the time a Habit, I don't have that many habits.
Speaker 1: I mean I've tried to have more habits like wearing blazers every day instead of almost every day a
Speaker 0: habit I would like to When I do my laundry I don't put the clothes away soon enough and then When I it's like when right out if I do put the clothes away, and the floor is clean I'll start putting all the clothes in the basket, but then I'll put them on the floor.
Speaker 0: And you know right now basically my room is just it always.
Speaker 0: it happens every time and every time I try not to do it And I end up doing it anyway like right now.
Speaker 0: My room is basically clothes all over the floor.
Speaker 0: I don't know what's dirty.
Speaker 0: I don't know what's clean.
Speaker 1: Actually the one thing I'll do is whenever I'm like dealing with a bunch of papers to file or something I've got like like a now and I was building all the cables into this desk I will often find a problem that could be solved right now But will require a lot of annoying and tedious work, or it can be solved 80% of the way Shittily in like two seconds.
Speaker 1: I will always go with the 82 sec at the 80% two-second solution Always and I'll always say to myself someday.
Speaker 1: I'll go with the long and tedious solution, and it never happens.
Speaker 1: hmm right now I basically have a Nest of cables behind this desk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've got it to redo some wires behind my TV a little bit.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna fix that once everything is situated wire channels wire channels and wire bag and getting a speedway I'm gonna put the two speakers behind and get the whole thing going on all right.
Speaker 0: What is the most offensive thing?
Speaker 1: you don't wake up.
Speaker 0: I didn't see two girls one cup.
Speaker 0: But I guess tub girl is the most offensive thing I've seen.
Speaker 0: but it's like it's not offensive and that like oh I am offended.
Speaker 0: It's offensive as like it offends my senses like it makes me nauseous.
Speaker 1: Well, we really you know what is the most offensive thing you've ever seen in any media.
Speaker 0: that was from You know by the way that was in the you know tub girls in the medium of photography, right?
Speaker 1: Well, I guess it's that you have to separate between.
Speaker 1: I mean There's like tub girl goat see offensive, and then there's like guy murdering babies offensive.
Speaker 0: I never said I've never seen.
Speaker 0: it says what have you ever seen?
Speaker 0: I've never seen.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it exists.
Speaker 0: I've never seen it.
Speaker 1: I've seen things like that.
Speaker 0: answer the question which I've seen have you ever seen?
Speaker 1: I well I I still bry have two completely separate scales in my head for offensive.
Speaker 1: There's actually offensive on the grounds that someone is doing great harm and offensive on the grounds that that is totally disgusting.
Speaker 1: Yeah Totally disgusting is two girls one cup which you know, I'd seen all the gross stuff on the internet forever Yeah, I'd seen rotten calm even yeah, but I went into two girls one cup thinking Why is everyone making a big deal about this tub girl?
Speaker 1: What could be grosser than that without actually hurting someone?
Speaker 1: and I I don't even I. to this day nothing has.
Speaker 1: Two girls one cup was an order of magnitude More vile than I could have possibly expected even knowing what it was a shampoo Wasn't there?
Speaker 0: that other video that came out shortly after the people were saying was even worse that I didn't watch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway, that's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: I mean If you could take over a local high school, what would be the first policy change you would implement?
Speaker 1: and why from Kate monster?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I'm sure this is one of those things.
Speaker 1: we could do a whole show If possible, I'll get Bill Gates now say Bill Gates take over the school.
Speaker 0: That's a good move I think.
Speaker 0: basically, you know regardless of any other policies.
Speaker 0: The number one priorities would be to Make failing a possibility.
Speaker 0: right, you know forget that, you know everyone left behind, you know If you suck you should fail and if you're awesome You should get an A. so we need to have you know, the grading needs to be on You know and school should be fucking hard really hard.
Speaker 0: and the philosophy Segregate the school based on you know, I'd put the smart kids into smart class and the dumb kids in a dumb class.
Speaker 1: I'll say this my high school did that my high school was heavily heavily segregated based on ability.
Speaker 1: they're even separate wings depending on how good at very, you know academics you were and What they did is the people who did very poorly were pushed more and more toward vocational things or they had interventions and everything and Like the really really smart kids had classes of like four people taking really advanced stuff.
Speaker 1: Like I took more math and science at in high school.
Speaker 1: Then RIT even offered outside of like the master's programs in those things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you'd have to like take if you wanted to learn more chemistry, you know You'd have to take be a chemistry major.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the segregation like that I mean really my philosophy is that you need to.
Speaker 1: you need to set the bar such that No one ever gets a perfect score in anything because if anyone in any class ever gets a perfect score on any assignment That means that there was not enough granularity There was no room for improvement and like all my AP classes the average score I got an AP bio was about 30 31 percent on a test Mm-hmm, and the goal was always try to get better.
Speaker 1: and you know When I finally went we took the AP test.
Speaker 1: Everyone in that class got a five because the AP test was laughable compared to what we were doing in class.
Speaker 0: Yep, the other thing is that I would make you know, I would sort of you know, it's a high school, right?
Speaker 0: So these are.
Speaker 0: the thing is in high school that college is basically sort of like assumed to be like 13th-grade at this point in the United States, right?
Speaker 0: But really I think that's kind of BS.
Speaker 0: and You know, you only really need to go to college if you know You want to be a doctor a lawyer something that needs a college, you know of.
Speaker 0: you know many years of extra learning.
Speaker 1: I would push the trade schools a lot more and at least It doesn't suck to be a plumber, right?
Speaker 0: I would basically point out to everyone, you know There's all sorts of jobs possibilities out there in the world that no one ever tells you.
Speaker 1: I would fire every guidance counselor.
Speaker 0: Oh for sure.
Speaker 1: No guidance counselor in my entire life ever told me that being a race car driver or a welder or any of that stuff was Even a possibility.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean there's all these jobs out in the world that no one even you know Like you I could have.
Speaker 0: you know, if someone would have told me in high school You could be like a sailor on you know Rich people's yachts or a juggler on a cruise ship or any print major.
Speaker 1: Remember our friend who went into the printing program at RIT and like had crazy money from his co-ops moved to Florida.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know there's all sorts of jobs out in the world.
Speaker 0: Right and the career centers at high schools are Terrible at you know Like teaching kids about all the creative possibilities of things that you can do with the rest of your life that are totally awesome.
Speaker 0: or just think that is a large reason That people are very dissatisfied with their jobs because everyone ends up in the office job.
Speaker 0: You know sit in a desk all day and there are plenty of big money.
Speaker 0: or you know Good money jobs out there that are not sit at a desk all day.
Speaker 0: And if I had known better when I was in high school, even though I'm a you know I'd like computers a whole lot.
Speaker 0: I might have been doing something else computer II.
Speaker 1: you would have at least tried to be a race car Drive.
Speaker 0: Oh, I could have.
Speaker 0: I could have been doing computers for a race car.
Speaker 1: Imagine being the IT guy.
Speaker 0: Like At CES today, they made big announcements for like the computer like the Ford Sync stuff.
Speaker 0: That's in the for in all you know, the Ford vehicles you can get.
Speaker 0: I could have been making that instead of making You know websites, right?
Speaker 1: Come on, but the real key was segregation.
Speaker 1: if you're gonna segregate students based on ability You've really got to set it up to where you Challenge the kids who do well and you give help to the kids who don't do well.
Speaker 1: like failing should be it sucks.
Speaker 1: You failed.
Speaker 1: we got to figure out either what to do Let you pass on your own without just giving everyone a B or Alright, you can't pass.
Speaker 1: Let's figure out what kind of jobs you can do.
Speaker 0: gas station Yeah, and if that's the best, you know That's.
Speaker 0: the other thing is that success is doing the best of your ability and it's just the reality that people have different abilities.
Speaker 0: That's just the way the world is.
Speaker 0: So if the best that you can do is gas station and you get to gas station like, you know attendant hells.
Speaker 0: Yes, awesome for you.
Speaker 0: That is succeeding.
Speaker 0: So what I would not be like?
Speaker 0: look down upon now if you could do a lot better than gas station But you work in one because you're a sad lazy sack who's all drugged up and drinking 40s or whatever.
Speaker 0: Then that should be looked down upon, you know, and that's that's what we need to teach people.
Speaker 1: Specifically, I think I don't you know, we can't get into all the details I think a good way to go about the segregation because you know They're all the way no matter what you do Someone will fall through the cracks.
Speaker 1: the reality of society is that it is impossible to do anything that doesn't have some edge.
Speaker 1: Situation where someone's gonna fall through the cracks on some end of the spectrum, of course.
Speaker 1: So what you do is you do standardized testing.
Speaker 0: It's like if you try to arrest all the robbers you're gonna accidentally.
Speaker 0: you can either arrest all the robbers But you'll accidentally arrest some non robbers or you can guarantee that you won't arrest any non robbers But then some robbers are gonna go free.
Speaker 0: You can't perfectly get all the robbers and not get any of the non robbers and it cannot happen.
Speaker 1: so you need is no way standardized tests across all curriculum and Standardized requirements for each grade like 11th grade.
Speaker 1: to pass it to graduate You need to meet all of these requirements and there's just a standardized test.
Speaker 1: However, if you fail that test you have one recourse Which is to go to an interview at the school instead.
Speaker 1: or maybe you know get experts that do these interviews.
Speaker 1: now It's like a magnet school and if you want to challenge the fact that you failed other than just taking the year again or retesting or whatever you have to go to the center and Intelligent smart people psychologists educators people who are trained Interview you and determine if either you are smart, but you screwed up the test you are smart But you have a problem that prevented you from doing the test or you aren't capable of that grade.
Speaker 0: I think just in general though It's like we you know schools in the u.s.
Speaker 0: You know sort of been following this formula and this curriculum and there hasn't been a lot of differentiation.
Speaker 0: Well grades are determined by age not by ability But it's like I can come up with a lot of different systems that I think would be better than what we have now.
Speaker 0: But really all we need to do is experiment.
Speaker 0: just try different shit all the time and see what works.
Speaker 0: You know and you might say oh you experimented on my kid and now he's stupid because you put him in a experimental thing.
Speaker 0: That was you know bad.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like.
Speaker 0: well, you know, it's the greater good, you know because your kid screwed up.
Speaker 0: We know not to ever try that method of education again, and we're trying some other things other people and you know.
Speaker 1: But I guess my point was just if you're gonna do any sort of segregation a smart way to go about it is two-factor two-factor authentication two-factor segregation.
Speaker 1: There's the broad brush broad brush factor the standardized test.
Speaker 1: But then you have to have a more fine-grained instrument that you only use on the people who?
Speaker 1: Appear to have been caught by the edge conditions in the standardized.
Speaker 0: that can help alleviate some of that.
Speaker 1: and there's and maybe even a third Factor, you know, but you can't do that forever.
Speaker 1: Someone's always gonna fall through the cracks.
Speaker 1: That's just life.
Speaker 0: All right On the show.
Speaker 0: one of you mentioned that there are things worth fighting for in the context of an army.
Speaker 0: What are some of those things that you believe should be fought for.
Speaker 0: I would join the army if it was like World War two.
Speaker 1: Well per I would fighting against genocide fighting against war.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean if it was if I you know That's my the only reason that I did not join any sort of military Establishment because like if I was in the Air Force or something I mean I have really good eyesight.
Speaker 0: I would have been probably pretty good at like flying a plane.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that the thing is.
Speaker 0: if I join the army They would have made me do a push-up and I would have I believed that if I had done it at the time though
Speaker 1: There is this problem
Speaker 0: I would have been you know If I had done it then I'll be push upping that the
Speaker 1: military in the United States just because of the environment is very hostile To.
Speaker 1: basically what is the modern culture of tech people?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I mean the other long-haired hippie dudes doing code are never gonna join the military no matter how strongly they believe in.
Speaker 0: Yes, the other thing is that in the military, right?
Speaker 0: There's always a risk of going back to my weakness.
Speaker 0: They tell you what to do.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much how it works.
Speaker 0: Right if I could join the military but choose What I you know in which manner I would serve.
Speaker 0: and there was you know There was no risk of me serving in a manner that I did not wish to serve.
Speaker 0: I would totally do it because I could just be like oh the genocide in Rwanda you want me to go help.
Speaker 0: Yes Oh, there's a war in Iraq.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm just not going.
Speaker 1: or Scott's super future cyber.
Speaker 1: Would you be a member of section 9?
Speaker 0: Depends, you know and I would be If I was.
Speaker 0: I would decide you know what I would do on a mission by mission basis based on my personal Feelings, you know.
Speaker 0: and if I decided yes, I will do this I would do it to the best of my.
Speaker 0: you know, of course that doesn't work.
Speaker 0: a military needs mindless drones.
Speaker 0: Who will follow orders to?
Speaker 0: exactly with no?
Speaker 1: Back talk.
Speaker 1: special forces needs people who will use initiative and ingenuity to solve problems at their own discretion.
Speaker 0: Yes, see I'm willing to use Ingenuity to solve problems at my own discretion if I want to.
Speaker 0: if I don't You know if I don't want to do what you want me to do You might say, you know, there's a bad guy in that building.
Speaker 0: go get him.
Speaker 0: I like no I agree with that bad guy Fuck you.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna leave him alone And then they're not gonna be very happy with me.
Speaker 0: But if there was a bad guy in the building, I would say absolutely Yes, and I would get that guy.
Speaker 0: so I would be the master I would get him so fast not the professional.
Speaker 1: No, one at one at one area.
Speaker 1: one way to get me to like pretty much add my services and add my abilities to some Sort of large military force in some capacity and I hate to use an anime reference.
Speaker 1: But if the United Nations or somebody like it went Gundam double-o
Speaker 0: Mmm,
Speaker 1: the whole you know the idea that peacekeeping forces where there's a multinational body that no matter what it was if ever there was a militarized armed conflict the peacekeepers basically Invaded and instilled martial law and were hostile toward any belligerence in the theater until and basically just Prevented any actual war from happening until the situation could be resolved.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: I mean basically what it comes down to is if there is something that is blatant and obvious You know evil to combat like, you know, like right now, you know Basically, all the evils in the world are sort of ambiguous and depend on your point of view, you know And you know one person's done wrong one person's done right at least most of the.
Speaker 0: you know, terrorism type evils You know, but there are.
Speaker 0: you know, if there was something that was just blatant and obvious like bad guys, right?
Speaker 0: Like, you know one country invades another country and just starts killing everyone and drops nukes and spreads poison gas or something It's like.
Speaker 0: well, those are obviously bad guys.
Speaker 0: I will gladly go and shoot them.
Speaker 1: You know, of course part of the problem is that we have the situation where the wars that have been like that like between Iraq And Iran we kind of made that happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just because we live in the u.s.
Speaker 0: The whole the whole situation with anything involving military is completely different.
Speaker 0: We basically live at any other point in time in history.
Speaker 0: in any other.
Speaker 1: we basically live in the nation That is the evil team from the Mighty Ducks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a problem from zarlak.
Speaker 1: Can religion and rituals still be meaningful and worthwhile even while embracing an atheist theology?
Speaker 1: There's no such thing as atheist theology.
Speaker 1: Anyway, do you have your own rituals either from established religion or do you or of your own creation?
Speaker 0: Well, I think the problem is is that ritual has many definitions, right?
Speaker 1: I mean I have the ritual of wine, but the ritual of wine is practical.
Speaker 1: I pull the cork out I examine it to see if the right wine is rotten.
Speaker 1: I pour it in a little glass.
Speaker 1: I look at it to see if it's rotten.
Speaker 1: I sniff it to see if it's poison.
Speaker 1: I take a sip to see if it's poison.
Speaker 1: It's practical.
Speaker 0: It's the same thing with not.
Speaker 0: yes rituals are not necessarily A supernatural right like you could have a secret handshake with someone.
Speaker 0: It's just a ritual it but it's not it, you know.
Speaker 0: But it's not supernatural or magical or religious in any way and there's absolutely nothing wrong.
Speaker 1: But that sort of ritual except for the fact that I I dislike being automatic in my life That's whatever anything is happening and I'm doing it automatically I always want to be aware of it so that I can stop it and at least do whatever I'm doing.
Speaker 0: consciously, you know.
Speaker 0: But there can be like intentional Traditional rituals like we can intentionally have a Festivus pole as a ritual.
Speaker 0: that or a tradition Right has nothing to do with any religion or supernatural, you know mysticism or anything.
Speaker 1: Well, we have yell at the sky day that really only the front row crew and only a small portion of that celebrates.
Speaker 0: Yes, but you know, but he says can religion still be meaningful.
Speaker 1: Nope No Religion is not meaningful period because everything that religion has to offer anything that a theological You know non evidence-based belief has you can have the exact same ritual the exact same meaning the exact same everything Without the supernatural belief.
Speaker 1: Yes, that's it.
Speaker 0: That's easy, right?
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: okay, what methods do you use to deal with ignorant people when the situation calls for such action?
Speaker 1: There are only three ways to react to ignorant people and that they scale from left to right on the far left is The I guess they could go.
Speaker 1: Complete avoidance, which is what most people do.
Speaker 1: the polite avoidance, you know You're out at a cocktail party and one of your co-workers says blah blah blah blah my chiropractor and you smile and nod because you're totally lame and you're totally avoiding confrontation and Sacrificing all your ideals because you're a pussy.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm The next level of escalation is the the the the fake that you you pretend to agree.
Speaker 1: you are very nice very accommodating but you're only doing this in order to Work a long-term goal of tricking them or forcing them to change their beliefs like yeah chiropractor blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: Then usually usually the end result of doing this is that they might say yeah chiropractor might be BS But then they don't change their behaviors in any way whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Keep going.
Speaker 1: The only other answer at this point is buzz-altering.
Speaker 1: yes, and I honestly I used to be the kind of person who would like go out of my way to Manipulate people like this to try to set them right and it took a lot of effort and it worked.
Speaker 1: occasionally And maybe I'm just tired like it takes too much effort to manipulate people to that degree.
Speaker 1: I just buzz-altering.
Speaker 1: I just I can't deal with people like that anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah at all.
Speaker 0: Basically, I sort of realized, you know, James Randi has you know, he says that basically it's hopeless.
Speaker 0: You cannot once someone is you know, completely ignorant and stupid.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: You're never going to you know, bring them back.
Speaker 0: They you know, like I said before what is smart people?
Speaker 0: smart people as people have critical thinking abilities.
Speaker 0: Well, if someone's ignorant and they don't have critical thinking abilities There are no words that you can say.
Speaker 1: the worst problem are there are people who are not ignorant who are very well informed And yet who lack critical thinking?
Speaker 1: Yes Those are the most dangerous people because they can very dangerous very bad and very evil things and if they can do it in a very Efficient manner.
Speaker 0: Yes, but you know if somebody you know doesn't have critical thinking abilities You basically are in pot.
Speaker 0: It's impossible to change their mind by.
Speaker 0: there is no Combination of words in any language that you could say to them to change their mind.
Speaker 1: Well pummel empathy I mean left fist and right fist can work to a degree, but that doesn't yeah, but that's not gonna change their mind.
Speaker 0: That's just going to you know, make them suffer the consequence truth the full life consequence consequences.
Speaker 0: But so, you know, it's basically like I just you know, it's like.
Speaker 0: well I just basically label the person as remember this is one of those people who is completely still my god Nothing to do with them anymore.
Speaker 1: You realize in our lifetime the Google goggles are gonna get to the point to where I in my glasses I can just have tags on people and I'll be able to see when other people have tagged people as a woo-woo.
Speaker 1: No, awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: We'll have Google moderator for people.
Speaker 1: That's so great.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I want this now.
Speaker 1: Yes, especially if you.
Speaker 0: only then you can go down the street and say there's an awesome person.
Speaker 0: Hey, what's up?
Speaker 1: We had to do a whole show on augmented reality.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, don't let us forget kids cuz you know I'll forget.
Speaker 1: we already talked about that.
Speaker 1: Right, but I just buzz aldrin people left and right and there's nothing.
Speaker 1: Have you ever gone back into the deepest depths of the geek nights archives and listen to episodes to see how your opinions on various?
Speaker 1: topics and issues Have changed ever since starting the show from Erin in Alberta, which doesn't suck but Calgary does.
Speaker 1: No I plan to.
Speaker 1: Actually, we have a whole plan.
Speaker 1: a crab people episodes we can do is pick an old episode We did a long time ago both listen to it and then redo that.
Speaker 0: Oh, that is double meta.
Speaker 0: Let's not do this or better?
Speaker 1: No Think about how interesting if we do the same show again without listening to that show and then just tell the listeners We did this show again See if our opinions have changed.
Speaker 1: We didn't listen to the previous one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I basically I've only The amount of geek nights episodes that I've listened to in full is a very small number.
Speaker 0: for a very short period of time.
Speaker 0: I basically never listened because When I did listen for the short period of time Basically, all it did was make me remember everything that I already said and heard.
Speaker 0: so there was really no point.
Speaker 1: I don't listen at all even when I edit there's no reason to.
Speaker 1: but I would like to take old episodes and revisit them without Listening and then maybe later I might listen to the two for my own edification like wow I really changed my opinion back there and I can't figure out when that opinion change.
Speaker 0: Yes, but the question was have you ever?
Speaker 0: and the answer is no.
Speaker 1: Nope nope, however, I have listened to in recent memory at least one of the Those episodes Unlistenable good fucking God.
Speaker 0: the next question.
Speaker 0: Do you have any friends who aren't geeks now?
Speaker 1: Mmm because I would say that those people are acquaintances and there's levels of acquaintance But they have not crossed the line into friend.
Speaker 1: Never mind family like the crew has.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean I guess they're you know The closest are.
Speaker 0: I think the people that I would count as friends who aren't geeks are people who are like friends of my family Right, so it's like, you know, my mom.
Speaker 0: there's someone I call like aunt Debbie, right?
Speaker 0: But she's not actually my aunt by any My mom's best friend since my mom was in.
Speaker 1: well, you know what that is cool, right?
Speaker 0: There's so hurt that so hurt, you know Debbie's family, you know Her husband and her children are friends with my family.
Speaker 0: So they're my friends and they're not all nerds.
Speaker 1: Here's how that works.
Speaker 1: You know is there are friends by choice.
Speaker 1: by definition friends are by choice unless you you know Can't deal with leaving high school and you join frats and things just to be forced into friendships as opposed to you know Friends on your own, but they're in with family.
Speaker 1: There is family by choice.
Speaker 1: front row crew is a self-selected sample of family by choice.
Speaker 1: There is also family by birth.
Speaker 1: and while family by birth is a very strong bond as a result There are friends through family by birth Yes, but the thing is friends through family by birth are you know, if they're you know, they're not.
Speaker 0: if they're not blood relatives Right.
Speaker 0: These are people who are friends by choice.
Speaker 0: But basically what it is is our hope.
Speaker 0: my whole family by birth Chooses another whole family by birth as friends, you know It just so happens that it happens to be like a group of people and another group of people.
Speaker 0: So imagine if like the front row crew saw another front row crew and decided that we should be friends with that front row crew.
Speaker 0: You know that back row crew, you know, we as a group decide so, you know The family that I was born into decided as a group that we would befriend this family in this family
Speaker 1: Periodically of a family convention and vote on whether or not you're still friends with these people.
Speaker 0: No, but you know there there are other families that my you know Family that I grew up with was friends with and those people are my friends and not all of them are geeks.
Speaker 0: However, it's actually surprising how many of those people are at least partially geeky, you know There's model railroad people in these families.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of sports geeks in these families Like cartoon watching geeks in these families People doing all sorts of Etsy kind of stuff in these families.
Speaker 1: I do not Regularly associate in any way with anyone who was not a geek on purpose.
Speaker 1: What was your favorite moment at a convention?
Speaker 1: I might have to go all the way back to 2002 only because while I've had probably more fun Actual moments than this moment.
Speaker 1: This is one of those moments that kind of solidified the legend of Krauser.
Speaker 1: for me This is back when I went to.
Speaker 1: basically I think I've told the story on the show, but we have a lot of new listeners.
Speaker 1: No, I'll tell these shortened version dubbed this old webcomic friend of ours Scott Johnson did along with Luke Morgan and They were invited to stay in a room with a bunch of their like readers at Anime Central, which was in Chicago.
Speaker 1: I happen to own a car.
Speaker 0: This is the moment you're gonna pick.
Speaker 1: That's the moment I'm gonna pick.
Speaker 1: so those two guys are like hey rim you want to go to Chicago and I was like For the whoring and the drinking.
Speaker 1: I was like, let's go.
Speaker 1: We had this, you know, there's this whole crazy adventure like all the things that happen on the car breaking down Yep, driving into Indiana and then up into Michigan and then paying with a bad check to get back on the road.
Speaker 1: Cuz we're out of money.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, so We get there and this scary looking nerdy guy kind of comes down.
Speaker 1: He's like, oh my god, it's rim Scott and Luke.
Speaker 0: Welcome Scott Johnson, not Scott Reuben.
Speaker 1: Yes different Scott.
Speaker 1: I'll just Scott Reuben didn't come to this convention.
Speaker 1: Nope I'll.
Speaker 1: uh, I'll take you up to the room.
Speaker 1: Everyone's waiting to meet you.
Speaker 1: We're like fuck.
Speaker 1: What are we getting ourselves into?
Speaker 1: he takes us up and he goes over to the presidential suite Opens the door and we see so many cute cosplay girls in various states of undress as they finish sewing all their enormous and beautiful costumes.
Speaker 1: and rim was single at the time I was single at the time and Luke and Scott Johnson.
Speaker 1: we all look at each other.
Speaker 1: We look at this kid and he's like.
Speaker 1: he's like the only guy staying in the room other than us.
Speaker 1: and we look at all these girls and One thing leads to another and we're like and we see there's a bar like a wet bar in the room.
Speaker 1: So we look at each other and Luke says to what the girl who's like run in the room.
Speaker 1: Who's this cute para para girl?
Speaker 1: Oh, man, you have a bar.
Speaker 1: Well tell we came.
Speaker 1: every time we go to conventions This is like one of the first conventions I ever went to.
Speaker 1: by the way, we run these parties.
Speaker 1: We have all the stuff in the car not alcoholic bar.
Speaker 1: It's great.
Speaker 1: You want us to run our party for your room?
Speaker 1: And he looks at me and I'm like, yeah We got this drink list like the southern Val dandy and it's really cool.
Speaker 1: And then she's like, oh, that'd be awesome.
Speaker 1: You guys are so cool.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, so we're like, yeah Let's go get the stuff.
Speaker 1: We got to the car.
Speaker 1: We're like, alright the fuck are we gonna do now?
Speaker 1: We found a grocery store and an epicness ensued.
Speaker 1: I'll leave it at that.
Speaker 1: That was probably the greatest moment at a con ever just because it was my first.
Speaker 1: it was the first moment in the Legend of Rims
Speaker 0: The greatest moment at a convention, you know, it's weird because like there are things that happen at conventions and it's like You know what scale of greatness I mean you have playing settlers with hooker midgets that you can't get a better story than that.
Speaker 1: No, you also have the first time you walk into the Otacon dealers room You just don't know what to do about right, you know, you've got that.
Speaker 0: You know like amazing concert be it Larkin Seattle or TMR or whoever you want, right?
Speaker 0: or Jonathan Colton or something, right?
Speaker 0: You know, what can what can you put above that greatest event at a convention?
Speaker 1: you've got excite bike to at packs, right?
Speaker 0: you've got like excite bike verse being revealed right.
Speaker 0: and then you've got stuff like you know just playing a really awesome game of Via poletti or something or play, you know.
Speaker 0: You know playing inheritance with Luke Craig, you know discovering the burning wheel or something like that.
Speaker 0: That was at a convention.
Speaker 1: We have so many crazy Convention like conventions.
Speaker 0: not there is not.
Speaker 0: I don't think there is one That stands out like above all the others like oh, they're just like, you know many many many many many many many.
Speaker 1: the thing I can say about that is just that we'll never get sick of conventions, especially now that we don't go to just anime conventions, but Conventions are like geek cities that just form Periodically and if we had a geek city then we wouldn't need convention.
Speaker 1: And New York City is the close.
Speaker 0: Talk about this because I think that's a question coming.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then we got to stop soon.
Speaker 1: I don't forget to it All right.
Speaker 0: Well, it's only three away anyway.
Speaker 0: Will you ever have a roundtable discussion on anything with the FRC?
Speaker 0: Parentheses this is overdue in the age of Skype one.
Speaker 1: Oh right after we have e-commerce one almost no one we know in the front row crew has decent microphones or anything at home.
Speaker 1: So they'll sound more ass than even Scott did over Skype for one and two.
Speaker 1: it's like herding cats.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's also Editing.
Speaker 0: it is like hurting double cats
Speaker 1: pretty much the way we're gonna see
Speaker 0: people talking over each other interrupting and skipping in and
Speaker 1: Yeah, the way we're gonna handle that is whenever we have multiple people on the show We're either going to Skype in people who we know have like radio show skills already Or we're going to have people physically in the studio with us.
Speaker 1: So unless people come to the studio and sit down on the futon They're not gonna be on the show.
Speaker 0: and even then there is there's still.
Speaker 0: there's a limit to the number of people who can be On the show at once and it isn't a very small limit like four or maybe five.
Speaker 0: You know you once you get more people than that.
Speaker 0: It just becomes a disaster.
Speaker 1: We basically have to train people up to.
Speaker 1: yeah You can do a talk like if you listen.
Speaker 0: there are some Podcasts out there that have very large numbers of hosts like calm geek speak as like can have five or six hosts and then they'll Guests.
Speaker 0: but the only reason it works is because they make like four shows a week and all the hosts are always on the podcast All the time.
Speaker 0: so they're all good at it.
Speaker 0: We had.
Speaker 0: we can have ten rims and Scott's on the podcast you know.
Speaker 0: But if it's a rim a Scott and then five people who aren't on podcasts all the time of course The way around that is to set it up.
Speaker 1: I mean I have the giant mixer here.
Speaker 1: I basically mute everyone and I unmute people as I want to let them speak.
Speaker 0: yes But even then it takes a large amount of preparation and setting up.
Speaker 0: You know it's not like.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: they say oh, it's overdue in the age of Skype.
Speaker 0: Hahaha.
Speaker 0: It's not that easy.
Speaker 1: If you had the time and patience to enter a long-term period in which you would either learn or improve upon a skill What would it be?
Speaker 0: Learn or improve upon a skill.
Speaker 1: I would become a musician again I would get my trumpet skills back and probably just become a professional trumpet player again.
Speaker 1: I mean that was you know.
Speaker 1: I don't know how many listeners remember this.
Speaker 1: I flipped a coin between Becoming a professional trumpet player or going to RIT and going into IT like I. just I didn't care is 50/50 I Would.
Speaker 0: I don't know what skill I would pick but would definitely be a skill of making something that is physical, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I make software's all the time, but it's like I really like making crafts.
Speaker 0: It could be you know and that's a wide for it could be like anything from like making cars To making little electronic things to making.
Speaker 0: you know shirts To.
Speaker 0: you know just making.
Speaker 0: some blacksmithing.
Speaker 0: You know just something that is making stuff boat boat making.
Speaker 1: what are some white gold-wielding white?
Speaker 0: You know it's not.
Speaker 0: that's not making.
Speaker 0: it would be some skill and you know carpeting cabinet making.
Speaker 0: it'd be some sort of skill in constructing Something physical with my hands, and I would you know basically I would become the master of whatever It was like making desks or chairs or something you know and then You know I'd make a whole bunch of them.
Speaker 1: That's the one thing I am going to do now with all this extra free time is I don't know I'm either going to pick my trumpet back up, or I'm going to practice my harmonica a lot more serious.
Speaker 0: Hey, you're not in my apartment.
Speaker 1: Well, you don't want to hear old Susanna a thousand times in a row.
Speaker 0: no Well, that's that is.
Speaker 0: another thing is that I do you know like I don't have that much interest in music But like I played the guitar when I was in fourth grade and fifth grade, but then when I went to middle school I had I wanted you know I joined the middle school band and guitar was not an option.
Speaker 0: so I chose clarinet and I could not do two instruments at once.
Speaker 0: so I you know put guitar down and Basically, I quit stupid band in ninth grade.
Speaker 0: I basically played the clarinet for four years, and then I quit that and So basically since 10th grade.
Speaker 0: I regretted giving up the guitar in the first place But I have never picked it up again, and you know sort of.
Speaker 0: you know I didn't regret it that much But when playing guitar hero, I regretted it much more.
Speaker 0: So it's like I don't know you know.
Speaker 0: and then I said oh I'll get the harmonica, and if I have the you know the the wherewithal to actually practice this then Spending money on a guitar won't be a waste, but I didn't practice the harmonica, so I didn't buy a guitar.
Speaker 0: But maybe I don't know.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 1: I got some free time.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh well.
Speaker 1: You're right that question was coming right up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, do you foresee outgrowing conventions?
Speaker 0: had we?
Speaker 1: Continued with our old convention policy, which was go to every freaking anime convention I would have probably just given up on convention.
Speaker 0: I think the thing is is I already have outgrown Attending non gaming conventions.
Speaker 0: You know I mean comic conventions are just places to shop.
Speaker 0: It's a big comic book store.
Speaker 0: That's temporary.
Speaker 0: I have no interest in that because I buy online at a discount.
Speaker 0: well the Well the mocha is different.
Speaker 0: the anime conventions.
Speaker 1: I have outgrown going to them entirely right I would argue we haven't imagine if we didn't go to any cons at all.
Speaker 1: all right Otacon once a year.
Speaker 1: We could have a lot of fun at.
Speaker 0: I think yeah, but it's not that much fun.
Speaker 0: I just go to anime, Boston.
Speaker 1: It's closer, but hey anime convention right anime, Boston.
Speaker 1: You're right.
Speaker 0: even so it's like you know.
Speaker 0: I you know and most of the only reason I would go is this people I know there.
Speaker 0: if I didn't know anyone there I wouldn't go.
Speaker 1: I probably would I used to go to conventions like just me and Scott Johnson all the time back in the day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the girls were much closer to your age at that point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's funny How the girls got younger as I got older.
Speaker 1: it's not like they stayed the same age, and I got older.
Speaker 1: It's that we diverged.
Speaker 0: yep, but they don't say we're 20. you were 20, but now you're.
Speaker 1: It's possible to outgrow anime cons just because the demographics were so squirrely, but all other conventions look at sci-fi cons or Gaming con.
Speaker 0: I have no interest in a sci-fi con but a gaming con.
Speaker 0: I can never outgrow as long as I like games because the gaming con is just a place to go and Play games with people you don't know and games You've never played before.
Speaker 0: and as long as I'm a game fan that will always be good and you cannot get old unless gaming itself also get any calm.
Speaker 1: that either involves doing or That involves geeks who are my age intellectually.
Speaker 1: I mean imagine if Otakon were 26,000 20 to 30 something year old techie punk kids.
Speaker 1: yep that Otakon would be the best thing ever.
Speaker 1: That's why pegs pretty good is the best thing ever because it's that and it's a gaming con.
Speaker 0: And there are other sorts of conventions like you know I guess like New York International Auto Show.
Speaker 0: You know it's like it's cool to go and look at shiny cars.
Speaker 0: But you know do I really need to go?
Speaker 0: not really the CES is going on right now.
Speaker 0: I'd like to go to that.
Speaker 0: maybe once in my life I was so cool to see all new gadgets.
Speaker 0: But it's just a room full of fancy new gadgets, but look at the question you reading gadget comm you do you foresee outgrowing?
Speaker 1: conventions?
Speaker 1: and the answer is never because at its core all a convention is is Geography unless you live in a major city.
Speaker 1: Geography limits your social life in a big way.
Speaker 1: I mean you can do stuff online But you go to conventions because it's a self-selected sample.
Speaker 1: the people who live in a particular area Live there for all these concerns that might not be related to.
Speaker 1: you know shared interest jobs economy all that stuff family.
Speaker 1: But a convention is a self-selected sample of people who say I am into X I'm going to go stay with all the other people or into X and have a tiny geeky city for a weekend.
Speaker 1: Yep by definition all conventions are geeky because there's people who have a deep interest in something or People are being paid to go there by the company.
Speaker 1: Yep hanging out all right.
Speaker 1: I think we should just do one more because this is a good question to end it on all right if you had to give One piece of advice to punk kids.
Speaker 0: What would you tell them?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna say punk kids are 14 to 19 year old kids who are otherwise a lot like we were when we were 14 to 19.
Speaker 1: My biggest piece of advice to you is that almost nothing you were doing right now matters for the rest of your life.
Speaker 0: I was the same.
Speaker 0: advice I was gonna give is that right now there are people telling you all sorts of lies like your your grades in high school or whatever school you're in or the Most important thing in the world if you get an F in like math or you get suspended once your life is gonna be ruined Forever.
Speaker 1: you're not gonna get to go right, but that's all the old hat advice.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 0: and the thing and the thing is right is that in if you want to be a doctor or a lawyer and you want A big fancy one at that.
Speaker 0: Yes You probably do need to get all A's and go to Harvard or something to be the big fancy doctor lawyer.
Speaker 0: But doing poorly in school, you know is not going to ruin the rest of your life.
Speaker 0: You are going to.
Speaker 0: you know, your school is like this huge huge thing.
Speaker 0: It just dominates your life at least in the United States, you know for in the Western world I guess as a whole, you know for like 18 years of your life and maybe even through college and then it's gone.
Speaker 0: You never had to think about it again.
Speaker 0: It's just this it's just gone.
Speaker 0: So as long as you gain the skills to live life It doesn't actually matter the well in school unless the results in school themselves are necessary towards your goal of being a lawyer.
Speaker 1: Now what I would say?
Speaker 1: that that's that's the rub.
Speaker 1: the real measure of school is Knowing when things matter and when things don't.
Speaker 1: once you can figure out what matters and what doesn't you're over there.
Speaker 1: You're set for the rest of your life.
Speaker 1: I mean In high school, right Once you figure out what kinds of grades and you know Quote-unquote extracurricular activities you need to get into the college you want to get into if you want to go to college even.
Speaker 1: but if you Want to get into a certain college figure out what you need.
Speaker 1: get that and nothing else matters.
Speaker 1: a very specific piece of advice would be this you get your diploma whether or not you walk and Mostly if you do some crazy awesome prank as a senior you still get your diploma.
Speaker 1: You just don't get to walk in a stupid ceremony that all the kids hate.
Speaker 1: anyway Pull the awesome fucking prank.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Do it be that guy just go for it And just don't do anything that will actually get you in jail.
Speaker 1: Yes, do not do anything that will actually not get you your diploma, right?
Speaker 1: Of course I point out.
Speaker 1: No one ever asked for or saw my high school diploma.
Speaker 1: No, I don't even have one I don't even know where it is.
Speaker 0: I don't know it might be somewhere, you know No one's ever gonna ask for it.
Speaker 0: is all these things like you think are so important?
Speaker 0: But they're not.
Speaker 0: look I would just I guess the advice can be can be summed up in Look at your life as a whole.
Speaker 0: look at long term, you know in the short term when you're a kid There's a lot of confusing and stuff that seems a lot more important than it really is.
Speaker 0: You need to look in the ultra long term of your whole life.
Speaker 0: You know, what are you gonna do for all these years?
Speaker 0: Look at that and then you will be able to make much better Decisions and live a much more fulfilling life as a whole.
Speaker 1: and don't be afraid to try things and do crazy stuff.
Speaker 1: I mean if there's a girl and she likes you make out with her.
Speaker 1: It's high school.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter as long as she doesn't have herpes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right We said make out.
Speaker 0: we didn't say get it on.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.