Speaker 1: It's Wednesday October 20th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight the scary flying ghost ship.
Speaker 0: It's not scary Let's do this.
Speaker 1: I remember a time at RIT when the only way I would get to play DDR Was when the anime club would be like hey, we're playing DDR, and they'd set it up at like this club space.
Speaker 0: That was the year Mm.
Speaker 1: We've been playing DDR for a decade.
Speaker 1: yep, and I still can't beat some of those nine-footers.
Speaker 0: It's cuz.
Speaker 0: you've been playing DDR for a decade.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it's sad, but I feel like I might have.
Speaker 1: finally for the first time like you know we're getting old.
Speaker 1: I'm pushing 30, and it bothers me, but at the same time.
Speaker 1: I haven't felt the effects of age too much yet until this past week Because I've been playing DDR a lot lately just for various replaying DDR without caffeine.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah Except even with caffeine I couldn't do it.
Speaker 1: But my trouble is I'm playing DDR And I decided I'm going to get to the next level the level I never reached in the old days.
Speaker 1: I want to be able to pass every nine-footer the same way I can pass every eight-footer.
Speaker 1: I'm about three-quarters.
Speaker 0: the way there that nine foot is a lot bigger than the eighth foot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know all feet are equal.
Speaker 1: I can pass almost every nine-footer.
Speaker 1: That's not my trouble.
Speaker 1: my trouble is that then I thought so there's those ten-foot fuckers like max 300 and legend of max.
Speaker 1: you know all that stuff.
Speaker 1: the crazy challenge to the So I was practicing.
Speaker 1: I've been practicing max 300 for two weeks now.
Speaker 1: Just now Scott saw I got within three seconds of beating it on maniac.
Speaker 0: It's bully and you had to beat it or you don't?
Speaker 1: yeah, but at the same time I'm getting there.
Speaker 0: see what I think they should have done right in DDR is instead of using this foot system of Difficulty they should rank every DDR song ever with a number of how hard it is and change them as new songs.
Speaker 0: I see I would agree.
Speaker 0: This is the number one hardest song.
Speaker 1: Here's why I disagree because some stuff like a rhythm in police and I don't know they love you like a fool.
Speaker 1: our two are similarly difficult songs that are very different in the manner that they're Difficult like.
Speaker 1: I can do songs with a lot of streaming.
Speaker 0: yeah But whatever you just pick whatever number you just rank them next to each other and then people can argue about it.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: What do you care if you're konami?
Speaker 0: It'll give a shit?
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, so you just but they had a good system.
Speaker 1: I mean I like the foot system.
Speaker 1: I like that web graph.
Speaker 1: They added remember where it shows like why it's difficult like this is a jumpy song.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: anyway people playing don't even pay attention to that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they do replay.
Speaker 1: We paid attention to it a lot.
Speaker 1: I remember.
Speaker 0: normal people do not even know.
Speaker 1: people don't play DDR.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they do.
Speaker 1: DDR is dead except among hardcore fans.
Speaker 0: hardcore people don't need the little chart.
Speaker 1: I would say we're hardcore.
Speaker 1: no there are people who are just hardest core whatever anyway.
Speaker 1: So I can almost pass it.
Speaker 1: so I've been playing you know legend of max and max unlimited And I reached a point that I never thought I'd reach in my life.
Speaker 1: I just I knew it.
Speaker 1: you know kind of intellectually, but I never viscerally really believed it until now.
Speaker 1: I Know the arrows.
Speaker 1: I know exactly what I need to do.
Speaker 1: I see them come in.
Speaker 1: I think you know like.
Speaker 1: I know it.
Speaker 1: I know it perfectly and I literally just can't move my legs fast enough to execute it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's that's how it is.
Speaker 1: I've never run into something like that in my life before.
Speaker 1: This is this is it.
Speaker 0: I'll go run like the New York Marathon, and it'll be like uh yeah You didn't realize it is that many miles all at once, but I feel like I could train for that.
Speaker 1: I feel like with this in particular I just there will.
Speaker 1: there is a physical limitation that I have hit that.
Speaker 1: had I attempted this when I was younger I probably would have been able to pass it.
Speaker 0: I do not know if I'm yeah, because you know why you're able to do when you're younger tiny legs.
Speaker 0: We have big legs which are younger.
Speaker 1: I'm talking like when I was at RIT.
Speaker 1: I'm not bigger now than I was then.
Speaker 0: there you are.
Speaker 1: I'm not bigger.
Speaker 0: I stopped growing like well you're definitely not bigger than me.
Speaker 1: That's like senior year of high school.
Speaker 1: I didn't get any taller after that I Mean.
Speaker 0: I think that's why the Japanese people are so good at DDR because they're like they are so tiny.
Speaker 1: How do you explain fanboy in the mall?
Speaker 1: He is fat Doing the fanboy piston.
Speaker 0: yeah, so when he steps It doesn't push his body up because his body is weighing his leg down.
Speaker 0: We bounce which makes it harder to hit another arrow again because your foot is farther away from it because it bounced.
Speaker 1: Anyway before we get into the one I guess anime news I do want to mention this briefly.
Speaker 1: Deno coil an anime that is highly acclaimed that I haven't seen yet either.
Speaker 0: Scott I downloaded the whole thing by doing well.
Speaker 1: I only watch like episode one Alex and Emily and everyone watching these legitimately released I don't know, but it's supposedly awesome all right, and it's about augmented reality and gaming and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: It's I think we have that now.
Speaker 0: wasn't there penny arcade comic with the Invisibles.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's Deno coil.
Speaker 1: So here's the problem.
Speaker 1: then I keep saying here's the problem.
Speaker 1: then our coil is gonna get a video game And it's gonna be made by game on.
Speaker 1: and I bring this up only because this is one of those situations Much much like our egregiously unrealized potential panel at PAX where we asked why there's no Pokemon MMO.
Speaker 1: This is a game world and a concept that could be an amazing game And I'll bet you any money.
Speaker 1: It is going to be a generic shit MMO or even worse like hexide a generic shit fake MMO.
Speaker 0: Yes, sir I was giving.
Speaker 1: yeah, that's all I got.
Speaker 1: that's it so much more important the New York anime festival, New York comic-con.
Speaker 0: I know it was already like two weeks ago, but we haven't done a Wednesday episode So we haven't done any posts reviewing talk about it.
Speaker 1: I talked about it a little bit on the gaming episode because yeah We talked about burning.
Speaker 0: can we talked about the gaming aspects of it?
Speaker 0: But we didn't really talk about all the stuff that went on there, so we should just do it briefly.
Speaker 0: You know some of the stuff we saw there good and bad and whatever.
Speaker 1: well the New York comic-con New York anime festival the double Double mega con had one thing going for it.
Speaker 1: there were a lot of goddamn people there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I only went on Friday, but supposedly Saturday was insane in terms of the number of people.
Speaker 1: Saturday was completely sold out.
Speaker 1: There's no way to get in if you didn't already have a badge.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're reported.
Speaker 0: turnstile figure is 96,000 ish.
Speaker 0: so the thing is a lot of people get the one-day badge especially Saturday and Sunday.
Speaker 0: So I'm thinking real numbers probably in the 50 to 60 thousand area.
Speaker 1: I'd top it at around 70.
Speaker 1: That's my guess.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the thing is Sunday there was a line.
Speaker 0: You know I only went Sunday, and then Sunday's kids day, so everyone brings their kids on Sunday.
Speaker 1: No, here's the scary thing.
Speaker 1: it wasn't just kids.
Speaker 1: So I'm walking around and the con is still crazy crazy crowded.
Speaker 1: and when I go to leave I said I've the whole kind of seen this gigantic line like snaking all around the inside and then going out a door and then snaking All around the outside of the Javits.
Speaker 1: so on the way out I'm looking I'm like what the fuck is this line for and I asked someone and they're like I'm just trying to get in.
Speaker 1: Every one of those people was trying to buy a one-day badge to get in and they were trying to buy it at the door.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the thing is they were also will call everyone's in the same line.
Speaker 0: Whoa will call?
Speaker 0: so the non will call line was short.
Speaker 1: They were all one as far as I could tell.
Speaker 1: okay, but the trouble was the trouble.
Speaker 1: I keep saying that I don't know why.
Speaker 1: Suffice it you got you got trouble.
Speaker 1: I got trouble.
Speaker 1: indeed The line was crazy and only about half the people in the line had kids with them and the kid Presence on Sunday did not seem substantially greater than the kid presence on Friday night.
Speaker 0: Yeah, for I was only there Friday and because I went in like an hour early I could have gone in it like 10, but I went in it like noon and It wasn't.
Speaker 0: you know, it wasn't early.
Speaker 0: It was in during the professional hours So I was able to see everything without a lot of traffic.
Speaker 0: and then you know I stayed there all day Friday and it never got you know, intolerably crowded on Friday.
Speaker 1: I'm curious if you had this problem on Friday because I had it Friday evening and I had it times 10 on Sunday and Emily And you know a bunch of our friends went on Saturday and they had this problem times a thousand Buckers just bump into you.
Speaker 0: No, my problem was people.
Speaker 0: just you know, stop it in the in the aisles.
Speaker 0: You know a little bit on Friday, right?
Speaker 0: You'd walk down an aisle and it's like I want to move and this room on the other side There's like two people in front of me and then there's space to move.
Speaker 0: But there's people to the left looking at something people to the right looking at something and people in the middle just standing still And it's like you people in the middle Move to the other side of these two blobs and then there's empty space just beyond you where I would like to go You know and it's like just keep walking.
Speaker 1: simple fix.
Speaker 1: it would take minimal staff.
Speaker 1: All I would do if I you know ran the double mega con is have directions.
Speaker 0: I would also one way.
Speaker 1: every aisle is one way.
Speaker 0: Yes, every aisle should be one way.
Speaker 0: and also I would just ban picture-taking in aisles.
Speaker 0: It's like there is the picture-taking of cosplayer area.
Speaker 0: You may not take pictures of cosplayers anywhere else and risk camera confiscation.
Speaker 1: Scott It's too hard to ban and there's no way you'd have enough staff to actually enforce that it.
Speaker 0: no But the thing is you don't.
Speaker 0: what you had to do is it's the same kind of thing.
Speaker 0: You don't enforce all of it, right?
Speaker 0: If a staff guys there, you know, no one's gonna risk it now.
Speaker 1: No one's gonna even know.
Speaker 1: no one'll even know.
Speaker 1: It's a rule.
Speaker 1: no one reads anything in the con book except the schedule.
Speaker 0: That's their problem.
Speaker 1: No, I think that's a terrible way to go.
Speaker 0: I think it's a great rule.
Speaker 0: I think that's 99% of the traffic and aisles is stopping to take pictures.
Speaker 1: Scott Maybe because you went on Friday when it was less on Saturday and Sunday.
Speaker 1: The problem was there's just too many people trying to walk in both directions.
Speaker 0: It was just a solid sea of people apparently at no point did the fire marshal think it was a problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's watching the whole time because they had a cap.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh The trouble is just.
Speaker 1: they really need one-way lanes.
Speaker 1: that would probably solve most of the overcrowding.
Speaker 1: and then beyond that It's just a. I feel like comic cons have this problem where anime and gaming cons don't so much of people just bumping into you Not like you know Squeezing by or crowded like Otacon crazy crowded in that upper skywalk and trying to get across.
Speaker 1: You're like the 300 level going.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but no one.
Speaker 1: just like slams into me full-on at Otacon Or anime Boston or packs or anything.
Speaker 1: yet at this con that dudes not just fat dudes But they were the biggest offenders would literally just like bang into me while I was walking.
Speaker 0: I think I only got bumped once.
Speaker 1: I got back course.
Speaker 1: you bang some people with those goddamn Boxes you had to pick up and then I had to carry to the stupid cab.
Speaker 0: Hey, but I got fancy boxes now.
Speaker 0: So yeah So it could have been a lot more inconvenient.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I show up at the con you're like, oh wait We got to go get a dolly and get these heavy fucking gigantic boxes and carry them around the con And then get a cab at the Javits at night when there's no way to get a cab.
Speaker 0: It wasn't that bad.
Speaker 1: It's like 20 minutes to get a cab.
Speaker 0: That's fun Would you?
Speaker 0: okay?
Speaker 0: would you rather pay the shipping for the for the boxes?
Speaker 1: They're not my boxes.
Speaker 1: So yes, I would rather you have paid the shipping for the boxes since that stuff.
Speaker 1: Then you try to dump them a cat's artist alley table.
Speaker 1: They're bigger than the space behind her table.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they would fit back there.
Speaker 1: Anyway, nevermind trying to squeeze them past the fat dudes to get to her table.
Speaker 0: That's all right.
Speaker 0: So What about you know, regardless of that situation, right?
Speaker 0: What kind of you see any cool stuff at the?
Speaker 0: I mean because it was mostly booths, right?
Speaker 0: it's one of those cons where you see every booth and Unless there's a specific programming you really want to see or a specific famous person You really want to meet right then?
Speaker 0: You see all the boobs and you leave and most of the famous people you want to see are like sitting at an artist alley Table.
Speaker 0: so it's sort of a mocha situation.
Speaker 0: You don't have to go to their panel, right or There they have.
Speaker 0: you have to pay to get an autograph with them So you don't see them or you look at them from far away and go there's a famous person.
Speaker 1: All right Honestly, the only thing that drew my attention that was really like stood out that I remember and really enjoyed was Other than checking out a couple of specific booths for like, you know publishers I know was all the models of Gundams in the middle.
Speaker 0: Well, that was the Bandai booth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's definitely by far the best booth.
Speaker 1: Oh my god The Bandai booth was made a win and there's stuff like that at like that sort of model kind of stuff at PAX in the Crazy expo hall but not to that scale.
Speaker 0: This is the one and I had every single current model built and on display well presented in these glass cases and It was pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: If you are a fan of plastic robots, it was like the greatest thing I ever saw.
Speaker 0: Yeah terms of plastic robots and I bought the best one that they had.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, I just walked around the whole place.
Speaker 1: I have mostly impressions about the con in general.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to avoid all the meta that no one cares about.
Speaker 0: just some stuff that I saw that was interesting right was There was a the hendane, you know, doujinshi people.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah They were up against the wall facing the wall in the back backity back back.
Speaker 1: cannot but hope that that was intentional.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was.
Speaker 1: I saw a lot of fucking yaoi panels though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we panels.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we paddles.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, cuz they were actually letting him sell them.
Speaker 0: those big heavy boxes that I bought were actually the comic cubes Which are like these it's like, you know, you buy comic books and you put them in a cardboard box.
Speaker 0: But this is basically the same thing only it's actually nice furniture.
Speaker 0: So you can put it out with the furniture and it's super nice and it was totally worth it.
Speaker 0: And it let me make room in the closet for the vacuum cleaner.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: All you need now is the hoplite.
Speaker 0: Yeah animal planet had a really fancy booth.
Speaker 0: what I don't know.
Speaker 0: what they were doing there.
Speaker 1: Why is animal planet the network of ghosts and midgets?
Speaker 1: There are no animals on the animal planet except things like yetis.
Speaker 0: Maybe ghost yetis, I don't know.
Speaker 1: And even there you know what they were promoting.
Speaker 1: they were promoting some like I don't know paleo zoology.
Speaker 1: Let's go find like cryptids and yetis and crap.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's what they were actually promoting.
Speaker 0: Sengoku Basara, that's the show with the horses that have mufflers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had some really good promotion.
Speaker 1: basically, you know They're psycho mufflers not you know muffler mufflers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know how Samurais wear flag on their back.
Speaker 0: They were set.
Speaker 0: they were giving out these Sengoku Basara flags for people to wear on their back.
Speaker 1: Realize if you know the e-commerce is coming along after the legal stuff is sorted out.
Speaker 1: Do you guys want like?
Speaker 1: I don't know if anyone would really want this but I want to make some of those.
Speaker 0: That's all you.
Speaker 0: They had these two shamisen playing dudes who were not the Yoshida brothers But I went to see them just by chance like I kind of wanted to see them and I just happened to stay Arrive at their panel room.
Speaker 1: I really wanted to see him but I was at work.
Speaker 0: They were way awesome and they totally played smoke on the water on the shamisen.
Speaker 0: It was wicked crazy.
Speaker 1: Really like shamisen.
Speaker 0: Alright, uh, they're gonna be at Carnegie Hall in March.
Speaker 0: We can go.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I think you mentioned that before.
Speaker 1: We should get some tickets.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was a guy cosplaying.
Speaker 0: I don't know if he was cosplaying or if he was.
Speaker 0: you know a company paid for it to happen But he was the high chew King and he was giving out high chew.
Speaker 1: Actually, I saw a perfect Zangief, but I realized college humor was probably there.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it was the dude who played Zangief in the later years.
Speaker 0: You think so?
Speaker 1: You look exactly like that guy maybe Exactly.
Speaker 1: I was gonna talk to him, but I was actually in a hurry.
Speaker 0: I Went to Vamps panel, which I realized I learned a few things in this Vamps panel, right?
Speaker 0: basically, they had this guy come out who sort of worked with them in the US and He basically killed time and bullshitted for the vast majority of the panel Meaning that they only had to actually do their panel for a very short amount of time.
Speaker 1: We should hire someone to do that for us.
Speaker 0: Like imagine there's a panel It's our panel and then for the first 45 minutes some guy comes out in bullshits and then the cosplay Come out and answer questions very slowly for 15 minutes and then we leave.
Speaker 0: and that was you know I asked them if they ate crab Any to know that.
Speaker 0: I actually you know that I everyone laughed.
Speaker 0: but then I asked them what you know They're.
Speaker 0: the best meal they had was and one guy he ate.
Speaker 0: I forget what the one guy ate but the other guy had like a bagel.
Speaker 0: He thought was really good New York bagel That works Yeah.
Speaker 0: And then we went to the.
Speaker 0: the big thing was right before our panel was the Hatsune Miku panel With the guys from Krypton future media.
Speaker 1: now as always whenever I go to a panel like this Usually the people presenting it even it packs like big game people.
Speaker 1: They really know their stuff and they're important people, but they're really bad at presenting presenting skills.
Speaker 1: Not the grade.
Speaker 0: They basically just read off their PowerPoints, which was pretty sad, but the information they presented was pretty top-notch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they gave us all this stuff.
Speaker 0: We learned about all this shit and I have it pretty much come to the conclusion That these guys the only guys in Japan that I know of so far
Speaker 1: other than maybe project X cup noodle Yeah
Speaker 0: that knows what the fuck is up in terms of like business models for the 21st.
Speaker 0: but here's why.
Speaker 1: here's why thank.
Speaker 0: the whole world can learn from these guys and the reason is is because they're Programmers.
Speaker 1: I was about to say they're technologists.
Speaker 0: They know that they said open source like 20 times During their panel because they know.
Speaker 1: anyone who knows technology kind of has these obvious things.
Speaker 1: The only difference is they decided to actually pursue a business.
Speaker 0: Yeah Look the number.
Speaker 0: this guy was in charge of the company.
Speaker 0: number one guy.
Speaker 0: number one President founder of Krypton future media and he was a programmer.
Speaker 0: He was he wasn't a businessman.
Speaker 0: He wasn't an animator not a businessman.
Speaker 0: He wasn't entrenched in any old ways, you know And he understands open source and Linux and everything.
Speaker 0: And if you look this is why even you know, their Hatsune Miku character is so open source, right?
Speaker 0: They know what's up.
Speaker 0: They understand creative commons and free culture and that is why they are kicking everyone's ass so hard right, and they don't even have an anime or a manga Reno really and You know, meanwhile, they're just completely dominating.
Speaker 0: You know Miku is like taking over the whole world.
Speaker 1: Yeah there were like seven Hatsune Miku cosplayers at the panel and then a whole bunch more people cosplaying as other characters from the program
Speaker 0: and the panel was packed and they presented a whole bunch of really impressive statistics and You know, I could go on and on and on but they were.
Speaker 0: they were awesome dudes and I asked him what the first computer He had was.
Speaker 0: it was like an Apple LC 2 or whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah What made me really happy though was that it seemed like the interest in the panel.
Speaker 1: Like I was worried that people showing up the panel were gonna be fangirls caring about.
Speaker 1: you know The the videos people have made or the music or the character.
Speaker 1: But most of the people in the panel seemed primarily interested in getting a hold of the program in English and making stuff Yeah, and I think it bodes well for the future because what is it that we think makes gaming cons so much better than anime Cons?
Speaker 1: by and large the creator culture or at least the participate Participatory culture?
Speaker 0: the thing is the anime and comic cons of the artists alley and the gaming cons do not have that.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: They don't have the the anime cons of the physic the physical space for that culture to live and the gaming cons don't.
Speaker 1: Every time I talk to keel I'm like.
Speaker 1: so we're gonna get an artist Elliot packs We're gonna get an artist Elliot packs.
Speaker 1: Come on.
Speaker 1: We'll do it.
Speaker 1: Let's do it.
Speaker 0: Go go go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right We'll see.
Speaker 0: I think you'd need to talk to Dave though to get that one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what's his name?
Speaker 0: I how are?
Speaker 1: yeah Kehil and you know pork fry and all the people that helped us do that.
Speaker 1: that thing we did That we did.
Speaker 1: that was bad that we may not ever do again.
Speaker 1: We do it again.
Speaker 1: It'll be like a moth turning into a butterfly.
Speaker 1: No, a better moth.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so after that we did our panel which Was a panel.
Speaker 1: it was not the pan I want to talk about it though because we didn't plan to do that panel.
Speaker 1: We were gonna.
Speaker 1: we had all these other panel plans and then as the con got more and more Commercial and they brought more and more professionals doing their kind of you know I'm a professional who doesn't know how to present were very well panels.
Speaker 1: We cut it down to just one and then the one panel he wanted us to do was not even one I offered Yeah, I gave you.
Speaker 1: I had this list of.
Speaker 1: alright if we just want to do one Here are the three like awesome ones.
Speaker 1: pick one and they're like, why don't you do this one anime?
Speaker 1: You never thought you'd like.
Speaker 1: and I'm like, that's actually a two-hour screening That's not really a panel.
Speaker 1: and they were like, can you do a panel called that?
Speaker 1: and I was like, yeah I can do that and we threw it together and it was really popular.
Speaker 1: It was anime.
Speaker 0: You should see with a slightly different list of anime.
Speaker 1: Actually.
Speaker 1: It was about 75% different anime and we approached it from a side with a different list of anime, but we presented slightly different.
Speaker 0: We presented it in the same manner.
Speaker 1: Sort of we did.
Speaker 1: at least this was a panel.
Speaker 1: That was nothing more than an excuse to show.
Speaker 0: No, we always have the show.
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: No, I feel like we should show that in every panel We ever do.
Speaker 0: it was great because I'm like, I'm gonna show Oh No But I saw it like the fifth row on the right.
Speaker 0: There was like a lady with her kids and the kids looked like they were six or eight.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I'm like, I'm gonna show Oh No, and I'm like, well this is the North Star is for eight-year-olds in Japan.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I was looking at the same woman the whole time I was like and then she and then when Oh No happened she was laughing.
Speaker 0: I was like the mom was like hysterical.
Speaker 0: I was like, that's right.
Speaker 0: You can't withhold the power of the Oh No I'm glad we're on the same wavelength because those on kite can defeats all.
Speaker 1: because when we were doing the panel I said fuck just in the course of doing the panel and I immediately realized wait a minute and I noticed them and I was Like, oh, all right.
Speaker 1: I got a how we gonna do this and I'm glad that we at least had the same secret concern.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I always have that slight concern.
Speaker 0: Not that You know, not that I care about offending anyone depends.
Speaker 0: I just don't want.
Speaker 0: I just don't want them to complain to the convention.
Speaker 1: No, it depends on the con.
Speaker 1: I mean remember when someone complained about our rape glorification.
Speaker 0: exactly It's like I don't care about if I if I actually do a rape glorification panel I just don't want someone to complain to the convention about me.
Speaker 1: I kind of do because that gets attention Negative yeah, but you know this depends on the con like packs.
Speaker 1: if someone complained about us swearing at a panel What do you think?
Speaker 0: He'll is gonna say he's gonna say what they swear at the Q&A What the fuck is what he's gonna say.
Speaker 1: But the cool thing was hardly anyone at the panel knew who we were which meant there are people who are still fans of anime Even though I think the majority of the people at this con were comic or Hollywood fans and they were not anime fans.
Speaker 0: Someone wrote a great article that they put up today on their blog.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll get the link for it right.
Speaker 0: pretty much talking about the anime ghetto right and I was sort of 50/50 on it is the one thing is The con had the big expo Hall area and in the expo Hall area was all the dealers of and all the exhibitors Right, but they were segregated.
Speaker 0: so like in the back right corner was selling plastic toys in like the pop cult zone and in the front right area was all The guys selling old dusty comic books and in the front left was all like the big boos from big companies.
Speaker 1: They made it way too easy to just go to the parts You cared about and not see random.
Speaker 0: in the middle was like the comic publishers that you know Weren't Marvel in DC and in the you know And all the anime people were in sort of the middle right in the back.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't mix it up.
Speaker 1: I would have been like guy with a rage spider-man guy with swords guy with yeah I mean sci-fi continuum was actually in the middle left sort of on its own.
Speaker 0: there I was like, yes, I have a continuum good spot Selling good stuff best dealer at every anime.
Speaker 0: con can't lose course part of the trouble about some lone wolf and cub volumes.
Speaker 1: What anime dealers are there that are left?
Speaker 1: I mean all the anime stuff.
Speaker 0: that was anime castle anime pavilion.
Speaker 1: What they're selling?
Speaker 1: they're selling the same The same job is or or they've got Mangas I say cheap DVDs because the DVDs No one in the dealer's room could beat Amazon by even within not even the six dollar DVD booth.
Speaker 1: Are you kidding the six dollar DVD booth?
Speaker 0: I found some of the stuff for like two bucks on Amazon, but they had like He had like Ghostbusters one and two together for six bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I already own that.
Speaker 0: and they had like all of She-Ra all of it six bucks.
Speaker 1: All right I'll clarify there were some good deals on non anime.
Speaker 0: Okay, but anime, okay They didn't have any anime at the six dollar DVD booth.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was no anime.
Speaker 0: and that con as far as I could tell that was Continuum had there, you know, you can get all of Pat LeVoir for like, you know, 60 bucks total.
Speaker 1: That's like three separate boxes and look how much it is online.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah about the same.
Speaker 1: I was walking around with my smartphone for like an hour and I couldn't find a single deal anyway.
Speaker 0: And then they had like it because there was construction going on at the Javits.
Speaker 0: So that was the expo area.
Speaker 0: Then they had another area.
Speaker 0: That was the comic artists alley the sort of You know exhibitors that aren't really exhibitors like the podcasters and some other folks.
Speaker 1: or I guess Tally was cool But a little sad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then there was like a variant stage which is just the annoying stage.
Speaker 1: Oh my god Did not want to be anywhere near that thing, you know Jedis and that sort of shit they had that by the by the maid cafe.
Speaker 0: No, that was not the very no.
Speaker 0: I'm saying that was the maid stay.
Speaker 1: I know what I'm saying is in the maid cafe.
Speaker 1: There was another stage just like that.
Speaker 0: That was just no It wasn't just like.
Speaker 0: it was completely different.
Speaker 0: In fact, they're annoying people yelling on it.
Speaker 0: Okay, the variant stage has a schedule right and there's actually the groups that are on the variant stage Scheduled to be on there like, you know The Mario Bueno guy and the Jedi's and all those people.
Speaker 0: the maid stage is just whatever the fuck.
Speaker 0: I think you can just go up there and sing and do whatever you want every time.
Speaker 0: Schedule for it.
Speaker 1: There were the same people running game shows up there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they just decided to do that.
Speaker 1: So what I'm saying is they were equal from a from a fan perspective walking around the con.
Speaker 1: they were equally annoying Mainly because they were way too loud.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the thing was is I think that the impressions Is that is that people think that these stages are popular and that's why they keep them.
Speaker 0: But the fact is people are sitting near these stages because that's the only place this.
Speaker 0: tables and chairs.
Speaker 1: Yep if you know if you had tables and chairs away from all this sad moment in the anime ghetto where someone's trying to work up The crowd and literally no one there is saying anything.
Speaker 1: They're like facing away like sitting at their table reading comics.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they just wanted a place to sit which happens to be near this annoying stage You know.
Speaker 0: and while the people on the stage love the stage people sitting near the stage.
Speaker 0: Nobody gives a shit To go.
Speaker 1: I want to do.
Speaker 1: if packs ever had like an artist alley equivalent like a beat bring your own awesome room.
Speaker 0: They do it.
Speaker 1: I want there to be a stage in that room.
Speaker 0: They have many stages of packs.
Speaker 0: They have the mode mostly musical though.
Speaker 0: You can go to the the you know, the magfest room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I want a generic stage and they have the rock band stage.
Speaker 1: I want the stage where some weirdos gonna get up there and do something weird and questionable.
Speaker 0: So you go and they could just be a sign-up sheet and you sign up and you get ten minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah period for set up and everything and that's it.
Speaker 1: I think that'd be cool.
Speaker 0: the ten minute sign-up stage.
Speaker 0: you get up there you get ten minutes do whatever you want You can give it you can get a soapbox it you can do whatever.
Speaker 1: um one victory from the con.
Speaker 1: We did our when we did our panel, right?
Speaker 1: We did the woo game thing and we tricked.
Speaker 1: You know We people did woo.
Speaker 1: we give him the woo game and for the first time ever the crowd listened and I realized the problem.
Speaker 1: If you stop the woo game No one was reacting to anything for the rep Like the second half of the panel other than this one guy on the front who was basically breaking his nose Trying to show me that he knew all the anime.
Speaker 1: he was cool But there was like no visual feedback at all.
Speaker 1: And then at the very end of the panel when everyone was like that was awesome.
Speaker 1: That was awesome.
Speaker 1: I was like, oh we didn't bomb it cuz everyone just said you guys I could tell when I'm doing.
Speaker 0: I don't see.
Speaker 0: the thing is for a panel like that.
Speaker 0: I don't even need the audience reaction anymore to know if it's doing and if I'm doing it right or doing it wrong.
Speaker 1: We will prove that we got to do it on video.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's your video.
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 0: The only other thing is so the anime right.
Speaker 0: so there was the main expo area.
Speaker 0: It was the sort of secondary expo area with the gigantic awesome comic artists alley the autographs the variant stage and the podcast errors and whatnot.
Speaker 0: And then there was the comic panel area which is down into the right which all the comic-con panels were in this ghetto hallway.
Speaker 0: That was pretty much empty.
Speaker 0: the whole that was.
Speaker 1: I went there Sunday.
Speaker 1: I have some videos I grabbed.
Speaker 1: It was very early empty.
Speaker 1: There were maybe 50 people spread out through that entire area.
Speaker 0: comic people were not interested in going to panels.
Speaker 0: But I think there were like a few incredibly famous people panels that yeah I saw.
Speaker 1: some of those got a big crowd and then I saw a lot of them were like Person like semi-famous person or comic arts or something doing a panel and there was there's.
Speaker 1: there was no one in those rooms Maybe like five or ten people.
Speaker 1: they were all pretty much empty.
Speaker 1: well And if you walked all the way down to the back I don't think anyone even knew there were panel rooms over there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those are hidden panel rooms.
Speaker 1: I saw three panels on Sunday in that hallway that had panelists sitting on stage.
Speaker 1: their panels had been quote unquote going for like 20 Minutes and there was no one in the audience.
Speaker 1: They were just sitting there.
Speaker 0: That was the comic-con panels, but and they had another areas the anime area.
Speaker 1: Yeah, our panel was like full.
Speaker 1: Close the door.
Speaker 0: they had an anime artists alley which I'm sort of for and against.
Speaker 0: right because it's like on the one hand you Can't charge the girl with the bookmarks the same money You're charging the comic people which is a lot of money, right?
Speaker 0: So put them in the same table and it would be unfair to put them at the same tables in the same area and charge different amounts.
Speaker 0: But Right on the other hand.
Speaker 0: It's unfair to sort of put them in this ghetto, you know far away from all the action.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing.
Speaker 1: if I were one of those anime people and I knew I could do well I would have just gotten a table with a comic-con instead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it'll cost too much.
Speaker 0: They can't afford it.
Speaker 0: It wouldn't be economically feasible for them.
Speaker 0: You know some high school girl, whatever the other thing was is like You know, they sort of hid the anime people away.
Speaker 0: Yeah The only people who saw any of that anime stuff were people who sought it out on purpose and most people just like didn't go Down there at all.
Speaker 0: and even people I knew who sort of wanted to get like a mixed experience And see everything and get an idea for it didn't go down there because it was a ghetto and they just didn't end up going Down there because it was out of the way in another place.
Speaker 0: and really you got to mix it up.
Speaker 0: You know, the thing is what's the point of you know, this segregation, you know?
Speaker 0: Mix it all up so that people end up being forced to experience all this different stuff.
Speaker 0: That's what it's all about.
Speaker 1: I think the trouble is and this is where why Pax is such an example.
Speaker 1: I know we always harp on how awesome Pax.
Speaker 0: They got the tabletop and the video games and it's all mix.
Speaker 1: Oh, but not just that.
Speaker 1: I have a very particular and specific point because Pax is this third way.
Speaker 1: We've got one way the Otacon way, which is we're fans.
Speaker 1: The industry will never be the boss of us.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do everything, you know in a kind of unprofessional way Internally, like we're all just fans.
Speaker 1: No professionals.
Speaker 1: No industry.
Speaker 1: Tell us what to do and you all know the problems that causes.
Speaker 1: the exact opposite side of that is the ultra professional Only really doing it for the money and what the industry wants which is mostly what the New York Comic Con anime festival was.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the third way is what Pax is doing which is in the middle.
Speaker 1: They're saying they've made themselves to the point where the industry needs them.
Speaker 1: They don't need the industry because the people would go to that con if there were zero industry and it was just people playing games Yep, and I feel like.
Speaker 1: but at the same time while they're a fan convention really they run the convention in a professional manner Yes, and like if anime cons ran themselves internally like professionals if they acted like adult professionals Even if they still told the industry to fuck itself They would be awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that third way is the way to go and Pax is the only convention I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: Magfest might be closed But Magfest is kind of.
Speaker 0: we've never been to Magfest.
Speaker 0: We don't know what it's like.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're just going based on the culture of it, which is similar to our culture.
Speaker 0: We don't actually know how it's run.
Speaker 1: We'll find out.
Speaker 1: I'm excited about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's gonna.
Speaker 0: it's probably a good party, but I feel four days.
Speaker 1: but I feel like the New York Comic Con New York anime festival combined is Really harmed by the fact that if you look at where the money is and you chart the money based on who was Important Hollywood.
Speaker 1: Yes the top of like the top of the comic-con hierarchy is Hollywood and under that is Big comic people like Stan Lee, you know I love on DC and under that is the indie comics and under that is old-school comics.
Speaker 1: under that is like Gaming.
Speaker 1: cuz Watsy was there.
Speaker 1: They had a little thing.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah the whole area under that is Professional anime industry.
Speaker 1: under that is fan done anime stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's you know, it was sort of you know, I would have rather had the con be all mix.
Speaker 0: You know have mix all the panel rooms together.
Speaker 0: be like, okay in this room It's gonna be Stan Lee at 10 followed by Riven Scott followed by a showing of some anime followed by indie comics company followed by Vamps I guess all in the same room.
Speaker 1: I guess my worry is that and my guess is that the anime convention will never go away the anime aspect of it But it will not grow and if anything it is only there.
Speaker 0: it was already not growing.
Speaker 1: That's why they merged it I know and I think it's only going to exist in that ghetto forever and it's only going to be there to.
Speaker 1: you know All I've noticed that there's the same group of people like anime fans that go to every single anime related thing in New York.
Speaker 1: Yeah Every anime thing.
Speaker 1: they're there and they'll all go to this forever and they don't bother with the comic-con stuff and the comic-con doesn't bother With them.
Speaker 1: Yep, kind of sad.
Speaker 0: It's gonna.
Speaker 0: it's a way to easily up the numbers, you know They put in a tiny little artists alley They put in some panel rooms and they get a whole.
Speaker 0: they get all that.
Speaker 0: You know time people coming in.
Speaker 1: there was one good panel that had a bunch of audience at the comic-con area on Sunday.
Speaker 0: What was it?
Speaker 1: It was the kind of panel that we would do or that an anime person would do.
Speaker 0: who was doing it?
Speaker 1: if they were?
Speaker 1: I Don't even know but if you were doing like at an anime con they did the archaeology of Indiana Jones.
Speaker 1: Oh interesting like how you know, what was feasible?
Speaker 1: What wasn't?
Speaker 1: where'd all these legends come from?
Speaker 1: What would you know?
Speaker 1: What did they use and not you?
Speaker 0: it was really well done.
Speaker 1: I like that Yeah, and it was packed nice.
Speaker 1: and yet that was.
Speaker 1: that was not the average panel in the comic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, most of the comic panel areas were we're a company.
Speaker 1: We're gonna make our announcements and They looked like we're a company.
Speaker 1: We're doing this panels that we can then say in a press release that we did this panel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what it seemed like as no one was in those panels.
Speaker 1: So anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: this guy made a shrubbery shaped like a cock and balls and he got in trouble with the law.
Speaker 0: That's it You must give us.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty good cock and balls - So this guy he's.
Speaker 0: he works at Sega.
Speaker 0: his name is Jerry.
Speaker 0: he got married to some hot lady named cat And their cake for their wedding was shaped like the macross, however, it was not just shaped like the macross.
Speaker 0: They also made recreated a scene from macross the.
Speaker 0: you know The wedding flight is the scene that is recreated for.
Speaker 0: therefore their wedding They recreated an anime wedding in cake and plastic model.
Speaker 1: That's pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, look at that not bad.
Speaker 0: So If you if you are a woman and if you're imagining a wedding involving this cake marry me.
Speaker 0: you will have this cake.
Speaker 0: It will happen.
Speaker 1: So very briefly met a moment.
Speaker 1: We'll be at magfest.
Speaker 1: We'll be in anime Boston.
Speaker 1: We'll be at PAX East book club.
Speaker 1: is World War Z.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: Any other metas?
Speaker 1: now, let's get right on because I want to talk about our show.
Speaker 0: All right Well, it's what's your show?
Speaker 1: So our show the anime we watch.
Speaker 1: we're gonna review it.
Speaker 1: It's something I don't think many of you have seen and the subtitles that I watched were translated from Russian to English.
Speaker 0: Well, that's because this anime was actually a Russian Japanese co-production in 1969. that's really really old like way old.
Speaker 1: and guess who did the key animation?
Speaker 0: Well, one of the people did the key animation was Miyazaki in 69.
Speaker 0: He was animating this movie and the thing is it's only a 60-minute movie, which is kind of.
Speaker 0: it's kind of nice, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you get an anime movie.
Speaker 0: They don't have to wait 90 minutes.
Speaker 0: You only gotta wait 60 minutes.
Speaker 0: It's over.
Speaker 1: It might have been nice had it been better.
Speaker 1: Oh snap so The flying ghost ship is literally about a flying ghost ship.
Speaker 0: really you don't say it's.
Speaker 1: They started out and you expect it to follow this certain kind of vibe.
Speaker 0: right in the beginning It was sort of Hardy Boys sort of Johnny Quest sort of Scooby Doo, right?
Speaker 0: You know, there's a kid on a boat with his parents and he's got a dog.
Speaker 0: The dog doesn't talk but it has a lot of personality.
Speaker 1: now now this dog is basically Scooby.
Speaker 1: It's Scooby Doo, but it doesn't talk and the kid Hayato is even wearing a goddamn ascot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know he's not it's not Scooby Doo cuz he doesn't talk but it is might as well be right and the kid is basically Fred.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, but none of the other Scooby cast is in it It's just him know.
Speaker 1: so Hayato is on the boat with his family and this gets into space.
Speaker 0: crabs in the end Don't play you skipping and spoiling the crab people That's not.
Speaker 1: that's not the spoiler the spoilers.
Speaker 1: who was running the crab people?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so anyway, they see a car crash right and they go to investigate.
Speaker 0: now that way and his eight people?
Speaker 1: now Here's where it gets crazy.
Speaker 1: so Hayato is just on the boat with his dad and everything's all cool and Everyone likes to hold their mouths open for a way long time after they stopped talking.
Speaker 0: They also like to sense because it was Russian mouth movements.
Speaker 1: But they also when they're just like they're not talking and a character just kind of looking at something Their mouth is usually open and their brows furrowed.
Speaker 1: They make the look that someone who is dumb and angry makes.
Speaker 1: I Wasn't looking that close and they make this.
Speaker 1: they basically look like this all the time But like it kind of looks like the guy in that one Perry Bible Fellowship with the scar-eyed shark and he figures it out.
Speaker 1: They all kind of make that face.
Speaker 1: now Jack has this bag and they never really explain the dog.
Speaker 0: Jack's the dog.
Speaker 1: Jack the dog Has this bag and he's got all his stuff in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they don't really explain it Like we let in the beginning.
Speaker 0: the subtitle is like we let you hold the bag But then throughout the rest of the movie, it's pretty much just like it's they make.
Speaker 0: it's sort of like it's the dog's bag.
Speaker 0: It belongs to him Yeah, and he keeps all the points in it his doggy stuff in the bag and it's just a thing He has.
Speaker 0: they don't really explain why or how it's got.
Speaker 0: I like the idea of like Especially that one part where he sort of whips it around his neck, you know, that was a key.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's like.
Speaker 1: he's like I'm courage dog now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's go.
Speaker 1: So but they see a car accident, right?
Speaker 1: They're on a boat and this car just flies off a cliff like a hundred feet up and crashes upside down.
Speaker 0: They go and investigate and it's the boss of the company the dads works for.
Speaker 0: that's like if I work for Microsoft and I saw A car crash.
Speaker 0: I go and investigate.
Speaker 0: It's Bill Gates.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's mr.
Speaker 1: Kuro.
Speaker 0: She is Steve bomber.
Speaker 1: Oh shit I thought it was Kuro Shiro, but no, she is Kuro Shiro.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz Emily was like black white.
Speaker 1: What kind of name is that?
Speaker 0: Like Pinocchio?
Speaker 1: Yep, but so the car crashed like a hundred feet up this cliff and a boat and They just scale free climb this sheer cliff.
Speaker 1: No problem Get to the car.
Speaker 1: fat dude is just unconscious in the upside-down car.
Speaker 1: Then it cuts to them up another hundred feet having dragged the dude somehow.
Speaker 1: they don't show you that That was a great digital target moment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and always wife's with them too.
Speaker 1: They just forget about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they get both of them up there somehow and what are they gonna do?
Speaker 1: The mom went off in the boat to call the police and they're like, well, we'll just wait for mom.
Speaker 1: Let's go into this spooky haunted looking mansion.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, it's obviously really giving you a scooby-doo vibe now, right?
Speaker 0: So you got a kid his dog his dad a mystery of a car crash and especially curse.
Speaker 1: It was like I crashed.
Speaker 0: Well, his wife a strange coincidence and a haunted house.
Speaker 1: He's like I crash.
Speaker 0: and because of that skeleton in the road Yeah, and you're like, oh man, this is scooby-doo the anime.
Speaker 0: Fuck.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I was kind of a dick.
Speaker 1: though He's like, what do you mean?
Speaker 1: a skeleton in the road the fuck's wrong with.
Speaker 0: actually I kind of like that cuz it showed the characters weren't moronic right?
Speaker 0: the scooby-doo people would be like a go You know shaggy like oh my god a ghost.
Speaker 0: and it's like dude.
Speaker 0: You've seen a hundred people take off ghost masks and you still think it's actually gonna be a ghost.
Speaker 0: this time At least this kid Hayato is just like a ghost.
Speaker 0: really sometimes they did.
Speaker 0: I'm eight years old I don't believe in that shit.
Speaker 1: Sometimes they take the mask off and it's red herring.
Speaker 0: That's wrong show that's Canon.
Speaker 0: it's not canon because it happens away in the future.
Speaker 1: now the funny thing is when they're on the boat in the beginning It's canon.
Speaker 1: if they age like Merlin They have this weird shot where they show his mom like look at this perfect smiling mom and that reeked of she's totally gonna die.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, she totally dies.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so they get into the spooky mansion and it's full of like Ravens and just crazy.
Speaker 1: It's totally spooky all over the place on purpose and everyone's afraid and they lay everybody down and then immediately What do they do?
Speaker 1: The dad's like let's split up.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go get firewood.
Speaker 1: you guys wander around.
Speaker 0: So they wander around and investigate.
Speaker 1: they leave courage.
Speaker 1: Oh just laying on the couch unconscious still.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like he's gonna wake up and empty in this empty scary house.
Speaker 0: He'll think he's in hell or some shit You don't know anyway or think he's been kidnapped.
Speaker 1: Oh remember when the wife first wakes up on the road and she's like lightning strikes and she sees the dad's face and she's like For no reason and then she's like, oh, oh, it's just a guy just a dude.
Speaker 0: That's a dude.
Speaker 0: Alright, let's uh, so they investigate and of course they find a skeleton Rooting through the fridge a guy in a skeleton mask.
Speaker 0: No clearly living in the fridge.
Speaker 1: It must be a real skeleton.
Speaker 1: Yeah real skeletons go in fridges all the time, but it's rooted in the fridge and The way they were they literally walk into the room and there's a guy rooting through the fridge.
Speaker 1: they tap on the back he turns around skeleton face and it just cuts between the skeletons face and The mom's face.
Speaker 0: Well, no the the what the wife the wife of Kuroshio's face.
Speaker 1: and there is this like 30-second scene where she makes all these different faces, but doesn't scream.
Speaker 1: She's like And then she screams.
Speaker 0: yeah, like it is hilarious I basically showed every state and then the animation in this isn't?
Speaker 0: you know There's no music to speak of.
Speaker 0: really right and the animation is pretty like, you know The drawing and the colors are actually pretty good for 69, but the animation is a lot of panning.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of You know still shot with the moving mouth, you know, there's a lot of back, you know You know the water just goes wish wish wish wish back and forth.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of times where like a particular like movement is really really well animated and everything else is just completely static.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like the dog whips the bag around his neck is really well animated but at the background
Speaker 1: The wife screaming because you know angry video game nerd James Rolfe is doing his monster madness right now and in old 50s horror movies It's a common trope for a woman to you know The heroine to run into like a skeleton face like in the screaming skull and not scream right away But just like stare in increasing shock and then scream and pass out.
Speaker 1: Yep, and that is what she does but the way it is animated.
Speaker 1: I was laughing so hard it hurts Like I couldn't deal with it.
Speaker 0: So then the this after they run away from that the dad comes back with a firewood and then eventually the police show up But before the police.
Speaker 1: no, no, no, the police don't show up before
Speaker 0: the police All right, but yeah the
Speaker 1: chief of defense for the country shows up, but
Speaker 0: before he shows up Basically the goat does the skeleton haunts them and scares them and tells them spooky mess Which was
Speaker 1: good because up until that point they forget about that skeleton pretty quick.
Speaker 1: They run away and the dad's like hey Hey, and then the skeleton shows up and it's like, oh you're bad There's a good series of scares where they get back and they're there.
Speaker 1: They're like, oh my god, there was a skeleton and then something's coming.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's the dogs the thing You know, it's the dead.
Speaker 1: something's coming.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's the skeleton.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is obviously though.
Speaker 0: The skeleton was not real.
Speaker 0: It's totally got a mask, right?
Speaker 0: and it's like how is he scaring them from this window?
Speaker 0: and if the kid throws a rock at the window and breaks the Window and it goes right through the skeleton.
Speaker 1: It's like I want to call bullshit.
Speaker 0: on a later scene later scene They say that he says oh, yeah That was using a projector onto the glass.
Speaker 0: then shouldn't the part of the glass that was broken made?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know made part of the skeleton disappear, but it didn't.
Speaker 1: but the ghost is like, ooh I'm a spooky ghost.
Speaker 1: I was murdered.
Speaker 1: I was left on a boat and burned by someone And then the cops come.
Speaker 1: he's like I gotta go.
Speaker 0: now The cops are coming.
Speaker 0: I Yeah, ha all the cops, you know if I can bust out and goes never do that.
Speaker 1: But then as soon as the chief of defense comes curse, he was like, yeah that guy's back.
Speaker 1: We got to do something about this ghost ship.
Speaker 0: So you immediately know that The red herring girl she was a bad guy.
Speaker 1: So then the movie just kind of picks up with the kid and his family just doing the normal stuff like dad and kid are In a car in the city and then a robot attacks the town.
Speaker 0: Yeah out of nowhere a giant robot attacks the city and smashes the fuck out of everything.
Speaker 0: It's like what.
Speaker 0: what the hell did that have to do with scooby-doo?
Speaker 0: suddenly scooby-doo is over.
Speaker 0: It's astro boy time, but the lead-up to this is awesome.
Speaker 1: There's like five full minutes of the kid being like I like to drink boa juice And he's like you shouldn't drink so much of that.
Speaker 1: and then they're just talking about mom and talking about stuff It's like.
Speaker 1: But they kind of goes down like it's a weird.
Speaker 1: they say it funny but they use that.
Speaker 1: I think they showed this on TV and actually use those as the commercial brakes.
Speaker 1: Maybe I don't know I wouldn't be surprised anyway But then then suddenly your traffic's been stopped for a long time like they're stuck in traffic and normally in a show.
Speaker 1: That's just kind of like you.
Speaker 1: don't worry about that in this.
Speaker 1: after a while The dad's like, you know The traffic hasn't moved in a while and then immediately fucking tanks destroy every goddamn car on the road.
Speaker 0: Yeah the tank the tanks that which are people are driving them trying to help save the town from the robot.
Speaker 0: the Military in the tank doesn't care about killing people and then they fail to kill the robot.
Speaker 1: but it's great.
Speaker 1: The tanks just crush all these cars probably kill a whole bunch of people and then they just start shooting and then the camera spins Around and you see they're shooting at some building.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, that's not a building It's a giant robot.
Speaker 1: and then golem the robot says I am golem the robot the robot who was sent to destroy you by the Ghost ship.
Speaker 1: I am golem goes robot.
Speaker 0: So golem is working for the ghost ship and to destroy the town and the military is fighting back.
Speaker 0: And you haven't even seen the ghost ship yet, so all you know is the title is flying ghost ship.
Speaker 0: So it's like why would the ghost ship that I don't even know about Anything where it's comes from or anything about it send a robot to destroy the town?
Speaker 1: and the robot isn't using missiles or heat get Erase or anything.
Speaker 1: He just has two big mace fists and he's just fucking smashing stuff, but he's gigantic.
Speaker 0: He's bigger than a skyscraper.
Speaker 1: So he is smashing shit up big time and they show you you're pretty sure the body count on this Movie is astronaut.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure most of the people in the world are dead.
Speaker 0: if that was New York City like Millions are dead millions of people would have been killed in that robot attack and they actually do a somewhat Astro-boyish job of portraying the fact that all these people actually did die.
Speaker 0: It was a horrible massacre catastrophe that spanned many miles in many bodies.
Speaker 1: The dead is pretty smart because he you know, he gets hit on the head and it sounds like I'll take you to the hospital.
Speaker 1: He's like the hospital.
Speaker 1: Are you kidding?
Speaker 1: Let's just go home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and Sure enough home smashed mom's dead.
Speaker 1: And thus this is why Leiji Matsumoto is a brilliant brilliant man because when he wants to do melodrama He has motherfucking melodrama up in your business and you cannot help but get caught up in his melodrama moment.
Speaker 0: That's right this movie.
Speaker 1: The kid is sitting there crying over his dead mom and it's a great scene and the man for many minutes He is just screaming.
Speaker 1: Why did you die?
Speaker 1: Why did you leave me?
Speaker 1: Very melodramatic.
Speaker 1: Then his dad is like, how's mom is she gonna make it and he's like mom just died.
Speaker 1: And then the dad's like I'm gonna die soon, too But you're not my son.
Speaker 1: and then the dad dies and then there's double melodrama and it's like mom dies dad dies.
Speaker 1: You're not my son all at once.
Speaker 1: No, Matt, no elegance or mastery was used in this melodrama.
Speaker 0: None whatsoever.
Speaker 0: It immediately goes off.
Speaker 0: I didn't care at all.
Speaker 1: I was like, okay The mom death was sad.
Speaker 0: the mom didn't even have any lines she was just seemed.
Speaker 0: oh she said she said okay Okay, she was definitely, you know, she was definitely portrayed as a cool mom, but she didn't say anything or do anything.
Speaker 1: She said okay when his dad said go behind the police in the boat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right But it was literally like he's crying over his mom.
Speaker 1: He's crying over his dad and then it cuts to him standing by himself on top of the ruins of his house with the dog Looking all melodramatic and hopeful and sad and everything.
Speaker 1: and then he tells the dog he hates it and go away.
Speaker 1: and then he says Never mind.
Speaker 1: I love you dog.
Speaker 1: And it's just all this drama.
Speaker 1: That's going nowhere.
Speaker 0: And then what does he decide to do?
Speaker 0: to go to mr.
Speaker 0: Kuroshio's house the evil head of the company?
Speaker 0: He doesn't know he's evil.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he gets adopted basically.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he like goes gets adopted by mr.
Speaker 0: Kuroshio Cuz.
Speaker 0: he doesn't have anywhere else to go.
Speaker 0: He doesn't have any friends or family or anything.
Speaker 1: They probably all got crushed by the robot and they're like, all right your stepson now, that's cool.
Speaker 0: It's like really I'll go to Bill Gates house if that's gonna work.
Speaker 1: and then immediately golem comes back and attacks the ghost ship.
Speaker 1: and This is when things get awesome.
Speaker 1: because the ghost ship before you see like this like ghost ship floating out in the water.
Speaker 1: It just fucking flies out of the water and has missiles coming out of it and it just fight.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it looks like a really old busted ship like a ghost ship, but it's got really modern missiles and shop coming out of it.
Speaker 0: So obviously inside it's a modern ship.
Speaker 1: I like how they show the same features technologies.
Speaker 1: They show the same missile coming out like a hundred times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So it's like wait a minute.
Speaker 0: I thought golem was working for go ship.
Speaker 0: Why is golem fighting go ship and the kid doesn't know who to root for?
Speaker 0: cuz he's like fuck that evil.
Speaker 0: go ship.
Speaker 0: Wait, fuck that evil golem who killed my parents.
Speaker 0: Wait, what what?
Speaker 1: so of course the kid wanders around in the mansion of Kuroshio who's not around.
Speaker 1: he disappeared somewhere and Finds a room that just has a chair in the middle of it.
Speaker 0: So he sits in this weird room that has a chair and of course It's Batman chair, of course right before it happened.
Speaker 0: It goes to do it.
Speaker 0: It's like you when you want to hide something like that You don't make a room that has a chair in it because that stands out so bad.
Speaker 0: What you do is you take your regular old chair and you have a bus next to it with a secret button.
Speaker 1: even Adam West Batman.
Speaker 1: you had to move the statue to make it appear.
Speaker 0: So I said you had to tilt the bus head push the button and then the bookcase open.
Speaker 1: No This guy has a room as big as our geek night studio with just a chair in the middle of it and nothing else.
Speaker 0: So the kid goes down in the chair and he gets to the bottom and there's another chair.
Speaker 1: I love that.
Speaker 1: so he's like this warrants exploration.
Speaker 0: So he checks out the second chair and that takes him to see the secret evil base.
Speaker 0: We're clearly dr Evil's base.
Speaker 1: clearly they have built a golem because golem comes back to get repaired.
Speaker 0: Why is golem in this base and hit the whole time?
Speaker 1: He's just sitting in the chair not thinking what if I get caught down here?
Speaker 1: What's going on?
Speaker 1: He's thinking he's just trying to figure out the mystery.
Speaker 1: I sure hope we solve this mystery.
Speaker 0: So the best part is that my favorite scene is the one that comes up next.
Speaker 1: Oh my god with the robot justice.
Speaker 0: robot justice.
Speaker 0: so so he goes to the basically takes the chair all the way the end and apparently Kuroshio and the defense minister and all the evil guys are having a meeting and They're yelling at the defense minister because apparently golem failed and golem was the defense minister's idea.
Speaker 0: And this is great because the other people are like listen, they're like listen, dude, your golem idea didn't work.
Speaker 0: You wanted to destroy the city and blame it on golem and have golem blame it on the ghost ship to make everyone hate the Ghost ship, but then you attack the ghost ship, but then you attack the ghost ship But now the whole thing has failed.
Speaker 0: and look what you cost us.
Speaker 0: Your golem was wicked expensive.
Speaker 0: all those, you know, military tanks and airplanes you destroyed with the golem were expensive And the whole time all the city all the city you destroyed and the people you killed.
Speaker 0: it was really expensive.
Speaker 0: They don't care about the morality they care about the expense.
Speaker 0: Right now like your plan totally failed and cost too much money What do you have to say for yourself now?
Speaker 1: The scene was very reminiscent of like the nerve and the sele scenes in Ava except that it was stupid.
Speaker 0: So he's like don't even you don't even get to say anything.
Speaker 0: We know what you're gonna say.
Speaker 1: He just sits there the whole time.
Speaker 0: like So like we're Minister of Defense, we're gonna let this computer.
Speaker 0: this computer knows everything you did.
Speaker 0: It's great.
Speaker 1: He's like we're gonna lose all your sins.
Speaker 0: We're gonna let the computer decide your fate.
Speaker 0: It's like oh my god computer justice.
Speaker 1: and literally he's like slides a punch card through the computer and it just sits there going.
Speaker 0: It's like that episode of the Twilight Zone where there's a computer that tells them how to survive in the post-apocalypse.
Speaker 1: Thank you, Peter.
Speaker 0: The computer is right But then when they find out that it is a computer they smash it and then they fail to live in the post-apocalypse.
Speaker 0: Cuz they didn't listen to the computer.
Speaker 1: Yep But basically it's.
Speaker 1: the scene is long and then the computer stops and it's all quiet for a while and everyone should stare into the defense minister.
Speaker 1: the defense minister is sitting there like And then his chair just gets dumped down.
Speaker 1: he disappears and then they're like, alright and they move on.
Speaker 0: But then the kid is in this room meanwhile watching and the room is a glass floor.
Speaker 0: You can see the ocean.
Speaker 1: But I love how you see the guy's hat just kind of float by in the ocean.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like ah snap He got eaten by the fishes or drowned or whatever some combination of the above.
Speaker 1: but the funniest thing.
Speaker 1: I almost want to make a Dave and Joel tribute here because at one point after they kill the defense minister They're arguing about what to do now and they turn to this one guy on the board.
Speaker 1: They're like you come up with a plan and the guy looks so Japanese and so befuddled.
Speaker 1: There is no way that he is not Tanaka as in the Tanaka of Dave and Joel.
Speaker 0: He's definitely that was Tanaka.
Speaker 1: I feel like you could take Dave and Joel audio and put it over the scene and just make something epic.
Speaker 0: It would be so awesome.
Speaker 1: So the kid is like I gotta tell the world about this and he's mad and he's like Kuroshio killed my dad my mom and my dad It wasn't the ghost ship and he's punching the wall and there's this fucking button on the wall and he accidentally punches the button And sets off the alarms and then he's like, oh no, they must have found out I'm in here somehow
Speaker 0: and then he runs away and he succeeds in running away with no trouble.
Speaker 1: Now does this the rest of this before we?
Speaker 1: because we didn't talk about Certain things yet.
Speaker 1: You remember this movie that our friend Amber made us watch called the stuff.
Speaker 0: I Remember being forced to watch it, but I don't remember it at all.
Speaker 1: The plot of the stuff was a meteor landed and it had this stuff in it that tasted really good.
Speaker 1: So they market and sell it to people and if you eat it Eventually turns into a zombie and then turns you into it.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Well, isn't that the same shit is like Slurm, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, kinda except Slurm didn't turn you into anything.
Speaker 1: It turned you into a big fat Slurm only if you had the special Slurm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, but in the stuff, you know, and the thing is some people figure this out and no one believes them.
Speaker 1: So The movie cuts to Tanaka not Tanaka to Hayato Going to the police being like look I found the secret base and I know we're going me and the police.
Speaker 0: It's like what really the police are not gonna believe that story dude.
Speaker 1: The police are like, yeah, what the fuck?
Speaker 1: So he tries to tell people in the street and they don't care.
Speaker 0: It's a they-live situation.
Speaker 0: It's actually that like the camera angles.
Speaker 0: He actually reminded me of.
Speaker 0: they live like you, you know These people were.
Speaker 0: you know, they ate the bad people and yeah sunglasses on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, one of the guys did have sunglasses.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But then while he's telling these people suddenly one guy melts into goop in the street Randomly and then a whole bunch of other people melt into goop and all these people had bottles of boa juice.
Speaker 0: And it's like obviously the boa juice makes people melt.
Speaker 0: There's a reason.
Speaker 1: they were focusing on boa juice before and it was just like in the stuff and no one's gonna believe him either.
Speaker 1: And then he's freaking out and he's not think he's a boa juice drinker.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he drinks a ton of boa juice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and apparently is for.
Speaker 1: But if we're to believe what the movie has told us today most of the people in the world drink a lot of boa juice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it's basically imagine if coca-cola made you disintegrate into coca-cola.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone's drinking it.
Speaker 1: But he doesn't have time to react to this because he's immediately picked up by these yakuza looking dude clamps That were sent by Kuroshio to bring him back.
Speaker 1: He's like, oh no curse you knows I broke in.
Speaker 0: The thing is these guys bring him back and what do they do?
Speaker 0: and it's like they're acting all evil like mugsy and bugsy.
Speaker 0: They're gonna take him back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we caught you kid and it's like oh shit.
Speaker 0: He got caught.
Speaker 0: They just bring him to go beep on TV.
Speaker 0: It's like what?
Speaker 0: So obviously Kuroshio doesn't know this kid knows anything because he just wants to put him on TV to talk about how evil the ghost Ship is.
Speaker 0: because you know He thought he thinks the kids still upset about having his parents being killed by golem in the ghost And this is the best Astro Boy moment of the entire.
Speaker 1: but it's like why did you send thugs?
Speaker 0: We're all evil to get him.
Speaker 0: It should have just been Kuroshio.
Speaker 1: Like hey, let's go the TV piece I think the Simpsons gives us precedence for that when there's knock-knock.
Speaker 1: Who's there?
Speaker 1: goons goons who hired goons?
Speaker 1: And then, you know burns bring, you know, they bring him in and he's just like a hired goons.
Speaker 1: That's what I said, like should I have sent something else?
Speaker 1: Yeah, how would I?
Speaker 1: how else am I gonna get you to come?
Speaker 1: Yeah, right exactly I mean hired goons are probably all this guy has cuz.
Speaker 1: he is really really evil really.
Speaker 1: But this is an Astro Boy moment because the guys like what do you do to fight the ghost ship?
Speaker 1: If you like we let you like and it's just TV shows on TV.
Speaker 0: He's on world TV like everyone can see him and the kid is like.
Speaker 1: Well, then of course use the evil guy.
Speaker 1: I saw it.
Speaker 1: the secret bases under.
Speaker 0: he tells the entire story all the ultra rare Beams are spilled and then they then they interrupt him with some boa juice commercials.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the message non-stop message already got out and there's all these scenes of people watching the TV going.
Speaker 0: but the problem here is the movie at this point explodes because Boa was watching that Boa Boa was watching.
Speaker 0: So now basically you don't realize, you know Kuroshio was only the the regular boss.
Speaker 0: Boa was the square boss.
Speaker 0: So Boa is like, oh shit.
Speaker 0: Now the whole world knows I exist.
Speaker 0: Well time to fight back.
Speaker 0: So immediately Gigantic robot crabs that were apparently hiding in the walls of everything appear everywhere.
Speaker 0: I don't know how they were hiding without anyone noticing them.
Speaker 0: They were gigantic robot crabs, but the giant robot crab people appear everywhere in the whole world all at once also Big blue lobsters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the blue lobsters and the red crabs everywhere They're robots and they freaking attack and they disintegrate Kuroshio pretty quick.
Speaker 1: They pick him up and the voice comes like and it's like I am Boa.
Speaker 1: What the fuck dude.
Speaker 0: You totally Kuroshio You have fucked up.
Speaker 0: you are now disintegrated.
Speaker 1: and then he spit some bubbles on him Which I guess are boa juice and turns them into boa juice super concentrated boa juice.
Speaker 1: So the kid runs away and there's panic everywhere and by this point I'm pretty sure he's about to get killed by the crabs.
Speaker 0: But then finally the flying ghost ship comes in and rescues.
Speaker 1: if I had to summarize how Stupid and crazy this movie is the scene where he is saved by the ghost ship.
Speaker 1: the ghost ship Which looks like a radio chip is just floating over the city with like a beam Pulling him into the body UFO.
Speaker 1: and then they pull him on and they're like, we're the ghost ship We're fighting Boa Boa's evil.
Speaker 1: Let's show you the ship and diagram and the blueprints and tell you about all the things in the ship that we're gonna use in The rest of the movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was totally like, you know a diagram of Mazinger Enumerate the powers of the ghost shit.
Speaker 1: I've got a laser on the front and an EMG on the back and I've got a radar blocker and a wave motion gun The the skeleton.
Speaker 1: yeah dude in a mask he's like, yeah, I wear a mask as my face was burned.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you just suddenly like the guy with the skeleton mask is the captain of the ghost ship and he just has a friendly chat With him.
Speaker 0: He's just like hey, so you're the captain.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why do you wear that mask all the time?
Speaker 0: Cuz my face was horribly burned and I want everyone to see it and I'm used to wearing the mask.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also our ship is invisible to radar when we turn on this thing.
Speaker 1: So yeah, that's why we're the ghost ship.
Speaker 1: and then the kid freaks out and Clearly it is the Boa poisoning.
Speaker 1: He's gonna turn into Boa juice.
Speaker 0: Yep, and he accidentally hits a button that turns off the radar Invisibility.
Speaker 1: what is with this kid and randomly flailing and then hitting buttons?
Speaker 1: So he really plot moves in this movie twice because he randomly hits a button on a wall.
Speaker 0: Yep, so he he accidentally turns off the Inviso radar the doctor takes care of his boa juice poisoning with a shot and then Boa fucking missiles the.
Speaker 0: The boat gets missled so bad that everyone on the flying ghost ship dies except for the captain who's injured the girl who's the girl the doctor and the and the main character kid.
Speaker 0: everyone else in the whole ghost ship dies and it's ruined and it crashes under the Sea.
Speaker 0: and that's the end of the flying ghost ship.
Speaker 1: so they're sitting on this ruined ghost ship.
Speaker 0: only four of them are alive and The captain in the go in the mask is Basically, you know out of commission.
Speaker 1: so that this girl who's there is being really friendly with him and she's like we should go kamikaze On this asshole.
Speaker 0: Well, this isn't first right the kid that because the captain gets injured They take his mask off and the kid realizes.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, the captain of the ghost is my real dad.
Speaker 1: Oh, right, and he kind of looks good.
Speaker 1: His burns are very like avatar bird.
Speaker 0: This is a purple Blotch on the whole side of his face and he's like two-faced purple and not purple.
Speaker 1: That's it Yeah, and he's like.
Speaker 1: I'm your dad.
Speaker 1: Okay, this is awesome.
Speaker 1: And then you know, the girl is like, all right Hayato We should totally go kamikaze on Boa because they gave us but they just talked about not minutes ago.
Speaker 0: how look we know that Boa's fort is here and we know it has this big star in the middle and we know that is.
Speaker 0: We haven't figured out any way to penetrate it.
Speaker 0: We're doing everything we can possibly do to attack Boa's fort.
Speaker 1: And she's like we should kamikaze and the kids like but it won't work.
Speaker 1: and she's like, what are you a pussy?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like dude.
Speaker 0: Listen, if we knew if kamikaze would have worked before we could have done it with the in the perfectly working ghost ship.
Speaker 0: now You want to do it with two people and a broken ass?
Speaker 0: Missile to hell ghost.
Speaker 1: or maybe they didn't want to do kamikaze because they had other options.
Speaker 1: But now that they have no options, there's no reason to not kamikaze.
Speaker 0: They're gonna die anyway, so they go to kamikaze.
Speaker 0: The Boa with the broken ass go ship and the kid who's never piloted it before is piloting and the girl who's lived on the Ship for a while is helping.
Speaker 1: the weird thing is through this whole scene.
Speaker 1: She's like, let's go.
Speaker 1: kamikaze He's like no it won't work and she's like Ben up Nancy boy.
Speaker 1: And then when they're going he she's basically like it's not gonna work and he's like man up Nancy boy.
Speaker 0: It's like what.
Speaker 1: and they just fucking kamikaze.
Speaker 1: through to this like there's a pillar event.
Speaker 0: That's a giant octopus, right?
Speaker 0: There's a. there's two or three obstacles.
Speaker 0: they managed to escape.
Speaker 1: I think the best obstacle the octopus whatever but there's the.
Speaker 1: I love the scene of the octopus robot losing his shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and no Reming itself in crane crush under a rock.
Speaker 0: No, but with the undersea mines, they they fail all the undersea mines explode, but they're okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what the fuck the fact that Boa doesn't isn't like.
Speaker 1: why did all my mines just blow up and my robot octopus disappear?
Speaker 1: and This movie just really.
Speaker 0: in the end they kamikaze and at the last second the captain shows up and says dude eject the bridge so we don't die.
Speaker 0: and then they do and then it's over.
Speaker 1: so we say it's over because I Don't even know what to say about this.
Speaker 1: So the diagram.
Speaker 1: and when you see Boa's lair It is like this kind of concentric design and there's a tower with a star in the top poking out And that's what opens and closes and all the robots come in and out through there.
Speaker 1: They ram it and it explodes.
Speaker 0: well, they ram it basically by flying this relatively tiny go ship, right?
Speaker 0: It's a big ship, but it's tiny compared to the base.
Speaker 1: It is nuclear-powered or something It's
Speaker 0: true, but they they drive this incredibly tiny ship into Basically this club, you know slowly closing Hall and it fits through the hole at the last second sort of like, you know Yeah, you escaped from the aliens in Independence Day, you know, you fit through the closing door hatch at the last
Speaker 1: Yep,
Speaker 0: and then they eject and then that is enough to destroy the entire base.
Speaker 1: Well, well, it turns out and I wish I was side of that little hole was Boa.
Speaker 1: Yes, that is Boa.
Speaker 1: In fact, that wasn't a hole to Boa.
Speaker 1: that was Boa because you see Boa is a giant Goddamn motherfucking clam.
Speaker 0: How does a giant clam or oyster?
Speaker 0: Make Boa juice talk to Kuroshio build robots etc.
Speaker 0: Etc.
Speaker 1: Even if it's a really giant mystical clam How the fuck it must have just been really pissed off about being a clam.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: it died kind of the way a clam would?
Speaker 1: it kind of goes?
Speaker 1: Oh, it comes out and then goes back down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and just what I mean?
Speaker 0: a giant clam that big eating a ship that small like that's gonna kill it instantly.
Speaker 1: Let's summarize.
Speaker 1: There's a world Boa's trying to kill goddamn everyone.
Speaker 1: the ghost ship stops Goa Boa But it's too late.
Speaker 1: Boa juice has killed most of the people in the world.
Speaker 1: The crabs have killed half the rest of the people.
Speaker 0: golem has killed a whole bunch of people.
Speaker 1: Basically, everyone's dead.
Speaker 1: but then there's this epilogue or everyone's totally fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean as soon as Boa is dead all the crab robots just stopped working immediately and the world is fine and all the buildings Are in one piece.
Speaker 0: like didn't golem smash them all?
Speaker 1: but maybe they were showing other places.
Speaker 1: I don't know but possible.
Speaker 1: even so Boa was a giant clam.
Speaker 1: The plot of this is that a giant clam sent robots to kill all humans.
Speaker 0: And then at the end is a tiny epilogue scene where the the I guess real dad who was go ship captain is totally chill And the main character and the girl are on a boat in the ocean and they're having a good old time.
Speaker 1: Oh, but poor Jack loses his bag, right?
Speaker 0: It's like the dog loses his bag full of stuff and it's like.
Speaker 0: was that supposed to be symbolic of something because I mean it could have been.
Speaker 1: But he lost his baggage, I guess.
Speaker 0: but what was it symbolic?
Speaker 1: Oh, I just felt bad for Jack.
Speaker 1: Jack loses his bag.
Speaker 1: It's clearly his bag.
Speaker 1: He cares a lot about it.
Speaker 1: And the hiato is just like.
Speaker 1: we'll get you another bag Not much better bag be fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh and forgot to mention, you know, not real mom's Shoe that really didn't play into it the movie at all though It's just oh it didn't.
Speaker 0: it was just like an excuse to have a discussion with a girl about his real parents.
Speaker 1: It's about a giant clam that tries to kill everybody.
Speaker 0: But I mean look it starts off with Scooby Doo then it's Astro Boy with a robot Then it's giant clam under the sea and in between it's like generic robot show.
Speaker 0: It's evil Businessman, it's like what the fuck dudes what the fuck giant clam?
Speaker 0: They say.
Speaker 0: the saving grace of this movie is that it's 60 minutes.
Speaker 0: So you only what the fuck for a little while and then it's over.
Speaker 1: and as the movie goes on people Increasingly make that I am angry and also confused.
Speaker 1: look with the furrowed brow.
Speaker 0: So if you want 60 minutes of what the fuck?
Speaker 0: why is this?
Speaker 0: five different animes barely squished together?
Speaker 1: Maybe you don't believe us.
Speaker 1: You're gonna be like yeah clam.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be a clam like the naked cars new tenant.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: Those are literally naked cars.
Speaker 1: This is literally a giant clan.
Speaker 0: That's right flying go ship 1969.
Speaker 0: I guess for 1969. it's something special and it has historical value being by Miyazaki with the key animation.
Speaker 1: but Well, there's also.
Speaker 1: You'll watch it and are you know, it seems to move slowly.
Speaker 0: I mean like it's not good, but it's like there's something to see and get out of 55 minutes.
Speaker 0: There's something to learn from watching it 55 minutes in.
Speaker 1: all I could think was how the fuck are they gonna resolve this in?
Speaker 1: five minutes?
Speaker 0: it just doesn't have any direction or pacing or Anything.
Speaker 0: it's like they just took ten scenes from random anime and pasted them one after the other with the same character.
Speaker 0: It's literally a giant clam giant clam giant robot scooby-doo.
Speaker 1: eject the bridge And the girl.
Speaker 1: just I love to see that the girl trying to convince the kid to go off.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ.
Speaker 1: And right, okay for the logo, right.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website News and more.
Speaker 0: remember my robot, but for different shows sci-tech Monday Discriminate Thursday Live with no studio.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I'm I'm in the secret base.
Speaker 0: They're gonna catch me.
Speaker 0: No, I'm just out in the streets.
Speaker 0: only chill at least a kid that me.
Speaker 0: Oh my just on TV It's at least great digital target.
Speaker 1: had the decency to not father showing us the giant plan.
Speaker 1: It was clearly again.
Speaker 0: That was bad equally bad in a different.
Speaker 1: But would it be better if the thing had gone in and then went to credits?
Speaker 1: it was like five minutes later.
Speaker 1: Boa stopped Transmitting.
Speaker 0: Boa was transmitting.
Speaker 1: I guess how else was it controlling all those robots?
Speaker 0: I didn't explain that because the robot stopped when Boa died.
Speaker 0: I'm done with the flying ghost ship.
Speaker 0: I got nothing more to say about it.