Speaker 1: Hey, it's Thursday, May 6th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: I crab people time travel.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So uh hey Scott.
Speaker 1: What's the Grecian urn?
Speaker 1: an amphora about 25 cents an hour these days oh?
Speaker 0: Do they really cuz?
Speaker 1: I mean That was just a FARC headline, and you know the radio DJ thing to do is to steal ahead.
Speaker 1: I mean just.
Speaker 0: I mean just cuz.
Speaker 0: they have economics problems.
Speaker 0: I don't think that they're like their wages are the problem.
Speaker 0: I think that the government is the problem right.
Speaker 0: well It's got too much debt.
Speaker 0: It's got not enough tax revenue.
Speaker 1: It's well the problems complicated, but what I would boil it down to and I'm by no means you know Wall Street job aside I'm by no means a professional you make sure that our kids yeah, okay?
Speaker 0: You learn a lot about this stuff just being around people who do it, but your job is make sure the server doesn't crash.
Speaker 1: Well actually no I have much bigger responsibilities than that now.
Speaker 1: I got promoted a while ago.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: So now you have to make sure two servers.
Speaker 1: But all that aside I mean what that situation basically comes down to is that Imagine you know our got like New York State the government again run out of money and budgets not done.
Speaker 1: So you know it periodically in America will have things shut down like we're out of money We're shutting everything down, but well that's no.
Speaker 0: usually things shut down When states can't pass their budgets.
Speaker 0: so the state doesn't pass a budget.
Speaker 0: the date goes past the deadline is gone And now they you know they can't allocate money to anything so they turn.
Speaker 0: so everyone goes home and know what.
Speaker 0: they can't spend any Money on anything except emergency service.
Speaker 1: I guess the point I was making that at least when I was a kid this happened in Michigan a few times But they never actually shut anything down.
Speaker 1: basically the state's out of money And it didn't mean anything.
Speaker 1: and part of the reason why it doesn't mean anything is that with credit We can do deficit spending.
Speaker 1: so if there is a problem you can always just spend the money and deal with it later And that works pretty well.
Speaker 1: But imagine if one day the felt like if tomorrow the federal government was told by Someone who had the power to tell them things you can't borrow any money for the next few years Starting right now, so we had to then pay for everything we did with cash Mmm.
Speaker 1: We don't have enough cash, so what do we do?
Speaker 0: you don't get everything you want.
Speaker 1: so the real tricky part?
Speaker 1: Is that in Greece basically?
Speaker 1: It's kind of a situation of the ant in the grasshopper where Germany You know the old parable.
Speaker 1: no, okay, never mind, then this doesn't work obviously the analogy.
Speaker 1: But so it's the line in the mouse.
Speaker 0: He's pulled the thorn out of his the hobo and the guy who is fiscally responsible.
Speaker 1: The hobo begs on the street and the fiscally responsible guy goes home and plays some video games, but basically today I you know I saw you guys playing that stock market game and someone was like oh Greece passed the thing and now the stock market collapsed.
Speaker 1: that is so far from the truth.
Speaker 1: so already There's riots going on in the street in Greece.
Speaker 0: I mean you know we have Yeah, well You know we always talk about how the reason we can't get anyone to riot is because this bread and as long as they have Bread and circuses guess what Greece no more bread.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 1: They're running out of circuses too.
Speaker 0: if that pool thing Oh, well, no they got plenty of circuses.
Speaker 1: They're not enough pools bread circuses and pools apparently plus You know World Cup's coming.
Speaker 0: That's plenty of circuses for them unless they lose.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know it doesn't matter, but Basically, it was sad.
Speaker 1: I mean it's one thing to work in the financial sector It's another thing to see the kind of visceral.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: people died in Greece in riots and attacks on banks because of the economic situation.
Speaker 1: My opinions and all that aside The stock market dropped.
Speaker 1: the Dow at least dropped nine hundred and something points in the course of like a minute.
Speaker 1: Yep, so I'm sitting at work.
Speaker 1: You know things are going pretty pretty fine.
Speaker 1: And then I see a little news thing pops up that says Greece passes austerity bill, and I'm like huh I wonder how that's going to affect the.
Speaker 1: and then I look up and I see Interspersed with CNBC saying like stock market collapsing oh my god, and they're like they're all panicking and Interspersed with this.
Speaker 1: in the background is scenes of further rioting in Greece.
Speaker 1: And then I look at all my market days exploding like the book like froze on my laptop.
Speaker 1: I could I couldn't even like see what was going on in the market.
Speaker 1: So I'm trying to like make sure all our systems are handling this okay.
Speaker 1: And and the markets dropping faster than the news can even report I see the news saying like it's dropped 400 points, and I'm looking at the real market data.
Speaker 0: It's like -800.
Speaker 1: It's like an 800 and still going down.
Speaker 1: We almost did the circuit breaker.
Speaker 0: What's the circuit breaker?
Speaker 1: There's a circuit breaker in the stock market that basically says if you drop more than X percent and all these other conditions Markets stop because we got to figure out what's going on.
Speaker 1: We got kind of close to that mmm, but Basically what happened now?
Speaker 1: This is all up in the air And this is not.
Speaker 1: I don't speak on behalf of any company of any entity other than myself and my personal Guess and opinion and CNBC is actually reported something similar.
Speaker 1: But it may well have been that basically there was a prince that when someone ever you buy stock There's a print in the tape.
Speaker 1: you know the ticker tape Still exists somewhere.
Speaker 1: yeah, but no one has a physical tip ticker tape okay?
Speaker 1: I found on Craigslist a ticker tape machine.
Speaker 0: Could you hook it up and make it print out what it's supposed to print out for reals probably?
Speaker 1: There might.
Speaker 1: it might print too fast it might break But I thought about buying it when you're in beacon because it was in the city.
Speaker 1: I could see if it's still there.
Speaker 1: imagine if we had a ticker tape machine.
Speaker 0: That's all.
Speaker 1: you hook it up to the Arduino.
Speaker 0: That's all you.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 1: anyway as Best as anyone on CNBC has been able to report it was basically a glitch and what happened was somewhere along the line Internet saying it wasn't a glitch though.
Speaker 1: well not a glitch in like the stock market or in the systems But there was some sort of print that was way outside of what anyone would have expected and because of that You know people treated it as legitimate.
Speaker 1: And it's possible that automatic systems and then humans in that fraction of a second made very poor decisions Because of that and started selling when they probably wouldn't have wanted to sell.
Speaker 1: so the market dropped 900 points then immediately went all the way back up as everyone you know rebought in or fixed everything and There were.
Speaker 1: it was crazy.
Speaker 1: I'm sitting there.
Speaker 1: Everyone's panicking.
Speaker 1: There's yelling going around There's yelling on the TV and on the TV.
Speaker 1: behind the yelling is riots and fireballs and riot police in the streets.
Speaker 0: It's awesome that thing is right.
Speaker 0: so that all happened to me.
Speaker 1: all this happens And then you know finally it's starting to calm down And I look in the geek nights forum And I see one of you guys playing that game basically like I think the stock markets going down.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, I wonder if it was because of Greece.
Speaker 0: But meanwhile right it's like all that crazy shit happens, but it's like yeah, son is sons up right.
Speaker 0: I mean like.
Speaker 0: you know everyone's driving around got biked home.
Speaker 1: Well people are driving around here.
Speaker 1: I mean Greece.
Speaker 1: things aren't doing so.
Speaker 0: well no But I mean it's like how can you tell that if that's happens, and it's not like the end?
Speaker 0: How can you tell when it's the end?
Speaker 1: well cuz it went back up?
Speaker 0: Okay, so wait so what if it's the circuit breaker right?
Speaker 0: so basically the market closes.
Speaker 0: The same is like the bell ringing right kind of yeah, so do all the exchanges of the same circuit breaker?
Speaker 1: That I'm not 100% sure on.
Speaker 1: basically you know as it was dropping.
Speaker 1: I'm talking.
Speaker 1: look at my co-workers.
Speaker 1: We're debating.
Speaker 1: so if the circuit breaker is hit how exactly should we handle this and do it this way?
Speaker 1: do it this way?
Speaker 0: Cuz you get to go home right I mean the market closes.
Speaker 0: go home.
Speaker 1: As much as I wish I would be the one to be there to deal with that bullshit.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 0: so the thing is right.
Speaker 0: Okay, so let's say hit the circuit breaker and the next day you open the market again.
Speaker 1: The idea is that something's going on and it's probably not good.
Speaker 1: So let's stop and give everyone time to cool down to assess.
Speaker 0: basically give everyone time to Scott Johnson it in a choir And count what if everyone counts all the ducks and there's like five ducks And there's supposed to be five million does well.
Speaker 1: Then the market has discovered a problem and now we got to deal with that.
Speaker 1: I mean if you only what?
Speaker 0: if the only answer is it's it's gonna go down like all the way.
Speaker 1: Actually had five ducks in the first place, and you've been just Acting like you had more ducks all this time.
Speaker 0: isn't that what the whole world's been doing for?
Speaker 0: you know a hundred years?
Speaker 1: It's a little more complicated than that.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it seems like to me.
Speaker 1: the gist of this is I had an exciting day at work.
Speaker 0: All right I got nothing Thursday.
Speaker 1: We couldn't decide what to do the show on even.
Speaker 1: yeah It's got a good idea, and we'll probably do it in the future.
Speaker 1: should we tell him what this idea?
Speaker 0: Necessary?
Speaker 1: you don't want to keep it a secret cuz I think it'll be a secret.
Speaker 0: We don't need to.
Speaker 0: you know we never really talk about shows in advance plus when I do right it could result in shit talking.
Speaker 0: So let's not it could.
Speaker 1: but unless we always preface things by saying we may we might we intend yeah It's not necessary.
Speaker 1: We desire to anyway.
Speaker 1: There is a news.
Speaker 1: I want to talk about really yeah I don't want to talk about it a lot, but I want to take this not from the technological side.
Speaker 1: I mean this is basically a Monday style news that there's an.
Speaker 1: so here's the deal.
Speaker 1: We have brain scan machines now that can detect fairly accurately whether or not someone is lying on the spot Like it can tell with a reasonable degree of certainty whether or not a person is fabricating the verbal data that they're expelling To you.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm now.
Speaker 1: It's not perfect yet.
Speaker 1: We shouldn't use this in courts because it's like lie detectors.
Speaker 1: It's still it's not.
Speaker 1: we can't Can't send someone.
Speaker 0: you can't lock someone up forever based on what a machine says it's not it's not cool.
Speaker 1: Well well well So what if we have a machine that recorded video of a dude stabbing another dude to death?
Speaker 0: that's okay?
Speaker 1: But that's just a machine telling us something?
Speaker 0: Not really.
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: What's different?
Speaker 0: What's different?
Speaker 1: Yeah?
Speaker 0: Because even though we have fmri's and stuff.
Speaker 0: That's not.
Speaker 0: you know people's brains Right?
Speaker 0: are not video cameras?
Speaker 0: video cameras are infallible a brain recording memory.
Speaker 0: even if you can read the memory out of the brain It's not exactly what the person reading the memory.
Speaker 1: Well, this is the very specific case here is the idea that what if you can tell?
Speaker 1: 100% whether or not a person right now is Fabricating what they're telling to you?
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: but here's the thing right.
Speaker 0: is it the same?
Speaker 0: What if I think I'm lying, but I'm not?
Speaker 0: what does it still look the same?
Speaker 1: well If you think you're lying And you're not then that means that you your intent is still to lie.
Speaker 1: you just happen to have accidentally told the truth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so now you're gonna now.
Speaker 0: What do you know?
Speaker 0: You don't know what to think right.
Speaker 1: so well But what if you could have a meter that basically says this person is guaranteed?
Speaker 1: right now We can prove with science is in whatever.
Speaker 1: He is saying he is intending to deceive what.
Speaker 0: how am I?
Speaker 0: what percentage?
Speaker 0: 100?
Speaker 1: let's say we get a hundred somehow.
Speaker 1: It's a hundred Let's just say for the purpose of a thought experiment.
Speaker 0: So you know that they're intending to deceive.
Speaker 0: you still have no idea what the truth is you haven't learned anything But you.
Speaker 1: but is it admissible?
Speaker 1: you would you say in a court if someone is?
Speaker 1: testifying like right now before Congress or before a court they're testifying and This machine says 100% the last two sentences that they spoke.
Speaker 1: regardless of the veracity of these sentences Were spoken with the clear intent to deceive the listeners.
Speaker 0: well You you couldn't say for sure whether those two sentences are true or false.
Speaker 0: But what you could do is you could just I could just strike those two sentences from the record and then leave it at That.
Speaker 0: so he'd be like okay those two sentences are not admissible in the court.
Speaker 0: And so here's the.
Speaker 1: here's the interesting thing that happened a judge in Brooklyn has excluded FMR eyes from trials.
Speaker 1: okay now it did not set a precedent because the way he did it.
Speaker 1: But all that aside the interesting part is that he did not argue that it wasn't accurate enough or that it's Ambiguous or anything like that.
Speaker 1: You know this is the conversation we could argue about forever mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: The reason he didn't let it go is quote Juries are supposed to decide the credibility of witnesses and fMRI lie detection even if it could be proven completely accurate infringes on that right.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, I don't know how I feel about that at all.
Speaker 1: I don't know the idea that you're saying that that the the jury were.
Speaker 1: if we have a machine that can determine an actual truth Verifiably, and he you know he said you know irrespective.
Speaker 0: Oh isn't?
Speaker 0: the purpose of the jury is because we can't find the truth.
Speaker 0: So we need a jury of peers to you know discover it.
Speaker 0: But what if there is a way to beyond reasonable doubt just scientifically determine the truth?
Speaker 0: for reals like let's say we have you know Magic Oracle that actually works and let us look at any you know or a quantum wormhole that a machine that lets us watch the past Yes, or watch exactly the word someone's thinking in their head.
Speaker 1: You know crazy future tired science.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then what do you need a jury for?
Speaker 0: it's you don't need one.
Speaker 1: well I think you still need a jury to look at that evidence, and you know I don't know.
Speaker 1: I feel like The idea of a jury of peers is still important in the idea that even if we're in some far-future society if we ever use Machines that are above beyond us or before us you know in terms of an AI That's smarter than us or a machine that's not as smart as us or smart in a different way.
Speaker 1: I feel like at least one other of us has to agree with what the machine did before we decide to enact justice.
Speaker 0: The thing is that the machine can Do that.
Speaker 0: the machine can also probably control the person that is that the person that's supposed to agree with it.
Speaker 1: It's interesting that this judge is basically sidestepped all the practical arguments of.
Speaker 1: well is it really accurate?
Speaker 1: What does it really tell us and said straight up?
Speaker 1: We shouldn't use machines like this because it infringes on the jury's rights to figure it out for themselves.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think it's interesting, and I don't know how I feel about.
Speaker 0: there was an interesting thing that I read about.
Speaker 0: They did something.
Speaker 0: I don't know where it was, but basically they compared rational jurists to non rational juries.
Speaker 0: I don't know how they determined who was a rational person And who wasn't but apparently rational people decide cases rationally gasp and non-rational people decide case.
Speaker 1: was that emotionally Where they showed that?
Speaker 1: because they segregated jurors again between emotional and rational and they found that but overwhelmingly so.
Speaker 1: irrational or emotional jurors Would pretty much say guilty or innocent based on how attractive the person was.
Speaker 0: yeah, I think that was the article there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and so it's like.
Speaker 0: so they were like look we have to only have rational jurors, so it's like aha You'll have no jurors.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: You know the old Everybody was that the judge said to the to the lawyers who didn't know who James James Randy was.
Speaker 1: he said that man there Will evaluate the facts in an empirical manner and make a decision based solely on the veracity of the whatever.
Speaker 0: yep Hell no.
Speaker 0: And then he was not on the jury.
Speaker 0: So yeah, but I think this was in a non-us Situation.
Speaker 0: I think it might have been in Ireland or the UK or something I mean, I think in the end Scotland my personal.
Speaker 1: You know it's Thursday.
Speaker 1: I don't really want to get in the news any further But I'm of the mind that regardless of how we define in law like what?
Speaker 1: Pardon me what the purposes of juries are with the purpose of law is what justice is I?
Speaker 1: Feel like there should be a stated goal in all in our entire legal system that Basically forces everyone to accept truth above all other circumstances Like if something can be proven like proven beyond a beyond any Already
Speaker 0: have that it's called beyond a reasonable doubt
Speaker 1: well beyond a reasonable doubt or beyond a shadow of a doubt.
Speaker 0: Well beyond a shadow of a doubt is is also beyond a reasonable that actually multiple lawyers have told me that those are actually two different circumstances.
Speaker 1: That beyond a reasonable doubt is for example Yeah It's possible that you didn't do it if there is a DNA clone of you out there that was taken from you know When you were born grown in a lab trained and dropped from the sky into this facility.
Speaker 1: You know something like that.
Speaker 1: That's not a reasonable doubt.
Speaker 1: No, but shadow of a doubt is that's also not possible.
Speaker 1: Okay, I Don't know.
Speaker 1: I thought it was interesting.
Speaker 1: Do you have anything interesting?
Speaker 0: No nothing.
Speaker 1: on this Thursday this fine summer day It's not summer yet.
Speaker 0: It's summer.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it's like 80 degrees out there.
Speaker 1: It's summer.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it's spring.
Speaker 0: still the leaves are summer green.
Speaker 1: They're no longer spring green I don't know.
Speaker 0: I went to work.
Speaker 0: He came home playing the Street Fighter.
Speaker 1: You know I Almost bought an X any second.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna go up buy an Xbox and then you get regret it You don't have a street fight.
Speaker 0: Maybe you should.
Speaker 0: maybe you should play some Street Fighter.
Speaker 0: to decide.
Speaker 1: I was I was playing some Street Fighter last night at the music Super Street Fighter for yeah, and he's well with actually a bigger stick from the one you had Conrad brought.
Speaker 0: he probably I think he has like a like a hori stick, so I kicked some ass.
Speaker 1: Yeah against two against people who sucked.
Speaker 1: Basically I used my Street Fighter 2 non pre gnosis skills so my completely non Gnostic.
Speaker 0: all your Street Fighter 2 stuff still works.
Speaker 0: There's just a whole bunch of extra stuff on top of it.
Speaker 0: But any character from Street Fighter 2 you could just play as if it's Street Fighter 2.
Speaker 0: I actually wish they would include like Street Fighter 2 mode where you can only use Street Fighter 2 characters And they work exactly the way they worked in Street Fighter 2 or at least Super Street Fighter 2 turbo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because every character from Super Street Fighter 2 turbo is in there.
Speaker 1: So against people who also do not know the gnosis and also who didn't really play Street Fighter back in the day I can just M bison and just slide kick slide kick slide kick slide kick slide kick slide kick until they die.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the slide kick.
Speaker 0: if a super day play I play as M bison all the time.
Speaker 0: That's my.
Speaker 1: I played one good person, and I was like slide kick.
Speaker 1: He's like punch to the nuts.
Speaker 1: You're done.
Speaker 1: Yeah I should not decide to slide.
Speaker 0: kick is basically the least safe move in the that you can possibly do as M bison.
Speaker 0: But you basically they can block it low and then start a combo on you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they can do an uppercut against even though you're low.
Speaker 0: They can basically hit jump and hit you while you're doing it and then start a combo.
Speaker 0: They can block it with a focus attack and then crumple you and then make a combo.
Speaker 0: It's basically the weakest most unsafe possible move you can do is the slide, you know.
Speaker 0: And I only throw out the slide when it's like completely Completely safe to do the slide and there's absolutely no chance and it's so rare that that happens.
Speaker 0: The thing is I have a reflex to do the slide when I shouldn't or accidentally do the slide.
Speaker 0: So I got it like avoid the slide basic, you know.
Speaker 0: And it's sort of annoying too because your M bison you want to do a low kick.
Speaker 0: You got to do the low medium kick Which is great because there's a great reach on it and also the standing medium kick has a great forward reach, you know.
Speaker 0: But if you accidentally push the other way you do the stupid slide you know like ah fuck and then the guy blocks it and show you can do and then you land on the ground and you Stand up and he gets you when you're trying to stand up and then it's a disaster.
Speaker 1: So anyway, we got nothing on this Thursday day.
Speaker 0: So things of the day Mmm thing of the day.
Speaker 0: All right, so check this out.
Speaker 0: You're ready.
Speaker 0: I'm checkin.
Speaker 0: Einfish.
Speaker 0: it's very fish.
Speaker 0: right to fish Blair fish.
Speaker 1: One fish to fish red fish blue fish.
Speaker 0: Yeah, apparently this is a Yiddish Translation of one fish to fish red fish blue fish.
Speaker 0: What gets better than that, right?
Speaker 0: I mean Yiddish is awesome But this is like dr.
Speaker 0: Seuss Yiddish.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Can you can you really beat that?
Speaker 0: I don't think you can beat that.
Speaker 1: I think I can beat that with the fact that we can now watch the original metropolis uncut.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: indeed Apparently guy had it for a long time.
Speaker 1: You know, everyone probably knows the whole story of metropolis.
Speaker 1: now We lost it and you know It was really was shown and people hated it because it was too like obtuse.
Speaker 1: so they cut out huge chunks of the movie and then they were lost and destroyed.
Speaker 1: and Basically, they're shown in theaters now.
Speaker 1: They found it.
Speaker 1: They've got the whole thing.
Speaker 1: It'll be on DVD soon.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna find out where it's playing in New York City and maybe we'll go see it though.
Speaker 1: It's like three hours long.
Speaker 1: That's fun but Cool things to note one.
Speaker 1: There's an entire like subplot.
Speaker 1: Well, actually there's multiple subplots that were completely cut out Involving the Thin Man and he looks pretty good in these shots.
Speaker 0: Why should we go to see this?
Speaker 0: and it's just rent arrows and you know the most metropolis.
Speaker 0: It's like no you didn't.
Speaker 1: Well the really interesting thing is that I'm gonna quote one of the guys who restored it and who worked with this project a lot who has seen all the real metropolis now Quote.
Speaker 1: it is no longer a science fiction film Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: The balance of the story has been given back.
Speaker 1: It's now a film that encompasses many many genres an epic about conflicts that are ages old.
Speaker 1: The science fiction disguise is now very very thin.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: I really look forward to seeing this.
Speaker 0: Have you watched any other Fritz Lang movies like M or anything like that?
Speaker 1: I've seen em.
Speaker 0: Ah, so great.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, all right.
Speaker 1: So the meta minute that you forgot about.
Speaker 0: Oh snap.
Speaker 1: Oh Cosmos is the book project.
Speaker 1: Dorf is the coding club project.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't know don't have much else.
Speaker 0: Kinetic on is coming kinetic on is coming up.
Speaker 1: But if you really want to do a panel you better get it to me like today or tomorrow Because I'm not really taking any more submissions.
Speaker 0: No, I don't know.
Speaker 0: do we have enough to fill the schedule?
Speaker 1: I think so.
Speaker 0: All right I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't have any more metas nothing at all.
Speaker 0: No Okay, so we couldn't think of an idea for the show.
Speaker 0: so we went.
Speaker 0: actually Emily will be happy.
Speaker 0: She made like a spreadsheet on Google Docs or a document on Google Docs that has Basically, she compiled all the suggestions from the forum thread into one document.
Speaker 0: So I actually looked at it for once and I'm like boring boring boring.
Speaker 0: and then I see this one suggestion for time travel.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, huh?
Speaker 0: You know, there was that reason.
Speaker 0: Stephen Hawking thing about time travel.
Speaker 0: Maybe this will be an okay show.
Speaker 0: So, let's see.
Speaker 0: What's up?
Speaker 1: I'll go straight up.
Speaker 1: I have a prediction about why He is saying the things he's saying now suddenly cuz.
Speaker 1: remember just a little while ago We came out and he was like, yeah, if aliens find us, they'll probably kill us.
Speaker 1: We should really be hiding until we're more advanced.
Speaker 0: Yeah, probably cuz anyway, I think the thing is is that if you're in a situation right where you cannot achieve interstellar travel and There are any alien for any aliens to meet you.
Speaker 0: They do know interstellar travel.
Speaker 0: therefore, right?
Speaker 0: They are automatically guaranteed to be more advanced than you.
Speaker 0: But if you have interstellar travel, then you don't really have any other measurement You know to determine if aliens are more or less advanced than you are until you meet them.
Speaker 0: So until you are able to meet aliens, you should not encourage aliens to meet you.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, you're guaranteed to have the lower hand.
Speaker 1: now at the same time.
Speaker 1: He's definitely relying in this case on Human experience.
Speaker 1: I mean uses the Christopher Columbus.
Speaker 0: That's the problem.
Speaker 0: Everyone has.
Speaker 1: well We got you know, we're this.
Speaker 1: this puddle is perfectly shaped to the space.
Speaker 1: I found it in.
Speaker 1: It must have been created that way duh the anthropic principle and such.
Speaker 1: but It's hard to say because in all of the experiences we've ever had Both with humans and with animals and plants and everything if a stronger or more advanced anything comes into contact with a weaker one It pretty much just takes it over.
Speaker 0: Yep So why risk it, you know, it's the most likely outcome, but what I think same universe, right?
Speaker 0: What I mean, huh?
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Hawking is incredibly smart.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, he's a genius.
Speaker 1: He's one of those Human beings.
Speaker 0: look so smart to me.
Speaker 0: I mean he can't even talk dude to ever live.
Speaker 1: He can sing But I think what he's doing right now is making himself future proof.
Speaker 1: I don't think he's had any major insights at least in this front.
Speaker 1: Like I don't think he was sitting there one day.
Speaker 1: He's like, wait a minute time travel is possible.
Speaker 1: And here's why I Think what he's thinking is that we're probably gonna figure something out at some point in the next hundred thousand years.
Speaker 1: If I say time travel is not possible Which is likely that it's not possible at least in a way that we could understand or take advantage of and Someone does something that is akin to time travel.
Speaker 1: I'll be in.
Speaker 1: the history book says yeah He was mostly right, but we proved him wrong on this.
Speaker 1: if I just say it's possible someday If it's never possible, no one will ever call me on it.
Speaker 1: And if we find out it's possible, I'll be a visionary.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think he's already a visionary.
Speaker 0: I don't think he really needs but he really needs that.
Speaker 1: Look at the way he writes the kind of person he is I would bet a lot that he's future-proofing himself with that time travel thing.
Speaker 0: I don't know I think what he's actually doing right, which is a much more Occam's razor idea Is that you know, he's so good at explaining advanced physics in ways that just even a normal person can sort of understand the concept You know and that's if you read his books the ones that are you know meant for mass consumption.
Speaker 0: That's what you're gonna get.
Speaker 0: You're gonna get like crazy astrophysics that you can understand.
Speaker 0: The way is that people are less interested in science technology and whatever and the approach He's taking is to say sort of things, you know about stuff that people care about.
Speaker 0: if he talks about time travel and aliens People are gonna pay attention to that even normal people.
Speaker 0: So what he can do is he can talk about time travel and aliens and he's sort of trying to get people to care About science and physics and whatever.
Speaker 0: would you know when normal people don't care right now as much and he's you know It's a it's a good strategy to bring people back into it.
Speaker 0: You know, maybe he's gonna sell some books and may you know, that's fine.
Speaker 0: That's you know, selfish interest.
Speaker 0: but then maybe one of those people will read the book and maybe those people will become more science minded and then the world be Better.
Speaker 0: because I have one more science II person, you know.
Speaker 1: Well, that is.
Speaker 0: if he just always talked in his hardcore physics way normal people wouldn't give a crap.
Speaker 1: in general We need we need another Carl Sagan.
Speaker 1: Carl Sagan got an entire generation of scientists to care about science and Cosmo still holds up.
Speaker 1: But I feel like with modern internet kids.
Speaker 1: We need like a new a modern like a Twitter slash 4chan cosmos.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's possible, but we need we really do need to get people excited about science because Kids who at least are in any way Skeptical and rational and reasonable or at least are confronted with the fact that there's beauty in the world That is scientific, you know deconstructing the rainbow is a rainbow less beautiful if you know how it works.
Speaker 1: I think that would go a long way to fight religious extremism and the such in the world.
Speaker 0: I mean if you look at some of the things he said too, it's like he's like, okay, so time travel.
Speaker 0: So let's say you had a train and the trainer went around the world so fast.
Speaker 0: So if it went around the world this fast time would actually slow down on the train.
Speaker 0: So if you looked at the train that people would be going real slow.
Speaker 0: It's like well, what if a girl you know The train is going almost the speed of light and then a girl is on the train and she starts running really fast?
Speaker 0: Isn't she gonna get past the speed of light and break the rules?
Speaker 0: We already know that.
Speaker 0: no because the time will slow down for her even more.
Speaker 0: so the other people on the train will be looking at her going real slow motion compared to them and Basically, you know, they'll get older as she doesn't get older.
Speaker 1: relativity is just like it amazes me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this whole idea that there's kind of the it's like this.
Speaker 1: It's not a speed limit It's more like it's kind of the thing you'd see in a video game engine.
Speaker 1: Well, I think no object can be moving Faster than this this number.
Speaker 1: That's the biggest speed.
Speaker 0: So weird is that it's like, you know the faster you move just in space right like take it just walking Right the more the faster I walk and move around.
Speaker 1: But see you're saying that any moving.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that means you're moving.
Speaker 1: you're not just moving in space You're also moving in time, right?
Speaker 0: But if I if I move around Then like the the the moving and the time the amount of movement I have in time is Changes based on the amount of movement in space.
Speaker 0: if I move across a lot of space, you know Then I move across less more time.
Speaker 0: Ah, it's crazy.
Speaker 1: Well, let me even think now we're hurt.
Speaker 0: It's totally true.
Speaker 1: We're hurtling in all these different directions the crazy speeds.
Speaker 1: You know earth is moving through the galaxy and the galaxies flying out from the center of the Big Bang And there's other galaxies out there moving faster than us.
Speaker 1: We'll never be able to catch him.
Speaker 1: yep, so What do you think would happen if you had a wormhole that looked at us five minutes ago and we shot ourselves?
Speaker 1: from the future Can't happen.
Speaker 1: Oh, why not?
Speaker 1: What if there's a wormhole to the past?
Speaker 0: Well, actually I was reading the other day There was some guy wrote a dr.
Speaker 0: Susie in Parable about the halting problem, you know of computer science.
Speaker 0: Basically the problem is could you write a computer program that would detect when another computer program would halt?
Speaker 0: Right, like so it basically an infinite loop detector.
Speaker 0: Could you write an infinite loop detector?
Speaker 0: And the thing is, okay So I'll take this infinite loop detector and I'll run it against itself.
Speaker 0: will there be an infinite loop in the infinite loop detector?
Speaker 0: and Basically, if there is an infinite loop in the infinite loop detector Then the infinite loop detector will say yes.
Speaker 0: But then if the infinite loop detector says yes, then there is no infinite loop in the infinite loop detector.
Speaker 0: And that's to say no no, no, but then if it says no then there will be an infinite loop.
Speaker 0: So it doesn't work right?
Speaker 0: So basically, you know, whenever there's a paradox what it means is not that oh my god There's a crazy paradox.
Speaker 0: What it means is that it's not possible right there.
Speaker 0: You cannot write an infinite loop detector.
Speaker 0: That's the answer right because writing one would be a paradox.
Speaker 0: therefore time travels the same thing.
Speaker 0: You cannot go back in time and kill yourself and have it actually kill yourself You know because that would be a paradox.
Speaker 0: therefore it can't happen right?
Speaker 0: It just it couldn't happen.
Speaker 0: There would be just not possible.
Speaker 0: You know people seem to think that like paradoxes are this thing that happens and then when they happen shit gets fucked up.
Speaker 0: Oh my gosh No paradoxes.
Speaker 0: if there's a paradox that means that that is a scenario that can never come to be no matter what that will never Happen, of course.
Speaker 1: at the same time that's still limited by our understanding and ideas of the universe, but it's true That's that's just how it is.
Speaker 1: Well, no But Matt does math describe the world perfectly?
Speaker 0: has it failed yet?
Speaker 1: Sometimes but usually just because we don't have we have an imperfect understand math.
Speaker 1: always.
Speaker 0: all the correct math is always correct.
Speaker 0: Only the wrong math is wrong.
Speaker 1: That's really the interesting thing that math.
Speaker 1: we can use it perfectly to describe theoreticals But in the real world, it will theoretically work.
Speaker 1: We just can't measure things closely enough to figure out if it works on.
Speaker 0: and you know that when you measure something you modify Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I Mean look at the world around us that we see it's just electrons banging off of what is effectively empty space.
Speaker 1: There's more empty space in me than there is me.
Speaker 1: Yep so time travel.
Speaker 0: Well, you do we want to talk about like, you know Real time travel or do you want to talk about?
Speaker 0: you know going really fast so that we can go to the future time I remember a long time ago.
Speaker 1: time travel is easy.
Speaker 1: Hi.
Speaker 1: Here we go.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: I've got about 10 seconds.
Speaker 0: Me too one second per second into the future.
Speaker 1: You're going up for different speeds now.
Speaker 0: Are you really I'm moving around?
Speaker 0: I'm also.
Speaker 0: but you know, is that really does that count?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, is that enough to count?
Speaker 1: I'm moving away from you right now.
Speaker 1: I Continue to move away from you.
Speaker 1: that matters cuz you're not moving and I am does it?
Speaker 0: is that really enough?
Speaker 0: I mean cuz I mean I'm moving a little bit but would not have.
Speaker 1: Because if something if something has zero effect then doesn't exist effectively.
Speaker 1: I don't know We're not physicists.
Speaker 1: he most probably just banging his head.
Speaker 0: How am I selling it to?
Speaker 0: like move like relative to the other person.
Speaker 1: I'm moving relative to you, but I'm also kind of moving But I'm the one bearing the burden of acceleration.
Speaker 0: We'll see whatever.
Speaker 1: Well, we already saw.
Speaker 0: so you want to talk about some not real time travels like Terminator or what do you think?
Speaker 1: What would you do first Terminator or back to the future?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think Terminator is actually kind of better than back-to-the-future Time travel.
Speaker 1: Terminator works, but it only works for the same reason that Final Fantasy 1 works time loop You know, I read.
Speaker 1: someone wrote a very long essay.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I could ever find it again, but they basically kind of proved Logically, but not mathematically or anything that the Terminator 1 & 2 forget all those other abortions work as a realistic idea of time travel if it were possible because they're self consistent in that.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: the problem you'd think of is so if you go into the past and Prevent Skynet from forming then Skynet wouldn't form and you would know to send someone into the past to prevent Skynet from forming Which is true, but what could happen is?
Speaker 1: So you Skynet is formed.
Speaker 1: you send someone into the past to stop Skynet from forming.
Speaker 1: Skynet sends someone into the past to do you know and you have this fight.
Speaker 1: if you win The future happens.
Speaker 1: and then you didn't send someone back, but you've altered the timeline slightly regardless.
Speaker 1: So basically you keep looping through these the pseudo same series of events 12 monkeys style and every time it's a little different and eventually You reach in you know a million loops out a situation where?
Speaker 1: Someone from the future came to the past prevented Skynet from forming but at the same time Insured a situation would come to pass to where in the future they would know to send someone back to prevent a future that did Not actually ever occur.
Speaker 0: so Basically the so the final history it might be someone went back into the past.
Speaker 1: it might
Speaker 0: be like listen listen You know where everyone's just chilling around right, and there's some crazy scientists, and he's like look I know we're living in this paradise guys right, but in order for this paradise to work someone has to go back into the past and Make this happen.
Speaker 1: Right we don't know why.
Speaker 1: we can't understand.
Speaker 0: How why couldn't you know why?
Speaker 0: because this Skynet thing would have been formed.
Speaker 0: If we don't go into the past now It's possible.
Speaker 0: You know why?
Speaker 0: I don't understand why knowing why.
Speaker 1: the trouble is that you know if you follow this time loop idea Then every time you go back kind of the future you came from never came to pass So you never went back.
Speaker 1: so it kind of recurses back to before anyone time-traveled Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: so without that future existing.
Speaker 1: you know chrono trigger had the same idea.
Speaker 1: That's why they made chrono across and radical dreamers You know what some world had to have had lavos happen for the people in this world to know to go.
Speaker 1: stop lavos Mmm, or 12 monkeys actually did it very similarly.
Speaker 1: I don't want to talk about that movies I don't want to spoil it for anyone who hasn't seen it, but Awesome bruce willis movie that a lot of people haven't seen.
Speaker 0: stupidly I don't even know what it is really.
Speaker 0: until just now you've really never seen 12 monkeys.
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: how many monkeys?
Speaker 1: well there's 12.
Speaker 0: How come not 13 monkeys?
Speaker 1: Well, that's 13 ghosts.
Speaker 0: What the hell's.
Speaker 0: 13 goes.
Speaker 1: you've never seen 13 ghosts.
Speaker 0: famous old horror movie ten zombies.
Speaker 1: Now my empire is just 13 12 monkeys and 13 ghosts.
Speaker 0: yeah $20.
Speaker 1: I think 13 ghosts is a vincent price movie.
Speaker 1: I don't actually remember.
Speaker 1: I'm not you know.
Speaker 1: a good move hello internet.
Speaker 1: I will look that up right now.
Speaker 0: I already got it.
Speaker 1: I think it was remade though, so look wow They're one three en ghosts 2001. oh, that's a.
Speaker 0: that's a shitty remake and shitty remake.
Speaker 0: 13 goes 1960. that might also be William Castle.
Speaker 0: I Think it's got some stuff.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: that's the one.
Speaker 1: never mind That's more recent than I thought it was but yeah It doesn't have the greatest rating in the world.
Speaker 1: it's a good movie though.
Speaker 0: It says five point nine out of ten on the IMDb.
Speaker 0: It's good.
Speaker 1: the 13 goes to the ender.
Speaker 1: hilarious.
Speaker 0: It's fun to be scared by.
Speaker 0: 13 goes.
Speaker 0: A family inherits what proves to be a haunted house, but a special pair of goggles, but the glass is on.
Speaker 0: They can see the ghosts in the house in the haunted house.
Speaker 0: Okay big deal.
Speaker 1: It's a good plot Horror movie.
Speaker 0: I'd rather watch.
Speaker 1: seventh guest Seventh guest or what about the 11th hour?
Speaker 0: Well, you know seventh guest is very similar to they were 11.
Speaker 1: it is and the 11th hour is basically the sequel to the seventh Guest.
Speaker 0: yep, oh shit Wow Here's some synchronicity was.
Speaker 0: I was riding my bike home And it did clocks at 519 and then I pushed the button and I think the odometer was at like 51.9 miles or whatever.
Speaker 1: you know you know what right now.
Speaker 1: It's 653 and yesterday at the same time.
Speaker 1: It was also 653.
Speaker 0: oh shit You fucking with me man they can't be true.
Speaker 1: You really haven't seen 12 monkeys.
Speaker 1: I can't get over that.
Speaker 0: I even know that you you didn't see the usual suspects when I met you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I still haven't seen dark city.
Speaker 1: that movie is not as good as 12 monk.
Speaker 0: I don't think you understand.
Speaker 0: dark city is like the great usual suspects.
Speaker 1: It's not as good as 12 monkeys.
Speaker 0: what you're fucked up in the head.
Speaker 1: well one 12 monkeys.
Speaker 1: I'm TV is 8.1 out of 10.
Speaker 0: all right, so what's usual suspects at IMDb?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: let me look since we're talking about movies We can just burn this Thursday show on whatever we got.
Speaker 1: the usual suspects is 1995 8.7.
Speaker 1: They're very similarly right.
Speaker 0: What's the other one 8.1?
Speaker 0: I told you I was right very close.
Speaker 0: I got you by 0.6.
Speaker 1: That isn't a non insignificant though because this is usual suspects is newer film.
Speaker 1: It's up 10% this week, but 12 monkeys is down 6% this week.
Speaker 0: Why I don't know.
Speaker 1: I can't have to log into the pro version to see.
Speaker 1: I'm not paying money It's BS.
Speaker 1: Regardless those are good time travel movies?
Speaker 0: no not at all that have any time traveling 12 monkeys.
Speaker 0: Oh, no usual suspects.
Speaker 1: So what about back to the future?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: the back to time travel in back to the future I always felt was sort of ham-fisted and not so great.
Speaker 0: It's like okay.
Speaker 0: You have to go at 88 miles an hour.
Speaker 0: Okay, no right.
Speaker 0: and then it's like what.
Speaker 0: you can go to the future and the past and you sort of disappear And you can make paradoxes, and it's like okay.
Speaker 0: at the same time I think it works in the sense that it makes a good movie, but it's not a good.
Speaker 0: Here's the way it works if time time travel in back to the future is like computers in summer wars.
Speaker 1: ah Here's one thing I can say though the time traveling back to the future Works.
Speaker 1: if you consider the the the worldview that every possible You know instance spawns a million.
Speaker 1: You know every different possible universe, so this follows one universe.
Speaker 1: We're in that universe.
Speaker 1: we follow the timeline of this one guy.
Speaker 1: what time travel.
Speaker 0: So he doesn't go to different universes.
Speaker 0: when he time travels only the same one.
Speaker 1: Maybe he jumps universes or maybe.
Speaker 1: so then jumping is that universe?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, maybe I mean that explains the whole no free will thing.
Speaker 1: every possible thing happens.
Speaker 1: He doesn't have any free will.
Speaker 1: He didn't make any decisions.
Speaker 1: We just watched the non free will iteration through all those events through that one universe Mm-hmm, which followed him.
Speaker 0: the thing is the universe had a history, and then it had a different history, so I didn't Had it so it had dirt.
Speaker 1: With this idea the timeline goes you know big bang all the way up to him going back in time And then the history.
Speaker 1: just the next step is like you've got two timelines.
Speaker 1: You're sticking behind each other.
Speaker 1: the next day is in the 50s.
Speaker 0: So the whole universe actually changes to the 50s.
Speaker 0: yes, so instead actually that's not a bad view of time travel.
Speaker 0: instead of you Traveling in time right what you actually do is you basically rewind the whole universe.
Speaker 0: You're actually going forward in time always But you're just rearranging all the atoms of the entire universe to be in a prior Configuration just like you're rewinding a videotape to start playing from an earlier point.
Speaker 0: right so it is.
Speaker 0: you know time is marching forward.
Speaker 0: It's you know, but everything all the atoms are being moved around to the wave.
Speaker 0: You know all the sub every single particle and every all the energy in the universe.
Speaker 0: the only thing is you know what law of Physics that breaks which one entropy's.
Speaker 0: you're basically undoing entropy's.
Speaker 1: No, because you could be injecting outside energy and say you're in another universe And you're.
Speaker 1: you find a universe, and you basically inject energy into it and control it to make it your own personal TV.
Speaker 1: That I don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe I mean the idea.
Speaker 0: What you would do is you have to create some entropy in one part of the universe because you know.
Speaker 0: But then you could rewind the rest of the universe as law But as long as the end result was greater entropies.
Speaker 0: But by in doing so when you played it forward that added entropy it would not play forward the same way it played forward before Because that entropy is adding a new Element.
Speaker 1: that's also possibly one of the ways out of you know the front row crew.
Speaker 1: for a while We had this whole thing for all you listeners Understanding where we were arguing about free will.
Speaker 1: ever since all the physics articles talking about how it's basically Not possible for there to be free will probably not yeah But basically there are.
Speaker 1: there's a small number of kind of philosophical or possible scientific escapes from that trap And one of them is the idea that we theoretically cannot escape from our universe or interact with the outside.
Speaker 1: But free will could arise in a situation where the universe is 100% deterministic and going along a path But then it's influenced from outside of the universe by something else And we don't know what the rules are.
Speaker 0: we still not have free will therefore It is outside.
Speaker 0: influence is actually just another force controlling our will and even if it is a force that you know is not A force that we can understand within our laws of physics is still a force We have no will full.
Speaker 1: What it would mean is that external things could possibly have free will and then they Screw up the predetermined destiny of the universe that we're in.
Speaker 1: They could screw it up in such a way as to give someone internally free will by kind of fun.
Speaker 0: It would still give you an illusion of free will because even though something could fuck up right it has to be.
Speaker 0: you know a The decision that is made has to be a product of a conscious decision.
Speaker 0: in a human brain.
Speaker 0: If the fuck up is because some guy from outside the universe comes and flicks me and makes me turn left instead of right You know I didn't decide to turn left or right.
Speaker 0: that wasn't the cause.
Speaker 1: the root cause has to be you know from an animal brain in order to free will pulls your you know the the total of your memories and consciousness out of the universe and Instills it with free will from that point forward somehow.
Speaker 1: So now it is a self-moving body.
Speaker 1: like the decision is made he replaces your brain with some material from the outside and your consciousness resides outside or in this material and has control and it basically can control the Physicality of your body.
Speaker 0: so my brain is in another universe.
Speaker 0: But then there is some you know like wormhole ish link between the other universe in this universe Through which my brain can control my body.
Speaker 0: so no scientist would ever See the free will coming from my brain because all they would see was the brain in this universe Which looks like is just doing stuff, but it's actually receiving completely undetectable signals from a free will at another universe and That so it appears to be having no free will of its own whatsoever.
Speaker 0: But the free will component is like in the hundredth dimension or some crazy fuck shit that we just made up.
Speaker 1: I think there's only 11 dimensions according to Kaku.
Speaker 0: so it's in the 13th dimension where they go with the ghosts and the zombies.
Speaker 0: and In fact no this all our all our Consciousnesses all our free wills are actually in the brains of 13 monkeys combined, and there's another universe which is monkeys.
Speaker 1: I remember reading hyperspace.
Speaker 1: They talked about how the fourth spatial dimension Was probably bigger at some point.
Speaker 1: I'm paraphrasing for when I was a young kid.
Speaker 1: But it collapsed and we're basically in it and we can move within it.
Speaker 1: you know strength theory and all that.
Speaker 1: But it's a cylinder, and it's so small that no matter how far we move We don't really move enough.
Speaker 1: like it's like we move around the cylinder so fast.
Speaker 1: There's basically no difference between whatever position.
Speaker 1: We're in in that universe or in that dimension.
Speaker 1: But if we start like imagine we name and find stuff at all the dimensions like the 11th dimension just dicks Just everywhere dicks.
Speaker 0: It's possible.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: It's already poking through fortune.
Speaker 0: I Think fortune.
Speaker 0: I think it wasn't that the fourth dimension.
Speaker 0: I mean 4chan isn't it?
Speaker 1: well if the fourth dimension is a cylinder I mean, it's kind of a primordial phallus.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's enough of that all right stuff of that.
Speaker 1: any other time travel movie.
Speaker 1: We can kill some time with I don't know Kill time boy you miss chairs there.
Speaker 0: any other non movie time travel discussion, okay?
Speaker 0: Let's pretend that movie science fiction time travel was totally for real.
Speaker 1: which movies time travel?
Speaker 1: Anyone you want back to the future is the easiest one.
Speaker 1: so what would you?
Speaker 0: what would you do?
Speaker 1: Well, maybe what about hyperion time travel?
Speaker 0: pick whatever you want.
Speaker 0: Just what were you know?
Speaker 0: you can pick any kind of time travel and do any kind of thing.
Speaker 0: What would you do?
Speaker 1: Honestly my a fantasy of mine would be the ability to travel back in time But in a non interactive manner because that couldn't cause any paradoxes.
Speaker 1: if I could simply view the Sure, you can do it.
Speaker 0: You can do whatever you want.
Speaker 0: You can you know you have a you have a scrying pool.
Speaker 0: You can watch all of history.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically.
Speaker 1: I'd watch the big bang of course.
Speaker 1: I don't know where I'd watch it from But I'd watch the pyramids being built.
Speaker 1: you know see oh they did it some obvious physics way.
Speaker 0: I would also want to see some pyramids because they're smart people.
Speaker 0: I think it's pretty safe to say that.
Speaker 0: any secret of history.
Speaker 0: We would want to see.
Speaker 0: right yeah Is there any secret of history you don't want to see?
Speaker 0: uh?
Speaker 1: Well, I don't want to see what happened to your mom last night again, okay?
Speaker 0: It's not exactly a secret of history right you know you can watch great works being created And you could you know recover things that were lost like it.
Speaker 0: There's a movie that was lost like metropolis.
Speaker 0: You can watch it.
Speaker 1: You just go watch it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know something like that.
Speaker 0: That's easy to do.
Speaker 0: and then what I would do is I would take all the stuff right and I would take all the people That I care about and I would go into the future or the past and also throughout space And I would find the best possible place and time to live.
Speaker 0: and that's the place that I would go.
Speaker 1: well clearly That's the 11th dimension now.
Speaker 0: You know it's like if I find out that like a hundred years in the future in You know Spain or something that this like everything's perfect for like a period of 200 years.
Speaker 0: I'd be like all right Let's go live our lives out in that time period in that place.
Speaker 0: You know and I'll be it and that's how I'd roll.
Speaker 1: I Just I feel like we might have the capability Probably not in our lifetimes, but I think at some point humans will have the ability to somehow Read information from the past in some capacity Maybe by you know if books.
Speaker 1: well if there's no call if there's a perfect causal chain you know that whole idea or Maybe a near-perfect causal chain then theoretically you could Reconstruct the path backward from where you are now.
Speaker 1: the trouble is with entropy is that we currently don't have the ability to do that.
Speaker 1: No cause of entropy.
Speaker 1: I mean well.
Speaker 0: No we can't.
Speaker 0: because of that Maybe because of entry but also because of the information theory stuff that people are talking about where it's like okay to simulate the universe.
Speaker 0: You would also need you need all the information of the universe But you can't possibly hold all the information of the universe in the universe because if you could you basically made it would be bigger.
Speaker 1: Then you can't do it or at best the best you could do is make the universe an exact copy of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 0: But you couldn't make a copy of the universe in the universe because that would be a require the entire universe and thus You could not make you know a copy of a Scott within a Scott because you basically have to use the entire Scott to do It and then you would end up with the Scott you started.
Speaker 1: what about a fat guy that already has enough room for a Scott inside of him?
Speaker 0: But then you're not that that mean we need a second universe already that we would then transform to be a copy of our universe.
Speaker 0: we only have one universe to work with.
Speaker 1: maybe that's our way out of entropy is we?
Speaker 1: when we get near the end we find a universe that's just formed and we Send all our shit there.
Speaker 0: I Guess that could work.
Speaker 0: I mean that's basically the same solution we have for everything right?
Speaker 0: Oh car country is burned down.
Speaker 0: Let's go to another one.
Speaker 0: Oh our planets burning down.
Speaker 0: Let's go to another one our universe burn.
Speaker 0: now Let's go to another one.
Speaker 1: You know that's not an interesting solution, but it's probably the best solution, maybe I Mean really I just you know.
Speaker 1: it goes back to that court thing.
Speaker 1: What if we had the capacity to basically turn on a camera at any point in history and just watch?
Speaker 0: We would turn on a camera at any point history and watch?
Speaker 1: yeah, and it really simplify having jury trials.
Speaker 0: Yeah, one thing that I think is interesting about at least the forward time travel is Stephen Hawking talks about which is totally real right with Relativity.
Speaker 0: is that you know we think oh, we can't possibly achieve Traveling you know far out to other stars and planets because it takes too fucking long.
Speaker 0: And it does take too fucking long.
Speaker 0: like if spaceship took off now Then it would be like a zillion generations before they heard back from.
Speaker 0: you know assuming that we they could even communicate Over such great distances from the spaceship that reached Alpha Centauri or whatever the fuck.
Speaker 0: you're good dramaturge Who knows where the hell you're going right like the galaxy?
Speaker 1: We're heading for Venus, but the thing is if I'm still we stand tall.
Speaker 0: if you can get your spaceship to go faster Like close to the speed of light fast enough right it'll actually get you to Pretty far away in a reasonable time as far as you're concerned because time is so slow.
Speaker 0: you know slowing down for you.
Speaker 0: Well, it's so long as you're going so fast.
Speaker 1: the trouble is it still won't get you Anywhere that there is to get because that the closest thing anywhere outside of our solar system is so far away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean if you're traveling close to the speed of light.
Speaker 0: It'll be a matter of like.
Speaker 1: you know hundreds of light years.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so hundreds of years right you will get there.
Speaker 0: I?
Speaker 1: Think.
Speaker 1: more interesting is you know Hyperion talked about this Phoenix talked about this is that we can use forward time travel to Create kind of wealths of knowledge and elder wisdom.
Speaker 1: I mean how many stories are there now of the idea that you've got a group of elders who?
Speaker 1: Come to the earth give a bunch of decisions and then fly up into a spaceship and circle the earth once very fast.
Speaker 1: You know basically traveling forward in time 100 years, so they reappear every hundred years.
Speaker 1: see how far We've come in a hundred years.
Speaker 1: have the wisdom of the last 10 million years of seeing a day's worth of human history.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean once you know we have pretty good data storage right now We could load like a whole shit ton of knowledge into a bunch of hard drives Take a whole bunch of extras and just fly them around the earth real fast And that could be someone's job, and I would totally sign up for that.
Speaker 1: I would go into the future you need to bring.
Speaker 0: the thing is though you would need to bring a whole crew.
Speaker 0: you would Need a doctor right you would?
Speaker 0: you need like two doctors to computer.
Speaker 0: peep You know mole you probably need the four computer people right?
Speaker 0: you need some astronauts who could repair the shit You would need.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: and the thing is every time you came down What you'd probably do is you would get all new technology all new stuff But the thing is right.
Speaker 0: what if you go around?
Speaker 0: And then you're going around looking at the earth and the earth is basically going in fast motion from your from your perspective.
Speaker 0: because right You're.
Speaker 0: why?
Speaker 0: basically watching the earth and fast-forward with your telescopes or whatever.
Speaker 0: It's like Sim City right exactly?
Speaker 1: So you don't have to sit out there, then you see nukes like damn it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you just see the earth is like turns Brown like freaking space about to be on the toe.
Speaker 0: you're like fuck.
Speaker 1: What do I do now come back down like what the fuck did you guys do the whole thing.
Speaker 0: you basically gave up your whole?
Speaker 0: Human life for that and now is nothing, but at the same time What do you do now?
Speaker 0: You know you escaped so you basically had to bring some women's and some in some dudes And you basically have to have the plan of okay, you know if this doesn't if we see the earth turn to shit We have to go down and start again.
Speaker 0: You know it's like the insurance policy for the whole earth.
Speaker 1: There's always the fun time travel like the girl who left through time.
Speaker 0: I didn't watch that yet.
Speaker 1: Oh, you didn't watch that.
Speaker 1: the same person did summer wars.
Speaker 1: I know I can't believe you got to see that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, tell me how many other million things.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen.
Speaker 0: I don't 12 monkeys, okay?
Speaker 0: You didn't see dark city still.
Speaker 1: I Think we've talked enough about time travel.
Speaker 0: all right.
Speaker 0: That's cool.
Speaker 1: We'll kill it.
Speaker 1: See you next week kids.
Speaker 0: It's killed.
Speaker 1: Mustn't kill time boy.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one, but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.