Speaker 0: Hey, it's Tuesday, March 9th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 0: paranoia.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: I feel like we should have said something.
Speaker 1: no, I feel like we should have said something.
Speaker 0: Are you impinging upon me?
Speaker 0: Are you are you a communist?
Speaker 0: No, I got nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel I always feel really awkward quoting like paranoia in any way Like if I ever ask anyone are you a happy communist on one hand or just be like why?
Speaker 0: well No, even if they know paranoia on one hand.
Speaker 0: It's social currency It's the whole.
Speaker 0: I am saying something from a media.
Speaker 0: that is cool Hoping that you will respond in kind thus proving that we can be friends.
Speaker 0: But at the same time if someone says to you the cake is a lie.
Speaker 0: What do you do?
Speaker 1: smack them up?
Speaker 0: So that's why I can't ever ask anyone if they're a happy communist.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: But at the same time I I know everyone's played portal, I don't know everyone's played paranoia.
Speaker 1: almost no one's played paranoia.
Speaker 1: Yeah, most it's weird.
Speaker 1: It's like this.
Speaker 1: it's one of those things That's like.
Speaker 1: it's popular enough that people know it, but it's not so popular like portal that everyone knows.
Speaker 1: I think a lot you can use it as an awesome detector.
Speaker 1: You can just be like Hey, it You know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, have you troubleshooted anything down in sector 3 lately?
Speaker 1: Right and if they respond appropriately then it's like aha I know this is a smart cool person, but it's the same thing.
Speaker 0: the cake is a lie.
Speaker 0: people are doing.
Speaker 1: Okay, well, let's save it for the actual main big business the main topic.
Speaker 0: All right, so I guess we have to talk about this because everyone else is gonna talk about it.
Speaker 0: And it's it's hilarious in manifold ways.
Speaker 0: so in case you weren't paying attention Ubisoft Decided to go all the way with DRM.
Speaker 0: They were like you know what we're going to just have the DRM.
Speaker 0: That is exactly as evil as everyone ever said DRM could be.
Speaker 0: You've got to have your internet connection all the time.
Speaker 0: if it drops for a second your game Just crashes and done well again doesn't crash.
Speaker 1: basically just doesn't let you play The internet.
Speaker 1: it will check every time you run the game You know with the DRM servers and constantly while you're playing the game And it stops your game.
Speaker 0: it interrupts the game if you lose the internet mm-hmm Or if you know anything goes wrong anywhere between your computer and their DRM servers.
Speaker 1: obviously people who don't have internet connections Can't play people with like you know even if they want to play.
Speaker 1: single-player isn't just multiplayer.
Speaker 1: This is a single player.
Speaker 1: even if they have like a dial-up modem.
Speaker 1: They probably are not gonna be able to play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what about poor people like me who tend to put steam in offline mode and plan laptops up?
Speaker 1: Yeah, can't plan an airplane unless the airplane is one of those cool airplanes with Wi-Fi can't play if the Wi-Fi is congested.
Speaker 1: So basically why would you buy this game?
Speaker 1: You know for you know the PC.
Speaker 1: You wouldn't.
Speaker 1: you'd be a moron if you did.
Speaker 0: and the thing is I mean a lot of people have made the I guess The best counter-argument you can make that every gamer who's serious about gaming one They're not gonna play this game on a laptop and to everyone just has broadband.
Speaker 0: It's no big deal except for you know the military people overseas who are some of the biggest gamers.
Speaker 1: There are yeah You know they don't always have a reliable internet connection.
Speaker 1: most lot of people do not always have reliable internet connection.
Speaker 1: We are not in the ghost in the shell world.
Speaker 1: you cannot write code that just assumes that there is a perfect and awesome You know connection to the internet at all times.
Speaker 0: I can't even write code that assumes that another demon on my server will get messages I sent to it exactly you know.
Speaker 1: so you know.
Speaker 1: until that day comes when networks are like incredibly reliable and super fast and awesome probably after we're dead then You can write this code and have this DRM But until then no and even in that such a world that DRM probably still would not work.
Speaker 0: So what's interesting though is that they were there was a lot of talk, and there's even a slash shot article.
Speaker 0: I think it said the DRM scheme that will work and people were talking about how.
Speaker 0: yes It's going to eventually be cracked But it'll take a long time for it to be cracked and in the meantime The people who care about the game are gonna be forced to buy it.
Speaker 0: the company will make its money and DRM will serve its purpose.
Speaker 0: It's the nuclear option.
Speaker 0: It's the final.
Speaker 0: This is it.
Speaker 0: It's happening and everything will be fine at.
Speaker 0: it was cracked right away.
Speaker 1: It was cracked like the next day as predicted right, and I know they denied that it was cracked though They said it wasn't and that the people who think they cracked it will get a nasty surprise Or something.
Speaker 1: and then in addition to that.
Speaker 1: right there DRM server went down if people couldn't play the game.
Speaker 0: well Let's get back to that.
Speaker 0: so one they said you know that something ominously bad will happen.
Speaker 0: Maybe they'll do what?
Speaker 0: was that one game where it just kept you on the boat.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, there was a Okay, so here's two stories right.
Speaker 1: number one There's a Dragon Quest game.
Speaker 1: And if you got a cracked version for the DS because DS piracy is huge with the r4 cartridges Then basically you couldn't get past the first screen like it would work But the first screen in the game you wouldn't be able to get past the boat you just be on this boat forever.
Speaker 1: It would say talk to all the people on the boat to continue and even if you talk to all the people on the boat Twice you wouldn't be able to continue.
Speaker 0: I forget what game It was.
Speaker 0: there was a PC game that did something similar where if the CD was copied And it didn't like catch this extra data on it the game would play perfectly normally.
Speaker 0: But it would ramp up the difficulty bit by bit and eventually about halfway through the game make it impossible Yep, and then corrupt your save file.
Speaker 1: So the other there's another story.
Speaker 1: I could I could find the link if I can remember and basically some guy who worked on Like a Spyro PlayStation game or something like that I forget what it was.
Speaker 0: I remember those games.
Speaker 1: He they they apparently made this crazy DRM that they were so proud of.
Speaker 1: and this DRM You know what it did was basically the game would appear to be cracked.
Speaker 1: but and so the crackers?
Speaker 1: they cracked it and they put it out there and they just said oh it works.
Speaker 1: and Then people who actually played the cracked version like the dialogue would be like you are playing a pirated version of the game.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna let you continue blah blah blah or.
Speaker 1: some people also do clever things like you'll get a never-ending level with infinite bad Guys, I think it's an iPhone game.
Speaker 1: if you pirate it does that.
Speaker 1: and the thing is you know these are you know from their?
Speaker 1: You know perspective.
Speaker 1: these are some pretty clever DRMs because you think about it people doing the cracks Right.
Speaker 1: those people are not interested in actually in playing the games.
Speaker 1: most of the time cracking is their game.
Speaker 1: You know it's like they want you to make a difficult crack for them So they can figure out how to break it.
Speaker 1: so the more difficult your crack the more you're basically spending development time Creating this free game.
Speaker 1: the free game is called break my DRM and the only people playing are these crackers And they're not actually gonna play Spyro or Assassin's Creed or your iPhone game.
Speaker 1: They don't give a shit, and then there's other people they're playing the game of.
Speaker 1: I have no money.
Speaker 1: I want to play all these games.
Speaker 1: I will get them for free from these crackers.
Speaker 1: all right and those people the ones who get upset when the crack doesn't Actually work the one thing that I'm really want someone to see.
Speaker 1: if anyone has freaking balls, right Show me the sales figures of DRM versus non DRM because I am entirely convinced right that Having this DRM no matter how good or bad it is and how strong or weak it is Doesn't help your sales at all.
Speaker 1: if I live let's say this DRM that I said you know they had.
Speaker 0: Well, you're getting back into the old argument of the vast majority of people who pirate things Only pirate because they place zero value on this entertainment.
Speaker 1: exactly they have.
Speaker 0: they have taught They're willing to spend their time to play the game.
Speaker 0: They're not willing to spend any other resource on most games.
Speaker 1: Yep, or the second if they could not pirate the game They would not play the game.
Speaker 0: the secondary list of people are people like me who actually do pirate.
Speaker 0: I don't bother pirating games.
Speaker 0: I have money.
Speaker 0: time is more valuable to me than money.
Speaker 0: So I won't bother with these cracks or anything, but I don't buy games when they come out anywhere.
Speaker 0: I've been burned too many times by a get like a new Zelda game Just not being as good as it should have been.
Speaker 0: or you know what about Bioshock?
Speaker 0: Bioshock wasn't worth buying when I bought it.
Speaker 0: I should have bought it last week for five bucks.
Speaker 1: It's really five bucks now.
Speaker 0: I don't know how much it is.
Speaker 0: man All the.
Speaker 0: any game that isn't a multiplayer game or some sort of Important game like portal where you have to play it or you give me that jackass saying the cake is a lie here later.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you.
Speaker 1: or a multiplayer game You know like NS2 you got to play it when it comes out because that's when the the you got to strike while the iron Is hot.
Speaker 0: well that is the separate problem of we learned.
Speaker 0: we learned very well from tribes too Because had we not bought tribes to immediately when it came out We would have had fewer hours of total tribes to playing in our lives.
Speaker 0: Yeah And I don't know if I could have stomach that later.
Speaker 0: now imagine if we'd gotten tribes to Like at the end of that whole era played it for like a week, and then it was dead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that'd be like finding You know you're some like peasant in the medieval times, and you find these ancient Roman ruins and all you can see is how awesome They were.
Speaker 1: Right you know, but I want to see.
Speaker 1: see nobody has ever done this.
Speaker 1: publish me your sales figures Right.
Speaker 1: put out that you know a game without DRM, and then put out a game with DRM.
Speaker 1: That's similar games.
Speaker 0: Similar games are.
Speaker 0: sorry I release an example.
Speaker 1: right Assassin's Creed 1 for the PC Assassin's Creed 2 for the PC.
Speaker 1: They could you know they could have done one with no DRM and one with DRM And you would assume they would have similar sales figures.
Speaker 1: You know give me give me portal 1 versus portal 2 1 DRM 1 no DRM.
Speaker 1: I have a. show me the difference in sales.
Speaker 0: It's hard though because the I mean portal 1 and sales versus portal 2.
Speaker 0: I mean I think it's gonna be completely different sales.
Speaker 0: I align Portal 2 is gonna have pretty much immediate everyone buying it right away because of the success of portal 1.
Speaker 0: Portal 1 had a spike in the beginning in the long tail of people Finding out the cake is a lie and then caring about it.
Speaker 1: the point is until someone shows some evidence of the contrary I will remain entirely unconvinced.
Speaker 1: I do not.
Speaker 1: I think you know putting DRM is a complete waste of time because even if it works Even if the crackers can't crack it it doesn't help your sales.
Speaker 1: well the people who are pirating would never have bought it in any Situation.
Speaker 0: there are many myriad arguments against DRM, and you've made one of them.
Speaker 0: I think the root issue is still that the vast majority of people now have no money not money.
Speaker 1: The people pirating are punk kids with no money.
Speaker 0: That's not that if they had money.
Speaker 0: They wouldn't buy the game.
Speaker 0: They wouldn't care.
Speaker 0: they only play the game because they don't care.
Speaker 0: they it's there.
Speaker 0: I'm bored.
Speaker 0: Let's see what's on YouTube.
Speaker 0: all right I've seen too many people get in the nuts.
Speaker 0: Let's go to crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: I'll watch all these shows because they're free yep.
Speaker 0: But the main argument against DRM all those other arguments aside and all the others didn't even make is That it only hurts the people who actually did pay you money.
Speaker 0: Yep, and Ubisoft proved this epically when just all this press.
Speaker 0: you know their DRM.
Speaker 0: It's uncrackable.
Speaker 0: it got cracked right away.
Speaker 0: Their servers went down.
Speaker 0: the only people who actually could play the game were the people who pirated it.
Speaker 1: So I think this is why people are.
Speaker 1: you know steam and Netflix are the two people with DRM.
Speaker 1: they get away with it because?
Speaker 1: It works.
Speaker 1: It actually does work.
Speaker 1: You know steam doesn't really go down.
Speaker 1: You know the offline play.
Speaker 1: You know they keep fixing it.
Speaker 1: It works mostly perfectly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know the Netflix has you know DRM, but it works and Nobody complains about it because it just works.
Speaker 1: and of course you know if this Ubisoft Assassin's Creed DRM had worked then Nobody would have laughed at it, but because it was cracked and because the server went down everyone goes aha You're right you fail.
Speaker 0: Well even you know cracked or not doesn't matter because that's not going to affect the bottom line.
Speaker 0: if the game like this never gets Cracked then all the people who would pirate it just won't ever play it.
Speaker 0: yep Or at most they'll buy it in the discount bin a couple of years from now.
Speaker 1: Yep But you know you think if you know what if they would have made the game $5 discount bin price.
Speaker 1: to begin with Sales.
Speaker 1: the sales would have been more than 10 times as much.
Speaker 1: What are they charging?
Speaker 1: I think 60 for the game, so they would have been more than 12 times as much.
Speaker 1: right they would have made More money and all those people who went on to you know wait for the crack or whatever would have said I was five bucks Whatever and just bought it because it would be easier that way.
Speaker 0: see now if we go back to the root issue of just people Don't value these entertainment options enough to pay money for them.
Speaker 0: What about the the people like us who don't pirate but buy everything in the discount bin?
Speaker 0: That I think hurts the industry just as much as piracy, but yet That's perfectly legal.
Speaker 1: and well the argument you can make against that the argument comic book people make this argument all the time.
Speaker 1: They say oh you got to buy the issues.
Speaker 1: You can't be buying the trades.
Speaker 1: You're hurting the you know artists, and I'm like if they don't make the trade then oh, but they have to to make the money.
Speaker 1: I'm like gee Make up your mind.
Speaker 1: Either they need to do it to make the money yet, but they'd be making more money if you you know bought the issues.
Speaker 1: It's not a charity.
Speaker 1: Go listen to that episode of geek nights.
Speaker 0: Wow that was a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like we were fighting with anime world order.
Speaker 1: It's not a charity.
Speaker 1: right consumer is number one.
Speaker 1: businesses that recognize consumers number ten.
Speaker 1: right those are the businesses That'll be king.
Speaker 1: businesses that say our business is number one and consumer is number ten.
Speaker 1: those businesses fuck them.
Speaker 1: We should steal from them because they're basically just assholes.
Speaker 0: now see I guess it's tricky that all this argue and this happens forever.
Speaker 0: Everyone rabbles out piracy and DRM on the internet and punk kids always rabble like DRM blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: It's evil I'm gonna pirate.
Speaker 0: I'll show them and they conflate some moral cause with their piracy which is pretty BS.
Speaker 0: But at the same time yeah, what's wrong with you know?
Speaker 0: I think people have been looking down on Civil disobedience lately and I think we need to most of the people I see who pirate stuff and conflate any sort of moral stand Don't actually have any moral stand as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: all they really have to say is I don't want to pay for this game.
Speaker 1: The other thing I think is that when someone we've been going on about this too long.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the root issue is just that even if there is perfect DRM Until we also lose our right to first sale the discount bin is more of a threat to gaming or at least the current gaming industry than piracy ever was Because the discount bin people still buy games.
Speaker 1: They're actually.
Speaker 1: I'll talk about it on the next show once I get the info.
Speaker 1: But there actually was a Linux game DRM developed recently that allowed you to resell the game with some clever technology.
Speaker 0: That is a good idea alright, so anyway.
Speaker 1: So in the other news steam related right.
Speaker 1: everyone probably knows this by now, but better Yeah, but steam is coming to the Mac.
Speaker 1: I should have realized this when they switched from IE to webkit.
Speaker 1: you know in the in the steam beta That's one of those situations where the nerds of the world said it's like oh, I should have seen.
Speaker 1: that was kind of obvious.
Speaker 1: What's wrong with me?
Speaker 1: anyway, so you know the thing is okay?
Speaker 1: So how is this gonna work right?
Speaker 1: what games exactly?
Speaker 1: because most games on steam are not are obviously not gonna be ported right?
Speaker 1: So which games and such and such?
Speaker 1: so basically here's here's the rundown right?
Speaker 1: Valve is porting the source engine right, so I don't think that includes For example Half-Life 1 or NS Source source.
Speaker 1: yes, it includes like Counter-Strike source, but I don't think you can play original I don't.
Speaker 1: it doesn't seem like they're doing the original Half-Life.
Speaker 0: and here's the thing.
Speaker 1: no only doing the source engine.
Speaker 0: No one on a Mac gives one shit about Counter-Strike 1 6, but they can't play NS 1.
Speaker 1: They'll only be able to play.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: and will they be able to play NS 2?
Speaker 0: probably not either yeah But that's a separate issue.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so other interesting pieces of information.
Speaker 1: right if you already have these games purchased on Steam And you get a Mac you can just download them.
Speaker 1: You don't to pay for the game again You know.
Speaker 1: so if I have a Mac laptop and a Windows desktop I can and I have Half-Life 2 I can just download Half-Life 2 on my.
Speaker 1: you know Mac You know Sony.
Speaker 0: you can learn a thing or two from this.
Speaker 0: I Still think the best way For game publishers to make a whole bunch of money is to have don't give away No Don't do?
Speaker 0: it seemed it don't.
Speaker 0: do the good thing and give every version of the game to someone who bought it.
Speaker 0: But say all right you bought Street Fighter on the PC for five bucks.
Speaker 0: You can have it on your Xbox, too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the other question is you know what about the graphics hardware?
Speaker 1: You know because people play games on computers with.
Speaker 1: you know high-end video cards And you know the Macs don't really have poopy video cards, but they don't have great video cards either.
Speaker 1: They've got like you know g-forces and whatever, but they're not high-end.
Speaker 1: They're not way powerful.
Speaker 1: They can almost definitely do like Half-Life 2 But could they do like Left 4 Dead 2 you know which needs a little more power to do like the level with the rain And the storm and all that?
Speaker 0: also what kinds of drivers I mean they're?
Speaker 0: they're not gonna have the same kind of Nvidia driver that I have I guess an Nvidia chip.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so you know they're basically they're extending.
Speaker 1: the source engine is support OpenGL And you know I guess they're gonna have to.
Speaker 1: The thing is at least they don't have to.
Speaker 1: it's gonna be pretty easy because they won't have to scale it to.
Speaker 1: you know Support different levels of graphics as much because it's pretty much only so many Macs And you know you know what they all have.
Speaker 1: so you be like oh, this is a MacBook Pro.
Speaker 1: These are the settings you know.
Speaker 0: in fact they could probably do something like you know how steam detects your settings.
Speaker 0: They do those periodic hardware surveys.
Speaker 1: They're gonna do the hardware survey on the Mac.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's gonna be really interesting But what the cool thing will be if I were them?
Speaker 0: what I would do is have it figure out exactly which Mac It is and then have some people who spend the time to figure out the optimum Graphics settings for each game for each kind of Mac.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: just to give Mac.
Speaker 0: You know you gotta give Mac people the Mac experience.
Speaker 0: It's got to just work there with no fiddling and be perfect immediately or at least as good as that Particular Mac can do.
Speaker 1: our Mac mini over there is not gonna be playing any half-life - yeah Still the thing that I worry about though is like you know the Mac still doesn't have.
Speaker 1: you know It's not gonna help them out with a lot of other things like you can't really use a joystick on the Mac.
Speaker 0: that well Well, you can but here's the problem.
Speaker 0: hardly barely if you pay for third-party software that does it well You know, but there's.
Speaker 1: you know they might build something in.
Speaker 1: it's like to add joystick support But the Mac OS itself doesn't have joystick support in it.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: so they had to add that Themselves because I know for example Team Fortress 2 you can play with an Xbox 360 controller on Windows.
Speaker 1: if that's your thing I don't know why you would do that For that game.
Speaker 0: you're not missing that much.
Speaker 0: Yeah games the mouse anyway.
Speaker 1: The second thing is like in win in When you're using Windows you have like a you know PC keyboard.
Speaker 1: trying to game with a Mac keyboard.
Speaker 1: You know it's not gonna work out too.
Speaker 1: Well like most Macs are laptops You know.
Speaker 1: and if even if you have a desktop Mac if you have a Mac Mouse God help you right right?
Speaker 1: So you know if you're gonna game on a Mac you're.
Speaker 1: even if these games work You're still gonna need like a PC Mouse and keyboard to get the right experience.
Speaker 1: Maybe you could use a PC Mouse with the Mac keyboard the chiclets.
Speaker 1: well It would still kind of suck, but it would be.
Speaker 0: I at least have a fish.
Speaker 0: I remember when Emily very pointedly got a Microsoft Mouse, and she was like it has three buttons.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think a lot of Mac users use real mice.
Speaker 1: now You know Pete there are people who are fans of the Mighty Mouse and there were people who are fans of the new Magic Mouse And it's sort of a love it or hate it thing.
Speaker 1: But the Magic Mouse even if you're one of those people who loves it You know which I think is maybe like five percent of people maybe even less than that.
Speaker 1: all right You can't really game with gestures.
Speaker 1: You know that is not precision enough.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: You know you do gesture, and you're like you change three weapons.
Speaker 1: It's like I know how.
Speaker 1: you know how you need to have clicks.
Speaker 1: you can scroll exactly one to change your weapon exactly one.
Speaker 0: Here's another problem something that is far more subtle that I don't think anyone has taken into account.
Speaker 0: on Windows Everything's great when I play an FPS, but remember when I bought the Mac mini And I tried the mouse sensitivity was the worst max.
Speaker 0: It works fine.
Speaker 0: if you're a desktop browser And you're not used to like ultra high precision like very kind of granular it like Fiddly mouse controls, which I like I have my mouse way way up.
Speaker 0: Yes I have that fancy mouse.
Speaker 0: now if I put it to the max It's literally.
Speaker 0: I move it a millimeter and the mouse is all the way across the screen mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So I had to actually turn it down.
Speaker 0: you cannot play an FPS with the way max handle mice by default.
Speaker 1: well actually at work I have a Mac right which I'm not a fan of but that's what I got.
Speaker 0: so how's the mouse sensitivity?
Speaker 1: it's terrible But I have this Logitech g6 gaming mouse.
Speaker 1: It's just a wired you know gaming mouse And it has buttons to move the sensitivity up and down has three different sensitivity settings And it's in the hardware of the mouse that it changes this.
Speaker 1: so if I up the sensitivity in this gaming mouse To like the second or third level it actually becomes pretty good right.
Speaker 1: So if you get like you know say your mouse there right to work with the Mac I don't think it does.
Speaker 0: I think it'll work as a mouse.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I gotta try.
Speaker 1: you can get the hardware of the mouse to jack up the sensitivity as Opposed to letting the Mac OS handle it.
Speaker 1: then you can probably get a passable mouse sensitivity experience.
Speaker 1: But you still you need to get in gaming mouse.
Speaker 1: You know I can play.
Speaker 1: you know It's not the greatest, but I can use like a Dell two button with a scroll wheel USB mouse right with a red optical normalness.
Speaker 1: It's not the greatest But I can play an FPS with that just fine.
Speaker 0: hey having grown up with the era of Optical mice that you could not use for gaming or before that real mice Yeah, remember like picking up the mouse and like tapping the tapping down together.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I used to use that wheel like as part of my gaming.
Speaker 0: I had to take that wheel into account.
Speaker 1: yep I had a gaming mouse.
Speaker 1: I think I still have it a logic USB gaming mouse that had.
Speaker 1: it was just three buttons didn't before scroll wheels were around Right and it had a ball, but it was a bigger ball than usual.
Speaker 1: It was like an extra-large ball for gaming.
Speaker 0: so I See you've got the biggest balls of them all.
Speaker 1: I had the biggest ball.
Speaker 0: I had a friend who used a trackball for FPS.
Speaker 1: is that's still a good call?
Speaker 0: Yeah, this gigantic trackball It was the kind that'll cut your finger off if you get it going too fast and catch it down at the edge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's still a good move if you can if you're used to it especially for rampart.
Speaker 0: What he always wanted and he talked about this almost every day You know back when we're really into FPS is he wanted a mouse that had a trackball in it That was ultra like ultra low sensitivity.
Speaker 0: So he basically used the mouse for his normal FPS and but then when he was sniping He just put his finger on that trackball there.
Speaker 1: Why don't we make that?
Speaker 1: we could make.
Speaker 1: it would just be a mouse with a thumb Trackball and a middle finger scroll wheel right and then two buttons for index and ring finger Right.
Speaker 1: and basically what you would do is the the mouse itself be a laser mouse.
Speaker 1: that would work normally But the thumb scroll the trackball would also always be on and would be ultra low sensitivity.
Speaker 1: So you could you could do a sweeping movement towards the enemy, but then precisionally aim exactly at his head with the thumb.
Speaker 0: Of course I can do something similar.
Speaker 0: now that I got that fancy mouse I can click the button that goes between ultra high and ultra low.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what I can do with the mouse that I have at work And that's actually becoming very popular these days is the gaming mouse that allows you to change sensitivity.
Speaker 1: So, you know you go you just you're sniping and you change you drop the sensitivity and then you're running.
Speaker 1: So you crank it way up.
Speaker 0: what I haven't done yet But I used to I'll admit I used to do this back in the like action quake days I would actually change my vertical sensitivity as opposed my horizontal.
Speaker 0: Whoa, so I'd basically pseudo lock my mouse at head level and then just sweep left and right.
Speaker 0: basically, yes, and it worked Horrifyingly well.
Speaker 1: that works incredibly.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is if you duck you've got a. you know You've got to have two different lock position.
Speaker 0: No, what you do is you set up the law.
Speaker 1: I guess there's no ducking and quake.
Speaker 1: But if you're playing counter-strike you would need to position the way the mouse works.
Speaker 0: is you pick you make all these profiles.
Speaker 0: So what I could do is have a profile for counter-strike Let's say where if I hit a certain button or I hold it down or whatever it basically Cuts down my vertical sensitivity to almost nothing.
Speaker 0: So I go up to head level while I'm shooting at someone and as soon as I'm at a head level I hit this and it locks on head level.
Speaker 0: Now at what point does this become cheating?
Speaker 0: yeah, I Don't know.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm just.
Speaker 0: I'm not actually aim botting.
Speaker 0: if I do that I'm just changing the way.
Speaker 1: I personally have to aim horizontally Yes, and you can still move the mouse vertically.
Speaker 1: It just take a lot of work.
Speaker 0: I could set it to zero.
Speaker 1: Yeah The other thing is that you know in a game like say counter-strike you we try to do that with the para The recoil would move you out of position and be very different.
Speaker 1: You know if you had the low sensitivity you couldn't get back down true true for sniping.
Speaker 1: It would be very effective.
Speaker 0: The other thing you can do is it actually lets me specify, you know All mines do sorts of corrections Like if you're trying to draw in a straight line most mice will kind of guide you into a straight line if they think it's Obvious you're doing a straight line.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all the.
Speaker 1: actually there was a good Article I read that showed how the different Touchscreens and the different phones correct for when you're sliding around And it showed how pretty much the iPhone does.
Speaker 1: does it better than everyone else?
Speaker 0: Things of the day.
Speaker 0: This is totally just ripped off from College Humor.
Speaker 0: I try to avoid that but I had to.
Speaker 0: I Like the song.
Speaker 0: I'm on a boat Not like ironically like he.
Speaker 0: he I mean I just straight-up like it.
Speaker 0: I think it's a great song.
Speaker 1: It's an okay song.
Speaker 0: I like it a little bit independent of all the humor and all the side stuff and the meta and the meme and everything.
Speaker 0: I like the song and I feel like the people behind the song where I don't know if we've talked about them But they they've gotten.
Speaker 0: they've improved their comedic songwriting abilities with every iteration of songs.
Speaker 0: They have done Mmm, I look forward to future songs by them.
Speaker 0: Hmm and a while ago, you know We did the I'm on a boat and we did that cool cover that a bunch of Navy guys did like.
Speaker 0: they basically filmed their Own music video to it.
Speaker 0: I now have to present to you.
Speaker 0: I'm on a boat the death metal cover.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I saw today, you know, amv hell not anime hell that you know, which is what you do at a convention Hell something that you show at a convention, right?
Speaker 1: So amv hell did like this these video.
Speaker 1: That's like a bunch of little me and these hells tiny ones all grouped up in a one YouTube video.
Speaker 1: And the final video of this collection was Pokemon, I'm on a boat using you know, the boat that's in the first Pokemon.
Speaker 0: That's okay.
Speaker 1: It was pretty funny.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's anywhere near mindless self-indulgence But it was still you know, a little Pokemon.
Speaker 1: I'm on a boat was fun.
Speaker 1: Okay, it's my thing today.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: There's this guy named Jake Adelstein.
Speaker 1: I didn't know about him until today, but apparently he's you know more famous than us.
Speaker 1: at least.
Speaker 1: He is an American Jew from the Midwest, right?
Speaker 1: Obviously with the name like Adelstein Obviously from the Midwest right and you know what his job was.
Speaker 1: I Don't know.
Speaker 1: his job was.
Speaker 1: he was the crime reporter for a newspaper in Japan.
Speaker 1: That and he lived in Japan and he was a crime reporter All right, and basically he became just.
Speaker 1: his life became a life of Yakuza.
Speaker 0: Oh This guy I think he was on the Daily Show.
Speaker 1: I think he was.
Speaker 1: people were saying something about that in the comments.
Speaker 0: I think I saw him on the Daily Show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I want to see him on the Daily Show.
Speaker 0: now that I know that I'll find the episode cuz if it I remember Seeing an interview.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it was on the Daily Show where he was talking about how he like he covered up all this Stuff he uncovered for a while because he didn't want to die.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he apparently carries around a titanium umbrella.
Speaker 1: I Should carry instead of a new umbrella instead of a baseball bat because you know, it's just like whatever.
Speaker 1: But if you try to fuck with him, he'll just bash you over the head.
Speaker 1: And he apparently had to break a dude's knee once with a golf club.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh some Yakuza men.
Speaker 0: if the Yakuza can't take this guy out.
Speaker 0: I mean, what if they sunk?
Speaker 1: Well, I think it's.
Speaker 1: he basically is in a situation You know, he played it cuz he was so smart and in with it, you know, and apparently Yakuza always keep their word.
Speaker 0: Well, he did this whole expose and how the Yakuza would come to America to get possibly black market livers.
Speaker 1: Well, no, there's one guy in particular who was like the biggest Yakuza who came to get a liver Candle in the Daily Show thing he implied.
Speaker 0: I recall that that was common Because Yakuza lose the livers real fast.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but anyway, so, you know There's a really good interview with him on Boeing Boeing here.
Speaker 1: that says a lot of interesting things and apparently he's got a couple books.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go buy his books because they need a book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they say I like Yakuza.
Speaker 1: At least I you know, I don't.
Speaker 1: actually I don't actually like Yakuza.
Speaker 1: in that I think they are, you know, I want to be one.
Speaker 1: well I want to be involved with them.
Speaker 1: But in that, you know, it is it be mystique of Yakuza is cool because I've sort of you know I had my fill of.
Speaker 1: you know, Italian mafia so now and Russian mafia.
Speaker 1: So now it's like.
Speaker 1: well, I need to get some eyes.
Speaker 1: mafia.
Speaker 0: You want to be a Yakuza or a British naval captain?
Speaker 0: But only if they are like we see them in sanctuary in Horatio exactly and not if they're like the real world exactly.
Speaker 0: I don't want to actually have been to the West Indies.
Speaker 1: I do want to have been to the West Indies on a cruise.
Speaker 1: Yes Going on a boat.
Speaker 0: I don't want to be suffering from tropical diseases in a wooden boat.
Speaker 1: but anyway, this dude is really fascinating and I want to Check out his books cuz they sound awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll have to find that Daily Show for you.
Speaker 0: Yeah So speaking of books, it's the meta Minute in a moment.
Speaker 1: We don't know.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so number one, of course book club is Carl Sagan's cosmos one of the most important.
Speaker 1: I was thinking do you want to change book club to like the Like book of the quarter like we do for a year or book of the by month Like we do one every two months?
Speaker 1: some guarantee like that.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Have you started reading cosmos yet new?
Speaker 1: Well, do you have a copy for me?
Speaker 0: I have one copy.
Speaker 0: Are you my old copy that I'm reading again?
Speaker 1: Well when you're done, I'll take it.
Speaker 1: All right, unless I get to the library first.
Speaker 0: cuz you know, I'm sure it's in the library.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm sure.
Speaker 0: Maybe just call it the club.
Speaker 1: Okay edgy something like that.
Speaker 1: Anyway news number two packs East not packs West yet.
Speaker 1: So there's actually you know, there's.
Speaker 1: the panels are doing.
Speaker 1: it packs East all three and Asterisk one of them.
Speaker 0: Yep beyond Dungeons & Dragons beyond candy land beyond your mom.
Speaker 1: No, not beyond your mom.
Speaker 0: losing should be fun and we are hopefully helping in the second half of Action Castle action castle.
Speaker 1: There's our panels.
Speaker 1: Okay The schedule is out.
Speaker 1: You can go find out when and where our panels will be.
Speaker 1: I think they're all in the wyvern theater.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling that the running person running the wyvern theater is an awesome person.
Speaker 0: it may in fact be.
Speaker 0: well We don't want to.
Speaker 1: I just have a feeling about this.
Speaker 1: It's a hunch.
Speaker 1: There are some additional news about this convention.
Speaker 1: Yes late-breaking news.
Speaker 1: Now we were worried because when you for every packs in all of history every West Coast packs when you applied to packs You would check off a box.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: I want to be in a mega knot.
Speaker 1: No, I do not right.
Speaker 1: and Then they would select the Omega knots they would contact them and they'd say hey, do you want to be an Omega knot?
Speaker 1: Yes, no.
Speaker 1: Hey do right.
Speaker 1: and then at the convention they had finally selected 16 Omega knots and they would go And compete in the Omega thon.
Speaker 1: There was no such questionnaire for the PAX East.
Speaker 0: So we're just like is there even gonna be you know Megathon at PAX East and you know We're doing a lot of stuff like planning for packs the panels and everything.
Speaker 0: But I never thought to actually ask the the people who would have known.
Speaker 0: Hey, what's the deal with the Omega thon?
Speaker 1: So There is gonna be an Omega thon at PAX East and when I first read what they were gonna do I was like that what are they doing the morons?
Speaker 1: Because what they said they were gonna do is okay.
Speaker 1: when you get to PAX in your bag is gonna be a card.
Speaker 1: you fill It out and you drop it in a thing at the keynote if you want to be in the Omega thon.
Speaker 1: I'm like, whoa What are they doing?
Speaker 1: signing up online is so much better.
Speaker 1: Why did they make it worse?
Speaker 1: What is wrong?
Speaker 1: All right, it's better than that.
Speaker 1: Here is here is the genius of this move, right?
Speaker 1: You think that's a stupid move.
Speaker 1: Why would you do things the old paper way when the technology way as far as superior number one?
Speaker 1: The effort of emailing people saying do you want to be Omega knot?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: No, right?
Speaker 1: No good.
Speaker 1: This way if someone fills out the card, they're at the convention.
Speaker 1: They just said they want to do it.
Speaker 1: right then and there you don't have to do this.
Speaker 1: You know work of filtering the people out.
Speaker 0: This also gives them they can do the come on down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because what they'll do is after the keynote they'll sift through the cards and pull out the names and it'd be like Scott Ruben your You know.
Speaker 1: And then you go up to the front and you line up on the stage and then they'll say these the Omega knots whoo Even more awesome did not think this is possible.
Speaker 1: But you know This is PAX the convention of magic where everything is always more awesome than you suspected it would ever be and more than awesome Than you could possibly imagine.
Speaker 1: This Omega thon at PAX East is going to be an all team game Omega thon teams of two.
Speaker 1: you do not get to choose your teammate.
Speaker 1: It is random pulled out of the Hat.
Speaker 1: So the greatest gamer in the world be paired up with someone who just wanted to do it for fun or who knows what?
Speaker 0: I look forward to versus team co-op style.
Speaker 1: every game is gonna be a two-player game such as double dash, you know such as Geometry Wars 2 Such as some unnamed rhythm game.
Speaker 1: those are rounds one through three rounds four and of course five are unknown.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to speculate of course about the final round and what it will entail.
Speaker 1: Obviously, it will be some sort of co-op game of at least teams of two.
Speaker 1: It could be an FPS because any deathmatch FPS will work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, though.
Speaker 0: I feel like that'd be a cop-out.
Speaker 0: They got it.
Speaker 1: It could be a sports game like double dribble or you know One of those sports games where you only really need two people per side.
Speaker 1: But I don't.
Speaker 0: they don't seem big on sports games, you know at packs I I think old school is the way they would go.
Speaker 1: It could be like pong program because there are pongs that are two verse two.
Speaker 1: But then again, it could just be straight-up table tennis like physical table tennis.
Speaker 1: I would hope that it'd be Mario tennis, which really makes you realize man It could be Mario Party also and it's like it makes you realize not be Mario Party.
Speaker 1: The closing ceremonies cannot be nine hours long But it's so crazy that just about every game you think of that could handle like two versus two.
Speaker 1: is Mario?
Speaker 0: it's like Mario tennis Mario Party, you know Mario Kart double dash really really old-school games Like there's a lot of Atari games that have team play two versus two.
Speaker 0: Yeah Or you can shoehorn it in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean they could.
Speaker 1: you know, you could always do like, you know You know Mario and Luigi, you know, just Mario Brothers.
Speaker 1: and then you know Two people are.
Speaker 1: you know play, you know, they have two separate games high score.
Speaker 1: You could always jury-rig it like that.
Speaker 0: But I remember the last time we were in a Mario Brothers tournament that was for high score.
Speaker 1: It could also be an RTS, you know, you can do Starcraft 2v2.
Speaker 0: Do you remember that?
Speaker 1: It could be Starcraft 2 2v2.
Speaker 0: Scott's trying so hard to get his points and I just asked the moderator Hey, what happens if I kill Scott and he's like, well, I guess he can't get any more points.
Speaker 0: I pushed him into a fireball in one first place.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, so that you know, that's I'm really curious as to what it's gonna be.
Speaker 1: Hopefully it'll be something awesome.
Speaker 1: And I know I know a Boston anime boss is the week after PAX East.
Speaker 0: we're doing a ton of panels there.
Speaker 0: In fact, we're doing Basically brand new panels for many of you because shit think about it All the panels were doing an anime Boston kinetic on panels or either working out account panels.
Speaker 0: But more importantly they were awesome new panels that all the other anime cons.
Speaker 0: for whatever reason we're like.
Speaker 0: no We don't want your new good stuff.
Speaker 0: We want you to run the same shitty.
Speaker 0: how to run an anime club panel again.
Speaker 1: Are we running that same shitty?
Speaker 1: how to run an anime club panel again?
Speaker 0: Yes, but we've never run it at anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Oh All right.
Speaker 1: What else are we doing at anime Boston?
Speaker 0: Ah, we're doing bite-sized anime.
Speaker 0: That's a good one.
Speaker 0: We're doing anime you should see and we're doing anime openers from around the world.
Speaker 0: Oh snap Let me tell you I got some gold.
Speaker 1: Some gold Jerry.
Speaker 0: I've completely reworked that stupid panel.
Speaker 0: Good God All right, and we're probably gonna do some other stuff.
Speaker 0: That's all TBA.
Speaker 0: I don't have the schedule in front of me.
Speaker 1: Okay And the final bit of meta is that we are doing some you streams if you are not watching them already because barely anyone is Which I can't blame you.
Speaker 1: basically we're practicing.
Speaker 0: We're pretty much just going to start you streaming and recording in some fashion every normal episode of geek nights Just to put it up there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we're also you know, we're doing some live streaming things outside of geek nights.
Speaker 1: We're basically realized that you know, we knew for a long time video was the future, but we were so lazy about it.
Speaker 1: But now I'm just like well, you know what?
Speaker 1: Fuck it We just have to just turn on a webcam at the very least.
Speaker 1: We got to do something We got to learn something about this.
Speaker 1: Let's just do it.
Speaker 1: So now we finally we're just gonna turn webcams on all the time.
Speaker 1: I'm even looking into you know, this trying to bring up some you streaming from packs and such.
Speaker 1: we're gonna work that out.
Speaker 1: Maybe we'll see.
Speaker 0: Okay, yep, so stay tuned for more on that front.
Speaker 1: so does the computer notice?
Speaker 1: stay tuned for more on that front.
Speaker 0: paranoia Interestingly enough, you know when paranoia was first released?
Speaker 0: the 80s 1984 yeah But I think that's a very poignant number for paranoia, I wonder if that was intentional to some degree I hope so.
Speaker 0: You know would be even better if that wasn't true and someone had edited Wikipedia to make it true.
Speaker 1: That would be pretty awesome If someone had you know edited Wikipedia to put in a joke like that.
Speaker 1: But no, I think it actually was released in 1984.
Speaker 0: So basically the deal like as far as I can tell with paranoia.
Speaker 0: almost every gamer in the world who's at least a Convention gamer or an old-school gamer or a role-playing gamer anyone outside of I just play Pokemon or I just play D&D.
Speaker 1: You know if you've been to any gaming con pretty much any tabletop role-playing gamer who is beyond the who?
Speaker 1: Has reached the point at which they realize D&D is not the only tabletop role-playing game has at least heard of Paranoia and knows at least a little about.
Speaker 0: but my suspicion and I see this a lot most gamers don't know anything about it.
Speaker 0: Almost everyone I run into they know about paranoia they know the gist of it and they have some crazy anecdote from either a time they saw some people playing it at a Convention or they ran into a game of it somewhere or they encountered it in some oblique way But they themselves had never played it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, very few people have actually played it relatively speaking.
Speaker 1: Of course I mean what the first packs who went up during the Q&A and we made this paranoia joke and taiko got it But nobody else got it.
Speaker 1: really they had no clue.
Speaker 0: Of course They didn't answer our question because it was telling that the pecs attendee badges were all red and then our panelist badges were blue.
Speaker 1: And yeah, and they all access badges were violet.
Speaker 0: There's no way someone in that chain of thought was not thinking paranoid.
Speaker 1: Someone was picking the colors based on some sort of paranoia based logic or just Roy G Biv.
Speaker 1: So I guess a short explanation of a paranoia is in order because I assume most people have no idea what's going on.
Speaker 1: So it's a tabletop RPG, right?
Speaker 1: But it takes place in sort of like a dystopian sci-fi future where there was a nuclear war.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be a nuclear war.
Speaker 1: who knows and everyone lives and like, you know These cities controlled by the computer.
Speaker 1: It's a lot like Phoenix future the second volume of Tezuka's Phoenix.
Speaker 0: Or take say Logan's run Logan's run very similar.
Speaker 1: mash it up with brave new world yeah, so there's a computer that controls everything and basically you can't piss off the computer or else you'll just die and All the people living there are arranged by color, right?
Speaker 1: So red is the lowest color.
Speaker 0: That's the troubleshooter That's not the lowest here now.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're right this zoom out.
Speaker 0: The story is that they set up a computer and the computer was to control this kind of vault.
Speaker 0: You know if you played Fallout about shelter because it's cold war there's gonna be a nuclear war or something someday maybe and One thing leads to another and the computer decides that the best way to protect everyone is to nuke everything out there and never let Anyone go outside again?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, so people everyone in the world as far as you know lives in the paranoia world this kind of underground vault that's controlled by the computer and Everyone is desperately afraid of the communists that are clearly trying to undermine the computer and kill everybody.
Speaker 0: Yep, everyone is also secretly a communist Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Everyone is afraid of the mutants who are trying to kill everyone and make everyone mutants.
Speaker 0: Everyone is also secretly a mutant.
Speaker 0: That is the world of paranoia.
Speaker 0: Everyone is paranoid.
Speaker 0: Every asshole is trying to kill you for some reason or other and you're just watching your back and trying not to die.
Speaker 1: Now this game has actually been released multiple different times and each version was crook slightly.
Speaker 1: So, you know those some versions were really serious and dystopian and like whoa some were really silly You know and humorous.
Speaker 1: and the newer versions paranoia XP and actually think there's one newer version that that's crook slightly.
Speaker 0: So here there is in 1984 first edition.
Speaker 0: Yeah 1987 second edition 1995 fifth edition Mmm 2004 XP and then 2009 ready to feel old the 25th anniversary edition.
Speaker 0: That really that really hits home.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean it's about the same age as we are.
Speaker 1: we were born in 82 It was born in 84.
Speaker 1: So we're slight.
Speaker 1: We're two years older than paranoia.
Speaker 1: So I'm older than 25.
Speaker 1: So there you go.
Speaker 1: But yeah, so paranoia the newest versions like XP has actually three different play modes zap normal and hardcore.
Speaker 1: I don't think that's what the actual names are But I know the first the run version names have.
Speaker 1: basically you can play it in silly mode or a serious mode Which actually is really interesting because it gives the game a lot of depth and it also gives you sort of like this entry point Into the larger world, you know It's like you can play some silly games of paranoia to get into it and learn the basic rules And then once you're comfortable you can start playing a serious game and it's like whoa, what the fuck dude.
Speaker 0: Now I think the best way to get into paranoia because a lot of people want to play paranoia But gotta play at a convention You've got to play it at a convention.
Speaker 0: But you have to basically find someone who's running a game of paranoia who is good at it and play in their game.
Speaker 0: And it is the less, you know about paranoia the better the better.
Speaker 1: indeed paranoia It's anyone who knows too much about.
Speaker 1: it's one of those things where if you know enough about it Then you won't make like stupid newbie mistakes.
Speaker 1: But stupid people making stupid newbie mistakes is where all the humor and awesome shit comes from.
Speaker 0: of course Advanced players take it one step further and do the burning wheel.
Speaker 0: You know metagaming of I am going to do the.
Speaker 0: the stupid thing that my character would think would smart would be smart But I know according to the rules is going to kill him.
Speaker 1: Well, it goes even to a higher level, right?
Speaker 1: For example, let's say you're playing with six newbies, right?
Speaker 1: You're the GM.
Speaker 1: You're gonna ask someone.
Speaker 1: Are you a happy communist, right?
Speaker 1: Oh And they're gonna fall for it maybe and then the computer will zap them and they'll chug down a can of soda and then come back to life.
Speaker 1: if You're playing with an experienced player an experienced player wouldn't fall for that trick.
Speaker 1: But in addition an experienced player would try to trick the other players, right?
Speaker 1: And if you have all experienced players Oh, it's a friggin cutthroat motherfucker at that point.
Speaker 0: I mean most games of paranoia are one-offs.
Speaker 0: Oftentimes, they'll be pseudo larp style where you'll play around a table But a lot of times you'll have props on the table all these sorts of you know Objects to interact with.
Speaker 0: you'll stand up you'll run around you might jump up and sing the bouncy bubbly beverage song You don't know the lyrics to but damn if the computer isn't gonna kill you if you don't sing it.
Speaker 1: Yep, and that you're speaking of, you know, the bubbly beverage is already a mentioned soda, but there's a. there's a a Thing in paranoia called the six pack.
Speaker 1: you get six lives and then you're.
Speaker 1: you know Your body is just regenerated and such.
Speaker 0: basically you get six clones of yourself.
Speaker 0: so every time you know, your clone is popped out and it's you and if you die, they pop out another you and Everyone gets six.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and after the sixth one, you're actually dead And so what people often do is you'll have a six-pack of beverage any beverage of your choice wink wink on the table usually something that will make you pee and Every time you die you open one up and you start drinking and when you finish that beverage Then you begin playing again and you are now that is represents your you know Coming back to life and being removed from the cryo chamber, whatever the hell it's in.
Speaker 1: right now The thing is drinking all these beverages you're gonna have to pee and when you're away from the table Your character is not away from the table and very likely when you come back from being you will be drinking another beverage immediately.
Speaker 0: It's a game where it's one of the first games I ever played where I started to understand that the meta like Metagaming can make a game better.
Speaker 0: It was the game where I realized that losing is more fun than winning Mmm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It's also a game where you're pretty much guaranteed to lose.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much event.
Speaker 1: You know, if you play a serious game, you're gonna die a lot less frequently and you're gonna.
Speaker 1: you know You're gonna make it a lot farther, but you're gonna die, you know, maybe once per session, you know Maybe once every other session or so.
Speaker 1: if you place not so seriously, you're gonna die Lose all six lives within the one session at the convention pretty much guaranteed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean basically the way most missions will go or one-offs at a convention are you're a bunch of mugs.
Speaker 1: You know red color maybe a higher color doesn't really matter and you're given some task And you the computer says do this and if you don't do that, the computer is just gonna kill you.
Speaker 0: So you better do it, but it's something serious like go figure out what's wrong with the the sewage thing over here find out why this guy disappeared or something like that.
Speaker 0: and Every character will probably have some completely ulterior mode if they want to accomplish and Oftentimes one of the players will be given by that, you know, there's a lot of secret information and note passing.
Speaker 0: So the game master might pass you a note.
Speaker 0: You know when the plate game starts up and you just open it and it just says something like You know for a fact that there is a cortex bomb in your skull and in so-and-so skull Great, or you are in fact a communist having read.
Speaker 0: This has made you a communist.
Speaker 0: Now smart players will give that note to someone else.
Speaker 0: a lot of times Players will like write a note like I totally want to do blah blah blah and blah blah blah and just pull up the note And just hand it to the game master.
Speaker 0: a lot of experienced players will write gibberish on a note or Nothing of note on a note or saying I'm running a note to make so-and-so paranoid and hand it to the game master.
Speaker 1: Mmm very very clever.
Speaker 1: Also a good idea is to hand a note to the game master that says I would like to talk to you privately over to The side.
Speaker 1: go over to the side and say I just wanted to talk.
Speaker 1: you do privately over to the side You know because that makes me even more paranoid than the fake note.
Speaker 1: or you can go over and tell them right.
Speaker 1: for example I could bring the game master over and I could say hey listen I'm gonna pass a note to so-and-so.
Speaker 1: that makes them a communist so that they something something something.
Speaker 1: So I need you to take advantage of that something something and you hand a note to that person.
Speaker 1: that does nothing different.
Speaker 1: So you can punk the game master - that's always a good time.
Speaker 0: That's the whole.
Speaker 0: that's basically the whole point of the game.
Speaker 0: that and the game master Usually why his job is to make you have a good time and if possible to kill all of you.
Speaker 0: mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: He wants you all to die and have a total party because you have six lives.
Speaker 1: It's like undead.
Speaker 1: whatever come back.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: It's not like ah dead in D&D You're gonna kill someone like guard that can or a marty duck.
Speaker 1: You know you got six lives.
Speaker 1: so as long as you don't lose all six And if you do lose all six as long as you're not the first person who's all six You can just be like god damn it And you just sit off to the side laughing at what everyone else is doing because the game is probably already almost over by then.
Speaker 1: Because even if you suck ass six lives is still plenty of game time to get your funds worth out of it.
Speaker 1: You know out of the single session Anything else to say about the paradigm?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't want to get into game details.
Speaker 0: I would say none of you should read anything, but kind of the intro book.
Speaker 1: Oh, this is true.
Speaker 1: There is there's a thing in paranoid.
Speaker 1: depending on what color you are Determines what colors you can interact with.
Speaker 1: for example if there's a blue gun like the gun is physically blue, and I am red.
Speaker 1: That's above me.
Speaker 1: I can't touch that.
Speaker 1: if I can well you can.
Speaker 1: But if you do and the computer sees you you're probably gonna die and if someone else sees you they're probably gonna rat you out To the computer or kill you or you know.
Speaker 1: so It's.
Speaker 1: you know you're not supposed to in you know involve yourself with things that are a higher color than you are.
Speaker 1: You know it's like you're.
Speaker 1: you're limited to what color you're at.
Speaker 1: if you're playing a serious game and not the silly game You're probably never.
Speaker 1: you're probably going to avoid interacting with anything above you because dying is more serious in a serious game.
Speaker 1: so What in the rule book if you buy paranoia XP for example the front part of the book is you know red red red red?
Speaker 1: Red.
Speaker 1: and then about halfway through the book the color changes to ultraviolet Which is you know so that only the GM can look back there and if a player looks you know takes the book and flips To one of those back pages.
Speaker 1: dumb dumb dumb.
Speaker 1: They actually print a separate book the little red book ha ha ha right that has only the red parts in it For the game so that you can hand that out to people who if you're actually serious about you know the color rules And all and you could you do all sorts of fun stuff with that.
Speaker 1: like someone picks up a pencil That's yellow you like oh, man.
Speaker 1: Or you know you could be like hey red guy the computer tells you to go over to get your orders from the you know Computer.
Speaker 1: it's it's printing out of the printer in sector 7.
Speaker 1: Oh my god Luke Did that you go to this.
Speaker 1: you go to sector 7 and there's a printer and it's printing out some you know.
Speaker 1: and there's a you Know security camera.
Speaker 1: looking at the printer and the instructions are coming out And you see that your name is written on the instructions on this purple piece of paper.
Speaker 1: It's just like oh fuck I can't take the orders out of this printer and like half the orders is still in the printer.
Speaker 0: well That's the the propness.
Speaker 0: I mean when Luke handed me.
Speaker 0: You know he basically held up his hands.
Speaker 0: We played paranoia at RIT around the table, and he kind of spit out the orders to each person like here are your orders?
Speaker 0: And then one of us we go up and like I I go to grab it and he holds on to it And he starts pulling it back in like I only got half of them.
Speaker 0: Paranoia is a game where you'll be at a convention and you'll see like some other do you know?
Speaker 0: there's all like the tables where People are playing different games like D&D game going on over there Maybe some inspectors over there and in the corner the people playing paranoia look like a normal game Except periodically they will cause a great ruckus in the room and everyone will look over and say what are they doing
Speaker 1: playing paranoia?
Speaker 1: The most ruckus ERPG available.
Speaker 0: it is possibly the most ruckus ERPG.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the guy who made paranoia at least one of the guys is a major guys is Greg Kostikin.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sort of very famous.
Speaker 1: He tried.
Speaker 1: You know he's actually doing a lot of big stuff now even he has a great blog.
Speaker 1: play this Thing I think I've talked about in the show way back and basically you go to this blog And it'll tell you about all sorts of interesting games all the time mostly indie games.
Speaker 1: He's big with the indie games, and he actually he started this like indie game thing But he sort of it failed.
Speaker 1: I think it was like man if red manifesto or something like that.
Speaker 1: I forget the exact name of the company, but It didn't work out You know because he couldn't compete with say steam and such and such and the indie games got a prominent spot in other online Game selling services, so you know his indie thing only didn't really need to stick around, but you know he's that kind of guy.
Speaker 1: he's pretty awesome and You know you should check out anything.
Speaker 1: if you see his name on it you know it's probably high quality.
Speaker 1: gaming is involved.
Speaker 0: plus paranoia definitely comes out of an older tradition of role-playing games.
Speaker 1: his day is definitely Steve Jackson sort of era of Gaming.
Speaker 1: not that he's not gaming now, but you know it's his his original era.
Speaker 1: It's a sort of gaming the illuminati versus the munchkin era.
Speaker 0: Paranoia is relatively mainstream compared to many more indie role-playing games.
Speaker 0: I mean most people most gamers we talked to don't even know there are any role-playing games.
Speaker 1: Alright, it's D&D.
Speaker 1: Maybe they know a white wolf exists.
Speaker 0: You know that's it, but paranoia just it's over with all the indie games like.
Speaker 0: it's unique.
Speaker 0: It does something cool and different.
Speaker 0: It's such a great game to play and you should all go to some convention somewhere and play paranoia.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website At front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.