Speaker 0: Hey, it's Tuesday March 23rd.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: your pecsies 2010 Survival guide.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Hey, uh, it's coming.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: It's coming shit.
Speaker 0: This is the last show before it comes.
Speaker 1: No snap Hey, might as well be here.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I cannot say if pecsies is going to be 100% as awesome as pecs west.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling there will be more people.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling that by I am unsure Vastly surpass pecs west in terms of number of people in the coming years.
Speaker 0: yes I'm talking like by 20 or 30 thousand.
Speaker 1: But I am curious as to the culture of pecsies.
Speaker 1: you see pecs west was able to build its culture from the lowly Necro Wombicon up and up and up right.
Speaker 0: it also built kind of in a weird vacuum.
Speaker 0: I mean think about it.
Speaker 0: in the east we have this incestuous like a million gigantic anime cons and gaming cons and everything and there's A lot a huge overlap of all these cons, but then out west I mean the cities are further apart And there's fewer people in each location.
Speaker 0: not that many people from pecs west went to all these other conventions in the area.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and also you know remember the new york comic-con was pretty.
Speaker 1: you know every convention I've ever been to right as built up small to big over time Otakon started a hotel con The New York comic-con started, but I was about to say That the New York comic-con is pretty much the only con that went zero to gigantic.
Speaker 1: you know immediately boom first con Gigantic thousands of people and it had serious serious problems for years as a result, so I am wondering if pecs east despite the awesomeness of pecs and the awesomeness of all the people getting the shit done will they be able to handle the zero to maximum size Immediate you know increase or
Speaker 0: not?
Speaker 0: at least they have read.
Speaker 0: And they have a lot of the pecs west enforcers and from what I can gather a lot of people who normally go to pecs West are kind of flying out for this thing.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 1: That's that's necessary.
Speaker 1: We need them to to be the seed to spread the correct mood about.
Speaker 0: there are two completely separate factors there.
Speaker 0: on one hand There's the logistics.
Speaker 0: I mean can it be the same?
Speaker 0: Seattle is a very Different city.
Speaker 1: it's a different.
Speaker 1: It's a different convention center a different city different people.
Speaker 0: They're very similar convention centers like surprisingly similar when you think about a little bit.
Speaker 1: They have models the head of verticals.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think they both will have better staff like local staff.
Speaker 0: then say the Baltimore Convention Center.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know the anime Boston.
Speaker 1: the staff were not so great.
Speaker 0: You know the convention center staff Yeah, but they were at least four or five times better than the Baltimore staff.
Speaker 0: That's more like the DC staff.
Speaker 1: That's true Yeah, well it remains to be seen regardless if it sucks.
Speaker 1: It's not our fault Yeah, of course.
Speaker 0: It's tough because we've you know if paxi somehow fails and does not live up the expectations All we're gonna say is well Everything we said was based on pecs West which we will continue to go to.
Speaker 0: yes Well I think it's gonna be good in the long run.
Speaker 0: I mean paxis is probably gonna be great.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be different.
Speaker 0: definitely They've brought a lot of the same culture like look the same kind of concerts the same concerts.
Speaker 0: in fact It's the same.
Speaker 1: it's the same concerts every year.
Speaker 0: It's not any different Yeah, but they're doing a lot of the same stuff, but it'll be interesting because it packs West.
Speaker 0: It's mostly people who know what to expect like oh the keynotes gonna be this go to the keynote.
Speaker 0: the first Q&A is this I mean, maybe at PAX East all these people who've never been to packs before.
Speaker 0: they're gonna go to the Q&A and basically actually ask Normal kind of questions.
Speaker 1: Oh you think see it could be a roller coaster situation.
Speaker 1: right the people at pax West have mostly been to Pax West.
Speaker 1: so it's like up riding the roller coaster again, but people go to pax East.
Speaker 1: It's like riding the tallest roller coaster for the first time ever.
Speaker 0: remember our first packs.
Speaker 1: There might be thousands of people who are just like.
Speaker 0: I mean the same thing happened with Otacon.
Speaker 0: I remember my first Otacon.
Speaker 0: I was dumbstruck at how big that come.
Speaker 1: well We're gonna talk about this for the rest of the show.
Speaker 1: So let's you know get the rest of this stuff out of the way so we can get to it.
Speaker 0: Well, it is you know it's that season of the year the time when young boys want to play DDR again.
Speaker 1: Well, you know I got the home theater PC, and we all know about step mania the open source.
Speaker 1: I think it's open source pretty sure free programs at least free as in beer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is a. it's basically a clone of DDR except It doesn't come with any songs.
Speaker 1: You know it's basically all the non copyrighted parts, and then you go and you pirate all the songs and the step files You nominally make your own.
Speaker 0: that happened to be exactly Identical.
Speaker 1: you download to me.
Speaker 1: download the other ones that are made by the community.
Speaker 1: actually I downloaded all the winners of the step mania Contest files from the step mania website.
Speaker 0: have you played any of them?
Speaker 0: some of them are alright Yeah, but by and large the community made ones are.
Speaker 1: these are like the highest rated community made ones.
Speaker 0: Well watch out the community is really fucked up and a lot of the very like popular ones are just stupid hard.
Speaker 0: I'm a loser who spends all my time playing DDR.
Speaker 1: One of them was actually cool.
Speaker 1: It was like a Riverdance kind of situation ooh.
Speaker 1: I could dig that.
Speaker 1: yeah anyway You know.
Speaker 1: so I was.
Speaker 1: I was thinking that's the obvious move when you want to bring DDR to your home theater PC And you already have you know a dance pad, but then I realized wait a minute.
Speaker 1: I've got this PlayStation emulator.
Speaker 1: Why don't I just go and get DDR fourth mix extra mix and fifth mix and kick it old-school Now with the real deal.
Speaker 0: the saddest part about what you're about to say is that we in fact had Nice burned physical media of every DDR mix we cared about from the ps1 air which were the three I just mentioned.
Speaker 0: Those CDs I have worn out to the point of being gone.
Speaker 0: I can't even rip an ISO off of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't even find.
Speaker 1: the thing is I'm trying to find these things on the internet.
Speaker 1: I found extra mix.
Speaker 1: it works, but it's got this problem where the timing is off.
Speaker 0: So it happened with the legitimate extra mix.
Speaker 1: It's effectively unplayable.
Speaker 1: right and if I Downloaded a fifth mix disc I haven't tried it yet When I get home, but I and fourth mix right.
Speaker 1: why is fourth mix is the best DDR ever?
Speaker 1: fourth mix Plus is the best DDR arcade ever.
Speaker 1: Why are they the hardest DDRs to find in the world?
Speaker 1: They don't know.
Speaker 1: it's like it's easier to find a third mix than it is to find a fourth.
Speaker 1: It fourth is just the best DDR period.
Speaker 1: no DDR has ever surpassed it.
Speaker 0: It has the kind of poppy dancy music that I think just peak children of the 80s like to dance to and then it moved more and more into kind of More modern techno II dancing and bump bump bump.
Speaker 1: anyway if I'm ever mega rich, I'm gonna get a fourth mix plus machine.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: That is near that.
Speaker 0: I'd like a fourth mix plus machine and independent of that Probably a 12th mix machine that I just modded to be a step mania machines.
Speaker 1: I knew he's got DDR is.
Speaker 1: give me the hookup you know and don't tell me to go buy a legitimate Japanese disc.
Speaker 1: That's like impossible.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: I remember back in the day It wasn't that hard to get him remember when red octane was basically Netflix of ps1 games.
Speaker 1: That was a good day.
Speaker 0: red octane had a service.
Speaker 1: people don't remember that red octane used to be game rental.
Speaker 1: It did instead of what it is now.
Speaker 0: so what their service was was you would say give them like five bucks And they'd mail you as DVD or CD.
Speaker 0: It was the CD of a ps1 game.
Speaker 0: You would burn it and mail it back to them the same day, and then they'd mail you another CD.
Speaker 1: It was it Netflix of games.
Speaker 1: Just there are.
Speaker 1: there are other Netflixes of games.
Speaker 0: But red octane specialized in these people only renting games to pirate.
Speaker 1: also lots of foreign Japanese games Specifically DDR and such right and actually sold dance pads.
Speaker 1: That's why they make dance pads.
Speaker 1: currently is because of that business.
Speaker 0: in fact We went through like seven or eight pairs of the song.
Speaker 1: And then the fact that they made pads.
Speaker 1: their business evolved away from the game rental to the pad making and then to the guitar Hero guitar making.
Speaker 0: and then well the game Yeah, then no one rented any games from them, but Japanese games and DDR and no one ever rented a game twice.
Speaker 0: Yep for obvious reasons yep.
Speaker 0: Also because it was mostly ps1 games, but I remember back then I mean I got fourth mix and fourth mix plus, and we played him like every fourth mix an extra mix Yeah, which together are almost a fourth mix plus arcade machine.
Speaker 0: Yep missing a few songs Yeah, but then you know we had all that and this was kind of still in the early days of modern piracy and even like Anime fan subs and all that.
Speaker 0: and one day a friend of ours was like I got fifth mix.
Speaker 0: Oh shit we spent like a weekend straight playing that game.
Speaker 0: my legs hurt I couldn't walk yeah, and then DDR died.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like the same thing.
Speaker 1: imagine gathering after you know fallen empires Whatever whatever is dead thing is it keeps coming back.
Speaker 0: and for me personally.
Speaker 0: I love DDR And you know what.
Speaker 1: and you gathering keeps coming back.
Speaker 0: It's still really popular Not to us not to us, but to the world.
Speaker 0: DDR is not popular to the world.
Speaker 0: It is popular to us and to the people who go to anime conventions and not even a lot of them anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's really sad, but they like that stupid pop and music.
Speaker 0: fuck that game.
Speaker 1: But well not too many people like you.
Speaker 1: just one guy really really likes it.
Speaker 0: Maybe it is just that guy.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it is.
Speaker 0: he's at every con, and you always wasn't.
Speaker 1: he was at katsu cut And maybe he's at every con.
Speaker 0: you always see the line.
Speaker 0: Maybe just people standing there trying to play.
Speaker 0: they see him there.
Speaker 0: They can't play they leave.
Speaker 0: no one actually plays it, but him.
Speaker 1: We should have just taken it off the projector Just broken it.
Speaker 0: I don't know why the sound stopped working on just that game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, but DDR is to this day possibly one of my favorite games ever like I. just I always want to play it.
Speaker 1: Yes, it is so fun to have the computer control your feet.
Speaker 0: I mean think about it.
Speaker 0: When was the last time you were in the presence of a DDR machine and not at a convention?
Speaker 0: And you didn't at least want to play it?
Speaker 0: no of course how many DDR machines are there?
Speaker 0: There's like one in Manhattan yeah And there's always Asians.
Speaker 0: yeah, so we'll do a quick news.
Speaker 0: We weren't even gonna talk about video game news because who cares?
Speaker 0: Pax is coming up.
Speaker 1: Pax east is the gaming news.
Speaker 0: we have to talk about the fact that Nintendo is releasing a new DS.
Speaker 1: That's 3d, and it's supposedly 3d without glasses.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: Here's the commentary.
Speaker 0: I've seen Nintendo is not going to make a ps3.
Speaker 0: They're not going to use the current like high-end 3d technology that you can get like they're selling for Playstations or whatever that they're gonna use for modern Sony TVs.
Speaker 0: yep That's way too expensive, and they don't use glasses and all that business.
Speaker 0: They're probably gonna do something really cheap and everyone says that it's going to use the camera To look at where your head is and do it.
Speaker 0: remember that old demo of the guy who had all the targets on his monitor And he had a webcam to watch where his head was.
Speaker 1: oh really cuz the thing was.
Speaker 1: is there was the reason.
Speaker 1: the thing is There was a DS game or a DS I game.
Speaker 1: all right that there's a video of.
Speaker 1: you can watch online and the way this game works is actually uses the camera on The DS I to look at the floor or whatever is behind the can't DS.
Speaker 1: And when you move the DS I around.
Speaker 1: it moves the picture in the game around.
Speaker 1: So it looks like you're sort of looking into a diorama.
Speaker 1: It doesn't pop out of the screen But it goes deep into the screen.
Speaker 1: and the thing is why do you need to me if that's the technology that?
Speaker 1: They're gonna use?
Speaker 1: you know that is cheap.
Speaker 1: That is a very you know impressive looking technology.
Speaker 1: That is something that is feasible.
Speaker 1: right that is 3d.
Speaker 1: The question is the DS.
Speaker 1: I can already do it.
Speaker 1: So why would you make the 3ds to do it right?
Speaker 1: there has to be something different for them to make a new Different piece of hardware to add this technology.
Speaker 1: Require right what?
Speaker 0: one option there is simply potato moto.
Speaker 0: They want more money.
Speaker 0: It's possible.
Speaker 0: They might add some other tchotchke support.
Speaker 1: Maybe you know I would.
Speaker 1: I would say it's false advertising to call it 3d right unless it comes out of the screen.
Speaker 1: And this is another problem.
Speaker 0: I mean Star Fox was 3d.
Speaker 1: That's exactly what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: is I was pissed in those days too and when people said like quake was 3d You know and I would argue with people cuz it's like look.
Speaker 1: It's on a flat screen.
Speaker 1: It's not 3d.
Speaker 1: if I draw a cube on this piece of paper is that 3d?
Speaker 0: well It's a projection of a three-dimensional object in the two-dimensional space.
Speaker 1: yes, so if that's 3d then 10d.
Speaker 1: then all they need to do then Mario 64 on on the DS right is 3d.
Speaker 1: so the 3d DS is no different.
Speaker 1: Might as well be.
Speaker 1: it's probably just gonna be like a DS with an Nvidia chip in it or some shit.
Speaker 1: You know well the thing is one.
Speaker 0: the other way they could do it.
Speaker 0: I don't think they will do it this way is if you held it like a book right and Maybe they'll do multiple things magic eyeball.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you get the stereoscopic effect.
Speaker 0: you can do that with like normal software anyway.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's very very difficult.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it won't work for a lot of people.
Speaker 1: to give people eye strain.
Speaker 1: It'll be a big probably won't work You know.
Speaker 0: anyone who doesn't work for just doesn't understand how to do it though That's true, but the thing is is that Nintendo is not gonna make a product that doesn't work for everybody though I will say never happen while it does work for me.
Speaker 0: my whole life I've hated magic.
Speaker 0: I've you know when I remember that was like the big craze and all the malls in the 90s, right?
Speaker 1: I spy also was a craze.
Speaker 0: But my trouble is I tend to always cross my eyes inward as opposed to outward when I look at those things And it's very hard for me to stop that from happening.
Speaker 0: so the image sinks, but the the 3d.
Speaker 0: This is 100% reversed.
Speaker 0: So I see everything going in as opposed to out.
Speaker 0: That's just my brain.
Speaker 0: it can't handle it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is just your brain.
Speaker 0: What's really going on here?
Speaker 0: We're not sure all the details.
Speaker 0: I don't want to talk about the technical details.
Speaker 0: There's a million.
Speaker 0: You know it's all a rumor at this point until Nintendo says here's what it is.
Speaker 0: We're calling it the poop.
Speaker 1: yep You see that joke from somewhere on the Internet, I thought of it just now.
Speaker 1: all right now They do it.
Speaker 0: look 3d is the current buzzword this 3d TVs avatar and Alice in Wonderland.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like they dissed HD.
Speaker 0: so they got to do 3d, but right now while it's the big thing They're gonna release the cheap handheld 3d console and all the people who bought basically the the current Demographic of Nintendo are the people who are gonna buy this shit.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna say the same thing I say when I bought the DS right which look this thing is either going to be the virtual Boy, or is it gonna be amazing?
Speaker 0: I don't think so anymore.
Speaker 0: You don't think the DS was virtual boy or amazing.
Speaker 0: it ended up being amazing Except once we realize once Nintendo said oh, it's amazing they stopped trying and it actually kind of stopped being amazing.
Speaker 0: What was the last DS game we cared about?
Speaker 1: I just bought?
Speaker 1: Edgeworth Investigations.
Speaker 1: it's awesome.
Speaker 1: I just haven't played it yet because I've been reading all right name.
Speaker 1: another one the The hero.
Speaker 1: what's that called the clash of heroes?
Speaker 1: About that in a big way know what the thing is though like I admit I pirated it for the DS Clash of hero.
Speaker 1: might magic clash of heroes is coming to the Xbox such and such.
Speaker 1: I can play it on the Xbox Live HD so I'm gonna pay for monies for that and that'll be fair and I just won't.
Speaker 1: I won't play the DS one anymore because I'll play the HD one, but look at the DS.
Speaker 0: It was a huge camera.
Speaker 0: people thought the DS was going to fail.
Speaker 0: back in the day a lot of people like this thing in Which case I said awesome.
Speaker 1: I'll own a virtual.
Speaker 0: Yes, but back Then the dichotomy was it's either going to be a crazy success and like the new era of gaming or a virtual boy.
Speaker 0: The DS I and this new 3ds are not.
Speaker 0: they cannot be virtual boys.
Speaker 0: They're going to be either middle of the middle of the grode like milk toast mediocre or they're gonna be money makers.
Speaker 0: Maybe that there's a tiny chance of awesome but there's almost no chance of virtual boy because virtual boy one was a hideous monstrosity a Disaster.
Speaker 0: it gave you a headache just looking at it.
Speaker 0: No one bought it like it was an.
Speaker 0: it was such a disaster that it was almost more popular as a result.
Speaker 0: It was so bad.
Speaker 0: It's kind of awesome.
Speaker 0: It's dangerous.
Speaker 1: The only thing approaching most danger The only thing I have to add right is that whenever a Nintendo has tried to like sort of refine a handheld portable system right, like they refine the GBA into the the the What's it called the SP right it was.
Speaker 1: there is a refinement.
Speaker 1: they were applying the gameboy into the gameboy pocket.
Speaker 1: the refinements that were successful were always the first refinements the DS into the DS light.
Speaker 1: and the reason those refinements were successful is because the original Version was had some hideous flaw usually being too gigantic to battery hungry.
Speaker 1: No backlight, etc.
Speaker 1: Right the further refinements the GBA micro, you know and such and such Just prey on people who have extra money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the the DSI these were you know relative Failures, you know because they basically, you know, DSI is better than the DS light, but it loses the GBA slot You know, it's not a refinement.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like an Yeah, you're right.
Speaker 1: So I think that if you are the kind of person who wants to save money right, what I would do is wait for the 3d the D the 3ds light and That will be the first refinement and you can just keep that forever and that'll be perfect.
Speaker 0: This is the problem with Nintendo.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go way back to the money level because the we I would say in terms of like Profitability and like good move for Nintendo all told and the DS are we're like the best thing they ever could have done.
Speaker 0: I mean they the intent that we sold like crazy.
Speaker 0: It's still ultra popular and important.
Speaker 0: but Nintendo has gotten to the point with me to where I no longer buy even their first party titles sight unseen It used to be.
Speaker 1: I do.
Speaker 1: I do buy their first party title sight unseen.
Speaker 1: Where the fuck are they?
Speaker 1: I'm waiting for Metroid other M. I'm waiting for Freaking Mario Galaxy 2 or even the big sound waiting for another Zelda game, right?
Speaker 0: Where is the next Advanced Wars right?
Speaker 1: You know, where is Advanced Wars DS again?
Speaker 1: Where is?
Speaker 0: but even then look we'll look at on the DS, you know Zelda game That's worse than the previous Zelda game that came out.
Speaker 1: Where's Mario Kart Wii 2, you know?
Speaker 1: They aren't even making Mario Tennis 2 or anything.
Speaker 1: Where are the first party games are not existent because that's not Another Mario Party.
Speaker 0: I don't think those games are Nintendo's primary demographic anymore.
Speaker 0: I don't think those make them nearly as much money.
Speaker 1: The last one was New Super Mario Brothers, which I'll wait until it's cheaper, but that's the other problem.
Speaker 0: We no longer have the urgency.
Speaker 0: I don't think Mario Party N came out.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: I need it today That's not.
Speaker 1: but if it was Zelda it was Zelda new.
Speaker 1: I would need it today.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I do.
Speaker 1: it was Metroid other M I needed today.
Speaker 0: Nintendo always had this special place for me where I would buy their games at full price right away Because I had to play them.
Speaker 0: they were great.
Speaker 1: if it was Smash Brothers, you know Royal rumble insanity.
Speaker 1: Yes, I buy today.
Speaker 0: but look at PC gaming now I wait on anything that isn't multiplayer.
Speaker 1: That's and even then I only I know and I would half-life episode 3.
Speaker 0: I wait for anything that isn't.
Speaker 0: unless I can get all my friends to also wait and if they'll do that I wait even on multiplayer games.
Speaker 0: I just I no longer have urgency.
Speaker 0: and Nintendo's the weird spot because their first party games usually don't get cheaper anytime soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it almost makes me just not bother with them anymore.
Speaker 0: while PC I'll wait and buy a game for five bucks that I never play.
Speaker 1: Yep on Steam.
Speaker 1: Oh Well, I don't know that I still would not bet against a Nintendo portable platform.
Speaker 0: I would not bet against it.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be a moneymaker guarantee it but it's not gonna be new Mario Brothers.
Speaker 1: We is $43 on Amazon Used cop.
Speaker 1: the cheapest used copy is 38 49.
Speaker 1: So it's gonna be some waiting.
Speaker 0: Yep But the 3d DS is not for us.
Speaker 0: I don't think I don't know.
Speaker 1: We'll see what games come out for.
Speaker 1: 3d advanced wars.
Speaker 0: What could that add to advance war?
Speaker 1: you can fly the airplane planes on top of a boat?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's exactly what I wanted.
Speaker 1: You can move guys up and down.
Speaker 1: They're actually standing on a mountain up above shooting down on another guy, but I can already do that in Final Fantasy Tactics.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe Final Fantasy Tactics 3d, but I don't like those games anymore.
Speaker 1: Phoenix, right 3d You got to look around behind.
Speaker 0: that would be cool.
Speaker 0: If you had a crime scene you guys to get it.
Speaker 0: in 3d You hold the DS up to your face and walk around in a semi VR world plus.
Speaker 0: remember remember this here's the.
Speaker 0: here's the crux.
Speaker 0: We will think of a thousand awesome things that Nintendo will never do.
Speaker 0: Nintendo is going to make one game that almost achieves that to prove that the console is viable.
Speaker 1: 3d Mario Tennis where Mario is Like out in front of the DS and the your opponents are deep in the DS.
Speaker 0: Once they make that one game that proves what it's capable of on some small level Every other game is gonna be basically a phantom hourglass.
Speaker 0: - yep things of the day.
Speaker 1: College humor again, but you might not have watched.
Speaker 1: you might as well just rim.
Speaker 1: You might as well just make your thing of the day.
Speaker 1: college humor.
Speaker 1: comm slash videos RSS feed.
Speaker 0: However, there are two classes of people that this will be relevant for.
Speaker 0: I mean of all of our listeners from what I can gather.
Speaker 0: almost none of you actually go to college humor on a regular basis to watch the videos and - I don't watch all the videos I kind of only watch the ones that I know are gonna be good and I think you have this - the kind of College humor sense of
Speaker 1: you can look at a thumbnail and the title and tell if you want to watch a video or not
Speaker 0: At least 90% of the time.
Speaker 0: Yep, but this was a video that I would not have watched.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't have even thought about it cuz there's a million videos like this.
Speaker 0: It's a guy who sings like 32 songs in eight minutes.
Speaker 0: No big deal.
Speaker 0: I was working on some geek night stuff ahead of packs and I just kind of clicked on it in the background.
Speaker 0: figure out listen To it not watch it while I'm doing something.
Speaker 0: This is a surprisingly nerdy and awesome collection of songs that this guy sings and I don't want to spoil anything for you.
Speaker 0: I think you should just learn what songs are in this list organically but Any song no matter what the lyrics are sounds pretty great.
Speaker 0: If you sing it as a ballad with an acoustic guitar Mmm, okay.
Speaker 1: So let me tell you about this story, right?
Speaker 1: There's a Nintendo DS game.
Speaker 0: I thought you were gonna tell me about the Fresh Prince Prince of Bel-Air.
Speaker 1: No, I. just there is a Nintendo DS game called imagine babies fashion.
Speaker 1: Look at the look at this game.
Speaker 0: All right Is that the baby's brand or is that some other baby?
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: It's babies with a Z. It's imagine babies fashion with a Z.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Wait, where are you going with this?
Speaker 0: I can.
Speaker 0: I can foresee ranging from.
Speaker 0: it's actually a good game - it was banned somewhere for accidentally being child porn.
Speaker 1: No, okay.
Speaker 1: So here's the story.
Speaker 1: There is a forum called the neo gaff forum, right?
Speaker 1: It's a famous video game forum where all sorts of video game people go.
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's very famous and popular.
Speaker 1: I don't go there, but it is famous and important.
Speaker 1: There was a guy on this forum named Kua Hoga c-u-y-a H-o-g-a, right and he posted in a thread about Imagine babies fashion about how he actually liked it And of course a typical lowbrow shit cock internet flame war ensued.
Speaker 1: Of course people calling him a pedophile, which I suspect he may be.
Speaker 1: I'm not I can't But he likes his baby's fashion game.
Speaker 1: chance of pedophilia greater than zero.
Speaker 0: right might just really be into fashion.
Speaker 1: I mean it does he have adults fashion - I have no idea regardless Right in this flame war in one post He said or typed so I'm a pedophile because I don't want to play.
Speaker 1: dude, bro My shit is fucked up.
Speaker 1: So I got to shoot slice you to colon It's straight-up dog time question mark.
Speaker 1: to throw around these sort of accusations of someone who seeks to do something different suggests quite the insecurity on your part.
Speaker 1: He came up with this amazing game title.
Speaker 1: dude, bro, my shit is fucked up.
Speaker 1: So I got to shoot slice you to it's straight-up dog time.
Speaker 0: I would play that.
Speaker 0: I mean that sounds like the alternate title for Bayonetta, so Him coming up with this game title, right?
Speaker 1: spawned the Awesomest awesomest outpouring of creativity.
Speaker 1: Well, not the awesomest ever but a huge internet outpouring of creativity as people began to create Concept art for this game Titles for this game mock-ups of this game and it seems like people are actually making this game.
Speaker 1: dude, bro My shit is fucked up.
Speaker 1: So I got to shoot slice you to it's straight-up dog time.
Speaker 1: May is probably going to become a real game and as you can see there are many parodies.
Speaker 1: For example, the president has been kidnapped by ninjas.
Speaker 1: Are you a bro enough dude to rescue the president GI, bro.
Speaker 1: What is a bro?
Speaker 1: a dog whose shit is yet to be discovered?
Speaker 1: Dude, bro, my shit is fucked up.
Speaker 1: And then when you cheat instead of choosing single-player or our multiplayer you choose bro-low or bromance.
Speaker 1: So here's a mega man, but in the back is dude, bro.
Speaker 0: This actually is interesting.
Speaker 1: What will dude bro do?
Speaker 1: he's fighting a hoot-hoot.
Speaker 1: Is a dude not entitled to the sweat of his bro?
Speaker 1: Dracula says what is a dude bro?
Speaker 1: a miserable little pile of straight-up dog time.
Speaker 0: so You know what this is.
Speaker 0: this is kind of weird like internet culture.
Speaker 0: like before.
Speaker 1: I noticed you were laughing so hard to dude, bro that you had to pause the show.
Speaker 1: Finish you're laughing and then come back into it.
Speaker 0: Well, the studio audience was also laughing.
Speaker 1: but you see this is what happens when you don't use a shitty college humor thing of the day Like rib, right?
Speaker 1: He's a high quality dude, bro thing of the day.
Speaker 1: In fact, I think it might be bro bro of the day bro of the day.
Speaker 0: Maybe that'll be a thing of the bro bro of the bro.
Speaker 1: Anyway, dude of the bro.
Speaker 1: Yeah, bro, that's right.
Speaker 0: So, you know what?
Speaker 0: This is remember back in the day the Photoshop Fridays like the old Photoshop Fridays and something awful.
Speaker 0: there were basically one picture and then people just took that one picture and kept like adding to it or doing things with just that one picture.
Speaker 0: like This whole kind of meme narrative evolved that was self-referential.
Speaker 0: Mmm, dude, bro is very reminiscent of that and you don't see that as often anymore.
Speaker 0: all the Photoshop II things and everything now are much More like people take a concept and run with it in many many different directions.
Speaker 1: The one thing that I have learned from dude, bro And I'm gonna I think you know I just want to get to the pack stuff right is that I think the solution to the internet is to turn
Speaker 0: at the final boss
Speaker 1: Yes,
Speaker 0: or the square boss No
Speaker 1: Just the solution right.
Speaker 1: the answer is to turn flame wars into creativity.
Speaker 1: If someone's having a flame war just start making don't just post like the oh really owl.
Speaker 1: You have to start posting shit specific to that flame war in the photoshopped and funny video category.
Speaker 1: Right turn all the negative.
Speaker 0: You know what that is.
Speaker 0: That's FARC.
Speaker 1: I know right, but you got to spread it.
Speaker 1: So anytime there is flame warring on the internet We have to create with to turn that energy into creativity.
Speaker 1: point You know.
Speaker 1: take any energies on the internet that are.
Speaker 0: you realize what you found here?
Speaker 1: So turn them into creation.
Speaker 0: you do realize this is a source of infinite energy Exactly.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: It is perpetual.
Speaker 1: Imagine if we could harness all of the flame war on the internet and use it to boil water For like and then run it that steam through a turbine.
Speaker 1: We could power freaking a rocket to go to the moon or in the very least, you know much time.
Speaker 0: much more relevant We can end.
Speaker 1: we could live 10 Pokemon.
Speaker 0: We can make a valve game Steam.
Speaker 0: yeah, yeah Not as funny as all the stuff that I've been saying but much more relevant because you see that creativity can only be used to Make creative things.
Speaker 0: we can't make physical things yet.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 1: It's a secret to every bro.
Speaker 0: So Very very briefly and we're gonna skip a lot of it now because we can talk about it in the real part of the show the meta moment.
Speaker 0: Cosmos is the book.
Speaker 0: read it.
Speaker 1: Yes read Carl Sagan's cosmos.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna discuss any PAX East in the meta moment.
Speaker 1: Oh, wait, I just did.
Speaker 1: PAX East is this weekend if you don't go.
Speaker 1: Well, if you don't already have tickets, it's sold out.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry If you don't go.
Speaker 0: you should keep an eye out at the geek nights Twitter account And you should keep an eye out on our website twitter.com.
Speaker 1: so he ignites for a crew to come and on our you stream.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the fuck you stream that come something something.
Speaker 1: just search for geek nights.
Speaker 1: It shows up right away on you because we are going to to the best of our ability post the news at front row.
Speaker 1: crew Calm live stream.
Speaker 0: key moments of packs.
Speaker 1: We're going to stream art.
Speaker 1: We're gonna try to stream as much as we can.
Speaker 1: we might have to resort to audio only.
Speaker 1: we've never really tried this before totally Experimental.
Speaker 0: if we do audio only I'm gonna have to take that image of nerve when they go to audio only in the end.
Speaker 1: Oh, it should just be like audio only say Awesome You got to put the Guinness logo on there also.
Speaker 1: You know We're gonna try to do as much content push straight from packs as we can and also anime Boston and Also during the week in between packs Easter may Boston when we're in Boston now and we're gonna upload YouTube videos
Speaker 0: Stream up to the extent that the data cards we have rented will allow us coupled with the bandwidth we can steal.
Speaker 0: So ever for things that don't get streamed you can also expect pretty big data squirts Period.
Speaker 1: we're gonna be putting the pictures direct to flicker from our phones and all this kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: So take a you know Keep your eye on all this stuff.
Speaker 1: If you cannot go to PAX East and you will get the second best PAX East experience.
Speaker 1: And the thing is you could go to like, you know, like IGN or wherever or game spot.
Speaker 0: Have you watched their coverage?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you'll get this typical g4 kind of coverage where there's an anchor saying stuff Microsoft booth.
Speaker 0: what have you got?
Speaker 1: Right, and they'll show you the stuff at the booths and they'll show you the big names.
Speaker 1: and you know, you go to Kotaku Whatever.
Speaker 1: we're gonna show you like the street level shit that no one else shows you.
Speaker 1: We're gonna show you like people playing tabletop games in the tabletop gaming room.
Speaker 1: We're gonna show you demos of like some random tabletop if at all possible.
Speaker 0: We're gonna live stream action Castle.
Speaker 1: we're gonna show you some small-time stuff, you know, and we're.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: It'll be like you're at packs not like you're at some press conference of packs.
Speaker 1: So Enjoy, you know if you have any tech tips for us that can help us out.
Speaker 1: We appreciate those.
Speaker 1: We're doing this totally experimental for us super ghetto based on what we learn But it's gonna be super authentic and share it with all your friends.
Speaker 1: and please don't bring our site down.
Speaker 1: Just you know, go to you.
Speaker 1: stream YouTube.
Speaker 1: flicker those at Twitter.
Speaker 1: Those will not go down.
Speaker 1: Well, there's a Twitter will go down.
Speaker 0: There's a reason why I did not build our video hosting server yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're not using that for this.
Speaker 0: We're gonna use that after we figure out how much bandwidth you assholes take up, right?
Speaker 1: So Keep an eye out.
Speaker 1: Okay, and of course I said already anime Boston.
Speaker 1: the weekend after that awesome con We're gonna do the same kind of thing, but there's probably gonna be less coverage because there's less to cover.
Speaker 1: And there are many, you know things we can't bring cameras into like concerts and such.
Speaker 0: Of no boo If he does some sort of con note that there doesn't seem to be any problem with cameras at the packs concerts.
Speaker 0: Yes, huh?
Speaker 1: Cuz packs is cool.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: anyway The weekend after that is the mocha arts festival in New York City at the armory on Lexington Avenue If you are in New York City and you're a human being who is literate and can read and can look at pictures.
Speaker 1: You should be there.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute literate and can read and can look at pictures.
Speaker 0: You only need at least one of those.
Speaker 1: Well, you know the thing is actually I know there's a blind dude who can who reads comics But it's like.
Speaker 1: I don't think there's gonna be too many Braille comics Pictures.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, so you should come to the mocha arts festival if you're a human being within distance of New York City.
Speaker 1: No, excuse it's wicked cheap.
Speaker 1: It's wicked.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 1: You just come for one day Saturday or Sunday.
Speaker 1: You don't really need to come both days unless you're really into it and you want to maybe want to see panels on both days Or something like that.
Speaker 1: There aren't really that many panels.
Speaker 1: I think there's one panel room period.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's also to be honest.
Speaker 0: if you want to say hi to us or meet us even for a little bit It'll be way more chill cuz we'll.
Speaker 1: just you know, we don't spend all day.
Speaker 1: They're constantly rushing around to things.
Speaker 1: you're waiting in lines and that you know, we're just chilling in New York We'll hang out all night.
Speaker 1: We live here.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll we should.
Speaker 0: maybe we should see we can plan some sort of a geek Nice event.
Speaker 0: Well, I'll go to Barcade.
Speaker 1: Everyone goes to Barcade.
Speaker 1: We should go somewhere else.
Speaker 0: I want to go to Barcade.
Speaker 0: I've suddenly inspired to go to Barcade and get ridiculous.
Speaker 1: It'll be so crazy crowded and stuff.
Speaker 1: It's too popular.
Speaker 1: We got it.
Speaker 1: We're less popular place.
Speaker 0: I want some shitty dive bar with like one broken miss pac-man machine.
Speaker 1: No, we can just go somewhere, you know, where.
Speaker 0: fun spot.
Speaker 1: Yeah If you live in New Hampshire, we're probably going to fun spot sometime between PAX East and anime Boston.
Speaker 0: just me and rim Biggest arcade in the world follow the geek nights Twitter.
Speaker 0: if you're in Boston There's a good chance that you can hang out with us a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well that that was possibly the most egotistical sounding thing I've ever said.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah If you're there You might be able to hang out with us.
Speaker 1: if you're there and you want to hang out with us You definitely can unless you're a fanboy getaway.
Speaker 1: Okay, so let's get on to the non meta bits.
Speaker 1: I Think that we are in sort of a unique position here and that we are probably some of the only people who went to PAX West more than once and also have an experience with you know, the Convention Center in Boston Yeah, and have sort of an inside track on the convention a little bit, you know.
Speaker 1: And I think that we may be more qualified than most people to give you the survival guide to PAX East Which is there's an asterisk there because we are basing all of this on everything.
Speaker 0: we're extrapolating from what we know about the people running PAX East and What happened at PAX West coupled with our knowledge of anime Boston?
Speaker 1: Yep, and many other things we have knowledge of like conventions in general.
Speaker 1: We've been to a ton of them.
Speaker 0: We may be wrong.
Speaker 0: And also if it's like the year 2040 and you're listening to this it's probably changed.
Speaker 1: Go listen to the PAX East 2011 coverage.
Speaker 0: I mean I listened to our old like Otacon like what to do at Otacon and it was perfectly valid back then Doesn't really work so much.
Speaker 0: Oh really about the artist alley What are we saying?
Speaker 1: What do we say?
Speaker 0: Well artist alley in terms like what sales change like a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: Oh, we were talking about remember back when the law that's not a survival guide for an attendee, but that is true.
Speaker 0: We did remember the advice of you know, just show up late at the line on Thursday You'll be right through.
Speaker 0: get your badge.
Speaker 0: that doesn't apply anymore.
Speaker 1: Oh that changed that year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're right.
Speaker 1: Okay Anyway, so here is the PAX East survival guide.
Speaker 1: number one thing you have to remember is that Parking in Boston sucks ass.
Speaker 1: It costs a fortune.
Speaker 0: Don't don't even like try just park outside and take a cab and don't take the tea.
Speaker 1: And you know, we were gonna take the bolt bus, but we bought tickets too late.
Speaker 1: So it was actually like $50.
Speaker 1: Fucking jet blue is like $200 total for the round trip flight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's so cheap.
Speaker 1: It gets in there in 45 minutes.
Speaker 0: This sort of advice is too little too late for anyone who's going.
Speaker 1: probably Okay, so here's some advice you can use.
Speaker 1: number one.
Speaker 1: Remember PAX East doesn't start until 2 p.m On Friday, so, you know what you should do on Friday.
Speaker 0: You should hang out in Boston with all the PAX people.
Speaker 0: It is going to be like a cloud of locusts descending onto that fair city.
Speaker 0: I mean Seattle tiny little city Pax not nearly as big as they say it is because they lie about the attendance numbers.
Speaker 0: smaller than Otacon but still big When packs ended and before packs began.
Speaker 0: Everywhere you went.
Speaker 0: there's like a hundred packs people everywhere.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So every restaurant every bar every bathroom every street.
Speaker 1: Just go to any cool place in Boston, you know leading up to PAX East and they'll be packs people hanging out.
Speaker 1: They'll be in like the comic store.
Speaker 1: They'll be up in the restaurants.
Speaker 1: They'll be.
Speaker 1: They'll be up in the Apple Store the Trident cafe I don't know.
Speaker 1: We're gonna have to wait until like, you know after packs in between I'm not gonna try to eat there during a convention.
Speaker 1: However, they're during the week.
Speaker 0: Well, let's talk about that on food Later, all right.
Speaker 0: So yeah, basically Anyone you meet and it'll be obvious who the packs people are.
Speaker 0: packs people all kind of look the same.
Speaker 0: They look like 20 to 30 something gamers wearing gamers.
Speaker 1: You can tell who's a packs person if you can.
Speaker 1: what are you doing there?
Speaker 0: You're gonna see Timbuktu bags.
Speaker 0: You're gonna see laptops.
Speaker 0: You're gonna see DS's PSP's.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now remember Um PAX East even though it begins at like 2 p.m.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: I believe that you can actually get into right PAX East much earlier than 2 p.m You'll be able to get in and start waiting in line I think earlier than that.
Speaker 1: if you look at the official PAX East Twitter It will tell you.
Speaker 1: I think maybe even 10 is the time that you can go wait in line.
Speaker 1: I'm not exactly sure but the point is is that you can go.
Speaker 1: Here we go up that did.
Speaker 1: What are you doing?
Speaker 0: Go on.
Speaker 1: Okay What did you do?
Speaker 0: I accidentally opened a browser tab that played stuff.
Speaker 0: Okay, that's fine.
Speaker 0: You can look up what you're looking up.
Speaker 0: It was.
Speaker 0: She told me her name was Billie Jean Mel caused a scene.
Speaker 0: She's just the girl who said that I am the one But the key is not my son Tee hee hee.
Speaker 0: Tee hee hee Are you finished looking up whatever you're looking at?
Speaker 1: I'm having a hard time finding it on this page.
Speaker 1: Oh here we go, I got it.
Speaker 1: Okay Yes, the lineup indeed starts at 10 a.m.
Speaker 1: On Friday 8 a.m.
Speaker 1: On Saturday and Sunday.
Speaker 1: So the thing is, you know, you want to wait in line at like Otakon.
Speaker 1: Oh, it sucks.
Speaker 1: It sucks.
Speaker 1: It does suck at PAX.
Speaker 1: The line is awesome because you're sitting you're indoors and there's PAX people everywhere and basically it's like this.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like a party.
Speaker 1: It's not really a line.
Speaker 0: We are I mean at PAX West Lineup is inside the convention center in a room that is dedicated to lining up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that it's gonna be the same at PAX East.
Speaker 1: I think there's gonna be a queue room.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty like 90% positive.
Speaker 1: Now the thing is they're going to open the doors to the exhibit hall and the keynote simultaneously.
Speaker 1: So you're gonna wait in this.
Speaker 1: you're gonna wait in this line and then it's at you know And you can get in the line as early as 10 a.m.
Speaker 1: And then at 3 p.m they're gonna open and you can go in the exhibit hall or you can go into the keynote and Pretty much there's no reason to go into unless you are like the person who really really wants to play like a game.
Speaker 1: That isn't out yet, you know There's no reason to wait in the exhibit hall line.
Speaker 0: Yeah well Go into the exhibit hall for one long stint.
Speaker 0: Whenever you can get into the exhibit hall like plan it out.
Speaker 0: Don't do it right away on any day because that's whatever other assholes doing it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Go to the keynote.
Speaker 1: It's mandatory.
Speaker 1: I mean Wil Wheaton, I'm not even like a big fan of this Wil Wheaton guy I'll admit.
Speaker 1: and he's done the keynote before you can watch his old one on the internets or on the PAX DVDs.
Speaker 1: But you can't miss the keynote.
Speaker 1: You just can't you gotta go.
Speaker 0: You know if you're used to anime conventions or gaming conventions like other than PAX.
Speaker 0: The keynote at PAX is not just a keynote.
Speaker 0: It is the opening ceremony It is the con.
Speaker 0: the con begins at that event.
Speaker 1: It is a real deal.
Speaker 1: It is not miss.
Speaker 1: if you did not go to the keynote You did not go to pack and we might as well just stay at home.
Speaker 0: We believe that the main events hall at the Heinz where anime Boston also puts its main events hall Has an upper tier that packs will have open it.
Speaker 1: Absolutely I have like 99% confirmed that they the upper tier does exist.
Speaker 1: Remember we saw it when you're anime Boston during that concert.
Speaker 0: It was unused at anime Boston because anime Boston's tiny compared to fax.
Speaker 1: The if you look at the back of the PAX badge Which I saw a picture of it specifically lists the upper deck as a room that is available on the back of the badge.
Speaker 1: Therefore it is a safe assumption that the upper decks of the you know Main events theater will be open.
Speaker 0: and thus Oh my god If I go to the Friday concert like after our last gonna wait in the upper deck I might just go to the upper deck lay down for the all the concerts.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna go to the upper deck and chill.
Speaker 0: it's hard to say.
Speaker 1: anyway The point is that there will be ample seating for the main event.
Speaker 0: Yes, you don't.
Speaker 1: if you you only nearly need to wait in the line if you want to be kind of close.
Speaker 0: But the keynote is mandatory.
Speaker 0: It is crazy.
Speaker 0: Awesome If you ever.
Speaker 0: you know other cons the opening ceremonies are like boring or crappy or whatever.
Speaker 0: The keynote is so great.
Speaker 0: And right after it is the PA Q&A panel number one.
Speaker 1: now This is where we have to talk about my vision.
Speaker 0: Ah the vision.
Speaker 1: now if you do not know about having a vision go and listen to the old geek nights episode about the vision I foresee and the bamboo small mushrooms.
Speaker 0: Yeah as far as the eye can see.
Speaker 1: Now there is you know.
Speaker 1: there I have decided that there is a new game We are playing.
Speaker 1: the new game is is basically the vision tally game.
Speaker 1: Every time you have a vision and the vision becomes reality you score one point and this game will end when we are both dead And that will be the game.
Speaker 0: So are we starting the scores at zero now?
Speaker 0: Are we gonna try to retcon have you any visions that you haven't become reality?
Speaker 0: Do I I envisioned a podcast?
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay anyway I Have this vision.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: and the vision is this if you do not know you probably don't if you didn't go to PAX West ever that when Gabe And taiko appear on the stage for a Q&A panel the song every day I am hustling is the intro song.
Speaker 1: it is always the intro song.
Speaker 1: one time They forgot to use it and someone reminded them.
Speaker 1: They left the stage then re-entered to the song as was necessary.
Speaker 1: You can find a video of this on the YouTube.
Speaker 1: I have made a forum thread on our forums with four such videos demonstrating that this is indeed a tradition.
Speaker 1: There is a ninety nine point nine percent chance that this will be the intro song to Q&A one and possibly even two.
Speaker 1: My vision is this Before every damn hustling comes in over the stereo system and the loudspeakers in the main event hall if the entire keynote audience Of packs because it's immediately after the keynote like you literally just stay seated and then they come out right.
Speaker 0: and it's not just they Come out like rock stars because they are rock stars at this point at the it's you know it's their convention It's you know.
Speaker 1: so If everybody were to sing just every damn hustle, and they don't need I don't even really need to sing We just need to chant every day.
Speaker 1: I'm hustling Again in unison.
Speaker 1: the whole theater every the entire audience were to just do this up until the point at which it comes in Over the music it would be the epic.
Speaker 0: now It would be a nice kind of welcome to the better coast to gave in taiko.
Speaker 1: That's what I'm saying, right?
Speaker 1: It's like Pax West has never done something quite that epic.
Speaker 1: so if Pax East were able to pull this off Immediately from the get-go right?
Speaker 1: not only would this say East is better than West bitches Right it would also some first ladies.
Speaker 1: It would also set the tone for the remainder of Pax in a very high quality way.
Speaker 0: in the same manner that we have a Plan at another big convention of giving all the people who have to line up outside chalk Because we don't want them to like graffiti with markers on the wall.
Speaker 0: Yes But if you give them chalk and you do not draw something nice first if the first thing someone draws is a penis It's all over yep, but if we get someone to draw some nice arts And then we give chalk out it will just be nice ours.
Speaker 0: so our goal is to prevent a Pax penis.
Speaker 1: Yes, so this is going to set the tone.
Speaker 1: So I need everyone listening to.
Speaker 1: this is going to happen.
Speaker 1: is the timing is going to be rough?
Speaker 0: We we learned a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Scott And I were discussing this.
Speaker 0: we attempted something similar at another con and Otakon a long time ago.
Speaker 0: We failed and the reason we failed.
Speaker 0: I'll link to it.
Speaker 0: Scott actually pointed this video to me.
Speaker 0: I've never seen it before.
Speaker 0: it's the principles of leadership.
Speaker 0: But basically if you try to start something like this in the wrong way, you're just one weirdo loser.
Speaker 0: Yep, but if you do it in the right way You are only a weirdo loser for a few minutes, and then you win.
Speaker 0: yep So we're doing this in the right way.
Speaker 0: This is a calculated move.
Speaker 1: the problem is we need we need proper execution, right?
Speaker 1: I will begin.
Speaker 1: Thing is what will my timing be?
Speaker 1: will I do it as soon as the keynote is over?
Speaker 1: I think what I'm going to have to do is the keynote will end.
Speaker 1: He'll leave the stage right and then like as soon as things are sort of settle settle.
Speaker 1: Then I'll have to begin it at that moment because I can't write because who knows how long it's going to be it It's going to need a few minutes to build up.
Speaker 0: It depends on if they're gonna show those ads between.
Speaker 1: so that's the thing is I completely forgot.
Speaker 1: I thought this is gonna be easy to get this going.
Speaker 1: But this good they usually play ads video ads and music while the crowd is sitting in the events hall.
Speaker 1: And if we start this thing up Yeah, if it's like no it's not gonna be 45 minutes.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be a technical problem.
Speaker 0: They can't.
Speaker 1: Yeah, depending on how long it takes for them to write.
Speaker 1: We're gonna have to.
Speaker 1: you know It will take some like some loudness and some effort to get this going above the music and advertisements that may or may not be Playing.
Speaker 0: so no.
Speaker 0: No, I thought of something.
Speaker 0: what if they're standing back there?
Speaker 0: They've got the guy with the hustling ready and the crowd starts doing this.
Speaker 0: They decide not to play it.
Speaker 0: They just walk out to the crowds hustling.
Speaker 1: That's fun.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: It's still epic awesomeness, right?
Speaker 1: The point is I'm gonna begin it, you know, we'll beat and leaves the stage, you know things settle sell for like literally like 10 seconds.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna.
Speaker 1: I will start on my own because if I start with a group then it doesn't work.
Speaker 1: It has to be me and then I need someone else sort of like.
Speaker 0: I believe I will be the second one.
Speaker 0: We'll stay kind of apart from each other.
Speaker 1: We need yeah, we need to.
Speaker 1: we need to do something.
Speaker 0: The choreographed Scott will start, you know every day.
Speaker 0: I'm hustling every day.
Speaker 0: That's all you had to do is just say that over and over again in unison I'll be like 10 or 15 feet away and I'll look at him and kind of pointedly be like every day.
Speaker 0: I'm hustling like doing the arm throw at him and then he'll throw the arm throw back and we'll do it together.
Speaker 0: We need like four or five more Stooges to one by one start doing that with us and Converge on a spot every day.
Speaker 0: I'm hustling and If we get enough people to do it the whole crowd will do it and it'll be a beautiful ghost in the shell like second Order Simulac.
Speaker 0: or we shouldn't?
Speaker 1: I shouldn't move from your location.
Speaker 1: You should stay where you are while you are while you were hustling a few people because it award.
Speaker 0: while they're doing it They'll lead a trail.
Speaker 1: No It's no good because you need to it's gonna be.
Speaker 1: we need the volume to spread around this.
Speaker 1: you'd realize how big it's gonna be.
Speaker 1: Remember that California concert?
Speaker 1: Yeah and the upper deck.
Speaker 0: but remember you need a core of people to like a few people in one area who then are loud enough to Cause it to spread and then people further away see it and then they start doing it further away.
Speaker 1: Just stay where you are.
Speaker 1: Trust me.
Speaker 1: I have calculated this.
Speaker 0: However, we will probably have the.
Speaker 0: uh, we have an artifact from PAX West.
Speaker 0: I don't know how many will be there, but we were bringing it.
Speaker 0: Yes the pip boy It was weird at the first PAX that we went to.
Speaker 0: it was one of the most sought-after Things.
Speaker 0: there were a few hundred of them at the con and the people who had them were just.
Speaker 0: they stood out and they used Them to great effect.
Speaker 0: the next packs only like 15 or 20 people brought them and those people use them to epic effect.
Speaker 0: Pax East.
Speaker 1: years later, there's gonna be like five and those are gonna be epic and I'm bringing mine, you know, hustle it I'm gonna hustle it day.
Speaker 0: I'm hustling.
Speaker 1: Alright, so that's what we got to do.
Speaker 1: That's the vision.
Speaker 1: Let's make it a reality Okay.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you you know the Q&A panels in all honesty aren't really Q&A panels.
Speaker 1: I mean you can Q&A, but usually it's basically your chance as a. you know It's a step up to the mic and make something happen.
Speaker 1: So for example people come up and say hey everybody just so you know Cookie Brigade.
Speaker 1: Oh shit, or you know, hey you forgot to play.
Speaker 0: every day I'm hustling or a lot of people do cool stuff.
Speaker 0: one guy sang, you know, Rick roll.
Speaker 0: one guy played a Rick roll.
Speaker 1: Yep, there's those guys who sang the whatever song the this night.
Speaker 1: What's it called the?
Speaker 1: The horse song.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, or the guys who brought the cardboard cutout of their friend who couldn't be there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the cardboard cutout on stage.
Speaker 0: it.
Speaker 0: now don't be a jackass and be like, hey Like try to sell something or anything, but got to do something cool.
Speaker 0: No, I mean everyone question or you have to have a really good question.
Speaker 1: You can't go up and ask the lame question.
Speaker 1: You know, it's got to be the high quality question.
Speaker 0: Of course, it's interesting because Pax West.
Speaker 0: I think the reason this culture came was that the same people by and large go to Pax West every year.
Speaker 0: So they already asked all the questions probably like six packs as a go.
Speaker 1: Pax East is gonna be a lot of reruns.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's gonna be a lot of people asking real questions that would never get asked at Pax West.
Speaker 0: I think all right.
Speaker 1: Anyway after the P&A panel 1 right Q&A panel 1 my suggestion to you Is that if you want a official Pax merchandise as in t-shirts the official Pax East scarf Pax East?
Speaker 1: Whatever you should get the to the merchandise booth.
Speaker 0: that stuff is gonna sell out before the end of the day on Friday.
Speaker 1: I don't realize this.
Speaker 1: you go to Otakon.
Speaker 1: you can buy an Otakon shirt.
Speaker 1: at Otakon They make a new one every year and like at New York and a festival You can buy merchandise that says New York and a festival with like a little Liberty girl on there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the every convention I've been to sells merchandise for itself.
Speaker 1: Pax.
Speaker 1: that merchandise sells out every single year.
Speaker 1: if you do not get it on Friday or perhaps early Saturday You will not get it.
Speaker 1: You will not get a Pax East shirt.
Speaker 1: There are not enough for everybody and if you want one get in line and get one.
Speaker 0: Pax did not expect the response They got.
Speaker 0: they did not expect the con to sell out and then extend it and then still sell out.
Speaker 0: They are not.
Speaker 0: when they decided way back how much merch to print there is no way on this freaking earth They understood how many people are gonna be there.
Speaker 1: They even know they said in their Twitter that it's going to sell out.
Speaker 0: Well, they know now But had they if they'd they'd listen to us way back they would have printed like 18,000 t-shirts And probably still sold out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if you want, right?
Speaker 1: The shirt you you had better there will be a very limited number of Pax shirts available.
Speaker 1: If you show up on a Friday, you shouldn't have a problem snagging one though, right?
Speaker 1: That is from the official Pax on Twitter.
Speaker 0: So panels.
Speaker 0: just go to any panel you like.
Speaker 0: however, if you go to our panels if you want to see a panel I'm not sure a hundred percent how this will happen But there aren't that many panels at a Pax compared to say an anime con.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they all have breaks in between them, you know, and there really aren't that many.
Speaker 1: each day.
Speaker 1: there's really only three theaters that have panels in them and Pretty much every panel fills up maximum.
Speaker 1: So you got to wait in line to go to a panel and like for example our first panel at Pax ever.
Speaker 0: You know Pax west years ago beyond Dungeons & Dragons.
Speaker 0: People lined up for like an hour and a half and the room filled up almost immediately and then almost no one got to See it.
Speaker 1: Yep They will not let you in once all the seats are filled But they enforcers will make a very good job of making sure there is an ass in every seat and there are no empty seats.
Speaker 0: Yes, but if you were looking for a panel to see our first one beyond Dungeons & Dragons 830 to 930 p.m.
Speaker 1: On Friday sadly conflicting with the beginning of the Friday night concert in the Wyvern theater Wyvern Our second panel losing should be fun.
Speaker 1: 1130 to 1230 in the morning So
Speaker 0: overnight Friday also in the Wyvern theater
Speaker 1: in theater also conflicting with the Friday night concert Which is if you are a Friday night concert person if you want to see the front a lot the onomatoguchi the Metroid metal The proto men just don't come to those panels.
Speaker 0: Yes, we won't feel bad.
Speaker 0: We're going to record them We're going to put.
Speaker 1: if I didn't have those panels at those times.
Speaker 1: I'd be going to that concert, too.
Speaker 0: However, I don't feel bad because we're going to go to PAX East or PAX West in like six months and see the same.
Speaker 1: We've already seen all those people.
Speaker 0: Yes, and they're awesome, but I don't need to see them again.
Speaker 0: I really just want Joe co to sing to me all night.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which will happen on Saturday night.
Speaker 1: Yes, we are not doing anything on Saturday except awesome.
Speaker 1: We'll be going to Expo Hall.
Speaker 1: We'll be playing games.
Speaker 1: This is something people don't realize our packs.
Speaker 1: It's sort of obvious though.
Speaker 1: You got nothing to do.
Speaker 1: Oh, none of the nothing on the schedule looks good right now.
Speaker 1: I already saw every booth in the expo hall.
Speaker 1: I'm bored.
Speaker 1: You can't be bored at PAX.
Speaker 1: You can always play games.
Speaker 1: go to the open PC gaming go to the open console gaming go to the open tabletop gaming Most of all and just fucking play games.
Speaker 0: play games all night long and everybody's cool.
Speaker 0: I mean even gaming cons.
Speaker 0: I've gone to other than packs.
Speaker 0: You know you might be used to this.
Speaker 0: you want to play a game.
Speaker 0: you find one cool guy who wants to play with you.
Speaker 0: Two really scary guys.
Speaker 0: you're trying to tell them the games full even though it's not and then you're trying to like slowly Look for the one other cool-looking person around.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Everybody's cool at PAX.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is very rare to deal with an uncool person and the tabletop gaming areas are so happening.
Speaker 1: I was in the tabletop gaming area packs West last year and it was like I'd be teaching two separate groups of people to play Agricola at the same time and then I'd bust out a Dominion and then I would you know talk to someone about a game a sushi game that they were playing and ask him if it was good Or not and then I'd get a demo from some guy who's trying to sell a game He made and then I would go and check out another game and that I never heard.
Speaker 1: I read the rules and play it And then bust out another Dominion and then teach someone Puerto Rico and then you know It's word of warning though the game that was hot at the last packs a pack Dominion was Dominion.
Speaker 0: it will be hot at PAX East.
Speaker 1: if you want to play Dominion bring your own buy one beforehand.
Speaker 1: If there will be dealers, I know the complete strategist will be in the expo Hall selling games.
Speaker 1: I know that Luke crane Jared Sorenson and some friends will be demoing things at that booth and possibly also in the tabletop area and If you they will sell games and there might be.
Speaker 1: there will probably other sellers of games as well.
Speaker 1: But hot games like Dominion will probably sell out.
Speaker 1: You should bring your own copy play someone else's copy etcetera.
Speaker 0: But my word of warning to you is that there is a very similar game that if you hear the description of it You will think it's the best game ever.
Speaker 0: It's Dominion with dungeon crawling.
Speaker 0: It's called Thunderstone.
Speaker 1: a thunderstone has a special inside joke meaning for us it does.
Speaker 0: it is however Not that good.
Speaker 0: So do not worry about playing Thunderstone.
Speaker 1: I know actually, you know for us it's not that good.
Speaker 1: I think the vast majority of our listeners would be like, oh my god Thunderstone so awesome.
Speaker 0: Well, just be warned because it's a game that you might start playing that will just drag on forever If they come.
Speaker 1: you don't want to play something that's too long because you might right make sure you look at the schedule before you get Into something like that.
Speaker 0: and also, you know They'll probably have retro gaming and you know modern gaming.
Speaker 0: and usually the way it works is you just go check out a game Find some people and play it and they have a leaderboards and all sorts of cool stuff.
Speaker 1: a very good idea If you want to save time is look for people who are you know game makers like Steve Jackson is there.
Speaker 1: just go to him.
Speaker 1: Be like hey I need I want to play a game and he'll have a game that you can play and some will teach you to be real Quick and you'll be on the road.
Speaker 0: Don't be afraid to go up to those people You know all that like like Luke Crane or Steve Jackson and just ask if they want to play a game with you.
Speaker 0: They very well might just say yes.
Speaker 1: Yeah talking to anyone, you know, everyone at PAX is awesome.
Speaker 1: There's like almost 0% fanboys.
Speaker 1: not gonna say 0% but almost 0% fanboys.
Speaker 1: You just go to people.
Speaker 1: be like they got DS.
Speaker 1: just be like, what's up Mario Kart and people like hell's.
Speaker 1: yeah There you go.
Speaker 0: Rock and roll till the wireless breaks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also if you are, you know, the dogs are tired at any time.
Speaker 1: head for the beanbags.
Speaker 0: Will they be there?
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure the beanbags will be there.
Speaker 0: How do they check?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's got to be being.
Speaker 0: I would assume there's gonna be sumos but there's no beanbags.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the hell That's not packs.
Speaker 1: Ah, I just ain't packs.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: There's gotta be beanbags.
Speaker 1: if there's no beanbags kill yourself.
Speaker 1: And always if you ever get to the beanbags and there's a free beanbag just always hold on to one extra one.
Speaker 1: that way If I walk by and you have a beanbag saved for me, you'll be my best friend.
Speaker 0: So unlike an anime con or a con you might normally go to Where there's a million million events and you have to choose like do I want to go to this or this?
Speaker 0: It's really easy to plot your way through packs.
Speaker 0: Just look at the panel schedule and look at the concert schedule and circle like the five things You really want to do and split all the rest of the time between eating.
Speaker 0: Don't forget to eat.
Speaker 0: Hanging out playing games.
Speaker 0: hanging out playing games.
Speaker 0: Hanging out hanging out playing games going to the exhibit hall once or twice and that's it.
Speaker 0: So there's.
Speaker 0: there's nothing else doing it.
Speaker 1: The only things you cannot miss the keynote.
Speaker 1: You should probably not miss PNA panel one because you're gonna help me with my vision.
Speaker 1: If nothing else if you have not been to a PAX before you should go to all the concerts.
Speaker 0: Do not leave the concert and go to bed.
Speaker 1: concerts will most likely go until 2 a.m When the con closes, right?
Speaker 1: I think the con closes 2 a.m.
Speaker 1: Friday and Saturday on Sunday.
Speaker 1: I think it closes at 6.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right it opens at 2 p.m Well, the line opens at 10 a.m.
Speaker 1: Friday, but the con opens at 2 p.m.
Speaker 1: Friday.
Speaker 1: It opens at 10 a.m At 10 a.m.
Speaker 1: On Saturday and Sunday.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 0: now if you have never been to a PAX go to the PA make a strip.
Speaker 1: It's awesome, but I've actually never been to it.
Speaker 0: We failed because well they I always failed to go to it for some reason.
Speaker 0: They failed last year and we bailed.
Speaker 1: Oh, right Yeah, there was the tech problem last year and they moved it.
Speaker 1: so we didn't go.
Speaker 1: but we yeah.
Speaker 1: But we were we almost made it.
Speaker 1: so there is some sort of curse.
Speaker 1: We never end up going to the make a strip panel.
Speaker 0: I'm going to try to go to it.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know what?
Speaker 1: I will also try to go to it and hopefully there'll be the hot dog fairy.
Speaker 0: We have an advantage.
Speaker 0: the Heinz has the upper deck.
Speaker 1: You want to go to the upper deck for the make a strip?
Speaker 0: good I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: this is total speculation.
Speaker 0: I will wager the upper deck will be the safe guaranteed way to see any main event.
Speaker 1: Here is a no.
Speaker 1: So here's some other random advices.
Speaker 1: Let's say you've got some friends going to packs right like some people on the internets and you want to meet up with them But you don't know where and when.
Speaker 1: one of the best places to meet up with someone is just say hey everyone Go to omega-thon round number one, right because the early omega-thon rounds are actually some of the lesser attended events.
Speaker 0: However, however, that's tricky because that's at PAX West where you know, people are used to it Hard to say.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I guess you give omega-thon advice.
Speaker 1: the omega-thon has changed this year, right?
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: because they used to have problems where like they would announce they would you know ask you when you registered Do you want to be an omega?
Speaker 1: not and they'd.
Speaker 1: people say no and they have a hard time finding omega notes.
Speaker 1: What they're doing is at packs at walking into the keynote.
Speaker 1: If you want to be an omega not you will fill out a form.
Speaker 1: Then they will you know after the keynote pull from a box or a hat The people who will be omega knots and they will pair people up into teams of two randomly.
Speaker 1: You don't know who your partner is gonna be now.
Speaker 0: I point out keynote three to four PA panel four to five.
Speaker 0: Omega-thon round one five to six.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: They're moving rapidly.
Speaker 1: Yes, so you if you want to be an omega not that you have to go to the keynote fill out the form etc.
Speaker 1: Wait for them to pick out of the head.
Speaker 1: you if you come up you come up.
Speaker 1: It's going to be an all co-op omega-thon, right?
Speaker 1: The first three rounds are gonna be like rhythm game Mario Kart double dash and something else I forget.
Speaker 1: and then the final rounds.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what they're gonna be.
Speaker 1: their secrets, I guess.
Speaker 1: And you cannot miss the final round a closing ceremony from five to six.
Speaker 1: There is nothing conflicting with it ever.
Speaker 0: That is and the thing is the the general thing to do it packs.
Speaker 0: This is the one time no matter what you should just line up way early Because that line is kind of the end run of the con and everyone lines up you all go in They fuck up the technology for like an hour and then they have the final round of the omega-thon And then packs ends and everyone walks outside.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: No, you cannot miss the closing ceremony.
Speaker 1: You must wait in line for it.
Speaker 1: You must go to it.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, it's not packs.
Speaker 1: Why are you coming?
Speaker 1: You know now the only other thing at home given your badge to someone else you must attend and this is not our panel.
Speaker 0: We are not doing it.
Speaker 0: Jared Sorenson is doing it at 10 30 a.m.
Speaker 0: Also in the wyvern theater.
Speaker 0: every panel we have is in the wyvern theater because the wyvern theater is awesome.
Speaker 0: I got you said wyvern.
Speaker 0: I got it.
Speaker 0: Got you.
Speaker 1: Fuck you the wyvern theater Action castle.
Speaker 0: if you do not know what that is show up.
Speaker 0: Seriously it has been the secret event.
Speaker 0: two packs is in a row But now it is finally not secret anymore.
Speaker 0: Steve Jackson played it and then he later tweeted about how crazy awesome It was.
Speaker 1: yep and followed immediately following.
Speaker 0: that is beyond Candyland our panel and you know what because we have the.
Speaker 0: you know It's.
Speaker 0: it's Jared and Luke and we're gonna help him like in the background and then us.
Speaker 0: We might just like continue like me like last year.
Speaker 0: We did action castle secret event right.
Speaker 0: then me Scott and Jared did kind of a game design gaming Q&A For the rest of the half-hour.
Speaker 0: We've then got the half-hour in the room before our panel Well acts.
Speaker 1: Oh, is it a really a half-hour break?
Speaker 1: It is a half-hour break.
Speaker 0: We'll probably just keep doing stuff in that room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I heard though that action castle is also going to include jungle adventure.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: You're gonna get two for the price of one.
Speaker 0: So if you show up in the wyvern theater for the 10 30 a.m.
Speaker 1: Panel on Sunday Just don't leave just stay there from 10 30 a.m.
Speaker 0: To 1 p.m Crazy shits going down in there.
Speaker 1: That is the geek nights and I'm pretty much at 1 p.m.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna go eat lunch Then I'm gonna play a few games then I'm gonna get in line for a clothing ceremony and that's gonna be it.
Speaker 1: That's that's my Sunday.
Speaker 1: I already know what my Sunday is gonna be now.
Speaker 0: if you are an old man and you Cannot stay up until 2 a.m.
Speaker 0: For two concerts two days in a row And this is your only packs you can ever go to I Would recommend going to the Saturday concert over the Friday concert if you have to choose.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because Paul and storm are kind of like a more modern more vulgar version of the Smothers brothers.
Speaker 0: No They're not as funny.
Speaker 0: I would say as the Smothers brothers, but they've been taller vibe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're cool.
Speaker 1: They've been touring with Jonathan Colton.
Speaker 1: So and Jonathan Colton, it's also the video game Orchestra.
Speaker 1: Yes, Paul and storm.
Speaker 0: then Jonathan Colton But and usually remember MC front a lot will probably slip in and sing at least one song with all these guys.
Speaker 1: Maybe I can guarantee you that Jonathan Colton will slip in and sing with emcee front a lot.
Speaker 0: Jonathan called Friday night is Almost my favorite part of every packs, even though he sings the same goddamn songs every pack.
Speaker 1: Well 90%.
Speaker 1: Did you see that epic picture I showed you?
Speaker 0: Yes But it's just like your dad singing to you with an acoustic guitar and it's just the nicest thing in the world.
Speaker 0: And you just.
Speaker 0: it's the whole crowd singing with him.
Speaker 0: It's so great.
Speaker 0: I love it so much.
Speaker 1: Alright, is there any other?
Speaker 1: Paxing.
Speaker 0: so if you want to eat food Yo, we know the Boston area from other cons.
Speaker 0: Here's the deal.
Speaker 0: if you have money It's easy.
Speaker 0: walk out the front of the convention center not the mall entrance, but like the main entrance Walk two blocks away from the convention center.
Speaker 1: There is a street with all sorts of little fancy restaurants.
Speaker 0: They're super fancy.
Speaker 0: They're super expensive.
Speaker 1: They're super not super expensive.
Speaker 1: They're just you know, they're expensive medium expensive.
Speaker 1: It was a. if it was like Yelp, they would be $2 signs.
Speaker 0: They range from like 10 to $30 for lunch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's about right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we're kind of spoiled by New York.
Speaker 0: I mean think of the average con goer like a McDonald's I don't know a little pricey.
Speaker 0: Okay If you do not so and also if you need to get away from someone That is the way to go because you can usually divide up to a fancy restaurant get a reservation and get away from the crowd.
Speaker 1: There's also an Apple store and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: The crowd of the con probably will not go over there that often because they're not gonna know about all those restaurants.
Speaker 1: Most of the people are going to be going to the food court in the mall.
Speaker 1: This is attached to the convention center.
Speaker 0: avoid it at all costs.
Speaker 1: avoid that food court.
Speaker 1: It will be doomed.
Speaker 1: You'll be waiting in line for like an hour to get like a mediocre taco at Qdoba or some shit.
Speaker 0: So if you need cheap food walk out the convention center Like the main entrance turn left and walk off into what looks like kind of a shadier area.
Speaker 1: There's bodegas and cheap restaurants and stuff over here is a secret to everybody if you turn to the right Near the food court.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it's near the food court But sort of outside near like these outside tables kind of down in the street.
Speaker 1: There is a grocery store around near the convention center somewhere.
Speaker 1: I think it's a shaw's right?
Speaker 1: Yeah I hope it's still there.
Speaker 1: You can go to the grocery store and get freaking food that you can eat.
Speaker 1: It's probably gonna be no line, you know, even though there's a gigantic invention You're just gonna be a walk in the grocery store get food.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be all good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it'll cost a grocery store.
Speaker 1: Normal price is normal grocery store and it's food.
Speaker 1: It's probably better than the food court also.
Speaker 0: So hell yeah Nope If you have time at all and also this place is cheap go to the Trident cafe and get breakfast or lunch.
Speaker 1: Good luck waiting in line.
Speaker 1: There's a line to get into the Trident cafe at anime Boston.
Speaker 1: You're gonna be waiting all day to eat.
Speaker 0: There's a line to get into the Trident cafe on a normal day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's why I'm not eating there until the week.
Speaker 0: That place is so awesome.
Speaker 0: You can remember your syrup.
Speaker 0: They gave me real syrup first, you can't fly with it.
Speaker 1: No, it's alright.
Speaker 1: I'll use it up in New Hampshire.
Speaker 0: Any other I'm thinking I'm just don't cover like you have to go to a million events.
Speaker 0: There's not that much.
Speaker 0: pick the panels you want pick the events you want.
Speaker 1: You just got to go the exhibit hall.
Speaker 1: get it covered, you know.
Speaker 1: get the.
Speaker 1: maybe the go-to events I listed keynote PA panel one make a strip concerts closing ceremonies.
Speaker 1: You got to have all those covered.
Speaker 1: spend the rest of the time playing games hanging out and go in our panels.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Heat nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.