Speaker 0: It's Monday March 1st.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight getting people to actually read the words on the screen.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Had a weekend of skiing that was half epic win and half epic epic fail.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean there was the whole fail with like the renting a car.
Speaker 1: Is there more fail than that?
Speaker 0: There is more fail than that.
Speaker 0: So I should have stayed home.
Speaker 1: We could have played some games watch some hockey.
Speaker 0: I was worth it.
Speaker 0: in the end though rental car fail.
Speaker 0: There was a bunch of snow.
Speaker 0: So the rental car place is just like yeah, you know what we closed.
Speaker 0: you're not gonna get your car.
Speaker 1: He could have taken the skiing bus.
Speaker 0: Yeah the skiing bus that's $85 a person and as I saw gets there kind of late and had some other trouble.
Speaker 0: because you see
Speaker 1: point if it gets there Late and you want to scale
Speaker 0: we get there right and as we're pulling up We're running like a few minutes late and I wanted to get there right when the slopes open But I see how the lift isn't even running yet.
Speaker 0: Obviously, they're having a late start.
Speaker 0: This is good.
Speaker 0: getting here earlier would have been a mistake.
Speaker 0: Oh, there was no power on the mountain all night.
Speaker 0: Oh, they just got power.
Speaker 0: now Most of the lifts aren't working and there are record crowds.
Speaker 0: What do they do?
Speaker 0: sell everybody lift tickets?
Speaker 0: Let them get in line and they get them all pissed off.
Speaker 0: There are people screaming and hunter-mountain employees in line demanding refunds screaming that they're gonna charge back their credit cards.
Speaker 1: I would demand a refund, you know, if I have a ticket and then lift doesn't work.
Speaker 1: It's like if I go to Disney World and you know Space Mountain is closed.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: That's you know, sure.
Speaker 1: That's it happens sometimes right?
Speaker 1: I got a Disney World and every ride is closed.
Speaker 0: There's a ton of lifts But there's only one lift from the bottom all the way up to the top and that one was running then.
Speaker 1: But the wait to get up it was like an hour Because it was basically every single person was lined up and it only goes person two people.
Speaker 0: Yep I don't get in this line and I wait an hour and I go up to the top and I find out that none Of the other lifts are working up there and the backside of the mountains is completely fucked.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So How could skiing?
Speaker 1: Get stopped by snow?
Speaker 0: You know how that happens if you ski in New York, there really aren't any really actually good ski places.
Speaker 0: They're all a little bit chintzy.
Speaker 0: I mean I look at a blue or a black and the places that my friends at work all ski.
Speaker 0: And it makes Hunter Mountain look like this tiny little baby mountain with tiny little babies.
Speaker 1: Why don't you go where the people are workers skiing?
Speaker 0: because I have to fly out there and spend like a week to make it Worth it.
Speaker 1: Oh They're flying in like Colorado.
Speaker 0: They're going to Colorado.
Speaker 0: Oh, they're closest.
Speaker 0: They're going is Vermont.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, Vermont is actually huge with skiing.
Speaker 1: Yeah gigantic.
Speaker 1: You can go to Poconos, I think right?
Speaker 0: So here's the problem.
Speaker 0: though I was I would have just charged back my credit card said fuck all this and hang out in the lodge drinking all day and Then gone home.
Speaker 0: But the snow was the best snow New York State has probably ever seen.
Speaker 0: It was like two feet of like awesome powder and moguls and bumps everywhere.
Speaker 0: So I stuck with it and after about three hours They got everything working enough to where I could ski the rest of the day And they kept the lifts open an extra half hour at the end of the day to make up for it.
Speaker 0: So all in all I'm not super mad because the skiing was pretty good.
Speaker 0: But here's the epic fail and this did not involve me at all.
Speaker 0: The lift on the back mountain.
Speaker 0: they got power back on so they turn that lift right back on.
Speaker 0: Bunch of people are on the lift, you know going down the West Mountain.
Speaker 0: Scogel and I are like, hey, let's go down the West Mountain.
Speaker 0: We're just about to go down the run when this guy's like stop.
Speaker 0: Stop.
Speaker 1: Don't go down.
Speaker 0: The lift just broke.
Speaker 0: There's no way back up if you go down there And we look and we see all these people sitting on a lift.
Speaker 0: Stop going.
Speaker 0: Better better better better.
Speaker 1: So you're about to get on a lift.
Speaker 0: well, we were about to go down the back of the mountain.
Speaker 0: the only way Anywhere from the bottom of those runs is up the lift that broke or walking two miles through the mountains back to the main lodge Around the base of the mountain.
Speaker 1: Whoa, they don't have like an emergency service road or anything.
Speaker 0: They do.
Speaker 0: but you got to walk two miles on it and damned if they're gonna drive a car down It's a service road.
Speaker 1: They're gonna drive us like a snowmobile back there.
Speaker 1: something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's like a hundred two hundred people down there.
Speaker 0: So they just made them all walk.
Speaker 1: really they fixed it for long enough to get 200 people down there.
Speaker 0: No, cuz you can go down you just couldn't get back up.
Speaker 1: So all these people went down when the lift wasn't running.
Speaker 0: they went down just as the lift had started up.
Speaker 1: 200 people went down.
Speaker 1: a lift starts 200 be one.
Speaker 0: Sheesh basically.
Speaker 0: Yeah This was the most crowded ski weekend like ever.
Speaker 1: Like people are just like.
Speaker 1: hundreds of people were standing there a lift Activated and they all went.
Speaker 0: basically and in fact show Joe and I we're standing there right and we're like, oh What are the odds that the lift will start up in the next few minutes?
Speaker 0: You think we can just go down anyway, because that was the one I wanted to do that run.
Speaker 0: It would have been worth it almost.
Speaker 0: So that's not the real epic fail.
Speaker 0: The real epic fail is captain snowboard Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: We're on the lift like the main lift.
Speaker 0: going back up means go Joe and we see you know a snowboarder who's not doing so well Way up in front of us and he is he on the lift or is he?
Speaker 0: he's actually snowboard?
Speaker 1: Okay, cuz I saw a video on the internets of a snowboarder on the lift who fell off the lift and landed face-first in The snow for the holes.
Speaker 0: I think I saw that same video.
Speaker 0: Okay, and those friends are like is he okay?
Speaker 0: and he didn't move.
Speaker 0: Yeah video ends.
Speaker 0: So he's coming down the mountain.
Speaker 0: He hits a mogul.
Speaker 0: He clearly didn't know what to do.
Speaker 0: and he flips over and disappears in like a sea of powdery snow.
Speaker 0: So we're all laughing on the lift.
Speaker 0: People's are clapping and then his snowboard comes flying out of the debris down the mountain.
Speaker 0: Hit.
Speaker 0: somebody in the skis flips him away.
Speaker 1: So a snowboard just did poop.
Speaker 1: Yes, the guy was still in the snow.
Speaker 0: The guy was in the snow snowboard no longer on.
Speaker 0: the guy going down the mountain snowboard just popped out going down the mountain like A rocket.
Speaker 1: how could it go so fast on its own?
Speaker 0: because it's going straight down and there's no guy on it anymore No one controlling it.
Speaker 0: I mean when you ski you kind of go left right left right around the buff You don't go straight down the mountain.
Speaker 0: That's how you die.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So it's picking up speed.
Speaker 0: it takes one guy out.
Speaker 0: at this point Everyone that lift is yelling look out look out and I look down.
Speaker 0: it goes past us and there's this whole chain of people skiing And it it's going straight for the person in the front and you hear in the distance as the guy sees it Oh shit, and then it hits his skis knocks him down all the people behind him running to him.
Speaker 0: It's this giant disaster.
Speaker 0: It keeps going.
Speaker 0: it took out like five more groups of people and disappeared in the distance.
Speaker 1: So how did the snowboarder get down the mountain?
Speaker 1: so on his ass.
Speaker 0: So I you know get up to the top we ski back down and I see this guy Walking down the mountain slowly and carefully and I'm like lose your snowboard.
Speaker 0: He's like, yeah You see where it went and I was like, there's probably gonna be some police waiting for you at the bottom.
Speaker 0: He's like what it do.
Speaker 0: That's exactly what he said what it do.
Speaker 1: Would they really police make you an arrest?
Speaker 0: He actually he broke.
Speaker 0: he didn't break a lot I don't think but one.
Speaker 0: you're not supposed to let your snowboard come off and to you have it.
Speaker 1: No, he can help it.
Speaker 1: Did he take it off on purpose?
Speaker 0: is the thing?
Speaker 0: You can't use devices on a ski resort like on a slope that don't have Arresters on like my skis if they pop off like if I screw up and flip over and I just happened a couple times.
Speaker 0: These things pop out of the ski like brakes so it can't actually go down the mountain.
Speaker 0: It stops Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: He did not follow the rules.
Speaker 0: They probably were waiting down there with his snowboard to cut his lift ticket off.
Speaker 1: All right, yeah.
Speaker 0: So that was some of the epic fail.
Speaker 0: Also, the road was closed on the way down when we were trying to leave not due to the snow But did a brawl at the pub.
Speaker 1: Of course, what are pubs for?
Speaker 0: Brawling and getting adventures.
Speaker 1: Yes So I spent this weekend.
Speaker 1: I put together a home theater Computer.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah how that thing turned out.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, I want my.
Speaker 1: basically he was my situation, right?
Speaker 1: It was like, okay, I can get another Mac Mini.
Speaker 1: The problem with the Mac Mini was that I had to get special cables to make the HDMI and stuff work.
Speaker 0: pros We know the form factor is great already.
Speaker 0: It's basically silent and tiny and looks good.
Speaker 0: pro We know all that Apple stuff works really really well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we know boxy runs on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah cons it costs more money than everything else Yeah, and it needs a special cable to hook up to the TV and it can't emulator anything unless you buy BS.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's that's.
Speaker 1: this is the thing here, right?
Speaker 1: All it could really do is play Video, right?
Speaker 1: It can't do other things Like, you know, I wanted to play Street Fighter which I bought on Steam right on my TV Even though I bought it for the computer which I could do if I had a computer connect to my television.
Speaker 1: But the Mac Mini even if I put Windows on it with the boot camp not powerful enough to really play Street Fighter 4 Right or trying trying was another game trying to the ps3 only game.
Speaker 1: and if you saw the news today good read good thing I don't have a ps3.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah we'll talk about that next week once we find out the end run, but You know, the thing is I want.
Speaker 1: I bought trying on steam.
Speaker 1: I want to play it on the TV.
Speaker 1: So I needed a. I wanted something that could you know play.
Speaker 1: it didn't need to play like, you know The crisis or whatever.
Speaker 1: It just needs to play, you know regular old, you know Middling, you know has that a middle-of-the-road 3d ness so it could play those kind of games on the TV, right?
Speaker 1: Otherwise Right, if I'm not gonna get that middle-of-the-road 3d ness to play games on the TV.
Speaker 1: I might as well not even get a Mac Mini.
Speaker 1: I should just get the Nvidia ion net top.
Speaker 1: Well, that
Speaker 0: is the crux of the issue that there are a million devices now That'll do like home media in some degree like some sort of connected to your TV like I have the Roku and the Mac Mini was one too, but You should either Figure out these specific things you want and buy a device that just does that and accept the fact you're gonna have a bunch of Devices to do different things or go all out and get the full-on general-purpose device.
Speaker 0: that will do everything, right?
Speaker 0: I want to minimize box, which is also cheaper than the Mac Mini.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: So The Mac Mini would have been like seven hundred dish and then a cable It could have.
Speaker 1: it would have been an eight hundred dollars ish in total, right?
Speaker 0: Yep, plus you need a Bluetooth keyboard and mouse or something to go right.
Speaker 1: exactly.
Speaker 1: the Nvidia ion computer Right would have been like four hundred maybe even five hundred dollars.
Speaker 1: when all was said and done right way cheap.
Speaker 1: But again, it would basically do the same thing.
Speaker 1: the Mac Mini did play video But it would be a little bit flaky because the CPU is an Intel atom.
Speaker 1: It's not that powerful, but it has the Nvidia ion chip.
Speaker 1: So it could play 1080p videos right smoothly.
Speaker 1: But it really would depend on if you can get the hardware acceleration working.
Speaker 1: So even though it works it pretty much just works.
Speaker 1: But there might be a few cases of trouble here and there where you couldn't.
Speaker 1: you had a video that you couldn't Accelerate the decoding with the GPU and it would be flaky and you couldn't get it to run smoothly on the 1080p.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's a little bit risky But it's so much less money and in 90% of the case is gonna work.
Speaker 1: So if all you want is video right.
Speaker 1: Nvidia ion was the winner right now, so I'm like, okay I'm on.
Speaker 1: the Mac Mini is now out right and the Nvidia ion is the choice.
Speaker 1: But I kind of want to be able to play these games.
Speaker 1: so I investigated and I'm like, okay What if I try to make my own Nvidia ion computer and put like a PCI Express graphics something like that, right?
Speaker 0: Now I did discounted that in the past because the last time I looked at the like the mini AT cases and all the things I could use or micro ATX.
Speaker 0: They weren't nice enough or at least I didn't trust them because I didn't know anyone who'd used one and I couldn't find power supplies That were quiet enough.
Speaker 1: Well, the Nvidia ion is actually mini ITX, right?
Speaker 1: And the thing with mini ITX is that all the Kate, you know There was some cases that were small and kind of nice.
Speaker 1: ish Right and some of the motherboards were actually had everything you need right on the board, you know There's no reason to buy like an aces triple-e because you can just build your own But because it's mini ITX and everything is weird.
Speaker 1: It's like is this really gonna work?
Speaker 1: You know if I buy one of these it's like what power supply do I get?
Speaker 1: and they were like all these weird power supplies.
Speaker 1: You know, there wasn't really a set step.
Speaker 1: like I saw an ITX motherboard with an ATX, you know power supply connector but the case was like 60 watt power supply.
Speaker 1: and I'm like why you know that gonna work with this motherboard and you had to get you couldn't put a Big hard drive in there.
Speaker 1: You get a tiny one.
Speaker 1: So I'm like if I get a tiny one, you know, is that gonna work?
Speaker 1: Am I gonna have the right serial ATA connectors, you know everything gets weird when you go into the micro ITX.
Speaker 0: I think that's partly I'll showing our age because remember back in the day We were willing to accept a lot more BS like that a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean remember when I mean a computer like will this motherboard work was a concern of any computer?
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: I mean if I did enough research I could have figure out a Combination of parts that would have worked or I could have thrown up my hands and bought, you know An already built NVI on which is probably gonna be just as good in the end Maybe even with a nicer case because the parts would have been packed in more close.
Speaker 0: There is a third option that we have not everyone has.
Speaker 0: you could have crowdsourced it to the listeners Find out what they would have been.
Speaker 1: I was basically like Alright, so, you know, I said I specked when I was like, okay, so then I'm like, alright Let's look at like another option.
Speaker 1: The other option was to get a micro ATX board, right?
Speaker 1: Which is you know, it's an eight, you know, basically I don't really see a reason why anyone today should buy An ATX motherboard, right?
Speaker 1: I mean they're really So Few people need right.
Speaker 1: all the extra, you know All you really get with a full-size ATX motherboard these days is a bunch of extra PC eyes and PCI Express slots that most people do not need.
Speaker 0: well to be fair when I was looking at mine For what I wanted I couldn't find a micro or a mini case that I liked that would have worked with my setup that's true, but remember you can always put a A micro.
Speaker 1: most ATX motherboards you can put a micro ATX motherboard in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, though at the because I wanted I had some weird requirements.
Speaker 0: I wanted Intel.
Speaker 0: I'm done with using like I have Intel Yep, but for what I wanted specifically I couldn't find a micro one that had what everything else I want.
Speaker 0: I want to get into the details of it.
Speaker 0: But I couldn't find basically a micro or a mini motherboard that had everything exactly that I wanted.
Speaker 0: that was also Reasonably priced compared to the ATX ones that did the same.
Speaker 1: So I got a hundred and twenty five dollar aces motherboard, right?
Speaker 1: It can take an i7 i5 or i3.
Speaker 0: It can take up to 16 gigs of.
Speaker 1: There's four slots, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, so it's only the dual channel.
Speaker 0: Not that that matters.
Speaker 1: None of the matters.
Speaker 1: It's got six serial ATA ports, right?
Speaker 1: It's got a PCI Express slot for the.
Speaker 1: for the video card the x16 onboard sound.
Speaker 1: Yeah onboard sound All right with optical out HDMI out, right?
Speaker 1: What I learned though is the HDMI out is actually you.
Speaker 1: it's this integrated graphics, right?
Speaker 1: It's not that great.
Speaker 1: It's Intel integrated graphics, but the Intel integrated graphics is in the CPU.
Speaker 1: So if you get a CPU that doesn't have it, it won't work.
Speaker 1: I mean the CPU will still work but the integrated graphics would just be like you don't have an integrated graphics Processor because you didn't buy a CPU that had one in it.
Speaker 0: So what do you need like an i5 i7?
Speaker 1: We know and I three, you know.
Speaker 1: You just had to look certain.
Speaker 1: as long as you buy the right i3 i5 i7 It will have the iGPU.
Speaker 0: and see I didn't bother with any of that research.
Speaker 1: when I built my compound Using the iGPU I bought a video card.
Speaker 0: basically all I did was look at I'm I want to buy at the plateau of price for the i7 and the plateau was the like $270 chip.
Speaker 1: this motherboard is optical out.
Speaker 1: It's got.
Speaker 1: it's pretty.
Speaker 1: it's got DVI VGA.
Speaker 1: It's got everything.
Speaker 1: It's got USB 3. right for reals USB 3.
Speaker 1: So when USB 3 stuff comes out, like if I can get a USB 3 external drive, I'm set All right, so I bought this fancy motherboard that it's basically a. it's a perfect motherboard period if you're built Even if you're building a desktop, it just happens to be micro ATX.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then I got the i3 CPU because I don't need it to be that powerful, right?
Speaker 1: I don't need this.
Speaker 1: I didn't need to spend the extra hundred two hundred dollars even more to get the i5 or i7.
Speaker 1: You know, the only advantage of getting the i5 is that it has that, you know automatic overclocking feature.
Speaker 1: I didn't need that right?
Speaker 1: I got this ultra quiet PSU.
Speaker 1: I got you know, four gigs of RAM.
Speaker 1: I basically built a $900 computer.
Speaker 1: The only thing is I got this case that was a horizontal case that was designed for home theater PC.
Speaker 1: So it looks like a piece of home theater equipment.
Speaker 0: So that's my real real question because I don't trust those things for shit.
Speaker 0: How was it actually build inside of the thing?
Speaker 1: It's a. what do you mean?
Speaker 0: Like was it easy to install the motherboard and everything?
Speaker 1: It was incredibly easy to install the motherboard easier than my to do it in my mid tower.
Speaker 0: See now that that that basically solves.
Speaker 0: I had this suspicion because my other computer, you know The old one that was in geek night sound before it was at the time like one of the better rated like full tower cases But it was kind of a pain in the ass to like route all the cables and everything in it my current mid tower.
Speaker 0: It took me like two minutes to put everything in and I think it's just a fact that in the last year or so Every case now is just fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah this case it was a Lian Li case.
Speaker 1: So it's you know, it's high quality Yeah, and basically all it is was you open it up and it's just.
Speaker 1: it's just.
Speaker 1: it's basically an empty box Really?
Speaker 1: I mean it was.
Speaker 1: there was nothing in there, right?
Speaker 1: Except for you know the stuff on the edges Right, and the only thing in there was a tiny metal crossbar that you would remove to put the motherboard in.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: that metal crossbar You know gave the case some structural integrity and it also sort of had this hard one single hard drive bracket attached to it Right and then in the front near the CD-ROM exit there was another bracket other than that.
Speaker 1: It was basically an empty box and you just take the crossbar out You drop the motherboard in you drop the power supply in.
Speaker 1: you got some extra room between the power supply.
Speaker 1: Does it have IR integrated?
Speaker 1: There's no infrareds.
Speaker 0: No, I was.
Speaker 0: I wandered because I didn't see a lot of things that have that I mean every motherboard or anything I saw that had integrated IR was either weird like really weird or old.
Speaker 1: Now see I am actually having some trouble with controlling this computer, right?
Speaker 1: I have a wireless USB mouse that I you know that it was extra that I've been using right but for keyboards It's like I don't you know, it's like I could go and try to use.
Speaker 1: The motherboard doesn't have Bluetooth.
Speaker 1: so I could try to use a Bluetooth dongle and use a Mac keyboard Which would be okay if it worked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's too much.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be too much fiddling to.
Speaker 0: what about paying for one of those iPhone apps?
Speaker 1: Well, there are you know, there are many free iPhone apps.
Speaker 1: There is a Logitech.
Speaker 1: let me see what's it called.
Speaker 1: Logitech has a free iPhone app that allows you to Use your iPhone as a mouse and keyboard with any computer.
Speaker 1: Logitech touch mouse.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, you were showing that to me.
Speaker 0: There's a really crappy chintzy thing like that for the pre but so does not appear to install the free Logitech touch mouse server on your computer.
Speaker 1: and then you install the free Logitech touch mouse app on your iPhone or iPod touch and as long as these your iPod your iPhone is on the same network as the computer You can use the iPhone as a mouse and keyboard to control the computer.
Speaker 1: The problem with this is that it doesn't work until you log in Right, and then if you have like, you know, one of those UAC things pop up.
Speaker 1: that's like admin.
Speaker 1: Yes No, you can't.
Speaker 1: suddenly the iPhone doesn't do shit Because it's locked out right.
Speaker 1: so but other than that the touch mouse works All right.
Speaker 1: the boxy boxy has a free app for the iPhone iPod touch that basically turns the iPhone iPod touch into a remote, you know up down left right?
Speaker 1: Okay back, you know You basically get those buttons and you get a keyboard.
Speaker 1: So when I'm running as long as I start I can start boxy with the wireless mouse and then use the boxy app on The iPhone to control boxy, which is pretty great.
Speaker 1: But as soon as the exit boxy, it's like.
Speaker 1: well now now What about you know, so I I've been taking my USB keyboard back and forth across the room because I don't have a spare.
Speaker 1: But I'm looking for you know, some sort of keyboard solution the boxy official boxy remote Thing the hardware one that is announced.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 0: if they just sell that on its own I would pay a lot of money to buy Right, so I'm pretty sure they are gonna sell it on its own.
Speaker 1: I think boxy made this big mistake.
Speaker 1: is they wanted to have the stuff to show at CES, which is good But they they're not able.
Speaker 1: where is it?
Speaker 1: It's we're waiting.
Speaker 1: It's like you Apple as I think one thing Apple does that's very smart for all the stupid things They do is they announce something at the last second and then they give it to you, right?
Speaker 1: So there's none of this.
Speaker 1: forgetting about it, right?
Speaker 1: There's none of this, you know people when the excitement is at the max here.
Speaker 1: It is buy it right now Big excitement excitement drops off.
Speaker 1: Oh, you can buy it And we didn't.
Speaker 0: here's the trouble the box.
Speaker 0: boxy would have had a lot more excitement if they'd come to the game sooner.
Speaker 0: But I mean the Roku's been around for a long time already.
Speaker 0: But the only thing boxy has going for it the boxy box At least not the boxy software is that their remote comes with it and it just comes with boxy.
Speaker 0: any nerd can just put boxy.
Speaker 1: Well boxy, you know wants you to just put boxy on anything, you know, but you know They want to sell the boxy box mostly to people who can't just put.
Speaker 1: you know, guys.
Speaker 1: They're smart nerds like us.
Speaker 1: I went to their event, you know, but I think they are gonna sell the remote on its own.
Speaker 1: They just aren't doing it yet.
Speaker 0: Well what now?
Speaker 1: I got the computer now, I need the remote.
Speaker 0: now what I imagined They have.
Speaker 0: they have two markets.
Speaker 1: if I buy something else then why would I buy this remote later?
Speaker 0: They're going to sell the remote to people like us.
Speaker 0: They're going to sell the boxy box along with the remote to people like us that we are then going to set up for our Parents.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway, so to make the law to end this story right because the case is all home theater case I needed to get a low-profile video card.
Speaker 1: and the thing is, you know The I basically bought the best low-profile video card, which is an ATI something something and it works.
Speaker 1: It plays the games.
Speaker 0: Well, you're not gonna install Linux.
Speaker 0: It's probably okay.
Speaker 1: Well, no you want it.
Speaker 1: All right, so here right, you know I was talking all you know the smack and the ATA fanboys in the forum came back at me like oh You're just full of shit, right?
Speaker 1: Because I was saying stuff like remember back in the day when we tried when you had the original Ubuntu computer in the living room and we couldn't use the ATI.
Speaker 0: There was the.
Speaker 0: it had an a video out as video out But you could not turn it on in Linux because the driver was so shitty, right?
Speaker 1: And because the car right but with the Nvidia card you would turn the computer on and immediately the video output would just work.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So this ATI card was a little bit better than that old ATI card.
Speaker 1: a turn.
Speaker 1: I plugged in HDMI.
Speaker 1: I never plugged in VGA or DVI and boom and immediately showed up on the TV.
Speaker 0: It was but Right.
Speaker 0: There's clearly a buck here.
Speaker 1: Of course after I installed the Windows driver, right?
Speaker 1: Which is really shitty compared to the Nvidia one.
Speaker 1: I don't care what you people say, right?
Speaker 1: Guess what happened?
Speaker 0: Stop working.
Speaker 1: No, the image was still 1080p, but there was like a two inch black border around the screen.
Speaker 1: So I had to go into a hidden area and you know difficult to find so difficult to find.
Speaker 1: I had to google for How to find it right area of the ATI driver and find this over scan setting to Basically get the image to take up the entire size of my television.
Speaker 0: Wait, that doesn't seem to make sense because to me over scan used to be on SDTVs.
Speaker 0: you have that little extra area that wasn't technically supposed to be there.
Speaker 0: But you could turn on over scan support if you knew that you had those extra like, you know 30 or 40 or whatever quote-unquote pixel I mean, I basically put the over scan up two clicks because it was sort of dead discreet, you know settings.
Speaker 1: It wasn't a smooth slider.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it was then exactly the same size as my television and it's definitely 1080p for reals.
Speaker 1: It's not like.
Speaker 0: that sounds like a case of a bad into a bad.
Speaker 0: a non-intelligent default.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I don't you know you at fanboys may have it correct, you know ATI talking about, you know 3d performance Versus price, you know for the card ratio if you discount, yeah, ATI might be currently winning.
Speaker 1: However, right ATI and I'm you know AMD they still fail on these fundamental Things, you know, does the product work?
Speaker 1: Does the video output correctly?
Speaker 1: You know that the basics you have to get all those fundamentals are far more important than your performance.
Speaker 1: I'll take an Intel chip Right over an AMD one every day.
Speaker 1: if an AMD one might be faster and it might be half the price It doesn't matter because you know what.
Speaker 1: if I take the heatsink off the Intel one, it'll just slow down And if I put the heatsink back on it'll speed up again.
Speaker 1: if I take the heatsink off the AMD one It'll just set on fire.
Speaker 0: now Stupid are you sure?
Speaker 0: I mean that was a problem with the old Athlons.
Speaker 1: That's true And you know what?
Speaker 1: That's enough is to be fair.
Speaker 0: your knowledge on on ATI and AMD is about Vintage.
Speaker 1: the last time you built a computer I just built a computer the other day the time before the ATI video card in it and it had a problem.
Speaker 1: Just the kind the exact kind of problem.
Speaker 1: I predicted it would have a fundamental problem.
Speaker 1: Not a lack of yes.
Speaker 0: I'm only calling you out on the set on fire.
Speaker 0: I don't think modern AMD set on fire as quickly as the old Athlons.
Speaker 1: quiet is probably true, but it doesn't Change the fact.
Speaker 0: when my first you're you're correct and the facts are in your favor But that does not change my opinion.
Speaker 1: My first computer was an in was in Pentium 3 with an Intel 440 and I'll back that up with an outdated Anecdote and that computer was 100% rock solid a bygone era that I cannot even prove.
Speaker 1: every computer I had after that up until recently was an AMD Athlon.
Speaker 1: I had an a. we had the solely based on personal anecdotes, right?
Speaker 1: I had multiple Athlons.
Speaker 1: all remember all that whole pile of computer parts.
Speaker 1: That was all Athlon equipment.
Speaker 1: How many different motherboards and Athlon processors.
Speaker 1: and duron process easy?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna step in right now because my anecdotal evidence is that the problems weren't the processors.
Speaker 0: in the end It was the motherboards.
Speaker 0: I remember yours one with aces because they were a little more stable and I was with.
Speaker 0: no.
Speaker 1: I tried a bunch of different ones.
Speaker 1: I had a bit.
Speaker 1: I had aces I had all different Kyle.
Speaker 0: I think it was other people in the crew that always went aces.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 0: maybe Pete I forget but I always went a bit because they were a little faster Little less stable and I remember I'd spend like hours tweaking the BIOS and overclocking.
Speaker 1: I think I had a bit and then a bit again.
Speaker 1: only my newest The computer I just bought.
Speaker 1: the HTPC was aces But before that it was all.
Speaker 0: my only anecdote is thus every computer I have ever built until this current one and an a bit motherboard and I would tweak the BIOS like crazy and Overclock and do all that stuff to make it work and do special stuff.
Speaker 0: and there are all these advanced functionalities.
Speaker 0: I learned how they all work.
Speaker 0: I Always had some weird problem some weird hardware incompatibility Weird stuff like really weird stuff.
Speaker 0: power supply with proper voltage doesn't work because of a weird bug that only affects this one power supply And there's one motherboard.
Speaker 0: Yep, but I finally switched to an Intel full-on motherboard.
Speaker 0: It was the first time I've ever built a computer and it posted on the first try.
Speaker 1: Well, you know what?
Speaker 1: I got to say, you know, yes, the a bit is a little weird like that You know with all those weird overclock settings.
Speaker 1: But the aces I just bought with the weird overclock settings.
Speaker 1: No problem.
Speaker 1: My current desktop is a gigabyte motherboard.
Speaker 1: No problem Right what?
Speaker 1: the difference in my experience of all the computers I've built is the as long as it isn't in all the Intel computers I've built.
Speaker 1: no problem because they had Intel chipsets even though none of the motherboards are made by Intel.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'll chip sets were Intel and the processors were Intel all the ones that were AMD processors AMD chip sets or you know Viya or whoever else made, you know Nvidia chip sets even the g4 the end price.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah the n-force Computer.
Speaker 0: I went with a bit n-force and I had all these weird troubles that still plagued the computer to this day.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, my my Intel everything down there humming like a champ.
Speaker 1: Yeah, n-force not not really that great in the end.
Speaker 0: Well, well, well, well Every.
Speaker 0: we have nothing but anecdotal evidence to back this up.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter right?
Speaker 1: I mean, this is my experience.
Speaker 1: all the Intel computers I've made we're freaking rock solid rock hard awesome.
Speaker 1: and all the AMD computers I've made and I've made a bunch rock hard Basically broke not rock solid rock hard.
Speaker 1: Yes So, you know I got Just now I bought a brand new computer all the Intel parts right or Intel related parts because I did get an i3 Right just fine.
Speaker 1: The only thing that any flakiness is always is one ATI video card, you know.
Speaker 1: And the thing is, you know, I'm not it was.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna regret the decision.
Speaker 1: I don't wish I had picked a different video card because at the current point in time that is the best low profile 3d card and if I would have gotten any other I couldn't have gotten a non low profile card because then I would not have been able to you know, get the gaming.
Speaker 1: and then what would have been the point?
Speaker 1: and You know, there wasn't a better low profile card to go for yet.
Speaker 1: Maybe in the future a year or two down the road a better low profile card will come out.
Speaker 1: I could put in there and replace this one but not right now.
Speaker 1: So it was still the right choice, but it had problems.
Speaker 1: It wasn't perfect.
Speaker 0: you went on.
Speaker 0: I couldn't make my really really lame joke.
Speaker 0: There was one thing that was rock hard about my last a bit motherboard the fluid in the capacitors.
Speaker 0: So we went on a long time for that.
Speaker 0: so I don't want to talk about this a lot.
Speaker 0: I'd rather I think do a show on it instead pan uncovering plagiarism authorship and social software misuse.
Speaker 0: They have a cool project that is basically they're trying to make systems that will automatically determine when someone is vandalized a website like Wikipedia as opposed to having added a legitimate update and It's kind of like taking catches to the next level and not just making someone prove They're a human before letting them post but making a post itself prove that it is meaningful
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 0: and the only argument I've seen against this sort of thing so far Is that it might weed out people who are making legitimate or trying to make legitimate updates to things, you know blog post Wikipedia update whatever but are not you know super competent or are not super Good at expressing their thoughts?
Speaker 0: and you know the capture problem where as captors get more complicated there are humans who cannot pass the capture legitimately.
Speaker 0: mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: and I feel the same way about this that I feel about those things.
Speaker 0: if you cannot get through the plagiarism and Abuse detection system and you are a human your post did not deserve to make it through anyway That's true.
Speaker 1: But I mean the sit, you know, that's giving the system.
Speaker 1: you're basically assuming that the system is perfect.
Speaker 1: I mean, what if you know you posted like a really intelligent essay legitimately like, you know some right and then it says You know, we've to take this as abuse.
Speaker 1: There's a false positive then what?
Speaker 0: well The thing is?
Speaker 0: you have to tweak it because they're all they're gonna be false positives and definitely have to about.
Speaker 1: yeah You definitely have to balance it for no false positives and let a few bad ones through.
Speaker 1: but I suppose to balancing it for Cuz I mean letting a few bad guys through and just marking them as spam is a lot better than some guy put writing a Big essay in it not getting through the goal of balance it for the other side.
Speaker 0: I think the goal of this primarily is detect, you know, those people who randomly insert the word penis just into an article.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but what if he's writing it?
Speaker 1: It's a actual article.
Speaker 0: So you have to use statistics and heuristics to figure things out.
Speaker 0: like alright The word penis was added to an article that has nothing to do with biology or genitalia and is between two.
Speaker 0: You know these parts of speech.
Speaker 0: it does not seem to fit things like that.
Speaker 0: I Mean mine would never fit.
Speaker 1: So when you come up with that algorithm will be rich.
Speaker 0: So so here's the way to do it.
Speaker 0: the same way Google does.
Speaker 0: they're doing, you know Crowdsourcing it and statistically, you know saying alright Let's look at these your hundred thousand edits that humans decided were bad word.
Speaker 0: Nothing, but abuse.
Speaker 0: Let's find statistical correlations and then make an engine based on that.
Speaker 0: They're even talking about using the Mechanical Turk to outsource the I Guess crowdsource the generation of the data set so they can use human statistics to then come up with a mechanism Determining abuse and different level.
Speaker 0: It's a really cool article.
Speaker 0: I recommend you guys check it out.
Speaker 0: Wow, we went on a while things of the day.
Speaker 0: Nikolai Tesla's Letterhead, I have no idea if this is legitimate or not, but legitimate.
Speaker 0: I want this to be my letterhead.
Speaker 0: Good God This is like the best letterhead I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: I want a letterhead.
Speaker 1: perhaps, you know, the thing is letterhead is sort of pointless now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is But this is.
Speaker 0: I kind of want a letterhead just for purposes like I don't know writing a letter to someone.
Speaker 1: When would you do that?
Speaker 0: Here's whenever we do press stuff, right?
Speaker 0: I don't?
Speaker 0: you never run afoul of this.
Speaker 0: most media places or people that accept press Registrations require a letter from the editor or the producer on the company's letterhead Stating the assignment of the reporter.
Speaker 0: So you realize I have a long file of geek nights Letterheads and letters from me saying that you and I are on assignment.
Speaker 1: I love how people like, you know, because there's a letterhead it must be right.
Speaker 1: I could just go down to the kinkos print out letterheads for New York Times NBC CBS ABC.
Speaker 1: figure out who executives are put their names on the letterhead fake a signature find their signature.
Speaker 0: You don't even need to fake it.
Speaker 0: I know a guy he where he's a friend to someone who works at my company Who goes to a lot of Major League Baseball games for free by showing up because he knows where all the press guys goes in Here is the same like color shirt that they all wear and he pretty makes a credential that is perfectly real in that He's endorsing it himself.
Speaker 0: He's not lying.
Speaker 0: He's not fraudulent.
Speaker 0: He's just saying like, you know Me is covering this event for me and no one checks and he signs the thing and he stands down on the field watching the game as press.
Speaker 0: yeah, I Want to do that, but I'm also kind of afraid of getting arrested.
Speaker 1: Would you really get arrested though?
Speaker 0: See, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: I'll bet is it against the law?
Speaker 1: bet me they would just kick you out, right?
Speaker 1: I don't mean the worst that might happen is they might ban you from the stadium part, you know for life Which well, I'll bet it's not.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't know it might not be illegal because he's not committing fraud.
Speaker 0: He's not saying I am from NBC.
Speaker 0: He's saying I am Joe Schmo my real name from just Joe Schmo's blog or a blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: And I have a fancy press credential.
Speaker 0: that is for Joe Schmo's blog and I sign the thing.
Speaker 0: I sign all my real contact information.
Speaker 0: I in no way misrepresent myself and then you gave me access.
Speaker 0: Yep, so I think that's his angle.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to try it sometime for some investigative reporting.
Speaker 1: The thing is I would try to be willing to try it at a stadium.
Speaker 1: I did not care to return to like Yankee Stadium.
Speaker 1: You Know the worst part is like I can't.
Speaker 1: you know, it's.
Speaker 1: it's like the thing is to do it at a stadium I don't want to return to is a game.
Speaker 0: I don't want to see unless it's the Mets and the Yankees Would you?
Speaker 1: The thing is at a big game like that the odds of getting in trouble try to sneak in and the security your way up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got to do it at like, you know an afternoon Sunday game against like the Pirates.
Speaker 1: No one gives.
Speaker 1: That's when you got to do it.
Speaker 1: No one gives a shit.
Speaker 0: No security game course in a game like that They might notice cuz you're the only press guy who bothers to show up.
Speaker 1: No, because there's always you know people that go to every single game because you never you know Someone's got to get the pictures of all those crazy highlights and whatnot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, as long as you show up with a gigantic DSLR with that, you know, oh he does.
Speaker 0: that's one of his props.
Speaker 0: He has an awesome DSLR.
Speaker 1: See that's the thing is that's the problem, right?
Speaker 0: So great even so Emily has an awesome DSLR.
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: No, you got it.
Speaker 1: If you don't that's not the kind of the sports guy.
Speaker 0: Have you seen this thing?
Speaker 0: It's good enough.
Speaker 0: It's no better than what this guy who gets away with this.
Speaker 0: This guy gets away with it.
Speaker 0: He doesn't have as good a camera as what Emily.
Speaker 1: no But he's got that gigantic lens that friggin goes on the front.
Speaker 1: That's like, you know, then for the price of that lens I could buy season tickets.
Speaker 1: So Why?
Speaker 1: Right, you know, well the thing is you couldn't buy season tickets that let you stand like on the edge of the field That's true, but season tickets that let me sit in a normal place and not have to worry about getting caught or finagle.
Speaker 0: Here's the probably.
Speaker 0: if you're worrying you're already done.
Speaker 0: You've got to be.
Speaker 0: so not worried because if you're worried at all your body language might make you look worried.
Speaker 0: The people like wait a minute.
Speaker 0: What are you doing back here?
Speaker 0: You got to be like that French guy who pulls all those pranks.
Speaker 0: He dresses up like sports players and runs out onto the field and acts like he's part of the celebration.
Speaker 1: season tickets are better anyway.
Speaker 1: In my thinking today is a funny video of a Russian guy singing.
Speaker 1: I can't tell if this was dubbed over by someone else.
Speaker 1: Was this a thing of the day before?
Speaker 1: because it's familiar?
Speaker 0: I remember it because I saw it independently of you and I thought wow, that's really weird and I didn't do anything with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's been a thing of the day, but it is familiar.
Speaker 1: I've seen it before.
Speaker 1: I was on Boing Boing today.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it was on College Humor at some point.
Speaker 1: Anyway, here it is.
Speaker 1: It's funny.
Speaker 1: I can't tell if it was dubbed over by someone else if it was dubbed over by him.
Speaker 1: But like the the audio like matches up with his mouth.
Speaker 1: But strangely it's like he doesn't move his mouth in a shape that matches the way you would expect the shape of his mouth to be like.
Speaker 1: when he says look he's like smiling instead of going.
Speaker 0: look like His smile reminds me of like Eric Idol when he does the fake shopkeeper kind of smile in Monty Python like it's so Painfully fake.
Speaker 0: it's the kind of smile that only works like on stage if you're in a play.
Speaker 1: Hey, it's a weird.
Speaker 1: It's a. it's a video from pockner, but it's there is no pockner.
Speaker 0: ease in it someone out there.
Speaker 0: You totally got to mash this up with something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, you know, just watch this.
Speaker 1: it is, you know, it is Internet's.
Speaker 0: so so Slashdot article.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna read it, but it made me realize something and we've talked about this off and on.
Speaker 0: We've never actually done a show about it.
Speaker 0: The vast majority of people use computers don't read anything that's on the screen let alone really Really you don't say so.
Speaker 0: and from the Slashdot article some Bafa basically says so what do we do like?
Speaker 0: seriously?
Speaker 0: What do we do to get people to read?
Speaker 0: Is there a way to get people to read the words that are coming out of my mouth on the screen?
Speaker 1: I don't know if there is.
Speaker 1: I mean I was in kindergarten, right?
Speaker 1: There's an Apple to in the classroom and you know Occasionally they would.
Speaker 1: they would take you down the whole class to the lab full of Apple twos, right and the teacher would say Okay, everyone do this.
Speaker 1: Okay, everyone do this and ever you're supposed to do things as the teacher said to do them.
Speaker 1: I just immediately for the first time ever sat down at the thing read the words on the screen and Not only did I figure out that I could use the up and down arrows and then the enter key to select
Speaker 0: But I figured out that
Speaker 1: I figured out I can actually press the number of the option I wanted.
Speaker 0: but I figured out that there was a shared unprotected network drive and then this was in kindergarten on an Apple to on its own.
Speaker 0: I'm talking middle school here.
Speaker 0: the previous class is already had already done the BS assignment and I just went to the network drive found the teachers copy of what you wanted to look like saved it as my own.
Speaker 0: it was Done.
Speaker 0: Yep, and then I played commander keen for the rest of the class.
Speaker 1: That's right So, you know.
Speaker 1: but the point is is that I was reading the words on the screen and then Inferring from those words What things I could do and what would happen if I did them, right?
Speaker 1: I did have to do some trial and error but not much, you know, the option would say one start playing word munchers.
Speaker 1: So I pressed the number one.
Speaker 1: Word munchers starts.
Speaker 1: Yes, you know, it said start playing numbers.
Speaker 1: That's that.
Speaker 1: You're right.
Speaker 1: So It seemed like though that few other kids in the class had this ability and even today for you I mean a couple weeks ago.
Speaker 1: I upgraded my parents and newer Ubuntu and it was much better from that Boon - I haven't done that in a while.
Speaker 1: All right, the thing is right.
Speaker 1: they You know, they there's a new I am client.
Speaker 1: It's not pigeon like default.
Speaker 1: I am client is different, right?
Speaker 1: So they had to create their I am accounts in the you know epiphany or whatever it's called.
Speaker 1: So I'm like.
Speaker 1: they're like, how do I do it?
Speaker 1: And I'm like, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Just read the words on the screen and you know, look for a word like, you know To create account click here or accounts add new account or something along those lines.
Speaker 1: Just read the words.
Speaker 1: Click on the words that make sense, you know.
Speaker 1: infer from the words what buttons do what.
Speaker 1: so and my mom still Was unable to do this Even though I told her read the words on the screen.
Speaker 1: read the words on the screen and she just couldn't.
Speaker 0: so here's the thing I I'm gonna read someone else's anecdote from slash dot because we all all of us for tech people We have a million anecdotes of you know Dumbass users like I changed one like change the color of a button and they couldn't do their job.
Speaker 0: or the error said Your monitor is unplugged.
Speaker 0: and they and it read it to them out loud and they just didn't know what to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah But this anecdote is the rare occurrence where it seems like it's a techie Who saw the person who was having the problem and got to overhear their conversation with the tech while simultaneously?
Speaker 0: Observing what the user was doing that the real tech on the phone couldn't see.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, that's good.
Speaker 0: And this I realized everything that's going on here.
Speaker 0: So hungry hobo Your anecdote.
Speaker 0: I salute you All right, the most memorable example for me was when I was working part-time as a tote at a racetrack during college a horse racetrack.
Speaker 1: Yes, what does a tote do?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: shovels a horse poo.
Speaker 0: I think they carry stuff around.
Speaker 0: Okay, there was a some significant quote-unquote technical problem which was delaying the races.
Speaker 0: I was in the cash room and the manager was on the phone to the control room as head was wrong.
Speaker 1: She made a heist.
Speaker 0: She asked me to carry down a TV.
Speaker 0: So I grabbed one of these dusty little old ones and carry it down thinking one of the displays must have burned out or something.
Speaker 0: I get down to the room and the woman who was in the control room was on the phone with some tech support drone Wherever the company outsores.
Speaker 0: this shit too Turned out.
Speaker 0: she told my manager there was something wrong with the monitor and had somehow translated that to TV.
Speaker 0: So obviously this is why the guy was asked to carry a TV down to the control room.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I look at the screen and bouncing slowly around all over the screen.
Speaker 0: There's a big gray box.
Speaker 0: It covers half the screen and the only way it could make more of a point was if it was flashing in many colors.
Speaker 0: Yep, current monitor resolution not supported colon 1200 by 1600.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm The first thing I assumed was that she had read this to the tech on the other line and there was something deeper wrong.
Speaker 0: So I don't do anything just hang out blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: It becomes very clear after a few moments that she had not in fact read this error to the tech.
Speaker 0: It's as though there's a massive blind spot where the error is.
Speaker 0: This isn't a little error like you get in Windows Whenever it tells you to do something and users ignore and click right through?
Speaker 0: this is a fairly unusual big gray box Bouncing around the screen.
Speaker 0: I can hear the tech on the other side asking her if she sees any errors or Messages of any kind and she says no at this point.
Speaker 0: The guy is in parentheses.
Speaker 0: What the fuck?
Speaker 0: All the while the clock is ticking costing the racetrack money per minute?
Speaker 0: I tactfully hint that perhaps I being a computer nerd in the comp sci program who's worked with tech in the past Might be able to help but she's one of those territorial types doesn't want me to intervene.
Speaker 0: Blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: She basically will not let the guy even go so far as to read the error message that he sees on the screen To her or to the tech.
Speaker 0: Yep And yeah, I don't want to go through the rest But basically what he's realized here and what I now realize is that people Don't actually see the error messages.
Speaker 0: They see something has gone wrong and something is different and the words don't appear to them.
Speaker 0: All that appears in their brain is either nothing or a big gray box that is translated in their brain, too.
Speaker 0: There is a problem that I'm 100% unequipped to deal with and I cannot and will not in any way Interact with anything on this device at any point further.
Speaker 0: I need someone to hold my hand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they physically do not see them.
Speaker 0: It's like the error is there and it's not that they read it and didn't understand it.
Speaker 0: It's not that they didn't read it.
Speaker 0: It's that they don't even get to the point of recognizing it as a problem.
Speaker 1: Well, let me give another anecdote, right?
Speaker 1: So my cousin had a laptop once and it was full of viruses and shit, right?
Speaker 1: He's like, oh, can you help me out?
Speaker 1: So I'm like, oh, we'll just reinstall Windows No problem.
Speaker 1: So what?
Speaker 1: that's what I did and it was fine.
Speaker 1: And you know, I was basically she was.
Speaker 1: I was like trying to give her advice and how to not get viruses in the future.
Speaker 1: And I was like, yeah, you know You really need to just install all the updates.
Speaker 1: whenever it tells you to that there are updates install them.
Speaker 1: She's like, oh Yeah, I see something about updates.
Speaker 1: so she was reading kind of right because she had seen messages about updates But the thing was she would just always click.
Speaker 1: no It's just.
Speaker 1: they just want to make it go away.
Speaker 1: anything that pops up Even if they you know read it or kind of read it.
Speaker 1: They just want to make any pop up anything in their way go away.
Speaker 1: Just go away now No matter what it is.
Speaker 1: It could be the computer will kill you in five seconds if you click.
Speaker 1: no They'll just click.
Speaker 1: no just wanted the whatever button on one hand, right?
Speaker 0: I'm very much enjoy tribes too.
Speaker 0: But on the other hand, I value my bean machine exact.
Speaker 1: I've been back any any message that pops up and gets in the way of someone just doing what they want to do.
Speaker 1: right now They just want to make it go away and they'll click.
Speaker 1: Okay cancel.
Speaker 1: They don't give a shit There's whatever makes it go away.
Speaker 1: is what they want, right?
Speaker 0: but there's this separate problem where they probably don't actually notice or Recognize that the words on the screen will tell them what the problem is or even if they you know read the words Right and partially understand them.
Speaker 1: They don't fully understand them.
Speaker 1: Right like my cousin, you know, she saw the word updates.
Speaker 1: She understood on some level that this would update something, you know that there would be Software added and she I think she sort of knew also that that would make like a progress bar and involve some waiting And she didn't want to wait for anything Right.
Speaker 1: just wanted the message to go as you working and it didn't really connect.
Speaker 1: You know just how important that was.
Speaker 1: that it would prevent your computer from being fucked up, right?
Speaker 1: So well because it didn't do anything, you know directly to her user experience.
Speaker 1: It was actually making her user experience more negative by giving her all these messages and any updates would have been completely invisible To her behind the scenes.
Speaker 0: see now there are multiple levels going on here because another I keep craving from slashdot notes here, but Maybe it's just the anecdotes from all these other people.
Speaker 0: Give me a like us a bigger experience than the ones we have on our own.
Speaker 0: another guy Mikker bids I'm only saying who these people are because I want to give them credit because I'm totally stealing from them Points out a couple of interesting facts that these people probably in many cases like there's one level of they see the error But they don't understand it so they ignore it and want it to go away.
Speaker 0: But there is I think a legitimate lower level of actually do not see them.
Speaker 0: and then he has two examples of quite likely one.
Speaker 0: Car drivers will often many times this has been documented hit a motorcycle.
Speaker 0: But if you look at video of like the accident they looked directly at the motorcycle as they were changing lanes but their brain did not process somehow that it was a that the motorcycle was there.
Speaker 0: because they're not used to seeing motorcycles and Think about when you the first time you drive, you know, you've never driven a car before you're learning how to drive.
Speaker 0: There's all this information and it's really hard to parse it all.
Speaker 0: it's kind of bewildering experience.
Speaker 0: the first time you're driving in real traffic You're worried about obstacles and people and cars and birds and signs up.
Speaker 0: Once you're a good driver your brain kind of breaks these things down into symbols.
Speaker 0: So when you're changing lanes, some people who aren't good drivers their brain thinks is there the symbol of a car in my way?
Speaker 0: No, then I can change lanes if there's a motorcycle there.
Speaker 0: They don't see it.
Speaker 0: They really don't see it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because their brain doesn't say there they don't see obstacle.
Speaker 0: They see not a car I can go.
Speaker 0: and another example of this is pilots.
Speaker 0: if you do training with pilots and you put like garbage trucks or buses or things on the When they're supposed to land.
Speaker 0: that are not the typical obstacles on a runway.
Speaker 0: They will often crash right into him.
Speaker 0: in the simulation.
Speaker 0: They just don't even see him.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: So these two anecdote are these two.
Speaker 0: I guess The guy doesn't have citations, but he claims he had citations of studies.
Speaker 0: So if this is true It does make sense.
Speaker 1: think about like the things you can do with peripheral vision Like you hold up a green card and it's the corner of someone's eye.
Speaker 1: They look away you swap it for a red card They look back and the card will be green green green.
Speaker 1: They really see green and it'll be red as soon as they're actually looking at it for reals.
Speaker 1: So think about unless someone really looks and concentrates, right?
Speaker 1: They're they're.
Speaker 1: they're not seeing what is physically there necessarily because their brain is trained You know and has a incorrect expectation.
Speaker 1: the brain will just see what it expects to see which is nothing.
Speaker 0: So I think the real problem, you know, the multiple levels the layer one problem is very simple There are some people who for whatever reason are not that good with a task or have oversimplified A task or an interaction like the drivers don't see motorcycles have oversimplified the symbols They're dealing with in their brain into car Sign, you know these sorts of things.
Speaker 0: They literally do not see the pedestrian.
Speaker 0: They literally do not see the motorcycle because their brain is working on says a simplistic symbolic level.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: The same thing happens with computers.
Speaker 0: some people they only know how to do a little bit with a computer.
Speaker 0: Their brain is only working on very limited symbol sets and they probably actually do not see Some of these symbols.
Speaker 0: like if the error message doesn't look like what they expect an error to see they just don't notice it.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean think about right those the the big hubbub on the internet a couple weeks ago about all that.
Speaker 1: There was a if you type Facebook login into Google and felt lucky if the top The top result was this blog post about Facebook changing its login.
Speaker 0: those comments
Speaker 1: and a bunch of people thought that this was right the Facebook login page and it had changed because they didn't actually read the page or Comprehend that this was a blog with an article talking about the Facebook login or that when you type Facebook login You're actually doing a search, you know.
Speaker 1: And people were they all they they may say like ah what changed and they saw a place to comment and they know how to Comment because they know how to do things on Facebook.
Speaker 1: So they commented and we're like Why is Facebook red?
Speaker 1: What did you do?
Speaker 1: I just want to log into my Facebook.
Speaker 0: Think about this.
Speaker 0: This is the same thing that happens to young kids who are learning language.
Speaker 0: Like they're learning to read but they learn how to read not phonetically not with phonics But through like word recognition or first character last character recognition, which is the common way kids learn.
Speaker 0: if they're not guided properly Kids will see like a word starts with M and they'll assume it's mom but the word might be massive or mononucleosis.
Speaker 0: But they say mom because they've they've.
Speaker 0: they've basically taken this symbolic mental shortcut And they didn't see the rest of the word because their brain made a decision before they got to that point.
Speaker 0: and I think it's the exact same thing.
Speaker 0: these the the symbols your brain is using if they're misapplied or So simplistic that you like things that don't fit into the symbols don't exist Then you get into the weird situation where you'll you won't be able to react properly to a symbol that is well I guess a real data or datum that is presented to you because your symbology is messed up.
Speaker 0: I think this I think they saw they their their symbology was Facebook login page.
Speaker 0: It looks different.
Speaker 0: so they misapplied the alternate symbology oops of Posting to a blog or commenting.
Speaker 0: so they applied the commenting symbology to the wrong situation Because they understood these two disparate contacts, but did not realize that they were two actually different situations.
Speaker 1: This is why we have the geek nights book club and this is why reading is important.
Speaker 1: And this is why audiobooks I don't care.
Speaker 1: what you people say is not reading Right.
Speaker 1: the ability to look at words and have words appear at you and to always be able to process those words No matter what context they appear in and process them correctly is what separates smart people from Vegetables.
Speaker 0: you guys saw that that post in the forum.
Speaker 0: I was talking about literacy.
Speaker 0: how a good third of Americans Cannot parse simple information from simple paragraphs.
Speaker 0: and I'm talking like bill has five apples.
Speaker 0: Joan has six apples.
Speaker 0: How many apples does bill have?
Speaker 0: And furthermore only 15% of Americans according to many metrics can actually be considered to be fully literate in the English language.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean they have what they say the literacy rate like if you look at the almanac or whatever is 99% You know.
Speaker 1: that means that people can you know read stop signs?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they can read.
Speaker 1: well the people didn't read a stop sign.
Speaker 1: It's just a big red sim.
Speaker 1: I don't like you don't read a stop sign like they can read street signs.
Speaker 0: They can read like, you know signs like mall this way that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: They understand words, but there's a whole different measure of literacy of being able to to take words put them together and figure out meaning.
Speaker 1: Yeah, take it.
Speaker 1: You know a lot of words and a lot of different contexts.
Speaker 1: put them together and extract the correct meaning from them.
Speaker 1: You know and I mean the first thing you need to do if you're going to do that is to be able to see the Words, if you can't see them, you can't read them.
Speaker 1: and then after you see them you need to read them.
Speaker 1: You need to know what they all mean.
Speaker 1: You need to read them correct, you know It's.
Speaker 1: it's actually quite difficult and most people in the world You know, most people can do it, but they can't do it Well enough.
Speaker 1: or you know in all context or is it all context?
Speaker 0: That's the key.
Speaker 0: These are a lot of people are very smart in one realm But in the computer we're at realm.
Speaker 0: they miss apply some brain Symbology or some brain process to a completely unrelated process in the computer because they don't understand what's actually going on.
Speaker 1: I mean the thing is like look look at me, right?
Speaker 1: I don't really know, you know, I know science, but I'm not a scientist.
Speaker 1: I don't really know science, you know, if you give me some like, you know medical handbook, it's just like blub blub blub, right?
Speaker 0: Yep Like.
Speaker 0: I can tell you all the phases of mitosis.
Speaker 1: But I can I can take it and I can like.
Speaker 1: it is a chapter about some crazy bacteria, right?
Speaker 1: And I can read it.
Speaker 1: I can look at it.
Speaker 1: I'll be slow at reading it but I can read every word and I can sort.
Speaker 1: I can extract as Much meaning as my vote.
Speaker 1: I'm only limited by my vocabulary because I don't know some of the terminology.
Speaker 1: So I could you know if you I can say I can read a sentence in a medical journal and say oh well proper noun A that I don't know what that is, you know Does this verb that I don't know what it is to proper noun C?
Speaker 0: well So if I learn the vocabulary I can tell you what it means got back in the day when I took the ACT test Which is like the SAT that the rest of the country uses.
Speaker 0: But you know I don't know if it's changed since then has a science section that a lot of people had tons of problems with like it was Considered to be very difficult and a lot of people did very poorly on it.
Speaker 0: But all it consisted of was they would give you a short paper or a short explanation of some topic.
Speaker 0: You didn't need to know anything about it.
Speaker 0: They would give you all the information you needed and then ask you questions about it.
Speaker 0: It was basically sounds like fun.
Speaker 1: I won't do that.
Speaker 0: It was basically reading comprehension, but it was all scientific principles and people just couldn't.
Speaker 0: but all that aside Oh, we've gone on a very long time.
Speaker 0: I think we can break it down to users.
Speaker 0: Level one like the level one.
Speaker 0: problem of people not reading the screen is that they literally Do not see what's on the screen due to some weird brain symbology problem.
Speaker 0: level two is they read it but do not understand the importance and just want it to go away.
Speaker 0: and Then layer three is you're already 99% on the way to being able to solve your own problems.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that you know.
Speaker 1: level four is if you can read well enough to you know.
Speaker 1: See type it into Google.
Speaker 1: you can type it into Google and that's then.
Speaker 1: as soon as you can do that You're on our level.
Speaker 1: I mean I started out in kindergarten.
Speaker 1: I had an apple - I read the screen.
Speaker 1: That's how come of a computer scientist.
Speaker 1: That's all I'm not a genius computer scientist.
Speaker 1: I'm not Donald Knuth.
Speaker 1: All right I don't know fancy calculus.
Speaker 1: I don't know fancy maths.
Speaker 1: I mean, I know Matt even start.
Speaker 1: I don't know fancy math.
Speaker 1: I can't integrate anymore.
Speaker 1: really that much in my only kind of kind of like.
Speaker 0: the other day someone asked me How do I make this group?
Speaker 0: in my regular expression greedy as opposed to non greedy and I was like, uh I don't remember offhand.
Speaker 0: I was like Google.
Speaker 0: Oh duh put a question mark here.
Speaker 0: You're done.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh question mark doesn't make something.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it does if you're grouping versus lazy.
Speaker 0: Oh, you're.
Speaker 1: well, you're using a pre anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a completely different use of the question mark, yes anyway But the fact is it's something I use reg exes every day But many many things that are part of my daily job or part of my expertise in computer science and information technology.
Speaker 0: I look up on Google.
Speaker 0: I look up syntax.
Speaker 1: Basically all I do all day, right?
Speaker 1: I went to school for five years to learn, you know programming.
Speaker 1: All I do every day is literally I have to do this.
Speaker 1: I read and read and read and read and read until I figure out how to do it.
Speaker 1: It's the same thing I did with the Apple - oh, I want to play word munchers.
Speaker 1: I read until I can figure out a word muncher.
Speaker 0: There's the other way that is equally important.
Speaker 0: Keep trying shit till it works.
Speaker 1: I also keep trying shit and you know what.
Speaker 1: every time I try something words usually come out and I read them.
Speaker 1: So I type some code in and it says error Integrity error in the database and I go ha there must be something wrong with the database when I do this.
Speaker 0: So I came under what it could be.
Speaker 0: before we end I think we should do a separate show later some day or something on What can we do to force people to read if they don't.
Speaker 0: but I think I have an easy answer.
Speaker 0: If you have an error message in your program and your program is aimed at people who are not technically confident.
Speaker 0: You need a capture a modal window that pops up and gives them the error message and basically Does not let them make that go away until they take some action that proves that they understand.
Speaker 1: That's the opposite of the Steve Jobs philosophy.
Speaker 1: The Steve Jobs philosophy is there are no error messages.
Speaker 1: You never have to read anything ever this.
Speaker 1: we're never gonna put an error message in your face.
Speaker 0: What if when your internet internet connection is down right and this is like just makes a frowny face on a network cable if it Pops a window that says your net internet internet connection is down?
Speaker 0: Do you understand what this means?
Speaker 0: and if it says yes Then it gives you a list of things that could have caused it and it forces you to like answer quest Windows sort of.
Speaker 1: does This?
Speaker 1: when you know Windows Vista and Windows You can just keep clicking.
Speaker 0: Okay, and yes and no and yes and no and eventually all the windows go away.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: You need it to be like, alright, you know It says the network is down.
Speaker 0: Do you understand?
Speaker 0: if you say yes, then it says what went down?
Speaker 0: And it gives you a multiple choice question.
Speaker 0: It is like the internet connection.
Speaker 0: your mother Maybe just insult the users to you've.
Speaker 0: they've got a type stuff.
Speaker 0: ask him like what is your what is your username that you logged?
Speaker 0: In with you cannot proceed until you type it.
Speaker 0: I think type what you see on the screen.
Speaker 0: It shows him a picture.
Speaker 1: I think actually a large part of this problem Right is the mouse.
Speaker 1: if we never if we didn't have the mouse and we just for eat the keyboard Right was how you interacted with the computer people either, you know They just they wouldn't be able to even use the computer period unless they you know had much better reading ability.
Speaker 0: It's tricky though Because while everyone says the mouse causes a lot at least a lot of older school people say the mouse causes all these problems.
Speaker 0: I put forth that watch someone who has not grown up with technology try to use a computer keyboard.
Speaker 0: They understand like that mouse.
Speaker 0: Am I the guy?
Speaker 0: is that me?
Speaker 0: Is that me over there moving around?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the thing is they don't use the computer they don't you know, they don't use the keyboard.
Speaker 1: even though they understand the keyboard.
Speaker 0: They do not grok.
Speaker 1: They do not.
Speaker 1: they don't use it, right?
Speaker 1: This is a they'll go to.
Speaker 1: they'll go to they'll click on the save icon a hundred times and they'll go to file save file Save edit copy edit paste.
Speaker 1: Oh, I didn't see that that it says control s right next to the save word and that on my keyboard There's a control and an S. Well Scott, they don't read they don't that word.
Speaker 1: They don't see that there.
Speaker 0: They see but they do not witness.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brand ok for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and my comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.