Speaker 1: It's Tuesday August 17th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: expansion packs.
Speaker 0: Let's do this All right, so I got.
Speaker 0: you know what I got.
Speaker 1: What'd you get?
Speaker 0: I got the the adventure burner.
Speaker 1: ah You can realize I stupidly have not actually ordered it.
Speaker 0: Well, you should order too because this book is basically saving saving the world here.
Speaker 1: It's basically from what I can gather just from comments people have made the almighty Bible of role-playing Well, I don't know about that well of burning wheel style role-playing.
Speaker 0: I think it's just.
Speaker 0: I think it's actually what Luke said is that is incredibly burning wheel specific like like you know The thing is is like we were obviously not doing everything optimally, I don't think we ever have you know.
Speaker 0: and It's weird because like I knew on paper like what we were doing wrong and what we were supposed to do But I didn't I couldn't do it.
Speaker 1: isn't that the worst thing?
Speaker 1: when you like jam a game and like you know what you did Well, and you know what parts of the game didn't go, but you still can't.
Speaker 0: it's like you know But you still can't do it.
Speaker 1: You know you know cuz you know like this is the part where all right rim is looking at his cell phone.
Speaker 0: No, it's like all rooms got his laptop out rims pooping.
Speaker 0: It's like if you're playing Starcraft.
Speaker 0: It's like I might know what I need to do better, but I know if I if I fail to do it at least I know why I failed.
Speaker 0: I'm just not fast enough.
Speaker 0: I don't have the physical dexterity right.
Speaker 0: I know the reason I couldn't do something that I knew to do But the burning will not so much.
Speaker 1: it's like some of the things are easy like don't argue with players about the obstacle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I read there's a nice chapter on obstacles that saving the world.
Speaker 1: also my conventional wisdom was always its ops 3.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's exactly what this is.
Speaker 0: But actually that most helpful chapter my favorite is the short chapter about wises, right?
Speaker 0: But I want to.
Speaker 0: I want to read at least part of the chapter on wises.
Speaker 0: I know Luke Luke gets mad when people put his stuff on the internet But I can read some bits of the chapter.
Speaker 1: I point out that fair use is quite liberal in regard to excerpts Especially for journalists.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna get.
Speaker 0: I'm not giving you like a couple paragraphs otherwise would be here all night, right, but basically It says here, okay, I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna paraphrase some of the parts here, okay Long ago a black dragon descended upon a great dwarven Hall slew the defenders and took it as his own.
Speaker 0: What our fortress.
Speaker 0: one of the players took the role of the last scion of that dwarven house.
Speaker 0: his long-term goal was to slay The dragon and reclaim his homeland.
Speaker 0: the rest of the players created characters that wanted to help him.
Speaker 0: right the blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: And basically someone asked the GM do I know any stories about the origin of dragons?
Speaker 0: question mark?
Speaker 0: So is this a situation for wises?
Speaker 0: right and basically?
Speaker 0: You know it goes on and talks about well, okay look You know I.
Speaker 1: suddenly I think I wonder if this is going where.
Speaker 1: I think it should be going in that situation As it as a player.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't say do I know any stories?
Speaker 1: I would say I know a story and the role would be whether or not that story is legit.
Speaker 1: I'd do something like that.
Speaker 1: I would never ask do I?
Speaker 1: I would ask I would say I X and then roll the dice.
Speaker 0: well it says here Do I know any stories about the origin of dragons?
Speaker 0: before answering my question the first thing Anthony the GM had to think about was Whether he knew the answer or not when he was preparing the campaign.
Speaker 0: did he?
Speaker 0: Determine where dragons came from or does he have no way?
Speaker 0: he doesn't know and we're gonna find out where dragons came from.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: so you could say yes Or force the guy to roll a dragon wise test.
Speaker 0: and it goes on to talk about when you should say yes.
Speaker 1: I imagine this.
Speaker 1: do I know any stories about the origins of dragons?
Speaker 0: game master says yep well if he says yes He has to give you the information.
Speaker 1: doesn't you say yes?
Speaker 0: No, it says yes, you do you know you?
Speaker 0: maybe you should read the adventure burner cuz.
Speaker 0: clearly you're wrong.
Speaker 0: It says here He has to decide whether to simply say yes And give the information or call for a dragon wise test.
Speaker 0: right and it says when and when.
Speaker 0: you shouldn't You know give a dragon wise test.
Speaker 0: They don't.
Speaker 0: maybe the person will get false information.
Speaker 0: Maybe they get the right information.
Speaker 0: You know You know.
Speaker 0: make sure that the information doesn't contradict any previous information.
Speaker 0: like someone might say sure dragons come from the Isle of Dread.
Speaker 0: Well actually you've already been to the Isle of Dread and there weren't any evidence of dragons there, so we can't go with that right.
Speaker 0: but then You know.
Speaker 0: later on it says remember when you guys are searching for the lost city of Panax And you fought your way to the Chronicle of Ages and the Hall of the All Fathers to do some research.
Speaker 0: You recall there was a section dedicated to dragons that you didn't have time to investigate.
Speaker 0: I would have to wait for another opportunity to test dragon wise and it would be a bit more time before we learn the awful truth.
Speaker 0: Dragons are born when a dwarf advances his greed to exponent 10.
Speaker 0: You know the the.
Speaker 0: it is full of much awesomeness of that variety.
Speaker 0: So there you go.
Speaker 0: adventure burner even if you're not playing well even if you're not playing burning wheel You'll probably get something out of it, but if you are playing burning wheel and you are you know player or GM It is pretty much.
Speaker 0: I don't know how you could really play.
Speaker 0: You know play properly without it You know unless you you know have much much practice in grokking.
Speaker 1: so Scott How come you didn't make any shows this?
Speaker 1: where live past week?
Speaker 0: How come you didn't make any shows?
Speaker 0: I was you're the shit talker.
Speaker 1: I was on vacation, but you were.
Speaker 1: you were here.
Speaker 1: There's nothing stopping you.
Speaker 0: I was busy not shit talking whereas you were laying on the beach Laying on the beach or to-do list.
Speaker 1: I was also drinking heavily and playing games.
Speaker 0: Yes Not doing any of the things that you have should have had done years ago.
Speaker 1: well except for the packs late show stuff.
Speaker 1: now that We can actually talk about that.
Speaker 0: Yes, but you're still.
Speaker 0: you have.
Speaker 0: you have a mighty list of shit talking whereas I where is my shit talking list?
Speaker 0: Can you name a single thing?
Speaker 0: I am shit talking.
Speaker 1: you never Made that e-commerce site.
Speaker 0: that was you was it?
Speaker 0: yes In fact I did more than I should have on the e-commerce site.
Speaker 1: Doesn't matter I'm working on that, but uh-huh I know you're not.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm working on a solution to that.
Speaker 1: that does not involve me making an e-commerce site great.
Speaker 0: Good job You're not doing shit.
Speaker 1: But now 90% of what I was working on for this whole period where we were saying yeah We can't talk about it was the packs late show and for the meta moment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's in the schedule now, so I can at least mention it, but no over the whole week It's funny.
Speaker 1: every year at the shore Scott will be like hey, let's play a game and everyone's like Then we go to the beach or we lay there watch like some terrible old anime.
Speaker 1: We still did that this year.
Speaker 1: We watched Babylon 5.
Speaker 0: It's actually pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm actually really enjoying it.
Speaker 1: I want to know what happens to the membari.
Speaker 0: I've actually watched That some episodes back in the day.
Speaker 0: because what episodes?
Speaker 1: because two things.
Speaker 1: one Babylon 5 not only has bad CGI CGI Compared to shows of today it has bad CGI compared to shows of back then.
Speaker 0: well I don't know which episodes.
Speaker 0: they were random episodes that were airing it like the middle of the day on Sunday when I was in high school.
Speaker 0: Bored you know just home doing nothing and it was terrible.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It was a good show.
Speaker 1: what episodes Do you remember?
Speaker 0: how am I supposed to remember in high school?
Speaker 1: really you don't remember anything from high school?
Speaker 0: I don't remember what TV show I watched on a random Sunday.
Speaker 1: I wish I had watched more of it when I was in high school but no I'd stay up late and watch TNG and then deep space 9 would come on and be like Yeah, I kind of fall asleep during it.
Speaker 1: Babylon 5 was way later on a different channel, so Yeah, all the show sec.
Speaker 1: No those shows are all awesome.
Speaker 1: No terrible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, nothing to do with Tuesday.
Speaker 1: Regardless all that aside at the shore for some reason now that Scott wasn't around it was like the gaming time.
Speaker 1: We played like every board game.
Speaker 1: We had multiple times.
Speaker 1: We even whipped out a weird indie RPG that Scott's never even heard of.
Speaker 0: yeah Yeah, yeah, they're like aha Scott's not here.
Speaker 0: Let's play some games the whole time.
Speaker 1: We're like man.
Speaker 1: only Scott We're here.
Speaker 1: He loved this jerks.
Speaker 1: You could have just come yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you want to pay me.
Speaker 1: Just take vacation time.
Speaker 0: give me some vacation time.
Speaker 0: you spend it all on what hung in this man.
Speaker 0: Don't worry.
Speaker 1: He's spending it on.
Speaker 0: I'm spending on good stuff plus I don't have that much to spend.
Speaker 1: but regardless what I do want to talk about you know We played a bunch of games the Battlestar Galactica game, which is basically Shadows over Camelot plus mafia, and that's it Universe, it's okay.
Speaker 1: The real trouble with it is that it's shadows over camelot.
Speaker 1: now the fun part of the game is Figuring out who the Cylon is but smart players can make that decision.
Speaker 1: Completely pointless really.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 1: smart players Just play randomly, and it doesn't matter if you're the Cylon.
Speaker 1: just dick everyone all the time.
Speaker 1: They cannot figure it out.
Speaker 1: the game is set up to where they cannot actually figure it out without using their powers.
Speaker 0: Really because like in shadows over camelot right you can you know you can help with the quest or you can sort of not Help with the quest.
Speaker 0: so you're saying that in Battlestar Galactica game It's like people will be forced to not help even when they want to know.
Speaker 1: it's more like you.
Speaker 1: you can dick Secretly so people don't know you dicked and you can kind of statistically figure it out But they introduce enough randomness into the stuff you're doing.
Speaker 0: so you can basically dick people secretly So no one can tell who's doing good.
Speaker 0: Then your dicking is concealed by luck.
Speaker 1: basically yes.
Speaker 0: So there's no way to tell who's the side.
Speaker 1: the real trouble in the end is just that if it suffers the same problem fundamentally the shadows over Camelot suffers.
Speaker 1: it Relies on two things.
Speaker 1: one it relies on the fact that you have a hand of cards that are secret.
Speaker 1: So you can play cards and those affect the outcome.
Speaker 1: But at the same time the game does not let you actually say what the numbers are on the cards in your hand.
Speaker 0: Oh, they have stupid rules about what you can.
Speaker 1: I can't say I can help a little I can help a lot But you can't say things like I got 18.
Speaker 1: Let's roll.
Speaker 1: So I don't know that it's.
Speaker 0: that's a fundamental brokenness.
Speaker 0: if you I mean you can have really Specific rules about what can and cannot be said.
Speaker 0: for example you can say this game must be played silently.
Speaker 0: That's okay.
Speaker 0: You can say Players may only say numbers they may not say any words.
Speaker 0: That's okay, but to have such these you know flimsy kind of rules like that It's like sorry guys better than shadows over Camelot.
Speaker 1: They were more precise But there was still a fatal flaw in that it.
Speaker 1: it did not preclude me from making a code ahead of time and using said Like a lot means I have five blue.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I will say a lot.
Speaker 0: the number of times I say the word a lot is the number that I have on my card.
Speaker 0: yeah a lot a lot a lot a lot a lot.
Speaker 1: So that was kind of disappointing, but we played cosmic encounters.
Speaker 1: It's really fun, but it's basically a vote who wins game because you can have mutual victory.
Speaker 1: so the one game I played I was getting the shit.
Speaker 0: we play a lot of games with the mutual victory though But they're not.
Speaker 0: vote who wins.
Speaker 0: you know Illuminati has mutual victories and vote who wins yeah?
Speaker 1: Well, that's cuz the game.
Speaker 0: Dixie has it And that's not vote who wins this game.
Speaker 1: basically you go around and you keep kind of hell.
Speaker 1: you you invite people to help you And then the attacker invites and the defender invites, and you can invite specific people.
Speaker 1: I can be like.
Speaker 1: I invite Nury and Pete's to help me attack and then you know Wyatt who's being attacked and be like.
Speaker 1: well I invite Nury and Scott Johnson, and you know what everybody can to help me defend.
Speaker 1: And I was getting a shit kicked out of me But I had like just enough stuff and Bruce was pretty much winning.
Speaker 1: and then everyone else starts coming up and like anyone could have won like it was getting real close And on my turn I was in the right position.
Speaker 1: I go to Bruce.
Speaker 1: I'm like mutual victory.
Speaker 1: He's like mutual victory.
Speaker 1: we shook hands.
Speaker 1: We did it.
Speaker 1: we won.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got a hundred percent win rate in that game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you played it once.
Speaker 0: yeah, maybe Any other good games.
Speaker 1: I always play some cosmic encounters, which is yeah Some race for the galaxy.
Speaker 1: we played that at anime Boston yep, and having played it two more times everyone was right.
Speaker 1: without the expansions the game is Definitely eminently solvable.
Speaker 0: you need more cards in there to mix it up.
Speaker 0: Otherwise you're just gonna figure out all the cards know exactly which ones to use when and the whole thing is done.
Speaker 1: Yeah, turns were pretty deterministic, and it comes down to the fiddliness, but the expansions?
Speaker 1: I don't know if they make the game great, or if they just delay the figuring out further.
Speaker 1: It's no Puerto Rico, Puerto Rico is a far better game.
Speaker 1: however I enjoy race for the galaxy, but most importantly the game we played.
Speaker 1: I doubt many of you have heard of it 1001 nights a game of enticing stories.
Speaker 0: This is one of those lysing.
Speaker 1: is it indie indie indie role-playing?
Speaker 0: how indie could it be?
Speaker 1: have you ever heard of it?
Speaker 0: Well, I haven't heard most indie game.
Speaker 1: It's put out by night sky games Meg away Baker and The game.
Speaker 1: so it's.
Speaker 1: it's basically Inception the role-playing game, but not in the literal sense, but in the figurative sense.
Speaker 1: it is the yo dawg.
Speaker 1: I heard you like role-playing so put some role-playing in your role-playing so you can role play while you're role-playing The game you play and this might sounds like it'd be really confusing.
Speaker 1: you play a bunch of courtiers courtiers in The Sultan's court in some Saudi Arabian setting.
Speaker 1: you know Arabian night style All right And you all make your characters and name them and as cool mechanics for making characters.
Speaker 1: And then you roleplay a scene with all these courtiers hanging out and doing their thing and at some point someone in the group will suggest a story a Sign rolls to all the other characters and now you roleplay those characters Role-playing that story.
Speaker 0: how many times do you how many stories do you do?
Speaker 1: You keep going around until some metacondition occurs until someone gets beheaded like say in the course of your story Their character gets beheaded or their characters character gets beheaded.
Speaker 1: the real character the meta character the media How does the hat is that have?
Speaker 1: so I don't want to get it all.
Speaker 0: if you're just sitting or if you if you have these Characters who were just sitting around telling stories Role-playing how does anything happen outside of that?
Speaker 0: Story in a story.
Speaker 0: It's a Sultan's courts.
Speaker 0: So when did things happen?
Speaker 0: in the Sultan's?
Speaker 1: all the time Like I said, I don't want to get into the mechanics But say like say you finish your story everything gets resolved, right?
Speaker 0: The story hates it.
Speaker 1: No, the story gets resolved It's all done.
Speaker 1: Then you go through all these mechanics to figure out.
Speaker 1: was the Sultan insulted by something you did in the course of the roleplay?
Speaker 1: or Did you get closer to your ambition?
Speaker 1: and then you roleplay the aftermath of the story as the meta characters until another story happens?
Speaker 1: And you kind of take turns Describing and then playing out the scenes outside of the role-playing and then playing out the role-playing itself.
Speaker 0: So it's basically that that Monty Python skit.
Speaker 0: Oh, that one was his Like a golden your Your majesty is like.
Speaker 1: So, here's the weird thing.
Speaker 1: Look, what is one of the biggest problems our group has?
Speaker 1: role-playing?
Speaker 1: people don't remember each other's in character names.
Speaker 1: Very few people can maintain first-person dialogue as their character in character.
Speaker 1: I think the biggest problem more than a paragraph or so.
Speaker 0: But I think the fundamental problem there is simply that people can't sit and pay attention And focus and not get up and do anything else.
Speaker 0: They are they are constantly getting up and doing other things and not sitting down an only role-playing and not doing not looking at their Phones not going to get food not go.
Speaker 1: That's simple anytime.
Speaker 1: They're doing that.
Speaker 1: they're bored.
Speaker 1: If they're doing that the games already failed I'm just saying but this game.
Speaker 1: but even that aside part of the reason they're not engaged Look, no one remembers each other's characters names.
Speaker 1: Can you name any of the characters from the Oasis game other than Goma the Oasis game?
Speaker 1: Yeah What was my character's name?
Speaker 0: I don't remember really.
Speaker 0: I got to think for him.
Speaker 1: Can you name any character from?
Speaker 0: I could if you let me think for like a little bit or take a while.
Speaker 1: Can you name any characters from the the ferret game?
Speaker 0: We were playing the ferret All that.
Speaker 1: any of them?
Speaker 0: any ferret game any ferret game?
Speaker 1: Can you name any character from any role-playing game that we have played as a group in the last decade?
Speaker 0: That wasn't my character.
Speaker 0: Yes Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: I know the characters names and like door in the dwarf fortress game.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah name.
Speaker 1: What's my character's name?
Speaker 0: I forget but I know that she Illustrated.
Speaker 0: she's character is kygar and I think so.
Speaker 0: my point illustrated Someone else's.
Speaker 0: someone else is like earn.
Speaker 1: People don't know their characters names in person and they don't roleplay in person.
Speaker 1: people very have a lot of difficulty kind of actually having a conversation that makes sense in the course of the game as their character without defaulting to proper noun Anything.
Speaker 1: that guy's name.
Speaker 1: my character tries to convince the guy to do this.
Speaker 1: roll the dice A thousand and one nights forces the opposite.
Speaker 0: I thought it was called something else.
Speaker 1: It's called a thousand and one nights a game of enticing stories Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So not only did everyone remember every other character's name and speak to them Continuously in character for pretty much the entirety of the game and I have a recording of this to prove it Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: No one even had trouble remembering the fucking secondary characters every time around and they go What what was it about the game that did that?
Speaker 1: So one the game is heavy on atmosphere.
Speaker 1: The book tells you you'd better be lounging.
Speaker 1: You'd better have like wine and grapes and things really get into character.
Speaker 1: Change the setting have physical tokens put a bowl in the middle for the token?
Speaker 0: Well dread says the same thing if you read.
Speaker 0: if you actually follow the instructions of dread You're supposed to make the room all dark and spooky.
Speaker 1: Yes I cannot express to you how well that works.
Speaker 1: the physical space of gaming Matters far more than we'd even suspected when we mandated that you must have a table.
Speaker 1: Yeah I know I knew that I knew it mattered when we mandated the table but mandating the lounging and we kind of we all Lounged and played and it worked beautifully because it was it fit the setting Also the way you make your character.
Speaker 1: you describe your character.
Speaker 1: you make six sentences Describing your character.
Speaker 1: each one must reference one of these senses and then the last one is what they look like Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So site my character, you know, nothing escapes my character's gaze.
Speaker 1: or my character is blind or my character is ugly just anything involving sight and scent and taste and touch and hearing.
Speaker 1: and Then you have to go around and after everyone knows everyone's characters Everyone has one ambition and then everyone has one thing about every other character that they envy Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Not so you have to.
Speaker 0: so if you have five players you have five envy.
Speaker 1: Yes, not hate but envy which means that before envy.
Speaker 1: so you'll be sniping You'll be insulting each other.
Speaker 1: a game like that in a Sultan's court.
Speaker 1: You think courtiers aren't gonna be insulting each other?
Speaker 1: But because you can't really insult each other directly.
Speaker 1: It's a court.
Speaker 1: You can't be like.
Speaker 1: you're a big and fat and stupid.
Speaker 1: But what if in the course of telling a story you ask the big fat stupid guy to roleplay the big fat stupid guy.
Speaker 1: Oh You get to ask Yes, the person starting the story says alright, we're going to play.
Speaker 1: You know this I'm going to tell the story of.
Speaker 1: you know It's I forget the Arabic name.
Speaker 0: you can be the but Smith But it's been.
Speaker 0: I will be the Sultan.
Speaker 1: the Don Juan story about the famous lover and let's see I need and this was Pete's character Mustafa bin Mustafa.
Speaker 0: That's a good name.
Speaker 1: He was the fat powerful Eunuch of the court in charge of the harem.
Speaker 1: his envy of my character.
Speaker 1: I was the pretty boy You had a clean position was that I can lay with a woman.
Speaker 1: my envy of him is that he is physically powerful
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 1: so he wants to tell the Don Juan story because the envious of me He cast himself as Don Juan, of course and as a slight he casts me my character as the eunuch To try to and his and he's trying obviously to like make me understand what it's like.
Speaker 1: So of course because the you know, the role-playing is so important.
Speaker 1: I immediately stuffed pillows under my shirt Physically and then when I when I come on to the scene in the scenario Her did her.
Speaker 0: I am the eunuch big and stupid.
Speaker 1: Look at how much I smell.
Speaker 1: One is so much smarter and cleverer than me.
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 1: He will get away and That is the way the game flows.
Speaker 1: It is so awesome.
Speaker 1: Once we played we have to review.
Speaker 0: know why.
Speaker 0: well You know why the game is good for us?
Speaker 0: Because the game where you insult the other people and we are experts at that.
Speaker 0: Oh my are we?
Speaker 0: That is our expertise is insulting each other viciously.
Speaker 0: So any game about insulting is our game.
Speaker 1: So, uh any games that you played?
Speaker 0: I played I went to board game night and I played some games.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Borges Emily one.
Speaker 1: There's some manga things you wanted you to go to but you were like at board games.
Speaker 0: Yeah Let's see.
Speaker 0: I played the Castlevania game on the Xbox.
Speaker 1: I bought it.
Speaker 1: I have not even played it once.
Speaker 0: It's alright It's not the problem.
Speaker 0: The only problem I have with it.
Speaker 0: Is that like you're doing these individual levels?
Speaker 0: and It's got?
Speaker 0: I wish it was just more.
Speaker 0: one gigantic cat, you know, how come?
Speaker 0: no one does it?
Speaker 0: I just make the game Gigantic.
Speaker 0: they hadn't think that they spent enough time making these like I guess six or seven I don't know how many.
Speaker 0: there are maps cuz I didn't finish the game.
Speaker 0: You could have just put them all together and made one gigantic one, dude.
Speaker 0: Come on.
Speaker 0: Just go crazy big make something That's like Symphony of the night size, you know, maybe even twice as big as that, you know go large.
Speaker 0: That's like the example of what if four swords let anyone go anyway, I mean if there's six players simultaneously, that means we can explore it.
Speaker 0: That means we can explore this shit in one sixth the time.
Speaker 0: So you got to make it 6x size of the Symphony of the night.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm looking for.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway, uh, well it I've been playing some FPS.
Speaker 0: is you know what FPS I'm playing?
Speaker 1: NS doom doom Doom one doom - all kinds of doom.
Speaker 1: final doom all doom final doom.
Speaker 1: wasn't that fun?
Speaker 1: to be honest playing all doom Play some doom deathmatch.
Speaker 0: I got this new doom engine the doomsday engine and then I went.
Speaker 0: I went into my steam folder and I got the wad files and I wrote a blog post telling you how to make it happen.
Speaker 0: because Remember when he went to that that thing?
Speaker 0: and there was the CEO and the and the 30. yeah, the the bald guy the Kotaku guy.
Speaker 0: Apparently he never played.
Speaker 1: Do you remember his name?
Speaker 0: Totillo.
Speaker 0: he never played doom.
Speaker 0: And he wrote a blog post about his first attempt to play doom.
Speaker 0: like very, you know Which is very recently like, you know, what's after the y+30.
Speaker 1: so having not like interacted with this I don't know where this story goes.
Speaker 1: Doom, I think if you just sit down to play it is Emanently 100% accessible.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is is that he had a great time playing it actually but he played it like the flash version and then he tried to play like an Xbox crappy because He couldn't get it to work on the computer Technologically speaking because the steam dos box thing just didn't work out of the box.
Speaker 0: the steam dos box thing works Barely, so I had I wrote a blog post how to make the doomsday thing work, which is far superior and far more accessible.
Speaker 0: Let's see what else I play Forbidden Island.
Speaker 0: I played once.
Speaker 0: it's basically It's the same genre as pandemic, right?
Speaker 0: It's a verse the game game.
Speaker 1: I think though that always a mixed bag.
Speaker 0: I think the problem with this one is that we I'm not sure, you know we should have made it a harder difficulty because we just won and It was like a turn or two before we actually won but we were guaranteed to win already.
Speaker 0: So I was like, oh we've already won But the guy next to me was like I want to play it out and I'm like, dude It doesn't matter you can make any move as long as you don't as long as you're not stupid.
Speaker 0: There is no way we can lose.
Speaker 0: and he was like no we might lose.
Speaker 0: and I'm like look Tell me what combination of cards can show up and where we would lose.
Speaker 0: there isn't he's like.
Speaker 0: I can't tell you which specific one I'm like, have you not been paying attention?
Speaker 0: even if the worst possible cards are all in a row There's no way we can lose.
Speaker 0: we have two helicopter cards.
Speaker 0: We can't lose.
Speaker 1: go back to the Horatio hornblower books, right?
Speaker 1: There's one where he's playing and this is in the show - you saw this part where he's playing whist.
Speaker 1: And then the guy's like you're cheating and he's like no I'm just good.
Speaker 1: and then later like he's like well this hands over and the other three guys throw their cards in And the guys like no we should keep playing It's not over.
Speaker 1: and then the smart people are all like well No, because you couldn't have more than blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: I don't think a lot of people are at that level on most German board games.
Speaker 0: This isn't even a German game really but yeah, it's a beat the game game.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't recommend it really, you know, it's sorta It's not you know, I mean if you're gonna play that game just play pandemic.
Speaker 0: It's you know, it's if you want to play those games as the best of them You know what I'm bringing to the next board.
Speaker 1: game night I got the Tigris and Euphrates expansion that none of us fucking knew about.
Speaker 1: All right, I can't believe it.
Speaker 0: How good is it?
Speaker 1: We haven't played it.
Speaker 1: I don't know but it did what we said it should do.
Speaker 1: They have the normal board and on the back an alternate board with a big open area and a river kind of around the edge.
Speaker 1: There's a spot.
Speaker 1: there were two spots for the blue monument.
Speaker 1: Whoa, and one of those spots is six squares And there's also another expansion.
Speaker 1: you can you kind of mix and match I think the ziggurat If you make a three across and three across to kind of like a plus.
Speaker 0: So you so when you place the ninth tile, you can flip it over.
Speaker 1: So a plus so five tiles.
Speaker 1: Okay, then you turn it into the ziggurat.
Speaker 1: It is a black only monument and the black leader there gets one cube of their choice every round.
Speaker 1: Yeah There's also one building for you.
Speaker 0: Can you can the five tiles?
Speaker 0: Does it have to be like one color?
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter what doesn't matter which one.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: Okay, but it's a black.
Speaker 1: only there's another thing.
Speaker 1: there are four buildings one of each color and you place them once.
Speaker 1: you make a Horizontal or vertical line of tiles of that color that are at least three long.
Speaker 1: You can choose upon placing the third one to place that building on the tile.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Now any further tiles placed in that kingdom give that colored leader double points.
Speaker 0: Right, so the colored leader?
Speaker 0: who's in the king?
Speaker 0: So
Speaker 1: if I place the green special building in a kingdom and I have the green leader and then later I place a green tile You get
Speaker 0: two green
Speaker 1: now, but
Speaker 0: if someone takes that from you, so
Speaker 1: the way you take that from someone is not normal It's longest road.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, if I build a line of four green somewhere else in the boards fucking You can just internal conflict him in the kingdom that has or I can build a line of four green.
Speaker 1: You could but you could end the tiles don't go away they stay in the kingdom for strength.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know someone external conflicts or what?
Speaker 1: if I catastrophe that shit you can get asked me around it Yeah and break it.
Speaker 1: All right, but someone else still has to take it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm It's interesting.
Speaker 0: That's interesting Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 1: well because the reason they added it is.
Speaker 1: the other alternate board has this huge open land area.
Speaker 1: So there's a. there's much more kind of pattern recognition action going on in that area.
Speaker 1: That board also has kind of an inside outside Mechanic of the river in terms of pressures to take and more treasures.
Speaker 0: We gotta hurry this up because we're burning the whole front of the show.
Speaker 0: But I played one more game called space alert space alert space alert.
Speaker 0: was this weird?
Speaker 0: It was a real-time board game, right?
Speaker 0: And basically the way it's supposed to work is you get these audio recordings that tell tell you what happens But we didn't have the audio recording.
Speaker 0: So one guy sat there with a with a clock a timer and he read off the card at the precise times.
Speaker 0: What you know, but if you have the audio recording You don't need a person to run the game because it'll just say the things that needs to say at the right time.
Speaker 1: That's a really interesting idea.
Speaker 0: So for example, you'll play around and the round will be X minutes and then it'll resolve And when the time is up you resolve and figure out if you want or not, right?
Speaker 0: and it's a beat.
Speaker 0: the game game and the way it works is you're on a spaceship and Aliens are coming and they're gonna shoot you right and you need to basically you all program your character, right?
Speaker 0: And you probe you have cards and you put the cards down on this little thing to sort of Command your guy to do so to be like go to the left side of the board Go to the bottom half of the board you have up down left right, right?
Speaker 0: Use push the a button move right.
Speaker 0: push the B button move Right.
Speaker 0: So some of the buttons shoot lasers and some of the buttons, you know Break open a canister with more energy and some of the buttons transfer energy from one area the ship to the other.
Speaker 0: Some of the buttons charge up a shield, you know, all the buttons do different things.
Speaker 0: So you have you know some number of players and the different ships attacking you have different special abilities too Like we got screwed because I tried to attack this one ship, but I attacked it too early.
Speaker 0: So it was too far away and the shot didn't reach and so you got it.
Speaker 0: Basically, you have this short time limit.
Speaker 0: You're basically racing against the clock all the all these all of you together and you're trying to each program your own character.
Speaker 0: You know together Such that and you can't program them.
Speaker 0: face up either.
Speaker 0: you're programming them.
Speaker 0: face down, huh?
Speaker 1: I just had an idea.
Speaker 1: What did you?
Speaker 1: take that and combine it with the multiple transforming combining sentai robot kind of show?
Speaker 1: Five pilots in the robot.
Speaker 1: You've got to coordinate to win.
Speaker 0: That's not the same kind.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it could work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yeah, it was.
Speaker 0: it was a little bit hectic.
Speaker 0: The problem was I think not you know It only really works if everyone gets it.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: we barely won on the easiest possible scenario And we played the second most easy scenario.
Speaker 1: and was it obvious who didn't get it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Mean I see I thought I got it but even though but because I was I got it.
Speaker 0: But the thing was I couldn't keep track of all the stuff.
Speaker 0: it was because it was so much going on.
Speaker 0: I didn't recognize.
Speaker 0: You know I couldn't keep in my head all that.
Speaker 0: there were three different aliens attacking us and each one had a different special ability and You know, there were.
Speaker 0: you know, we had to get the energy and fire the guns and do enough damage and you know You really need every enough people to all get it simultaneously to be able to parse all the information To program all of your characters to actually win.
Speaker 0: and you know while you're playing it'll be like new alien appears, you know You know, it'll be like, okay, you can trade cards with each other for the next 30 seconds And you know, you can't trade cards anymore.
Speaker 1: I never considered the idea of using an audio recording or some sort of audio like triggered Mechanism to make a game.
Speaker 1: that is actually like physicality and timeliness matters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can go to their website and listen to some of the mp3 Not that they're gonna help you without the game.
Speaker 1: But yeah, but it's a brilliant idea.
Speaker 1: I think more people should try that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's a beat the game game.
Speaker 1: So I guess right on to things of the day.
Speaker 1: You got a thing of the day Great thing of the day.
Speaker 0: So I don't know.
Speaker 0: Did I use this on the show before we'll find out?
Speaker 0: Apparently there's this guy named Jake Adelstein, right?
Speaker 0: I don't know if you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you did this last week.
Speaker 0: Did I wasn't my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Did we do any shows last week?
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 1: No, we didn't.
Speaker 1: I'm messing with you.
Speaker 0: Go on.
Speaker 0: Okay, and he's I think I might have talked about him on the show before He's his Jew who went to Japan and he how he we like how he was a yacht.
Speaker 0: He was a crime reporter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you talked about.
Speaker 0: he got all in with the yacht.
Speaker 1: is the guy on The Daily Show, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and he did the expose.
Speaker 1: and the guy they come to America to get livers Exactly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So this is this is this guy who's all in with the Yakuza?
Speaker 0: So he actually what he did was he went to some of his Yakuza friends because somebody told him to right?
Speaker 1: Oh, oh, I know what you're doing.
Speaker 1: This is good.
Speaker 0: And he got the game the PlayStation or is it's a PlayStation game, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, Yakuza 3 the Yakuza simulator when we played at packs and he got some Yakuza to play Yakuza 3.
Speaker 0: This is sort of like when football players may play Madden, right?
Speaker 0: So and he wanted that or when they get race car drivers to play like Forza Gran Turismo and ask him how it is I'm glad he's not worried that they're gonna kill him anymore.
Speaker 0: These are his you know, these are friendly Yakuza Yakuza that he was friends with right?
Speaker 0: I'm sure they're still Yakuza who would probably want to kill him or maybe I don't know but you know These were Yakuza that he was on good terms with even though There's a funny part in this in this piece where it's like one of the Yakuza says Gaijin and one of the other ones like Don't say Gaijin.
Speaker 0: Jake's a Gaijin.
Speaker 0: He's like.
Speaker 0: you just say gai kouguji.
Speaker 0: But you know they talk about.
Speaker 0: you know Some of the things in the game that they like and some of the things in the game that they don't like, you know.
Speaker 0: And stuff, you know and how they like how.
Speaker 0: you know Sake powers you up and he's like, oh they should have crystal meth It should be a power up.
Speaker 0: and oh they were excited that the game had Sake and all the different, you know Cuz we saw that right all the different Sake's.
Speaker 1: We did the Sake part and the pool part and I like Sake and I like pool Billiards pool not pool pool.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yeah, it was a. It's a really interesting article about Yakuza playing Yakuza.
Speaker 1: random aside listeners Do you guys actually know that billiards and pool are different games and do you know the difference?
Speaker 0: And there's also multiple different billiards and multiple different pools I think the only people and there's also the kind with the bumpers I think the only people.
Speaker 1: we had a bumper pool table and also snooker.
Speaker 1: We actually had a bumper pool table for games and you could lift it out and put in a billiards table instead.
Speaker 0: But I don't know.
Speaker 0: actually I don't really know how any of the games work.
Speaker 0: I think I know there's one where you have to get all the balls it but you have to give him an order and there's one we have to get all the balls in but it doesn't really order doesn't matter as much.
Speaker 1: nine ball is one of the.
Speaker 1: get Him in in the right order, but regardless I think Donald Duck in math magic land is the primary reason I know about billiards.
Speaker 0: and then there's you know snooker Which I don't even fucking know.
Speaker 1: Snooker is awesome.
Speaker 1: It's the 10-foot table.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, so really quick This is a list someone compiled.
Speaker 1: he's a prison guard in Wisconsin medium security because I'm sure the list is actually probably very different and He just.
Speaker 1: he's a board gamer board game geek.
Speaker 1: So he observed and tried to make a list of.
Speaker 1: here are the games that I see played most often by people in Prison, I mean they let you play board games in prison medium security.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it's a way.
Speaker 0: So what crime do I commit to go to medium security prison?
Speaker 0: Ah shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, here's the problem.
Speaker 1: They don't play.
Speaker 1: risk that often you know why.
Speaker 1: it takes forever to check out and check in all the individual dice.
Speaker 0: They have to check out and check in every dice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz you don't want the dice to get in the wrong hands.
Speaker 1: They might turn into a tiny shave.
Speaker 0: But can't you just check out the whole box and then they just check when you return it that every single pain in the every Single item in the box is in the comments on every game.
Speaker 1: This is well worth perusing.
Speaker 0: number one dominoes make sense, but don't you to check out each and every individual domino?
Speaker 1: I think I could make a shiv out of a domino pretty easily.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I could just friggin snap make triangles in here.
Speaker 1: The one that I found funny is Jenga.
Speaker 0: you could make a wicked splinter.
Speaker 1: you hold out a little bit and there's like escape from Cold.
Speaker 1: it's duh, really?
Speaker 0: They have cold.
Speaker 0: It's in some Prison.
Speaker 1: I and and one that I just noticed so I looked it up.
Speaker 1: It's called prison bitch.
Speaker 1: It is in the category of fighting horror and mature adult.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh Yeah, all right, so Man, I'm gonna move right on to the meta moment.
Speaker 1: We can finally announce straight up.
Speaker 1: We're doing three Events at PAX prime this year.
Speaker 0: No, we fixed the pecs prime.
Speaker 0: Oh my god Actually, they should totally expect it.
Speaker 1: cuz you're there every year though the one that you're probably most interested in We are in fact Scott and I the hosts of Pax's new late show.
Speaker 0: packs late, I guess is that we're calling it.
Speaker 1: It's packs late night.
Speaker 1: is the title?
Speaker 0: Is it okay if we tell them the name we wanted and I think I'd.
Speaker 1: I think we're gonna.
Speaker 1: we're working on a story For that.
Speaker 1: because remember we considered making the title the 11th hour because we had thinking title at the 11th hour.
Speaker 0: You know, I I haven't told you this yet.
Speaker 0: But what do we try?
Speaker 0: calling it packs nights?
Speaker 1: I'm trying to shy away from the geek nights Brandon.
Speaker 0: I know but it's like we had the perfect name and they took it away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well don't be my All right, we'll see.
Speaker 1: I plan to make oblique references to that throughout the entire show.
Speaker 1: Okay, it's too damn late to do this.
Speaker 1: Anyway.
Speaker 1: So yes weird.
Speaker 1: It's we're gonna have a musical act.
Speaker 1: In fact, I just last night confirmed the musical act.
Speaker 1: It is not what we reveal.
Speaker 1: Uh, we did not is not officially announced yet.
Speaker 1: I could reveal it.
Speaker 1: It's set in stone.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna.
Speaker 1: All right, we'll announce it later.
Speaker 1: But the musical act she is totally cool Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: You're revealed effect.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: I have revealed effect.
Speaker 1: She.
Speaker 1: I asked her if she had any questions for me.
Speaker 1: after I gave her all the stuff right like.
Speaker 1: here's the recording.
Speaker 1: There's the taping blah blah blah and her question was Kirk or Picard.
Speaker 1: So she's our kind of people.
Speaker 1: All right We got like Albrecht as one of the guests.
Speaker 1: We've got three of the roosterteeth guys.
Speaker 1: We're finalizing the details on getting balls of steel.
Speaker 0: The show is only an hour long.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna fit all these people in.
Speaker 1: well, we're gonna have dynamics.
Speaker 0: They're gonna be like 10-15 minutes each.
Speaker 1: That's fine We'll manage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm sure we will do stuff with these people around packs independently of packs late night.
Speaker 1: It is Friday 10 p.m.
Speaker 1: In the serpent theater.
Speaker 1: So if you want to be in the live studio audience and see this thing before we edit it together Line up and then Saturday air it, you know stream it out.
Speaker 0: We're gonna have time to like prepare before.
Speaker 0: You know, we're gonna be in there like 9 preparing right?
Speaker 1: Oh my god We're gonna.
Speaker 1: we're probably doing some rehearsals and tests nothing scheduled right before it is there.
Speaker 1: don't worry We got some empty space.
Speaker 0: Okay We're also doing our two new panels egregiously unrealized potential Which is you probably shouldn't go to because it's right before the end of the packs Which is gonna be down the street in that.
Speaker 0: What's the theater that they got?
Speaker 0: We'll go down in a mob.
Speaker 1: our entire panel will go down there.
Speaker 1: All right I'm gonna make sure we get into the final thing no matter what.
Speaker 1: And we're doing our hardcore panel game mechanics and mechanism design.
Speaker 0: I got it right that panel this weekend.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got it outlined.
Speaker 1: yeah, I am mostly done with egregiously unrealized potential.
Speaker 1: after testing it at Kinetic on I was reminded of some egregiously unrealized games.
Speaker 1: One guy the audience was like motherfucking space shooters tie fighter tie fighter.
Speaker 1: Someone else was like, what about metal Marines?
Speaker 0: Yeah What's the book club book?
Speaker 1: the book club book is golden apples of the Sun by Ray Bradbury, I'm done with it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna lend it to Scott.
Speaker 0: Give it to me before I leave today of short stories.
Speaker 1: You have no excuse not to read it.
Speaker 1: They're like three pages long each one of these actually, you know what I wanted to.
Speaker 0: I want to tell you a quick aside here.
Speaker 0: You know, I mean, I'm not gonna ever buy a DRM D book.
Speaker 1: probably as long as I live I almost considered buying the new Kindle because it's like a hundred and thirty bucks.
Speaker 0: No, but you know what I got.
Speaker 0: What'd you get?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I've been doing is when I'm on the subway or sitting around somewhere I would play games on my iPhone.
Speaker 1: I read a book.
Speaker 0: I had that sword and poker on there, you know, but I beat all the sword and pokers.
Speaker 0: So I'm sitting there and I'm like, what should I play on my iPhone?
Speaker 0: and Civ Rev was free, but not your DS Hmm.
Speaker 0: I don't really bring my DS around as much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got like Dragon Quest 9 on there, but I'm you know, whatever.
Speaker 0: But what I've been doing is I actually got project Gutenberg books and I got them or PDFs and I put them in the iBooks App on the iPhone.
Speaker 0: So when I'm on the subway, I'm just like, you know flipping through a book real quick.
Speaker 0: And I've actually.
Speaker 0: this is actually the first time I've been able to read like two books Simultaneously like an actual book and a book, you know, I usually I can't read two books at once.
Speaker 0: I know you love that simultaneously.
Speaker 0: So it keeps coming up.
Speaker 0: I'm actually like in 75% of the way through like around the world in 80 days now, you know, so any project Gutenberg book, you know.
Speaker 1: Actually not to cuz you get to pick the next book club book, but not to push you.
Speaker 1: But I'm most of the way through the golden compass, which I'd never read.
Speaker 0: What's the golden compass?
Speaker 1: You don't know about the golden compass.
Speaker 0: I know about his dark materials.
Speaker 0: I don't know about any dark material.
Speaker 0: atheist Narnia Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it doesn't sound so exciting.
Speaker 1: It's it's really exciting.
Speaker 0: Okay, I got better books than that.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: Like what?
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: Okay, let's do Once and Future King bitches.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll read it again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: There's there's a hot goose in this one, too I'm not even kidding.
Speaker 0: or we could do crystal caves.
Speaker 1: We should just anyway, so New York anime festival comic-con all those stuff is coming up, but we talk about it every show.
Speaker 1: We'll let it be pecs prime late show.
Speaker 1: It is motherfucking us.
Speaker 0: It is on it's on It's on like Donkey Kong.
Speaker 1: This is one of our more ambitious projects.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Okay, so let's talk about expansion packs, so we're not people named expansion.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, we we had all these new friends that are IT a long time ago and we start with the complete tangent.
Speaker 1: So we met, you know all these people no names and then a few days later We met some more people that those people had known Mm-hmm, and one of those people hung around.
Speaker 1: but because he came second we always referred to him as the expansion pack which shortened later to Expansion pack, you know what.
Speaker 0: you can thank that guy for the book club in a part in part.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah You're right because one time rim I wasn't there but rim and some other people were hanging out and that guy was there and They were talking about books and this guy wasn't saying much.
Speaker 0: He looked at a bed Yeah, and eventually he was just what did he say?
Speaker 0: You were there?
Speaker 0: Well one of us like I wasn't there.
Speaker 1: We're like expansion pack.
Speaker 1: Why don't you join in the conversation?
Speaker 1: Don't be shy cuz we figured you know, he doesn't notice that.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe he's shy and he's like, well, I don't have anything just really add to this conversation.
Speaker 1: We're like, why not?
Speaker 1: Don't you agree?
Speaker 1: He's like, I don't really read books and we all I don't.
Speaker 1: I don't read like.
Speaker 1: what do you mean you don't read books?
Speaker 1: He's like, I just I don't read for like anything.
Speaker 1: He's like no, not really For like can you read is like I can read but you don't.
Speaker 1: No, I don't read and yeah, we didn't have anything to say.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so don't be that guy.
Speaker 0: Okay expansions of games.
Speaker 1: I got the teeny expansion.
Speaker 0: I'm so excited about this even though it's really because I don't know how it's you know, I mean it could be good.
Speaker 1: But here's why I'm excited.
Speaker 1: Tigers New Freighties is a game.
Speaker 1: It's my favorite board game in the world.
Speaker 1: Nothing is better than it right now in my eyes for my own personal rim amusement Mm-hmm, but the game is very played out as a crew.
Speaker 1: We have mostly solved that game.
Speaker 1: Very small number of strategies.
Speaker 1: It probably comes down to luck.
Speaker 1: We haven't proven it yet because we're now.
Speaker 1: we play that game a lot.
Speaker 1: We always speculated.
Speaker 1: Well, if we just change the aim a little bit, it'll be a whole new game.
Speaker 1: We don't know what the dynamic would be if we like move this river a little bit or you know Took out like 10 red tiles and then went.
Speaker 1: So we never bothered doing that because game balance is difficult.
Speaker 1: So all the expansion here for Tigers New Freighties is is a balanced a known balanced a tested.
Speaker 0: You would hope so, right?
Speaker 0: I mean a lot of times expansions come out and they're not actually balanced tested.
Speaker 0: It's like they just took some house.
Speaker 0: Sometimes they're fixes for a broken game, right?
Speaker 0: Sometimes they're broken like the river.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know sometimes there's something that's just thrown together to make more money Dominion.
Speaker 1: They're just printing money.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it's something like carcass own cities where it's not accident expansion But a whole new game that has nothing to do with carcass And they just slap the carcass own label out.
Speaker 1: Remember there was even a salary to you and Euphrates card game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they'll just take the same.
Speaker 0: Well, that's not really an expansion, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it was still called Tigers New Freighties.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it was at least you know, but the thing is like the settlers card game the Tigris and Euphrates card game.
Speaker 0: There's you know, Colorado.
Speaker 0: Those are at least mechanically similar to their board game counterparts.
Speaker 0: They're just you know They make the same a similar game with just cards to make it more portable.
Speaker 1: I think the bottom of the expansion barrel is and we were standing we were at a cat a pension.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it was uber con.
Speaker 0: I know it's Connecticut.
Speaker 0: Was it Connecticut?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're standing there and we see carcass own expansion.
Speaker 1: It's like huh?
Speaker 1: What if there are any new ones?
Speaker 1: and I pick up the catapult and I turn it over and sure enough is a physical Catapult and you lob your meeples at the board.
Speaker 0: I don't know exactly the mechanics of this.
Speaker 0: What do you physically do it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I'm holding it and I look at Scott and he looks at me and I'm like Seriously, that is I mean the shark was jumped way before that but that was like you jump the strike again.
Speaker 0: It's like okay We jump the shark and now we're gonna jump a beluga whale and the guy running the stall looks to us and says Yeah But it's like dude you put this in your inventory and he's like you didn't have to order this shit.
Speaker 1: it sells.
Speaker 1: I mean look at pecs.
Speaker 0: who has bought the dead pecs?
Speaker 1: We're like, why do they have a thousand copies of ticket to ride and no copies of Puerto Rico?
Speaker 1: They sold all those tickets to ride.
Speaker 0: Hey, they really sold all the tickets to ride.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know about all of them out of a lot of memory or that.
Speaker 1: I guess they buried him.
Speaker 0: They should have had a stack of dominions equally high.
Speaker 1: But the thing is if they're gonna sell dominions and tickets to rides No matter what they're gonna sell them all and they can only bring us that number.
Speaker 1: bring the shit of your game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't sell your good game.
Speaker 1: If you don't have to the good game will sell.
Speaker 0: you can sell both.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they kind of had him stacked up filling the whole booth.
Speaker 0: I don't know where they got so many.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the deal is with that.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah But yeah, I mean, you know expansions are kind of weird because like sometimes, you know There's no like.
Speaker 0: usually when there's something you can have a set rule Like I don't do any expansions or expansions are good.
Speaker 0: But really there is no set rule, you know, sometimes it's just more of the same Right.
Speaker 0: It's like okay.
Speaker 0: I played this game and now I need another map like battle tech or
Speaker 1: like the final doom Yeah,
Speaker 0: but sometimes You know, it's like, okay, you're trying to make more money and you just made some crap, you know And you put the same name on it or to make some more money
Speaker 1: or the full extreme of that is now the micro expansions Aka the gun horse.
Speaker 0: What's the gun horse?
Speaker 1: the penny arcade comic when Grand Theft Auto?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the DLCs where it's like pay money and your character can look different or Gun bound right and pay money and your character actually is better.
Speaker 0: I mean, what is the difference like between an expansion to a game and say a booster pack of magic cards, right?
Speaker 0: I mean if you consider the starter pack to be the game a booster is an expansion, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, or maybe the expansion is not the booster cards, but the booster sets.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so some magic the gathering like I like how you hmm like that was somehow wise.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean like, you know edition X of magic is a game or ice age is a game but fallen empires.
Speaker 1: I said magic died long before ice age came out.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying right now who would be?
Speaker 0: that would be the game and the expansion would be fallen empires or Whatever else.
Speaker 0: dark would be an expansion.
Speaker 0: Yep, but unlimited would be.
Speaker 1: which came first?
Speaker 1: the darker fallen empires Dark, which came first?
Speaker 1: the dark Arabian Nights Arabian Nights which came first?
Speaker 1: Arabian Nights or antiquities.
Speaker 0: Uh Antiquities came after I think the dog.
Speaker 1: So you remember the order of the expansion?
Speaker 0: How do you know?
Speaker 1: I'm right because I know uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Yeah Arabian Nights was the first expansion to magic.
Speaker 0: All right anyway, anyway What's my character's name?
Speaker 1: in the dwarf game you're the game master for Boring.
Speaker 0: you're in something like that.
Speaker 0: You're in Gormor Gormor.
Speaker 1: That's it Very bronze murder II kind of name.
Speaker 1: Yeah You're right though, there's.
Speaker 1: no I can't make any blanket statements about expansions because they range from the catapult To the gun horse to Like Dominion.
Speaker 1: in here I'm trying to come up with the name of a good one because Dominion injury really just like the Dominion expansions.
Speaker 0: Dominion Seaside was actually really good.
Speaker 1: They took a game that we the best that we had immediately solved and made it unsolvable a little bit longer.
Speaker 0: I think seaside is the one that really made the game better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think after alchemy and all that.
Speaker 1: I don't think there's much more.
Speaker 0: Well, I might get this prosperity one because it's basically epic level and then that's it.
Speaker 1: That's gotta be it because they get that.
Speaker 1: this is my real beef with expansions right now.
Speaker 1: And I think it's weird because I think the board game industry in particular is following this path Which is kind of separate from the DLC problem We're seeing in.
Speaker 1: you know The fact that people will make a game that is clearly Unfinished and will clearly sell DLC.
Speaker 1: that would have just been part of the game had the game come out five years earlier Mmm, but board games are going this different tag.
Speaker 1: I Feel like any board game that is popular will have expansions no matter what?
Speaker 1: Modern board games like Dominion came out as soon as it succeeded.
Speaker 1: Expansions every fucking five minutes like up.
Speaker 1: Here's another one up.
Speaker 1: Here's another one.
Speaker 1: They just keep making them there.
Speaker 1: There doesn't seem to be a lot of thought to balance in these expansions.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean and even when there is Thought to balance it's this clearly the motivation is more money as opposed to actually making the game better.
Speaker 0: It's like some games need an expansion.
Speaker 0: Sometimes an expansion is nice, but some you know, like formula day, right?
Speaker 0: You're playing formula day.
Speaker 0: Why not get some more maps in there, right?
Speaker 0: It doesn't hurt, you know.
Speaker 0: And if you played a lot of formula day, you probably want some more maps.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a totally good expansion.
Speaker 0: power grid Same way when I get some more maps and more power plants make total sense, right?
Speaker 0: But Dominion it's like you add some cards.
Speaker 0: Okay, you add some more cards.
Speaker 0: All right, you add some more cards to do something different.
Speaker 0: All right Yeah, we're gonna add just you know The same exact cards again only even bigger
Speaker 1: because you can go down this road where if you expand too much You've basically made an entirely separate game that has this dumb dependency on owning some other game
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: which culminates in the box that includes the game and all the expansions for like 60 bucks
Speaker 0: You know, but that's that's how they roll.
Speaker 0: I think the other trouble is that video games do the same thing by the game of the year edition.
Speaker 0: that includes all the DLCs.
Speaker 0: That's my Borderlands.
Speaker 0: Like I came with a bunch of DLCs
Speaker 1: I think there's a big push when making a board game expansion at least to add a lot of unnecessary physical bits Because a lot of the good expansions in the old days you'd buy it for like 20 bucks and you get home and there's like One little deck of cards and like one token.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean look the carcass own expansion.
Speaker 0: Some of them are like just a tiny little box.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they're like two bucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 1: But like remember all the El Grande expansions back in the day the one that added a medic ooh, Maddie America or the Inquisition or the.
Speaker 0: yeah the there was like a doge.
Speaker 1: I remember I played the Inquisition before then because everyone knew the rules the rules that were very simple.
Speaker 1: You just made an extra card stuck it in there.
Speaker 1: people would use like raisins or pennies to be the Inquisitors.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean Sometimes an expansion is just really a rules modification and it's like why should I pay money for a rules modification?
Speaker 1: But that's the thing you pay to get.
Speaker 1: the physical accoutrement of the rules modification like the teeny expansion.
Speaker 1: The alternate board is there these four buildings.
Speaker 1: I have these little buildings I can use.
Speaker 1: I don't have to make them Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I mean like, you know Agricola get some sheep get some actual animals instead of cubes, you know Get some more cards.
Speaker 1: Is that really an expansion?
Speaker 0: Well, I mean there's a mod but they do have that there is an expansion for Agricola the farmers of the whatever I feel like we need it.
Speaker 1: I feel like we've already tapped out Agricola.
Speaker 0: So really you think so?
Speaker 1: I think with the base I could play a lot of Agricola that I could do.
Speaker 1: but I think we've The.
Speaker 1: everyone plays the solitaire perfectly and are mostly.
Speaker 0: I believe the thing is is that there's still Even though I know the solitaire perfectly like sometimes I play.
Speaker 0: it's like I'm trying to get on the schedule to get the babies.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it just doesn't happen.
Speaker 1: So obviously it's not every time it doesn't happen.
Speaker 1: I argue it is because other players have stepped up the game and they're playing left right or I'm where you need to be Possibly and I and that's the whole game.
Speaker 1: The real game of Agricola is really just I'm where you need to be or I left righted you And everything else is.
Speaker 0: sometimes the cards can get you ahead Yeah, but then you just you're playing solitaire.
Speaker 1: if you have the cards that'll get you ahead.
Speaker 1: you play the cards to get yourself.
Speaker 0: Mmm, I mean You know, sometimes you gotta you gotta be.
Speaker 0: sometimes depending on the cards you get Maybe there'll be a creative way to get ahead.
Speaker 0: You didn't think of or?
Speaker 1: yeah It's weird because it's.
Speaker 1: I feel like the game is solved But because it takes a lot of mental effort to figure out the solution to the new solitaire I get every time we play I never get bored with Agricola.
Speaker 1: I can still play it forever.
Speaker 1: I can still play Puerto Rico a million times even though I don't know the plantations change.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I'm actually making that many decisions when I play Puerto Rico most of the time anymore.
Speaker 0: The other thing is that a lot of board game Expansions these days are actually just like they'll be promotional things like a board game geek.
Speaker 0: I've gotten like four different Dominion cards for free.
Speaker 0: Well for the price of shipping, right?
Speaker 0: They're just giving them out promotionally and it's like that's.
Speaker 0: I think that's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: You know, imagine if it's just like.
Speaker 0: hey look, here's some more metal pieces from Monopoly So you don't have to be the dog or the boat.
Speaker 1: Well Nintendo does that with Pokemon?
Speaker 1: Hey, you want a new Pokemon.
Speaker 1: come to Toys R Us.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: That's exactly right.
Speaker 0: Same thing.
Speaker 1: Ah, why isn't there a Pokemon board game?
Speaker 0: I think there is is there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think I know this Pokemon Opoly, but I'm pretty sure there's other Pokemon.
Speaker 0: I have to look.
Speaker 1: I know this Pokemon card game.
Speaker 0: There's the Pokemon Clicks game.
Speaker 0: right that actually has the really good figures.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you know, the game is any good, but the figures are really nice.
Speaker 0: I don't know if that ever took off or kept going or died out or what.
Speaker 1: but can you think of any expansions?
Speaker 1: Because I remember it when I was trying to come up with examples of like from the catapult - I Couldn't name an expansion that was like mind-blowing to me.
Speaker 0: No, I don't think there is an expansion that's mind-blowingly awesome.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, I think the best expansions are the ones that just give you more goodness, right like El Grande was a good example.
Speaker 1: the expansions to El Grande because the game is still one of the most popular Board games ever like the fact that it's still in the top 10 of board game geek Despite the fact that no one fucking knows what it is and hardly anyone we ever meet has played it.
Speaker 1: It's still like an enduring game, but we played it enough to where the basic game.
Speaker 1: We know what to do.
Speaker 1: We know what's going on.
Speaker 0: I think that the the expansions that are that are really good are the more of the same ones.
Speaker 0: more like it's a video game.
Speaker 0: You beat it.
Speaker 0: Here's another level right?
Speaker 0: Like how can you kill?
Speaker 0: like half-life 2 episode, right?
Speaker 0: Is that written expansion?
Speaker 1: turn in taxes?
Speaker 1: Here's another board.
Speaker 1: So you have a new board to solve.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know it's like.
Speaker 0: it's just you like this.
Speaker 0: Here's more of it with no changes or not many changes You know like fallout 3 if you like it that Vegas thing.
Speaker 0: It's like here you get to.
Speaker 0: you have a whole new city to go explore, you know, if you like that action There you go.
Speaker 1: The reason for this is again that if you if you change in mod too much, you're not making an expansion You're making a mod final.
Speaker 1: doom was a sequel or an expansion to doom But like Bethesda was a mod of doom and s is kind of an expansion of half-life But really it's a mod.
Speaker 1: You're using the pieces of one game to play a totally different game.
Speaker 1: I think that's you know It's like if I use a teeny board and I make up like all these new rules and this totally different game That's a mod.
Speaker 1: That's not an expansion of T and E even if I package it and sell it.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's.
Speaker 0: it's really a tough distinction to think about.
Speaker 0: What's a mod?
Speaker 0: What's an expansion?
Speaker 0: What's a sequel?
Speaker 0: You know, there's a lot of blurry lines here Like, you know is half-life 2 episode 1 a mod or an expansion or a sequel, right?
Speaker 0: Expansion because it's I think the line is counter-strike a mod a sequel or an expansion mod or You know what?
Speaker 1: So far these are easy, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, so what makes it a mod as opposed to a completely separate game?
Speaker 1: Because it would because all the underlying bits were from another existing game.
Speaker 0: So because it's using the same technology as half-life.
Speaker 0: counter-strike is a is a?
Speaker 0: is a mod?
Speaker 1: I think so.
Speaker 0: So how about Jedi Knight 2 which uses the quake 3 tech?
Speaker 1: So I was about to say technology one layer above the engine.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh
Speaker 1: because it uses the assets of the game to not just the engine
Speaker 0: some of them but Counter-strike source doesn't really has complete
Speaker 1: counter-strike source I would argue is a sequel to counter-strike itself a mod of half-life,
Speaker 0: but is counter-strike source a mod of half-life 2 Using the source engine.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: How about left 4 dead?
Speaker 0: Is that a mod of half-life 2 which is using the source engine?
Speaker 0: Nope, but left 4 dead 2 is a sequel to left 4 dead 1.
Speaker 0: Yep, but is it a mod or an expansion?
Speaker 0: Yep How can you know, there's a lot of confusion going on there.
Speaker 1: But this at least explains not to get off on a tangent that I was about to go off on Why I couldn't come up with an example of a mind-blowing expansion?
Speaker 1: because anything that was ever mind-blowing always kind of fit into a separate category as like this is a totally different game.
Speaker 1: or This is a crazy house rule.
Speaker 1: It never was an expansion.
Speaker 0: Well, cuz I think that nothing that's an expansion or at least is considered an expansion or even a mod.
Speaker 0: I guess mods can be mind-blowing but nothing.
Speaker 0: that's Merely an expansion to be mind-blowing because not a significant portion of it will be original enough to blow your mind.
Speaker 0: It's all it's you know, like if portal had an expansion of new levels.
Speaker 0: It's like portal was the mind-blowing thing.
Speaker 0: What can you add to portal that will blow my mind?
Speaker 0: portal blows the mind to portals?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, okay great Thanks, daddy to PP.
Speaker 0: You know in order to blow someone's mind It needs to be something that's new and fresh.
Speaker 0: if it's something that they've seen before or that they're very familiar with you cannot blow The mind.
Speaker 0: it's impossible.
Speaker 0: So nothing if any of it is if it is so dissimilar from the thing it is Expanding such as to blow the mind.
Speaker 0: It would not be an expansion.
Speaker 0: It would be a new game or a mod or something completely new.
Speaker 0: All right Like if I found some way to use a monopoly board and dice and pieces to make this amazing game.
Speaker 0: It would be so dissimilar from monopoly that could you really call it a monopoly expansion?
Speaker 0: No, it would be a mod or a new game entirely.
Speaker 0: So, you know an expansion is pretty much just like you like something you but you didn't get enough of it or me?
Speaker 1: Well, there's three.
Speaker 1: I think there's multiple categories.
Speaker 1: An expansion is good if it gives you more of the same of something you already liked.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm if it fixes a problem with something that I think it's on see when they do that I mean it is an expansion.
Speaker 0: but Hot fix I think is bullshit that if they sell that as an expansion the game is broken and you're fixing it with your expansion.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, the fix should be free if your game is fucking broken.
Speaker 1: However, I've noticed a lot of games that like a not race for the galaxies, but cosmic encounters included this.
Speaker 1: there's one Card that was controversial so it was removed in the re-release of the game But they included it with a note saying here's the old busted card.
Speaker 1: if you really want to play with it Yeah, well, why not know what the car does?
Speaker 0: it's one card.
Speaker 1: It's the filch fair.
Speaker 1: won't flare while it's in your hand.
Speaker 1: You can just fucking cheat until someone calls you on it.
Speaker 1: You can just like grab extra car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that definitely sounds like the kind of thing that would normally be in an expansion and not in the normal set.
Speaker 1: Yep That's pretty cool that it was in the normal set and not an expand or they can fix something that isn't necessarily a bug But kind of a like.
Speaker 1: this game was good But there's a balance thing that if you fix this one thing would have been great Mmm, then I think it's okay to be an expansion because the game still was fun.
Speaker 1: But you wanted a little better and someone had a cuss a concise way of saying for five bucks.
Speaker 0: Here's better Yeah, but here's an example right that the roll through the ages which is pretty good But basically it wasn't really that good, but they made a better score sheet.
Speaker 0: that's free online But it's like fuck.
Speaker 0: I just bought this pad of score sheets, but it's free.
Speaker 0: It is free.
Speaker 0: if they charge you five bucks to download the PDF that we bullshit would be but they don't which is cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah They probably wanted to ship the game faster or something.
Speaker 0: I don't know, you know, and sometimes you know People are taking things that would have been a mod or expansion and you know Or but or would have been part of the game and splitting it off on purpose and sometimes they're not and it's like you got.
Speaker 0: I guess call them as they lie.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean if something is a Carcassonne catapult you should Point out that it is a Carcassonne catapult and don't actually play it, you know?
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: take for example, like it like a Street Fighter 4 right this tournament mode.
Speaker 0: It was a downloadable content But it was free.
Speaker 0: Right because that is something that should have been included in the game.
Speaker 0: if they try to charge money for tournament mode Fuck that shit.
Speaker 0: Fuck them up the ass Right, but they didn't but say Madden they would totally.
Speaker 0: if it was Madden they would have charged you for tournament mode.
Speaker 0: You know, they would.
Speaker 0: yeah, they would have those jerks.
Speaker 0: All right, you know how they roll.
Speaker 0: so You know, it's some things should be included something shouldn't.
Speaker 0: and you know, everyone's just trying to make monies.
Speaker 0: So fuck them.
Speaker 1: So but there is like I said, there's three.
Speaker 1: there's one final point where an expansion is very good.
Speaker 1: All right inside your mom.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brand-okay for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: Here's it's an it's an RFC.
Speaker 0: You ready?
Speaker 0: So here's we do.
Speaker 0: we forget the XLR input right what we do is we take The microphone right and on the back of the microphone.
Speaker 0: There's a vuvuzela and the Goes into.
Speaker 1: why don't you sell a vuvuzela with an XLR cable sticking out of it?
Speaker 0: Well, it has to be on the other end.
Speaker 1: So I got it.
Speaker 1: I'll make a MIDI vuvuzela.
Speaker 1: I only need to support one note.
Speaker 0: Why don't we just have like the megaphone on top of the microphone?
Speaker 0: So you're talking into a megaphone that goes into the microphone.