Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, November 23rd, 2010.
Speaker 1: I'm rim and this is geek night tonight Pac-man Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So Scott pop quiz was Davy Crockett a real person or not.
Speaker 1: I'm Leaning towards not because we just had a discussion about this and I feel the need to bring this up live Because he is in fact a real person.
Speaker 0: So Davy Crockett was real.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: When was he real?
Speaker 0: 18?
Speaker 0: What 17 what?
Speaker 1: Well through 18 what he lived a while.
Speaker 0: Okay, so he was not there for say the Civil War.
Speaker 1: Oh, he was there for the Alamo.
Speaker 0: Oh, but I thought that that was just like, you know, the album.
Speaker 0: I know the Alamo is definitely Was definitely real.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Pee-wee's bike was down there.
Speaker 0: I know the Alamo is real, but I did not think that there was a. you know The the Davy Crockett part of the tale was real.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was Davy Crockett king of the wild frontier.
Speaker 0: What was he actually like as opposed to?
Speaker 0: What he was like?
Speaker 1: in the fables there's a whole Wikipedia page about him.
Speaker 1: You can read it.
Speaker 0: Was he actually awesome or was he just you know fabled like it was?
Speaker 0: he's someone who was talked up.
Speaker 0: He seems fairly awesome to be honest But how much of that is like fake history?
Speaker 0: I want to read.
Speaker 0: I want to read like the Howard Zinn history of Davy Crockett.
Speaker 1: It's just because a minute before the show I was like blah blah blah Davy Crockett because we were looking for examples of like Politicians from the boonies and Scott's like, yeah, Davy Crockett wasn't real I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 0: I'm still not quite sure.
Speaker 1: is real, you know, you have a computer.
Speaker 1: you could just look up on Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: I couldn't have made an article this elaborate that quickly.
Speaker 0: someone else did.
Speaker 0: I mean There's gonna be a page about him whether he's real or not, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I bet there's a page on ball Bunyan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it probably says Paul Bunyan mythological, dude.
Speaker 0: But Paul Bunyan was real.
Speaker 0: Oh He's the blue cow was so the other weekend.
Speaker 1: Well, Robert Coo was in the city and he had a little meetup gathering that we went to and it was pretty goddamn awesome.
Speaker 1: I Will note for the listeners here that I removed a good 15 seconds of gum smack.
Speaker 0: So rim you owe me like 25 cents.
Speaker 1: Yeah captain.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna chew gum right before we record an audio show.
Speaker 0: Hey Needed to chew some good Tastes good.
Speaker 0: But anyway fake watermelon flavor.
Speaker 1: It was fun primarily because it was the first time I think in my entire life where I've spoken to Robert Coo in any Capacity other than in regards to like a specific issue at PAX Professional work like we got to deal with this thing.
Speaker 0: thing is normal guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Scott has a reputation for being a hater.
Speaker 0: now Yeah, everyone say whenever I meet anyone they always seem to think either I hate them or I hate everything.
Speaker 1: Do you ever wonder that maybe that is a defect of the womb?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Do you think I hate everyone?
Speaker 0: Everything.
Speaker 1: Well, you're a hater now.
Speaker 1: Okay, but the important part is the coup.
Speaker 1: man had a bag full of this game called banana grand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the game itself comes in a bag, but then he had a banana.
Speaker 0: He had a bag of bananas So he basically had like a whole bunch of copies of this game.
Speaker 1: He had a bag of bags of what are scrabble tiles and it's funny.
Speaker 1: We just did a stupid episode on word games boggle boggle and we didn't know about banana grams.
Speaker 0: If only we had known it would have been the perfect addition to that episode.
Speaker 1: Suffice it to say banana grams is basically real-time directly competitive Scrabble, but everyone has their own board and you're just fucking going for it.
Speaker 0: It's awesome.
Speaker 0: I just played.
Speaker 0: I just played my co-worker and I just I crushed him.
Speaker 0: I was like peel peel peel peel peel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's a nice intern.
Speaker 1: It's one of those games where it has its own terminology and you kind of get used to it Like I'm gonna peel.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, I'm a rotten banana.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's a bunch.
Speaker 0: It's all banana language and it actually works out, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you.
Speaker 0: you peel to you know, and there's a bunch and you when you win you say bananas and If you lose if you cheat and you have a word that's not a word rotten banana.
Speaker 1: Now the rules are not necessarily perfect.
Speaker 1: So I feel like after right, I think the rules are definitely perfect.
Speaker 1: They're not perfect in one regard.
Speaker 1: They do not explicitly state that you should agree to a dictionary ahead of time.
Speaker 0: It says it says use any available dictionary.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I have a French dictionary with me.
Speaker 1: All right, so I can use French words.
Speaker 0: now the nice life they're in there In an available dictionary, yes, I have.
Speaker 1: in fact, I have a dictionary of some functions that I wrote in Java.
Speaker 1: I have urban dictionary.
Speaker 1: I have the OED.
Speaker 1: I have dictionary.
Speaker 1: I just wrote.
Speaker 0: I think it's.
Speaker 0: it doesn't say use it.
Speaker 0: I think the language.
Speaker 0: use any available dictionary means that you pick one dictionary But it does not say so by suggest.
Speaker 0: that implies that you use one dictionary that is available.
Speaker 0: So whichever one it is that you pick is the only one.
Speaker 1: I pick one.
Speaker 1: Someone else picks another one.
Speaker 0: now, I know everyone has to use the one.
Speaker 1: That's what I was saying.
Speaker 1: that what?
Speaker 1: if you want to play this game and your friends are assholes aka they're like us you have to agree to a dictionary ahead of time.
Speaker 1: you get everyone to say okay and Don't even try to challenge words mid game.
Speaker 1: It just doesn't work.
Speaker 0: just while the rules say that you shouldn't they?
Speaker 0: basically the way it works is you don't?
Speaker 0: you know, You can play the whole game and it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: You know You don't check anyone's words during the game and at the end of the game when someone says they've won You stop and you see if they've actually won and if they haven't they get the ultimate penalty.
Speaker 1: So it's a penalty for not having a like.
Speaker 1: a full set of actual words at the end of the game is basically You lose and you're done and you have no chance of winning.
Speaker 0: You're the rotten banana Yeah And so it's like instead of slightly punishing you along the way for putting out a bad word like Scrabble?
Speaker 0: does they just give you The ultimate punishment for having any words at all that are wrong at the very end?
Speaker 0: and that is you lose Which is fairly elegant because otherwise if there were a challenge It would slow down the whole game and you had in the middle of the game You'd have time to sit there and think which would be unfair.
Speaker 0: In fact, I would start where speed matters.
Speaker 1: I would start challenging people just to get the time.
Speaker 1: if I needed it.
Speaker 1: Like I got a new cue and I got to do something with it.
Speaker 1: I just feel like I challenge everyone's goddamn words.
Speaker 0: I think though it would be pretty cool to play the game Digitally, right and you know, you could.
Speaker 0: there's two different ways to make it happen digitally.
Speaker 0: Obviously you could just play it, you know straight up with like iPads or on computers And then it would just put big red blocks around any words that were invalid, you know.
Speaker 0: So you would know in real time if your words are wrong and no one would ever get anything wrong.
Speaker 1: As a side this would be a good candidate for a game to get ported to Xbox Live.
Speaker 0: Well, here's right.
Speaker 0: What I think they really want to do is take like the Kinect or something or the Sony eye camera Right and have it look at a table full of tiles Right and then it would look at the words and it could.
Speaker 0: basically if you had some sort of light Mechanism it could shine lights on so you could still play with the tiles on a table off camera.
Speaker 1: I have all the tiles I need to make any word I want and I just swap them in the whole game and cheat.
Speaker 0: I see you're cheating by having a second set of banana grams tiles.
Speaker 1: You really think that wouldn't happen.
Speaker 0: All right, but that's just that's at least.
Speaker 0: that's not a flaw in the game though, that's you cheating.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at the same time though, if you're gonna play a game online where the rules are only enforced by not saying online I'm saying just as an aid to play in person.
Speaker 0: Oh, that'd be cool.
Speaker 0: You know, that'd be cool.
Speaker 1: Anyway, banana grams is not only awesome, but it's going to be like the hot sensation at PAX East.
Speaker 0: It's definitely coming up big mark my words.
Speaker 1: A lot of people are gonna be playing this game.
Speaker 0: I think it's just gonna.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be like the next apples to apples, right right now You can get apples to apples in like the Duane Reade.
Speaker 0: You're gonna see banana banana grams in the Duane Reade right next to the Scrabble and monopoly Within you know six months or so.
Speaker 1: a word of warning because ku told us like what this game was all about.
Speaker 1: So we looked online.
Speaker 1: they make all these other games like apple grams and such and you know what.
Speaker 0: ignore that shit.
Speaker 1: They all suck.
Speaker 0: only banana grams that get the banana.
Speaker 0: ignore all other fruits except apples.
Speaker 0: to apples Which is I don't think it's the same company.
Speaker 1: There's no way.
Speaker 0: but it is weird.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of fruit themed games.
Speaker 0: I think we should wait.
Speaker 1: How is that weird?
Speaker 1: Why is fruit?
Speaker 0: I mean eventually you have run Renaissance Europe war or Fantasyland with dragons and can I get trains trains trains and fruit fruit?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's fine I think.
Speaker 1: the next stop I note there is precedent because as you may recall Arms you may recall and I mock hair or D mock governments.
Speaker 1: You can bet on the square tomatoes.
Speaker 0: We need the the vegetable game.
Speaker 1: Oh, there was that game for the NES.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: What was it called?
Speaker 1: You were basically a cucumber and it was like shadow gate and you went around.
Speaker 1: you met Percy the parched persimmon and it was like a man.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: It was like a puzzle-solving Crazy ass game.
Speaker 0: It was princess tomato that maybe that was it.
Speaker 0: That was a side-scrolling.
Speaker 1: now, then this is a different game I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: I gotta I gotta figure out what this game was.
Speaker 0: So, yeah banana grams, all right, so gaming news Gaming news is getting kind of light because they were talking about.
Speaker 1: there's tons of stuff to talk about.
Speaker 0: Oh, it seems like there was a bunch of holiday release action.
Speaker 0: And now it's just like alright everyone go spend your goddamn money, right?
Speaker 0: And there's no real action gonna happen until after the holidays.
Speaker 0: and there's new releases again, you know.
Speaker 0: because if you were gonna release a holiday game, it better be out now because Black Friday is Three days.
Speaker 0: So all the holiday games are out.
Speaker 0: today was Tuesday the game release day.
Speaker 0: So instead of talking about game release I could talk about something else that happens every year, right?
Speaker 0: Maybe we'll move it to the meta moment for the the remainder of the year, but the child's play has Rebegun, ah child's play.
Speaker 1: I gotta go send some DS's or something.
Speaker 0: Empty your wallets for the children's Empty?
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: Banana grams.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm gonna send two copies of banana.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna send a banana grams to every hospital and all the child's play Every hospital, that's not that much money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know how many hospitals they have now.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's true.
Speaker 0: They might have had a ton.
Speaker 0: I might not be able to afford it.
Speaker 0: So everybody send one banana grams to the children's hospital.
Speaker 1: Let's make this a thing.
Speaker 1: Let me hear you Let's make banana grams the gift.
Speaker 0: The thing is the other bet the bad games apple grams.
Speaker 0: and when you know all those Yeah, they are better for they're better for the children's even though you might not like them, right?
Speaker 1: So also, you know sentiment sentiment apples to apples.
Speaker 0: then all the children's will play together.
Speaker 1: banana grams better for the smarter children's Definitely.
Speaker 0: There's some other good game.
Speaker 0: You could send a settlers to the hospital.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: I'm sure there's like a some teenage kid there who's like, oh man settlers in the hospital.
Speaker 1: That's about you realize that the blows mine the president here.
Speaker 1: Is that some sad kid is gonna get Twilight struggle?
Speaker 0: Don't send Twilight struggle to the hospital.
Speaker 0: They actually have Amazon wish list.
Speaker 0: You just pick it off the list and you know, so there you go.
Speaker 1: So in non child helping news, in fact, perhaps the opposite of this child killing news.
Speaker 1: We haven't talked much about the fact that farm Ville is getting a city Ville.
Speaker 0: that is basically fake Sim City But there's already like 20 farm Ville's right?
Speaker 0: There's like there's a there's the farm and there's a city.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a frontier.
Speaker 1: this stuff is getting off the home.
Speaker 0: There's a fantasy, you know, they got every theme.
Speaker 0: They got it covered.
Speaker 1: what I do want to talk about because I realized something recently that scares me is the civilization network Which is basically Civ 5 came out and is very popular even though multiplayer is broken and I hate you guys.
Speaker 1: on that aside Sit the civilization network is basically let's take Civ 5 and mash it up with farm Ville and Facebook and make it shitty.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be terrible.
Speaker 0: They're basically slapping a Civ theme on a crappy.
Speaker 0: You remember that there was that game We played.
Speaker 0: what was that one?
Speaker 0: It was like all.
Speaker 0: you had a city and they're all the different buildings in it and all you did was wait until you you For the time to elapse and then you upgraded a building Tim Tower.
Speaker 0: No, remember everyone was playing it for like a day or two and they were like, oh fuck this.
Speaker 1: There was that one where we made Greek city-states.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was the one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's basically what this is gonna be.
Speaker 1: what amazes me though.
Speaker 1: And here's the scary part.
Speaker 1: So it's a Facebook whatever game.
Speaker 1: apparently The guy who designed Civ 2 and Alpha Centauri Brian Reynolds.
Speaker 1: He works for Zynga.
Speaker 0: now Mmm, how about that?
Speaker 1: and my worry is that it's weird because I don't consider social Well what we call social games to be in any way like in competition with actual games like they're.
Speaker 1: they're not even gay They're a different class of entertainment.
Speaker 1: I don't know what to call it yet, but it kind of bothers me that that's what we're calling social games.
Speaker 1: I mean to me a social game is like mafia.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or any Mario game on any game that is multiplayer is thereby social?
Speaker 1: I would argue not multiplayer games that don't involve player interaction.
Speaker 1: They can be social but the social is not an obligatory component of them.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing right is it's tough?
Speaker 0: because you think about something like a race Right, and it's like there's some races where it's just go as fast as you can But then you look at something like roll to the ages which appears to have no interaction But you can roll the pestilence and poison everybody, right?
Speaker 0: So there is a little bit, you know or like, you know NASCAR you think everyone's just racing But or f1 everyone's just racing, but you can crash into somebody.
Speaker 1: So what worries me here?
Speaker 1: the reasons.
Speaker 1: I mean, we don't have any details about this game yet.
Speaker 1: So Theoretically, it could be awesome.
Speaker 1: It could just be like it's not it's not gonna be.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be less complicated And less good than Civ Rev there.
Speaker 0: So that's guaranteed.
Speaker 1: Well Civ Rev was basically.
Speaker 1: baby wants to play Civ the game.
Speaker 0: Yes, this is gonna be less than that, which means it's gonna be.
Speaker 0: but you know, really small baby wants to play Civ.
Speaker 1: There was a non-zero chance that maybe this was going to be a good game in some way.
Speaker 1: maybe they're going to take advantage of the social nature of Facebook to make like 40 person like everyone's got a civilization awesome.
Speaker 1: Here are the statements that make me believe that is the opposite of the truth.
Speaker 1: one.
Speaker 1: It is quote a fully persistent environment.
Speaker 0: They turn down down.
Speaker 1: So that means that there's no way it's actually a competitive game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because then you know, I started first.
Speaker 1: my Civ has nukes you have sticks Yep, and two free to play.
Speaker 1: Yep free to play is what DDO did.
Speaker 1: It's what every like Korean model MMO is doing.
Speaker 0: my only hope right.
Speaker 0: and also a Facebook.
Speaker 0: I think this is also the hope of say, you know, the the people working on it, right?
Speaker 0: Is that you know if they can?
Speaker 0: right now, let's say you're a Farmville person, right?
Speaker 0: So they get all these people to play Farmville and some people just farm it up a little bit.
Speaker 0: But some people they farm it up a lot.
Speaker 0: right if there was a Farmville that was actually hardcore, right?
Speaker 1: If it wasn't necessarily good by our standards But if it were not this you're not graduating from Farmville to anything.
Speaker 0: you graduate from Farmville to more Farmville Mate, they're all eventually to death.
Speaker 0: I. the fact that this game is free tells me that they're hoping that they can get these people who are not Gamers right who have no interest in games to graduate from baby Civ, right?
Speaker 0: I think this is also why they made Civ Rev.
Speaker 0: They want people to graduate from that Civ up to the bigger Civ and Because it's.
Speaker 0: you know If it's too difficult to make a game with a with a learning curve where you can start easy and get harder as you go On the game, you know, it's Civ.
Speaker 0: it throws a lot at you right from the get-go.
Speaker 0: pick a science What are you gonna build in your city?
Speaker 0: Where are you gonna move?
Speaker 1: your warrior frames already got spearmen around your city, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it throws a lot of you right from turn one and even though turn one is a lot simpler than later turns It's still a lot.
Speaker 0: if you've never played games before right?
Speaker 0: So instead of making Civ scale up from you know, baby Civ up in the same game They're trying to make a separate game and you can graduate up to the big boy game.
Speaker 0: now what and that might work.
Speaker 0: I think that there are some people who might get hooked on the baby Civ and then they're gonna Advertise the advertised for the real Civ in the baby Civ and people graduate.
Speaker 1: Well, it's tough to say because it really depends on how they design the game.
Speaker 1: the crux of it is whether or not it is Actually a game because if it is not a game at all Then this is kind of a false path where it's going to take people from things that aren't games to something that isn't a game that has the same name as something that is a game and I think that's a Less easy jump to make through the real game versus.
Speaker 1: if this is a game even if it's a very easy game If there's actually something going on, that is my obi-wan that this game is not great But it has some sort of decision-making that actually matters and has some way to fail.
Speaker 0: I think that what's gonna happen right is Even more likely is people will play the baby Civ and they'll graduate and then they won't like the big boy But they might like Civ revolutions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Civ Rev is basically they did sort of dead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they maybe they'll bring it back I don't think.
Speaker 1: maybe they'll put it on Facebook and you have to pay for it.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know what's gonna have to.
Speaker 0: five is gonna be around for a while.
Speaker 1: These games usually last a few years Yeah, and they're it's sort of a perpetual seller too Even though I'm basically not playing any more Civ 5 until I have pit boss and can play by mail.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that that's they definitely said that's it come in in the next big patch is the the pit boss and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: So but anyway things of the day daddy two things of the day.
Speaker 1: Well, you can't do that cuz I got to use a normal one and I think this is really cool.
Speaker 1: You might have seen it on Kotaku, but it's a cute little song that tells you how to draw Mario and it works.
Speaker 1: Okay, I tried to draw Mario and I got almost Mario.
Speaker 1: Mmm, interesting, but the song is stuck in my head.
Speaker 1: So I figured she'd be stuck in your head too much like GGG.
Speaker 1: you get GGG stuck in your head You know, but I got this Mario song stuck in my head.
Speaker 0: You watch the GGG.
Speaker 1: I yes once and I've never watched it again.
Speaker 0: Why don't you watch it again?
Speaker 1: Cuz I don't want to get it stuck in my head, but the girls are real hot.
Speaker 1: I've still got the Tetris song stuck in my head.
Speaker 1: I'm good with that.
Speaker 1: Okay Every day at work.
Speaker 0: I'm sitting there like Anyway, because that's the rings true.
Speaker 1: So my other thing is the day.
Speaker 1: The reason I give to is that you may not want to click on the second one.
Speaker 1: This is disturbing But it's not disturbing because of any graphic ness or sex or like ultra violence or any of the things you'd expect.
Speaker 1: It's disturbing in a Jesus Christ kind of way.
Speaker 1: a bunch of people in the forum.
Speaker 1: We're talking about flash games and I saw someone say like oh man I played covetous and I was like covetous little flash game.
Speaker 1: All right, whatever.
Speaker 1: I'm game I'll play it and I'm about to go to bed.
Speaker 1: I sit down.
Speaker 1: I played this little flash game.
Speaker 1: It's like a minute long Jesus fucking Christ.
Speaker 0: It's weird.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's it's just you got to admit it is disturbing.
Speaker 1: It is not scary, but it is disturbing.
Speaker 0: I wasn't really disturbed.
Speaker 0: I was just like a weird internet game and it has this interest.
Speaker 1: It's an idea where you have a game where ostensibly your utility is to win the game.
Speaker 1: So the game presents you with this very simple challenge You can't lose at this game and yet going through the challenge will make something horrible happen But yet you're obligated to go through it as the player which makes an almost more visceral Response.
Speaker 1: that had a similar thing been made as an animation or a movie.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: it's much like passage.
Speaker 1: It's proof that games are art on a fundamental level.
Speaker 1: for anyone who's stupid enough not to believe that You've been too much high praise in this little crappy flesh And also our friend Conrad.
Speaker 1: he was working late.
Speaker 1: So he was like, what's that creepy flash gave you mentioned?
Speaker 1: I'm like covetous.
Speaker 1: and two minutes later.
Speaker 1: He messaged me with the exact words Jesus fucking Christ.
Speaker 0: Okay So anyway, you know holidays are coming right.
Speaker 0: black Friday is Friday.
Speaker 0: this Friday So I I was thinking hey, we should have a geek night's gift guide, but there's a problem with that.
Speaker 0: That would require effort on our part to make a gift guide.
Speaker 0: so well, I don't want anything me either.
Speaker 1: I mean things.
Speaker 1: I want a Miata a beach house a garage to put it in.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, keep the car, right?
Speaker 0: But apparently right boing-boing.
Speaker 0: put up a gift guide and the boing-boing gift guide is 90% identical to the geek.
Speaker 0: That's gift guide or what the geek nights gift guide would be gig nights gift guide.
Speaker 0: It includes such items as an Arduino a big-ass tub of Lego you know a copy of Minecraft who you know?
Speaker 0: a Stylophone which is basically a musical Synthesizing device with a little stylus right?
Speaker 0: No banana grams banana grams Remote control helicopter, you know, though I get and something I did not know existed that is relevant to this episode Which is pac-man moleskine, there's a special limited edition pac-man moleskine.
Speaker 1: are the pages different or just the outside?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think just the outside.
Speaker 1: I just put a sticker of pac-man on.
Speaker 0: my moleskine idea comes with some pac-man stickers.
Speaker 1: All right, not that bad.
Speaker 0: You know it.
Speaker 0: look at it.
Speaker 0: It's actually pretty vent, you know It's got a lot of pac-man styling going on.
Speaker 0: It's not it's not light on the pac-man.
Speaker 0: It's got a lot of fruits man.
Speaker 0: What's are the fruits?
Speaker 0: Oh Nanograms pac-man fruits.
Speaker 1: So before we get into the real stuff, you know, we got the meta moment Which we've forgotten off non lately, you know There's one thing I've always wanted to include in the meta moment that I keep forgetting to include.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that is corrections of things we get wrong.
Speaker 1: We never get anything or how we get things wrong.
Speaker 0: pretty much all the guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we never remember.
Speaker 0: I want to from now on if we get something wrong Remind us, you know two weeks afterwards because if it's I get something wrong on a Tuesday I want to correct it the next Tuesday episode.
Speaker 0: So remind us of the corrections to put in the meta moment.
Speaker 0: if we when if what not when if when?
Speaker 0: We get things wrong.
Speaker 1: You might have to remind us repeatedly because we are also very forgetful.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's like.
Speaker 0: I'll remember I got it wrong, but I'll forget to put it in the meta moment.
Speaker 0: So That's meta.
Speaker 0: Number one meta.
Speaker 0: number two mag Fast.
Speaker 1: we're gonna be at mag fest.
Speaker 1: We're part of the mag nine.
Speaker 1: We're doing one panel and we're sitting out a bunch of other panels.
Speaker 1: The rest of the time you will find me halfway to completely ragingly drunk wandering around.
Speaker 0: being awesome You'll find me playing fidget games and board games.
Speaker 1: We'll likely be at anime Boston.
Speaker 1: We will definitely be at PAX East doing tours to three panels.
Speaker 1: give or take.
Speaker 0: we'll say There's a nerd NYC recess.
Speaker 0: That's the same weekend as mag fest.
Speaker 0: So we're not going to that.
Speaker 1: No, we're not going to that.
Speaker 0: And Thanksgiving send me your cornucopias and nobody has sent me a cornucopia.
Speaker 1: Last but not least the book club look was Max Brooks World War Z. We're done with it.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do the show real soon.
Speaker 1: So if you haven't read it yet, hurry up read.
Speaker 0: I got.
Speaker 0: I still have to read it.
Speaker 0: What sucks?
Speaker 0: I'm still only a third of the way through.
Speaker 1: If you haven't read it by now you're not gonna like my review.
Speaker 0: You know, how can anyone believe that our review is fair and unbiased?
Speaker 1: This book until I read it?
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, anyway Nobody's gonna believe you if you act that way.
Speaker 1: act what way?
Speaker 0: being honest about what I believe no being all honest It gives it an impression of prejudice.
Speaker 0: ask anybody by being completely honest.
Speaker 1: So you're saying I'm not being honest.
Speaker 1: I secretly like this god-awful book.
Speaker 1: No You're not denying that the book is god-awful.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying either way.
Speaker 0: What I'm saying is that people got off.
Speaker 0: people will believe that you were knocking it before trying But I read it a while ago.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying that you it's gonna be difficult to convince people otherwise In fact, so what if I waited until the show and then said the same thing that it was awful?
Speaker 0: He will believe it.
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: I think they would.
Speaker 1: I think anyone who likes these zombie books is gonna hate us No matter what after that review and we'll see.
Speaker 1: So pac-man.
Speaker 0: Oh We had another more meta though, there's too much meta.
Speaker 0: what other meta do we have that Just in time for Black Friday for all your shopping needs despite the lack of a geek night's gift guide.
Speaker 1: All right The geek night store went live as of Sunday and no one noticed.
Speaker 0: one person just noticed and they were complaining that we don't ship To Canada.
Speaker 0: Can we do we ship to Canada?
Speaker 1: I ship to wherever Google will ship if Google won't ship to you.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry No, well, how can we fix that?
Speaker 0: We'll look into it.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I set it up to go to anywhere that Google check out.
Speaker 1: We'll let it go.
Speaker 1: All right Maybe because I only set up USPS as a thing because that would be USPS ships to Canada.
Speaker 1: Yes I don't know.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, if you want a geek nice t-shirt we currently only have one t-shirt design.
Speaker 1: It's the old one.
Speaker 1: Once we sell out.
Speaker 1: We'll have to order more.
Speaker 0: We're gonna have to order more.
Speaker 0: Did you actually put in like the inventory in there?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay, so it will sell out when it cares about the inside stuff We've got.
Speaker 0: I just want to make sure that it'll say sold out when it's sold out.
Speaker 0: Yeah taking orders and we don't have anymore.
Speaker 1: No, it all works.
Speaker 1: I don't the listeners don't care about all the back-end stuff.
Speaker 1: I even put this in the meta.
Speaker 0: I just want to make sure that you know, we don't get like a thousand orders in for sure It's we don't have and then we're gonna get a thousand orders.
Speaker 1: It could happen.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling there are about two people are gonna order a t-shirt in the next few weeks.
Speaker 1: You know also I point out you could have just asked me that any time.
Speaker 0: I You know for people to see what the you know to make sure that they're not waiting.
Speaker 0: if people might you know Think that they're gonna be waiting for a long time.
Speaker 0: if that we don't have enough shirts.
Speaker 0: okay, that's For their benefit, you know, so pac-man championship edition DX all pac-mans I want to do.
Speaker 0: if we haven't done any show on any pac-mans I want to talk about all pac-mans but the reason that we came up with the idea to talk about pac-mans is because the pac-man championship edition DX which is The awesome.
Speaker 1: I don't however want to bother talking about the history of pac-man or anything.
Speaker 1: I just want to talk about pac-man is games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we don't need.
Speaker 0: you can look at the history of pac-man and only canonical real pac-man games.
Speaker 1: I don't want to talk about pac-man jr.
Speaker 0: But that's a real pac-man game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not a good game.
Speaker 0: How about pac-man world - I?
Speaker 1: Never played that pac-man world - it's right over there.
Speaker 0: You have a copy of it on your shelf.
Speaker 1: How the fuck did that get there?
Speaker 1: Ah There it is, oh my god That is perhaps the worst game I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: It's not that fits not.
Speaker 1: Custer's revenge is at least a game.
Speaker 0: I know this is worse games.
Speaker 0: How is it compared to ET?
Speaker 1: You know what ET not that bad.
Speaker 0: Oh, I see you come around on that one.
Speaker 1: ET is the worst game.
Speaker 0: I've beaten Anyway, so pac-man Champion edition DX right is basically the idea here as they wanted to make a pac-man game for the 360 But they wanted it to be like, you know, like big, you know and have championship miss.
Speaker 0: And if they just went with regular old pat, you know, they had to come up with some spin on pac-man.
Speaker 0: so the spin they came up with is have a fucking ton of ghosts.
Speaker 0: and The thing with having a ton of ghosts is that the old maps don't work.
Speaker 0: So they came up with all new maps.
Speaker 1: also the old like fundamental game mechanics don't work.
Speaker 1: that well.
Speaker 0: No, I mean the original pac-man is mostly once you've figured it out, you know Once you know how to avoid the ghosts and you know how to clear the board.
Speaker 0: It just gets faster.
Speaker 0: So your reflexes need to improve but it was hurt.
Speaker 1: the power pills last less laws.
Speaker 0: power pills last less long.
Speaker 0: so you need to be more accurate in getting the ghosts right next to you and you get the power pill.
Speaker 0: and Other than that though.
Speaker 0: Once you've maxed the game out.
Speaker 0: you've maxed it out, right?
Speaker 0: At that point once it's maxed out you just it's just endurance.
Speaker 1: like as a kid in the Atari I'd play mrs.
Speaker 1: Pac-man all the goddamn time.
Speaker 1: 7800. so it was a real pac-man.
Speaker 1: It wasn't like that abortion.
Speaker 1: That was the.
Speaker 1: you know, hundred pac-man.
Speaker 0: You know, the first game system ever had was 2,600 and the first video games ever played were 2,600. so I actually Was sadly thought that that 2,600 pac-man was the pac-man.
Speaker 1: God Scott I never knew for
Speaker 0: a long time and really
Speaker 1: sad
Speaker 0: when I was three That was like the only game I played and I didn't even I like I had such a poor Understanding when I was that young that like I would just start the game and I would set it on like level 8 because I Was I didn't realize I would just start at level 1. just you know, cuz you could pick any level to start at.
Speaker 0: and I Didn't realize like I didn't fully comprehend much like I didn't fully comprehend drawing in the lines Right that I was supposed to get all the dots Like it wasn't all there in the early days
Speaker 1: Even when I was older like when I was eight or nine I would play games not necessarily pac-man but more complex games Where I realized looking back I wasn't good at them because I wasn't actually trying to win.
Speaker 1: I was just kind of like dicking around in these games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't you know, so this is when I was like three or four, right?
Speaker 0: I was real little.
Speaker 0: not fully get in the pac-man But I was playing.
Speaker 1: but my trouble with miss pac-man and then pac-man in the arcade and everything was that very rarely Would I die like me and not having the skill to continue going would not stop me.
Speaker 1: What would stop me is that it's been 45 goddamn minutes and I'm bored.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean, you know, that's why I prefer games like say Galaga where you go and die It's like you're gonna die.
Speaker 1: Actually, I'm not impressed much with the twin galaxies records or any of that sort of stuff and this is why pac-man fundamentally wouldn't have worked as a modern game because Basically the skill cap is actually other than going for endurance and perfection Relatively low and these ultra high scores are just a matter of patience
Speaker 0: and practice.
Speaker 1: patience in practice But mostly patience and endurance of just being willing to sit there forever.
Speaker 0: I once played Dig Dug for like three hours and then I just got sick of it and turn it on Not like kaboom right where it just gets faster faster faster faster, and you're gonna you're gonna lose at some point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're really good max it out and then it does and then you can just like max out the score completely.
Speaker 1: I just never got that good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean look at for the perfect example of endurance, right?
Speaker 0: Look at the guy who was the high score for asteroids.
Speaker 0: he had his own asteroids machine and he videotaped himself which is a legitimate way of getting a twin galaxies score and he basically Played so well that he would get a zillion extra lives and then he would go to the bathroom.
Speaker 0: He'd eat lunch, you know and the game would just sit there.
Speaker 0: and in asteroids You don't die that often because the asteroids move kind of slow.
Speaker 0: So if you just beat a level and then you sit still in the middle there, you know You might get hit a couple times, but if you just got ten lives You're not gonna lose them all, you know.
Speaker 0: And this guy would get enough lives to go off of the board because that's how the scoring mechanism works.
Speaker 0: you know you you can get just tons and tons of extra lives and then he would just come back when he was ready and Rack up a zillion more extra lives in a zillion more points and then go about his daily business.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's.
Speaker 1: it's basically a fundamental design flaw of any competitive game.
Speaker 1: where you can reach a point We're like all players are relatively equal and it comes down to something like endurance or time Especially in video games when there's like there's nothing to differentiate the high-level players quickly Yeah, or like you can have the same problem as pitfall.
Speaker 0: right where basically pitfall you finish it you get all the treasures.
Speaker 0: So people basically end up playing, you know a perfect or near-perfect pitfall and then that's it.
Speaker 0: so there's like X number of guys in the world who can pretty much beat pitfall almost or completely perfectly and There's no way to differentiate between them because they all hit max at the game.
Speaker 1: I mean the only way to do it is whoever did it first.
Speaker 0: Yes, however Pac-man championship edition DX has solved this problem.
Speaker 0: They've taken the basic mechanics of pac-man.
Speaker 0: eat all the dots power pills let you eat ghosts ghosts.
Speaker 0: Try to chase pac-man.
Speaker 0: The bombs are new.
Speaker 0: you push a bomb and all the ghosts go back to the middle.
Speaker 0: But you only have a limited number of them.
Speaker 1: I found that I have infinite of them because I get them so frequently.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, it depends like if you're doing a time trial mode, which is the mode I actually like the most You only get so many bombs and you're probably not in the way.
Speaker 0: to get more bombs is to eat ghosts that are carrying them right, so You're not likely to eat a lot of ghosts because that takes time away.
Speaker 1: Yeah Now I play an expert all the time now, so you only get three bombs on expert.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, the way the game works basically is each level each course has sort of a pattern to it You know and some of them the patterns sort of easy and obvious Like in the first course is challenge two.
Speaker 0: I don't know why challenge two is the first course and challenge one is harder, but whatever don't you recognize?
Speaker 1: challenge one?
Speaker 1: Okay, never mind anyway anyway.
Speaker 0: But Challenge two right.
Speaker 0: you just basically go to where the fruit is and then follow the dots go to and then a fruit appears And you go for that fruit and you follow the dots and that's the pattern.
Speaker 0: But saying challenge one it's much more difficult to follow the plus even the simple pattern.
Speaker 1: This is a brilliance.
Speaker 1: All right, you're following the pattern you're doing good you cock up once and suddenly it's gay.
Speaker 1: You're all over the place now running from ghosts hitting bombs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got to get back in that pattern.
Speaker 0: Also, even when the pattern is obvious, right?
Speaker 0: It's like all follow this pattern.
Speaker 0: There's also the mechanic of waking up the ghost, right?
Speaker 0: There's sleeping ghosts around the map and if you go near them They wake up and they start they join this chain gang of ghosts that is chasing you down Which is the crux of the game.
Speaker 1: This is a game and the first time I played it I'm like, this is fun.
Speaker 1: This is fun.
Speaker 1: And then suddenly I was like wait a minute if I get a power pill and then I ate like 200 ghosts.
Speaker 0: I think it actually maxes out because I've reached a point where I had a huge chain of ghosts and I would wake up more ghosts from their sleep And they would just sort of fly off the screen.
Speaker 0: I was watching them and I was like, oh they're not even joining the pack because this pack is so big.
Speaker 1: Well one it depends on like if you're when you grab fruit and more importantly are you doing the ghost challenge?
Speaker 1: You're just in the normal game.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: It's like cuz.
Speaker 0: there's different modes, right and there's the.
Speaker 0: there's the score mode Which is play for X minutes.
Speaker 0: get the highest score.
Speaker 1: you can brilliant the fact that it's minutes as opposed to lives Yep, and because that makes this game right you do direct competition course.
Speaker 0: You do have lives.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you do but it's much better for come for competitive purposes.
Speaker 0: get the most points You can in five minutes get the most points You can attend men a tournament in.
Speaker 1: this is basically like what the wizard should have been Yep, then this ghost combo mode.
Speaker 0: The only thing that matters is how many?
Speaker 0: what's your biggest ghost combo?
Speaker 0: and that's it?
Speaker 0: It gives you like ten minutes, but you basically hit select and end as soon as you've gotten your big combo Yep, and then There's time trial mode Which is the mode I like and that is get X fruits as fast as you can.
Speaker 1: and there's ten.
Speaker 1: It's actually really cool how it does it because you have to do like ten courses of varying difficulty And then your aggregate times are what puts you in the leaderboard?
Speaker 0: Yeah And so and the thing is it adds up right your.
Speaker 0: all these different.
Speaker 0: every course has all these different modes.
Speaker 0: Some of the courses of different modes like the half-track course only has time trial modes.
Speaker 0: It doesn't have any score modes.
Speaker 1: My favorite one so far was the dungeon because it changes Constantly, I like the dungeon.
Speaker 0: I like the half-track.
Speaker 0: I like the highway.
Speaker 0: I think the highway is the best designed one.
Speaker 0: Highway is the most fun because It lets you go off the edge and come around the other side a lot.
Speaker 0: Yep But you know the.
Speaker 0: the thing is I totally lost it.
Speaker 0: All right It adds up your scores on your time trials and your high score mode and everything together and it looks at your world Ranking of all the players playing this game.
Speaker 0: This is pretty much real time.
Speaker 1: like every time I log in it shows you've dropped X number and I gotta like get better scores To get up to.
Speaker 0: so you're competing against everyone in the world who's also playing this game, which is apparently is right now.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's like 30,000 people.
Speaker 0: It depends tens of thousands of people, right?
Speaker 0: So depending on which mode like you can see like oh only like a few thousand people have actually played the darkness mode Time trial all the way through, you know
Speaker 1: My overall worldwide ranking like as of the last time I checked which was last night because it gives you the overall Ranking aggregate of everything you've done is like 1002 out of 28,000.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm in the hundreds I think somewhere and I'm basically individual ones.
Speaker 1: I'm all over the place some of them.
Speaker 1: I'm in the double digits.
Speaker 0: Yeah, some of them I'm no good and some of them I'm like insanely good.
Speaker 1: So it's amazing playing cuz.
Speaker 1: sometimes I'll do a round I think I did really badly and then my rank is way way low or well way high I guess or I'll do one.
Speaker 1: I think I was doing awesome that I look and I'm like at the bottom of the pack.
Speaker 1: I'm like what.
Speaker 0: what I really like is how the game really is true to its name of Championship Edition.
Speaker 0: right a lot of games have the word Championship Edition, but this one really is Championship Edition, for example Let's say you do a time trial in 30 seconds and you do the time trick.
Speaker 0: You want to try it again to see if you can beat your time it as when you get to 20 seconds It starts counting down 10 9 8 like there is no reason to play unless you are going to beat your previous score.
Speaker 0: You know, it's pretty much you.
Speaker 0: only the game is entirely focused on get the high score improve improve improve do better.
Speaker 0: You know get become the best in the world get an s-rank and everything go go go.
Speaker 0: There is that is the only focus of this game.
Speaker 1: This game has to be at some point of the Omega thon because it's too perfect for that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I only wish there was some sort of multiplayer or even co-op mode.
Speaker 0: There's two of you working together.
Speaker 0: get the highest score as a team.
Speaker 0: That would be off the hook.
Speaker 1: Well, we do have the other pac-man game that was delayed.
Speaker 1: that's coming out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there is a game I saw at PAX that is coming out eventually or at least it's a prototype or something Which is pac-man battle royale and basically pac-man battle royale.
Speaker 0: is you know a four player?
Speaker 0: Everyone plays pac-man at the same time and you can turn into a big pac-man and eat the other pac-man's.
Speaker 0: You know, I mean pac-man verse.
Speaker 0: which did we ever talk about that on the show?
Speaker 1: I don't know, but it's one of the most brilliant games ever made.
Speaker 0: we talked about versus.
Speaker 0: that's the Miyamoto pac-man, right?
Speaker 1: We talked about that at PAX in egregiously unrealized potential.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: So pac-man verse if you haven't ever heard of it or played it It's a pac-man for the GameCube and the way you have to play it is you need one game boy advance Connected to the GameCube and you need three GameCube controllers, I believe right?
Speaker 0: Yes, and one person with the Game Boy Looks Game Boy Advance looks at the screen on the Game Boy Advance and on that screen They play regular old pac-man like straight up.
Speaker 0: But the other three people with the GameCube controllers look at the television and on the television They're playing.
Speaker 0: I'm a ghost.
Speaker 1: eat pac-man and I can only see the area directly around me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and some if you eat a fruit you can get a slightly bigger view.
Speaker 0: But the Pearson playing who's pac-man?
Speaker 0: can see the whole map.
Speaker 1: I'm so goddamn good at that game.
Speaker 0: The game is really really good but what pac-man battle royale is is everyone is pac-man and this ghosts and You're trying to get the high score and beat everyone else, right and they're still working on that game But it looks promising at least.
Speaker 1: but in terms of the experience of playing this new pac-man it is intense.
Speaker 1: The music is pumping the style.
Speaker 0: It's got the best fucking music style is off the.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's got the best fucking style styling.
Speaker 1: it is amazing that this is a true and proper sequel to pac-man.
Speaker 0: you could basically call this pac-man - I Think there was a pac-man - wasn't there?
Speaker 0: No, this is now pac-man - this is as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 0: This is the pac-man that matters for the modern day, right?
Speaker 0: You know, the old pac-man is an important historical artifact.
Speaker 0: You know, you should probably play it sometimes learn about it.
Speaker 0: You know get good at it if you must but if you really want to care about pac-man in the year 2010 It's pac-man CEDX.
Speaker 0: That is the pac-man to pay attention to.
Speaker 0: One person did point out though that it's an Xbox 360 game.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's out for any other systems.
Speaker 0: It might be but I don't think so.
Speaker 0: at least the world rankings aren't definitely not.
Speaker 0: I just realized how sad that is for Nintendo that world rankings are definitely not including anything but the Xbox 360.
Speaker 0: So You're probably not going up against too many Japanese people which is why we're able to get such high scores.
Speaker 0: Granted it is strange.
Speaker 0: It's like the world championships.
Speaker 0: You know all these twin galaxies are very u.s.
Speaker 0: Centric in terms of the Donkey Kong's and the pac-man's.
Speaker 0: You know the Japanese people might dominate at the fighting games and that sort of thing But maybe they're not really there for 40 hours playing a boring game that they've already saw.
Speaker 0: They're not really dominating at these old-school, you know games, you know, at least as far as I know.
Speaker 0: I think I blame it.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna pull this right out now.
Speaker 0: I blame it on the fact that they're mostly concentrating on the no skill RPG games.
Speaker 0: No That's a burn is a burn but they are good at the fighting games.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean if we're talking about Japan or just Asia in general cuz what about South Korea?
Speaker 0: I was saying South Korea is not the same.
Speaker 1: I was only talking about Japan.
Speaker 1: Yep I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think America might have more to do with the fact that the games were the focus of our culture like the games themselves Were the cultural focus where in Japan I think in the long run the characters and the nostalgia became more of the focus.
Speaker 0: No pac-man fever that wasn't from America It was.
Speaker 1: but that what the focus of fandom was still on playing the games in the arcades.
Speaker 1: and then arcade culture died.
Speaker 1: But Japan still has arcade culture.
Speaker 1: So maybe rather than thinking back fondly on the games that were in arcades people are still in arcades.
Speaker 0: I also think that part of it was You know, there was a significant difference between our arcade culture and Japan's arcade culture.
Speaker 1: Well theirs was like they had.
Speaker 1: I love those those sets that had like two Opposite side screens and you'd fight with each other.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well virtual on but it was sort of you know virtual on the sideways.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the thing is right is if you look it's like It's sort of a weird thing because look around at the arcade cabinets in the arcade right an old-school arcade and a lot of them Are Japanese.
Speaker 0: most in fact, you know, you got the Namco's and the Konami's and all that, right?
Speaker 0: But pong was totally u.s.
Speaker 0: Thing, right?
Speaker 0: So I think what happened is we had this old-school arcade culture.
Speaker 0: That's you know, this old retro, you know thing that you know.
Speaker 0: It is as large place in the US because of pong right and the games that followed including the ones that came from Japan like pac-man in Japan because our case actually stuck around.
Speaker 0: they're not a retro thing they're a constant thing even though they might be from what I hear diminishing right and As a result, you know The old goes out and the new comes in.
Speaker 0: here the old went out and no no new came in.
Speaker 0: So pac-man is still pretty much like, you know top tier arcade stuff in the US.
Speaker 0: We didn't really replace it.
Speaker 0: Whereas pac-man over there is like, you know It's old because now they're playing Street Fighter, you know, they replaced it and stuff.
Speaker 1: But at least all that aside this game is fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got to play pac-man zedx, you know You have any other like pac-man memories?
Speaker 0: I know that I when I was a kid I had this vinyl record that had like a pac-man story and possibly some music on it.
Speaker 1: I vaguely recall a pac-man cartoon, but it was terrible.
Speaker 0: I think the vinyl record was related to the cartoon.
Speaker 1: I mean really miss pac-man was my game because I had the Atari 7800.
Speaker 1: I had miss pac-man 7800 at the real.
Speaker 0: you know
Speaker 1: I played the ever living crap out of that game as a kid and I It's amazing because a lot of these like a lot of games that I think oh, I'll practice and get good like Street Fighter I mean fighting games didn't appear until I was much older and I did not try to get good at them as a kid.
Speaker 1: I didn't practice and it shows today Like I play Super Street Fighter despite all my trying and practicing not so good.
Speaker 1: and yet finally Pac-man makes a comeback a game.
Speaker 1: I played the fuck out of.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty goddamn awesome at it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the thing was is like I played that pac-man on the 2600 but then the 2600 broke.
Speaker 0: So I didn't really play it when I was older So didn't get good at it.
Speaker 0: and then not that it mattered to getting good at 2600 back And then I mostly played NES and I wasn't about to buy pac-man for the NES even though it did exist.
Speaker 0: Why would you buy pac-man for the NES?
Speaker 1: of course back when I had an NES, you know, I'd play pac-man Arcades.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is even arcades.
Speaker 0: by that time I was playing like Ninja Turtles and x-men and you know, obviously I'd alternate I'd go I'd play the.
Speaker 0: I played a pac-man once in a while in the arcade.
Speaker 0: I didn't avoid it entirely But I wasn't throwing quarters into it to actually get any good or any memories or any experience.
Speaker 1: See after our quarters in because it was the only game that was one quarter And that's pretty much.
Speaker 0: what I would do is I would basically play all the two quarter games and then at the very end of The day when I had one quarter left I played one round of pac-man and I left
Speaker 1: and later on before things ended remember those pseudo 3d Hologram looking Sega games that were like you're a cowboy don't die.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those are a quarter.
Speaker 1: I played the crap out of those two.
Speaker 0: really those those would be like a dollar.
Speaker 0: I was cuz it's a fancy hologram.
Speaker 1: They were a quarter.
Speaker 1: cuz no one liked him anymore.
Speaker 0: That was way later.
Speaker 0: Yeah, when people realize they're actually kind of terrible all those things were was a TV with a mirror and a dome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it looked good.
Speaker 0: It looked all right.
Speaker 1: It was just video was basically Dragon's Lair.
Speaker 0: Yes, basically There was a fighting game though that was in that thing.
Speaker 1: There was and there was always a line for that and that one was still a doll.
Speaker 1: It was a terrible game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was always a crazy line for it by the.
Speaker 0: if you're gonna play that you might as well have played by killer instinct Where you can just type in a combo and walk away from the?
Speaker 0: Even though I could never do that other people could.
Speaker 1: the longest lives I ever saw were to this day for Mortal Kombat 3 More.
Speaker 0: look I saw the longest lines from Mortal Kombat 2 and Super Street Fighter 2 turbo And that was you know that was the big ones and where I came from anyway.
Speaker 0: Any other Pac Man's notes?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: I think I'm petering out.
Speaker 1: I love this game.
Speaker 1: Pac Man is back And I feel like I also.
Speaker 0: I just want to say I love Pac Man style in general Not so much Pac Man himself was kind of doofy, but the ghosts right thought Clyde watch out.
Speaker 1: So what's your job?
Speaker 1: I don't remember the names, but what's your favorite style in the game?
Speaker 0: Inky-pinky Blinky and Clyde.
Speaker 1: because like there's styles ranging from like a Lego looking thing to a retro thing to like line art.
Speaker 0: I said I like this the style that I believe it on the default style for each level.
Speaker 0: Yep But I like the.
Speaker 0: I like the one that's in challenge to.
Speaker 0: you know that the first one and I like the dungeon one.
Speaker 1: I love that also ultra retro one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the half one is alright.
Speaker 1: In fact the dungeon one is almost more retro than is possible like it's worse than the original Pac Man.
Speaker 1: Yeah Which makes it kind of endearing in a Minecraft kind of way.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's kind of like a minecraft.
Speaker 1: music is just well.
Speaker 1: I feel like we could do a whole panel at like a Pac's.
Speaker 1: that was just Music and games and how very few games have gotten it right of messy games that have done it right.
Speaker 0: tribes.
Speaker 1: Wait wait wait.
Speaker 1: done it right because there's different ways to do it right.
Speaker 0: tribes to doom Mega Man Zelda Pac Man CEDX.
Speaker 1: We're talking about the kind of music that pumps you up and keeps you pumped up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because doom 2 and doom had some of the best music for them And tribes to just think it's perhaps remember had that dynamic music.
Speaker 1: We're depending on what was going on around you in the game.
Speaker 1: the music would change.
Speaker 0: Mostly what it would do is it would just choose Whether it should restart the track or increase the volume or decrease the volume.
Speaker 0: It wasn't that dynamic?
Speaker 1: no, it was more dynamic than you remember.
Speaker 1: you would add loops as Like if you got into a firefight with someone or your health was low.
Speaker 1: it would add loops Uh-huh, and in the beginning, I mean remember it would play the normal music and then it when it was loading That was pretty much the key is.
Speaker 0: all the songs and tribes to were designed Such that they would start while the loading screen was there And
Speaker 1: then you hit the
Speaker 0: ground and it would slowly build up and then as soon as the game started That would be like the go go go part of the song.
Speaker 1: They're like, yeah, come on.
Speaker 1: Come on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it'd be like you're sitting there while it's loading.
Speaker 1: It's like well, I mean meanwhile even counter-strike today great game And I'm waiting for my next round.
Speaker 1: I'm not sitting there going.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, come on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm just sitting there going.
Speaker 0: Yeah, when tribes 2 is loading it like.
Speaker 0: And then as soon as the game started back tent tent tent tent tent tent tent.
Speaker 0: it was awesome.
Speaker 0: And pac-man does the same thing.
Speaker 0: This is my Batman.
Speaker 1: I sweat a lot playing this back.
Speaker 0: The thing is the original pac-man.
Speaker 0: or I think about the music in the original pac-man.
Speaker 0: It was basically we.
Speaker 0: And how did that?
Speaker 0: how was that not?
Speaker 1: annoying is all it was annoying.
Speaker 1: I turned the music die.
Speaker 1: I basically muted it every time I played him as pack.
Speaker 0: really Because if you just listen to that we on its own you're like shut it off.
Speaker 0: But if I actually go to an arcade machine and play pac-man the we doesn't bother me for so I don't know what it is, dude
Speaker 1: If we ever do a panel on game music I'm gonna have a clip of that and just play it in the background for like five minutes while we're doing the panel.
Speaker 0: No, I just piss people off.
Speaker 1: It would make a good point.
Speaker 0: Remember pac-man Cheetah man, it's just the siren What?
Speaker 0: well I wonder I would like to know you know, cuz there's always those fun facts about old games Right what made them choose that siren as the pac-man noise and what made them, you know?
Speaker 0: I mean I could understand the waka waka waka waka.
Speaker 1: Well pac-man was originally puck manage.
Speaker 0: I know that there's nothing to do with the siren or the waka waka waka.
Speaker 0: I want to know where this though a siren and the waka waka came from.
Speaker 1: and also the When you died, that's a generic sound in death sound.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they came up with it, right?
Speaker 0: So who came up?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure games before pac-man had similar deaths, but who came up with that particular sound and when he was working on it?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's like asking a Foley artist like alright in this movie What made you think to make the like the claws sound just like this?
Speaker 1: it's like I don't know.
Speaker 0: I took a watermelon I shot it and then Yeah, but you know for other things people do have.
Speaker 0: you know, there's origin stories.
Speaker 1: I mean, I made some sound effects for some people's games at RIT just for my music classes and I basically just made like whatever.
Speaker 0: I was Use my thing of the day from a couple weeks ago the FS 6 or whatever.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: I should have used that in 2003.
Speaker 1: I basically just dicked around in a synthesizer.
Speaker 1: then I was like, alright, that sounds good, but that's the death sound.
Speaker 1: whatever.
Speaker 1: It was just a random sound that I thought sounded cool.
Speaker 1: There was no rhyme or reason at all.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.