Speaker 0: Hey, it's Monday October 18th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight because it's been at least a year.
Speaker 0: It's a tech news roundup.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So as you all know I went about a hundred and sixty eight hundred and seventy hours without caffeine last week My epic anti caffeine odyssey,
Speaker 1: so I guess you drink caffeine today of
Speaker 0: course But my plan was to reduce my dependence and get out of the physical addiction stage and then Experience something I haven't experienced in many years what a caffeine rush feels like when you haven't become completely a hundred percent tolerant to it.
Speaker 0: so Observations because a lot of people were really interested in this.
Speaker 0: the withdrawal symptoms are real and they occur like clockwork 48 hours after your last coffee splitting headache and then for like the next few days aches and all your joints mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And then you'll feel completely normal.
Speaker 0: I don't feel different though I expected that maybe caffeine was doing something to me that maybe I would feel like more awake or different in my life.
Speaker 1: Just can't tell.
Speaker 0: Maybe I mean it might be a Jekyll and Hyde syndrome.
Speaker 0: But the one thing I can say is I don't feel different.
Speaker 0: I feel normal.
Speaker 0: I feel the way that I felt when I had caffeine in my system when I was addicted mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But when I consumed caffeine over lunch today after having gone a complete week without any it was a fucking rush.
Speaker 0: It was awesome.
Speaker 0: It was really awesome.
Speaker 0: So now I did a bunch of research.
Speaker 0: I feel like if I have no more than 100 milligrams of caffeine Per two days I can maintain at most a low level tolerance yet at the same time not achieve total tolerance and enjoy all the benefits of caffeine without all the Pain in the ass of having to constantly take caffeine just to stay awake.
Speaker 1: Yeah Let's see.
Speaker 1: so today right I went to work Yeah, and then I realized since I'd worked from home on Friday my work computer was home.
Speaker 1: So I got to work and there was no computer.
Speaker 0: so I daddy to work computers.
Speaker 1: So I went.
Speaker 1: I went all the way home.
Speaker 1: now
Speaker 0: I got a work laptop that I leave at home
Speaker 1: when all I went all the way home and then all the way back Again
Speaker 0: see if you had dynamic DNS setup And you left the laptop on you could have remote desktop into it from work And then worked
Speaker 1: from what computer at work.
Speaker 0: You don't have any computer at work.
Speaker 0: Just the laptop.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: Oh Wow actually at work.
Speaker 0: I got this huge like quad-core Ubuntu development box And then I got my normal like quad-core Windows PC, and then I got my work laptop.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just have it the one computer the stupid Mac which I have.
Speaker 0: I also actually have a terminal server.
Speaker 0: So if all those computers die I can are.
Speaker 0: I can remote desktop into a terminal server that has all the stuff I need on it.
Speaker 1: Also Over the weekend.
Speaker 1: I actually tried to make donuts for reals that you did.
Speaker 0: I I would have come to your donut thing, but I had other plans.
Speaker 1: that the it's alright.
Speaker 1: because the donuts You know I don't they were not that it was weird.
Speaker 1: They were not.
Speaker 0: that magnificent should have used more trans fat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know, but I learned a lot about donutting and I'm sure my it will improve greatly.
Speaker 1: But the thing was is when I went back home to get that computer that I left there I grabbed one of the donuts that I put in a ziploc bag.
Speaker 0: was it good?
Speaker 1: It was much better actually better than it was when it was fresh out of the oil Which is the opposite of what I was going for because the place in Seattle fresh out of the oil They're like oh, you're gonna die you're gonna wait in line and fork over your whole wallet.
Speaker 0: I waited in line for 40 minutes to get those donuts again on Sunday.
Speaker 1: But if you but if you get them after they've been sitting there a while.
Speaker 1: They're no good.
Speaker 1: You know I ended up making the opposite like when I ate the donut that was like You know like sat in the plastic bag overnight And it was much superior to the donut that I you know when it was fresh the day before.
Speaker 0: Huh, maybe the oil congealed.
Speaker 0: well what it was is hot.
Speaker 1: the edges of the donut the crust part You know the surface was still slightly burninated because of you know factors like using butter inside the donut Which I shouldn't have done and inconsistent oil temperature.
Speaker 0: We definitely have a pro butter bias.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sometimes butter is not the answer, but I always feel like I can make like the answer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think I'm gonna do is well cuz why I like butter?
Speaker 1: because doesn't have trans fat right.
Speaker 0: well remember we can't.
Speaker 0: you can't use if you want to do the Project DT.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't actually DT works for that.
Speaker 1: You can't use the trans fats And I gotta figure out what's going on with that.
Speaker 1: But anyway if I I'm gonna try to use peanut oils right.
Speaker 1: if I use peanut oil for the frying I can Filter it and reuse it over and over again because I had to use a whole tub of Crisco to fry this Donuts and it still wasn't enough.
Speaker 0: I would add to bite you fried them in Crisco straight up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whoa that's what you're supposed to do.
Speaker 0: when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: We always used like safflower oil Supposedly supposed to use safflower oil for stir-frying, but not for deep frying.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's what they.
Speaker 1: that's what people say.
Speaker 0: yeah You know I've read the same forum thread.
Speaker 1: no, but I'll sir on the Internet.
Speaker 1: I didn't read it in the forum.
Speaker 1: but I'm gonna get peanut oil and I'm gonna use the peanut oil can reuse cuz I mean that's how.
Speaker 1: but Crisco was six bucks and I would have needed actually two of them to make it deep enough.
Speaker 1: and Reusing Crisco is not great because you want to let it cool before you rebottle it or whatever.
Speaker 1: But if you let Crisco cool it turns into white goop, and you have to scrape.
Speaker 1: It's no good, but the peanut oil will stay liquid right.
Speaker 1: so I get the peanut oil.
Speaker 1: I'll fry the donuts in peanut oil, but I'll use Crisco in the donuts themselves Such that they'll be full of trans fat and therefore delicious they will not.
Speaker 1: You know well it is zero trans fat per serving in the Crisco way.
Speaker 0: Yeah See I'm dubious of that.
Speaker 0: I mean if the ingredients say zero trans fat for this tiny serving and they also say Constituted almost entirely of partially hydrogenated oils.
Speaker 1: Yeah There's no trans fat in there at all is there, but anyway the you know I'll put that in the donut itself because it's actually a relatively small portion of the of the whole right.
Speaker 1: I mean this recipe that I used had like three and a half cups of flour and all this other stuff and like half a stick of butter.
Speaker 1: wait I got an idea, so it's not a lot of Crisco that goes into the actual dough.
Speaker 0: I got a really good idea because we you know we didn't go apple picking last weekend and this coming weekend is the last Goddamn weekend.
Speaker 0: you can go apple picking and have it be even worth going.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm if we go apple picking They'll be cider donuts.
Speaker 1: you want to ask them what there is.
Speaker 0: you should just be friendly and be like hey What's the recipe for these cider donuts?
Speaker 0: and watch them and like see how they're making them?
Speaker 1: They just you know what they're gonna have.
Speaker 1: they're gonna have a machine and they're gonna have a bag full of powder.
Speaker 1: They're gonna add water to it And they're gonna dump it in the top of the machine and then out come the side and just be seriously.
Speaker 0: just ask him like alright Where'd you get that white powder?
Speaker 0: They buy it from a food distribute and find out who that food distributor is.
Speaker 1: and I mean if you get it from any food Distributor yeah, it's just donut mix.
Speaker 0: so why not use the stuff that tastes the best?
Speaker 1: Cuz that stuff isn't necessarily the best.
Speaker 1: I got it.
Speaker 1: I want to make it special.
Speaker 1: right you got to go.
Speaker 0: project Cup noodle on this like you look at Chipotle.
Speaker 1: right Chipotle doesn't just order.
Speaker 1: You know that meat from you know I mean they do order it But it's like they prepare it and it's so they got a recipe that they prepare at the Chipotle.
Speaker 1: That's like.
Speaker 1: that's what sets them apart Scott.
Speaker 0: It's like the cup noodle.
Speaker 0: when they found the the ultra fancy particular one shrimp that stayed pink.
Speaker 1: exactly That's what I got to do.
Speaker 1: I got to do project X donut.
Speaker 0: You know I can't just be but I think the way to go about this would be to first go around and sample everyone else's Cider.
Speaker 1: I've already done that in my whole life.
Speaker 1: I have 28 years.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, and you know what my experience has been.
Speaker 0: all cider donuts are fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 1: That's why I'm trying to make.
Speaker 1: I'm also gonna experiment with glaze because you can't be a donut king if you don't know about glaze.
Speaker 0: But you know you know why is glaze cider donut?
Speaker 0: fuck that.
Speaker 0: what do you mean?
Speaker 1: You make like a cider glaze.
Speaker 0: no no if you're gonna make a glaze donut like that the key is maple.
Speaker 0: maple glaze Maple glaze.
Speaker 1: very good.
Speaker 0: That's the way to go.
Speaker 1: I think is that so I got experiment with glazes.
Speaker 1: I got to know all about glaze.
Speaker 1: I gotta be and I'm gonna glaze all kinds of shit.
Speaker 1: glaze pretzels.
Speaker 0: Glaze fruit glaze pretzel does not sound so good.
Speaker 1: Oh come on Do you get like a you know a chocolate-covered pretzel?
Speaker 1: now just imagine glaze strawberry glaze pretzel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it would be like.
Speaker 1: it would be like fucking Pocky with Saul's.
Speaker 0: So it sounds like double Pocky with.
Speaker 0: sounds like project DT is the backup plan of project st And project continue to work at a job.
Speaker 0: both fail.
Speaker 1: I think they're all project fail.
Speaker 1: But you know the thing is if there's anything that I've learned over the past many years It's that the things that are awesome are not the things that you try to do the accidents right.
Speaker 1: Twitter was an accident.
Speaker 1: Almost everything was an accident and not intentional.
Speaker 0: so how come with geek knives?
Speaker 0: we never made anything To accomplish something that itself was useful independently.
Speaker 1: I made a Podcasting website.
Speaker 0: yeah, if only podcasting mattered.
Speaker 1: I think our problem is that we use money a lot of times instead of making something right like if we would have made a Mixer that was like the ultimate podcasting mixer instead of buying one.
Speaker 0: Then we would have like a product that we could sell except There's a million podcasting mixers that are way cheap made with Chinese parts, and I couldn't do better than that on my own No But I mean just in terms of the feature set.
Speaker 1: right because we would design one that have like more inputs And a USB and you know all these things that no one is gonna make.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem.
Speaker 0: when I was doing all my research because you know we're the problem really is that we do our own research And my research showed that oh all that exists, and it's actually really cheap
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 0: so I just bought it,
Speaker 1: but I mean there's always something that I'm like oh They should do this like that doesn't exist there's no market for it.
Speaker 1: It's like the in-between product you know.
Speaker 0: yeah except the problem There is a lot of times there really isn't a market for.
Speaker 0: I mean look at podcasting.
Speaker 0: podcasting is basically dead.
Speaker 0: Like it is such a niche that most podcasts that are popular are professional or semi-professional like us anyway And the other half it's just Skype and like that Logitech stick microphone Actually nowadays.
Speaker 0: I think a lot of people use like Xbox style headset, whatever.
Speaker 1: you know they're using something.
Speaker 0: Oh, so get this total randomness.
Speaker 0: Emily And I went to a jazz club last night that also had awesome barbecue.
Speaker 0: you know that blue smoke barbecue place?
Speaker 0: no Well, it's in.
Speaker 0: it's like 28th Street.
Speaker 0: They have awesome barbecue Underneath in the basement.
Speaker 0: It's the same restaurant, but it's a jazz club.
Speaker 0: So you get the full meal, and you just eat it while they play jazz mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It was okay.
Speaker 0: It was kind of avant-garde you know guy in a saxophone going For like 20 minutes all righty.
Speaker 0: But that aside on the way home right biggest fan of that as always the are came Much sooner than the end of the queue.
Speaker 0: so we took the our home and in Queens Plaza station.
Speaker 0: There was you know those white like four foot by three foot like metal doors that are always locked.
Speaker 0: They're just all over the place in the subway.
Speaker 0: No, they're like steel plates that like their doors, and they aren't.
Speaker 0: they lock.
Speaker 0: one of them was just open.
Speaker 0: There's no one around.
Speaker 0: so I crawled in there to take a look.
Speaker 0: And there's there.
Speaker 0: basically it was in the wall and the wall is all tiled and there's like ads and posters like a subway wall.
Speaker 0: right Inside of this plate Was a crawlspace.
Speaker 0: it was about two and a half feet wide And it was just.
Speaker 0: it was tall enough to walk in like a hallway any rats get you?
Speaker 0: nah.
Speaker 0: And it was cleaned and it followed the entire length of the hallway.
Speaker 0: You know what it was Another wall with old ass ads still in frames right behind it.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh like they built another wall two feet in front of the original wall and left all the ads and everything in there.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and I I can't figure out what the fuck the reason is for that.
Speaker 0: But I gotta go back sometime at night.
Speaker 0: There was a guard kind of hanging out, and I saw that I was poking at it.
Speaker 0: So we left before he bothered us.
Speaker 0: I gotta go back when no one's looking and go in there and see what's up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe take some videos.
Speaker 1: It's probably just you know the structure of it.
Speaker 1: It's like that's how they do you know yeah?
Speaker 0: But they built a wall and the thing is it wasn't like that subway station is even that old and the wall in there was Relatively clean and new and there was just an even newer wall in front of it.
Speaker 1: How old were the ads in back there?
Speaker 0: I gotta go back and look.
Speaker 0: they mean they look kind of faded at least a year or two Okay, but it was no.
Speaker 0: It's not like 1940s.
Speaker 0: Burma shave something crazy.
Speaker 1: I was like yeah I was like is it Burma shave?
Speaker 1: It's like what the hell's back there.
Speaker 0: No casks of a Monti auto or anything.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: Oh well so things of the day.
Speaker 0: This one's real simple.
Speaker 0: It's a girl with a ball.
Speaker 0: That's all all right.
Speaker 0: It's pretty awesome actually.
Speaker 1: yeah I think it's the best one ball juggling ever seen.
Speaker 0: I'd say so I want to see.
Speaker 0: look Burj try to do something like that.
Speaker 1: I don't think he can.
Speaker 0: no probably not.
Speaker 1: and now he's gonna cuz.
Speaker 1: I challenge Whatever.
Speaker 0: now he'll call a shit talk debt until we do some of the things we've talked about.
Speaker 1: Anyway, there's a if you remember in the olden days of the old Prodigy the oldest prodigy for like IBM ps1 DOS prodigy.
Speaker 0: I had that at school.
Speaker 0: I never had that at home right?
Speaker 1: I had friends who had it.
Speaker 1: They had IBM ps1 and they had because their dad worked at IBM still works at IBM and they had Prodigy on this IBM ps1 and is the oldest prodigy.
Speaker 1: and there was a game you could play on it called madman Fuck mad maze.
Speaker 0: that game sucked, but I loved it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no right.
Speaker 1: There's the only game There was some other fun stuff to do was never winter nights.
Speaker 1: You had to pay for that, but mad maze is the best game on there.
Speaker 0: pretty much I remember I would play mad maze, but and it was fine.
Speaker 0: But I never beat it because I had a 2400 baud modem 2400 baud.
Speaker 0: it would always time out before it finished saving my game.
Speaker 0: So I always had to start from the beginning.
Speaker 0: That's when I gave up and started playing magic in the chat rooms instead.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So anyway There's apparently this website at pages dot prodigy dot net something something where you can play mad maze 2 in your browser But you need to do some fiddling with your browser because it was designed This is made in 2001.
Speaker 1: So it's made to work with like ie5 plus some.
Speaker 1: you might have to break out a virtual machine with Some old-ass windows 95 or something, you know to make this thing go.
Speaker 1: But if you do that, you'll be all.
Speaker 1: maybe Windows 98 would actually probably best But if you do that, you'll probably all set.
Speaker 1: I might actually work in ie6 I don't know, but it's not gonna work in your real modern browser unless you do some crazy hackage.
Speaker 1: But otherwise, it's actually you can play mad maze - it's there.
Speaker 1: It does work.
Speaker 1: Damn, yeah, how about that?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So very briefly in the meta moment up next in the geek nights lineup is magfest in January.
Speaker 0: We're doing one panel by our panel.
Speaker 0: losing should be fun.
Speaker 0: We're also now part of something called the mag nine mag nine Alright, and basically I do any other panels But one.
Speaker 0: we're doing one panel and then we're going to split up and sit on some of all these other panel.
Speaker 0: They've got a whole bunch of pretty high-powered Awesome people in the gaming industry and they're gonna split us all up and sit on panels and talk about stuff I don't know how much I like, you know, the many people I like our panel doing.
Speaker 0: well We don't do panels.
Speaker 0: you realize what we do is lectures.
Speaker 1: I know that's right.
Speaker 0: So I want to do are actually panels which I like being on.
Speaker 0: because think of this if you've got a panel That's actually smart people.
Speaker 1: Well, I hope that it's not nine people on the panel.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be four.
Speaker 0: five absolute max is five mostly four Uh-huh, and they're gonna split it all up and like someone will be on like this one in this one depending on what they're interested In what they have stuff to say about that.
Speaker 0: That's what that thread that email thread your cc'd on is all about.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I know why we only do one panel.
Speaker 1: I'll do more panels.
Speaker 0: That's all they want is to do is one panel which has to do one more.
Speaker 1: and why are we doing that one?
Speaker 1: We should do Game mechanics to make it was done instead.
Speaker 0: now losing should be fun.
Speaker 0: At least none of the people there have probably seen it and it's a good penalty.
Speaker 0: was that originally I also really wanted to do?
Speaker 0: I don't know the Miku panel.
Speaker 0: I want to do everything.
Speaker 1: so yeah, why did they?
Speaker 0: uh, anyway, it was that or beyond Candyland where the two they really wanted.
Speaker 1: Yeah, uh Beyond Canada would have been real good.
Speaker 1: We should done that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe we'll do it.
Speaker 0: You know what we could do.
Speaker 0: if people are interested We can just go find a spot and just do it like out in the hall.
Speaker 0: So we need a projector.
Speaker 1: It's weird.
Speaker 1: Then I'll buy a projector.
Speaker 0: No, it's a little handheld one.
Speaker 1: That's all you.
Speaker 0: Also, we've got axes coming up.
Speaker 1: axes in March get a hotel now or get a hotel yesterday.
Speaker 0: We've got anime Boston in April.
Speaker 0: it's coming.
Speaker 0: we'll be there.
Speaker 1: it's a while for now.
Speaker 1: I think anime Boston panel reg went up.
Speaker 1: You can apply to get it beyond a panel.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: That's all you.
Speaker 1: And if so, anyone knows book club book is World War Z by Max Brooks is about zombies.
Speaker 0: I'm so not looking forward to that.
Speaker 0: Okay, but also for anyone who's interested pecs East panel submissions are not yet up.
Speaker 1: Hotels are though.
Speaker 1: get a hotel room.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, you're gonna be fun.
Speaker 0: from what I can read all the really close hotels are already sold out.
Speaker 1: It's like that's what you get for not reaching immediately and I'm gonna tell immediately the hotel that we reg for sold out that day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why don't Pete like people just don't get it.
Speaker 1: It's like listen if you want to go if you have any interesting going whatsoever.
Speaker 1: No, no, you can cancel these things like a couple days beforehand.
Speaker 0: it's no.
Speaker 0: it's because of the cultures are different in packs because of the fact that you can just cancel and Because the fact that you can resell the badges.
Speaker 0: People are the weird.
Speaker 0: They're not as rushed.
Speaker 0: They don't sell out as quick.
Speaker 0: Look at Otacon hotels.
Speaker 0: Those fuckers sell out almost immediately.
Speaker 1: You just got to go immediately.
Speaker 0: Look at the artists alley it like Otacon it sells out like in second.
Speaker 1: Listen people don't hesitate on this shit.
Speaker 1: If you want to go to San Diego Comic Con, you got to buy your badges for the next one at the current one.
Speaker 1: That's how it works.
Speaker 1: You got to get your hotel room for the next one at the current one.
Speaker 1: All right, and if you can't plan that far ahead in advance then just don't even be disappointed.
Speaker 1: Just just be like, alright, I'm never going.
Speaker 1: just pretend you're never going and just don't even think about it.
Speaker 1: No, I'm disappointed if you can't commit.
Speaker 0: I have much more important advice delay delay delay.
Speaker 0: Order your badges like the last minute like when they say they're gonna sell out.
Speaker 0: wait until the last second get some cheapo hotel like a mile from the con because that Just makes it so much easier for me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're gonna have a real terrible experience traveling back and forth to the con from faraway hotels and all that You know, don't be doing that.
Speaker 0: The thing is at least with tax I mean with an anime con like Otacon or anime Boston even it's not like you can resell your badge easily.
Speaker 0: so a lot of people probably delay the pre-registration because they don't know if they're gonna go.
Speaker 0: and a lot of hotels at anime con specifically anime cons require large deposits and Such or even will require non-refundable deposits and a couple of conventions.
Speaker 0: I've seen Are so prone to canceling rooms at the last second, man, and it's actually becoming a big problem.
Speaker 0: But with packs you can totally just resell your badge.
Speaker 0: So if you even consider for a second, you might go to pack.
Speaker 0: There is no reason not to buy a badge because they will be trivial to sell that badge and you're already too slow.
Speaker 1: You should have gotten it a few days ago.
Speaker 0: Anyway, in fact, if you're a jerk you could scalp it and make some money.
Speaker 0: Let's go.
Speaker 1: Let's continue.
Speaker 1: So tech news roundup.
Speaker 0: tech news roundup.
Speaker 1: So actually a lot of the new.
Speaker 1: we haven't done this in a while and actually been light on tech news even light on Monday Shows.
Speaker 1: if it was Monday show ideas, let us know.
Speaker 0: So all you new listeners good Monday show ideas.
Speaker 0: tech news roundup is code for rim and Scott didn't have shit to talk about.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: But there is at least one source of a ton of tech news slash dot.
Speaker 1: Well, no, I'm not talking about.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about a thing right?
Speaker 1: So Oracle they have done many things lately which have resulted in numerous news is in sequence.
Speaker 1: So this is pretty much three, right?
Speaker 0: That was perhaps as vague as you could possibly be.
Speaker 1: Okay, so the first thing right?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, let me go through the whole story right.
Speaker 1: so my.
Speaker 0: so there's a man named Larry Ellison, that's too far in.
Speaker 0: So slash just as an aside.
Speaker 0: slash dot pointed out because I don't like Larry Ellison and I really don't like Oracle and slash someone anonymous on slash dot I'm stealing their joke pointed out that Oracle actually stands for one rich asshole called Larry Ellison.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway continue.
Speaker 1: So anyway, there's Sun Microsystems, right and recently Sun Microsystems bought MySQL and that put Java and MySQL And open star office all together under the same roof.
Speaker 0: three very important open source II things that suddenly are Under the nominal control also also virtual box.
Speaker 0: Ah shit Yeah, it's then but it was remember Oracle is a company that has a history of being dicks.
Speaker 1: They're pretty much is the worst right?
Speaker 1: I mean you think Microsoft is bad.
Speaker 1: now Oracle's the worst.
Speaker 0: Microsoft fights against Oracle.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like watching two evil giants fighting and you don't really want either one of them to win.
Speaker 1: But you don't want I mean apples bad - it's like the three evil Google's standing up for us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, barely So you've got.
Speaker 1: Oracle comes in and buys sons now.
Speaker 1: It's like oh shit What's gonna happen?
Speaker 1: all this good stuff that Sun was up to?
Speaker 0: well I recall when all these newses were announced way back, you know That Oracle basically started owning all this stuff.
Speaker 0: a lot the the posts on things like slashed out and digger about 50/50 half the nerds Saying this is the end.
Speaker 0: We got to watch out.
Speaker 0: They're gonna do evil stuff.
Speaker 0: the other half people saying they haven't done anything.
Speaker 0: evil.
Speaker 0: Java is always gonna be Java.
Speaker 0: they're not gonna like close my SQL.
Speaker 1: and well, the first thing they did right is Apparently there was some sort of drama discussion among like the open office Leading people or so.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what the hell they are.
Speaker 0: But wasn't it the guiding board?
Speaker 1: I guess something like that and basically Oracle asked a bunch of the people on the board to leave for conflict of interest reasons.
Speaker 1: Whatever it's like what?
Speaker 1: Something weird is going on there, right?
Speaker 1: I don't know what's up with that and it's like do they want to like Take open office and close it up or do something evil with it.
Speaker 1: I don't know but it's not looking too good, but Luckily, it looks like.
Speaker 1: do you remember when?
Speaker 1: X3 86 changed their license and was all evil and weird and then there was X or and then they just came out with X Or gonna.
Speaker 1: no one uses x86 anymore.
Speaker 1: I don't know if anyone's working on x86.
Speaker 0: It doesn't look like the same things happening here with LibreOffice.
Speaker 1: yeah, basically all these things that Oracle is fucking up with their evilness are just getting forked and They're gonna be like X org, right?
Speaker 1: So instead of open office, you're gonna use LibreOffice.
Speaker 1: No one's gonna think about open office anymore in a few years.
Speaker 0: So what about my SQL?
Speaker 1: Well, there hasn't been any news about that later now, but there has been news about open Solaris Which also they pretty much just canceled it.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, yeah, we're Yeah, we're gonna just get rid of open Solaris, you know, it's done.
Speaker 1: We're gonna we're gonna go just stick with the commercial Solaris.
Speaker 1: it's like well great guys, thanks a lot for that.
Speaker 1: and the other thing is Java.
Speaker 1: there's some weirdness with Java.
Speaker 0: Well, it's particularly Java mobile because there's basically all.
Speaker 1: no, it's actually no listen It's all Java's right?
Speaker 0: So I only know about the mobile thing with the the job.
Speaker 1: It's all related.
Speaker 1: So basically the thing is is they decided with IBM, right that they're going to concentrate on all the Java standard edition Development.
Speaker 1: concentration will be on the open JDK.
Speaker 1: That's what they're gonna concentrate on.
Speaker 1: and IBM was like, okay, let's do that, right?
Speaker 0: Wait now open JDK.
Speaker 0: That sounds great.
Speaker 0: It's open.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: But the thing is is goes like this right?
Speaker 1: is IBM really likes to do Apache Foundation open source stuff Like they?
Speaker 1: they're buddy buddy with that right like IBM hired the couch DB guy to and they couch DB went through the Apache Foundation, you know IBM's all about Apache Foundation open source.
Speaker 1: So IBM was working on this thing called harmony, which is a Java implementation, right?
Speaker 1: that was in the Apache.
Speaker 1: it's like the Apache Java basically and Harmony is what Android was using because Android is all Java.
Speaker 1: eat.
Speaker 1: if you do any Java Development for Android you're using harmony.
Speaker 1: You're not using Sun Java or Oracle Java, right?
Speaker 1: You're using or open JDK using harmony.
Speaker 0: No one uses the open JDK yet I don't know people use it.
Speaker 1: So the thing is is because of this agreement with IBM and Oracle to concentrate an open JDK all the IBM employees Were working on harmony are now gonna work in open JDK instead Thus putting the Android Java in a shady place.
Speaker 1: because now what they're gonna?
Speaker 1: they're still using harmony.
Speaker 1: So what the hell are they gonna do?
Speaker 0: See I read a much more sinister story talking about how Oracle is now claiming to that Android's virtual machine that basically they didn't want.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're making some lawsuits because the mobile edition there was encumbered and I think there was even some cost involved.
Speaker 0: So instead Google has Dalvik which is their Java virtual machine to run on Android and Oracle is now saying Yeah that infringes in all our patents.
Speaker 0: We're gonna sue the fuck out of you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know Oracle's is basically getting all evil and people are gonna have to.
Speaker 1: just you know Java was already has a bunch of alternative.
Speaker 0: apparently mobile Java actually was not included when Java was opened up.
Speaker 0: Mobile Java was not open.
Speaker 0: Google said fine We'll make our own and then we get to the problem.
Speaker 0: and actually this leads into my.
Speaker 0: the news I want to talk about next is the patent lawsuit clusterfuck that is smartphones and cameras.
Speaker 1: No, well is everything Technological.
Speaker 0: Yep, but think of this.
Speaker 0: So basically Google did something innovative and new on their own But they may or may not have infringed upon a whole bunch of ultra-broad patents that Oracle has.
Speaker 0: So Oracle can sue them to prevent competition in the phone world.
Speaker 0: As far as I can tell everyone who makes phones and make software has sued everyone who makes phones and make software.
Speaker 0: There's a funny graphic online that the only flaw and it shows like all the clusters and all the lawsuit lines.
Speaker 0: The only problem with that graphic is doesn't show all the lawsuits.
Speaker 1: Usually from what I've read is the way this works right is everyone gets a ridiculous number of patents And the reason they get him is for defense, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I'll infringe your patents and you infringe mine But if you go too far as long as we're sort of both have a ton of patents It would be mutually assured destruction, right?
Speaker 1: So we're just not gonna.
Speaker 1: everyone's gonna be chill.
Speaker 1: But then it is, you know, so that no one actually goes after anyone big time.
Speaker 1: They only go after when there's a slight advantage.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because or when there's a really strong patent or something like that say I'm IBM in your Oracle sure say I find out.
Speaker 0: Oh, they're violating like 50 of our patents.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we might be violating like 50 of theirs.
Speaker 0: It'll be a giant lawsuit.
Speaker 0: and when elephants fight, it's the grass that suffers.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, the grass is the grass is suffering right now, I don't think it is.
Speaker 1: actually I think what's gonna happen those.
Speaker 1: We're gonna have a whole bunch of X org situations.
Speaker 1: We're gonna library office.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be some.
Speaker 1: one of the Java's is gonna stand out as the Java Right and all the people are gonna go to one Java to rule them all, you know Maybe one of the MySQL forks will stand out, you know virtual box.
Speaker 0: Yeah You know what's gonna stand out.
Speaker 0: the database world post grass, you know, the new post grass has replication.
Speaker 0: that fucking works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's still post grass Like post grass.
Speaker 0: it's
Speaker 1: a pain in the ass to use You know and virtual box so far is still Goes on it, but otherwise, it's still good
Speaker 0: I think something for more fundamentals in the works because it's interesting that the patent lawsuits in particular About a third of them as far as I can tell our hardware patents on fairly legitimate Awesome things that companies did and the other two-thirds are patents like my patent Like and a lot of them are oh, yeah this software thing on a phone On two phones networked and I think The end result of the clusterfuck of reality is that if they don't all start settling with each other or?
Speaker 0: If we get patent trolls that go in grenade style like a company that gets one patent Or like member SEO Yeah, anyone who goes in with one patent and says we're just gonna broadside you bring it on.
Speaker 0: Nobody wants that because when that happens Courts will start to do something about it.
Speaker 0: If all these lawsuits go through and none of them settle out of court the courts are gonna have to start invalidating patents on one side of the other or doing massive damages and all it does is point out more and more to even people Who don't care the obvious flaws with the entire patent system that we have today.
Speaker 1: Well, I heard that what's gonna happen soon is they're gonna start having like public Things for patents.
Speaker 1: They're like it's.
Speaker 1: it's very likely that what's gonna happen is when there's a patent they're gonna put it out there before it's approved and Just people like you and me will be able to relatively easily You know with a little bit of bureaucracy.
Speaker 0: I could go and validate my own goddamn patent.
Speaker 1: You just basically Allow you to submit prior arts, right?
Speaker 1: So if you can go find prior arts you can submit them eventually maybe soon.
Speaker 0: So if I were a company that relies upon this giant patent, I would hire someone to just find prior arts.
Speaker 0: I would also hire someone to flood the system with penises Thus preventing them from actually validating any of the real prior.
Speaker 0: on my pens, maybe I Mean you've got some patent on like imaging a system to rebuild it with a new MAC address and dynamic DNS.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then the prior art is.
Speaker 0: here's a picture of my penis.
Speaker 1: I think the thing to just take away from this is that watch out for anything that Sun used to own that Oracle now owns because they're evil.
Speaker 1: and If you're gonna use anything that is in that category, right?
Speaker 1: You might want to look for like the up-and-coming replacement project and use that instead, you know?
Speaker 1: Maybe use LibreOffice instead of open office or use a B word.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know that's only word processor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, but the Google Docs at least, you know, it's look for Alternatives to those things.
Speaker 1: if you have to if you can, you know Maybe you'll be better off in long run if Oracle gets progressively more evil as time goes on.
Speaker 0: So there's the story.
Speaker 0: I only want to talk about this briefly.
Speaker 0: but Dutch hotels under this law that may or may not be passed May have to register as ISPs and then be subject to all the regulation that ISPs are Like data regulation everything just because of the shitty way the laws are written.
Speaker 1: No It's terrible.
Speaker 0: and now imagine that If a hotel that just offers like free Wi-Fi to the people at the hotel has to register as an ISP into all this data retention Theoretically like some store that just wants to offer free Wi-Fi has to do the same thing.
Speaker 0: All this.
Speaker 1: this would basically say offer free Wi-Fi at my house I have to do it too.
Speaker 0: This would basically say it's illegal to offer Wi-Fi because it'll be too kind of like what I'm trying to do.
Speaker 0: our e-commerce Properly Following the law is so much more expensive and so much more difficult than breaking the law And in fact if the more we follow the law The more likely we are to accidentally break it and be noticed than if we just never follow the law in the first place.
Speaker 0: yeah, but I point this out one because I think that's been bothering me lately is that half the laws we have related to anything internet were written in the 80s and Literally make no sense at all in light of any modern technology.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and - and that's why people just break the law like with piracy and such because it's like.
Speaker 1: well The law is completely meaningless.
Speaker 1: It's so out of the judges don't understand it.
Speaker 0: Why should I understand it?
Speaker 1: Why should I even bother?
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna do what I know is best.
Speaker 0: I mean look at how hard it is to even convince tech people that net neutrality is a problem or not a problem.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the other thing I want to point out is that the United States does not have a monopoly on internet law.
Speaker 0: bullshit This is Dutch.
Speaker 0: This is not American.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: No by no I mean if anything the US actually has not the work anywhere near the worst internet law.
Speaker 1: Look at how many places are all censoring right?
Speaker 1: Look at how There was a. there was a URL shortener not bitly.
Speaker 1: but another one that ended with ly.
Speaker 0: Okay, and it was.
Speaker 0: it was aimed at porn.
Speaker 1: basically Yeah, is he a porn URL shortener?
Speaker 0: only who would need that?
Speaker 1: and because they registered In ly You are a length right, which is Libya, but I'm right qaddafi totally shut them down.
Speaker 0: So they just was it actually qaddafi.
Speaker 1: Well, no, but it was Libya, you know.
Speaker 1: So they just lost their domain and it's like whoa bitly could just lose their domain and he any time.
Speaker 0: because look At the same time.
Speaker 1: I'm almost okay with remember that happened with goat C CX just the canary island.
Speaker 0: It was ever one reason our TLDR Not TLDR our top-level domain system and the DNS in general is kind of broken in that people are just using Designations that weren't intended for those uses.
Speaker 0: I mean ly was intended for Libya and we're using it because it's clever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, CX was clever.
Speaker 1: It's you know, you're not actually from the Canary Islands Yeah, and a long time.
Speaker 0: I mean you used to actually have to be a nonprofit to get a dot org.
Speaker 0: Yeah, daddy to you is still pretty tightly controlled.
Speaker 0: calm, whatever men, whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah gov int int is the one people don't even know exists.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know how to get an int.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I could.
Speaker 1: yeah, I don't know either.
Speaker 0: the UN has one as far as I can tell but you know It's like.
Speaker 1: it is true that they're making a mockery of the top-level domains But at the same time it's like you think about this right bitly, you know, they need the short URL, right?
Speaker 1: That's the whole thing.
Speaker 1: if they added another character Like well what we should put in by a quest to have a new top-level domain that is just like Zed Mm-hmm and just that might exist.
Speaker 0: and that's the official.
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: They're usually two letters It's anyway, the other thing though is that they've already.
Speaker 1: there's already all these bitly URLs.
Speaker 1: So if they yoink those expire.
Speaker 0: what do you mean?
Speaker 0: I thought I thought they eventually got reused and expired.
Speaker 0: I don't think they last forever.
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: I think they last forever.
Speaker 1: So if they go yoink that's like gonna ruin like this whole.
Speaker 1: that's gonna like just make 404 is all over the internet.
Speaker 0: Well that it should.
Speaker 0: here's the thing.
Speaker 0: It'll it should if people were smart if people were responsible internet citizens It should only affect fucking Twitter if you're using bitly on your blog to link to stuff.
Speaker 0: You're stupid.
Speaker 1: A lot of people are using bitly and they shouldn't play.
Speaker 1: No The reason is not because they want to shorten the URL but because bitly provides tracking for you.
Speaker 0: Well, you can do the tracking yourself trivially.
Speaker 1: You're running Apache Yeah, but that's a lot more work than just having bitly do it.
Speaker 0: Ah, I have no sympathy for plus.
Speaker 1: a lot of people Remember, we're sort of weird, right?
Speaker 1: We actually have an actual hosting where we control a true A lot of people are like.
Speaker 1: most people are using like wordpress.com or they're using like dreamhost where you can't control shit.
Speaker 1: You can't control your Apache server.
Speaker 0: You basically put files in a folder and you can maybe But at the same time the only people who need that sort of tracking are people who are trying to sell ads anyway.
Speaker 0: Maybe I don't care any mind.
Speaker 0: Okay, I doubly don't care.
Speaker 1: But I mean the point is that all these links on Twitter who's just gonna be broken?
Speaker 0: You realize whenever I can I give raw URLs on Twitter.
Speaker 1: We're also using bitly a lot too Yeah, so our Twitter would be broken.
Speaker 0: Yeah, our Twitter would be but not our RSS feed.
Speaker 0: We don't have bitly links in the feed burner.
Speaker 1: No but it's you know, it's still.
Speaker 1: it's pretty it's pretty bad and it's also.
Speaker 1: a lot of people have jobs at bitly and have invested in bitly and if the domain is pretty much This place I work is the same thing.
Speaker 1: I work at broadway.com at our.
Speaker 1: the domain is pretty much our whole company at the same time.
Speaker 0: You know, there's hope.
Speaker 0: there's people who work at bitly and they're reliant upon.
Speaker 0: they're relying upon the fact that their URL is from Libya.
Speaker 0: They should have known that when they got but it's too late now.
Speaker 0: Actually, I went to bitly to see stuff just to try to figure out if they ever expire.
Speaker 0: and For some reason the only link I see is a geek nights link.
Speaker 0: Okay, I don't know why it's showing me that on the front page.
Speaker 0: All right, I've never.
Speaker 0: I never used bitly.
Speaker 1: All right, let me let me say check it out.
Speaker 0: It's just weird.
Speaker 1: Are you logged in?
Speaker 0: No, I don't have a bitly account.
Speaker 1: I'm logged in as geek nights on bitly.
Speaker 0: I'm not logged in as geek nights on bit.
Speaker 1: What does it say?
Speaker 1: at the very top it says bitly.
Speaker 1: to the right where it says sign in and sign out It says sign in or sign up.
Speaker 1: It doesn't say hi geek night sign out.
Speaker 0: No, all right, and then under shorten your long links.
Speaker 0: It shows one link.
Speaker 0: That is the geek nights link.
Speaker 1: But let me click at it and find out.
Speaker 0: yeah, it takes us to the vanilla farms episode a1 b2 c3.
Speaker 1: Ah Don't know What's the?
Speaker 1: what is the bitly link?
Speaker 0: I have a thing that turns bitly links into non bitly link see a KQCI Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: I don't know where you're seeing this.
Speaker 1: I'll have to look later.
Speaker 1: All right, just keep it open.
Speaker 0: Anyway, crazy meta aside My writing I just have little sympathy.
Speaker 0: I mean This is part of the problem.
Speaker 0: Bitly is using Libya because we really didn't think our TLD system through to handle a modern infrastructure.
Speaker 0: But at the same time I'm not gonna be one of those You know freshmen and IT at a tech school who will you know be in class learning how DNS works like yeah This is stupid.
Speaker 0: We should use something new and modern which is code for I don't understand it And I can't be asked to read the documentation.
Speaker 1: All Right, what are their?
Speaker 1: what are their?
Speaker 1: tech?
Speaker 1: news has happened.
Speaker 0: Well, there was the announcement that Google had been testing autonomous robot cars for some time now.
Speaker 1: I mean that's not.
Speaker 1: I mean there have been.
Speaker 1: I've been when I was in high school You could watch TV and there would be shows about robot cars.
Speaker 0: Yes, but none of them really worked.
Speaker 1: I mean in College there were kids making robot.
Speaker 0: Yes, but they worked in such controlled situations and didn't work at all outside of those situations.
Speaker 0: They worked on empty roads that were straight.
Speaker 0: they worked on predefined courses.
Speaker 0: They worked in like these pathetic, you know, like proof of concepts.
Speaker 0: Google kind of came out and they've actually you know they hire dudes apparently 15 bucks an hour to sit in the cars and just be ready to take over if they go apeshit and They're able to drive in city traffic on freeways thousands of miles.
Speaker 1: Apparently all these even where the roads are really weird Other cars are doing really weird.
Speaker 0: You know, they were testing these just downtown San Francisco.
Speaker 1: All right, the driving's not too bad there it is is it?
Speaker 1: yeah?
Speaker 1: But I mean like, you know, what if other cars do weird stuff?
Speaker 1: the Google car still works.
Speaker 0: supposedly They do and all this time only one was involved in an accident for the many thousand whatever miles they've driven and that accident It was stopped at a red light and someone rear-ended it.
Speaker 1: I mean like.
Speaker 1: what if like the road is just really weird where you know, this is out west.
Speaker 1: I mean, how would it do on an East Road right East Coast?
Speaker 1: The roads are old and very weird out west.
Speaker 1: They're a lot more grid like and you know easy to pattern.
Speaker 0: San Francisco's pretty shitty to drive in.
Speaker 1: from all the tell I've seen on the I mean, maybe they can deal with other cars But they're still not dealing with weird northeast old roads not yet.
Speaker 0: but the point is that what Google showed and demonstrated at least is Leaps and bounds beyond.
Speaker 0: the last time there was big news about robot cars.
Speaker 1: that is true.
Speaker 0: And I think within our lifetime you and me we will see Autonomous or at least semi autonomous robot cars on the streets for real.
Speaker 0: Yes, which will be great when we're old because then I don't have to deal with the problem of I'm too old to drive safely.
Speaker 1: And yeah It'd be great now cuz I could go somewhere without having anyone have to drive.
Speaker 1: We can have four seats facing the middle and play board game.
Speaker 0: if I had a robot car I would pay whatever it took to own a car and have it parked in this building and every con I just get in the car and say take me to Otacon.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Maybe not Otacon.
Speaker 0: Take me to PAX.
Speaker 1: I would take you to Seattle when you wanted to go to Boston.
Speaker 0: Yeah Course maybe it'll be like ex-driver.
Speaker 1: Yeah, robot cars are awesome And really any Luddites just need to STFU right if anyone's like.
Speaker 1: no again, I don't trust it.
Speaker 1: It's dangerous.
Speaker 1: It's like it's not any more dangerous than your shitty driving.
Speaker 1: I think human error is way more dangerous than even flawed computers.
Speaker 0: two points One of the biggest killers of humans in the world today at least world is car accidents.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and to think about the fuel economy of robot cars that can autonomously form road trains on the freeway Yeah, and the fact that you know, they don't drive like morons.
Speaker 1: everyone has robot cars.
Speaker 1: There'll be a lot less traffic because the cars will just be like an inch from each other all going at the maximum possible Speed.
Speaker 0: and here, you know mass transit works.
Speaker 0: in very dense centers like in New York City Our subway system works because all the jobs are in one place and all the people are in a couple of places and the subways Just work.
Speaker 0: Mass transit despite the dreams of a lot of people who want it to be is not feasible in most of the country
Speaker 1: unless Everyone moves which they should yeah
Speaker 0: But it won't be ever
Speaker 1: unless every state becomes a country and then all the states that aren't feasible will go bankrupt.
Speaker 0: I don't have to leave them.
Speaker 0: mass transit like Detroit doesn't service even in like New York mass trans.
Speaker 0: It's awesome.
Speaker 0: Unless you want to go a couple of miles to the left or right of where the mass transit goes.
Speaker 1: Yeah There are certain places like you just can't get right like if I had to go to the UPS of the FedEx in mass.
Speaker 1: Like if you don't drive there like there is a subway stop, but it's not close and the bus goes there.
Speaker 1: But it's a shitty.
Speaker 1: you got to take like two or three buses and it's real.
Speaker 1: I just bike there.
Speaker 1: It's way easier.
Speaker 1: macadamia Mean macadamia gazebo on the bus.
Speaker 0: Yeah the bus bus bus But even more The like.
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: I want to go skiing.
Speaker 0: Who would ever make a train that goes to Hunter Mountain?
Speaker 1: nobody.
Speaker 0: so I got to take the bus.
Speaker 0: You know what the bus sucks.
Speaker 0: every time I've been to Hunter Mountain I will see that bus pull up after I've been skiing for like an hour.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it just gets you there late.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I hate that shit and it's like 80 bucks a person what it's cheaper If I'm going with more than one other person it is cheaper to rent a car for the entire weekend.
Speaker 0: That is to take.
Speaker 1: that car is a ripoff and that's still cheaper.
Speaker 0: Yeah zip car is not that bad.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking about getting it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe I would get if it was less money.
Speaker 1: It's still way too much money because like I wouldn't use it most of the time and you paying even if you're not using.
Speaker 0: I looked into it actually for how much I rent cars.
Speaker 0: It would be useful because when I go skiing I have to rent a car.
Speaker 0: I have to run a car like five times every winter.
Speaker 0: It's already used worth it?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't I wouldn't use it that much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz you don't go skiing.
Speaker 1: I would use it a lot less.
Speaker 0: I also might use it to go to like kinetic on rather than I don't know what we're gonna do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's like that's when I would use it which is like what when one's twice a year, you know, it's not a lot Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, the other thing is that in general if we had robot cars It solves so many societal problems that you wouldn't even think about like getting kids to school and dealing with buses And you
Speaker 1: just have the kids get in the car and you can say car go to school Yeah,
Speaker 0: and old and
Speaker 1: then the car would just drive itself home.
Speaker 0: We don't need taxis anymore.
Speaker 1: Maybe robot taxis the driver on all the taxi workers would be out of work.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: All the any bridge any chauffeur would be out of work.
Speaker 1: Yeah now I feel like really rich people would demand to have human Robots anyway only really old people who didn't trust the robot cars and we just had to make human driving on roads illegal.
Speaker 1: I guess I'm just and only only human drivers and races and other situations like that.
Speaker 0: Well, I think there'll be a transition where what we'd have to do is just phase in the robot cars.
Speaker 1: That's the one the new engines got.
Speaker 1: the Jetsons had flying cars that you drove.
Speaker 1: It's like what?
Speaker 1: X over had non flying cars.
Speaker 0: I saw Elroy get into a car in one episode and tell it to go to school.
Speaker 0: They just drove him there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was all but most of the time George just is sitting into the stick and he's wiggling it back and forth.
Speaker 0: You know, he wasn't just playing like a game cuz he didn't see the guy.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It was in his brain.
Speaker 0: maybe It's not like he was staring.
Speaker 0: He's just going left right left right left friend Like everyone in old movies with that back projection is always Larry's.
Speaker 1: the Jetsons had flying cars.
Speaker 1: They would still line up in traffic when they could just gone out.
Speaker 1: There's different ways to directly to the destination.
Speaker 0: There was even traffic in the fifth element, I know at least that made sense.
Speaker 0: there were just so many cars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they actually cars fucking everywhere.
Speaker 0: I'm just.
Speaker 0: I'm really excited about robot cars.
Speaker 0: if if there was anything that I want from science other than Immortality and perfect eternal.
Speaker 1: I think robot cars are the most convenient awesome and drastic Improvement to everyday life that is feasible in the near either on the near future in the industrialized world because there are parts of the world Where clean water is a revolution.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean another related thing right is, you know I've always said I would get a tattoo if it was like digital like just a race.
Speaker 0: Oh digital ink tattoo ink.
Speaker 1: There's strides in that as somebody invented basically like LED tattoo.
Speaker 1: So you implant this LED grid and then you can light it up in different colors and so I would get that.
Speaker 1: I would get it under three conditions.
Speaker 1: condition number one if I could turn off all the lights and it'd be invisible.
Speaker 1: Condition number two, I could easily program it to do whatever.
Speaker 0: condition three.
Speaker 0: It doesn't cause cancer.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, I mean, it's just a grid or I have lights.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna be cancer.
Speaker 0: Never know my just you might get an infection now, you'd be surprised how much stuff leeches out of stuff.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's true, especially in the human body.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if there's any pain or any sort of hazards I don't want it.
Speaker 1: but condition three is what's the battery situation with that?
Speaker 1: Yeah got a battery in your ear Yeah, and you to replace the battery.
Speaker 1: if that, you know, it's like.
Speaker 0: fuck that, you know You charge it with induction maybe but be a way to do it.
Speaker 1: But if but if it has if it had all of the if did none of those caveats, I'll get it.
Speaker 0: If you lottie know what you got to get is the thing where you can just wave your hand and your hand as the LEDs in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So cuz Scott doesn't even have any tech news.
Speaker 0: There's this dude and this is a common problem That's been around for a long time.
Speaker 0: This is not a new story.
Speaker 0: This guy is just a new story and that is calling attention to it.
Speaker 0: Dude is smart has a smartphone goes to use book sales scans is BNS Automatically looks on Amazon to see if the books are worth money or not Buys all the books that are way underpriced sells them on Amazon.
Speaker 1: What I read is he's actually used bookstore owner, right?
Speaker 1: So he goes to you know, he doesn't go to used bookstores.
Speaker 1: He goes to like, you know second-hand stores and other places that books aren't their primary thing that they can tag sale.
Speaker 0: You're talking about Michael Savitt's the guy.
Speaker 1: that's the guy.
Speaker 0: there's a bunch more people involved in this this story.
Speaker 1: But I mean this one guy got most the internet attention cuz he goes around and he's trying to buy books to sell in his Used bookstore and he has like a database of the used books.
Speaker 1: cuz he's used bookstore owner.
Speaker 1: So he checks the value in his little database with his smartphone And if he sees that the book is underpriced he buys it and then sells it in his used bookstore.
Speaker 0: now, here's the problem.
Speaker 0: First and weirdly I looked around on the internet and even slashdot.
Speaker 0: I'd say the majority of the people posting are totally against this guy and are totally for the bookstores banning him.
Speaker 0: What the fuck most of slash jobs?
Speaker 0: Yes, last shot.
Speaker 0: People are like fuck this guy.
Speaker 0: What the fuck?
Speaker 0: He's being a jerk to the bookstore.
Speaker 0: He's undercutting all the competition.
Speaker 0: Like I can't imagine Called business isn't slash.
Speaker 1: It's usually super live.
Speaker 0: It's not even called business.
Speaker 0: It's called being smart and using technology to do something better.
Speaker 0: notice how the article says arbitrage.
Speaker 0: You know what arbitrage is if there is someone selling something and someone else buying something and their prices are crossed.
Speaker 0: as in someone will buy Something for more than someone else is selling it and they just haven't met each other.
Speaker 0: Arbitrage is when you buy it from person a and sell it to person B and pocket the difference.
Speaker 0: Yep, and arbitrage is a very important thing in the stock market.
Speaker 0: That's how you're able to trade even if no one's buying right now In in pretty much any time.
Speaker 0: there's an imbalance.
Speaker 0: in any market.
Speaker 0: Arbitrage is when someone takes it upon themselves to balance that out.
Speaker 1: but what will happen right is right now we have a situation where there's a few smart people and a bunch of stupid people in every market.
Speaker 1: if we have a ton of Arbitrage in all different markets then all prices converge on real price.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but basically the problem is that real price I think is gonna ruin our economy and make every all even more unemployment and porn.
Speaker 0: Definitely what I think it's going to do is use bookstores will just disappear but they're gonna disappear.
Speaker 0: Anyway, Amazon wins Kindle wins.
Speaker 0: Yeah, use bookstores only existed like the beach pretty much and even then most used bookstore owners don't use technology for shit.
Speaker 0: I never see barcodes or barcode scanners or even usually they've got that one like 486 that their grandkids set up for him 20 years ago, maybe Ten years ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it's the same in a lot of industries.
Speaker 1: I was at this little hacker meetup and this guy he wasn't that technological He's mostly a business guy, right?
Speaker 1: And apparently his family owns liquor stores, right?
Speaker 1: So he knew how to program like a palm pilot and he programmed.
Speaker 1: he went to business school.
Speaker 1: So he knew these business algorithms to figure out like how much inventory you should buy like what you should order You know and he knows he really knows how to figure out what you should order.
Speaker 1: So he wrote a palm pilot program where you just keep the inventory and your sales on this palm pilot.
Speaker 1: Not even a point-of-sale system doesn't even have that right because all his family's liquor stores are so technologically inept.
Speaker 1: Even this shitty palm pilot app helps them like make better orders and not buy some alcohol.
Speaker 1: that's gonna sit on the shelf and Order enough of what's gonna sell and have the price be correct, you know.
Speaker 1: And it's like imagine if they had a point-of-sale system and an actual computer instead of just this palm pilot thing.
Speaker 1: This guy wrote.
Speaker 0: You could blow away all the liquor stores in town or even use bookstores.
Speaker 0: You know correlate like the guy at the beach right that used bookstore.
Speaker 0: What if he just correlated like what sold and when it sold what authors were popular and you know The demographic of like a girl bought this.
Speaker 1: a guy bought that right?
Speaker 1: It's how many girls, you know general age.
Speaker 1: You just look at the person right?
Speaker 1: You could have cameras in your store perfectly legal You can.
Speaker 1: just you know you could get all kinds of crazy data from that and use it to vastly improve your sales.
Speaker 1: and then Like you could also if books aren't selling you can look on Amazon.
Speaker 1: You can try to sell them on Amazon if no one's buying them in the store, you know do stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah The funny thing is I've run into this before I got kicked out of a Best Buy once when I was in high school Because I was shopping for something and I actually pulled out a camera and took a picture.
Speaker 0: now You're not supposed to do that technically so I got kicked out.
Speaker 0: But I got kicked out from another Best Buy when I did it with a pen and paper.
Speaker 0: instead I was just writing down the prices of the things I was gonna buy and then going around other stores and seeing where it was Jeepist and they kick you out.
Speaker 0: I was writing down prices and they asked me to leave.
Speaker 0: Wow And it's fairly common store and especially now that people have some like iPhones.
Speaker 0: they're taking pictures or like.
Speaker 1: well They're scanning the barcodes.
Speaker 0: Yes, take pictures of the barcodes and then looking on you know, there's apps.
Speaker 0: They'll just tell you here's what this cost on Amazon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I've gotten a lot of no one can kick me out of like an anime dealers room But a lot of people have had harsh words for me.
Speaker 0: when I stand at a guy's booth and I pick up like princess Tutu it's like 40 bucks and I just hold it in my hand and I hold my phone and I type in princess tutu And I see it's 30 bucks in Amazon.
Speaker 0: I put it back down and walk away.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I Was just what.
Speaker 1: as the guy gets that's that's the you know, I mean you can charge a slight premium for you know Sell it getting it now, right and you can get away with that.
Speaker 1: For example, right?
Speaker 1: I bought it.
Speaker 1: I had to buy a new DS cuz the other one was stolen.
Speaker 1: I bought it in Best Buy.
Speaker 1: I didn't show my receipt at the door.
Speaker 1: I did the no thanks trick.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it worked Didn't?
Speaker 0: they pause for a second like what and they just walk out?
Speaker 1: I didn't even look at him I just walked out.
Speaker 0: You gotta say no Thanks, like.
Speaker 0: you're totally sincere and they'll pause and just walk past him whatever.
Speaker 1: so, you know, it's the same price in Amazon.
Speaker 1: Apparently wheeze and Xbox 360s are also the same price in Amazon as they are in the store.
Speaker 0: So even my life camera.
Speaker 0: I was gonna you know, I was gonna buy this webcam.
Speaker 0: I go to Best Buy I see the price I go on Amazon.
Speaker 0: I see it's the same.
Speaker 0: So I just bought it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's you know, it'll happen.
Speaker 1: Most of the time Amazon is gonna be cheaper right and most of the time Best Buy is gonna over.
Speaker 1: But here's the final problem.
Speaker 1: memory cards like.
Speaker 1: I need a new memory card, you know a micro SD card.
Speaker 1: so I go.
Speaker 1: and of course Best Buy is like 40 bucks and Amazon's like $10.
Speaker 0: But here's the amazing thing Anyone I can see why store owners physical brick-and-mortar store owners are against people doing this.
Speaker 0: That is self-interest and I can understand that if you don't own a store.
Speaker 1: But I mean wouldn't it just be better if you were the owning the store if you just Competed and then one it's like, you know, because currently people don't do this by and large.
Speaker 0: so they win by not competing.
Speaker 0: I mean think about how many people buy an.
Speaker 1: They make more money ripping off all those customers and just getting rid of a few smart customers and not getting their business at all.
Speaker 0: Oh source hate smart customers.
Speaker 0: They'd rather us just not shop there.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, kind of like how TV networks will often, you know, if the demographic if a show is popular But not with the right advertising demographic They'll just take it Even if the show is very popular because they don't make money from the popularity of the show.
Speaker 0: They make money from the advertisers and the advertisers want the.
Speaker 0: you know, the dream demographic 20 to 30 something affluent white dudes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean or you know It depends to like if you're.
Speaker 1: if you're advertising like prescription drug plans you advertise people CBS during the daytime when the old people are watching, you know It's like they.
Speaker 1: it's.
Speaker 1: you know If a show doesn't have a particular demographic then even if the even if the audience is very large if you're not advertising something that has a broad audience that's just generic pop culture then It's cute.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna get that many, you know eyeballs that you want cuz like, okay, I'm gonna advertise.
Speaker 1: You know Some like toys and I'm gonna advertise the toys on HBO.
Speaker 1: HBO doesn't have commercials, but you get the point, right?
Speaker 1: It's like no kids are watching that dude Even if a billion people are watching it.
Speaker 1: Advertising he-man is not gonna work in that spot.
Speaker 0: There was a time when cable didn't have commercials.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: So, I mean, you know, it's it might want to show that.
Speaker 1: okay We want a show where even if only a million people are watching even if only a few thousand people are watching They're all in the same demographic or mostly.
Speaker 1: so our advertising be very effective.
Speaker 0: So my point is thus I can understand why store owners are against this sort of thing.
Speaker 0: Fuck them But I understand where they're coming from.
Speaker 0: anyone who's not own a store.
Speaker 0: I can.
Speaker 0: there is no possible rational argument you can make against someone using extent information that is publicly available on their smartphone to figure out if a deal in a store is a good Deal or not.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: there it's.
Speaker 1: it's weird the attitudes I see people have.
Speaker 1: I've seen different attitudes such as there are people who feel charitable towards the store owners Like especially.
Speaker 1: I see this a lot with comic people, right?
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: I'm like, why do you?
Speaker 1: why don't you just pre-order and get the crazy discount?
Speaker 1: They're like, oh because I'm supporting the store.
Speaker 1: It's like Just listen to the not a charity episode.
Speaker 0: Here's a quote from one of the one of the haters on slash dot.
Speaker 0: and now that I'm looking at the article again Luckily all the haters have for every hater.
Speaker 0: There's two responders saying what the fuck's wrong with you.
Speaker 0: So slash dot dot respect plus plus Quote.
Speaker 0: sure you can go through all those second-hand bookstores and strip them of anything.
Speaker 0: They'll make a profit.
Speaker 0: It makes the store less interesting for the rest of us who actually want to read the books we find.
Speaker 0: I like the search which may turn up treasure I recognize or may turn up something obscure that I but virtually nobody else wants to read.
Speaker 1: You can just do that on the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, fuck you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like I Think a lot of it is.
Speaker 1: it's.
Speaker 1: it's like feelings and nostalgia.
Speaker 1: Like people say oh, I like to hold it in my hands It's like that's a legitimate thing.
Speaker 0: But to then say therefore you smart person should use your smartphone to find a smart price Because then this if you TV take it to the logical extreme the store won't exist anymore.
Speaker 1: They won't be able to go there anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the store only exists because there's so many stupid people.
Speaker 0: It's the nostalgia.
Speaker 0: People are not the majority of the market either They're the minority.
Speaker 0: We're the minority.
Speaker 0: the majority just doesn't know better.
Speaker 0: When I every time I'm in a Best Buy or a surgical circuit city or a store like that I guess not Circuit City anymore.
Speaker 1: That was a long time ago.
Speaker 1: I forgot they existed.
Speaker 0: remember Well, I guess FYE is still around.
Speaker 1: media play media play was the best.
Speaker 1: media play was the best one Because that's the real media play cuz actually competed with the internet.
Speaker 1: That's why they're out of business.
Speaker 0: Yeah, media play was the store that sold what the internet now sells.
Speaker 0: Yeah, media play was great when I couldn't buy stuff on the internet and sure was Plus that one media play in Rochester is one of the only Profitable ones toward the end as far as I could tell and it actually sir.
Speaker 1: I bought my GameCube.
Speaker 1: there They serve nerds.
Speaker 1: Well, they're like, this is our IT could pre-order stuff easily You know you would.
Speaker 1: I'll bet that that you would actually get the stuff you pre-ordered.
Speaker 1: if you pre-ordered something You have like a pre-order bonus.
Speaker 1: You'd get the bonus.
Speaker 1: I had D&D books.
Speaker 0: They had I will bet money that that media play if media play had gone under and somehow that media play had been exempt from The bankruptcy could have stuck around.
Speaker 0: maybe they would had to get rid of all those CDs.
Speaker 1: They had a huge music section and a whole bunch of other crap They were mandated to have.
Speaker 0: that cuz that never sold that.
Speaker 0: the manager herself said that yeah This anime shit is like half our money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they sell anime shit.
Speaker 1: They had you know, some nerdy books.
Speaker 1: You know that kind of thing whatever.
Speaker 0: but anyway I I don't know what to do about this because stores are literally like yelling at people and like making people leave or just scan.
Speaker 1: If anyone yells at me, I'll just leave I'll be like fine no money for you I'll never come back here.
Speaker 1: And in fact, I'm telling everyone else never come back.
Speaker 0: Yeah At least I do a public service whenever I'm in a Best Buy and I I love the look on Best Buy employees faces cuz they Work there, but they don't own Best Buy's They don't really care.
Speaker 0: But they're still annoyed a little bit when you know I'm standing looking at something and a guy's like Asking him a question and I just kind of look at Amazon to see what it really cost and I turn and say yeah You can buy that exact same thing on Amazon for like 40 bucks less and then just walk away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I love doing that.
Speaker 0: one Best Guy guy was like, yeah, but you won't get the extended warranty.
Speaker 1: Actually if you buy it with the American Express card you will get an extra warranty on time.
Speaker 0: If everyone knew that that benefit would go away.
Speaker 0: I think it's only there because most people don't know all those.
Speaker 1: the reason all those part of the reason all those benefits exist is No one knows about them.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So do you have anything cuz I got one more thing I want to talk about.
Speaker 1: Alright, let's just get it over with cuz I'm way hungry and I'm gonna make some awesome dinner.
Speaker 0: Alright, there's a slash shot article on like the 12th.
Speaker 1: So like last week on a Tuesday We haven't done tech stuff in a long time So that's plenty.
Speaker 0: and it basically said that people are stupid with their passwords online and it made all these kind of disparaging remarks.
Speaker 0: But yeah, the stupid users like they use passwords incorrectly and I read the.
Speaker 1: I think the biggest problem is simply that it's it.
Speaker 1: There's nothing wrong with the people passwords people make.
Speaker 1: I mean except for the people who make a password.
Speaker 1: That's like password or admin or ABC 123.
Speaker 0: You don't need a password.
Speaker 0: That's 16 like high ASCII.
Speaker 1: It helps to have something that's a little bit complicated likes and something that's something that no one you know can figure out.
Speaker 1: Right, a lot of people will make something like the name of their dog, but now it's like, okay great That's you know, no one's gonna figure it out some stranger, but everyone you know can figure it out.
Speaker 1: So you wonder you know most of the time when you hacks, you know Some people talk about oh you hacked my myspace.
Speaker 1: It's cuz he figured out your password cuz he knows you personally, you know?
Speaker 1: Or they look at your profile and they figure out your password from your profile
Speaker 0: or keylogger But
Speaker 1: or keyloggers, you know, but that's that's much more rare As long as your password isn't something personally that someone can figure out about you if they know you and it's not something completely stupid.
Speaker 1: The biggest problem is people tell people their passwords.
Speaker 1: Don't tell anybody don't tell your your wife don't tell nobody.
Speaker 0: I don't think that's the biggest problem anymore.
Speaker 0: That is a huge problem.
Speaker 0: But reading this article I realized that one Everyone recommends like have a huge hard-to-remember password that's unique to every site you visit.
Speaker 0: No have like two throwaway passwords for all the throwaway bullshit sites.
Speaker 0: The only things that actually need a password that is actually difficult are your bank Yeah, and any financial stuff like you have Scott trade account or something?
Speaker 0: But more important than that your goddamn email address because if you Compromise someone's email address you can compromise every other account they've got in the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz all you have to do is search through their email figure out the username go reset the password Get the new password from their email.
Speaker 1: They're fucked Yeah, but the thing is if let's say someone compromises your Facebook if you still have your email you can recover your face.
Speaker 0: But yeah, but if you if someone compromises your email you are so fucked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mail is probably the most if you have to rank all your passwords.
Speaker 0: I think email is actually number one in this world today.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, unless you are a lot of you doesn't do anything important on the internet.
Speaker 1: See I've been using super gen pass and the way super gen pass works is one of those domain hash salt thingies.
Speaker 1: So what basically the way it works is you have one password that you remember and make it a good one, right?
Speaker 1: Because if but what happens is you go to a website.
Speaker 1: Let's say I go to a website for American Express.
Speaker 1: it basically takes the American Express comm domain Combines it with my master password and generates a new password.
Speaker 1: That's crazy complicated and it uses that as the password for the site.
Speaker 1: So what I do is I just type in the one password that I remember and then I go to any website and I click the super gen pass thing and Automatically spits out the password for that site.
Speaker 1: So I have a different password for every frickin website.
Speaker 1: That's crazy complicated.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what most of them are, but I don't have to remember all of them.
Speaker 1: and super gen pass.
Speaker 1: You know, you normally would be like whoa What a super gen pass disappears, but super gen pass is a little bit of JavaScript and I've got it saved.
Speaker 1: So I have it forever in case anything happens.
Speaker 1: and they have a mobile site and they've got it all.
Speaker 1: it's all set up It's all good.
Speaker 0: Now a poor way to go.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 1: it's not the best solution.
Speaker 1: There's new a better solution I'm gonna switch to and the better solution is a password card.
Speaker 1: This is a website you go to and you print out a password card and it generates one randomly and it's basically just this grid Of random symbols and each row and column has a symbol on it identifying it.
Speaker 1: so you could just be like, alright I'll remember that the first eight symbols in the dollar sign column are my bank.
Speaker 1: So you look and there's a password right there for you.
Speaker 1: But if you lose the card someone looks at and they go Uh, it's just a card with a bunch of crazy symbols on it doesn't help them at all.
Speaker 0: And even you know brute-forcing is not an issue anymore because every site that's worth anything After you try three or four times it slows you down or locks you out or something.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean a brute-forcing from that angle.
Speaker 1: But even then if your passwords are hashed and salted in the database as someone who has access to the database So if it's an inside job, it's still gonna be really hard for them to get your password.
Speaker 0: Uh, unless it's a shady like, you know crappy for a lot of places do not salt and hash the password properly Even if you do nothing else.
Speaker 0: if you just use like the lowest goddamn level Apache like HT access and HT password You're fine.
Speaker 1: Well, mostly fine.
Speaker 0: Well, you're fine enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah, mostly not completely.
Speaker 1: you're fine for morons But still they're hacker people who just be like they'll break that so fast.
Speaker 0: They have to break in.
Speaker 0: usually they have to at least break Apache right but it's easy to do that.
Speaker 1: if someone's who someone Who's not doing stuff properly?
Speaker 1: It's already they're all.
Speaker 1: their whole thing is gonna be easy to destroy.
Speaker 1: true true Yeah, they're gonna have holes all over.
Speaker 0: actually what I want.
Speaker 1: You're either Swiss cheese or your Fort.
Speaker 1: not There isn't a lot of in between.
Speaker 0: I have my Yuba key and I have an open ID And I use that for every site that takes it which currently is fucking nothing.
Speaker 1: I'll actually a lot of sites use open ID.
Speaker 0: They're just not sites that you use Yeah, but nothing that I use except uh, well nothing now Yeah, no, but you know.
Speaker 1: if thing about Yuba key and other, you know, is that?
Speaker 1: If you're making sites for yourself your internal stuff at a company or like our own geek night stuff You can make it use The UV.
Speaker 0: well open ID is interesting because it's not.
Speaker 1: you have your own WordPress blog.
Speaker 1: You can install the Yuba key plug-in open IDs or something like open ID.
Speaker 0: not to plug open ID because it does have its problems.
Speaker 0: Not to say that I promise is open idea.
Speaker 0: Nothing fucking uses it.
Speaker 1: every the lot of stuff uses it Not enough stuff stack overflow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I use it for that.
Speaker 1: I think the thing is that most sites right are actually open ID providers.
Speaker 1: So like you get you know, Google your Google account is an open ID and your Facebook account is an open ID But you can't use your open ID from Google to log into Facebook.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I want a universal one.
Speaker 1: They're not consumers They're just they're their providers.
Speaker 0: Also, like maybe a different company could do it better or different open version or whatever There's.
Speaker 0: there's different ways to go about it But with something like open ID.
Speaker 0: the primary benefit of it at least in my opinion is proof of identity more so than authentication.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's the ability to say look I made this post and I am me Yeah, or I am X this and I was you know, oh I can prove later that that was me.
Speaker 1: Well, oh off is helping with that a bit.
Speaker 1: But oh off is not the same thing as open ID.
Speaker 1: people get them confused a lot.
Speaker 1: They're actually completely separate.
Speaker 1: What Oh off is is is when I go to say your website and your website is some integration with Facebook Right.
Speaker 1: I mean I could use you know, Oh open ID to log into your website with Facebook.
Speaker 1: But Oh off is basically I give you permission on Facebook to do stuff with my Facebook account, right?
Speaker 1: It's it's the other direction, right?
Speaker 1: So if I want to log into rims website with Facebook That's open ID.
Speaker 1: if I want to give rim the ability to do stuff to my Facebook Then that's Oh off right?
Speaker 1: There's two things going on there and people.
Speaker 1: people are not, you know Always up on that.
Speaker 0: so something Google's been doing lately my last thing and Facebook is doing it now, too.
Speaker 0: But Facebook introduced their one-time passwords.
Speaker 0: if you set it up get this?
Speaker 0: you text some number.
Speaker 0: It texts you back a temporary password that you can log in in the next 20 minutes.
Speaker 0: All right, and That's a great part of the problem is great part of the problem of email You know being the point of attack for everyone is that you can reset all the passwords to email.
Speaker 0: It's a hell of a lot harder to hack someone's phone Straight up.
Speaker 1: It's really easy to send someone's text.
Speaker 1: It's really hard to intercept someone's text unless you take their phone.
Speaker 1: Which do you do have to worry about?
Speaker 1: people are very close to you.
Speaker 1: A lot of people are very free about like letting their family members mess with their phone and sharing, you know This is something people really need to do.
Speaker 1: and you know, I mean a lot of people have you know, trustworthy families.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of shared passwords in situations where there's no better solution But everyone should have their own.
Speaker 1: the thing is a lot of people Have you know, they get fucked by the people that are closest to them, you know There's plenty of people have like shitty parents or you know shitty, you know spouses or shitty siblings.
Speaker 0: Not just text out.
Speaker 1: don't share your shit.
Speaker 1: Don't let anyone even touch your phone, you know, even if it's like, you know You're your person you've been married to for 50 years.
Speaker 1: Do not let them touch your phone.
Speaker 1: get your own damn phone Right because who knows what the fuck right?
Speaker 1: You can't even if it's it could be incompetence that fucks you over, you know, well, I would argue more generally.
Speaker 0: I mean, I let people use my phone sometimes because there's not much on my phone.
Speaker 1: You could do No, but I mean like, you know, somebody could get a one-time password with my text messaging, you know It's.
Speaker 1: that's pretty serious.
Speaker 0: if you have my phone, you know, but at the same time my bank.
Speaker 0: I can see if they did that.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't let my phone to a stranger.
Speaker 1: No, my bank tells me to verify like you could do it by email or by text or by telephone audio call.
Speaker 1: So it's like you got two out of the three ways to get to my bank account if you got my phone, you know, so Well the real thing.
Speaker 0: look at society in general.
Speaker 0: forget all the tech stuff.
Speaker 0: most murders and most Violence and most robberies and most kidnappings and most sexual assault are close friends and family.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not like crazy random psycho on the street or like dedicated robber.
Speaker 0: are the rarity.
Speaker 0: Notwithstanding the anecdotal evidence the scotches got robbed by a stranger by not my family.
Speaker 1: I could have been someone I know was it you?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was me.
Speaker 1: Where's my TV?
Speaker 1: Why do you think I have two Xboxes, you know, I should just steal your Xbox.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't have to buy a new one.
Speaker 1: You have more money.
Speaker 1: You go buy a new Xbox.
Speaker 1: I'll just take yours.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening.
Speaker 0: music can't leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.