Speaker 0: It's Wednesday November 3rd.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 0: tonight 2010 we review eaten of the East.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: I Gotta say the year we've had like five years of geek nights.
Speaker 1: I don't think it sounds good when you say the year And it's also not necessary because if someone I'd like on the daily show any like real show.
Speaker 1: It's like September 28th 2014 sounds good when they say because of their style.
Speaker 1: if you could reformat the Opener somehow to get the year in I think it's fine.
Speaker 0: You know it's blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: 2010.
Speaker 0: How does 2010 in any way sound bad?
Speaker 1: It sounds bad?
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: what's bad about it?
Speaker 0: It just sounds bad.
Speaker 1: I was aesthetically displeasing to you.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone else cares.
Speaker 1: I think it is not necessary.
Speaker 0: I think it's very necessary because we've had five years of show.
Speaker 1: Figure out what year the show they're listening to is.
Speaker 1: I mean it's.
Speaker 1: you know it might be hard to figure out the date and the Month.
Speaker 0: it's all the iTunes users though.
Speaker 0: They'll never come to the website.
Speaker 0: They'll have no idea.
Speaker 0: There's no way.
Speaker 1: if they're using iTunes the date is in fucking iTunes.
Speaker 0: only if they look at it I know it's also on your iPod.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they don't look at it It's all right, but in there if they really need to know what year it is then they'll look Yeah, mark my words someday like Otakon.
Speaker 0: like four years from now Someone's gonna call us and be like you said you were gonna be at Otakon.
Speaker 1: That's their own damn fault for being a Moran.
Speaker 0: see I can agree with a lot of your points But I can't agree that it somehow sounds bad to say the year It.
Speaker 1: it sounds bad the way we have it structured.
Speaker 1: why restructure it to get the year in there?
Speaker 0: It's you know Wednesday November 3rd 2010.
Speaker 0: No Scott sucks, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: It's no good.
Speaker 0: So I have been watching a bunch of anime lately And I've been trying to use the more legitimate means of watching anime Which doesn't matter because half the anime I want to watch aren't released in the US.
Speaker 1: anime I'm watching right now is galaxy railways, which I bought completely legitimately from those incredibly inexpensive DVDs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and apparently there's a whole this is only the first 20 some odd episodes And there's actually a lot more that are not on DVD.
Speaker 0: And I just got my try gun box set that I paid $30 for.
Speaker 0: re-released.
Speaker 1: That's less.
Speaker 1: It's like only a little over a dollar per that per episode.
Speaker 1: That's a good price.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think it's definitely worth it for one of the best anime ever.
Speaker 0: I I hope it stands up because I haven't seen it in about seven years.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen it in a long time, but I think it'll hold many times back then.
Speaker 0: I think it'll hold up We'll see.
Speaker 0: but so I'm watching that and I've been watching Eden of the East which you know obviously reviewing.
Speaker 0: But I've been trying to watch a lot of anime through the anime news networks kind of hobo Hulu equivalent.
Speaker 0: Why are you doing that?
Speaker 1: Why don't you use a crunchyroll?
Speaker 0: So, you know, the East was released legitimately.
Speaker 0: crunchyroll is not gonna have it.
Speaker 0: Oh crunchyroll doesn't have it now because it's released legitimately.
Speaker 0: I could get it.
Speaker 0: I mean there are towards I could get.
Speaker 0: so I go to the anime news network thing Which links to like the different websites and they've got a million anime.
Speaker 0: You can just watch them subbed.
Speaker 0: They've got dubs for a lot of the shows.
Speaker 0: It's not that bad except the video quality is pretty low.
Speaker 0: It takes forever to load.
Speaker 0: the ads don't work at all.
Speaker 1: It's a good thing.
Speaker 0: It is a good thing except that every time it comes to the point where the ad would play and crunchyroll's ads works.
Speaker 1: They're always watching these stupid skittles ads.
Speaker 0: over and over again A pop-up appears over the video that you have to close.
Speaker 0: that basically says trying to load ad Oh, and then it just immediately plays the rest of the episode Alrighty, so I can't really complain about that.
Speaker 0: Except the pop-up keeps coming this kind of annoying.
Speaker 1: and Well, imagine an ad every time that pop-up shows up.
Speaker 1: and how glad you are is just a pop-up.
Speaker 0: Even if the East has a really good opener It has that Oasis song.
Speaker 0: like it's a solid anime opener the kind like a ghost in the shell openers.
Speaker 0: Well, I'll watch it every single episode.
Speaker 0: Like I'll just watch it every time.
Speaker 1: I didn't watch it every time I watched it enough times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they changed the opener Because they couldn't afford to pay Oasis for the rights to the song.
Speaker 1: How come the Japanese could afford it apparent?
Speaker 0: I don't know what happened in Japan, but at least in the American release They changed it to this Japanese song.
Speaker 1: and how come when the Japanese people pay how come that doesn't include the rights for The showing the show in every country?
Speaker 0: because DDR was never even licensed in the US.
Speaker 1: I know right it's like if I buy.
Speaker 1: if I make a movie and I pay a Rim for a song he made to put in my movie Then I sell that movie in other countries.
Speaker 1: I shouldn't have to pay again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but copyright laws really broken.
Speaker 0: so bullshit, but they made you know, right boy they made an opener.
Speaker 0: It's they sorry.
Speaker 0: Hi Ami sang it.
Speaker 0: It's really really stupid and it makes the show feel like a crappy kind of standard show Like watching the opener with that music has such a different vibe that I probably wouldn't have bothered with the show right away Had I seen that first?
Speaker 0: Have the reason I watched Eden of the East was that I watched the Japanese opener and I was really intrigued.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, you know the abuse of greatness and all that it was.
Speaker 1: isn't this the main bit for our show?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so are you wasting it in your news section?
Speaker 0: cuz I'm reviewing this meta stuff That has almost nothing to do with the show.
Speaker 0: Well, you're reviewing the opener of the show right now Yeah, and the opener of the show is not on the legal way to watch the goddamn show.
Speaker 0: So I just pirated blu-ray rips of Eden of the East and much better idea much better idea.
Speaker 0: There's no broken ad that pops up every few.
Speaker 0: Let's see.
Speaker 1: Why are people pirating things?
Speaker 1: because legitimate stuff sucks.
Speaker 0: It was faster to download the torrent the blu-ray HD rip than it was if I added up all the delays.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to watch the show on anime news network because it takes forever to load even on my files.
Speaker 1: I don't know why crunchyroll doesn't have it.
Speaker 1: I mean crunchyroll has other legitimate things.
Speaker 0: I know there's definitely the Legit right.
Speaker 0: It's trying something.
Speaker 0: I mean this anime news network thing even pops up like watch it legally.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know I'm not impressed but there is a lot of anime there and you can.
Speaker 0: I would recommend if you're a punk Kid and you don't want to use bit torrent you can watch the show with the same impact on the anime industry Technically legally and still not see ads.
Speaker 1: Well So check this out, right?
Speaker 1: I'm checking.
Speaker 1: normally when this remakes or nostalgia trips or whatever I'm like, ah, whatever fuck that shit.
Speaker 1: All right, who cares?
Speaker 1: but Somebody is gonna make a remake of Thundercats.
Speaker 0: Wait, so Thundercats as far as I can tell was just an extended adolescence metaphor where his penis was a sword.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, but anyway, the thing is about Thundercats why it is different from the other kid grew to symbolize his adulthood.
Speaker 1: Is that why I was a kid, right?
Speaker 1: I mean I liked all those shows the Voltron Transformers I liked GI Joe, but I really only liked the movie.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 1: actually really I wasn't really much about GI Joe at all, but I wasn't.
Speaker 1: you know, the other stuff was all great.
Speaker 1: I love mask and he-man.
Speaker 1: I did not enjoy Transformers that much but Thundercats was like for me at least was like the number one.
Speaker 1: I mean Voltron.
Speaker 1: the robot is the most powerful and of all nothing.
Speaker 0: to be bold It is telling why I had far more Centurions toys than I did Thundercats toys Yeah, but thing is I most?
Speaker 1: I mean, you know how every toy set had like a big toy, right?
Speaker 1: Ninja Turtles had the sewer right?
Speaker 0: I had that no and it was really chintzy.
Speaker 1: and like The techno drone, you know transformers you could get fortress maximum.
Speaker 0: I never had that right?
Speaker 1: I mean there was always a big toy.
Speaker 1: the only thing I ever had the big toy for Was the Thundercats lair with the friggin flashlight in the mouth and the opening hands of the tanks that rolled out.
Speaker 1: That's the only big toy for any of the action figures that I had and I had Frickin lino and panthro and the kids and I had this mum-ra playset where you would spin around and There'd be mother be old mum-ra.
Speaker 1: It would be you know.
Speaker 1: Oh, I remember ads for that and you'd spin it around and then the big mom-ra would come out.
Speaker 1: And then I also had the big mum-ra - and I had fucking.
Speaker 0: I'd see the ads for that crap.
Speaker 1: like right after double-day I had the snake mutant guy and the jackal mutant and I didn't have the bird mutant.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I had I was.
Speaker 1: Thundercats was like number one.
Speaker 0: I never saw the first episode of Thundercats until a few years ago.
Speaker 1: the first episodes the best ever said it.
Speaker 0: I just never saw it.
Speaker 1: It's also a Thundercats movie.
Speaker 1: We're just like a multi-parter situation.
Speaker 0: I never saw that either.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, that's actually you know, it's like it's weird cuz but I did see the My Little Pony movie in theaters.
Speaker 1: exciting Yeah, I think I did too.
Speaker 1: So this remake of Thundercats, right?
Speaker 1: Like why would I get excited about this?
Speaker 1: You know There've been other remakes of things recently and they've been hit or miss and I don't really need to pay attention to that much Thunder.
Speaker 1: what is interesting about this remake?
Speaker 1: Well so far we have three facts about it.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's a whole big article But there's really only three facts in the article that mattered.
Speaker 1: fact number one The guy in charge of it is this Jalen ik guy and apparently he's the guy who did Batman brave in the bold cartoon Which is a very popular and well liked cartoon among the nerds, even though I've never seen it the nerds like it So that makes some people happy.
Speaker 1: All right fact number two Snarf is in it, but he will only say snarf snarf.
Speaker 1: He won't say anything else.
Speaker 0: He's not gonna say Sam a flange.
Speaker 0: Panther said Sam if I have a snarf could also say Sam a flange.
Speaker 1: The thing is I'm like.
Speaker 1: I kind of kind of understand that cuz you were changing the tone of the show.
Speaker 1: if there's a talking Snarf who's sort of like, you know, he's not as he's not a Jar Jar Binks.
Speaker 0: He's definitely the.
Speaker 0: I don't know about this character.
Speaker 1: yeah, he you know, he sort of throws it off if you go with the darker theme, which is what it's going for.
Speaker 1: but I Like I actually don't find snarf to be annoying.
Speaker 1: I think he's just fine, you know.
Speaker 1: anyway, the third and most important fact is that it is a joint venture between Warner Brothers who I guess owns Thundercats now and Studio four degrees C.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: Oh shit that is like doom stamp of platinum 4c is Hot hotness as hotness right.
Speaker 1: all these other remakes did not have like, you know Like huge awesome perfect studio of awesomeness on the list, right?
Speaker 1: You know, so it'll be like that's.
Speaker 1: basically it would be equivalently awesome if they said oh, yeah This is a joint venture between Warner Brothers and Studio Ghibli like oh snap.
Speaker 1: or if they said yeah So she can come back from the dead to do Thundercats.
Speaker 0: You know considering that it's a long adolescence metaphor where the sword is his penis and it grows every time he has to assert himself It should have been guy next.
Speaker 1: That would have been a different show.
Speaker 1: But anyway, yeah.
Speaker 1: So I'm definitely gonna.
Speaker 0: oh, oh my god I got to make a little video mashup now of that scene from the beginning of the Ava movie and Just dub line of saying Thunder Thunder Thunder.
Speaker 1: go for it.
Speaker 0: I'll do it.
Speaker 1: But anyway, this is a I'm liking this.
Speaker 1: This is looking like it's going in a good direction.
Speaker 1: Obviously judgment needs to be withheld until we see the real thing as with all things But I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: I'm slightly looking forward to it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna keep my eye open my eye of Thundera.
Speaker 0: So things of the day.
Speaker 0: I fell into a deep nostalgia trip when I was watching something from the 70s and thought it looked really old and Then suddenly felt the urge to look at things from the 80s and 90s and realized that they look just as old.
Speaker 0: so I have for you two TV shows that I watch and Enjoyed as a kid.
Speaker 0: Alrighty, and it saddens me.
Speaker 1: I was just talking about Thundercats.
Speaker 1: Is it Thundercats now?
Speaker 0: as much as this saddens me?
Speaker 0: There's a YouTube comment on the first one that says quote better than the stuff on g4.
Speaker 1: Okay, it must be video game related.
Speaker 1: It's Captain N.
Speaker 0: I kind of after captain is not better than g4 captain.
Speaker 0: that is not better than g4.
Speaker 0: But do you remember game pro TV barely?
Speaker 0: or the one you probably remember video power.
Speaker 1: I remember video power excellently.
Speaker 1: I was so annoyed about video power because he would end when I got home.
Speaker 1: So I get home and I'd see the velcro and I wouldn't get to see the dude for me.
Speaker 0: It was on before I went to school.
Speaker 0: It was not at 6 a.m.
Speaker 1: Oh mine was.
Speaker 1: it was only on right before I got.
Speaker 1: I would get up at 545 like the middle middle school kids who got home a half hour an hour earlier got to see it.
Speaker 1: The elementary school kids didn't get to see that shit.
Speaker 0: So all I remembered about the show was kids play real video games and compete and it was awesome and wacky.
Speaker 0: and then at the End whoever wins puts down a velcro vest and runs through a mini toy store.
Speaker 1: No You actually had two people on your team and you could.
Speaker 1: you had to take turns going in with the velcro and you had to tag out.
Speaker 0: All I remember is that you would velcro games to your chest.
Speaker 0: and if you Nintendo games if you made it out before The timer went off you got to keep all those games.
Speaker 0: and if you found the secret game You want a special prize like a neo geo?
Speaker 0: Yeah, holy shit.
Speaker 1: And I mean think about you're a kid of one.
Speaker 1: getting one video game is like Oh, I got one Nintendo game like a month And if that I got a lot less than that like one winner a few months, so you get a video game.
Speaker 1: It's like oh my god I got a video.
Speaker 0: watch these kids on TV.
Speaker 1: if they win this game and they're less like video game every second They're going down the shelf being like game game game game game.
Speaker 1: By being good at the games I was already good at he's velcro them to their bodies there this velcro suit and then they have to just leave.
Speaker 1: and it's like.
Speaker 1: It's like shoplifting Toys R Us with no consequences.
Speaker 0: It was like Hey, remember that old contest with Toys R Us the you get five minutes and as many shopping carts as you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how many times did that ever actually happen?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I believe it did.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I just I saw videos of people winning it and I remember them like running down aisles with their hands out like grabbing toys.
Speaker 1: I would have gone I would just gone to three aisles and they luckily these aisles are right next to each other.
Speaker 1: So I was there.
Speaker 1: us Nintendo tiger now would have gone to the video game aisle, right?
Speaker 1: Then right next to the video game aisle and the Toys R Us was the Lego aisle and board game on all the leg And it was the same aisle.
Speaker 1: so I could take a Lego from one side and board game from the other and toss him in And then run the hell out before time ran out and I would just get all the biggest Lego I'd be like, you know what?
Speaker 1: $300 Lego castles fuck.
Speaker 1: Yes, so you do.
Speaker 1: now watching of the biggest castle video power again.
Speaker 0: They're playing Megaman and that's cool.
Speaker 0: But these kids I think that this was a pivotal moment for the two contestants in video power because they any good at Megaman.
Speaker 0: Hey, they were okay.
Speaker 0: They were as good as every kid was back then.
Speaker 0: They were like the legends but these kids have the look of children who came in with expectations had those shattered saw behind the veil now understand what the real world is and Are going to live productive lives.
Speaker 1: then video power served a great purpose even though that is not the purpose It was trying to serve because it served for the greater good.
Speaker 0: You can tell they were so excited because I would have been so excited but they have this look on their faces Like really?
Speaker 0: This is what I was excited about for the last three years.
Speaker 0: This is what I thought would be the climax of my life.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm sure they got excited when they got to go velcro games Except for the kid who didn't get to go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's very Blue shirt and he has a bowl cut.
Speaker 0: He's kind of funny.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those old video game game shows are were exciting.
Speaker 0: What's weird is that TV from the 70s looks better than TV from the 80s and the 90s?
Speaker 1: Well, the reason for that is that TV from the 70s that we still have available to us What we actually have the Masters from the studios.
Speaker 1: But TV from the 80s that we still have available to us was mostly VHS and Betamax recordings.
Speaker 1: Yeah So it actually looked better on the television when you were watching it Even though the technology was largely the same because it was still mostly over-the-air broadcast color TV with no higher resolution or anything Even though the tubes improved in the 80s, right?
Speaker 1: The signal really wasn't any different or better anything like that.
Speaker 1: I guess the cameras also improved at the at the studios.
Speaker 0: more than anything is that this old crap is terrible But the faux glamour that they were trying to convey now actually exists and is called the penny arcade Expo.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that was a lot but I don't know.
Speaker 0: I very much enjoyed watching these and also did not enjoy watching these.
Speaker 1: Alright, so Today is an important day because something is being released and no it is not the Kinect which is also being released at midnight tonight.
Speaker 1: Yeah It is a new album from Machine Supremacy and I like to pronounce the name of their band Maki Nai Supremacy because that's how it's spelled even though technically it's Machine Supremacy.
Speaker 1: and this is important because What are you doing?
Speaker 1: nothing, all right, this is very important because they only release like one album every couple years and Because they are like.
Speaker 1: you might as well call them geek nights the band.
Speaker 1: Alright It is.
Speaker 1: they are in a genre of music known as quote Sid metal because they say it is the chip that were the audio chip from the Commodore 64.
Speaker 0: one of the few things I want to make happen at PAX that doesn't already happen is to have them do a concert.
Speaker 0: Absolutely I would do almost anything to make that.
Speaker 1: and basically they started as a Commodore 64 back cover band doing you know see Commodore remixes of Commodore 64 songs.
Speaker 1: and Now they basically they're a metal band that incorporates these unique sound of the Commodore 64 into their music.
Speaker 1: And they have a new album that just came out called a view from the end of the world.
Speaker 1: It's also the title of the first song.
Speaker 1: All right, but I want to prove to you that That they are geek nights the band.
Speaker 1: All right, and I don't know if they listen to geek nights or what the hell But here are the lyrics to the.
Speaker 1: the second Song on the on the album, which is called force feedback.
Speaker 1: You ready for these lyrics room?
Speaker 1: I'm ready All right, these are.
Speaker 1: these might as well have been written by geek nights.
Speaker 1: Are you ready for this?
Speaker 1: Okay Take a look across this vast uncharted battlefield.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna sing.
Speaker 1: by the way You still don't know your enemy a bunch of pissed-off freaks with infinite mad skills and a newfound taste for blood.
Speaker 1: We made this life.
Speaker 1: You have no place here.
Speaker 1: No, right This is the world you're in and this is where ours begins a borderless nation of thoughts to replace your Walden existence in space.
Speaker 1: Sure, you already know that your age was long ago.
Speaker 1: We augment reality online and you hail from ancient times.
Speaker 1: We are like sleeper cells.
Speaker 1: We hide in plain sight.
Speaker 1: if you can't see you cannot fight.
Speaker 1: This is a war between our culture and your laws with millions born into the cause.
Speaker 1: Now we're taking it back.
Speaker 1: You don't believe me force feedback.
Speaker 1: I don't think you understand.
Speaker 1: these are our shores and our land.
Speaker 1: you are a stranger here and we won't be idle as you interfere.
Speaker 0: Wow, that could almost be the anthem of fortune.
Speaker 1: now There's like two other songs on this on this album.
Speaker 1: that are all there basically geek nights the the album But the geek nice theme song but To further drive this home.
Speaker 1: I want to give you some of the titles to these songs, right?
Speaker 1: So track six well track five is Nova prospect.
Speaker 1: Okay track Five is six is world of light which is like okay world of light whatever but track seven is Shinigami.
Speaker 1: Okay, so you put those.
Speaker 1: so you so far we've got video games if you got Commodore 64, we've got Internet's.
Speaker 1: We've got force feedback.
Speaker 1: We've got half-life 2. we've got death note his crouching tiger hidden sniper Alright.
Speaker 1: so There you have it Mike and I. supremacy has new album.
Speaker 1: It's amazing.
Speaker 0: That was Low energy, I guess it's hard for us to faint like.
Speaker 0: even when I'm excited about some music in the show We don't get yeah, but then we'll have this awesome music playing in the background and we'll be like, yeah Background just play it like now.
Speaker 1: Okay, okay I don't know if you played it or not.
Speaker 1: We'll find out.
Speaker 0: So there before we get to the main event We should talk about the meta moment because we are going to be at magfest.
Speaker 0: We are going to be likely at anime Boston.
Speaker 0: We are going to be at PAX East and PAX West and the book club book is still Max Brooks World War Z Fucking zombies.
Speaker 0: I'm sick of this shit.
Speaker 0: Any other things of course as just as zombies are getting so played out.
Speaker 0: Walking Dead's got his TV show now and zombies are like having this mainstream.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm probably gonna watch that when I go home.
Speaker 0: I was gonna watch it, but I got a game night tonight.
Speaker 1: amuse There is Any other?
Speaker 1: no action going on now?
Speaker 0: nothing.
Speaker 1: There might be some geek nights delays in a few weeks because it's gonna be Thanksgiving in the u.s.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be eating turkeys and shit, which means you can't really podcast when you're full of turkey.
Speaker 1: You could be sleeping and it's not because of whatever chemical that's tripped a fan.
Speaker 1: That's something's bullshit.
Speaker 1: It doesn't make you go sleep.
Speaker 0: So Eden of the East he got.
Speaker 0: she know Eden is Pretty much the newest anime.
Speaker 0: I've watched all the way through almost all the way through in a long time Other than like, you know stuff from the 90s.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I watched the first episode of the show a long ways back like maybe a year ago.
Speaker 1: I think we all that many watched it together and I was like, oh, that's a really interesting and unique premise.
Speaker 1: I'm interested in that.
Speaker 1: I didn't finish watching you.
Speaker 1: I just stopped and then recently I went back to it and I finished the whole Thing.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So the plot of Eden of the East not to spoil anything This is all pretty much first episode second episode stuff to see you.
Speaker 0: You know what you're getting into.
Speaker 0: it's the kind of show that you can sell to someone just by explaining the present the the whole That just explaining the premise the premise.
Speaker 0: Girl from Japan is in America Standing for to the White House.
Speaker 0: out of nowhere comes a naked dude with a cell phone a gun and amnesia Whoa.
Speaker 0: And that's pretty much the plot.
Speaker 0: why is that guy naked?
Speaker 0: what's with the cell phone?
Speaker 0: Why do you have a gun?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know the girls just like a normal Japanese tourist girl.
Speaker 1: She's not like.
Speaker 0: I'd argue that she's desperately cute and not like the main girl characters.
Speaker 0: a lot of other anime.
Speaker 1: She's I mean, she's not stupid in my way right like oh save me.
Speaker 1: She's like a normal person who can take care of herself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but she's also not a. She's not crazy or weird or anything, you know.
Speaker 1: she's intelligent and just a smart normal person and the only reason that she's there alone is because she was on like a trip with her school like a graduation trip or something and she She decided that she was gonna like, you know, they went to New York I think and she decided to take a side trip to DC because she want.
Speaker 1: she thought that the White House is like the center Of the world and she wanted to see the center of the world.
Speaker 1: You know, she had like a thing about it.
Speaker 1: She's like well, I'm here I'm gonna go check it out and then go back on my own.
Speaker 1: so she did so.
Speaker 0: What it's really about which is also not a spoiler because you get this pretty much right away Dude has a cell phone that has eight point two billion dot yen, which is like a hundred million dollars Which actually isn't that much money?
Speaker 0: It's I'll take it and he has to spend it all and he'll die when he spends it all and he'll die if he doesn't Spend it all and he has to save Japan with it.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, and it's basically the phone.
Speaker 1: he can call up on the phone and get anything He wants like he's in fact a sell-a-sell.
Speaker 0: Skip all the kind of details.
Speaker 1: you can call anything on the phone.
Speaker 1: He could just be like kill so-and-so and then suddenly something will happen that will result in that person.
Speaker 0: There's a great point where he's tested out and he calls the phone.
Speaker 0: He's like, yeah, he basically says yeah I'd love the Prime Minister to say uncle.
Speaker 0: and there's this live conference and the Prime Minister like gets a he's watching Japanese C-SPAN and then uncle uncle uncle.
Speaker 1: And it's like why And it totally worked.
Speaker 0: and it's this huge kind of spy Conspiracy technology.
Speaker 0: half of it's about Google goggles and it goes in a lot of directions.
Speaker 0: You really wouldn't have expected from the first episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's where it's like.
Speaker 1: the first episode was so great And I just wanted it to go.
Speaker 1: Basically, like what I wanted was to take the premise of the first episode and attack it straight on full force.
Speaker 1: But it sort of diverges and gets into these other side Tangents and it's sort of like, you know There's all sorts of stuff going on and which thing is the primary thing sort of changes like it goes down these branches along the Way and gets away from the main thing of what the hell with the sell us out shit, right?
Speaker 1: You know and naked guy who lost all his memories showing up, you know, it doesn't stick with that.
Speaker 0: There's just something about that Naked dude with the gun of cell phone and amnesia and you throw that in in the first five minutes of the first episode of a Show with no backstory at all.
Speaker 1: That's awesome But they sort of get away from it a little bit, you know, he's not naked.
Speaker 0: much longer though Johnny's come up a lot.
Speaker 0: In fact, I would say that's what the show is really about because in that episode There's a lot of English being spoken.
Speaker 1: Surprisingly well for an anime there it is strange how much like English speaking is going on like the helicopter pilots all speak English.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that female cop who's like, let me see your Johnny which I assumed meant.
Speaker 0: Let me see your ID And he showed her as Johnny.
Speaker 0: and then later there's a Johnny thief who yeah, Johnny thieves steal penises.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, she murders guys and cuts their penises off either before or after and she had a good reason for doing it I guess somewhat kinda.
Speaker 0: that's one of those side plots that I really didn't care about.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 1: I really have much to do with the main and it's not even that many episodes, right?
Speaker 1: It's like 13 11 It's 11 episodes really it's not.
Speaker 1: So have it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I haven't watched the movies either.
Speaker 1: I heard that they were bad, but I don't know I got to watch them.
Speaker 0: So a little bit about this show though.
Speaker 0: It's a production IG which is a plus one already.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's like, you know studio 4c is plus 10 but production IG is plus a lot.
Speaker 0: Anyway, they did stand-alone complex and it was on no automata and they also did.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, that was all studio 4c.
Speaker 1: Nevermind.
Speaker 0: So The director Kenji Kamiyama is actually pretty well known.
Speaker 0: It looks like he worked with Satoshi Konoha bunch.
Speaker 0: He worked on minipato Jin ro.
Speaker 0: he also happened to direct screenplay and write standalone complex.
Speaker 1: This is a winning bus production IG rights.
Speaker 1: He must work there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there's obviously a winning guy.
Speaker 1: They put the a-team at production IG on this job.
Speaker 0: now Sometimes when you say like oh so and so like so and so's show like this guy directed this It's easy to say like.
Speaker 0: oh he directed it.
Speaker 0: But all these other people is based on a manga or anything.
Speaker 1: just he just wrote it.
Speaker 0: He wrote the script the screenplay did the storyboards for a bunch of the episodes was the original creator and the director.
Speaker 1: So who wrote the movies that people supposedly say also him?
Speaker 0: Okay, so this is basically him.
Speaker 0: all the way except for the character designs themselves.
Speaker 0: They actually got Chica Umino who did a honey and clover and I love the character designs.
Speaker 1: Okay, they're really good They're pretty good.
Speaker 1: The girls cute.
Speaker 1: Well characters are distinct.
Speaker 1: You can tell them apart.
Speaker 0: Saki the main character, you know, the girl who meets the naked guy with a cell phone gun and amnesia is Really cute with like kind of this big cheeks and a wide face with like a wide thin smile And all the characters do this thing which I mean I haven't really read much of honey and clover but Emily's read a lot where they'll like put their hands up in an X and Like make a funny face whenever anything scary happens.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, that's a classic thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's basically the closest to super deformed or anime BS that the show gets to.
Speaker 0: it's really cute.
Speaker 1: So is this a good show?
Speaker 1: I think it's.
Speaker 1: I think it's mostly a good show, right?
Speaker 1: It's like it's not an amazing show like oh my gosh.
Speaker 1: But I think what it is is sort of has a little bit of the Death Note problem, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz in Death Note, there's like a two parts of Death Note, you know There's the first half and the second half and the first half is so good that even though the second half I still think is good is not as good as the first half.
Speaker 0: the relativity of it makes it seem like the second half Like if I drank a glass of $500 Kings fee and then after it I had $100 Kings fee the $100 Kings fee.
Speaker 0: It's still really really really good and expensive and valuable, but I just had the $500 Kings fee.
Speaker 0: exactly, right?
Speaker 1: So I think the first episode of Eden of the East remember there's only 11 right is a really good episode.
Speaker 1: I like you can't have a better first episode of anime.
Speaker 1: that makes me want to see the rest of the show But after that it sort of goes.
Speaker 1: it doesn't go down in the shitter.
Speaker 1: It just goes down.
Speaker 1: You know, it's not as it doesn't stick with what it started.
Speaker 0: the rest of the show does not give me the same feeling because what I liked about the show and they're mostly in the first episode that one the character is really cute and they react in surprising ways and the plot was interesting.
Speaker 0: and aside from all the Johnny's there were a ton of movie references that were kind of integrated with the plot of Eden of the East.
Speaker 0: but we're also kind of these meta references and they were all over the place and it just worked really well.
Speaker 0: and the kind of budding pseudo romance between Saki and Akira who's the?
Speaker 0: you know, the man the naked guy who on nakeds was just really charming.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of charm in the first episode and there was charm in the second episode and the charm kind of Went away and got replaced by a solid B anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if it had kept the charm up It would have been a B plus a minus.
Speaker 1: Yes The problem was is how do you keep up the charm while also making progress on this dark intriguing?
Speaker 1: You know sci-fi plot, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they when they started to investigate like the parts with the doctor.
Speaker 1: That was pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: But then when they got further into the parts with the Johnny thief and the hacking fat guy You know, I guess the hacking fat guy had a little bit of charm.
Speaker 0: So there's a guy in the show Itazu.
Speaker 0: they call him pants cuz.
Speaker 0: the kanji of his name could also be right everywhere.
Speaker 1: He never wears pants.
Speaker 1: He's rim.
Speaker 0: Well, he used to wear pants and he became a hikikomori because one day he was sitting, you know He just graduated he wasn't doing so well in life and his pants were hanging up to dry and they blew away And he never left the house again.
Speaker 1: You only had one pair of pants.
Speaker 1: That was it.
Speaker 0: He didn't have any others but to his credit He's the hikikomori scary dude, and when you finally meet him in the show and they show him to you He's fat and disgusting But at the same time he is a legitimate awesome smart hacker.
Speaker 1: He's not you know.
Speaker 1: I think it's actually a pretty good portrayal of a hikikomori right because a lot of the portrayals You see like in welcome to NHK or whatever are Perhaps too realistic Scary people you'd never want to be around.
Speaker 1: but this guy it's like he's actually not a bad guy.
Speaker 1: He's not really bad or evil or freaky or disgusting.
Speaker 1: He's just a guy who doesn't go outside, but is otherwise.
Speaker 1: he's a smart hacker.
Speaker 1: He's fat just because he doesn't go anywhere not because you know, and it's like, you know It's like I at first like I didn't want.
Speaker 1: you know, I'm not gonna like hikikomori character.
Speaker 1: I can be like all day get him away.
Speaker 1: But you know, I kind of was like hey I could do it This guy is alright.
Speaker 1: I'm with this guy.
Speaker 1: But yeah, at least that part of the show though, even though the character was alright, it was dragon.
Speaker 0: because it got a little too.
Speaker 0: Death node II almost like it started getting into all the procedural Bs of the mystery.
Speaker 0: Yeah and look at something that ghost in the shell standalone complex first gig.
Speaker 0: The main mystery was hardly addressed in most of the episodes.
Speaker 0: There was individually awesome.
Speaker 0: Yes, they stood alone From the complex episodes.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean with only 11 episodes you've kind of got to use every episode.
Speaker 1: But
Speaker 0: at the same time unlike Death Note while it's doing this procedural stuff The Akira is kind of hiding a lot of information from probably the only person in the world He can actually trust to help him out Which doesn't really make a lot of sense both for his character and for the charm of the first episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also they they don't.
Speaker 1: it's like they give the viewer a lot of information, but they don't give you all the details.
Speaker 1: So even after the whole show is over you still have like all these question marks.
Speaker 0: that is just like, all right Worse they give all this information to you and to him but not to sake who is arguably the main character.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's sort of it's like even though she is technically the main character like she's actually getting less screen time as the sucks because I wanted her to be more.
Speaker 0: the Interaction between her and Akira was like the best part of the show.
Speaker 1: That's what the show is supposed to be about.
Speaker 1: That was what the first episode was.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And then the second best part of the show was him fucks in with the phone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: So here how about this?
Speaker 1: right?
Speaker 1: so they bring in when they go back to Japan, right?
Speaker 1: There's all those like sake's friends like the club.
Speaker 1: She's in.
Speaker 0: I hate all of them Why don't know.
Speaker 1: but like what is their club that they're?
Speaker 1: what is their club trying to do?
Speaker 1: Aren't they like they have a goal?
Speaker 0: or they were trying to form a company?
Speaker 0: remember and then it didn't do so.
Speaker 0: Well, and then but it's John I love this character.
Speaker 0: She's like a cute nerdy cute girl.
Speaker 0: Who's also a hacker?
Speaker 1: What about the guy who lives in the desk?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah that guy never mind.
Speaker 0: cuz we just watched Sanjuro not that long ago.
Speaker 0: He reminded me the guy who hid in the closet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, who would open the door and say something.
Speaker 0: They're like good point.
Speaker 0: and then he's like back into the closet.
Speaker 1: I go But the thing is is that it's like where that came out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: It's like suddenly she's at this club and they were doing something and there was no explanation.
Speaker 1: Like we I'm in a club and we were you know, it would have been fine except that then that club.
Speaker 0: So I was confused way too much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wasn't confused for like 10 minutes of like.
Speaker 1: who are these people?
Speaker 1: What are they doing?
Speaker 1: What relation do they have to the characters?
Speaker 1: already know they just didn't explain it all.
Speaker 1: They just went right into it and it took me like at least an episode and a half to figure out like what the fuck These people about it was almost going in an interesting.
Speaker 0: so important because you know Saki has this adventure with this mysterious guy and they have this kind of really interesting and charming interaction.
Speaker 0: And then the show's following that and it's good.
Speaker 0: And then it has a kind of Frodo situation where she's had this experience and she can't go back to normal life and they dwell on that for a little while and Then it just kind of drops that thread when actually that was that thread would have kept the show better than the phone thread.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is right.
Speaker 1: if you that's a good thread, you know can't go back to the normal life.
Speaker 1: But if you look at Frodo, right, they save that thread for the end.
Speaker 0: While they save that thread for the end Frodo doesn't go back to Hobbiton halfway through the books and just like putts around for a couple of chapters Exactly.
Speaker 1: He goes back to Hobbiton at the end.
Speaker 0: Saki goes back to her normal life.
Speaker 0: She has her Frodo moment for like two episodes and then just goes back to the club and the club's really important because they made Google goggles, why is that Google goggles thing even there?
Speaker 1: That is that's like what their company was trying to make, right?
Speaker 1: They were trying to make Google goggles and sell it.
Speaker 0: That was their product Yeah, but the fact that that mattered so much just did not jive with what I liked about the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like what this case this thing came out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: these characters came out of nowhere And you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: I don't think he planned out the whole thing before he started.
Speaker 0: Of course the tertiary con didn't plan out paranoia agent.
Speaker 1: So yeah, but I mean he didn't plan the end.
Speaker 1: this guy didn't play the middle.
Speaker 0: and really what is it with the word Johnny?
Speaker 0: Why did they use the word Johnny?
Speaker 0: They don't know any other words so much to refer to both penises and skeleton otaku aliens?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: remember.
Speaker 0: the skeleton otaku alien shoves his head like up the guy's shirt.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I promise the show is not as weird as I'm making it out to be.
Speaker 1: I would say some things about the ending of the show, but I know you didn't let watch the last two episodes yet.
Speaker 0: Yep, we don't want to spoil it.
Speaker 0: We'll eventually review the movies that people say they're terrible.
Speaker 0: I don't know, but once I finish the show we'll do a spoiler episode.
Speaker 1: The end of the show the last two episodes.
Speaker 1: they answer one of these questions right that you have but it's not.
Speaker 1: it's like.
Speaker 1: You know, sometimes there'll be things that are unexplained and there'll be things that are you know mysteries, right?
Speaker 1: and you actively want to know them and They don't answer all of them.
Speaker 1: And in fact, they answer one that was a mystery.
Speaker 1: It was an unknown but you weren't even asking it or thinking about it, but they answer it and that's the big reveal.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, come on Why did you give me something I cared about like who is the supporter?
Speaker 1: or something like?
Speaker 0: they tell you who?
Speaker 0: mr Altas I'd always it's guys.
Speaker 1: it though.
Speaker 1: It was that's a question that you're asking.
Speaker 1: So then it's not something to answer.
Speaker 0: It's something you're actively questioning to sake and Akira Get together.
Speaker 1: if it's something that you're actively questioning like I really want to know this then they don't answer.
Speaker 0: But if it's something they're gonna be like the cell phones were powered by nuclear power, you know, the battery was infinite.
Speaker 1: You know how.
Speaker 1: there's things you know, you don't know and there's things you don't know.
Speaker 1: you don't know.
Speaker 1: It's one of the things you don't know.
Speaker 1: not one of the things you know, you don't know Huh?
Speaker 0: Like why do you get rid of his memory?
Speaker 0: or how or what the fuck?
Speaker 1: Here's the priority you can't.
Speaker 1: it's something you think it up.
Speaker 0: So it's always gonna be this one thing funny I mean you kind of find out that he erased his own memory like they get to that pretty quick.
Speaker 0: and then the question that two episodes before the end has not been answered yet is What was his plan?
Speaker 0: He erased his own memory and left himself on purpose naked with a gun and a cell phone in front of the White House And somehow that was supposed to further his plan.
Speaker 0: Yeah Does that get answered?
Speaker 1: Maybe he's just being selfish.
Speaker 1: I wanted to get away from whatever horrible things.
Speaker 0: He knew his dog is really cute.
Speaker 1: It's actually a Galaxy Express episode about that.
Speaker 1: You know where there was a. I mean a Galaxy Express a Galaxy Railways or episode where they go to this planet where there's a Some kind of elf creature that steals memories.
Speaker 1: So it's like this is lady who's like, oh, please steal my memories.
Speaker 1: They're so horrible and the other people like.
Speaker 1: I don't want you to lose any memories no matter how horrible they are.
Speaker 1: They're mine, you know.
Speaker 0: and that kind of message, you know, there's an a on flux episode about that, too.
Speaker 0: Ah, it's actually a really good episode.
Speaker 0: Very interesting.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So all in all the show is like a solid B show Like I'm enjoying it about as much as I enjoyed like scrap princess Let's say standard B to watch.
Speaker 1: why not go for it?
Speaker 0: pros I mean the show.
Speaker 0: the characters are really cute and really good.
Speaker 0: The first two episodes are just incredibly charming.
Speaker 0: Just don't be disappointed too much when that awesome like charming interaction with the characters the cute dog with the wings Just kind of takes the back burner to this club and Osugi and all these other characters.
Speaker 0: You really don't care about Mm-hmm, and then the plot gets kind of Death Note II but not in a good way.
Speaker 0: He doesn't just call chewy stuff like.
Speaker 0: he does things that spend his money to solve problems When there were probably much better ways to go about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he makes a lot of really dumb mistakes Yeah, and the show kind of protects him from that.
Speaker 1: I would have almost rather seen a show where it was like what would happen if you got me like got the telephone.
Speaker 1: I just do the same exact thing.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: That's a fanfic someone should make fuck.
Speaker 1: Dueling telephone.
Speaker 1: I Know have two phones Daddy, two phones.
Speaker 1: I'll make a fake phone.
Speaker 1: It looks like the phone but isn't the phone?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so back to the opener.
Speaker 0: though I I really like the opener partly because it's a good like it has.
Speaker 0: it really is Telling you the what the plot is.
Speaker 0: the whole noblesse obligé thing Like it fits the plot really well kind of like how the gundam seed Opener told you the entire plot.
Speaker 1: if you paid attention the gundam seed openers are the best.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were this.
Speaker 0: this gave me the same feel in terms of it was relevant and independently good.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And there's that one quote that really stands out what the abuse of greatness is when it disjoins remorse from power.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm in the beginner, you know in the opener.
Speaker 0: All right, you don't remember that It kind of is really important.
Speaker 0: Anyway, nevermind Good job.
Speaker 1: I was also not paying attention.
Speaker 0: Good show.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.