Speaker 1: Hey, it's Tuesday September 28th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 1: Andy Schatz the creator of Monaco.
Speaker 2: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I'll keep this brief.
Speaker 1: Scott is off playing Civ 5 and I'm gonna go play Civ 5 in a second because Civ 5 is Pretty much taking up all of our time right now.
Speaker 1: But we did right before we did this show get Andy Schatz the creator of Monaco a fantastic game.
Speaker 1: We tried out of packs to come onto the show come into the studio and talk to us a bit.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna skip on talking about news or things of the day or any of that and we'll just get right into the interview Because I think it's pretty fantastic and I look forward to playing the game for real when it's actually out which should be fairly soon.
Speaker 1: So like we said, we've got a guest in the studio tonight Andy Schatz.
Speaker 1: Uh, so we were at PAX and we played this game called Monaco in the expo.
Speaker 2: Well, I had seen the game before on the internets and then I saw it at PAX and I was like, oh man's it's it's There I can actually play this thing.
Speaker 1: I got to do that and we were blown away by it.
Speaker 1: So we called up Andy and we're like, alright, we got to talk to you about this game.
Speaker 1: So Andy Schatz, hello everyone.
Speaker 2: Hey, thanks for coming on the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, absolutely.
Speaker 0: Thanks for having me.
Speaker 0: Thanks for enjoying the game.
Speaker 1: Well, you gave me that little bag of diamonds.
Speaker 1: I had to come get you on the show after that $10,000 in real life.
Speaker 1: Scott swears that they're not Kubrick zirconia, but I checked and they definitely are.
Speaker 1: they have the right refractive index.
Speaker 2: How did you make the refractive index?
Speaker 2: he doesn't just full of crap.
Speaker 0: you know, you actually can blow hot air onto cubic zirconia and and the the What's it called.
Speaker 0: I see I'm not enough of a geek for your show.
Speaker 0: It actually doesn't.
Speaker 0: it holds the moisture on on cubic zirconia.
Speaker 0: Whereas it won't it'll clear up on diamonds.
Speaker 1: I Did not know that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the one layman's way of telling the difference.
Speaker 2: Well, he you know, he did a lot of research and making his heist game.
Speaker 2: He had to know all about these things.
Speaker 1: So tell us about Monaco.
Speaker 1: Like what is this game as you would describe it?
Speaker 0: so Monaco is a Four-player or one to four player co-op stealth game in the in the style of like oceans 11.
Speaker 0: So you're all on a heist Trying to get in and steal something and get out or steal a whole bunch of stuff and get out And each player.
Speaker 0: it's a class based game.
Speaker 0: So it's like Team Fortress.
Speaker 0: So each player Has unique abilities that they can help use to help the team get through the mission.
Speaker 0: So you might have the hacker who can hack computers and plant viruses in them or you have a locksmith who can get through locked Doors much faster than everyone else or the cleaner who's got chloroform to knock out guards with.
Speaker 0: and there's a. there's eight different classes of character in the game and The game's sort of a. it's a. it's a tile based game So you can edit all the levels yourself and make new levels and share them with your friends.
Speaker 0: And yeah, I mean that's the basics of it.
Speaker 0: I think the most unique thing about it is probably the the line-of-sight system.
Speaker 0: It's a top-down game So it plays a little bit like a I'd say like pac-man crossed with hitman.
Speaker 1: Well, it reminded me of the old Ultima games where it would like show and not show things depending on what you could see But actually dynamic in real time as opposed to incredibly cripplingly slow and frustrating.
Speaker 0: Right exactly and it's all sort of vector based.
Speaker 0: So as you come around the corner the areas that you can see are rendered in Their their actual lighting And the areas that you can't see are rendered as if they're a blueprint.
Speaker 0: So as you walk around corners You see areas change from this sort of the dark dim monochrome blue blueprint into the bright full color of the visible areas.
Speaker 1: well, that was actually really cool with the stock because we were playing the game and Watching it not actually playing it.
Speaker 1: It looked like I thought I was gonna embarrass myself.
Speaker 1: Like that's really confusing.
Speaker 1: There's stuff moving all over the place.
Speaker 1: It's just crazy.
Speaker 1: But then when we sat down it like just it made perfect sense and I knew exactly what I was doing.
Speaker 2: It's weird because you're playing it and the gameplay is actually really fast for a stealth game.
Speaker 2: You know, a lot of stealth games are so quiet and you're creeping along like at two miles an hour So no one sees you.
Speaker 2: but like I was like running really fast.
Speaker 2: Even when I was going from bush to bush to bush, which is actually is also really that was one of my favorite parts.
Speaker 1: I was in the bush.
Speaker 1: then we realized we could go from bush to bush to bush.
Speaker 2: Yeah, that's how else you gonna make it over to the window with that Individually along the way like now.
Speaker 1: I'm here now.
Speaker 1: I'm here.
Speaker 2: It's very cute.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's funny.
Speaker 0: Actually if you play the game single-player the game plays a lot more stealthy stealthily, I should say and because you're you know, you're really you can it.
Speaker 0: when you play four players all of the Visible areas are visible to everyone.
Speaker 0: so the game is less about like making sure that you're hiding behind something so that the guard can't see you and more about Working together and using your abilities to accomplish your mission.
Speaker 0: Whereas when you're playing by yourself You don't have teammates around that can revive you if you get shot And you don't have all of their extra abilities to be able to use in order to get out of sticky situations.
Speaker 0: So the game plays much more like sort of I would say a traditional stealth game when you're playing single-player Than when you're playing when you're playing with up to four people.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I think also we played.
Speaker 2: we didn't have anyone using the cleaners So we really couldn't do anything about the guards except run.
Speaker 2: So there was a lot of guards see you but there's not much you can do about it.
Speaker 2: Just go go go as opposed to.
Speaker 2: if we had someone who was the cleaner then we probably could have you know All stayed waited for him to knock out the guard and then you know gone with much less hurrying Exactly.
Speaker 1: We should have just not woken up the guard in the first place.
Speaker 2: I mean the only way we could have the only thing with our class is the only thing we could have done to the guard Was I could have hit him with the dynamite, but I really like blowing a hole in the wall instead Which is way more fun.
Speaker 2: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've.
Speaker 0: actually I was just refining that the redhead which wasn't a playable character at PAX but I Almost put her in and I took her out last minute cuz I didn't think her as her abilities were really balanced enough.
Speaker 0: But her special ability is that she can charm a guard.
Speaker 0: She's like she's like the sexy seductress and she can charm a guard and he'll follow her around for for 30 seconds opening doors for Basically Also, we're just the doors.
Speaker 0: yeah, he'll open anything.
Speaker 0: he'll open anything if she points towards it he'll open it for her Yeah, and obviously she won't shoot at her during that time either.
Speaker 2: So then as soon as the 30 seconds is up, but she's got to start running.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what's the 30 seconds are up?
Speaker 0: She's got.
Speaker 0: she's got like a two-second window in which she his heart is broken and she can get out of there But if she doesn't get out before he before his heart Completely breaks before he's crippled on the ground crying Over her then then she's fucked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the game really like the gameplay is really strong But at the same time it's definitely rockin.
Speaker 1: the style I mean it is super retro and simple looking.
Speaker 1: and was that very much the aesthetic you were going for?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean so.
Speaker 0: so the game won the the IGF independent games festival in 2010.
Speaker 1: I was gonna ask you about that a few questions from now, but I guess you got to it now.
Speaker 1: So sorry.
Speaker 0: Well So so well, it's sort of the part of integral to the story of how the looks evolved.
Speaker 0: I I entered the game in the IGF after I'd only been working on it for about six weeks And at the time it was totally tile based.
Speaker 0: So everything in the game was completely tile based rather than having you know The sort of pretty vector lighting.
Speaker 0: as you walk around a corner things gradually appear.
Speaker 0: Things would light up and darken down Kind of like a roguelike except all in real time And and entirely based upon the light or I was based upon the tiles.
Speaker 1: Wow So you really pushed out the kind of.
Speaker 1: this is my proof of concept like.
Speaker 1: this is what I'm trying to do.
Speaker 1: It's not there yet.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I know when I cuz when I saw the videos originally online before packs, you know It looked totally different than what we played.
Speaker 2: You know, I mean like I could tell it was the same game But the the graphics it was told.
Speaker 2: obviously a lot had changed.
Speaker 0: Yeah it and it.
Speaker 0: You know when I decided I wanted to to make this into a more ambitious game rather than just it originally I actually made the game because I was working on another game at the time a game called venture dinosaur ea Which was a sim game about about Dinosaurs.
Speaker 2: I was like, you know and sounds good.
Speaker 0: No, no and it never came out.
Speaker 0: it's actually the third game in the in a series that I've been working on for years and I'd worked on it for like a year and spent a lot of money trying to get the damn game done and it just wasn't fun and eventually I started taking breaks from working on that game and on the very last time I had to let go my staff and and so I basically cut back to nothing.
Speaker 0: and The last break that I was on I was gonna quit and go get a job.
Speaker 0: You know, I've been I've been indie for about six years And I pulled out this old design that I actually designed like eight years ago for Monaco And started making it and after like a week it was already really fun.
Speaker 0: so I decided well, I better keep going with this.
Speaker 0: so I kept making it and after six weeks, I'd entered it in the IGF and You know, I'm thinking maybe I had a long shot chance of sneaking in with a nomination or something like that And it ended up winning the excellence in design award and the grand prize.
Speaker 0: So at that point there was that that was a 12 to 15 week build that it won with and At that point I figured well I can get I can be a little more ambitious now and actually make it into the game.
Speaker 0: It was meant to be rather than just this sort of little throwaway thing that I was using as a break for my other project.
Speaker 0: and So here I am almost a year later.
Speaker 2: So you wait, it's really surprising.
Speaker 2: You said that Monaco is like an eight-year-old design.
Speaker 2: Is that is that right?
Speaker 2: Yeah Well, yeah but I played it.
Speaker 2: the first thing I thought was this is totally inspired by like four swords or you know All those those GameCube and GBA games at the four player co-op going on.
Speaker 1: I was also reminded of the recent aesthetic of games like passage that had this very particular like kind of large pixel Old-school look or like pac-man versus right, but if it was designed eight years ago You were way ahead of the game.
Speaker 2: then you should have come out with it for the for the GameCube.
Speaker 0: Yeah the original idea actually Was something that I was working at like a triple-a gaming company and luckily I got it in my contract that I owned the design And we actually built a basic prototype of it.
Speaker 0: and the original design actually didn't only had a few preset missions But everyone built their own mansions and all of the missions were basically about breaking into other people's mansions and stealing They're.
Speaker 2: oh my god.
Speaker 1: That's got to be some DLC for monica.
Speaker 0: You got to put that in and so we actually pitched it to Microsoft and Jay Allard In.
Speaker 0: during in some interview someone asked him what the next generation of Xbox Live games would look like and he described our pitch in detail.
Speaker 1: That's got a good feeling.
Speaker 0: but then they turned us down.
Speaker 2: Yeah, so well they didn't rip you off obviously, so I guess it's.
Speaker 2: you know, it's not all that.
Speaker 0: yeah I know they did.
Speaker 0: they didn't make the game and you know That sort of thing probably happens all the time and who knows if he actually was talking about my concept?
Speaker 0: But at the time it certainly felt like he was and So at any rate Yeah, I pulled that old design out the games that I've been making as an indie.
Speaker 0: I'd built up a fan base of people that really liked games about like sim games about nature stuff And so my fan base just this wasn't gonna be something they were interested in.
Speaker 0: So it was something I'd really held off on on approaching as an indie.
Speaker 0: but when I was kind of at wits end, I I said fuck it and Decided to make a game about stealing shit.
Speaker 1: So you definitely said ocean like Ocean's 11 style the kind of like heist.
Speaker 1: I love the you know, what's yours is mine Like what?
Speaker 1: were there any games?
Speaker 1: or like Lupin the third or anything else out there that kind of?
Speaker 2: Influence your get your design and your style like spy for a spy for the NES or anything like that.
Speaker 0: I've actually had a lot of people Suggest a number of different ones.
Speaker 0: mainly it really was hitman crossed with pac-man.
Speaker 0: I've always felt that I love hitman and I like trying to go in and get get Silent assassin on it on the various different the hitman's But it's it.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's a totally flawed game design.
Speaker 0: but the the the thing that I thought about hitman was that the top-down view the mini-map view that you can't you can't move around or see the world when you're looking at the Mini-map, but it was so much more informative than looking at the actual game world That I always thought that the game it's that that game would be better played just from the mini-map.
Speaker 0: And And so I figured you so.
Speaker 0: so that's where the original inspiration for the game came from.
Speaker 0: And then you know and then there's all this these other social elements that I was I was thinking about doing and when I went To prototype it as an indie.
Speaker 0: I just prototyped, you know, the basic version of it without all of this sort of sharing related stuff.
Speaker 0: But the game will actually have an editor and you can share levels And at least for the PC version I'm pretty sure I'll probably I'll probably host a Central level repository where people can upload their levels and rate them.
Speaker 0: So You know, you can go check out the best levels.
Speaker 1: There will be cock towers galore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: So going way back, I mean not about influence in this game in particular, but obviously you're very passionate about gaming.
Speaker 1: So what were the games that kind of started that passion that really got you into this?
Speaker 0: I'm a nerdy old-school PC gamer.
Speaker 0: I actually never owned.
Speaker 0: I didn't own a console until the first Xbox Zork or more like star control.
Speaker 0: Well, both of those games are fantastic.
Speaker 0: I would I'd say my favorite my favorite my two favorite games of all time or at least I should say that probably the two that influenced me the most were Sim City and Ultima for Ultima for that was a quest of the Avatar right, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was in.
Speaker 0: I was a pretty young kid at the time.
Speaker 0: I played it with my dad and I remember I I go to school and at the end of the day I'd actually like rate myself and how well I did in each of the eight virtues Myself.
Speaker 2: the next day we should make an app an iPhone app that does that.
Speaker 1: Just don't let the smell of mundane.
Speaker 0: So, yeah for them for me that was a really influential game just because it was something that affected my life outside of the actual playing of the game.
Speaker 0: And then Sim City to me is still The most.
Speaker 0: I'm totally amazed at at how he actually created that design.
Speaker 0: having made some sim games myself the challenge involved in making a game that simultaneously plays itself and is fun for the player to play is incredibly difficult.
Speaker 0: And I you know, I don't know exactly I don't know how he managed to come up with with the perfect balance in that game But I still think that's the best sim game of all time.
Speaker 0: Or simulation game of all time, I should say One not 2000.
Speaker 2: you like the original better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do.
Speaker 0: It's the simplicity of it.
Speaker 0: I think is There's something to be said for the simplicity of it And I think that if I were going back and making a game like that today I'd want to make it about that simple as well.
Speaker 0: It's because it's something you can just you can get right away.
Speaker 0: There's this.
Speaker 0: I mean the depth of some.
Speaker 0: city 2000 is fantastic and it feels more like a city.
Speaker 0: It's sort of less of a puzzle game But just the original inspiration for for the first Sim City is something that I just find totally brilliant.
Speaker 1: so it sounds like it forgive me if I'm putting words in your mouth that you definitely seem to have this idea and I think I agree with it that Hardware and speed are not the limitations of games anymore and that we can kind of go back to Simple things and just perfect them and make very simple games that are amazing without Necessarily needing a lot of processing power or depth that like Sim City 2000 or civilization 5 would need.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I definitely.
Speaker 0: I definitely believe that the the art of designing a game is the limitation these days.
Speaker 0: It has nothing to do with the hardware I mean, there's.
Speaker 0: there's plenty of other limitations like, you know If you're trying to make a big blockbuster game with that competes with other Big blockbuster games sure you have to compete graphically and you have to have a huge team But at the same time to make really sort of the truly great games.
Speaker 0: That that's not.
Speaker 0: that's not the main limitation.
Speaker 0: It's I like to describe it as I Look at game design and I like to think of game design as that as like a two-dimensional plane with a like height map with peaks and valleys, right and Any time someone decides to design something totally new it's like they're just like randomly dropping a ball somewhere on that 2d plane.
Speaker 0: and When someone then sees that, you know sees that game design and says hey, that's really cool I want to improve upon that.
Speaker 0: and they take it and they tweak it in some way.
Speaker 0: It's like the balls rolling downhill, right?
Speaker 0: and you're always trying to move that ball downhill from whatever that original inspiration was.
Speaker 0: and at some point maybe you want to sort of Reinvent an old classic and you go somewhere near that that where that original ball was dropped and you drop it somewhere nearby and you hope That that's actually downhill from where the original one was.
Speaker 0: and it's entirely possible.
Speaker 0: You're gonna discover a new local minima right that that you're gonna find a valley that was inaccessible from the original spot That's much deeper than the original one.
Speaker 0: So you might you know, you look at like You know doom or Wolfenstein and then doom 2 was just you know Sort of a ball rolling downhill from Wolfenstein and eventually you end up way down with like, you know Call of Duty and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: But then you take something like Bioshock and Bioshock took a big risk and they're like, okay I'm gonna take this and just sort of randomly drop the ball sort of near the FPS Valley But not quite in the FPS Valley and see if it's fun, right?
Speaker 0: and they you know and here they are, you know where the game.
Speaker 0: that feels a little different from an FPS and They're sort of exploring a new valley.
Speaker 2: I don't know if Bioshock was the one.
Speaker 2: I mean Bioshock It's pretty much the same as System Shock - right?
Speaker 2: Yeah, pretty much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that's the point stands that yeah that that the game is.
Speaker 0: you know, it's a it's a tweak It's not just an improvement on the on the genre.
Speaker 0: It's actually it's Somewhat of a reinvention of the game design and that's a big risk, you know You might end up somewhere where it's just not as fun or where there's where there's not even as much potential.
Speaker 0: And clearly the FPS Valley is a deep one because people love playing FPS Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, who knows?
Speaker 2: Platformer Valley.
Speaker 0: Well, but there's there's lots of valleys out there.
Speaker 0: There's lots of lots more to discover.
Speaker 2: So some I'm a programmer by by trade and I noticed that at least at PAX that Monaco you did it with XNA, right?
Speaker 2: Yeah, yes, so Which version of XNA did you use because I like.
Speaker 2: there's sort of like a flux going on.
Speaker 2: It's like there's a really new version like 4. that like yeah, it's sort of or is actually working on the Xbox yet.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it's like it's weird.
Speaker 0: It's like a beta but it's not you know, yeah I think it's only for Windows mobile devices, but they're launching the Xbox version of it in like two weeks or something like that.
Speaker 2: And I did it with 3.2 or whatever.
Speaker 2: The number is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think I I think I started with Whatever the two-point something was and then I went up to three somewhere along the line.
Speaker 2: So have you programmed games and you know other platforms before?
Speaker 2: like, you know, if you have had his XNA compared to those.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm a c++ programmer.
Speaker 0: I My backgrounds in programming.
Speaker 0: I went to school.
Speaker 0: I was an art and computer science double major actually But my my Game development backgrounds in c++.
Speaker 0: I've done a fair amount of like flash work You know and some just rudimentary online stuff PHP and and the like.
Speaker 0: But I love C sharp.
Speaker 0: It's a blast working in C sharp.
Speaker 0: It really is much faster and and I I don't I've never spent more than a couple of hours on a bug, you know an hour Maybe maybe two hours on a bug Whereas you know you're working a c++ and it's like you can spend a week on Stupid, you know memory leak or something like that.
Speaker 0: So so yeah, I absolutely love it That they make it real easy or at least with with X and a X and a makes it real easy to drop assets in make them usable with what you know with all the XML integration and and You know if you use the click once deployment, which I've been using it It's super easy to package up your stuff and and deploy it.
Speaker 0: So yeah, it's basically taken the stuff that I mean, I'm not a very.
Speaker 0: I'm honestly not a really very good techie.
Speaker 0: I'm a quite good programmer, but I'm not a good techie.
Speaker 0: So when I get down to like either systems level stuff or stuff about like, you know Setting up build environments and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: I'm really pretty crappy.
Speaker 1: I feel like a lot of programmers are that way and I even have trouble with that.
Speaker 1: I mean I started using dotnet at work and C sharp Which I can't disparage you for using C sharp because I freaking love it now that I've had to actually use it for a few minutes.
Speaker 1: But even I have trouble like actually deploying my applications to like the different IIS servers and all that.
Speaker 2: You know, not everyone's like a vim terminal guy like me, you know some people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I'm pretty crappy at that stuff.
Speaker 0: So so I'd say I mean honestly I think that I spend if you if you add up all the time I spend like fixing C++ related bugs or dealing with deployment or dealing with system level stuff.
Speaker 0: In the previous games I've worked on I swear it's like at least 50% of my time And now that's now it's like 3%.
Speaker 2: So so when did like did you start programming in college or were you programming earlier than that?
Speaker 0: I've been.
Speaker 0: I actually made my first game.
Speaker 0: I think when I was seven It's a.
Speaker 2: what kind of?
Speaker 2: what kind of computer did you have then?
Speaker 0: That was a Commodore 64 All right.
Speaker 1: So what kind of game was it?
Speaker 1: Are we gonna see this on like the Masters collection years from now?
Speaker 0: But my mom I think it was a one of these like ones where you had to actually where My mom got me a book where you just type in the code that was already in the book and you could play like a slalom Aski slalom skiing game.
Speaker 1: I choose your own adventure game books that were like that and then you had to type in a game and then the game would Give you like a result.
Speaker 1: you have to go to the page number.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Yeah, I remember those ones too.
Speaker 0: And and I think I did my first original design when I was in about like Fifth grade or so something like that.
Speaker 0: I think I had my first made my first good game in seventh grade.
Speaker 0: It was a. it was a warlords clone And It was a hot seat warlords clone and my family used to play it all the time.
Speaker 2: So it's like warlords like the the pong with the four corners warlords.
Speaker 0: No, it was a turn-based large mapped army management game.
Speaker 0: so imagine like She's like, I don't know What's a panzer pan.
Speaker 0: Again yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry panzer blitz.
Speaker 0: No, what's the famous panzer game?
Speaker 0: That was the turn-based.
Speaker 0: That's the rail shoes sounds of blitzes the board game.
Speaker 0: I don't know at any rate that I can't remember what it is.
Speaker 0: It was like game of the year in like.
Speaker 0: It was it this?
Speaker 0: so my game was a turn-based Game with a randomly generated world with cities that you had to conquer and and you know neutral basically a bunch of neutral stuff on the map and you go out and you you conquer a bunch of cities and You use those to to earn gold which you used to hire armies and you go out and conquer the other people cities.
Speaker 1: So you got your family to play this with you?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, my family's a bunch of geeks.
Speaker 0: All right Yeah, like my dad and I were actually making in my in when I was in high school We started making a real-time strategy game.
Speaker 0: That was like a side view underground style.
Speaker 0: So it's actually kind of like pixel-junk shooter as an RTS And I actually still think that's a fantastic idea and one day would love to go back and make that game.
Speaker 1: Well, did you see that video someone made of 8-bit Starcraft?
Speaker 1: It was like a scene based like side view.
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: it sounds like that video would look like the game that you were talking about.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I'm imagining more like a sim ant kind of thing word But there's two.
Speaker 2: there's two different sim ants going on in the same screen in the.
Speaker 2: they're going at each other Exactly.
Speaker 0: It was like it was like cement only with you know, you would try and flood the other guys cave with lava But you're also trying to mine for gold in order to hire your units, you know, that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's not fun And it's all like command and conquer style You know, it's like every idea you're talking about.
Speaker 1: all I can think is I'd play that.
Speaker 0: That's because I'm a great fucking designer.
Speaker 1: So I'm curious.
Speaker 1: Do you have any background at all in mathematics or game theory?
Speaker 0: No, I just been playing games and making games all my life.
Speaker 0: and well computer I you know, I went to school for computer science.
Speaker 0: And so there's a fair amount of math in there it's.
Speaker 0: it's funny too because one of the things that I I've only learned recently is that I Really think about game design as it's the game designers are tend to be split into two camps Designers that really focus on like the mechanics of making a game and they think those people tend to think about like fun is a Commodity and how you can pace the fun and like, you know how all the pieces work together really well.
Speaker 0: And then and that's like the will right camp, right?
Speaker 0: And then there's the the game designers that are all about the experience of playing the game.
Speaker 0: It has nothing to do with like, you know how things work together But just like the sort of emotional experience you have whether it's laughing or you know intense thought or whatever it is.
Speaker 0: Or you know enjoying the music or something and that's like, you know You're Tim Schafer or you're that game company type type designers and and I'm not saying that those designers don't think about it in the other way also, but But I think a really truly great game needs to have both.
Speaker 0: You know that sort of that perfect intricacy of of like a you know a Sim City and also you.
Speaker 0: you really need to focus on the experience of playing the game and sometimes most of the time the things that a player actually Remembers about their favorite games are the experiences not the mechanics.
Speaker 0: There's very few games that actually do really well just based on the mechanics with some exceptions like a Starcraft or Sim City.
Speaker 0: But but people remember the individual experiences of playing a game and those experiences are the ones that I've only sort of recently learned That you really have to focus on making those sort of one-off moments in the games The really memorable moments for for for players so that so that they can you know, so they'll remember them ten years from now.
Speaker 1: So what are some moments that you remember from the last 10 or 20 years?
Speaker 0: Huh, that's a good question.
Speaker 0: That's a really good question.
Speaker 0: well Just individual like I I guess I think about like Tim Schafer and I think about Like various different psychonauts levels, but in particular the the the velvet painting one with the bowl Going around it out to me.
Speaker 0: This is that you this is just top of my head That's certainly not one of my favorite games but That was memorable.
Speaker 0: I think the first.
Speaker 0: there's a couple of in like really tiny indie games that are memorable to me the marriage and passage even though I think you know, they're just tiny tiny little games and I I don't think of them personally as Great great games, but they but they sort of encapsulate that one little experience.
Speaker 0: That is very memorable to me.
Speaker 1: That kind of proves your point that you remember this experience from this one Not that great game because the experience itself was kind of burned into your memory, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and those games really are simply about one.
Speaker 0: They're not about mechanics They are about a single tiny little experience and then and giving that experience to the gamer or the player.
Speaker 0: Let's see, I don't know after that What's what's been a really memorable recent one.
Speaker 0: Josh I you know, I have my memories are my.
Speaker 0: my really great memories are often of the games I played when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: So like like at the end of xcom.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and here's You gotta hear my story about the end of xcom.
Speaker 0: So so this honestly this is the best.
Speaker 0: This is the best ending of xcom anyone ever had.
Speaker 0: So my my main guy that I always relied on his name was Chuck Bryant, right?
Speaker 0: And and you get to the end of xcom you're in the alien base, right?
Speaker 0: and all my all the other guys are getting picked off and Chuck is just barely making it to the end and he he gets into the last room nearly dead where the alien brain is and He he's on like his last hit point and he goes to shoot the alien brain and click click click He's out of he's out of ammo, right?
Speaker 0: So he's like you have a grenade.
Speaker 0: So no I had nothing.
Speaker 0: so I'm like Well, maybe I can throw the gun at the brain and you never know.
Speaker 0: Maybe that'll work All right, so I throw the gun still doesn't?
Speaker 0: it does nothing.
Speaker 0: and then he's out of action points.
Speaker 0: I'm like, ah shit I'm gonna have to do this whole thing over again at that point.
Speaker 0: so the two aliens that are chasing me come into the room and If you remember an xcom you could choose either between a single aimed shot or a triple auto shot.
Speaker 1: Who did anything but first guy?
Speaker 0: Yeah the first guy did an auto shot at me and The first two shots are the second.
Speaker 0: the first shot hit me and then the second shot hit me and Chuck died.
Speaker 0: and then the third shot went over his dead body hit the brain behind him and Destroyed it.
Speaker 0: and then I got the cutscene of like.
Speaker 0: my main character is supposedly leaving the base as the base is exploding.
Speaker 0: So Chuck, of course, you know over his dead body it ends up.
Speaker 0: He ends up crawling back out of the the alien station and and winning in the end.
Speaker 0: So yeah that that is an experience that's totally burned into my head and and and I yeah I definitely think that those are necessary for for memorable couldn't have asked Couldn't have asked for better than an xcom story.
Speaker 1: I feel like xcom did that really well because it named every single character and you'd feel bad when they died and I would I'd identify with them and I'd worry about them and I'd always kind of protect the ones that I liked and kind of hold them Back from the chrysalids and
Speaker 2: you would manage like the inventory of each and every one.
Speaker 2: It's like okay, you're gonna do this and they actually look different like they had different faces and different hair.
Speaker 0: and yeah Yeah, I don't I have no idea whether or not from a mechanical perspective It would be fun these days because you know, all of our tastes have certainly changed.
Speaker 0: But uh, but I certainly remember it.
Speaker 1: So I think if anything the sheer number of people trying to remake xcom, I think but none of them is exceeding.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but there's actually a decent.
Speaker 0: there's a decent indie one that just came out recently.
Speaker 0: It's actually I think in beta called frozen synapse.
Speaker 0: And if you guys like xcom, it's really worth checking out.
Speaker 0: It's a um, it's.
Speaker 0: it's just like xcom Except you're playing against other people and it's all.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: it's basically tactical SWAT teams And it's it's short sessions and it's hot seat.
Speaker 0: and so the server set up so you can actually have a whole ton of games Going at once.
Speaker 0: so, you know you go in and you put in your moves for one game And then you go and put it in the moves for another game and after you do a couple You know one of them someone else will have already put in the moves and you can go back and see what happened.
Speaker 0: that turn And you you put in your moves again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just it's a hasn't gotten a lot of press but it's really well done.
Speaker 0: It's too bad.
Speaker 2: Sit five came out this morning.
Speaker 1: We're trying we're talking to you here and every two seconds someone is it pops up like so-and-so is playing said five so and so Is playing said five and I just want to go play some fun.
Speaker 2: I just I've stopped playing to do this interview.
Speaker 1: So these kind of Experiences aside.
Speaker 1: What are you playing right now?
Speaker 1: Like when you're not busily coding Monica, like what is your go-to game?
Speaker 0: I Hadn't actually was was not playing games for a few months because I was crunching to get ready for packs.
Speaker 2: Yeah, that happened to have us does too.
Speaker 0: Yeah and And before that I was playing the Starcraft beta and I just picked up Stark the regular Starcraft To on Saturday, I think and I did my placement matches.
Speaker 0: I think I got totally lucky on my placement matches because I placed platinum and there's no way I belong.
Speaker 0: plan Are you actually?
Speaker 2: are you actually good?
Speaker 2: because I need cuz you know I'm.
Speaker 2: I'm like pretty much the worst in the universe at Starcraft like if I'm playing against the computer on easy mode.
Speaker 2: just You know the regular old map.
Speaker 2: just you know.
Speaker 2: go, you know, here's right.
Speaker 2: basically what happens is is, you know They send over a wave of you know, little bad guys and I can't even fend off the first wave.
Speaker 2: I'm just done.
Speaker 1: So if you have any spacecraft advice be fair Scott, I should the same problem in advance wars.
Speaker 2: No, I don't have the same exact problem in advance wars.
Speaker 2: I don't get killed by the first wave in advance second wave.
Speaker 2: No Anyway, you might.
Speaker 0: you might want to think about the possibility that you're just stupid.
Speaker 1: It's possible To be fair.
Speaker 1: I'm equally bad at RTS is I just don't advertise this fact?
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's so even command and conquer back that I never beat it.
Speaker 1: I never buy any single-player RTS.
Speaker 0: in my entire life I loved the original command and conquer.
Speaker 0: that's still my favorite RTS and my next game I think is I think I'm gonna try and make the first great console RTS and that's I got him.
Speaker 0: I'm sounding like a cocky ambitious guy.
Speaker 1: So now I'm cuz we have.
Speaker 1: we've talked a lot.
Speaker 1: You obviously don't listen to geek nights But we've talked a lot about what we think is wrong with a lot of current popular RTS's and RTS is a genre and where they've gone.
Speaker 1: So what what mechanic like what would make the great American RTS?
Speaker 1: Like what is it that you obviously have some like very strong idea here?
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I actually think that that To go back to my my sort of 2d plane local minima analogy This is a perfect example of it that like that command and conquer and Warcraft were were well and before that What was the predecessor to Warcraft?
Speaker 0: What was?
Speaker 0: sorry dude?
Speaker 0: No doing that's right.
Speaker 0: Yeah doing it was doing - I think Was the first RTS really the first modern RTS and they've just been iterating on that same formula and adding features all along And they did a pretty good job not getting to not expanding upon it too much with Starcraft 2 and and keeping it Still somewhat accessible, but it's still far from well.
Speaker 2: I think the reason that they the reason I realize the reason that they do a lot of the things they do in Starcraft 2 Is because of the Koreans right?
Speaker 2: It's basically right football in Korea So when coming out we start coming out with Starcraft 2 is like coming out with football - you can't You know, I've heard that from a blizzard person.
Speaker 2: So you really know how much can you how much can you really change?
Speaker 2: You know, it might you know, it's very risky.
Speaker 1: Well, I think so.
Speaker 0: I think that to answer your question I think that to make the the really sort of the next great RTS and that the first notable RTS not including Starcraft 2 and in you know, 15 years will be to go back and and Design a game based upon what the original idea of an RTS was supposed to be.
Speaker 0: So RTS is really a few.
Speaker 0: if you break it down What is core to a real-time strategy game and what's core to the things we like about real-time strategy games?
Speaker 0: You break you.
Speaker 0: you can basically say well, it's chess So it's a there's a 2d there's basically a 2d space or at least there's a there's a manageable Space of air of area in which where you're dealing with like land control issues You have a variety of mixed units that might have strengths and weaknesses against one another And have different different things that they can do.
Speaker 0: and then you have an opponent that has You know somewhat somewhat equal Abilities and and I think if you sort of break it back to that and design a game based on that.
Speaker 0: and then if you if you add in some extra limitations like you know trying to design it around a classic gaming controller like a You know an Xbox controller except, you know, not with quite as much stuff.
Speaker 0: I mean the problem with every console RTS is that they try and use every button.
Speaker 0: And if you want to make a great console RTS stick to like, you know the four face buttons and and maybe a couple other buttons and You know, you have to do that because if you try and use every button you're gonna fuck over 95% of your your audience.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I'm just getting old but I no longer have the patience even read the instructions to a game and if I Can't figure it out on my own.
Speaker 2: It doesn't help.
Speaker 2: the instruction manuals are not what they used to be.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, I mean you have to you have to build your instruction manual into the game these days.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, but like I lay next to me we talked about the show recently.
Speaker 1: we have the original Zelda 1 instruction book.
Speaker 1: It's full color.
Speaker 1: There's comics in there jokes.
Speaker 1: It there's like maps hidden all over in this book.
Speaker 1: It's it's an amazing little book.
Speaker 0: No, man.
Speaker 0: Ultima used to come with a cloth map.
Speaker 0: I still have them all.
Speaker 1: Wow I don't have any of those anymore.
Speaker 1: I Don't even have my quest for glory to map.
Speaker 0: So So, yeah, I think that what you need to do is you need to break it back to not not.
Speaker 0: what is it as not?
Speaker 0: What are the basics of a RTS video game?
Speaker 0: And build off of that.
Speaker 0: but what are the basics of what we like about the concept of an RTS not just as a video Game, but as a game and try and build a game based upon that?
Speaker 0: and I when I design game stuff I do just Despite the fact that that Monaco is absolutely inspired by like pac-man and hitman.
Speaker 0: I do generally try and and Draw most of my inspiration from things outside of games.
Speaker 0: because if you're drawing your your design inspiration from games themselves You're just gonna end up sort of frankensteining something together, you know drawing bits and pieces of stuff that already exist And and I'm not saying that Monaco is you know, something totally revolutionary that it's never existed before.
Speaker 0: it certainly has.
Speaker 0: But at the same time I think that if you're drawing drawing your inspiration from things outside of existing games You're much more likely to not only Break the game down to sort of the basic pits and bits and pieces of what makes the experience fun.
Speaker 0: But also you're not likely to end up just you know, becoming a me to game something that looks exactly like something else.
Speaker 1: Alright, so I guess now let's step back from the gaming a little bit because we've got you on the show.
Speaker 1: We can talk about you as a person.
Speaker 1: I mean gamers are people too.
Speaker 1: So Obviously you're into video games pretty hardcore.
Speaker 1: But are you like do you a roleplay at all?
Speaker 1: Do you play board games any of that other kind of gaming stuff?
Speaker 0: I I have some friends that play a fair amount of board games and I love playing them.
Speaker 0: The main my main hobby actually is is ultimate frisbee.
Speaker 0: I play a lot of all day.
Speaker 2: It's not like for in a league or professionally.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, I I play.
Speaker 0: I usually captain my summer league in my winter league team.
Speaker 0: In fact, I met my wife playing winter league.
Speaker 2: I used to play used to play really seriously.
Speaker 0: Like I was a good college player.
Speaker 0: I'm not good anymore.
Speaker 0: I had a couple of knee surgeries and now I'm Lazy because I sit in front of the computer all day.
Speaker 1: where the knee surgeries from ultimate frisbee injuries?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they they were.
Speaker 0: well, they were both.
Speaker 0: I tore my meniscus in my right knee.
Speaker 0: I thought it was just.
Speaker 0: this is so that's like a piece of cartilage that sits in your in your knee that keeps the bones from.
Speaker 0: Okay, I actually watched the surgery the first time.
Speaker 0: okay, it's enough My meniscus broke in half and they gave me a spinal anesthetic Knocked out knocked me out from the bottom half down and I watched the surgery on the screen above me While they were going in.
Speaker 2: and I can't I can't even watch someone else's surgery.
Speaker 1: So the important thing is did you guys win that game?
Speaker 0: Though well, the thing is I broke.
Speaker 0: I broke my meniscus and I thought I was just dislocating it.
Speaker 0: So I kept just popping it back into place.
Speaker 0: So I broke it like maybe five or six times until the last the last time and it swelled up so bad I had to go to hospital because I couldn't.
Speaker 0: I couldn't bend my knee anymore.
Speaker 0: You found out that yeah, I had a serious problem and not just a dislocated knee And then and then I busted it again the second time is the same problem.
Speaker 0: It just never healed.
Speaker 0: I busted it surfing the second time so That was.
Speaker 0: that's that.
Speaker 0: that's a bummer But you know, I was probably gonna get fat and happy after that in any case.
Speaker 0: So that just that just sped up the the process.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I do love.
Speaker 0: I love my disc sports and I definitely love board games Some actually some of those breaks that I was taking from venture dinosauria before I started working on Monaco.
Speaker 0: I actually was designing board games based on my like the other games that the video games that I've made So I'd made like that because it's rare that people go in that reverse direction.
Speaker 2: Usually if they take a board game and they turn it into a video game That's just the same exact thing.
Speaker 2: But now you don't need a. you know, this reduces setup time and count, you know It makes it easier to play.
Speaker 2: play it online, but I never seen a lot of video games turned into board games.
Speaker 2: I mean what half-life 2 the board game looked like.
Speaker 1: It probably exists Like penny arcade Metroid.
Speaker 2: I mean, I mean there are.
Speaker 2: there are games that are that have video game licenses Right, like there's a World of Warcraft board game and a doom board game, but they're nothing like the real, you know They just have some of the same characters and artwork.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Yeah, it was actually my venture.
Speaker 0: Africa board game was actually really fun and I pitched it to a couple of board game companies.
Speaker 0: it was a very sort of chess like game in which you have a number of African animals and there's a a son that moves around the board.
Speaker 0: You can actually rearrange the board configuration so that every game is different and then there's a son that moves around the board.
Speaker 0: You're trying to any time and that represents the great migration and any time you have animals that are passing beneath them.
Speaker 0: They're passing within the great migration.
Speaker 0: They get to breed So you actually get to put pieces back on the board?
Speaker 0: And you have your predators and you're trying to use your predators to take out.
Speaker 0: the other guys are before us But also keep your herbivores from getting eaten by the other guys predators.
Speaker 0: It sounds a lot of fun.
Speaker 2: It sounds like a combination of like the dune board game, which has the storm that blows around the planet But also roller derby where you're on offense and defense at the same time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it sounds very similar to those.
Speaker 0: and then I did a a card game based on venture Arctic which is Was a game in which you're sort of it's a little bit sort of Puerto Rico inspired in that you are.
Speaker 0: Their seasons pass and during each season you get to choose Or during each turn you get to choose which season you want to be And that determines the order of play and what things you can do during those seasons.
Speaker 0: so you can be and in the Arctic Of course, the the seasons are you know, everything is seasonally dependent.
Speaker 0: So you're trying to either kill animals or or help the animals based upon what season you are.
Speaker 0: Say there's a see sort of Autonomous animals in the world and then and then your role shifts each turn based upon what season you want to be.
Speaker 0: I actually did a dinosauria card game that played a little like magic.
Speaker 0: not it's not really like magic, but it It's a game in which the the world actually is growing and so there's more and more of the world to access as you as You go.
Speaker 0: but then occasionally there's disasters that sort of destroy a whole bunch of the world.
Speaker 0: But then the cards that are in your hand represent dinosaurs and you can only you start by placing the sort of low-level dinosaurs and then you spend.
Speaker 0: you can discard cards to Evolve your your existing dinosaurs up to more powerful dinosaurs.
Speaker 0: So you're kind of trying to get to the point get to the end of the game with the most evolved dinosaurs And yeah, it's an interesting little card game.
Speaker 1: So, you know, the show is called geek nights and it's something we like to ask a lot of different people Do you consider yourself a geek or a nerd or anything like that?
Speaker 1: Do you even think there's a difference in the terms?
Speaker 1: Do you even care about it?
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, probably all of you.
Speaker 0: I actually I won.
Speaker 0: I won the California State Science Fair when I was in high school.
Speaker 2: What was your project?
Speaker 0: Fractal analysis of Southern California lagoons I took I took Satellite photography at the internet wasn't really around at the time and and I took satellite photography from the USGS and Wrote a program.
Speaker 0: so I scanned in the photography and I wrote a program that actually analyzed the flood the flow patterns Within the flood plains of the lagoons to see whether or not Human intrusion like buildings and things like that actually interrupted the the fractal characteristics of the the flow plane or the flow pattern And did find that they did actually do that.
Speaker 0: That they're.
Speaker 0: they're fractal.
Speaker 0: They're fractal characteristics that Flood lagoons and lagoons that had seen some human development in them loss were no longer fractal in terms of the way that their their curves self related To to themselves and I can't talk about this anymore because I don't I don't have the.
Speaker 0: so there are a lot of kind of yeah, so I think I'm a nerd and a geek and all of those things and and I Embrace it back in my dating days.
Speaker 0: I used to I used to every time I'd go on a first date with someone I'd tell him look if you don't like nerds or geeks don't date me because I'm I'll say oh you said you're married so it worked out, right?
Speaker 0: Yes a beautiful wonderful geek.
Speaker 1: So she's specifically a geek now.
Speaker 1: So there's a lot of conflated things.
Speaker 1: like nerds and geeks are supposed to be into sci-fi and into role-playing games and into anime.
Speaker 1: So are you into like science fiction at all or science fiction like literature or movies or anime or any of these other?
Speaker 1: traditional comic books?
Speaker 0: My I did host a Star Trek themed murder mystery party once I were I I was commander Riker.
Speaker 0: My wife despite being a geek is not a is not a geek by by history.
Speaker 0: She's just a geek because of her brain and so I actually watched Star Trek first contact with her the other night and I was.
Speaker 0: she was surprised actually how much she loved it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was good.
Speaker 0: it's it's it's pretty cheesy I mean, I'm definitely a definitely a bit of a you know, sort of culture file.
Speaker 0: So I I'm you know, I'm picky about my movies.
Speaker 0: But but I did definitely brought me back and I enjoyed it like I turned on the.
Speaker 0: I turned on next generation the other night actually and The the episode where Q loses his powers was on and that's one of my favorite episodes.
Speaker 0: It's got so many good lines in it.
Speaker 1: just when he freaks out he fought he falls asleep and he can't figure out what happened To it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's hard to work in groups when you're omnipotent.
Speaker 0: Eat any good books.
Speaker 0: lately wharf is in there, too.
Speaker 1: Actually kind of randomly I was watching cuz I as a kid I never watched Babylon 5 and randomly we started watching it.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure if I like yeah, Scott doesn't.
Speaker 1: Scott doesn't like any like Star Trek or any of that stuff even like Firefly.
Speaker 1: So yeah, yeah, it's a fun.
Speaker 0: I didn't get into any of the newer ones.
Speaker 0: Like I I always I scoffed about X-Files ever because everyone loved X-Files after next generation was dead Like X-Files like early on.
Speaker 2: but I had this plot line But then they didn't really you know, they would always just they wouldn't advance that main plot line at all.
Speaker 2: You know, they were just.
Speaker 0: I hate to say it, but I hate it lost.
Speaker 1: Oh, don't worry.
Speaker 1: We're in that camp.
Speaker 1: Okay, I watched one episode and I thought alright clearly they're just making this shit up and they don't have an actual ending in mind.
Speaker 1: So I'm not gonna waste my time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, everyone.
Speaker 0: and then you get to the ending and I like I watched the freakin recap.
Speaker 0: It was like a three-hour recap episode just before the last episode.
Speaker 0: Just to see if like maybe I'll enjoy this last episode because of course they're gonna like throw everything But the kitchen sink and the kitchen sink at that last episode, so maybe it'll be good, right?
Speaker 0: But that boat after watching that recap episode is like I want nothing to do with this piece of shit.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So let's get way out.
Speaker 1: We'll wrap it up pretty soon.
Speaker 1: But a bad question to ask we found is you know What are the like what's your favorite movie or anything like that?
Speaker 1: Cuz it's hard to actually qualify.
Speaker 1: So what are like five movies that you think are awesome?
Speaker 1: because I think this is a good insight into the the mind behind Monaco.
Speaker 0: actually, I have a great I One of the the most underrated crime movies I think is a movie called confidence With Edward Burns and Rachel Ice and it's got like Dustin Hoffman as a strip club owner and I actually drew a lot of the the visual inspiration for Monaco from that movie and It's really good.
Speaker 0: It's like it's a con movie.
Speaker 0: It's a con man movie so it's a team of con men that are trying to you know con people and it's got Who's the sideways actor?
Speaker 0: Anyways before he was famous.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, I think that's a really underrated like con heist movie.
Speaker 1: I'm a fan of the con heist movies.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, I've watched them all at this point And speaking of which there's another another crime-based movie.
Speaker 0: I Really can't stand the Soderbergh Ocean's 11 12 and 13 movies.
Speaker 0: I think they're awful, but before he did those he did out of sight with George Clooney and J. Lo Which actually is fantastic really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's actually really pretty steamy.
Speaker 0: It's like it's got a pretty steamy, you know a couple of love scenes with the two of them and it's got like really funny stupid criminals and and a great plot.
Speaker 0: So Yeah, and that's Soderbergh before before traffic and before Yeah, I liked traffic alive.
Speaker 0: I think that was probably his high point.
Speaker 0: But but then, you know, he's had a bunch of bad movies, too and So those two I love Children of Men.
Speaker 0: That's a recent one.
Speaker 0: I guess that I thought was really good.
Speaker 1: Well have that one long cut in the middle that one scene that was crazy
Speaker 0: Unbelievable, yeah, and it's hard for me to know whether or not that movie is really as fantastic as I remember it to be Except that that scene is just so fucking mind-blowing that like I love that movie.
Speaker 0: It might maybe it's no good Maybe the movie is no good.
Speaker 0: But but that scene really is incredible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's I love those I Comedy wise like I'm a fan of I'm a fan of like the Royal Tenenbaums.
Speaker 0: I like really quirky stuff and that was quirky before he was.
Speaker 0: Well, he I guess he was always Self-consciously quirky, but that was quirky before we were conscious of his self-consciousness.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, I enjoy that and you know, I like the stupid stuff, too.
Speaker 0: But but those are the certainly the ones that I I find memorable.
Speaker 2: All right, so we so we met you at PAX 2010. have you been to any other Conventions before then or do you go to any others?
Speaker 0: I've never.
Speaker 0: I've never actually done a booth at a convention.
Speaker 0: That was my first time doing a booth and it was a blast.
Speaker 0: I've been working in the video game industry since So I've been to my fair share of conferences, you know E3 and GDC and all that stuff, but I've never been to like, you know other like San Diego comic cons or maybe.
Speaker 0: yeah Yeah, I've been to comic-con a bunch of times.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of it's a little over my head and and I'm not into waiting in lines for We tend to not wait in line for things anyway, those are things that are worth writing, you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually said we don't.
Speaker 1: so prat packs.
Speaker 1: at least press and speakers get the same privileges.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, which is almost nothing.
Speaker 1: Oh They don't give press that much.
Speaker 1: exhibitor is the badge that gets you a way more access than press gets Because it mostly gets you into the exhibit hall because your booth is there.
Speaker 1: We're thinking about getting our own booth in the exhibit hall to share with some game designer friends.
Speaker 1: We have partly so.
Speaker 1: we can get that exhibitor badge along with the speaker badge between the two.
Speaker 1: We'll get around.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, actually Chris Hecker the guy who did spy party.
Speaker 0: He's the guy that I Shared the booth with at PAX.
Speaker 1: I was slowly working toward bothering him next.
Speaker 0: Yes I was sharing.
Speaker 0: I shared the booth with John Blow who did braid and he's working on the witness And and Chris Hecker who's got a long storied history with with technology and game development And he's been working on spy party at any rate he.
Speaker 0: so he actually came and stayed at my place For comic-con this year and that was sort of how we hatched the idea of doing a Doing a booth together at PAX.
Speaker 2: So how do you think packs compared to the other conventions that you've been through?
Speaker 0: I was my favorite.
Speaker 0: This is there was my favorite one I've been to.
Speaker 0: I didn't actually get a ton of time to to Really look around a lot because I was constantly babysitting the booth But I loved the gamers.
Speaker 0: there were great really just totally awesome people that were really interested in games and You know a lot of just smart interesting fun people that were really there to have fun and just play games like I. and I mean granted it's a self-selecting audience the people that are gonna come over and play and play Monaco.
Speaker 0: But pretty much everyone that came over to play Didn't seem like unduly impressed by the big triple-a stuff, you know.
Speaker 0: I actually think that you know the smaller budget games can have just as good graphics or at least art if you want to call it that with it with a Capital a as the big budget games.
Speaker 0: and so it sort of bugs me when someone comes over and like sort of treats us as Second rate because I don't think there's any reason that we are.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I didn't encounter any of those people at PAX everyone who came over to play and a grant Like I said, it's a self-selecting audience, but everyone who came to play just was there to have fun.
Speaker 2: Well, I mean you're pretty close to like the PAX 10 area too, you know And that was it's pretty much all indie games in there, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah All right.
Speaker 1: So is there an ETA and when Monaco is gonna be available for purchase or is that still in the works?
Speaker 0: Now still in the works until I know which consoles it's gonna be it'll be PC and at least one console.
Speaker 2: If you did it with XNA, right then I mean it has to be Xbox the really what else can you get it on?
Speaker 0: Well, you can port it.
Speaker 2: Oh, I guess you could yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess you can voice the things get farted.
Speaker 2: Actually, could you you could put it on like the the the Windows Phone 7 and the zoom if you wanted to.
Speaker 2: I don't know How well that would work.
Speaker 0: I can.
Speaker 0: I can say that it will be PC and at least one console.
Speaker 0: It's it's not gonna be a mobile app Although I I do think that it'll be really fun to make a version of it for the 3ds.
Speaker 2: It can be a blast would be But that won't be.
Speaker 0: that won't be of course right away.
Speaker 0: Of course not but but yeah PC and at least one console and that kind of I'm I. After it won the IGF back when everything was all blocky and tile based I got a lot of enthusiasm for wanting to talk to me.
Speaker 0: But most of the the big console companies You know, I was having to rely entirely on that enthusiasm rather than them actually getting it.
Speaker 0: They most of them most of them didn't really get it.
Speaker 0: But and some of them were like, yeah, but we'll take it anyways because we might not get it, but clearly there's something here And I wasn't satisfied with that response originally.
Speaker 0: so I went dark for a while and decided well I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: you know, the thing that the game that I was showing to them was 15 weeks of work By literally just me.
Speaker 0: I did all the art and programming and everything.
Speaker 2: Is it still just you or it is still just me?
Speaker 2: Yeah, pretty good.
Speaker 0: But so I figured you know I went dark for a while.
Speaker 0: it went sort of deep into development and really focused on Making sure that everyone who played it not just the business people but everyone who played it got it, you know.
Speaker 0: and Because because the game I think is is a lot of fun.
Speaker 0: It's fantastic.
Speaker 0: But you know there was a. there's a fairly big barrier to entry at that point.
Speaker 0: So so that was really my focus and and next month I'm gonna be moving back into talking to some people again and seeing who wants to play ball.
Speaker 1: All right Well, I mean we wish you the best of luck.
Speaker 1: This game was one of the few that actually literally legitimately did blow us away at PAX.
Speaker 1: So Andy Schatz the game was Monaco.
Speaker 1: Thanks a million for coming on the show.
Speaker 0: yeah, and if you don't mind people can follow development on the Facebook page or on Twitter at www.facebook.com.
Speaker 0: slash Monaco is mine or twitter.com.
Speaker 0: slash Monaco is mine.
Speaker 0: so I'm very active on on both on you know, everything about the business and and Art of game development.
Speaker 0: So come on and take a look.
Speaker 2: Is there anything else that you want to you want to promote?
Speaker 1: Well, we'll put up links to all that stuff.
Speaker 1: when we tweet out work We're I'm recording all this but we're pretty much done.
Speaker 1: That was a saw.
Speaker 1: I can cut that into a solid show easily.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 0: Cool Thanks guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's that was a lot of fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cool Yeah, so we'll link to everything we'll we'll tweet out and we'll tweet at you too.
Speaker 1: So people the kids like to go and they'll start following you and all that Awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, guys.
Speaker 2: Yeah, actually I didn't notice that on your website It's like all you really have.
Speaker 2: there is the link to Facebook and a link to link to Twitter.
Speaker 2: I was like screenshots is not even like a YouTube video.
Speaker 2: It's you know,
Speaker 0: well, you know, I All my old games used to be through my mate the main pocket watch games calm web website and I spent a lot of time just like, you know, maintaining WordPress and maintaining forums and maintaining whatever image serving program I was using and This time around I just wanted to make a game.
Speaker 0: So I figured I'd do everything through social media where all of that infrastructure is pre-built and I don't need to maintain anything.
Speaker 0: At some point I'm gonna have to go in and revamp the website at least make it a little prettier But but I'll probably never.
Speaker 2: I mean, you don't really need like a forum if you're using Twitter and Facebook.
Speaker 2: But I mean, I feel like you do need at least a page with text like Monaco.
Speaker 2: Here's a picture of it.
Speaker 0: I Completely agree with you.
Speaker 0: It's on my list of things.
Speaker 0: I got it.
Speaker 0: I've got to go back and do so.
Speaker 1: Well again, thanks a lot.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna cut out now so we can actually make some frickin dinner.
Speaker 0: Joy, see up guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah looking forward right.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 2: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 2: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 2: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 2: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 2: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 2: It's actually recorded at night.