Speaker 1: Hey, it's Monday, May 10th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight We talk about Twitter and then go off on a tangent for a while.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I was biking over the the bridge like you do like you do which bridge?
Speaker 0: Queensborough Bridge now so the normal bridge and Sunday and There's a lady walking the other direction, and I didn't notice her till I got pretty close Maybe like 10 feet away, and she was fumbling around with something and then she kept walking after she stopped fumbling.
Speaker 1: now That's I've often fumbled with things while I walk.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'll fumbled with my wallet trying to pull the metro card out of there Maybe in the middle of the bridge is like what do you need to fumble with in the middle of the bridge?
Speaker 1: sometimes my phone?
Speaker 1: Maybe the phone's ringing you got to answer.
Speaker 0: that I don't know.
Speaker 0: but anyway She just stopped fumbling and kept walking.
Speaker 0: so I noticed that near where she was fumbling pretty much the exact spot was Money's like a dollar.
Speaker 0: so I pick up the dollar and I bike over and I'm like hey is your dollar?
Speaker 0: and She just keeps walking.
Speaker 0: so I think oh Maybe she didn't hear me or notice me because I wasn't right in front of her.
Speaker 0: I was sort of to the side, and I couldn't tell you said it like that straight up.
Speaker 1: Just here's your dollar.
Speaker 1: Yeah, as opposed to excuse me miss.
Speaker 1: I think you dropped this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean Maybe she thought yeah I don't know.
Speaker 1: I could foresee if a stranger came up to me And they said here's your dollar I would probably ignore them anyways, then I was like you dropped this dollar do you sure you don't want it back.
Speaker 0: and She like she didn't say anything and she had sunglasses on and she wouldn't know.
Speaker 0: so I couldn't even like.
Speaker 0: you know It would look like some crazy person was like hiding from the world and she just like you know Eventually, she sort of like stopped and like like, you know coward and I was like what the fuck.
Speaker 0: So I'm like all right, I'll just keep your dollar and so I kept her dollar.
Speaker 1: You know it's weird because I've run into that too like the the cowering every a couple of times in the last few months I've like I've for whatever reason have to talk to someone in the street.
Speaker 1: You know like a situation comes up and When I have talked to certain people they cower like they literally like back And then they like hunt their shoulders down and like avert their eyes from me.
Speaker 1: Was that what she did like?
Speaker 1: back eyes down like it?
Speaker 0: I couldn't tell what the eyes were doing but alright cuz of the crazy sunglasses.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know, she had like a thing over her head.
Speaker 0: She was like, you know, maybe she didn't speak English I don't know, but I was holding out.
Speaker 1: at least it's not like beacon.
Speaker 1: The last time I interacted with some one of the crazy people on the streets of Beacon Kind of noise Literally, I was.
Speaker 1: I was rollerblading and there's a woman.
Speaker 1: she's walking toward me and she kind of looks at me and I smile at Like morning and she hissed at me the most horrifying hiss I've ever heard come out of.
Speaker 0: maybe it was someone like us Who was just trying to be silly?
Speaker 1: You know, I wish I could believe like I wish that were true.
Speaker 1: I wish I expected that.
Speaker 1: I Believe it was a legitimate hiss.
Speaker 1: I believe that hiss was intentional and and came from some deep meaning some deep hiss.
Speaker 1: There was no meta to it.
Speaker 0: What is up with these people?
Speaker 1: Anyway, I don't know I didn't run in any crazy people when I was rollerblading over the weekend.
Speaker 1: Actually, I roll it is so different rollerblading a long distance in the city compared to like Michigan.
Speaker 1: I mean, I went all the way down to Brooklyn through hipster ville Williamsburg across the bridge.
Speaker 1: other hipster ville Went through some areas where Hazy's gave me dirty locs, but they didn't throw anything at me.
Speaker 0: lucky Yeah, I could have gotten some free tomato.
Speaker 1: I know I was kind of.
Speaker 1: I wasn't looking for trouble.
Speaker 1: I was just rollerblading around down there and then I go through that neighborhood where there was the bike path and then they took It away.
Speaker 1: then the hipsters repainted it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, but no one threw anything at me, but they gave me dirty looks.
Speaker 0: That's what they'll do.
Speaker 1: It was the stink.
Speaker 0: I stink.
Speaker 0: it's the evil eye.
Speaker 1: Are you sure?
Speaker 1: was it?
Speaker 1: was it the full-on evil eye or just the stink eye?
Speaker 1: because there is a difference?
Speaker 1: No, I'm pretty sure it was the evil eye.
Speaker 1: Anyway, get the stink eye from like a farmer.
Speaker 1: Maybe a gypsy.
Speaker 0: Gypsies also have the evil eye and what do you get from?
Speaker 0: Who gives you the lazy eye?
Speaker 1: So we got any news.
Speaker 1: we definitely didn't have a good idea for a show to do today.
Speaker 0: no well tonight Well kind of but this is not really news.
Speaker 0: But basically this is dude and he made a blog post right and I replied to the blog post like they do and then I got a weird email About my reply to the blog post.
Speaker 0: That was really clearly from someone who is just I don't know but Wasn't that the email from me that I forwarded?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but basically because someone emailed me about the blog post it stuck in my mind.
Speaker 0: Usually you don't remember when you comment on something you just sort of do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but so now I remembered the stupid comments and I remember this post and why not?
Speaker 0: Let's discuss the post.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: It's interesting cuz with Twitter I kind of just throw stuff out there and then like I don't know a week later I'll randomly just look at my ads.
Speaker 1: I see all these people answering and I have no idea what I said that prompted them to respond.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but basically this guy makes a long blog post and basically his complaint is that in New York City Right that the technology people are not Entrepreneurially minded right?
Speaker 0: It's like no, but everyone wants to be an employee They don't want to be a co-founder and you're kidding right.
Speaker 0: and that he also says that there's all these You know business people out there who are looking who are non-technical and they're looking for technical Co-founders and they can't find them.
Speaker 0: They're really hard to get.
Speaker 0: I'm right here right and you know, he goes on to say all this stuff, right and Basically my response to him was all right, dude.
Speaker 0: Well, the response is pretty much.
Speaker 0: some are in multiple categories, right?
Speaker 0: The category number one is okay.
Speaker 0: so you're some business dude with an idea right and You're looking for a technological person to help you make your idea reality and you don't actually have any money to offer.
Speaker 0: You're just offering equity.
Speaker 1: Equity and stock are not how to pay me, right?
Speaker 0: Right, so he's like and we had to compete with Wall Street for you know employees here we go after people have What is this?
Speaker 0: To dah dah dah dah and try.
Speaker 0: I can't find the exact quote right at this moment But can you paraphrase?
Speaker 0: basically he you know, he's like, you know, how come people in New York?
Speaker 0: You can't sway them with.
Speaker 0: you know stock and equity.
Speaker 0: they don't realize how valuable it is.
Speaker 1: I think I can answer that.
Speaker 1: I think we can because we have money.
Speaker 1: We have money all over the place.
Speaker 1: people give us money to do stuff.
Speaker 1: You can't give us not money and expect us to do stuff unless it's something we want to do.
Speaker 1: Anyway, plus What is this tech thing?
Speaker 1: like what it's just in general because He sounds a lot like the people who email Neil Gaiman and they're like I got a story idea and you want to write it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so here's my post is basically I'm a developer in New York City.
Speaker 0: I would very much like to work at a startup.
Speaker 0: if it were the right one I could potentially be very exciting now that the job now I have is bad.
Speaker 0: It's actually pretty great.
Speaker 0: However, I think a lot of people here pointed out exactly the problem.
Speaker 0: There's pretty much zero percent chance I will risk my livelihood and someone else's dreams.
Speaker 0: I'm not even in the financial sector, but I'm doing alright.
Speaker 0: I have rent to pay if you give me equity or stock options.
Speaker 0: There goes rent and groceries.
Speaker 0: That's just not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: No way.
Speaker 0: I like eating more than I like you.
Speaker 1: You know, what's funny is he forgets the very basic thing that people like us Definitely, we definitely want to do that exact thing like that.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean all want to do but we already have ideas.
Speaker 1: We just don't have time or people like him to come into our.
Speaker 0: the only thing right that a you know for a tech person The only thing that a business co-founder who is non-technical can offer to a technical person.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: We have ideas.
Speaker 0: We also have skills.
Speaker 0: The only thing that you can possibly offer us is enough monies Actual monies that we don't have to give back that we aren't like lent monies or capital monies just given monies.
Speaker 0: Right that are our monies so that we don't have to work and we can work on our idea all day instead.
Speaker 0: That's the only thing you can possibly offer us right?
Speaker 0: You'd be like, oh, I'll give you some equity.
Speaker 0: It's like I have an idea.
Speaker 0: Would you like equity in it?
Speaker 0: Sure, you know do this work for me for nothing.
Speaker 0: go Be my guest.
Speaker 0: I have a million ideas.
Speaker 0: I'll give you equity in all of them.
Speaker 0: Let's go.
Speaker 0: You know it.
Speaker 0: we want actual monies and apparently like the people elsewhere right, apparently it's easy
Speaker 1: to
Speaker 0: find people in San Francisco or wherever else to do this and I Guess those people are just more free-spirited or risk-taking or the cost of living is lower or I don't know what's up with those people and why they're willing to do it, but Maybe I think just New York people aren't stupid.
Speaker 0: Maybe we don't work for no money.
Speaker 0: You got to pay Huh, but yeah, it's a you know, I think that there's like this whole Entrepreneurial thing that's sort of gotten really tied in with tech things.
Speaker 0: Like if you read any sort of tech stuff, you know hacker news or whatever.
Speaker 0: Like half the stuff is like entrepreneurial stuff and half of it is tech stuff.
Speaker 0: Like there's been like this intermingling that's been going on, right?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean look at the whole.
Speaker 1: the original tech boom.
Speaker 1: You know the one that we avoided the following bust by going into college during.
Speaker 1: yeah That was all.
Speaker 0: we also avoided our chance to go in on the boom and leave before the bust by being high school during Because we were definitely.
Speaker 1: it's sad because I feel like we were at least some of the people who in a boom like that Would have quit the second they stopped paying us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much as opposed to working for nothing for any amount of time.
Speaker 0: Yep But the you know, this is like this.
Speaker 0: this intermingling has been going on And I think the fundamental reason that it comes up is because a tech person is a smart person and a smart person Wants to.
Speaker 0: you know, they want to be their own boss.
Speaker 0: They want to be their own person do what they want to do.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They don't know what I want.
Speaker 0: They don't want to do what someone else wants to do But at the same time they also want to eat more than they want to do their own thing, you know and It seems like there's a lot of these entrepreneurial Venture kind of guys out there.
Speaker 1: I would argue that some of these people want to do their own thing more than they want to eat.
Speaker 1: Well, the problem is that if they're gonna sacrifice food for doing they're only gonna do if it's their thing Not anyone else exactly.
Speaker 0: That's what I said.
Speaker 0: I'll do my own thing and I'll do my own thing with you.
Speaker 0: know money I save up and if you want to just give me money, okay, but if you give me not money What what you're not giving me anything?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know but I think that a lot of these people are just sort of Like.
Speaker 0: they just sort of misrepresent What intrapreneur isms is about and they sort of like they're scamming a lot of tech people in a lot of ways you know like they get someone's like believe in the dream like we can work and be awesome all day and not have to work For the man and basically I'll pay you nothing and it's
Speaker 1: really easy to get those people straight.
Speaker 0: And then there's pretty much a one out of a hundred chance that will actually get anywhere.
Speaker 0: There's a one out of a ten million chance that will become Facebook or Google.
Speaker 0: see if so Buy some lottery tickets.
Speaker 1: kid if someone had approached me with something like that like right as I was about to graduate from our IT I probably would have been like hells.
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah work for my parents Can approach me after our IT and said here's money Yeah, and I said thanks for the money.
Speaker 1: I will do things in return for it.
Speaker 0: Yep So here I am now, you know, it's like.
Speaker 0: at the same time, you know with these intrapreneurs I share the common desire to you know, be your own person own your own company do your own thing.
Speaker 0: You know work from home work how you want to work not work the way the man wants you to work.
Speaker 0: a nine-to-five behind a desk in a cube.
Speaker 0: But I have rent and I like to eat.
Speaker 0: and unless you give me money Go home.
Speaker 0: I will admit I think you want to be an intrapreneur my and you need tech people.
Speaker 0: my suggestion to you Get like a hundred thousand dollars Find a tech person give them the entire hundred thousand dollars all at once and that person will probably Just work for you for one or two years
Speaker 1: or disappear
Speaker 0: or disappear
Speaker 1: or in five years say yeah, it didn't work.
Speaker 1: I need another hundred thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 0: But you know, the point is they'd give them money Enough that they won't do it, you know And then they will do the thing that you want them to do.
Speaker 0: or if you think you know If you're just a business person, right and you having trouble because all the good tech people only want to work on their own ideas Just give the tech person the money and let them do their own idea and they'll give you all the equity you want because that ain't worth shit.
Speaker 0: On the off chance that it actually, you know makes money you.
Speaker 0: basically all you did was give some guy money.
Speaker 0: You didn't have to do any work.
Speaker 0: and if it works out Your bank and you know what with the current with the sit with the scenario that they want to do in the first place It would be the same thing.
Speaker 0: So what's the difference?
Speaker 1: Right, you know what is interesting is back when we lived in Beacon and then when I was thinking about buying that house or if I'd bought the house up there I would have been much more able and willing to do some sort of.
Speaker 1: you know Stop working for the man and just do like geek nights or something like that.
Speaker 0: I wasn't willing to do it any differently, you know in terms of not having money to eat.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm saying like.
Speaker 1: I was much more able to do that because my substantial savings and everything together I could go for a while without a job if I wanted to or with only a part-time job Mm-hmm, but by choosing to move into the city instead, I mean living in New York.
Speaker 1: We lead a very luxurious lifestyle Which cost a lot of money to maintain and like the the baseline money I need to maintain my comfortable lifestyle is much much higher now, but here's what I understand right in San Francisco ain't cheap, right?
Speaker 0: It's not like you can live there for ten bucks.
Speaker 1: I think a lot of the people who do this stuff live outside in the burbs and commute in work.
Speaker 0: It's that's even less cheap.
Speaker 0: This is the burbs in Silicon Valley are mad.
Speaker 0: money's further out.
Speaker 0: how far out.
Speaker 0: I didn't even know the geography that far.
Speaker 0: I imagine telecommuting and what you know These people like living and how much are they paying for rent that they're willing to work for equity and not money.
Speaker 1: How many of them are there really who aren't just trust fund babies?
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: And how many?
Speaker 0: how skilled are they?
Speaker 1: Yeah Mmm, I mean New York kind of choose.
Speaker 0: you Understand the mentality of these people.
Speaker 0: are they just being scammed by these venture people or are they just really?
Speaker 0: I don't know?
Speaker 0: Do they not care about eating?
Speaker 0: are they willing to live in squalor in a slum or something?
Speaker 1: A lot of people who have succeeded were willing to live in squalor.
Speaker 1: That is one option to success.
Speaker 1: if we lived in Beacon in squalor like Like ramen for dinner all the time and never eating that already and not going to conventions you'll be dead already maybe or fat To dead and fat.
Speaker 1: I mean look the dwarf fortress guy.
Speaker 1: He lives off of the poultry donations from dwarf fortress.
Speaker 0: I don't think you're that paltry, but I don't think they're.
Speaker 1: I don't think they maintain the lifestyle that we demand these days.
Speaker 1: Well, he also lives where the cost of living is much lower, which is one thing you do beacon real cheap to live in.
Speaker 1: We could even live even cheaper if we had the mortgage on that five-bedroom house was substantially cheaper than the rent on this place.
Speaker 1: Yeah So speaking of upstart venture capital and entrepreneurialism and all that stuff Twitter had a problem and it's a problem.
Speaker 1: that's kind of hilarious.
Speaker 1: If anyway, you all miss the boat to have fun with this Apparently, I don't know how long this was the case if you just tweeted accept and then someone's at name in Twitter They followed you and there was nothing they could do about it.
Speaker 1: They could go on follow you but they they were now following you.
Speaker 0: I guess that is that how Twitter like worked under the hood is like.
Speaker 0: basically it sent tweets and Certain tweets that you would send or maybe like certain SMS.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's like an SMS command, right?
Speaker 0: So if you cuz you know you're doing Twitter over SMS, right?
Speaker 0: You have to type in.
Speaker 1: you know command you basically to send texts to Twitter and goddamn if I wouldn't have sort of Encrypted hashes and like special command codes and rotating keys and all that stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and apparently right so that those commands Just told allowed you to control Twitter by tweeting and so those tweets obviously wouldn't get tweeted But they would tell Twitter to do things.
Speaker 1: Well, it's funny because Twitter like they haven't said and they just coded it real shitty Like I don't believe they've said, you know If the problem had always been there or what.
Speaker 1: but the accusations I've seen are that one There were shady companies who knew about this and were basically selling followers Uh-huh, because they knew how to do it.
Speaker 1: and the other accusation that's much more Interesting, but also much more conspiratorial and I don't believe it because frankly Occam's razor.
Speaker 1: It's just coded shittily.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the reason Lee is every coded.
Speaker 0: but
Speaker 1: what people are alleging which is an interesting idea because it brings up kind of the whole Root issue of Twitter lately is that maybe this is a feature they were building and they screwed up and exposed it to everyone Because there's a lot of talk about monetizing Twitter nowadays.
Speaker 1: Well, they have the sponsored tweets Yeah, but sponsored tweets and all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 1: I'm the kind of person where the moment, you know There's a bomb that has not yet fallen on Twitter.
Speaker 1: the day I'm looking at my timeline and there is a tweet that was not retweeted by anyone.
Speaker 1: I know that is in my timeline that I did not follow.
Speaker 1: That is basically a nuclear weapon going off in Twitter because that people like me disappear immediately.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much either that or we write things to figure out where they come from and block them.
Speaker 0: Yep, so I can't imagine how Twitter can ever Understand right if I have a Twitter client, right the Twitter client gets tweets.
Speaker 0: It could just not display those tweets in my timeline.
Speaker 0: There's nothing they can.
Speaker 0: how are they gonna disguise it?
Speaker 1: Well, that's why I don't think this is exactly what's going on.
Speaker 1: I mean, I think the way they're gonna monetize in the end is gonna be some some mishmash of Send it selling trending and analytics and selling clients and basically they're gonna do all the stuff that right now.
Speaker 1: You know They built Twitter and it didn't do much like.
Speaker 1: it did what it did and that was it and a lot of people made entire businesses just off of Selling all the things that Twitter didn't do by doing it for Twitter like doing analytics.
Speaker 1: I think Twitter is just gonna start doing all that on their own a million times better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, that's all those people out of business, which is fine Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That's what Microsoft does right?
Speaker 0: They put out something Visual Studio.
Speaker 0: So some other company makes a Visual Studio plug-in and then some companies buy the Visual Studio plug-in cuz oh man They need it so bad.
Speaker 0: And then what does Microsoft do?
Speaker 0: They include the features of the plug-in in Visual Studio.
Speaker 0: The other company goes out of business, right?
Speaker 0: This is the is how things work in the plug-in market.
Speaker 0: when you build on someone else's platform, right?
Speaker 0: There's always the risk of the people who make the platform are just gonna make you redundant and you're gonna be screwed.
Speaker 0: Which is why you don't want to build on someone else's platform.
Speaker 0: You want to build on your own platform or be your own platform or be platform independent, you know, like what?
Speaker 0: if you make?
Speaker 0: You know a platforming game for the Wii and then the same month Nintendo comes out with a platforming game.
Speaker 0: That's better than yours.
Speaker 0: It's like oh fuck me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're done.
Speaker 1: And the thing is you knew Nintendo existed.
Speaker 1: You knew they were capable of it.
Speaker 1: You basically said I know there was someone else out there who can do what I'm doing right now a thousand times better and beat Me in every way, but if you made a platforming game For Wii, Xbox, PS3, PC And everything.
Speaker 0: Yep, right, then you'd be alright.
Speaker 1: I mean basically I think any company whose business model is based in any way on Twitter that isn't Themselves.
Speaker 1: Twitter is fucked Just completely.
Speaker 1: I think that's the whole way of monetization.
Speaker 1: So a Little advice to all of you out there who might be working unpaid for one of these things.
Speaker 1: It ain't going anywhere but it is interesting because someone on slashdot, you know, they're like this big you know insightful post was The suggestion that you would stop using Twitter because it somehow started.
Speaker 1: introducing spam is laughable.
Speaker 1: has spam stopped you from using email?
Speaker 0: It would have if I didn't have a spam filter.
Speaker 1: In fact, I stopped using email.
Speaker 1: We all stopped using email at RIT.
Speaker 1: We used IM and we started using email again when Gmail came out and spam disappeared again.
Speaker 1: Yep I mean even alright.
Speaker 1: my RIT email address was useless at RIT because I got spammed constantly.
Speaker 0: I had spam filter.
Speaker 1: I made Thunderbird.
Speaker 1: I didn't use Thunderbird.
Speaker 1: I set one up on my spooler and everything.
Speaker 1: I used Thunderbird Yeah on the the open, not the bags.
Speaker 0: Man, who's using Thunderbird these days?
Speaker 1: Because you don't need to.
Speaker 1: webmail is king.
Speaker 1: Yeah, webmail and phone mail, which is basically a webmail on a phone.
Speaker 0: But maybe I should try to set up Thunderbird hook it up to my Gmail.
Speaker 0: See what it looks like.
Speaker 1: But basically I just.
Speaker 1: This Twitter thing is interesting because immediately half the people I see in the internet are freaking out like oh, no They accidentally revealed the stuff they're doing to monetize Twitter.
Speaker 1: They're gonna send us spam tweets and there's no way.
Speaker 1: there's absolutely no way that would ever happen.
Speaker 1: Of course It's fun to speculate what would happen if that did happen because I think here's my timeline.
Speaker 1: Zero hour a spam tweet goes to everyone on Twitter.
Speaker 1: the next 10 minutes a thousand open-source developers Join in and try to make Laconica not be shitty.
Speaker 0: It sucks 15 minutes later.
Speaker 1: They all give up on that.
Speaker 1: Four days later someone else reveals a whole new thing.
Speaker 1: people just use Google buzz and Facebook and whatever But then someone will jump in and do a whole thing that does basically what Twitter does But they'll cut off the baggage that is you know integrating with SMS.
Speaker 1: Scott I were talking about this before the show and you know, I came up with this whole scheme.
Speaker 1: I was thinking about what I would do to make Twitter better And I think the best way to do it is to hook in a lot more interesting metadata And it's already doing that but the way I would.
Speaker 1: I mean I came up with a scheme basically just for my.
Speaker 1: you know It's a thought exercise for me of how to let that be backward compatible with SMS and my scheme involving multiple SMS's and a protocol for requesting the metadata within the characters set within an SMS worked pretty well, but it increased the I guess SMS message overhead by about 50 to 60 percent You know on average which for people who don't have unlimited text plans fail.
Speaker 1: but as Scott pointed out, why don't we just bail on SMS entirely?
Speaker 1: and I feel like there is a point in time where someone is gonna be able to do what Twitter does.
Speaker 1: and all I would add to make Twitter awesome is drop SMS and let messages be any size and kind of just scale it up by removing those limitations of 144 characters and Let people set their own filters and scales and have some sort of radius.
Speaker 1: so you can say like these people are four radius from Me and these people are eight radius for me of like this expanding contracting circle.
Speaker 1: And then you tweet and you say what radius you wanted to go out to so it replaces that whole protected tweet bullshit.
Speaker 1: And you can have like.
Speaker 1: basically you can separate secretly your real friends from your fake friends from the people who follow you from the internet as a whole and It's already far too complicated for anyone to use the reason Twitter is successful and works in the reason face.
Speaker 1: because yes It's brainless exactly, but I want to give you Scott the example of doing.
Speaker 0: people can't even use threaded comments.
Speaker 0: That's why flat comments are the king.
Speaker 0: so threads are fail here.
Speaker 1: Here's here's why this is the awesome thing.
Speaker 1: dig was awesome before.
Speaker 1: it was popular among people who aren't like us.
Speaker 1: Dig was great back.
Speaker 1: Then like it was a really great way to find stuff and then when it became popular among the masses because it was so simple It became a Ron Paul shitstorm, and it remains so to this day.
Speaker 1: Twitter is the same way because it's so dumb so simple so popular.
Speaker 1: It's just a sea of garbage.
Speaker 1: Imagine if all the geeks had their own Twitter that did everything Twitter dud did and did all the awesome stuff that only geeks would Use but then at the very end of it it had the option of and send whatever I'm doing at this level to Twitter and Pull in.
Speaker 1: you know have an API for it to interact with Twitter.
Speaker 1: You can still publish to the idiots and get a filtered feed from the idiots But otherwise you have this massively powerful tool that does what buzz should have done.
Speaker 0: No, it's not gonna.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna work.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: because people that the power of the tool you're thinking that you know the value of Twitter or Facebook or anything is The technology itself.
Speaker 0: it doesn't matter what features you have as long as people can use it.
Speaker 0: the only feature that they can offer The number of people that are signed up and unless you already have people signed up It's it.
Speaker 0: it doesn't matter you can have the best possible technology in the universe right for this sort of thing.
Speaker 0: And you figured out everything perfectly.
Speaker 0: and Twitter is mad.
Speaker 0: Twitter is still the same as it was when it was first released Crashing every day.
Speaker 0: piece of shit right you put yours up.
Speaker 0: Twitter already exists.
Speaker 0: Twitter already has a million people.
Speaker 0: you can't win.
Speaker 0: You're zero you can't.
Speaker 1: there's no way because there were always things like that.
Speaker 1: then Twitter appeared and at first you know only nerds.
Speaker 0: Twitter was the first one.
Speaker 1: no I'm saying trends of like a bunch of people.
Speaker 1: Dig was you know when it came in there was a lot of early adopters there for a long time But it wasn't that big of a community at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so so you could make something that could succeed that could have enough critical mass to become useful dig wasn't competing with anything.
Speaker 1: I Would argue that it was originally competing with things like slash dot.
Speaker 0: not really I mean where there was.
Speaker 0: there wasn't any actual Democratic you know news site.
Speaker 0: it was the only one.
Speaker 0: well corrosion That's not a news site.
Speaker 1: It was an aggregator.
Speaker 0: It wasn't.
Speaker 1: there was a way.
Speaker 1: It was a site for fiction.
Speaker 1: It was not just fiction.
Speaker 1: There was a lot of nonfiction written there.
Speaker 1: Well in fact that was mostly what I read on corrosion, but it was.
Speaker 0: it was for writing.
Speaker 1: It was not news Yeah, but it was still an From people.
Speaker 0: it was not a huge pile of links every day.
Speaker 0: It was like a. it was like a whole blob of text.
Speaker 0: one every few days Had not even close to a dig is it not even remotely in the same category?
Speaker 1: so this is I'm just saying that there's.
Speaker 1: I think you're just overly cynical about the possibility of a More powerful thing that does similar things to what Twitter does working you.
Speaker 0: you couldn't get it.
Speaker 0: You know one would join it.
Speaker 0: How are you gonna start it off?
Speaker 1: Just do it and see if people come.
Speaker 0: Google did it.
Speaker 1: No one came because Google did it.
Speaker 1: half-assed Lee and shit Lee.
Speaker 0: So how it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: there have been plenty of people come off and did it not?
Speaker 0: shit Lee and no one uses them.
Speaker 0: Who?
Speaker 1: Who's done anything like that?
Speaker 0: the giant shit who totally failed?
Speaker 1: yeah, Jake it was crappy.
Speaker 0: No, Jake who was technologically vastly superior to Twitter in every conceivable fashion, but it did.
Speaker 1: I have a feature.
Speaker 1: But for me personally, I mean if you want to argue this that's fine But I have a feature list of things that if they were there I would use even though they only want using it.
Speaker 0: All right, that's you all right.
Speaker 0: It's not getting good.
Speaker 0: There's no point in using something if no one else is using it.
Speaker 0: well basically I'm gonna go you.
Speaker 0: oh man this IRC chatroom is so great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's no one in it.
Speaker 0: well But it has all these great features like logging and all it's got.
Speaker 1: what about our you know private forum?
Speaker 1: No one uses that but our friends and yet.
Speaker 1: It's super useful to us and our friends.
Speaker 0: I actually really don't like that.
Speaker 0: everyone uses that and I wish that people would you know use more correct technology like what.
Speaker 1: how am I?
Speaker 1: Gonna tell everyone in the group in the entire crew hey, we're having a party on this day.
Speaker 1: You can send an email to everybody I don't even have all their email addresses and after people don't read create a Google Calendar event and then invite everybody And no one uses their Google calendars.
Speaker 0: That's uh so now you're.
Speaker 0: you're agreeing with my point?
Speaker 0: Is that the technology that people use it doesn't matter?
Speaker 1: Calendar is vastly superior Because the calendar doesn't give me an easy way to post a date and then have a discussion about if that it's good.
Speaker 0: it Absolutely does.
Speaker 1: now how am I gonna send an invite to everyone and then what?
Speaker 1: we're gonna have an email chain discussion.
Speaker 0: It works.
Speaker 1: that's a really kind of shitty way to go about it.
Speaker 0: How is it shitty?
Speaker 1: Because it's not one.
Speaker 1: It's push instead of pull.
Speaker 1: I can't just go to the forum and check the status.
Speaker 1: It doesn't.
Speaker 1: yeah, I mean it email chain.
Speaker 0: You go to your email.
Speaker 0: You check.
Speaker 0: the status is no different.
Speaker 0: I Disagree.
Speaker 1: I think it's.
Speaker 0: you go to the calendar you click on the event you check the status.
Speaker 0: What's different?
Speaker 0: there's nothing that's different about it, but my calendar.
Speaker 1: so the status of what in my Google Calendar?
Speaker 1: Yeah, what status are you talking about?
Speaker 1: I'd have to dig read the discussion and see.
Speaker 1: you know what people have said But it's not gonna say like now the events on now the events off.
Speaker 1: unless I manually do that It'll be deleted from the calendar or moved or I'm the one who made it.
Speaker 1: So I'm the one who has to do all that manually.
Speaker 0: So you had to do the same thing by making a post in a forum.
Speaker 0: Yeah but then difference.
Speaker 1: but then the discussion is there and People it's.
Speaker 1: I think it's a better space for interacting and deciding what we're gonna actually do.
Speaker 0: throw a little poll up the calendar is Technologically vastly superior to just using a flat forum discussion.
Speaker 1: I don't think it is sorts of things because I have to shoehorn it right.
Speaker 1: People are.
Speaker 0: I disagree where the people know.
Speaker 1: I disagree with you a hundred percent on that because the calendar does not implement it.
Speaker 1: Very well.
Speaker 0: the calendar is implemented fantastic.
Speaker 1: So I got to make the calendar thing and then I got to make sure I have an up-to-date List of the email addresses of every single person.
Speaker 1: I want to have any.
Speaker 0: the only reason you don't have this?
Speaker 0: because you don't use The contacts even if I because there's no people there.
Speaker 0: It's the people had to be there.
Speaker 0: I have everybody.
Speaker 0: things work fantastically if people use them But why aren't they working?
Speaker 0: because people aren't using that but that doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: But now it's got yours you have.
Speaker 0: you need people to use it.
Speaker 0: That's all you need Scott.
Speaker 1: So I've got a list of all the contacts.
Speaker 1: then we make a new friend.
Speaker 1: I gotta go update that shit.
Speaker 0: You gotta update that shit anyway.
Speaker 1: No, I don't.
Speaker 1: I just make a forum post.
Speaker 1: Everyone's always in there.
Speaker 1: anyone new is just automatically in the forum.
Speaker 0: What you have to add them to be in the see the secret threads though.
Speaker 0: It's the same shit.
Speaker 0: No That's a lot easier to maintain than an email list because people's email addresses change just like Twitter is really much easier than a very Complicated system of radiuses and all this sorts of fancy stuff that you want.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's another reason that the easy thing that's brain dead and has the people will always beat the fancy system with all the features That doesn't have the people.
Speaker 1: I think a better way to go about it at least for someone like me.
Speaker 1: what I want is You have the brain dead and you have the advanced mode.
Speaker 1: I see cute did that very well back in the day when I am was still new.
Speaker 1: there's a well You know I am and I see cute and what I see cute did is they had basic mode by default Which was brain-dead simple I am and no fancy stuff and everything was real simple.
Speaker 1: But if you were smart And you want to do all the crazy stuff and it had a lot of crazy functionality awesome stuff that I am clients today Like what?
Speaker 1: It had one before AOL had it.
Speaker 1: it had online offline messaging queued messaging.
Speaker 1: you could schedule messages in and out.
Speaker 1: you could be Just email.
Speaker 1: it was kind of in between email, and I am.
Speaker 0: what was the only thing different about it was the user interface.
Speaker 0: Absolutely no other differences whatsoever Because you could transition.
Speaker 1: you could have an email chain that just becomes a chat.
Speaker 1: you couldn't do that with the old clients easily.
Speaker 0: It does.
Speaker 0: it's not any day.
Speaker 0: It's just the user interface was different.
Speaker 0: Everything was actually just an instant message.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz you're just changing the user interface.
Speaker 0: there wasn't actually any advanced functionality.
Speaker 0: It was the same exact functionality provided in a different way.
Speaker 0: You're just looking at it different.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: They put it in a bigger window therefore.
Speaker 0: It's an email now.
Speaker 0: It's in a small windows.
Speaker 1: They also hid a lot of stuff from the simple users like file transfers and setting up dedicated rooms.
Speaker 1: all this stuff.
Speaker 0: basically Everyone else has.
Speaker 0: it's not nothing AOL didn't have back then.
Speaker 0: I had chat rooms before I seek you my chat rooms chat rooms, but that was in AOL.
Speaker 0: Yeah, instant messenger was also originally in AOL.
Speaker 1: I know and a ICQ was for everyone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know why you're so adversarial because you're spouting bullshit.
Speaker 0: You get away with that.
Speaker 0: you're saying not you're saying things that ain't true.
Speaker 0: cuz you're you haven't named a single feature that ICQ Had that nothing else had back then.
Speaker 1: file transfer direct file transfer.
Speaker 0: He had fought.
Speaker 0: AOL had file transfer.
Speaker 0: before aim It was outside of AOL and when aim went outside of AOL, which was useless to anyone who didn't have AOL It was hidden behind a walled garden.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and as when aim was outside of AOL it had file transfer.
Speaker 0: Also file transfer was always there.
Speaker 0: Name something else.
Speaker 0: you got nothing.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: It's been a long time, but you said ICQ had all these features, but clearly you can't even remember a single one of them.
Speaker 0: All right, I'll go back.
Speaker 1: It's been like a decade.
Speaker 1: I'll let you go.
Speaker 0: Are you making claims?
Speaker 0: You don't even remember.
Speaker 0: you're just making shit.
Speaker 1: because they had an advanced mode and a simple mode.
Speaker 1: They hid all the advanced mode.
Speaker 0: All it did was show you all.
Speaker 0: these different menu options didn't actually have any functionality.
Speaker 1: Oh, so there's no one else.
Speaker 0: Oh my god a whole bunch of menu options appeared that let me set like, you know, my profile in crab.
Speaker 0: It was ICQ did not do anything differently.
Speaker 0: It was only had user interface Differences that made it appear and feel as if it was more advanced functionality.
Speaker 0: in other in terms of instant messaging It was exactly the same as everything else except it made you use a number.
Speaker 0: So it was harder and it made you feel cool when you had a number that only had a few digits in it instead of A whole bunch of digits like everyone else.
Speaker 1: You'll feel really stupid when I pull up the old ICQ client and then look at what was actually in there.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, so much fancy stuff in there.
Speaker 1: What's wrong with the idea of having a simple mode in a complex mode?
Speaker 1: Twitter, you know, simple Twitter Just works exactly like current Twitter.
Speaker 1: If you're not in the advanced mode gives you all this extra stuff if you want to use it.
Speaker 1: Having multiple groups of friends deciding, you know, this tweet will only go out to these friends But this tweet is public.
Speaker 0: The problem with that is that it's inevitably going to cause conflicts.
Speaker 0: if you are like Interacting with some simple mode users the it's not gonna work so well.
Speaker 1: There are easy ways around that.
Speaker 0: like give me an example of a problem like you've put all this metadata on something But they don't see metadata because they're in simple mode where it just shows in the post.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so now you but you're discussing something that's in the metadata like some attached GPS coordinate photos something something They don't even see it and you're talking about it and they don't.
Speaker 0: they totally miss out.
Speaker 0: They don't get it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's like what the fuck is this?
Speaker 1: Cuz you're if you're interacting with simple, you know people with a simple client will just hide that all from them And they won't know they won't care.
Speaker 0: but it's not hidden because you're discussing it in the part that they do see.
Speaker 1: Well, that's just because you're stupid in that case.
Speaker 0: But the thing is most of these people are stupid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I that's what all the users are.
Speaker 0: those same stupid users are the ones that are adding the value to the system.
Speaker 0: That's the reason you're there.
Speaker 1: I don't tweet at or interact with any of those people.
Speaker 0: That's you.
Speaker 0: I'm saying is that's you.
Speaker 0: we're talking about the success of the system.
Speaker 0: Not what rim wants.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I think there's a room for a system that caters to people like me.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yes, exactly We'll have one user rim.
Speaker 1: I think more people would use a more powerful.
Speaker 0: Twitter has five users rim and the five people like rim that rim didn't know yet.
Speaker 0: Alright, everyone else will actually be getting use out of a system that is much much less technologically capable and is brain dead But is useful because they're actually people on it except it's not useful and I ignore the vast majority of people on Twitter.
Speaker 0: It's not useful to you.
Speaker 0: But guess what?
Speaker 0: So then why do you just don't use it at all?
Speaker 0: don't use anything cuz actually you're either gonna have something that's not useful to you because it's a bunch of brain dead people or Something but there's no one on it.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: I used Twitter's useful in very specific situations partly because I have such a very strong filter of information in it.
Speaker 1: I only see tweets.
Speaker 1: very small number of people and their people were actually, you know Like at a convention.
Speaker 1: the tweets are useful and outside of that I basically just post stuff for the listeners and I really don't read tweets.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so why do you want something that's all fancy just so you can read tweets that you don't want to read
Speaker 1: Because I would actually start using it to publish information toward other sources of I guess other Data receivers out in my life that I currently don't use Twitter for cuz it's not powerful enough.
Speaker 1: How is it not powerful enough Cuz I can't like I can't have my private ring of tweets that goes out to group of people easily like.
Speaker 1: Tweet all my friends versus tweet this with the clients.
Speaker 1: I have now I want radii.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: why do you want to keep very shit secret?
Speaker 1: I don't want to give the address of a party out to the listeners.
Speaker 1: if we're just gonna go to a party with our friends So why you Twitter's?
Speaker 1: that's not Twitter's for yeah, but it'd be useful to have you know Get rid of email and all these things.
Speaker 1: just kind of have one Way where I just take a piece of information and toss it in the pipe with simple directions of.
Speaker 1: I wanted to go to My.
Speaker 1: I wanted to go to these people maybe my friends Maybe the listeners whoever and it just goes out over all the different pipes and all the different ways To whoever it wants it or should get it based on my initial directives But there's no way.
Speaker 0: see the thing is at this point in time There isn't really any reason to even have any restrictions whatsoever.
Speaker 0: because okay, I tweet something to just my friends Only and then the friend retweets it another whole world ceases.
Speaker 0: What's the point?
Speaker 1: That's fine if they do that.
Speaker 1: That's trust.
Speaker 1: That's the whole bay.
Speaker 1: all technology all chains of trust fail if you trust someone who might.
Speaker 0: but the thing is you just might as Well make everything go out to the whole world.
Speaker 0: This is why all these people are going crazy like leaving Facebook over privacy.
Speaker 0: shit I'm like I fuck.
Speaker 0: everything on Facebook should be 100% public.
Speaker 0: There should be zero private data.
Speaker 0: You know if you want to be private don't type it in anywhere.
Speaker 1: Good idea to open up our private forum with all our stuff in there.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, what are people gonna find in there?
Speaker 0: Oh my god, they're playing burning wheel on Saturday.
Speaker 0: Oh shit It.
Speaker 1: you don't think it would be annoying at all for everyone out there to have.
Speaker 1: you know All of our phone numbers email addresses, you know, our actual phone numbers are actual email address.
Speaker 0: You didn't want people to find it out.
Speaker 0: Why'd you type it in?
Speaker 1: because no one's republishing it.
Speaker 0: What do I care if someone people can know my phone number.
Speaker 0: where they can do they're gonna call me.
Speaker 1: They might.
Speaker 1: I dare them to call me Alright, so you just wanted said why don't you just put your phone number out there on the forum and see what happens?
Speaker 0: Alright my phone number is 6 4 6 4 1 6 1 8 9 5. don't call me Why not?
Speaker 1: they can call you.
Speaker 1: all you want is not you bother me.
Speaker 0: I'll call the police and you're because you're harassing me.
Speaker 0: It's not legitimate reason to call me.
Speaker 1: go ahead It's got basically any reason.
Speaker 1: to call you is legitimate unless they repeatedly call you after you tell them to stop.
Speaker 1: So if a million people call you once per day, there's nothing you can do about that.
Speaker 1: I'll just get a new number and then you're gonna publish that number.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: And then the same thing happens You can never use the phone again.
Speaker 0: It'll be pretty awesome Because what I'll do is I'll if people have a million people continue to call me day after day after changing my number even Once and they never stop I can turn that into something.
Speaker 0: I'll be like this the calls to Scott and I'll make a whole website about it.
Speaker 0: be fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: Plus Scott part of the reason that that you know our internal forum our discussions work Is that we don't have outside people just butting in saying stuff that we don't care about.
Speaker 1: you know spamming it up I.
Speaker 0: this is why I think the forum is the incorrect usage for you know, that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Would you suggest for public discussions just among our friends?
Speaker 0: if it a public discussion it's public among our friends.
Speaker 1: It's private for the rest of the world.
Speaker 1: What would you for, you know small discussion?
Speaker 0: I don't have a reason to keep anything private.
Speaker 0: I would just you know, I would just make everything public.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 1: You really don't think that would be annoying at all.
Speaker 1: What would be annoying it, you know, just like random kids on the internet start You know getting in the way of our thread and we're trying to make our characters.
Speaker 1: I just scroll past it All right, so you're gonna scroll past like thousands of posts of penises and all that.
Speaker 0: There aren't even thousands of posts of penises in the regular.
Speaker 1: we already don't let people in.
Speaker 1: We already have a very high filter.
Speaker 0: I approve everyone who applies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, unless they're spam I don't not, you know, that's not there to keep people out.
Speaker 0: I don't like.
Speaker 0: it's there to keep out spam.
Speaker 1: So anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, you're not gonna believe this thing today.
Speaker 1: I'm not.
Speaker 0: no check this out.
Speaker 0: this lady She's got this blog mad Shabbat holes blog right, huh, and She basically it's a blog.
Speaker 0: That's about one thing The dollhouse that she is making the dollhouse.
Speaker 0: That is a pretty much perfect Bag-end my handcrafted Lord of the Rings dollhouse.
Speaker 1: I saw that on FARC.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't look at it though.
Speaker 1: Is it actually high quality?
Speaker 0: It's pretty much as high quality as it can possibly possibly Imagine we be what scale?
Speaker 1: it's dollhouse scale, which there's multiple dollhouse scales I have.
Speaker 0: no I what do you think?
Speaker 1: I have a dollhouse expert like is it standard and Western or is it Imperial?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know a little tiny shit like little tiny hobbit American freestyle.
Speaker 1: I mean, you're like like.
Speaker 1: Actually American freestyle is from penny arcade.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the point is is that the railroad gauges there's like H gauge and O gauge double Z gauge.
Speaker 0: The point is that this list this lady is like a pretty good-looking like, you know, mommy lady right there me with hobbit house.
Speaker 1: Not bad, right.
Speaker 0: So my all I got to say is if like you're 20 something and you're gonna grow up to be that lady call me So, uh I had a couple of things.
Speaker 1: but this was cool because we saw it not that long ago.
Speaker 1: So it was present in the mind some confirmation bias when we were at PAX and anime Boston.
Speaker 1: You know We hang out with our friend Steve who works at MIT and when we went to visit him Away these secrets we stopped at the the Kendall t-stop.
Speaker 1: the T is basically Boston's bus subway that's underground and mostly and They had in it this whole huge art exhibit.
Speaker 1: That was basically Instruments that you could manipulate from the platform that would then play like notes and do cool stuff and basically annoy all the commuters.
Speaker 1: and It was a very old sculpture very intricate that had been broken for some time now and That was cool.
Speaker 1: Remember we talked actually to Steve about this and like yeah, it's kind of broken.
Speaker 1: We got one to work the the Thunder I think was the one we got to work.
Speaker 1: And I remember saying oh, it's sad someone should rebuild that thing.
Speaker 1: and sure enough a bunch of students MIT at the rapid Fabrication lab and all this stuff a rapid prototyping lab.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's what we saw that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they got together and they're rebuilding all the instruments.
Speaker 0: I love that You know.
Speaker 0: That's one thing that constantly bothers me is when you see like ruins of things out and about especially like you go to a science Museum and this exhibit.
Speaker 0: that doesn't work.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Or you go to the arcade and there's a game the roller coaster park and you see the abandoned mine ride that a kid died in Wildwood.
Speaker 0: there was the the barrel of fun or even like right here you get the Queensborough Bridge and there's the elevator lift that no Longer operate man.
Speaker 1: I just want to ride that elevator.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know you got all these.
Speaker 0: I hate it when things stop operating.
Speaker 0: It's like Rochester subway, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah We explored the Rochester subway at least.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean if you got something right and you make it It's like you got to keep you know, go to the World's Fair.
Speaker 0: They got all this stuff.
Speaker 0: It just doesn't you know, it's like keep the shit in repair.
Speaker 0: So when someone repairs something that was disrepaired, that's awesome.
Speaker 0: That's like made of wind.
Speaker 0: if I was the mayor of New York I would just have a World's Fair just so I could get over the fact that all that shits in disrepair.
Speaker 1: Something about how as Dense as our human population is especially in places like New York at the same time how sparse it is that you go Like 20 minutes north in the Bronx and they're like gigantic just abandoned rail yards and abandoned factory Houses all over the place.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Even in one of the densest and most like the biggest cities in the world There's just abandoned stuff all over the place that we can't even fill this little tiny space.
Speaker 1: We've got yep.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so the original point of this show, I guess we'll have to call this how long did we use?
Speaker 1: like 44 minutes fuck me.
Speaker 1: Maybe we shouldn't even talk about antivirus.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: we got to change that.
Speaker 0: We got to redo the opening bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we can redo the opening bit some post-hoc.
Speaker 1: Well, it's built.
Speaker 1: We already did redo it Bill and Ted style.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah So this show was actually about what.
Speaker 1: what did we do the show on?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Is it like Why you can't beat Twitter with fancy features and also why privacy is unnecessary?
Speaker 1: Well, I guess we did that in the news.
Speaker 1: We kind of disagreed.
Speaker 1: Scott's got a love line set up.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: So call layman Scott if you've got any questions or if you have boobs.
Speaker 0: boobs should also call Not if you are a boob, but if you are in possession of them.
Speaker 1: Wow, I haven't used the word boob as a pejorative like that in a long time.
Speaker 0: You have the you know, the blue-footed boobs also call.
Speaker 0: we would like to do some sort of animal show.
Speaker 0: it would be fun You know what?
Speaker 1: I think the first half of the show speaks for itself Even though your listeners sadly missed out on the fact that we argued for like another half hour.
Speaker 0: Hey the you stream people got it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but no one else back to be recorded.
Speaker 0: the you stream, right?
Speaker 1: I believe.
Speaker 0: so you go to you stream.
Speaker 1: you can watch the record get it there, you know, well right into the meta moment We got a moment.
Speaker 1: We've got a you stream channel that we've started.
Speaker 1: for those of you who don't know or don't pay attention We've started.
Speaker 1: kind of whenever we record the show and we think to we turn on a camera and you can kind of watch us record the show live and You get to hear it's really boring Cuz.
Speaker 0: all you do is you watch us laying.
Speaker 0: you basically look at a picture of us that barely moves.
Speaker 0: Well, it's funny.
Speaker 1: You see Scott laying like lounging scratching my couch scratching my feet, you know, I mean well I'm like my whatever's I'm wearing like a sport jacket and I got the mixer and I'm sitting my hair on chair.
Speaker 0: Yep, but I'm facing away from the camera and you basically watch this while you hear the exact same thing you're hearing now.
Speaker 1: The only difference is you get to hear things like when we stop like between the first half of the show and the second half Of the show will stop and be like man.
Speaker 1: I gotta go.
Speaker 0: We'll stop and have like a 40-minute discussion.
Speaker 1: Yeah Or we'll say yeah, what are we doing the show on?
Speaker 1: You know, you'll get some of the pre-show.
Speaker 1: We try to figure out what the show is gonna be about.
Speaker 1: Mmm, get some post show.
Speaker 1: sometimes you see the studio audience.
Speaker 1: Yeah Oh, you can actually see the noise gates kicking in and the downward expander kicking in on the compressor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's going in real time there those red flashing things like right down there.
Speaker 0: Okay, Oh Cosmos is still the book.
Speaker 0: I actually bought a copy on Amazon for 65 cents.
Speaker 1: I'll be ready isn't here yet, but you know as soon as you finish it or I've read enough of it I'll be ready to go.
Speaker 1: cuz I'm just reading parts that I remembered vaguely as a kid.
Speaker 0: far too slowly.
Speaker 1: I'm working on stuff and playing video games.
Speaker 0: I'm also playing video games, but I'm also reading and working on stuff.
Speaker 1: I'm also Connecticut's taking up most of my time.
Speaker 1: to be honest.
Speaker 0: Oh, you know, you didn't give me any of the the load to bear because there's no easy way to collaborate.
Speaker 1: I'm actually I can't.
Speaker 1: I started writing making a database that I'm gonna use to make collaboration easier.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Yeah, but all that aside I guess we can finish out the show on something fun.
Speaker 0: What do you want to finish out on?
Speaker 1: so there was a story on slashdot about Monitors Quattro monitors that added a fourth color pixel in the sub pixel level.
Speaker 0: so instead of just RGB there's like the opposite of the the Nexus one that has green red blue green red blue.
Speaker 0: great, you know the word it does like the double greens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, instead.
Speaker 0: It's green red blue yellow.
Speaker 0: Why is there a yellow?
Speaker 1: for because it gives you a wider.
Speaker 1: you can make yellow by using It gives you a wider like spectrum of total possible colors You can show like the RGB that we use in CRT's and LCDs cannot show every possible color.
Speaker 1: All right And independent of that our human eyes fail us and there are certain real colors perfect wavelengths That due to the fact that like a blue will like excite a couple of red cones in the eye and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: We cannot by default see those colors anyway.
Speaker 1: So I found this awesome side.
Speaker 1: This would normally be a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: There's a whole bunch of like optical illusions, you know those kinds of sites But all of them illustrate a point as opposed to just being cool and the one that I want to point out.
Speaker 1: I'll just bring this up, you know talk about displays Randomly the eclipse of Mars and if you do this debate this this debate If you do this illusion It basically tires out the red receptors in a portion of your vision and then when you pull your head back You will see a halo around this red ring.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 1: Perfect.
Speaker 1: Cyan.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm You will see the cyan and it shows it next to a gradient Showing you that this color cannot be displayed by your monitor Even though it should because it's a real color.
Speaker 1: and you will see a color you have probably never seen before.
Speaker 1: It's pretty it's pretty damn cyan.
Speaker 0: I must say so what if you know the?
Speaker 0: you just made monitors that were CMYK CMYK.
Speaker 1: Well CMYK, I mean that you know, that's the K is the light behind the.
Speaker 1: you know, yeah Yeah, well, there's also, you know Additive versus subtractive.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: maybe we should do a show physics show on light and pigments because The people cannot just look this up on Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I feel course.
Speaker 1: at the same time I don't think a radio show about that is gonna be super enlightening.
Speaker 0: It is kind of anything like if you go to the store by LEDs, right?
Speaker 0: You can get green red blue white LEDs you can.
Speaker 0: I guess you can get purpley ones But yeah, you never.
Speaker 0: I don't really see like cyan.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess they have yellow, right?
Speaker 1: But what we could talk about?
Speaker 1: you see that a lot in stage lights.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's true You'll have the difference right but but those are just white lights with you know translucent filters in front of them.
Speaker 1: Well, that's just.
Speaker 1: it's cheaper and easier to make color that way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, really You don't say I think is you know, you think about it, right?
Speaker 0: You're actually using a fuck ton more energy with that sort of system because you're making it pretty much every wavelength of light Right with this huge friggin light bulb and then you turn it on then you're getting rid.
Speaker 0: You're turning it on the heat and you remove and most of those Wavelengths of light you're not even using.
Speaker 0: if you could make a light that was just the color you wanted like just yellow You would use a lot less energy than a white light with the yellow filter in front of it.
Speaker 0: Is that it?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I had nothing else there.
Speaker 0: Well, but maybe we can save a lot of energy on monitors if we.
Speaker 1: yeah Well, maybe display is too part of the reason I bring that up.
Speaker 1: So I remember a lot of discussions in the forum where an unnamed friend of ours bought a bunch of cheap LCDs Compared to the ultra sharp.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: We explained that this was a bad idea, but even the ultra sharp I mean it can't show every color and it can show 16.7 million colors.
Speaker 1: Your eyes just can't see them, but there are more colors than that 16 point whatever million.
Speaker 1: technically They're infinity colors because you can break the way there aren't because quanta the way they're there Discrete wavelengths that you can't be smaller.
Speaker 0: So so what is the smallest possible wavelength?
Speaker 1: If I try to even answer that question at all Timo is gonna have the biggest palm to forehead reaction that the world's ever seen.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, in fact would probably.
Speaker 0: are you sure you're not wrong already?
Speaker 1: He would probably in fact already cause a further eruption of a hanger hitting him.
Speaker 1: I can't pronounce the name of the But what I'm going to say and I hope I am NOT too wrong is that it probably Is in some way related to Planck's constant.
Speaker 1: Okay, because that is isn't?
Speaker 1: that's the smallest like distance that makes sense.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is.
Speaker 1: the point is that yeah, they're okay There isn't.
Speaker 0: I don't think infinite doesn't matter because even if you have more than 16.7 million colors You can't see more than 16.7 million colors.
Speaker 1: Well, according to this we can't even see like basic colors like cyan perfectly.
Speaker 1: So It raises an interesting question though, because look I the limitation is not Necessarily my brain.
Speaker 1: the limitation is the shitty physical nerves I've got that are processing this, you know reflected electron information.
Speaker 0: Oh, we already know that mine are a lot better than yours.
Speaker 1: Uh, I would argue that with my glasses mine is better.
Speaker 1: No, why not?
Speaker 1: gives me 20/10 vision The only.
Speaker 0: let's get some eye tests going on.
Speaker 0: We'll see who wins.
Speaker 1: I actually paid.
Speaker 0: that would be a great video game.
Speaker 0: I test battle.
Speaker 1: You'd make that in flash.
Speaker 1: people might cheat.
Speaker 0: How you gonna prevent cheating?
Speaker 1: make him use a webcam and then figure out how far away they are and then make the images sized accordingly.
Speaker 0: That's an actually interesting problem.
Speaker 0: How would you make a video game?
Speaker 0: That is the eye test game?
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: You could do the same thing that that fancy window did where you could have a fake window in your house.
Speaker 1: if you wear a Necklace that tells the window where you are.
Speaker 1: It makes a perfect 3d scene outside.
Speaker 0: Oh So basically if you got close to you tried to get close to your TV screen to cheat.
Speaker 1: It just makes it get smaller.
Speaker 0: No because what you do is you just put the necklace far on the other side of the room and then walk up to.
Speaker 1: you could Do it with a camera, but then I'll use a cardboard cutout of my face like in three men and a baby.
Speaker 1: Yes, so then you have to do an IR sensor.
Speaker 1: then I put a heat pack behind the cardboard cutout of the face.
Speaker 0: But it would be actually that might actually be the best solution because the heat pack would not be the right shape of a person.
Speaker 0: so if your IR Imaging sense I get my friend to stand in front of the computer while I stand back But it would see that there's two people so it turn off.
Speaker 1: it could only be one person stand directly behind him And I look at the screen from an angle above Detect double heat though Behind a shield a thermal blocking shield.
Speaker 0: Oh fuck I get like a big rectangular thermal shield that you could hide behind it and then look at the screen with a mirror right While your friend was standing on the other side of the room making it think he was far away to display at the largest possible size.
Speaker 1: for all this we could just Make a proctor go to your house sign in with an RSA key and watch your ass.
Speaker 1: That is a way to make 3d displays though if you only have one person watching It's really easy to make a great 3d display.
Speaker 0: how so tracking head movement.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, yeah, cuz we've seen stuff that does that already.
Speaker 0: yep All right, yeah This show is like on the worst shows.
Speaker 1: oh my god, I don't know we're going all over the play.
Speaker 1: I mean we've done things that we haven't done in a long time that you guys always ask for one.
Speaker 1: we had an argument about bullshit and Then we went off on a tangent.
Speaker 0: Okay, I think we're to guess that you know we didn't have any ideas coming to the show.
Speaker 0: so that shows you what happens.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, I had a bad situation.
Speaker 1: It's all good.
Speaker 1: We'll wrap it up.
Speaker 1: I think we got a decent Wednesday show coming up mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening.
Speaker 1: music can't leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website At front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.