Speaker 1: It's Wednesday September 22nd.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm Ram and this is geek night tonight the sword.
Speaker 0: Let's do this So you might recall on the previous episode of geek nights.
Speaker 0: We were distracted by a large Strange bright wasn't that large.
Speaker 0: it was very very bright light, and we couldn't figure out what it was Mm-Hmm, so shortly after doing the show we decided to actually try and figure out what it was.
Speaker 0: and you know Scott took the camera we were using for project st And we discovered that it was in fact coming from the top of the roosevelt island tram aka the Spider-Man tram.
Speaker 1: This is a that's what they're calling it now.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone really knew what it was until they saw Spider-Man Uh-huh at least people outside of the city already, so that's what it was.
Speaker 0: It was just a light on top of that thing.
Speaker 0: But the reason it was so bright was that later it continued to blink But it was red.
Speaker 0: so it's ultra bright.
Speaker 0: and then when they put the red filter over it It is not nearly as bright.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I see it blinking in the same position now.
Speaker 0: Yep, same position same pattern, but now it's red and now it is not so bright that it's painful even from miles away Mm-Hmm, I can't imagine what it was like being like in one of those buildings next to that thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, and it's weird to think the light is so crazy bright and only you know putting a plastic thing over it makes it.
Speaker 0: I think all the colors were getting out now.
Speaker 0: Just red is getting out.
Speaker 0: all those other colors turn it into heat.
Speaker 1: Thing must be real hot like oh you touch it and you get burn.
Speaker 0: amaited That's it.
Speaker 0: That's all I got.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: That was the thing.
Speaker 1: Did you read that?
Speaker 1: The strange tales I did?
Speaker 1: how about that?
Speaker 0: it was pretty good.
Speaker 0: I believe you geek-bited this on the last Wednesday night episode.
Speaker 1: I did indeed But I felt like mentioning again because you read it and I you know I want people really pay attention to it and purchase it because it was alright wasn't great.
Speaker 1: You don't think it was great.
Speaker 0: No, I don't think it was great.
Speaker 1: I think it was great.
Speaker 0: individual comics in it were great.
Speaker 0: I really really liked Spider-Man in the spider town And I liked the a lot of the really short one-off ones and the one where the kid gets his head popped off.
Speaker 0: But a lot of them were kind of.
Speaker 0: they were funny, and they were good, but they were good in that.
Speaker 0: kind of.
Speaker 0: check out this Generic indie comic.
Speaker 0: it's making references to things that you don't know a lot about.
Speaker 0: it's okay.
Speaker 0: It's probably funnier if you'd read that comic.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean the thing that the only thing I could say negative about it Right is that they had like this.
Speaker 1: the one they gave the most pages to is like the spider megalomaniac one which had a whole bunch of pages in the back right, but it's like the really good stuff like you know the Parry Bible Fellowship guy and Jason.
Speaker 1: they only gave him a few pages.
Speaker 1: It's like why couldn't the Jason one be like the whole back of the book at the same time?
Speaker 0: look at the Jason one and The Parry Bible Fellowship ones.
Speaker 0: they had clarity of vision and focus they had.
Speaker 0: this is my joke.
Speaker 0: I've made the joke as soon as I have made the joke and executed it.
Speaker 0: I'm done.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, no, no, I'm not saying that they should not have removed the clarity.
Speaker 1: I'm saying they should increase the quantity.
Speaker 0: right maintain the VF guy.
Speaker 1: do ten one-off Joe exactly what I'm saying right?
Speaker 1: He doesn't need to do a whole strip But it goes on and on and on.
Speaker 1: he just needs to do more of the very focused high Like.
Speaker 1: if Jason did like ten three pagers for 30 pages, you know, I guess just if you get a 30 pager It'd be like
Speaker 0: it was all over the place in terms of quality or at least in terms of my personal enjoyment And a lot of times something would happen in like one of the short ones and I would basically think all right This is clearly referencing something in that universe that I don't know about and it probably would be funny if I knew.
Speaker 0: well I think I like how when you know in some anime you're watching that subtitled poorly, you know They made a Japanese pun and you get that a pun happened and you might even get like.
Speaker 0: well He said the word for tree, but blah blah blah blah, but you only find it funny because you knew there was a joke there.
Speaker 0: But you don't actually laugh at the joke itself because it's completely inaccessible to you.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, I mean, I think the thing is is that You know, it's like you're an indie creator.
Speaker 1: You don't get to draw a spider-man and Wolverine at least not commercially right too often.
Speaker 1: So you get this chance to draw it for real in a real Marvel comic.
Speaker 1: So you're basically those are the jokes that you've been holding on to Right all this time that you couldn't make because you need those characters to make the joke.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the joke is about the characters.
Speaker 0: so that's the kind of joke you're gonna get and I can't disparage the effort at all because That kind of inside joke is the kind of thing that I want in my own realm.
Speaker 0: I mean like when I want a video game joke like College Humor does a video game thing.
Speaker 0: if it's inside baseball It's a thousand times funnier to me and screw everybody else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it's like if you're if you get finally get the chance to like put Wolverine in your comic for reals It's actually Wolverine not Wolverine, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, or wolf this arena or lone wolf and oh wait, right.
Speaker 1: Well lone wolf came first.
Speaker 1: But the thing is you finally get this chance to do a spider-man comic, right?
Speaker 1: And if you just made it like a regular comic and you just happen to draw the main character as looking like spider-man But and he swung with webs But you didn't actually make any jokes about like J. Jonah Jameson or anything like that Then what the hell was the point?
Speaker 0: you could have just made that comic without the spider-man I guess the way who I would advertise this to seriously like if you're not into these sorts of comics, it's good It's worth reading.
Speaker 0: I don't know if I'd buy it necessarily But if you are a fan of superhero underwear pervert those universes.
Speaker 0: This is pretty much the best gateway drug into indie comics the world has to offer you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because I guess you get to laugh at jokes that you will understand.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: it's like if you like indie comics You'll like this book because all your favorite indie comic creators are in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you like underwear perverts this has all your favorite characters in it.
Speaker 0: But other artists that you know styles you might never run across doing their thing and hopefully you can get the crossover going on.
Speaker 0: I guess it's the breed.
Speaker 0: the trouble is if you don't like indie comics and you don't like superhero comics You will not like this.
Speaker 1: I mean did you basically don't like comics?
Speaker 1: Which makes you pretty stupid because I mean that's like not like in movies or not like, you know, I don't know What if you're blind?
Speaker 1: Hey, listen what I know.
Speaker 1: this guy the comic pimp right and he is blind and he loves the comics.
Speaker 1: He is like the greatest.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: This guy is amazing.
Speaker 1: He leaves voicemails and like a bunch of comic podcasts.
Speaker 1: Ah, he is hilarious.
Speaker 0: What can we do to raise his eye?
Speaker 1: doesn't like nerdcore though?
Speaker 1: He like frequently complains that nerdcore sucks.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah in particular.
Speaker 0: That's that's like saying Yeah, rap sucks.
Speaker 1: If we saw if we see him at the New York Comic Con I'll point him out to you because there is nerdcore that sucks.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm not gonna pretend there isn't.
Speaker 1: if we see him in New York Comic Con.
Speaker 1: We'll go talk to him.
Speaker 1: All right, cuz he's pretty awesome, huh?
Speaker 0: It's just interesting to me and I'm trying I'm not making light of this or making a joke But I kind of am.
Speaker 0: I laughed a tiny bit that the blind guys really into comics But really doesn't like some particular kind of music.
Speaker 1: I know.
Speaker 0: So You got any news for me?
Speaker 0: I know we really almost never have anime news anymore.
Speaker 0: So I'm assuming you've got some anime news.
Speaker 0: There's been all this time.
Speaker 0: So I assume something happened to the anime world.
Speaker 1: actually know there's a big comic book news, right?
Speaker 1: I mean great Okay, so anyway, this big comic news is basically, you know It's been sort of coming down the line right because there have been sort of like DC.
Speaker 0: It's basically it's a DC news, by the way God I don't like the Marvel Universe like just for what it is, but I don't like the DC Universe a thousand times more anyway.
Speaker 1: They've had some shakeups, you know in in recent history, right?
Speaker 1: But here's and they but what they've sort of been doing is they sort of doing it one step at a time, right?
Speaker 1: Instead of making one big earth shaking shakeup It's like they have phases almost in the shakeup and I don't know if this is the end or not But it looks pretty close to it.
Speaker 0: So this is a shakeup of the industry not of like the universe.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, there's five Batman's and one's on the moon.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's nothing like that.
Speaker 0: And there's some sort of infinity and terror Multiple worlds.
Speaker 1: It's enough from you.
Speaker 0: Okay, so hit you you little guy.
Speaker 1: basically, that's Marvel and Stanley.
Speaker 1: So Basically, what happened is right is zuda which is sort of their digital thing, right?
Speaker 1: They closed.
Speaker 1: the website was closed a while ago in a previous shakeup phase.
Speaker 0: I did not even know that happened.
Speaker 1: But now they're closing down the whole thing.
Speaker 1: So the zuda label is gone.
Speaker 1: Whoa, but you know any comics in zuda that are going to survive are going to survive.
Speaker 1: They're just gonna say DC on them instead of zuda on them.
Speaker 1: So what?
Speaker 0: so what like?
Speaker 0: why they shut it down?
Speaker 0: Did they say because it wasn't making money?
Speaker 1: Also their Wildstorm right, which is also DC You know, they published Ex Machina and such right?
Speaker 1: Well Ex Machina is over.
Speaker 1: So they have no good comics left.
Speaker 1: and anyone who likes the remaining Wildstorm comics you suck because they suck.
Speaker 1: So they're shutting that down too.
Speaker 1: and any remaining Wildstorm comics that they're gonna keep around will be say DC on them and Any all the Wildstorm characters that they're getting rid of right because those comics are ending or just canon them.
Speaker 1: those characters might appear in the DC Universe in some other book who knows and They fired I think like some percentage of the people at these places.
Speaker 1: It's a whole bunch of people lost their jobs and basically what they're doing is they're putting all the digital Stuff right.
Speaker 1: all DC's multimedia and digital productions are gonna be on the west coast.
Speaker 1: Well all their printing and publishing is gonna be in New York City.
Speaker 1: So it's like they're splitting it up two ways because really all their digital stuff is sort of way behind.
Speaker 1: You know even Marvel which is kind of slow is ahead of DC in terms of digital.
Speaker 0: in terms of digital content I note that neither Marvel nor DC have quite grasped webcomic.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: I know right It's like what they're really good at finding webcomic creators and eventually giving them a job doing regular old comics.
Speaker 0: But they I mean look at the media and finance Empire that penny arcade is and they still do not charge for penny arcade.
Speaker 1: I know right It's like look at Marvel right.
Speaker 0: They're doing a three panel strip.
Speaker 1: It's just don't ask me so Frickin and you know Gabe and Tyco are totally and Robert coup.
Speaker 1: They're definitely making more money than almost any of those comic creators at Marvel or DC with a contract.
Speaker 1: There is no question.
Speaker 0: and then look at things like dr.
Speaker 0: Ninja.
Speaker 0: if you say oh well, you know the comic book style format like we do wouldn't work in a webcomic.
Speaker 0: dr McNinja works as both both a comic and a webcomic.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: and dr.
Speaker 1: McNinja.
Speaker 1: He lives off there, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah He's doing all right assume, so I don't actually know.
Speaker 1: there's a lot of dr.
Speaker 1: McNinja t-shirts.
Speaker 1: You walk down just the street no convention.
Speaker 1: You'll see the freaking shark high-fiving the the gorilla whatever it is.
Speaker 0: That's a good shirt.
Speaker 0: I only don't buy it because everyone else has it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway.
Speaker 1: So yeah, the shake-up is a pretty interesting shake-up right here, and it's shaky All right, so kind of.
Speaker 1: I kind of actually kind of glad because ex Machina ended and there's no good Wildstorm comics I think at all.
Speaker 0: What do they?
Speaker 0: what comics are there right now?
Speaker 1: Nothing you care about really?
Speaker 1: Like it's it's still.
Speaker 1: it's all crap.
Speaker 1: The only reason ex Machina was Wildstorm instead of vertigo right is because it's a superhero comic right you know.
Speaker 1: and vertigo Doesn't really do the superhero stuff.
Speaker 1: So you know cuz why the last man was vertigo all right and so his fables and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: So it couldn't be vertigo, but they didn't want.
Speaker 1: you know mayor hundred in DC Universe.
Speaker 1: You know you couldn't have Superman flying in.
Speaker 0: That would ruin everything I liked about the ex Machina work right.
Speaker 1: so they put it in the Wildstorm.
Speaker 1: That's the only reason it was over there as opposed to vertigo because it was a superhero comic And they didn't want to put it in DC.
Speaker 0: So they they only See just put it out and say it does not say it's in their fucking universe.
Speaker 1: Because freaking nerds right the only people who buy these things And look at the labels and nerds and the nerds will go there And they'll see the DC label on it, and they'll see Brian K Ooh, and they'll buy it and they'll be like hey, where's Batman?
Speaker 1: The fuck see.
Speaker 0: Anime fans are one thing and like every fandom has its this is visa.
Speaker 1: Hey, I bought this comic right 20th century boys.
Speaker 1: It's his vis on the side.
Speaker 1: How come friggin luffy isn't it?
Speaker 0: What's the deal?
Speaker 0: I feel like comic fans in particular the really hardcore ones the ones who would say I am a comic nerd And I'm proud of it.
Speaker 0: the dude with a little rolly suitcase full of silver age silver surfer looking for the one issue of silver age silver surfer that he doesn't have.
Speaker 0: I Feel like any time you interact with that industry.
Speaker 0: It's like poking an anthill with a stick.
Speaker 0: Yeah So I actually have some anime news.
Speaker 0: This is actually pretty important news because I'm important.
Speaker 0: could it be because I don't pay attention to anime news And it stood out and I would have liked to known this sooner.
Speaker 0: So madhouse was actually doing an anime movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they didn't try gun movie.
Speaker 1: now aside from the dragon and they're doing Satoshi khan's movie that aside from that I saw lightning outside.
Speaker 0: There is another movie another movie that madhouse is doing that is already aired at some film festivals like two years ago.
Speaker 0: That's now it is premiering in Japan.
Speaker 1: wait If it aired two years ago What took them two years?
Speaker 0: fuck if I know maybe it was an incomplete version.
Speaker 0: a lot film festivals get incomplete versions of film So they polished it over to you I'm assuming.
Speaker 0: so I don't know.
Speaker 1: if it's got two years of polish You better be fucking good.
Speaker 1: So and it better not look like it's two years old either.
Speaker 1: It better look like it's from this year.
Speaker 0: So I'm linking to the trailer because it is premiering in Japan next month.
Speaker 1: Like early does it look like a new movie or does look like a two-year-old movie?
Speaker 0: It looks like a brand new move.
Speaker 1: All right, good.
Speaker 0: If I had to describe this just based on looking at the way it looks take wings of oni amis and mash it up With f-zero and remove any derp-de-der.
Speaker 1: Is there was an f-zero anime that was derp-de-derp.
Speaker 1: It was loaded with derp-de-derp and actually there's a lot of racing animes.
Speaker 1: wasn't there that studio I g1 production I g1 about racing?
Speaker 1: that I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't think that was any good.
Speaker 1: and then initial D. Well, it's initial day.
Speaker 1: So well man.
Speaker 1: This lightning is awesome.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 0: You're getting distracted by things.
Speaker 0: The listeners can't see removing any Possible forgetting that this is a show that we're recording like in a studio.
Speaker 0: You're just like ah breaking walls all over the place.
Speaker 1: I get to look at the lightning and you don't cuz I'm looking at because I can look at the fucking audition and the fire wire.
Speaker 0: So sweet, it's important because one anime movie any anime movie if you're an anime fan You should see because there aren't that many.
Speaker 0: if you especially if you don't count Pokemon number X and one piece number Y Yeah, I'll pretty.
Speaker 1: I'll see pretty much any anime movie as long as it.
Speaker 1: the ones I'll skip though Besides the Pokemon X and the one piece Y are things like.
Speaker 1: I guess I'm not necessarily need to skip them But I you know I won't rush to see them necessarily are things that are attached to a TV series that I didn't see or I'm not interested in Like.
Speaker 1: I think they're those Pokemon.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, I think there was like a Eureka seven movie, right?
Speaker 0: I didn't even watch Eureka seven exactly.
Speaker 1: So, I mean, it's not you know, it's not some movie in a string of movies But it's also not a movie I'm gonna rush to see.
Speaker 1: I might see it I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'll put those at least for now in the same category as Pokemon X. All right, but it's madhouse.
Speaker 0: It's being directed by a guy named Takeshi Koike, and I'd never heard this was.
Speaker 1: is he related to Kazuo Koike.
Speaker 0: I'm going to go down the list of other things he has done.
Speaker 0: I'm just going to say what role he had and see if this this will make.
Speaker 0: well He wasn't.
Speaker 1: he wasn't director director director.
Speaker 0: No, no, but he has the role that indicates.
Speaker 0: He's probably the kind of person we're looking for.
Speaker 0: Key animator key animator key animator key animator key animator animation assistant.
Speaker 1: key animator carries eyes an animator and not a character designer.
Speaker 0: He is a key animator and he did stuff for other big stuff and under other big people.
Speaker 0: He might be one of those protege people that we just didn't know about.
Speaker 1: All right, so what did he?
Speaker 1: what did he do?
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: what animes were they?
Speaker 0: Oh like Ursa Yatsura stuff and Goku midnight eye DNA squared.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so fairly big stuff.
Speaker 0: not necessarily good stuff ninja scroll, but he's good.
Speaker 0: He's doing the kinds of things He's in the kinds of roles for the kinds of anime that Traditionally have been the sign of someone who was a protege of someone.
Speaker 1: good Well, we'll see how his movie is.
Speaker 1: It took him two years to polish it out.
Speaker 0: The trailer looks really fun and it's I mean, I wanted the f-zero anime to be good, but it was stupid as shit.
Speaker 0: This is basically the f-zero anime done right as far as I can tell but animated really lushly.
Speaker 1: man How come we need?
Speaker 1: we need a fucking f-zero game.
Speaker 1: not since the GameCube.
Speaker 1: if we had Even that game is still good.
Speaker 1: I can play the film That game right now if I had to which follows the deadliest car race known to space.
Speaker 1: that's f-zero.
Speaker 1: Well open in Japan on October 9th, you know The only thing that could be.
Speaker 1: you know that you mean like if I if I couldn't live in the Tron world.
Speaker 1: f-zero world is My second choice.
Speaker 0: zero world not that bad.
Speaker 0: also Objectionable content is rated as significant.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: It probably means exploding cars with guts everywhere.
Speaker 0: This looks pretty fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: I suggest you watch the trailer and you know what if it's not awesome.
Speaker 0: It's a movie.
Speaker 0: It's a hundred and ten minutes and that is it.
Speaker 1: We'll find out if it's awesome or not.
Speaker 0: We'll probably see it when it come in the Angelica or something when it comes to New York, hopefully.
Speaker 0: So things of the day, what do you have for me Scott?
Speaker 1: What do I have for you?
Speaker 1: So you are very familiar with the daikon animation.
Speaker 0: the daikon animation the thing that we show at like every anime con.
Speaker 0: Whenever we're trying to inspire kids the most people cry, but have you seen daikon 3 extra?
Speaker 0: Daikon 3 extra.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: This is daikon 3 extra.
Speaker 1: You're not hearing the audio You know because I just turned it off on my laptop.
Speaker 0: I saw someone linked to this recently, but I didn't watch it.
Speaker 1: It was on the Twitter.
Speaker 1: someone linked to it and that's how I found out about it.
Speaker 1: So here is daikon 3 extra and pretty much all it is is the daikon animation girl in her daikon You know her younger daikon form Transforming into a whole bunch of other characters sort of cosplaying.
Speaker 0: a whole bunch Happily recognize most of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and That's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: That is desperately cute.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the kind of thing We got a whip out at a panel like at the end like hey, we got something for you.
Speaker 1: Yep Alright, so there you go.
Speaker 0: So a while ago.
Speaker 0: Well a long time ago I read a webcomic and you know right when I was really getting into webcomics like really I was reading mega Tokyo Penny arcade.
Speaker 0: Nowadays, I just read penny arcade.
Speaker 1: I read here.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna run down my webcomics really quick.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I have a bookmarks right open.
Speaker 1: Well, actually I read some newspaper comic so I can do those too.
Speaker 1: So Leo Li o is a newspaper comic Calvin and Hobbes that you can actually read it online and they cycle through the old ones in order.
Speaker 0: I've already read everything.
Speaker 1: The thing is the calendar that they're using doesn't match up with the real world calendar.
Speaker 1: So sometimes you read a Christmas comic in the summer.
Speaker 0: I think I've read every single Calvin and Hobbes to the point that seeing any one panel from one I can recall all other panels from it anyway.
Speaker 1: You know Dilbert just because sometimes it's not funny anymore.
Speaker 1: No, but you know, no Does its comic right even though it's often not funny.
Speaker 1: the people who do that are actually Like really good in terms of comics like they do all sorts of interesting, you know Like they're the only ones who are actually comic artists, you know Most of the people in the comic strip newspaper comic strip business Right are like Dilbert or Garfield where they just do panel panel panel character character character copy pasta, right?
Speaker 1: But the guys who do zits actually do like art and it's just cool to see like some of the stuff they do especially when they're doing like, you know real like big reactions of people, you know, like they'll have.
Speaker 1: For example, if the kid is like eating too much They'll draw like, you know, this like ridiculous like amount of food or just really exaggerated stuff.
Speaker 1: It's it's good arts.
Speaker 1: Let's see web comics real life.
Speaker 1: Just because of inertia.
Speaker 0: Wow, I Actually legitimately honestly forgot about real life until just that.
Speaker 1: so he's still updating it.
Speaker 1: Wow penny arcade I've got that janky old real-life shirt, right?
Speaker 1: So here's that is real comics.
Speaker 1: I'm actually reading for real penny arcade.
Speaker 1: Dr McNinja xkcd boases which hasn't updated in forever, but it might update soon.
Speaker 1: Wonder mark Johnny wander order the stick freak angels I guess foxtrots and newspaper comic.
Speaker 1: but it's only updates on Sunday.
Speaker 1: gun show Hark of vagrant ex-cop.
Speaker 0: Wow right now things I mean, I read a lot of web comics but not kind of regularly like.
Speaker 0: I'll go Yeah, and I'll read like every day.
Speaker 1: I load that whole folder of Ted.
Speaker 0: the ones I load every day are Hark of vagrant dr.
Speaker 0: McNinja penny arcade xkcd vg cats Johnny wander and now a Perverted comic called ogloff vg cats really.
Speaker 0: Yeah, did you catch this really funny?
Speaker 0: She's never fucking updates.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so what's up love.
Speaker 0: way back in the day when I read any webcomic I could find I used to read a comic called The thin H line.
Speaker 1: it then later became sexy losers, but you don't read order the stick.
Speaker 0: I guess yeah, I do read order the stick.
Speaker 0: Okay, but I don't load it every day like once a week.
Speaker 0: I'll kind of go back and read whatever.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the thin H line Aka sexy losers was a perverted like sex comic.
Speaker 0: It was actually funny But it was dirty Really dirty and unabashedly dirty and a lot of his dar IT were into it and it was kind of a popular I wasn't.
Speaker 0: a lot of us were though.
Speaker 0: Greg read it.
Speaker 0: I think Pete read it.
Speaker 0: a bunch of us read it.
Speaker 0: It was all you.
Speaker 0: All right, it was funny.
Speaker 0: But anyway, I don't know how many people realize that there are a lot of dirty webcomics out there.
Speaker 0: Really funny you don't say so.
Speaker 1: are they the same?
Speaker 1: they're funny in the same way that You know, what's it called?
Speaker 1: The the elf?
Speaker 1: what the hell's that kind of?
Speaker 1: call them anime?
Speaker 1: So what the hell is that elf princess rain not elf princess rain the.
Speaker 1: oh elven bride elven bride That's the thing is.
Speaker 1: I kept thinking elven leader.
Speaker 1: I was like hell it's not elephant.
Speaker 0: No god.
Speaker 1: No god No, so I'm like elven something.
Speaker 0: well in that they're funny But they use sex or violence or something perverted to make the same kind of joke you'd get somewhere else.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the problem is right is that we sort of have this, you know censorship going on, right?
Speaker 1: But it's not censorship that says, you know perverted comic you cannot exist It's censorship.
Speaker 1: that perverted comic must be separate from regular comic, right?
Speaker 1: so you have some comics that are totally without any pervertedness and some comics that are nothing but pervertedness.
Speaker 1: and Really, you know, there isn't a comic out there that's just has perverted stuff mixed in with regular stuff in a in a balance the same way that real life has a balance between Sex and not sex and that kind of comic doesn't really exist.
Speaker 1: so much, you know If you go and find like a hentai anime, it's got all sex.
Speaker 1: if it's comedy It's got all sex jokes.
Speaker 1: Every joke is about oh my god dildo got stuck where right.
Speaker 1: but if you read something that's not sexy There's.
Speaker 1: no there's no dildo jokes in it at all.
Speaker 0: So I have three comics for you three bad comics.
Speaker 0: They're bad in some manner.
Speaker 0: just to point out that there are comics out there that are weird or fucked up That you might not know about.
Speaker 0: All right, so let's start with fucked up.
Speaker 0: The parking lot is full.
Speaker 1: It's dead.
Speaker 0: it ended in 2002, but the archives are online and you might Occasionally hear someone in the FRC say something to the effect of it's goofy time.
Speaker 0: This is where that came from.
Speaker 0: this comic is fucked up.
Speaker 1: you should link directly to the it's goofy time.
Speaker 0: I guess I should.
Speaker 1: it's a lot like the far side, but fuck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not not.
Speaker 0: not sex humor Just really fucked up humor.
Speaker 0: It's like the far side the dark side And then sexy losers, which is you know The problem.
Speaker 0: Scott talked about where there are comics that are sex jokes or no sex jokes in the middle of the road This is just sex jokes.
Speaker 0: Yep, and then there's a comic called Ogilaf and This does what Scott says.
Speaker 0: nothing does.
Speaker 0: it's one of the rare comics I don't know.
Speaker 1: I read it and most of the strips are about.
Speaker 0: most of them are but not all of them.
Speaker 1: Not all of them is true.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: I find this comic utterly hilarious.
Speaker 1: All right, I think it's all right.
Speaker 1: It's not that hilarious.
Speaker 0: No, it's it's.
Speaker 1: it's got some good.
Speaker 1: It's got some good ways.
Speaker 0: It's nowhere near even the good VG cats.
Speaker 1: There were some good ones in there.
Speaker 1: I kept clicking next for a while.
Speaker 0: The ones I like the most are the dwarf ones those fucked up little dwarves making their fucked up.
Speaker 1: really I sort of like the evil bitch Queen.
Speaker 0: Ah When the the sprites keep coming.
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: That was good.
Speaker 0: These are all not safe for work.
Speaker 0: if I can't if you didn't get that impression you should write NSFW on the post.
Speaker 0: I definitely will.
Speaker 0: All right, so we read a comic the sword the sword.
Speaker 1: So basically this was actually recommended it to us by a listener at least a year perhaps two or more years ago Right, and that's how I even knew about it at all.
Speaker 1: Because really I never heard anyone discussing on any forums or podcasts or anything.
Speaker 1: But it was recommended by a listener and I looked into it and one day volume one was on sale.
Speaker 1: So ordered it and I read volume one and all that after reading volume one.
Speaker 1: I was like, well shit that is fucking hot.
Speaker 0: I was excited.
Speaker 0: Scott made me read volume one and I was like, yeah get the rest already.
Speaker 1: So then just recently the comic ended like the final issue came out and it's based on the elements, right?
Speaker 1: I mean how many things are based on the elements?
Speaker 1: almost everything?
Speaker 1: That's like the theme the go-to theme but you know, so what volume one is?
Speaker 1: earth.
Speaker 1: I forget which element is which volume but there's four volumes.
Speaker 1: are the four elements of earth air water and fire And I don't know the order because I'm not looking at him right fire water earth air.
Speaker 1: Those are.
Speaker 1: that's the four volumes.
Speaker 0: It's in the.
Speaker 0: it's in an order.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so The fourth volume just recently came out.
Speaker 1: So what I did is I ordered two three four And then I hadn't read one of the longest time since I got it for so cheap.
Speaker 1: So I just I read one two, three four and I said, aha This is a comic that we can do a podcast about because it is only four volumes and I'll give it to him and he read.
Speaker 1: He actually read them.
Speaker 1: It's a miracle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we'll not spoil anything yet.
Speaker 0: We will spoil things into a full review, but we'll warn you before we get to that point.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm It's a solid B comic.
Speaker 0: I enjoyed it.
Speaker 0: I think the first volume set up a lot of expectations and I don't think it Quite lived up to what I wanted, but it was good.
Speaker 0: I enjoyed reading it.
Speaker 0: I would not tell anyone not to read it.
Speaker 0: If you're a fan of comics, there's no reason not to read this.
Speaker 1: I definitely think the setup in volume one right.
Speaker 1: you read volume one and you're like, oh shit.
Speaker 1: Fuck.
Speaker 1: Yeah What the hell's going on here?
Speaker 1: Right, but it's one of those things where just the premise is so awesome and the guy obviously was thinking about that setup for a Long time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was done by the lunar brothers.
Speaker 1: So it's actually two guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're like Jonathan and Josh.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're they're faint.
Speaker 1: They're pretty famous comic creators two J's.
Speaker 1: Yeah But they you know, they obviously had that setup coming But then they spent only one volume with this awesome setup and giving you the premise but then three volumes of resolution of that premise and the resolution while satisfying at times and such, you know wasn't the as exciting as
Speaker 0: Volume was when I suddenly got really worried because as soon as the second volume ended I thought
Speaker 1: oh,
Speaker 0: that's how they're gonna end all of them now, isn't it?
Speaker 1: Yeah pretty much You know, the thing is is that the in the in the beginning right?
Speaker 1: It's like, okay There's there's a mystery like what the fuck is going on, you know, and it sort of just comes out in nowhere.
Speaker 1: You're really getting it from the perspective of the main character like oh shit What the fuck.
Speaker 0: and I really like.
Speaker 0: it really comes out of nowhere in a way that few comics have been able to pull off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then you know, there's totally tons of mystery and intrigue and it's like what the fuck is going on.
Speaker 1: This is crazy.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 1: Oh my gosh, but then pretty much right after that they tell you the whole story.
Speaker 1: They don't leave any secrets whatsoever.
Speaker 1: So the rest of the comic.
Speaker 1: you're not trying to discover anything anymore There's no more mystery to it.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: You're just waiting.
Speaker 0: All right, how's this gonna end?
Speaker 1: Oh, I guess if I let me describe the premise so we can use less dodgy language.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty good premise.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there's a girl and she is in a wheelchair.
Speaker 1: Alright, so, you know from a car accident, I think right?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And so he's just chillin, but she's living a relatively pretty good life.
Speaker 1: You know, she's got a her family.
Speaker 1: is you know, not doing too badly?
Speaker 1: her dad's a professor.
Speaker 0: The comic really just starts you out with kind of you know, this is her life.
Speaker 0: Everything's all cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she goes and you know, she's hanging out with her friends and her sister.
Speaker 0: Nothing is foreshadowed like.
Speaker 0: there is no hint of anything Interesting.
Speaker 1: The only foreshadowing is the girls in a wheelchair.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: That could foreshadow almost anything, you know, it's it but it does come into play obviously.
Speaker 0: So basically then one night wait by that logic then not being in a wheelchair is also foreshadowing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I guess.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so just one night.
Speaker 1: well, they wouldn't you know, put her in a wheelchair on purpose.
Speaker 1: You know if it wasn't on purpose for a reason someone could just be in a wheelchair for no reason.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you wouldn't do that.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of works of art where someone just happens to be in a wheelchair.
Speaker 1: If you're writing if you're writing a comic happens to have a uterus.
Speaker 1: I mean if you're writing a web comic and the main character is in a wheelchair There's a reason you have done that.
Speaker 1: You don't do that.
Speaker 0: Surely a better reason of trying to include people like that or what if it's what you read the whole comic that was it?
Speaker 1: for a reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it kind of was.
Speaker 1: it kind of was so anyway.
Speaker 1: So, you know.
Speaker 1: one night there she's eating dinner with her family.
Speaker 1: her sister came home from because her sister doesn't live at home.
Speaker 1: She came over and the family's eating dinner together and these people just bust into their house.
Speaker 0: Well, no first they knock on the door and they come in and they're like, hey We're here to see your father and the dad's like, oh hi And he actually doesn't recognize them at all.
Speaker 0: And he's like, what do you want?
Speaker 0: And then they fucking go apeshit with magic and kill everybody.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I guess it spoils volume one.
Speaker 0: That's like spoiling the cowboy.
Speaker 0: bebop is about some people in space who are bounty hunters.
Speaker 1: So basically, all right these people come into the house and they're like give us the goddamn sword.
Speaker 1: They're calling the dad by a different name, right?
Speaker 1: And it's that's it there.
Speaker 0: Give us the goddamn sword What sword don't seriously give us the sword.
Speaker 0: what the fuck you're talking about?
Speaker 0: murder murder.
Speaker 1: What's what's the name that?
Speaker 0: Demetrios to me.
Speaker 1: so they're like, all right, come on Demetrios.
Speaker 1: It's like so this girl is this sitting in a wheelchair is like why the fuck are they calling my dad Demetrios, right?
Speaker 1: That's not his name.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: The violence is immediate and graphic.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah They freaking just rip the family up like they riggin like just boom your heads exploded.
Speaker 1: Boom.
Speaker 1: You're on fire You know over setting the house on fire and they're just having these mundane conversations with each other.
Speaker 0: So why isn't he talking blah blah blah?
Speaker 0: Yeah, three and the dad is just like what the fuck?
Speaker 1: Yeah, obviously it seems like there are these three people with magic powers.
Speaker 1: who have you know?
Speaker 1: They obviously are enemies with some guy named Demetrios who has a sword that they want and they think that this dad is Demetrios and they're the dad is just like what the fuck?
Speaker 1: I don't know what you're talking about.
Speaker 1: What the fuck.
Speaker 1: and So they just use their magic and kill everybody And it's like whoa, what the what the fuck?
Speaker 1: So that is already comes out in nowhere And then he'll just knock on the door and then boom we're killing your family.
Speaker 0: now that could already set up a pretty good comic And this is kind of the last spoiler, but it's not a spoiler.
Speaker 0: This is like it happens right away.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean it's in the title of the comic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, obviously the sword is gonna come into play So long.
Speaker 0: story short she is the only survivor of this massacre and she falls into the basement and there's the fucking sword.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just there right there.
Speaker 1: It's crazy how they that there was.
Speaker 1: like the number one most genius thing in the whole comic was how this like the dad Reacted like not at all to this conspiracy.
Speaker 1: That was apparently true like apparently he was Demetrios right or at least.
Speaker 1: or something is out or something is up because the sword that they were looking for was in his house in his basement right hidden down there, right.
Speaker 1: and So magic.
Speaker 1: people come looking for a sword, you know, and it is there.
Speaker 1: But the dad who you would assume was the one who would the one who knew about it, right?
Speaker 1: Totally didn't give anything away at all until the end and was killed like a lot.
Speaker 1: It's like if I had say a secret robot in the basement.
Speaker 1: the government came looking for it and I was like And I just said to the very end I don't know what you're talking about and they kill and I let them kill me Before I go and get in the robot and defend myself.
Speaker 1: It's like if you have the secret robot you go get it and defend yourself.
Speaker 0: Maybe there's something else up that we don't know about it.
Speaker 0: Maybe we have to read the comic to see why the sword was actually there and what this whole story is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know basically it goes from there for three more volumes and you know, I think it was it's really original.
Speaker 1: I mean, I never read any story that you know went like that before, you know, usually if there's some sort of conspiracy, right?
Speaker 1: It's like it's uncovered and there's a hint about it and then it's revealed and then you know Whoever it was revealed comes out and spills the beans and that's the typical, you know Pathway, right or it's an Indiana Jones kind of thing where nobody knows.
Speaker 1: they can you know the secrets but they slowly discover them.
Speaker 1: The
Speaker 0: only inter other thing I'll say and otherwise I mean We'll kind of end the review and get into the spoilers because I got some things to say about this comic having read it all is that the government pretty much does what you'd expect and that was surprising kind of like Uh Bocorano the government did exactly what you expect.
Speaker 0: There's a fucking robot.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: Let's go.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not just the government right?
Speaker 1: It's like all kinds of characters are acting in you know in Intelligently based on the information that they have and the experience they've had right?
Speaker 1: It's like they try something.
Speaker 1: It didn't work.
Speaker 1: So they're not gonna try that again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know and or I know this.
Speaker 1: therefore I'm gonna be smart and do this.
Speaker 1: Nobody does anything sort of stupider for no reason.
Speaker 1: they they I mean, you know, everyone sort of acts according to their motivations their goals and Intelligence.
Speaker 1: nobody goes like crazy and does something stupid that they shouldn't have done.
Speaker 1: that causes unnecessary Conflict, you know the conflict the only conflicts are the real conflicts that matter.
Speaker 0: So other aspects the arts, okay It's kind of generic.
Speaker 0: The dialogue is okay.
Speaker 0: It's not gray.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the colors are really good, but the the art itself did not really blow me away.
Speaker 0: Literally one of those stories where the story itself kind of like Locke Lammer.
Speaker 0: Locke Lammer was not written particularly Well, it didn't have like it didn't have much going for it Other than the fact that the story it told was itself interesting and engaging and was a hell of a ride.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm that the story matters more than the way the story is told.
Speaker 0: like this could have been a movie and in fact reading it It probably it probably be a good movie like this.
Speaker 0: In fact the panel I showed just a Luke Burge You know, I was hanging out with him Brian Park today and when he was like, yeah This art really does nothing to me for me and we discussed it and it really it Looks like storyboards to a movie.
Speaker 0: It might as well have been a comic or a novel or a movie.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: I wonder if it's been optioned.
Speaker 1: It doesn't say anything on Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: I guess the point I'm making is that you know sometimes there's a comic that uses the medium of Comic to do something interesting or a movie that couldn't be told in a comic.
Speaker 0: or like the Prince of Nothing books You could make them a movie but they wouldn't be the same thing Because you couldn't tell the same story in the different medium.
Speaker 0: this story stands independent of the medium.
Speaker 0: It's the kind of story like surrogates where I would say.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just make the fucking movie.
Speaker 0: It'll be fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, it's probably you know, I mean a lot of people these days are making comics You know first in hopes of it becoming a movie right as opposed to try because it's a better.
Speaker 1: It's a better luck than just sending scripts to producers
Speaker 0: But at the same time having
Speaker 1: them feel like tossed in the trash in
Speaker 0: a way that is hurting Comics because if you make a comic with that in mind You're really just storyboarding your movie and as a result, you might not be doing more artistic things You could be doing with the medium of a comic.
Speaker 1: well yeah, but I mean the thing is anyone who could be doing artistic things within the comic medium are already doing them right.
Speaker 1: and This you know because this this being made doesn't block something else better being made.
Speaker 0: The only time we can actually complain is if someone who like if Jeff Lemire did a totally generic Comic that he wanted to make a movie.
Speaker 1: He's doing Superboy.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna buy the first 75 cents.
Speaker 0: Jeff Lemire is like we said way back.
Speaker 0: He was a rising star.
Speaker 0: And yeah, he's a rising star.
Speaker 1: We'll see if it's any good.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so this is totally worth reading.
Speaker 0: It's like a BB plus comic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can get it from like the library or if you can buy like some used borrow it from someone.
Speaker 1: It's for trades, but I think two months from now or like in November They're gonna come out with like this complete edition like one hardcover.
Speaker 1: That is the whole thing in it.
Speaker 1: So, I don't know which one's gonna be cheaper.
Speaker 1: Maybe the hardcover will mean you can get the four trades at a discount, you know Look, just try to save money when you buy it, you know get the four trades get the hardcover.
Speaker 1: Getting all the issues is probably gonna be a pain in the ass.
Speaker 1: It's 24 individual issues.
Speaker 1: So, you know, that's that's not an easy easy purchase especially since they came out over the course of two years.
Speaker 1: issue one was in April 08 and The last issue was in July 2010.
Speaker 1: So it's not gonna.
Speaker 1: it's not gonna be easy to get every issue if you weren't buying them all along.
Speaker 0: So very briefly before we get on to the spoilers, we forgot to do the meta moment.
Speaker 0: Oh shit I only have two things I want to talk about because this is a Wednesday night show.
Speaker 0: on October 8th 9th and 10th is the New York comic-con New York anime festival in New York City.
Speaker 0: We'll be doing a panel on Friday night and it's gonna be awesome.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be a big mega con the first double con like this ever.
Speaker 0: Yep It'll be something to see the weekend before that on Saturday afternoon at Kinokuniya in New York City in Manhattan.
Speaker 1: But we definitely definitely doing.
Speaker 0: we are doing an event there.
Speaker 0: I cannot say more yet.
Speaker 0: We will be there doing a half-hour kind of mini panel event and we'll be able to hang out answer questions.
Speaker 0: So if you're a fan and you want to actually see us talk to us hang out say hi I'm Saturday October 2nd at Kinokuniya is a much better chance of seeing us in a position where we are able to talk to you.
Speaker 0: Then the New York comic-con New York anime festival will be.
Speaker 1: we'll also be at 10 10 10 the burning wheel con Over the same weekend as the double mega con.
Speaker 1: but who knows which times will be at which kind of which times?
Speaker 1: the other who knows?
Speaker 1: and the book club selection is Ray Bradbury's golden apples of the Sun.
Speaker 0: next Thursday or so we will be doing that.
Speaker 1: I'm almost done.
Speaker 1: I got like the two or three more stories to read.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think you've already read then the story That is my favorite far and away.
Speaker 1: Is it the one about television?
Speaker 0: That's a good story.
Speaker 0: No, mine's the one about the Emperor and the flying machine.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's okay.
Speaker 0: one just for the line at the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a good one.
Speaker 0: The line at the end sells that story because that that story I think has the most practical Application to modern day of any of the stories.
Speaker 1: Yeah, definitely.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so Spoilers if you have not read the sword.
Speaker 0: do not fucking listen any further I'm.
Speaker 0: or if you never plan on reading the sword No, no You should read the sword because what we're gonna do is tell you all the events.
Speaker 0: if you know what's going to happen.
Speaker 0: There is little artistry in the way it is told.
Speaker 0: toward the end.
Speaker 0: You will not.
Speaker 0: you will lose much of the enjoyment of reading.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even though I've already described the first issue to you It's still really, you know, that's not.
Speaker 1: I sort of knew what the first issue was about a little bit before I read it.
Speaker 1: Not much, but it'll still be good.
Speaker 1: It's not spoilable.
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: But the rest of the comic is Pretty just you know, it's just the story.
Speaker 1: So if I tell you the story, it's not spoiling it as in oh Ruined a surprise.
Speaker 1: It's spoiling it as in it's completely redundant with the comic.
Speaker 0: You know I'm giving you the pretty much the exact same experience moments later where a fact about the way the sword works is revealed which has Ramifications.
Speaker 0: and now you wonder well, how are those ramifications gonna make this especially when you think back to like the family on the boat?
Speaker 0: Oh my god, and the answer to that is poorly very poorly.
Speaker 0: So spoilers from this point forward.
Speaker 0: I was kind of surprised by the fact that the story was actually simpler than I expected.
Speaker 1: I find this lately Yeah, I mean cuz it starts off with a conspiracy.
Speaker 1: That's sort of strange.
Speaker 1: So you you think it's gonna get twisted entangled and become this dark spiral like those TV shows You know where they just keep throwing mystery after mystery at you.
Speaker 1: But really they just come out and explain it like nope.
Speaker 1: Here it is.
Speaker 1: And even though it's really fantastic It's you know, it's got lots of fantasy involved in magic and craziness.
Speaker 1: It's not complicated and then they just go about resolving it in a relatively straightforward procedural way.
Speaker 0: But I think it's funny how usually even though there's also suspense stuff has a twist or something you didn't expect even if it isn't A twist or something you didn't figure out.
Speaker 0: and that's what I expect from media because that's what's popular now.
Speaker 0: And it used to be.
Speaker 0: that was kind of like the crazy thing to do.
Speaker 0: now It's almost like the crazy thing to do is to tell a straightforward story where all the craziness is not what happens.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: I assumed from the beginning that the dad was not Demetrios.
Speaker 0: really my assumption was he was like Demetrios his great-grandson.
Speaker 0: That's why he looked so much like him and or like son or something and the real Demetrios was hanging out somewhere.
Speaker 0: The sword was buried in the basement and he really didn't know.
Speaker 1: Okay, that's that's reasonable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I assumed that right up till the end and I assumed further later that Justin Are you assume that until up until the end up until when Justin revealed I was like, oh, he's Demetrios.
Speaker 0: And then he was like no, I'm face whatever I was like, oh really because I assumed he was alive too because the falling into the fire consumed by his own that was bullshit.
Speaker 0: Obviously he was still alive.
Speaker 1: Actually.
Speaker 1: That's the one thing that totally got me right.
Speaker 1: was the that you know The I believe the lie all along that the kid was in the clay in Demetrios his class.
Speaker 0: I believe that too, but I did not believe that the fire lord was dead.
Speaker 1: Oh See I totally believe that they were dead because you saw them get chopped up with this.
Speaker 0: No, you saw him got stabbed not deadly and then he fell into a pit and caught on fire.
Speaker 1: No, okay.
Speaker 1: You're thinking a little bit too hard about.
Speaker 0: I thought about it very literally Yeah, but also along those lines the fact that it was meta foreshadowed only but not actually foreshadowed.
Speaker 0: I mean look the name of each book is who dies in that book.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: and fire book book one Duh, but then alright, I'm gonna go the reverse of that because I expected all these more complicated things.
Speaker 0: that didn't happen.
Speaker 1: Yep, now but pretty much that's it.
Speaker 1: You know in the fire book the fire guy dies in the water book the water guy dies earth air, you know It's pretty much.
Speaker 1: it is four people.
Speaker 1: They die one per book.
Speaker 1: one, two, three four.
Speaker 0: so game over There are only two moments of violence that I was actually taken aback by like I.
Speaker 1: oh really it took you aback We're not taking it back.
Speaker 0: Like I mean, I've seen each of the killer and didn't blink in fact laughed handily That's true, but there were two moments.
Speaker 1: I was like, oh ah Usually usually I went oh and ah when limbs were just sliced off by the sword that didn't get me so much.
Speaker 0: What got me was when she ripped her fucking uterus out?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that really got me.
Speaker 0: So I was like, did she rip her stomach out?
Speaker 0: Oh, oh Oh.
Speaker 0: And then when the jog got popped off Oh, yeah, right because those two moments came back to me when I realized let go of the sword and all your injuries come back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz the sword has healing powers as well as killing powers.
Speaker 1: But at the very end of the book very close to the end They sort of come out and they're like, yeah the healing powers of the sword sort of get undone if you You know, let go of the sword Touching it over and over and over again To reheal and I sort of felt like that was sort of tacked on at the end a little bit.
Speaker 1: it didn't feel like that.
Speaker 1: that was foreshadowed a whole bunch, but Whether it was tacked on or not It actually fit really well because all throughout the book like she had been stabbing and healing people like that guy in the boat Right.
Speaker 1: He gave her the free ride.
Speaker 1: People are dead all those people and it's like oh shit even better.
Speaker 1: And it also gives them a reason for her to die at the end, you know as opposed to just you know.
Speaker 1: Have it without having to answer the question of what the fuck is she gonna do for the rest of her life with the sword?
Speaker 0: Now at the same time what got me was that the moment that's revealed when she's like my bullet wound came back I was like, oh shit.
Speaker 0: So at the end she's gonna have to go back to being a paraplegic again.
Speaker 0: I wonder how they're gonna.
Speaker 0: and then I stopped.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh wait She had her fucking jaw punched off and all her arms caught.
Speaker 0: Oh The other violent moment when she had to rip the flesh off of her own body multiple times to reheal properly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that that was rough real rough.
Speaker 0: Of course notice how rapidly she turned into a consummate badass.
Speaker 1: That's what's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: if you know, especially if you've you know, you probably imagine what it feels like, you know I mean someone punches your jaw off, right?
Speaker 1: You didn't do that on purpose and then touch a sword and it heals right?
Speaker 1: Imagine what that feels like.
Speaker 1: So if you felt that it's like just cutting some flesh off your leg and doing it is not it's like whatever.
Speaker 0: Here's the roller coaster situation was totally foreshadowed in one way or the other.
Speaker 0: How come?
Speaker 0: he never took a bullet and survived all that crazy bullshit.
Speaker 0: She was doing at the end.
Speaker 1: I I just wasn't thinking about it that hard, you know, I just sort of went along with it.
Speaker 0: I was kind of thinking he was Dimitrios.
Speaker 1: No, I mean, it's like, you know, I like.
Speaker 1: there were certain things that like I was obviously questioning all the time.
Speaker 1: But that one thing totally fooled me up until the end.
Speaker 0: What was hacked on is the whole how come your hair's different color?
Speaker 0: How come your hair is not impervious to damage like everything else and one they made him bald when he caught on fire.
Speaker 0: So that was okay.
Speaker 0: and she was like, oh, yeah dead skin doesn't count.
Speaker 0: Yeah, duh Whatever death note handled things like that a lot better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I definitely think so.
Speaker 1: The other thing is that it was cool how as the progression of fire water earth air the bad guys were smarter each time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: It's like the fire guy was just you know, the typical angry moron, you know the water guy.
Speaker 1: He was sort of worried a whole bunch, but he got his.
Speaker 1: the earth guy was he was the drug dealer in Mexico, right?
Speaker 1: He he actually has the freakin brains, you know, he didn't have big enough brains even when he turned into a giant Which is totally freakin awesome, but you know, his problem was overconfidence.
Speaker 0: It was not like tricked at the end.
Speaker 0: She was too smart and then suddenly got stupid.
Speaker 1: that that's true.
Speaker 1: But she was way smart, you know when she start hurt her whole thing up until her demise.
Speaker 1: She was doing way smart awesome stuff.
Speaker 0: earth guy gets points for making a giant robot out of mud And then trying to kill with that.
Speaker 1: that's that's a genius idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he just you know, if he wasn't so confident he would he would have pulled it off, too.
Speaker 1: But yeah, the the air girl was just.
Speaker 1: she was so smart pretending to be the good guy making the girl out to be the bad Guy, but then it was.
Speaker 1: I liked it because it was a really cool redemption when the military guy was like, alright I know what's up.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was like fuck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, military guy who knows what's up?
Speaker 1: is it yours like?
Speaker 0: I hope you don't kick me in the balls.
Speaker 1: Have you ever seen?
Speaker 1: I don't know the exact title of the movie.
Speaker 1: it might be in invaders from Mars or something where you could.
Speaker 1: it's like the guy the kids in the school nurse and Like they're the only people who aren't fucked up.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, and they go to the military.
Speaker 0: They're like, oh and the military is like, alright Well help you.
Speaker 1: anyone who has a band-aid with a little mark on the back of their neck is been infected by the aliens Right and everyone else is totally chill and there's almost no one left.
Speaker 1: He's totally chill.
Speaker 1: and they go to the military and like let us see the back of your neck.
Speaker 1: and he's like, okay And he wasn't he was chill.
Speaker 1: so they were like listen this aliens.
Speaker 0: Oh my gosh, and the military was like really Did that - they're like the kids are like there's fucking giant robot blah and this thing.
Speaker 0: and then the military guys like show me.
Speaker 0: And then they show him and he's like, oh that's becoming a trend.
Speaker 1: that the military is smart and gets involved.
Speaker 1: We're gonna need to go back to the military is stupid again.
Speaker 0: I think that the real trend is that you can no longer get away in media with having They're not like.
Speaker 0: Emily and I watched the burbs again recently a movie I hadn't seen in a long time and it's still a funny.
Speaker 1: just go check out the dude's basement.
Speaker 0: But what doesn't win is they don't just call the police when they find the goddamn femur.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right Yeah, just call the police.
Speaker 0: It's a femur exactly.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and movies can't get away.
Speaker 1: That's a comedy.
Speaker 1: It's not a. you know, this is not a comedy.
Speaker 1: So you're not.
Speaker 0: you're not questioning about the police in the burbs because it's supposed to be the fact that the clo packs go and call The police themselves.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: But you know in it's something that's procedural or suspenseful with danger, right?
Speaker 1: You need a reason to not call the police like look at monster right and monster.
Speaker 1: Why doesn't he call the police?
Speaker 1: cuz he'll go to jail.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like they give you a reason not to just go for some obvious answer.
Speaker 1: They make it so that the daring and suspenseful and brave option of incredible danger and action is Also, you know the only way for the good guys to make it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sometimes it's the contrived moral dilemma.
Speaker 0: I mean try gun every episode.
Speaker 0: the answer is you could just shoot him.
Speaker 1: Yeah No, you know.
Speaker 1: but that they always make some sort of reason not to do the obvious things so that you know.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, you know crawling through the vents and being a total badass and stealing guns or whatever is not the best idea.
Speaker 0: So my only real complaint about the comic is the n1.
Speaker 0: as an aside I really like the fact that their names are all the names of the cities They took over from ancient Manoa and Crete.
Speaker 0: That was awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like setup I also like how.
Speaker 1: you know, they had a dad but he never came into it.
Speaker 0: They kept praying to God and that didn't.
Speaker 1: one one of them did but the other one they were bring to their dad.
Speaker 1: But some of them didn't believe in their own dad anymore, but I like how that didn't help at all.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: it's so weird though.
Speaker 1: Cuz like if I had magic powers, right?
Speaker 1: And I know I had them and no one does.
Speaker 1: and I grew up with no dad and my mom was like Yeah, some magic dude and disseminated me with magic.
Speaker 1: I'd be like, well, it might not be God But there was definitely some magic insemination.
Speaker 1: That was my dad.
Speaker 1: So whatever it is You know, I would thank it.
Speaker 1: I might not pray to it or worship it, but I would thank it and seek it out You know, yeah, cuz it's definitely real as is evidenced by my ability to set things on fire.
Speaker 0: But on the meta level the only thing that really bothered me was that Characters kept fucking having to explain everything that they knew.
Speaker 0: the characters They met along the way and they're just words and words and words.
Speaker 0: I just had to skip.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I kept every time.
Speaker 0: it wasn't just that it was throughout the entire comic after the first volume.
Speaker 0: I didn't read all the words.
Speaker 0: I would just be like, alright They're talking about this and I would literally skip all the word bubbles until I got to word bubbles that talked about something.
Speaker 1: Well, you're definitely, you know, none of them miss anything is disgusting it with you.
Speaker 1: There's nothing you missed right?
Speaker 0: Yeah Nothing happened at all.
Speaker 1: I definitely think people need to learn the lesson of if you have a story right and a character is explaining something to another character That's already the golden.
Speaker 0: Yes, it would literally have a sentence saying so and so like the story.
Speaker 0: Yeah so it's a part about blah.
Speaker 1: I think part of the reason for that is because we're reading the trades and They've made it, you know, it's a comic.
Speaker 0: So if someone buys issue like 17 if they don't know what's up That's the excuse they use in TV shows to make them non-serial to have recap episodes all the time.
Speaker 0: Mmm I don't get a recap.
Speaker 1: episodes are just filler.
Speaker 1: but you know having some sort of explanation in the individual episode.
Speaker 1: But also just honestly because I mean, I'm not gonna say that I agree that that I disagree.
Speaker 1: I mean having too much of that recap is sort of annoying and stupid.
Speaker 0: Wasn't just the recap?
Speaker 1: you're selling a comic.
Speaker 1: that's an individual issue.
Speaker 1: I don't care what numbers on it.
Speaker 1: It needs to stand alone as a work and if it's not comprehensible on its own, you shouldn't make these spider-man 121.
Speaker 1: Yes, you shouldn't do that.
Speaker 0: But a lot of the dialogue between the characters was really really boring and I didn't care and I just like it wasn't necessary.
Speaker 0: they're snarking at each other in this really contrived force way like the dialogue was so expository and Non-natural that it really and I I skipped word bubbles any time It didn't like directly drive the story forward and I didn't miss anything.
Speaker 1: Nope No, that's that's what happens in a comic like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but on the story level and this isn't a complaint this is just something that I In her situation even with all of her circumstances would not have acted the way she acted.
Speaker 0: I would not have gone on murderous rampage.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, you know, I Wouldn't gone on a murderous rampage.
Speaker 0: She made the point to the earth guy of you know, you all.
Speaker 0: you say you're a god But you can only create what men can see.
Speaker 0: you've never created anything on your own.
Speaker 0: I feel like she should have broken the cycle of Dimitrios and gone to all of them and subjugated them and made a deal and They all come out openly to the world and she uses the sword to keep them in line.
Speaker 0: But yet they could use their powers for the better of everybody which is what they all kind of wanted to do all along.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean one guy was dealing drugs.
Speaker 1: They weren't they didn't.
Speaker 1: Everybody convinced them.
Speaker 0: I mean Dimitrios once you see like what he was actually doing and he He was kind of a dick and wasn't really dealing with the situation that.
Speaker 1: well Well, cuz he just wanted to live and do his own thing and he just didn't want the whole world to end.
Speaker 0: at the same Time he didn't know he wasn't trying to force them to be human which was bullshit But at the same time went without him.
Speaker 0: there were being gods and there were also independently of being gods being dicks And I feel like he could have made them into gods that weren't dicks But instead he was just having sex with one of them and kind of being a dick himself and trying to force them to be Something they could never be.
Speaker 1: He didn't want to kill anybody right, you know, especially not a god But you know plus like they could have come in useful like let's say if there's a meteor coming to earth or something?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were basically the Fantastic Four.
Speaker 0: So instead of you know, you know dealing with mother the evil Fantastic Four They could have been I guess I don't.
Speaker 0: she was presented with an opportunity of transhumanism and her choices were Become a transhuman and let's go with this or give up the sword and die in the end after killing all the gods.
Speaker 1: I Don't know.
Speaker 0: I think that and I see why she did what she did but I in her situation would have acted very differently.
Speaker 1: I think part of the thing was she went to the government right and The government, you know basically tried to dick her over and that you know.
Speaker 1: It's like I would have done the same thing.
Speaker 1: But as soon as they dicked me over I also would have been like Now what the fuck am I gonna do?
Speaker 0: I would have sought out the gods and talked to them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I also would have tried to like, you know She had a big problem towards the end of the story with the media not knowing anything.
Speaker 1: I would have gone to the media, you know on my own to make sure that the true story was out from the get-go.
Speaker 1: You know make sure that people know what's going on.
Speaker 1: Don't do this like all secret like even if it means that the bad guys know where you are.
Speaker 1: Who cares?
Speaker 1: They're running from you not the other.
Speaker 1: so it's okay if they know where you are.
Speaker 1: Right because she obviously if she was able to catch up to them every time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess she was just.
Speaker 0: She is a character became Ultraviolet and full of rage and permanent anger pretty rapidly, but that's why her end was also appropriate, right?
Speaker 1: It's like she became like this horrible monster of murder to get rid of these people and then or gods and then she was gone.
Speaker 1: You know, she didn't stick around.
Speaker 0: I feel like I would even if I had killed all the gods.
Speaker 0: I would have kept the sword and become a god myself rather than go through what she went through at the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well the thing may but then eventually it's not gonna work anymore, you know, why not?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I guess you know because look at Demetrius also happen to him.
Speaker 1: Demetrius kept the sword and it didn't.
Speaker 0: yeah Because he hit it and he was.
Speaker 0: he could have dealt out with it better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe But eventually he just you know after so many years he didn't want to and you know You don't want you anymore kill yourself with it.
Speaker 0: Don't just throw it away and then you know go through that.
Speaker 0: That last shot of her jaw falling off again was.
Speaker 0: was that that really hit home.
Speaker 1: It's I think that's the point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, I'm glad they did not show the other parts though.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right, do you have anything else to say about this ward?
Speaker 0: I enjoyed it.
Speaker 0: it was solid.
Speaker 0: B I think I said everything I have to say about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's that's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: Stay tuned next time for more geek nights.
Speaker 0: Same bad time same bad place.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening.
Speaker 0: music can't leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.