Speaker 0: It's Monday August 23rd on rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight tech zealotry and the canoe heard Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So Scott would you consider yourself a computer expert?
Speaker 1: I am indeed a computer expert perhaps in the 99th percentile.
Speaker 0: I am the world.
Speaker 0: I would tend to agree with that too.
Speaker 0: to a point.
Speaker 0: I mean we're tech professionals in New York.
Speaker 0: so Scott When you connect to a wireless network, and it doesn't work Why is your first instinct to tell me my wireless network that I am connected to just fine is broken?
Speaker 1: Because I pushed all the buttons that would normally repair a wireless network, and it didn't wait.
Speaker 0: so you use the windows.
Speaker 0: I don't know what I'm doing.
Speaker 0: fix it fix it fix it fix it fix it button.
Speaker 1: But I also I also restarted the entire computer and did that work?
Speaker 0: no so then what fixed it?
Speaker 1: Flicking the switch on the side of the laptop that turns the radios actually off for reals Looking it again.
Speaker 0: so some sort of problem with your laptop.
Speaker 0: Not a problem with my perfectly fine Wireless network because I'm an IT problem did not happen at my house with the exact same laptop.
Speaker 1: therefore the problem was in your router.
Speaker 0: Yes, my router somehow required you to reset the radio on your wireless car.
Speaker 1: that is correct.
Speaker 1: It was an evil router with evil waves Through the air.
Speaker 1: so I did evil.
Speaker 0: all that aside Promised At least in the forum that tonight at the metabit we would actually announce the musical act for the penny arcade expo Friday night Late show.
Speaker 1: why are you saying this now?
Speaker 1: It's not the medevit because people might be wondering.
Speaker 0: I'm not actually going to announce it.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying that I'm going to announce it.
Speaker 0: It was that it was a meta meta bit Metabits going.
Speaker 1: the reason we have the meta moment is we don't want meta, so it's can't.
Speaker 0: no meta We don't want.
Speaker 0: I agree a hundred percent, but meta meta.
Speaker 1: We don't want any amount of meta.
Speaker 1: Minimize all metas no matter how many metas there are.
Speaker 1: so can it.
Speaker 0: but meta meta is very different.
Speaker 1: No, it is not is exactly the same.
Speaker 1: save it for the meta moment.
Speaker 0: Not now I am.
Speaker 0: I am saving the meta for the meta moment.
Speaker 1: also the meta meta.
Speaker 1: Thou shalt save us to all metas despite the exponent for the meta moment.
Speaker 0: All right, so I guess we should talk about the news.
Speaker 0: since I can't talk about my meta stuff I don't have any opening bits whatsoever.
Speaker 1: It's raining.
Speaker 1: all right Woman, it's raining.
Speaker 0: She got some woman really woman.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: It's just raining I Guess I guess Poseidon.
Speaker 0: so you can talk about the Heliums.
Speaker 1: I'll talk about the Helium.
Speaker 1: So apparently there's this guy who is and he says he's an expert on helium.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure he is an expert on helium, but he is saying I don't feel like editing my voice.
Speaker 1: He's actually a Nobel Prize winning physicist, so he's smart.
Speaker 1: I'll spare you all.
Speaker 0: I was gonna just like edit this and make us sound really high-pitched And that idea Felt really stupid right away, so I didn't do it.
Speaker 1: That's good because usually you think those ideas are not stupid.
Speaker 1: your judgment is is getting clear.
Speaker 1: Anyways, he is a very smart person.
Speaker 1: He says you're running out of helium and the problem is that a we need helium for many things.
Speaker 1: for example We need it for MRI machines.
Speaker 1: Yep, and we need it for rockets.
Speaker 0: We need it for balloons and funny voices.
Speaker 1: Yes, we need it for many things.
Speaker 1: that is very needed.
Speaker 0: But so where do we get helium from?
Speaker 0: Scott?
Speaker 1: we get helium from rocks under the ground.
Speaker 1: It's apparently only in a certain geological situation.
Speaker 1: We're like this salt and a certain kind of rock.
Speaker 1: you can extract helium from it But it kind of sucks.
Speaker 0: now the worst part is I will admit straight up until I saw this article I'd never even considered where helium came from because it's in the grocery store.
Speaker 0: We waste it like crazy, so I just never thought that it was trouble to get helium.
Speaker 0: Otherwise why would it just be wasted?
Speaker 1: all the other thing is with helium right as soon as you let go of it Not only does it go in the air, but you can't really get it out of the air easily.
Speaker 1: Why cuz it goes up in fact not above everything.
Speaker 0: It does not just go up.
Speaker 0: I read that law goes into space go into space and are gone.
Speaker 0: Yep I guess we could mine some gas giant for its helium.
Speaker 1: right, but anyway.
Speaker 1: So you know when we use helium is gone That's it and we get it out of the rocks and once it's out of the rocks It's gone, and the problem is is that the United States had this gigantic helium reserve.
Speaker 1: ah very clever Because we have strategic reserves of all kinds of crazy elements.
Speaker 0: yep I mean we have the oil reserve partly because to date there is no electric fighter jet.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: So we have this strategic reserve of various elements and one of the elements he has cheated reserve of his helium.
Speaker 1: But there was an order.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure if it was a law or something But it basically they have to sell off the helium reserve all of it by a certain date.
Speaker 1: So they're selling helium like crazy.
Speaker 1: so the price is a wicked low.
Speaker 1: But when that runs out there isn't gonna be a lot of helium and like a helium balloon for your birthday party is probably like $100.
Speaker 0: so rim seems really short-sighted.
Speaker 1: Well, it does if it's true, but you brought up the fact that well the people trading the commodities markets They know all this information, so how come the commodities the helium futures aren't crazy way high now?
Speaker 0: This is why I'm dubious because at the same time reading all the physics and the science and the mining behind it I don't doubt that it's gonna be very difficult to this guy's a Nobel Prize-winning physicist.
Speaker 1: this sounds right to me.
Speaker 0: I also kind of disagree with Selling off a strategic reserve or something like that because I feel like I think it's too late on that.
Speaker 1: It's already been done.
Speaker 0: Well we could undo that.
Speaker 0: unless we could hold it all.
Speaker 1: stop and keep what we haven't sold.
Speaker 0: I think we should and then maybe start buying up more or at least keep what we've got left.
Speaker 1: Yeah, about 80% of the world's reserves are in the u.s.. Southwest the u.s.. National helium reserve located in amarillo, Texas.
Speaker 0: Why don't we just go over there with a drill?
Speaker 1: a recently passed law has ruled the reserve must be sold off by 2015 Regardless of market price.
Speaker 0: that seems like a terrible law.
Speaker 1: who made that law and what were they thinking now?
Speaker 0: Maybe it costs so much.
Speaker 1: Maybe it was some reserve.
Speaker 1: Maybe it was companies that needed helium to be cheap like people making MRIs That lobbied for that law.
Speaker 0: Maybe it was just pork to cut down on the spending there and to sell it off and bolster the budget with the pittance that We're gonna get from it.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I I don't like the.
Speaker 0: without respect to the market.
Speaker 0: a better law would have been hire a bunch of experts and Their job is to make the most money off of the helium reserve over the next 40 years.
Speaker 1: But you could possibly make even more money if you didn't pay the experts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same time maybe the experts gonna do better than the market price of a quantity where you own all of it If I own all of it, and I say I'm gonna sell all of it kids.
Speaker 1: It's a beer situation.
Speaker 1: It might see.
Speaker 1: two beers is smart.
Speaker 1: They keep all the fucking diamonds.
Speaker 1: if they just opened up the vault and let the diamonds out It would be diamonds like a dollar.
Speaker 1: But yes, but because they hold on to the diamonds They make such mad bank.
Speaker 1: If you got a big stock of something like helium and you're a government that is in debt You shouldn't be just opening the fucking vault.
Speaker 0: You should be selling that for a high price like the beers unless you know that the vault is not as valuable as everyone else.
Speaker 0: Is full of water or you have some other or dirt like maybe for example.
Speaker 0: We don't know.
Speaker 0: but helium is what attracts.
Speaker 0: I don't know earthquakes or aliens or Phalons, yeah, my dad's we don't know you and your bathroom.
Speaker 1: It is good.
Speaker 0: That is a really good word.
Speaker 0: It's perfectly.
Speaker 1: listen We have plenty of bath.
Speaker 1: My dad's in the bath.
Speaker 1: My dad reserved.
Speaker 1: I think we do the clue that the price is very low.
Speaker 1: We're good.
Speaker 0: So this is now to qualify this one.
Speaker 0: I do not speak on behalf of anyone other than myself - while I work in the equities markets, I do not work in options or futures or Commodities or anything like that.
Speaker 0: I have no expertise there but in general I would assume that if this were terribly solid research that People would be investing in this.
Speaker 1: they would buy the helium, but they would buy in long.
Speaker 1: you wouldn't want to buy a short future.
Speaker 1: They would buy the long futures like 30-year futures, right?
Speaker 1: You know, which is?
Speaker 1: I buy helium now, but you give me the helium in 30 years.
Speaker 0: There's also the possibility of buying real commodities of buying the helium or buying the helium.
Speaker 0: The problem with buying the helium is I know I'm well aware of all the problems But the one trouble with buying just futures and commodities and all that is that you know What if the time when we run out of helium is the time when Mad Max happens?
Speaker 1: It says here 25 to 30 years.
Speaker 1: actually remember how it always asked the one question about commodities Like if you buy hogsheads, do you actually get the hogshead?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I found the answer you did.
Speaker 0: What's the answer?
Speaker 1: It's depending on what you buy.
Speaker 1: There's like a time limit and If you don't do certain things by the time limit you basically you have to accept shipment somehow Like someone's gonna try to ship them to you and you have to like get to deal with it.
Speaker 0: You buy and sell a stock.
Speaker 0: You've got three days to clear and to actually give each other the stock.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like if you if you don't like, you know resell your commodity or something like that You're actually going to take shipment of wheat or whatever the fuck it is you bought.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well imagine the thing is these commodities.
Speaker 1: guys Basically, they have to do everything that possibly can to avoid that.
Speaker 1: So oftentimes when a whole bunch of people are gonna take shipment real soon They'll just fucking sell it off at like some low price cuz they got.
Speaker 1: no they don't have warehouses They don't have.
Speaker 1: what are they gonna do with some fucking barrels of oil?
Speaker 1: They like shit get the hell out of here.
Speaker 1: You know sometimes you see the price is moving because of dates on people and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: But regardless, I don't know.
Speaker 0: This is a broader issue.
Speaker 0: I don't know if we really want to get into the whole idea of Technological strategic reserves or the fact that every resource on the earth until we can mine space is finite.
Speaker 1: Carbon is is.
Speaker 1: I think we're okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we can get carbon pretty easy if we need it.
Speaker 1: I don't think we're worried about nitrogen either.
Speaker 0: I'm just thinking but it does take energy to compress nitrogen and do stuff with it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the nitrogen it's so easy and cheap compared to for now because we have you know, basically free.
Speaker 1: I don't think we have a shortage of photons either any time in the near future.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're not that good at harvesting them though.
Speaker 1: No, but I get harvesting there is dead.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's definitely really good harvesting.
Speaker 0: no shortage of your mom.
Speaker 0: So in something closer to home because silly voices are one thing.
Speaker 0: but bloggers Blogging is the most important thing ever.
Speaker 0: At least that's what bloggers told us.
Speaker 0: But an issue came up story on slashdot.
Speaker 0: I'll skip the details But basically there was this rabble about the fact that due to poorly written laws about business and such It appears that a blogger in Philadelphia who makes approximately five point five dollars a year From ads on her blog gross
Speaker 1: Yig nights forum ad which is just one stupid ad makes more than that.
Speaker 0: so she made five dollars and fifty cents a year gross not net off of her blog because she had some ads and Being a dutiful citizen this person reported it as income, you know other income on the tax form Like if Scott gives me 20 bucks and there's something where I reported This is some income 20 bucks and you just pay taxes on bad
Speaker 1: move.
Speaker 0: So because she reported this Philly in Pennsylvania said oh, wait a minute.
Speaker 0: You have to pay $300 to incorporate to have a license to operate a business.
Speaker 0: So basically what it'd be cheaper to stop carrying the ads and not make the five bucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just turn the ads off and then it's no longer a business, right?
Speaker 0: So How are we in this situation?
Speaker 0: I mean, this is not a situation where someone is running an illicit business.
Speaker 0: this is a situation where someone has a hobby and their hobby happens to generate a Trivial amount of money five bucks that doesn't even buy lunch in Midtown.
Speaker 0: Nope, unless you buy that hot dog from that guy You can buy like five of that guy's hot dogs.
Speaker 1: maybe go at five water bottles, maybe.
Speaker 0: yeah You can buy.
Speaker 0: but no, they're those like two packs of gum.
Speaker 0: It depends on the gum fancy gum.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, well, I mean think about this, right?
Speaker 1: This isn't just a case of Technology getting ahead of you know, the law as is so common, right?
Speaker 1: It's a case of actual society getting ahead of the law, right?
Speaker 1: I mean Back in the day would anybody for example open up a deli just for fun.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna open up a deli.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna try to make money.
Speaker 1: In fact, if I lose money, I don't even give a shit.
Speaker 1: I just like running a deli.
Speaker 1: It's my hobby and in my spare time when I get home from work You know for an hour here and there I'll open up my deli and make sandwiches for fun And I'll just give the sandwiches away for free really now and I'll be maybe a donation jar and I'll get a buck a week.
Speaker 0: Now we're gonna skip all the kind of food safety regulation of that.
Speaker 1: Okay, fine I open up a dry cleaner cuz I just loved cleaning fucking clothes.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: I just clean clothes for fun.
Speaker 1: I don't charge anyone money to do it.
Speaker 1: I just do it cuz I like to at random hours once in a while Yep, but suddenly we're.
Speaker 1: nobody would ever do that.
Speaker 0: Suddenly we're in a world where some people run a blog as they're living.
Speaker 0: Some people run a blog not as they're living but as a business.
Speaker 1: they're incorporated there Different groups of people both engaging in the exact same activity.
Speaker 1: some are doing it as they're living and some are doing it for fun.
Speaker 1: Before like this decade or before like the 90s There was nobody doing things just for fun that other people were doing for work.
Speaker 1: I mean, maybe there are some people like, you know writing a book for fun But they wouldn't make even a penny off of it if they didn't get a publisher.
Speaker 1: But now someone can write a book for fun put it on the internets and make some dollars.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's without actually engaging in real business.
Speaker 0: Here's one.
Speaker 0: Here's one thing that I see brought up a lot.
Speaker 0: So say I write software for open source.
Speaker 0: I mean, maybe that should be considered charity if I'm just writing it for fun.
Speaker 1: I don't know Is it?
Speaker 1: I mean, it's charity usually when you give to a specific group.
Speaker 1: But what if I just give something to the world?
Speaker 1: is that charity like if George Lucas just says, you know Star Wars public domain does he'd get up like a billion dollars tax deduction.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 0: no Yeah, but we're in a world now where there are a lot of people who are creating actual value.
Speaker 0: They're creating tangible real value in the world and they don't expect to make money off of it Or they don't even try to make money off of it.
Speaker 0: But yet because of the secondary problem of the ease of making very small amounts of money.
Speaker 0: I mean, it would literally take me like 20 clicks and I'd have to type like 15 words.
Speaker 0: And I've got Google AdWords on my blog and I make like a dollar.
Speaker 1: It's probably been less than that.
Speaker 0: Should I have to register that as a business?
Speaker 1: Did you have to pay $300 to register that as a business?
Speaker 0: I feel like there's an easy way around this but the only way we'll get there is if maybe all the old people die or Government wise is the fuck up.
Speaker 1: The thing is the government doesn't want to wise up.
Speaker 1: They want to force all these people to pay 300 bucks each Thing.
Speaker 0: that the only reason.
Speaker 0: this is an issue and there are things like this happening all over the country.
Speaker 0: now Some city or some state or some county doesn't have enough money and they find none of them have name one that has enough money.
Speaker 1: Uh Bridgeport, Connecticut, they don't have enough money.
Speaker 0: I think they have enough money.
Speaker 0: What can't they do?
Speaker 1: Anything?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they had a lot of scandals and recent years and things.
Speaker 0: So, all right regardless of all that so Forgot what I was gonna say.
Speaker 1: their place is all over looking for money.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, so states right they want money and they find a law that says, you know Technically women can't cut their hair on a Tuesday.
Speaker 0: So they go around finding all the barbers cutting women's hair on Tuesday.
Speaker 0: It'll take a while to strike that law off the books.
Speaker 0: They're gonna make as much money as they can in the interim.
Speaker 0: So what do you do when you have a legislature or a government that has a vested interest in?
Speaker 0: Enforcing a law that itself puts forth No value to society other than drawing a revenue stream and in fact will harm the thing It's drawing the revenue stream from and the money it's going to get is basically gonna force all these bloggers to not file Do not pay and to not even report the income this woman paid Legitimate income tax on this and the city basically said you know what?
Speaker 0: Because we want you to pay the $300 you're never gonna file again and we're gonna get zero dollars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it's like You know, isn't this a government that's supposed to be representative of the people but really it's adversarial?
Speaker 1: in this situation the people are just trying to go about their business and the government is trying to just come and take money from the people.
Speaker 1: and If you had like a referendum on any of these laws Nobody would agree.
Speaker 1: not as I don't think a single person would say yeah some blog that made $11.
Speaker 1: Not a single intelligent sane person who was literate.
Speaker 0: but at the same time we got referenda legitimate.
Speaker 1: That wasn't an old person.
Speaker 1: let's say $11 blog should have to pay a $300 registration.
Speaker 0: referenda sis are dangerous because a lot of people want very stupid things.
Speaker 1: well, no, but I'm saying is a Referendum on that specific thing, but what like a referendum on cutting hair on Tuesday?
Speaker 1: Not a single person except someone making a joke would vote that you shouldn't be allowed to cut hair.
Speaker 0: What if enough hipsters vote ironically and then it passes anyway?
Speaker 1: pictures don't vote.
Speaker 1: They didn't even do the census worthless.
Speaker 0: so This is the tip of the iceberg.
Speaker 0: What are we gonna do 40 years from now?
Speaker 0: when?
Speaker 0: Technology has gotten to the point to where we won't make it 40 years.
Speaker 1: We're only making it maybe 25 You know what?
Speaker 0: Let's make it two years from now.
Speaker 1: What are they gonna do?
Speaker 0: I don't think we're gonna be.
Speaker 1: fine is basically gonna be just these kinds of problems.
Speaker 0: times 10 Yeah, but what's gonna happen I think is This is part of the reason why I had such trouble setting up e-commerce because every time I go to do something.
Speaker 0: I find three paths in front of me the right way from a personal perspective.
Speaker 0: Don't file anything hide at all.
Speaker 0: It's probably the safest option.
Speaker 0: middle road file like the legitimate stuff like just alright on my taxes.
Speaker 0: I'm we're gonna make this money, but we're not gonna incorporate.
Speaker 0: the real way Incorporate lawyer accountant the real way removes all our profits right now.
Speaker 0: So there's no way I'm gonna do that.
Speaker 0: the the easy way the right way for my personal perspective Sets me up for legal liability if anyone ever catches me and I'm basically breaking the law flag.
Speaker 0: really the middle road.
Speaker 0: do what the law says but get fucked anyway Because the laws are too complex.
Speaker 0: Yep So it sucks.
Speaker 0: Basically, I gotta find someone else to do all this for me who doesn't want money.
Speaker 1: Okay, you just set it up in my name as if it's a business that is entirely run by me.
Speaker 0: You want me to do that?
Speaker 0: You want to take all the liability?
Speaker 1: I already have all the payment accounts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you do so Whatever yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, all that I just I feel like we're gonna hit some sort of crossroads because we've got a society now where a lot of people will generate a Surprising amount but still at the same time a fairly trivial Revenue or income from their hobbies.
Speaker 0: the average hobby that is creative can make money.
Speaker 0: I mean look at all the people in an artist's alley.
Speaker 0: Most of them just lie on that form or don't fill out the tax form.
Speaker 0: People we know didn't pay sales taxes because it's such a pain in the ass and if you try to do it and do it Wrong, you're fucked more than if you just don't do it They should.
Speaker 1: the thing is they government would be much better off if they did it for you But you know what the cost of doing it for you makes it unprofitable for them.
Speaker 0: Wait, wait, wait.
Speaker 0: But what about when we had?
Speaker 0: Announced originally when they said we should let people file online?
Speaker 0: The plan was the government will give you a website.
Speaker 0: You can just do your fucking back there and that's the end.
Speaker 1: and People other countries have it.
Speaker 0: Yes, but there was a huge lobby from people like HR block saying no that would destroy our business.
Speaker 1: It would destroy their business.
Speaker 0: Yes, and as a result, we don't have the ability.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know what the thing is when the government looks at something like that, you know Congress or whoever.
Speaker 1: they say Well, look H&R block.
Speaker 1: is this big company, you know into it with just turbo tax?
Speaker 1: is this big company, right?
Speaker 1: If we make this law those companies go out of business and it will create this much unemployment.
Speaker 1: This is the reason.
Speaker 1: see economists have this strange idea.
Speaker 1: They keep thinking that the the fact you know Everyone always worried that technology would create huge unemployment as computers are placed and it always did in the interim.
Speaker 1: Well, no, the thing is they would always.
Speaker 1: if you ask any economist will say no, that's not true.
Speaker 1: That hasn't panned out historically.
Speaker 1: it hasn't panned out historically because there have been legal blockades preventing it from doing so or Because the incompetence has prevented it from doing so.
Speaker 1: you could if technology was actually used properly and there weren't laws propping up businesses You would see massive unemployment due to companies just disappearing because they're not needed anymore.
Speaker 0: But at the same time I would argue look at what happened during the Industrial Revolution.
Speaker 0: there was mass unemployment and all sorts of social problems that then worked themselves out.
Speaker 0: because the I think it's kind of a corollary to the broken windows fallacy because the broken windows fallacy is the idea that if you break a window You create jobs.
Speaker 0: That's a simple way of putting it because you know Someone's got to pay to replace the glass.
Speaker 0: you make a job for the glass maker and other But at the same time if the window hadn't been broken in the first place all those people could theoretically go do something productive Instead of fixing something broken.
Speaker 0: if technology was used in the right way I think in the end what would happen is all the jobs that were lost will be recreated in Brand new value add to the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is they would all be.
Speaker 1: what kind of job?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think we need.
Speaker 0: the thing is I don't think propping up Bad old archaic businesses is the right way to go about it.
Speaker 1: so in the short term We're gonna create a.
Speaker 0: you're gonna create the massive economic problems and get blamed for it and get you know What that has happened at every major juncture of technology in history?
Speaker 0: So now it's only you know what this is like forest fires.
Speaker 0: Remember there were forest fires every now and then and one day human said you know what let's prevent forest fires.
Speaker 0: And then there is big fucking forest fires because we let it build up too long.
Speaker 1: Instead of having a bunch of little ones we had a few big ones.
Speaker 1: yep Then we couldn't even stop because they were too big.
Speaker 0: but regardless even if there would you know this is a political question.
Speaker 0: This is an ideological question, which should we do Scott?
Speaker 0: I'm going to ask you personally if our options are thus option one Continue to leave the laws in this situation as they are for bloggers and maintain some sort of a feeling.
Speaker 1: You're about to present me with a false dichotomy of course - all right, let's go with the taxes.
Speaker 0: should we have a net loss to society?
Speaker 0: from the ideological standpoint of government services should be free and not tied to the private sector and Force people to force the government not force the government.
Speaker 0: the government should make a site where you can just do your taxes And they'll do it for you because it's a boon to society on the ideological standpoint that if they're gonna force you to do The taxes they shouldn't force you to go through a private company.
Speaker 0: Or do we prop up the private company monopoly on this bullshit and not create that public boon?
Speaker 0: because of a short-term Pragmatic economic solution to the fact that we have more people who need work than we have work to do we should simultaneously Unit for the trigon approach.
Speaker 0: Let's try to do everything in fail.
Speaker 1: No we should simultaneously create the e-trade you know e-file thing you know.
Speaker 1: put those companies out and Find something new for those people to do all right.
Speaker 0: like what?
Speaker 1: Like Maybe rebuild our infrastructure gonna be porn stars.
Speaker 0: that porn stars good and make money.
Speaker 0: But I don't think anyone disagrees that.
Speaker 0: regardless of any other rationale I think there should be some sort of like trivial business license that you can get from the government.
Speaker 0: It should be a federal thing.
Speaker 0: even if you make less than like $5,000 a year from some thing whatever it is you can file something and then that's it like one piece of paper.
Speaker 1: That's as easy as like the easy.
Speaker 1: You know tax form.
Speaker 1: yeah It should be like the 1040 in corporation for hobbies like you put in the name of your business you put in your name and address and your security number and the date Can't write anything off.
Speaker 0: you get no tax benefits whatsoever.
Speaker 0: But and any money you make you just get taxed at your income tax rate based on your tax bracket.
Speaker 1: And that's it.
Speaker 1: That's it, and if you may start making more money in fact the way it works No, here's how it should work.
Speaker 1: you ready for this?
Speaker 1: yeah any money that the business makes The that you're the company that you form.
Speaker 1: you gave a w-4 to yourself And it just counts as your income, and that's it.
Speaker 0: you don't even need to do w-4 You just have to file it as income for you from hobby.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean if you know it could eat with the w-4 it could show that it came from your company like.
Speaker 1: so I don't think you need to take likes But it would take out the appropriate social security and such and such and such.
Speaker 0: yeah Do we want to even involve social security in a guy who has a blog that makes five dollars a year?
Speaker 1: Hey, why not be like two cents?
Speaker 1: They need money.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem.
Speaker 0: the math will get screwed up.
Speaker 0: It'll be like six bucks.
Speaker 1: No, because the computer would do it for you.
Speaker 0: Oh the computer because our government is so good at using computer.
Speaker 1: You just say how much money your hobby made and it would go And it print out the w-4.
Speaker 0: you'd be so things of the day.
Speaker 0: What do you got?
Speaker 1: so this is probably way old, but I just discovered it.
Speaker 1: so screw you anyone who says It's old.
Speaker 0: you've given me shit before for using something old.
Speaker 1: if you know what this is and you've seen it before then You can give me shit all right.
Speaker 0: so prepared shit loaded all right.
Speaker 0: So you know load it into wolf cannons.
Speaker 1: You know one of our favorite websites laugh at rice.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah It's been a while since I've been to laugh at rice.
Speaker 0: is it still going?
Speaker 1: I don't know, but you know I found another site that is actually superior.
Speaker 0: laughing hipsters.
Speaker 1: No, you drive what calm you drive what calm has two hundred and fifteen pages of stupid cars.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: These cars are these stupidest cars imaginable, so it's not just racers I cannot even be.
Speaker 1: no.
Speaker 1: This is just you drive what and you Just you go through some of these and it is.
Speaker 1: it is just ludicrous Ludicrous all over the place.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Again, my little pony car Fucking to me.
Speaker 0: my little pony car is pretty badass.
Speaker 1: too many vans attached to each other.
Speaker 1: It's like a still 80 like fucking Action like McDonald's kids meal toys just glued to all over the car, okay?
Speaker 0: That's kind of creepy.
Speaker 1: There's it's just the craziest most screwed up cars You've ever seen in your whole life one with like a zebra lady painted on the back I mean, I don't even know.
Speaker 0: wait wait wait a zebra lady like a furry like a. I don't know what that is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so just go to this site, and you could be entertained literally for days on end.
Speaker 1: it'll take you to look at all of these ridiculous cars and Yeah, all right.
Speaker 0: So the Empire State Building is the tallest building in New York City.
Speaker 1: however now it is well.
Speaker 0: So there's a lot of argument about the fact that someone plans to build another tower that is not as tall as the Empire State Building, but is Close to it.
Speaker 0: It is like 67 stories 1200 feet tall.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be a little bit shorter than the Empire State Building and it's gonna be nearby it.
Speaker 0: So the guy who owns the Empire State Building was basically like you can't build this.
Speaker 0: it'll ruin the Empire State Building.
Speaker 0: It'll ruin the New York City skyline.
Speaker 0: everybody hates it.
Speaker 0: No one should build this building.
Speaker 0: It should be like a quarter the size what it should be.
Speaker 1: double the size.
Speaker 1: make as big as you can yeah.
Speaker 0: And the guy who's building it.
Speaker 0: and there's this kind of piss fight between these guys in New York.
Speaker 0: luckily The vote is going to be tomorrow and by Wednesday.
Speaker 0: We should know the outcome.
Speaker 1: I get to vote now.
Speaker 1: Hey check this out.
Speaker 1: I say yes to all buildings.
Speaker 0: I do too.
Speaker 0: the thing is this building looks pretty cool and less.
Speaker 1: the building actually looks like a penis.
Speaker 0: It looks pretty cool, but this is why I think the Empire State Building guy sucks one.
Speaker 0: The Empire State Building is only taller than the Chrysler Building because they built that little penis on top of it.
Speaker 1: That's correct.
Speaker 0: It's done, and then on top.
Speaker 0: There's that little penis, and then the penis has like a long penis off of it.
Speaker 0: Yep, so this new building.
Speaker 0: I'm looking at pictures of them side by side.
Speaker 0: There's like an artist mock-up.
Speaker 0: It looks really cool for one.
Speaker 0: It's like this shiny glass, and it doesn't have a penis on the top.
Speaker 0: No penis at all.
Speaker 0: and if you look at it next to the Empire State Building And you take away the Empire State Building's penis.
Speaker 0: It's taller than the Empire State Building pun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I So hope they build this building.
Speaker 0: I mean
Speaker 1: I like the Empire State Building, but it's you know from everything I've heard and I've heard a story of like a salesman who tried to sell like a keyboard tray to the guy who built it Or something you know the guy who runs the company that originally built it.
Speaker 1: I don't even know.
Speaker 0: Is he a dick?
Speaker 1: Yeah, basically it seems like all the people who run the Empire State Building are dicks, but it's an awesome building.
Speaker 1: But you know what I got?
Speaker 1: no, but what do they care if someone else builds another building?
Speaker 1: It's like I hate just all nimbys and bananas.
Speaker 1: you have no say over what the fuck someone else wants to build on their land Near you.
Speaker 1: I mean people in neighborhoods like complaining about oh you put that ugly house in the same street as me.
Speaker 1: It's like what the fuck do you care?
Speaker 1: It's not your land.
Speaker 1: shut the fuck up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the worst thing is.
Speaker 0: this is the second controversy.
Speaker 0: There's another skyscraper.
Speaker 0: someone's trying to build up by Central Park and all the rich people in the area don't want a skyscraper Up there because they'll ruin the character of their neighborhood, but tough shit.
Speaker 0: well the Empire State Building got built.
Speaker 0: all those other Skyscrapers got built and I want to see the New York skyline just get so dense that it's just a wall of glass.
Speaker 1: Blade Runner guys we were behind schedule.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I want skyscrapers on top of skyscrapers.
Speaker 1: Big black pyramid.
Speaker 1: Let's go So here.
Speaker 1: check this out.
Speaker 0: Here's my thing of the day is not that?
Speaker 0: oh my thing of the day is the comments on The website that has the news story CBS New York.
Speaker 0: Oh boy public comments on non technology usually newspaper sites.
Speaker 1: They'll like real print.
Speaker 1: newspaper sites have heavy moderation like.
Speaker 1: so.
Speaker 0: here's the first comment from Joe all lowercase.
Speaker 0: This is awful news.
Speaker 0: not only are these new buildings ugly people can't even walk the streets We can.
Speaker 0: seems pretty stupid to me.
Speaker 0: Why not put another building there?
Speaker 0: the terrorists can go after.
Speaker 0: imagine you're going down to the middle of Manhattan.
Speaker 0: who the heck would?
Speaker 0: Rent or work there not me all caps at the end there.
Speaker 1: Why do you live here captain?
Speaker 1: You don't like it.
Speaker 1: leave.
Speaker 0: I don't think he lives here And It's amazing.
Speaker 0: the absurdity like it's gotta be boss.
Speaker 1: Why does the newspaper can like not moderate those away?
Speaker 0: now one guy said something smart?
Speaker 0: Do you think that the builders of the Chrysler building were happy when the Empire State Building put that giant spire on the top?
Speaker 1: No, here's your payback.
Speaker 0: And then the reply to that actually quote.
Speaker 0: This is Mother Teresa's revenge.
Speaker 1: That's a good comment.
Speaker 1: I don't even why did the newspaper come allow that comment?
Speaker 0: Fucking now.
Speaker 1: is it CBS right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they allowed that comment.
Speaker 0: CBS, New York.
Speaker 1: All right, but is it the radio or the or the TV?
Speaker 0: I guess the TV cuz it's got the eyeball.
Speaker 1: is it CBS 880.
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: CBS 2 HD.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's TV.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it's the only old people watch CBS.
Speaker 1: CBS is the old people channel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but this thing is 34 feet shorter than the Empire State Building and if you take away the Empire State Building's penis It's like 40 feet taller.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wonder if they'll be rise to the top.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I want.
Speaker 0: if this building is gonna get built I might go be one of the first people to go up into it.
Speaker 1: You can be waiting in line.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's fine.
Speaker 1: Oh So check it.
Speaker 1: Here's one more fun.
Speaker 0: Oh, we should make a thing.
Speaker 0: go to the top of this one.
Speaker 0: I'll go to the south of the Empire State Building.
Speaker 0: Let's try to get a paper airplane between the two.
Speaker 1: sweet.
Speaker 1: So check it out.
Speaker 1: Here we go.
Speaker 0: chandelier That's your ride.
Speaker 1: That's so awesome.
Speaker 1: I actually like that one.
Speaker 1: Wow, it has spinning rims though.
Speaker 0: spinning rims why not chandeliers in the rims?
Speaker 1: No, I think chandelier where the light usually goes in.
Speaker 0: so I believe it is time before we forget for the meta moment.
Speaker 0: the big night's book club book is Golden Apples of the Sun by Ray Bradbury.
Speaker 1: Really I thought about that title just now for it, you know The Sun really can't have any apples little own golden ones.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, you know, they're just getting set on fire.
Speaker 0: Have you ever read poetry?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know that It's alluding to a fairly famous poem new by Uh-huh Similar not go.
Speaker 0: Good I heard no Bunga wrote some.
Speaker 0: good We'll do a show on that soon.
Speaker 0: also the penny arcade Expo.
Speaker 0: this is not a Tuesday So hopefully you guys know what the put packs is.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much X. West packs.
Speaker 0: West packs prime.
Speaker 0: labor day.
Speaker 0: We labor day weekend in Seattle The most rockin gaming convention in the world possibly outside of Essen but Essen is outside of packs East in the same Touché.
Speaker 0: good, sir.
Speaker 0: We are going to be at the penny arcade expo packs prime.
Speaker 0: We are doing panels.
Speaker 0: We're doing Sunday.
Speaker 1: you don't have to come to that one.
Speaker 0: We are doing well, it's not gonna live up.
Speaker 0: We are doing game mechanics and mechanism design in the unicorn theaters.
Speaker 1: Saturday night you got to come to that one and Friday 10 p.m.
Speaker 0: In the serpent theater We are the hosts of packs.
Speaker 0: late night the packs late show.
Speaker 0: We have got Alex Albrecht.
Speaker 0: We have got the roosterteeth guys.
Speaker 0: We have got the voice of Duke Nukem John St.
Speaker 1: John and You got balls of steel balls balls balls of steel.
Speaker 0: We have got a musical act.
Speaker 0: It is Molly 23 who plays the ukulele.
Speaker 0: No One's gonna get that joke, you know what Molly 23 is pretty freakin metal.
Speaker 0: you should listen.
Speaker 0: She's got some of her songs online.
Speaker 0: She's totally cool.
Speaker 1: She's doing her musical act and Yeah, there you go.
Speaker 0: That's the Friday packs late show.
Speaker 1: Totally awesome.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I'm totally pumped for it.
Speaker 1: Well pumped and if you are not going to packs, fuck you You'll be able to watch that on the Internet's.
Speaker 0: yes in some form We're gonna have a website everything.
Speaker 1: more details will probably occur after it is on the Internet.
Speaker 0: It will not be hard to find.
Speaker 0: I'm sure if you look for packs late show you will find us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what other informations is?
Speaker 1: oh one more piece of information?
Speaker 1: It's a. it's a packs advice to people who might be listening to the show.
Speaker 0: Yes This is on the level of the advice.
Speaker 0: We usually give to like the Otacon people at Otacon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is one packs advice for a packs goer, right?
Speaker 1: I have learned and I'm I can't 100% say this is true But 90% that the packs main events right.
Speaker 1: the is going to be in it.
Speaker 1: Well, this is 100% right that it's going to be in the.
Speaker 1: what's the name of the theater?
Speaker 0: The bear is something I don't even have it up.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be in Benaroya Hall Which is a. it's like a concert hall down the road where the symphony plays much like how Otacon.
Speaker 0: because their stuff is too big They put it in the arena next door.
Speaker 1: So the main events of PAX West are gonna be in Benaroya Hall, which is this place of the symphony plays.
Speaker 1: So I assume it's gonna be all seats and not a general admission.
Speaker 0: It also only seats like 2,500 people.
Speaker 1: Yes, the concerts can be pretty sad because you're not gonna be able to stand really.
Speaker 0: I'll stand on my chair right anyway I'm in a beanbag anyway.
Speaker 1: So they're gonna give out exactly 20, you know The number of wristbands equal to the number of seats for you know The the concerts and of course many people will get wristbands and not show up.
Speaker 0: I've done that before.
Speaker 1: Yes, so I'm sure that some people will be allowed in without wristbands But I doubt many and I can't Gary I cannot promise you that you will get in without a wristband.
Speaker 0: But none of this is really news.
Speaker 1: No The news is.
Speaker 1: well, it's not really news but it is advice if you don't have the wristband right and You know and let's say it's not.
Speaker 1: if it's a Q&A and you want to ask a Q You probably want to get there.
Speaker 1: But if you just want to watch the keynote or you just want to see the concert and relax They are supposedly going to simulcast Everything in Benaroya Hall in the Q room in the Convention Center on a screen.
Speaker 1: so you could just chill in that Q room and Watch all the main events of PAX without having to walk down the street and lose a bunch of time waiting in line or dealing.
Speaker 0: so I get in line for event A. While I am in line, I watch event B simulcast from the hall.
Speaker 0: then I immediately go to event A Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: How have I at any point wasted my time?
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: I've gotten double awesome, that's right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so take full advantage of these simultaneously cast main events in the Q room because you can avoid you know Spending time doing walks between the main, you know, the Convention Center and the Benaroya Hall and you could play games.
Speaker 1: You know, you can't play a game during a concert if you're in the concert hall But you could play a game in the Q room while the concerts are going on.
Speaker 1: How awesome is that?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that'd be fucking.
Speaker 0: let's think of this.
Speaker 0: we're getting to the point.
Speaker 0: I mean they have entertainment in the Q room which already pushed packs like well above and beyond any other.
Speaker 1: Entertainment is also the main events.
Speaker 0: It's gonna get to the point to where there are people who I could almost foresee Spending their entire con in events or in the Q room because the Q room also has its own like exclusive entertainment.
Speaker 0: We might be screening the late show there at one point.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, all sorts of stuff goes out in there.
Speaker 0: There's that line entertainment the games.
Speaker 0: the Q room is an event in and of itself that is worth standing in line For.
Speaker 0: will we someday have a Q room for the Q room?
Speaker 1: That'd be so.
Speaker 0: will we have the Q room be simulcast into the QQ room?
Speaker 0: The whole convention will be one room And parts of it simulcast into other rooms.
Speaker 0: It's just a loop.
Speaker 1: now everyone on their phone.
Speaker 1: It'll be a hundred cameras and you could pick which camera you want to look at in the room.
Speaker 0: All right, I guess that's enough.
Speaker 0: meta near comic-con.
Speaker 0: New York anime festival, October 8th.
Speaker 0: We're doing crazy shit there, but you'll will announce that as it gets closer.
Speaker 1: All right, so Basically, I don't know this topic is sort of a. I guess it'll be an okay topic But it is not a mystery to anyone that it's a secret to everybody Yeah that there are fanboys in the world, but especially in the realm of technology.
Speaker 1: In fact, it was pretty much invented in the realm of technology because you know, the internet started out with technologists.
Speaker 0: So anything that happens argue the first fanboys you remember 12 Byzantine rulers?
Speaker 0: Okay, I I would argue that those debates about religion back then were basically fanboy arguments.
Speaker 0: yes, maybe so but is is Do you have to roll a 15 or an 18?
Speaker 1: The thing is on the internet right.
Speaker 1: the first blogs were about technology.
Speaker 1: the first, you know Podcasts on pod, you know, we're about technology.
Speaker 1: everything that's on the internet is always about technology first because the internet is technology and technologists Are the first people to take advantage of any of the new technology?
Speaker 1: so whenever there is a new technology the first instances of that new technology are about technology.
Speaker 1: and When these people who are about technology discuss technology they are often fanboys or zealots.
Speaker 1: They pick a thing and then every other thing But the thing that they like is a shitty thing and their thing is better than everyone else's thing and it could be a programming Language, it could be a piece of software.
Speaker 1: It could be an operating system, which I guess is a piece of software.
Speaker 1: It could be a hardware.
Speaker 1: It could be a hardware brand.
Speaker 1: It could be a software an open source license.
Speaker 1: It could be anything.
Speaker 0: it's weird how specific these things get.
Speaker 0: sometimes.
Speaker 0: I mean you might see like the Apple fanboy and think like yeah, look at our rabbit that guy Those guys aren't even on the radar.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I have like.
Speaker 0: have you ever spoken to like a new herd Linux kind of person you Correct you every time you say Linux.
Speaker 0: they will say it's GNU Linux.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it's GNU Linux like a summon won't even talk to you if you call it just plain old Linux.
Speaker 0: I mean, these are people who have focused on something so specific and are so like it is their entire life As far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: and it's weird because you don't see this in popular Culture on the internet as much as you used to.
Speaker 1: because those people because other people have made things on the internet.
Speaker 1: They're now podcasts about things other than technology Websites that are about things that are like remember remember slash shot like seven eight years ago.
Speaker 0: There is a lot more of that there and it's kind of falling away.
Speaker 0: I don't know if those people have just they're on reddit.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, basically.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz reddit has all the it's like, you know It's like a million digs because they have specific categories for everything.
Speaker 1: So you can go like the reddit just for a particular programming language and they'll be just just things for that You know.
Speaker 1: So that's where you find the fanboys and even people.
Speaker 1: there'll be people who are like.
Speaker 1: they're both use it.
Speaker 1: They're both fans of the same programming language, but they'll argue about like two different libraries.
Speaker 1: You know, they're like, oh no.
Speaker 1: No, you must use this framework.
Speaker 1: No, this framework is superior.
Speaker 0: Now the trouble is this I think is holding back open technology more so than any other factor in the world.
Speaker 0: It's not man-hours.
Speaker 0: We need to spend.
Speaker 0: it's not like direction or design.
Speaker 0: I think it's primarily that we have these weird divisions in almost all open software and open anything development Because people become zealots and they refuse to compromise on what I would argue are really stupid things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean like I'll see two people arguing about a particular thing, right?
Speaker 1: Maybe they're arguing about like JavaScript libraries so one guy like jQuery and the other guy likes prototype or moo tools or one of the other ones.
Speaker 0: So it's got.
Speaker 0: we're intelligent, you know, we're gonna debate that I use jQuery because of X and Y. All right, I use moo tools because of X and Y, you know If you use jQuery for Z, it's actually faster.
Speaker 1: If you change your program to use Z, you know moo tools is easier to write because it's all friendly and such.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, well, I'm gonna keep using jQuery cuz it's faster for Z. No, you should use moo tools Jake I thought we were gonna discuss it like smart people should discuss it not for zealots.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it's like first of all, why do you care what the fuck other people use?
Speaker 1: What do you care?
Speaker 1: what the fuck other people use right?
Speaker 1: Okay, so I guess I don't know the answer to that.
Speaker 0: Here's one case.
Speaker 0: All right at my work, right?
Speaker 0: We have a couple of guys who use Perl for all their kind of scripting.
Speaker 0: like you got to bang out something quick for some Monitoring or something.
Speaker 0: they use Perl.
Speaker 0: the rest of us use Python.
Speaker 0: It's like 50/50.
Speaker 0: I can.
Speaker 0: I would rather the Perl people use Perl or use Python Because I'm better at Python and if I have to change their shit or reuse it, it's easy for me.
Speaker 0: But if they want to use Perl, I'm not angry.
Speaker 0: It is not like.
Speaker 0: this somehow Bothers me outside of the specific inconvenience that causes me in the code.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's like it's it works.
Speaker 1: So I'm being paid.
Speaker 1: So what do I care that you're paying me for my time?
Speaker 1: I mean if I'm doing something on my own, I mean obviously I most cases I'm a programmer.
Speaker 1: I do have a preference right.
Speaker 1: usually or you know, sometimes I don't care but usually I have at least a slight preference.
Speaker 1: So I'll pick what I want when I'm doing it on my own.
Speaker 1: if I'm doing it for work I don't care what the fuck it is.
Speaker 1: I'm being paid to do it.
Speaker 1: So whatever it is that they want I'll do it and you know if there's like I might work There's basically one person who cares and no one else cares.
Speaker 1: So that person just picks everything and you know what.
Speaker 1: if another person were to join the team who also cared it would be Probably a big problem, but I don't care.
Speaker 1: It's like okay.
Speaker 1: You don't like this one.
Speaker 1: We'll use that one.
Speaker 1: Okay, it's not any more trouble for me to use something different.
Speaker 1: They're all pretty much the same and equal.
Speaker 1: I still prefer the other one.
Speaker 1: I might disagree but it's work.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna fight about it.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: what's the?
Speaker 1: it'd be more trouble to fight about it than to use the different one?
Speaker 0: Yep, but yet in the open-source world like the fighting becomes like its own thing.
Speaker 0: I mean people fight to the point that even to this day Ubuntu You know they don't do a lot of things that would make Ubuntu a lot more usable because they're worried about purity Purity of the license purity of the open.
Speaker 1: money back to Ubuntu is is less pure than all the other ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we won't use Ubuntu because it's not pure.
Speaker 1: I've run into those people so impure.
Speaker 1: I mean good You can't use that but you gotta use Debian or whatever fuck Debian doesn't do it Kind of sucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean like look You know I'm all about open source miss right and I know some people who refuse to use anything.
Speaker 1: That's not open source right, but at the same time.
Speaker 1: I got an iPhone, but I like open source.
Speaker 1: Why do I have this iPhone?
Speaker 0: iPhone works better?
Speaker 1: I just works better.
Speaker 1: You know I it's not like I'm some you know Fundamentalist.
Speaker 1: I must follow this rule in all cases.
Speaker 1: do I prefer open source.
Speaker 1: Yes, I prefer things that work more.
Speaker 1: I would rather have one device that does the work of two devices and actually works and doesn't crash.
Speaker 1: I would prefer it to be open source.
Speaker 1: that made me very happy But I'm willing to sacrifice that thing in favor of another thing.
Speaker 1: and if someone else prefers the open source more What do I care?
Speaker 1: it doesn't bother me.
Speaker 0: there was a guy?
Speaker 0: I was working on something at IBM and his thing like the.
Speaker 0: it was the Aladdin license.
Speaker 1: I think oh guys the worst.
Speaker 0: he was trying to convince me because I made some jokes.
Speaker 0: I was look I was doing a research on all the licenses that were encumbering and A bunch of open stuff we were about to use in a project I was writing up a report on.
Speaker 0: here are the license concerns.
Speaker 0: if we do X with Y and Z you know the standard like IT Programmer kind of stuff for a big company.
Speaker 0: and this guy I made an off-handed joke in the meeting like and this uses the Aladdin license Yeah, and the guy got really mad.
Speaker 0: He's like don't make fun of the Aladdin license in fact I think everything.
Speaker 0: and he like went off on this crazy grant.
Speaker 1: this guy actually knew it the Aladdin license.
Speaker 0: Not only did he knew no canoe I. I could have made a joke.
Speaker 0: not only did he know but he can do.
Speaker 0: Scott stood up.
Speaker 0: He's far away from his microphone.
Speaker 0: I can say whatever I want.
Speaker 0: There's nothing he can do about it, but the guy like not only did he know about the Aladdin license He cared about it really really strongly and was insulted that I had been flippin.
Speaker 0: in fact That's the word he used flippin about the Aladdin license.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: what was his argument for this Aladdin license?
Speaker 0: He didn't have an argument.
Speaker 0: Oh his argument was basically about like purity and stuff.
Speaker 0: He's one of those new herd kind of people mm-hmm He actually did.
Speaker 0: He is the basis of almost all of my feelings about these people because he corrected me more than once and said uh you're forgetting The GNU tool.
Speaker 0: said without that the Linux would just be a kernel.
Speaker 0: He always called it the Linux.
Speaker 0: All right, yeah, whatever it was an anecdote doesn't really go anywhere from there, but mm-hmm And it was some like postscript thing that I had to use.
Speaker 0: the Aladdin license that I was looking at.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so what?
Speaker 1: what do you think there is any?
Speaker 1: I mean there's my standard internet solution for for people who are fanboys Which is you know - I think younger programmers, which is creativity always wins, right?
Speaker 1: So if you've got people arguing about some software some they're on they're both worked in an open source project community, right?
Speaker 1: So they're both Linux kernel developers, right and they're arguing which way you should do something.
Speaker 1: You just come in write the code.
Speaker 1: productivity wins.
Speaker 1: I wrote the code here.
Speaker 1: It is.
Speaker 1: Here's the patch.
Speaker 1: You know, I did the way I wanted to and the other two guys just arguing Well, you're gonna win cuz you actually did the work and it's the dude, bro.
Speaker 1: It's the same lesson, right?
Speaker 1: productivity Creativity always wins over arguing.
Speaker 0: I mean, alright, so I did the thing that makes Ubuntu awesome, but it's not 100% pure It's not included in Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: and I got a fork.
Speaker 0: All right, so big deal No one's gonna follow my fork and then it dies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then my changes are lost.
Speaker 0: I coded for nothing.
Speaker 1: No, you know, that's that's The thing is if you if you really want it right you have to do enough work.
Speaker 1: There's a. there's an amount of work you have to do to actually make it succeed.
Speaker 1: You keep at it to the point at which you've actually got a distribution That's you know Like better than Ubuntu.
Speaker 1: people will just start leaving it and come over to you.
Speaker 1: look at like mint.
Speaker 1: mint is an Ubuntu based Linux distribution and quite a lot of people use that instead of Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: I think over time the problem is going to solve itself, but in a way that kind of sucks my personal feeling By observing younger people who are coming into tech and like new workers and companies and things.
Speaker 0: is that younger?
Speaker 0: Generations don't give a shit about most of this and their zealotries are so much more superficial than the old zealotries.
Speaker 0: I mean the old zealotries would come down to Surprisingly esoteric and specific things where people would make very Very like real mathematical arguments for one of the other or they would argue about like the lineage of GNU and the toolset and all This stuff.
Speaker 0: but now most younger zealots are zealous about some sort of very meta Abstract thing like.
Speaker 0: I like a GUI versus a command line.
Speaker 0: I like Mac versus Windows.
Speaker 1: Well, that's a general problem.
Speaker 1: I think in all of our society is people taking their preferences, right?
Speaker 1: You know if someone says I prefer GUI to command-line it's like alright cool whatever dude, but people will be like.
Speaker 1: This doesn't have a GUI.
Speaker 1: It sucks.
Speaker 1: You shouldn't use it.
Speaker 0: Well, it's like the correct answer Is it so?
Speaker 0: you're me and people like me?
Speaker 1: Yes, you are.
Speaker 1: you are misconstruing your personal preference for an Objective measure of something Scott and I could never be caught doing no ever ever.
Speaker 0: whether that has never happened you know.
Speaker 1: and the thing is I think actually the Technology itself is is to blame for a lot of this in the olden days, right?
Speaker 1: If you had like, you know some old computer like a pdp-11 or something, right, you know olden days They were pretty much objective measures of what was better.
Speaker 1: This uses less memory.
Speaker 1: This is uses three less instructions to execute.
Speaker 1: it goes faster, right?
Speaker 1: Because everything was so low-level you didn't really you know, whatever it was better was better.
Speaker 1: There was objective measurements of almost everything.
Speaker 0: That's kind of the point.
Speaker 0: I was making the.
Speaker 0: the zealotries now are more superficial and there's no order They can make.
Speaker 1: the computer is so fast that you know Some people are still working on that level and are still have these objective differences.
Speaker 1: and you know Sometimes those things actually don't like Linux kernel.
Speaker 1: That's that kind of thing still happens a lot.
Speaker 1: Aha My algorithm is more efficient.
Speaker 1: Okay, it wins right but at the same time You know, most arguments are not on that low objective level of computing.
Speaker 1: They're on some way up high level where they're not even measuring what's actually faster You know or what actually takes, you know, and the thing is, okay It takes an extra megabyte for my option But you know what.
Speaker 1: who gives a shit because I have four gigs of RAM So who cares that it takes an extra megabyte if it's better?
Speaker 0: Well, that's the thing because the zealotries are not working in a cell phone are more Superficial and they're more kind of opinion-based.
Speaker 0: They don't really have the same strength.
Speaker 0: I mean find the most zealous Apple fanboy you've ever seen and their arguments don't get that much far beyond.
Speaker 0: My platform is better.
Speaker 0: It looks better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean there is.
Speaker 1: there are some cases though that I think.
Speaker 1: The problem is that people Like I wrote a blog post sort of about this right which is people have no problem like modifying their computer, right?
Speaker 1: It's like I don't.
Speaker 1: I have a problem girl.
Speaker 1: It's not matching my preference.
Speaker 1: So they change their computer They'll change the Dvorak keyboard or something, right?
Speaker 1: Whereas, you know and then they go to another computer and it's not the same way girl, right?
Speaker 1: I learned my lesson like in the late to that, you know three or four years ago Don't change a computer at all.
Speaker 1: Just change your own damn self, right?
Speaker 1: Because it's a lot easier to change yourself than it is to change the computer.
Speaker 1: It's a lot less time-consuming.
Speaker 1: I can use like in any computer.
Speaker 1: and the thing is, you know, you might argue Well, I have this I have this preference, right?
Speaker 1: And you might try to say it's objectively better or not.
Speaker 1: Maybe you have an argument Maybe you don't
Speaker 0: but you
Speaker 1: might recognize that someone else is doing something in a particular way and you know Objectively that your way is perhaps easier or more efficient and you can actually you know Show this like look if you would just use the friggin keyboard shortcuts, right?
Speaker 1: You would be a lot better off.
Speaker 1: and the person goes and they don't want to learn they don't want to change themselves They don't want to bother with the keyboard shortcuts, but you know, maybe they don't mind the inefficiency Okay But if they simultaneously complain about the inefficiency and they won't learn to be more efficient and you're showing them the way It's like what the fuck dude what the fuck?
Speaker 0: Yep, at the same time sometimes if someone says Ella like say Dvorak is not better.
Speaker 0: We've gone over this.
Speaker 0: but say it were say it were somehow like two or three percent better.
Speaker 0: Okay?
Speaker 0: All right, so maybe I used on my keyboard two or three percent better.
Speaker 0: No one else supports that shit.
Speaker 0: So everywhere else I go, I'm gonna have to go back to QWERTY anyway.
Speaker 1: So not to mention a lot of it causes a lot of other side effect problems Like oh you want to do ctrl s to save on a Dvorak keyboard.
Speaker 1: Guess what can't do with one hand?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well you can if you're a freak.
Speaker 1: yeah, right.
Speaker 0: and maybe you play the piano.
Speaker 1: So suddenly all your keyboard truck has had to be different.
Speaker 1: and then on and suddenly actually I can.
Speaker 0: God, I just tested.
Speaker 0: I can use either alt control or shift with one hand and hit any letter on the keyboard.
Speaker 1: All right, good.
Speaker 1: Good luck for you.
Speaker 1: But yes, it's a lot easier to hit ctrl s on QWERTY than a Dvorak.
Speaker 1: so, you know, it kind of everything gets sorted, you know finagling.
Speaker 1: Oh, you got to use some WASD for a game.
Speaker 1: So suddenly every time you're playing a game you have to reconfigure it, you know It's a whole lot more work than you think it is to that You're gonna be spending reconfiguring and then if you use a different computer.
Speaker 1: Oh my god again, right?
Speaker 1: So it's best to just often forget your zealotry forget your preference for one browser another.
Speaker 1: right if you are Actually a good computer user and you know how a computer works and how to use one You should be able to use anything.
Speaker 1: I can use Microsoft Word.
Speaker 1: I can use Abby Word.
Speaker 1: I can use open office It doesn't.
Speaker 1: if I can use Google Docs, it doesn't matter what the fuck word processor I have.
Speaker 1: I might like one the most but I can use anyone I have to use and I'll be just fine.
Speaker 0: So I think there are two ways to deal with these people.
Speaker 0: If it's one of those like we should code with this or that the answer is alright, whatever.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 1: Yeah, unless there actually is you know a real reason need to pick one of the other.
Speaker 1: But in which case the person in charge whoever someone has authority.
Speaker 1: or there's a voting or there's some mechanism by which you will decide.
Speaker 0: But the second case is the GNU Linux kind of person.
Speaker 0: the person who makes the you know The kind of know it's GNU Linux.
Speaker 0: if someone ever corrects you and says sorry, it's GNU Linux I think your response should be to just laugh and say okay, dude Fine, and then they might get really mad and hit you.
Speaker 0: Uh Unix anis can't hit that hard.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: There's a lot.
Speaker 1: Oh, they might fall on you underneath that beard.
Speaker 0: Watch out Maybe they'll strangle you with the beard.
Speaker 1: But yeah in general I think you should fight zealotry with productivity or laughter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that you should You know change yourself before you start trying to change the computer.
Speaker 1: You should be.
Speaker 1: if you're actually good at computers You should be able to.
Speaker 1: I can use.
Speaker 1: I can learn a new programming language in a couple days as long as it's you know A kind of programming language that I've you know learned before, you know It's not a new category of language might take me an extra few days to learn
Speaker 0: some sort of aspect oriented language.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean, you know not I mean something even completely new.
Speaker 1: I mean, I've done all I've done functional programming and all sorts.
Speaker 1: so I can do.
Speaker 1: I can learn almost anything in a couple days.
Speaker 1: So what's you know?
Speaker 1: Throw anything you got at me if you're you know.
Speaker 1: If you can only use one particular thing and as soon as you're given a different thing you fall apart and don't know what to Do.
Speaker 1: well, then you know with it then you suck.
Speaker 0: Well, yes, you are failing.
Speaker 1: is you not failing?
Speaker 0: in the computer anytime you're looking for a developer for something Especially for a short project you'll find the majority of developers out there are Java, which is fine.
Speaker 0: Java is good for a lot of small projects.
Speaker 0: But here's the problem the majority of the people out there who if you look for a small project thing are Java coder.
Speaker 0: So if you're looking for a Java coder specifically You will find these people and if you talk to them you will discover that they do not know how to program.
Speaker 1: They don't know any length.
Speaker 0: They know how to write Java.
Speaker 0: They do not know how to write code.
Speaker 0: They don't know any other programming language or programming fundamentals.
Speaker 0: They just know enough Java to do pretty much what you want.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I would argue that they are not computer science professionals.
Speaker 0: They're not even coders.
Speaker 0: They are Java errs and nothing more.
Speaker 1: and There's people like that for all like this done not even just languages.
Speaker 0: You would be surprised like you think of an IT.
Speaker 0: They're excelers.
Speaker 0: There are so many IT guys who literally are I can support Microsoft Office on Windows or I can support Cisco.
Speaker 0: They don't know anything about networks.
Speaker 0: They can't even tell you how multicast works, but they can make multicast work on a Cisco device Uh-huh, and they have like.
Speaker 1: I guess it's like some rote memorization as without actually knowing anything.
Speaker 1: conceptually It's that I don't understand even how you could have that kind of knowledge.
Speaker 0: I don't but I would say that is the majority of the IT people I've ever interacted with Really?
Speaker 1: I don't even understand how you could memorize the steps for something and not understand what the steps were Like.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: I can't like.
Speaker 1: my brain doesn't even wrap around the way most schools teach it.
Speaker 0: and you know still A lot of IT people never went to school for IT.
Speaker 0: They went for something else and kind of picked it up as they went.
Speaker 0: But like look at our IT.
Speaker 0: compared to a lot of other schools our IT never taught a Cisco.
Speaker 0: They gave us weird-ass routers that work terribly and they made us just use them.
Speaker 0: They didn't even tell us how they worked.
Speaker 0: We had to figure it out.
Speaker 1: I saw a bunch of Cisco equipment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we had that too.
Speaker 0: We could go get Cisco if we wanted to but they wouldn't teach us like never.
Speaker 0: they never once told us how to do Anything with the Cisco router.
Speaker 0: if you wanted to know you had to go figure it out yourself.
Speaker 0: They would say make a router do this and you'd go find our router and make it do that Mm-hmm, and in one class they forced us to use this weird HP system.
Speaker 0: That was totally different from Cisco.
Speaker 0: In fact, I don't know Cisco that well, I only know like, you know routing fundamentals.
Speaker 0: I can make any router do anything.
Speaker 0: I just have to read the manual to figure out like how to turn on whatever routing protocol.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's CA.
Speaker 1: in the CS department CS 1 through 3 were Java But then CS 4 was C++ and then in classes after that I mean everything was always Java a bull usually because you know They needed.
Speaker 1: they couldn't like, you know force you to use something that you hadn't learned yet And the class was usually focusing on a specific topic and they couldn't force you to like Yep You know learn a new language.
Speaker 0: as part of the class that I do is that way every IT class but a programming project And you could write in whatever you want.
Speaker 1: But usually usually they let they gave you some choices and there was even a class that Gave you a bunch of small projects and a bunch of different languages.
Speaker 1: and you know, it was a weird adjunct professor But I learned like I did one thing in LISP and one thing in prologue and one thing in MATLAB Which isn't even really, you know, and I did like, you know one thing in a whole bunch of different languages.
Speaker 0: It sounds really fun one small thing each.
Speaker 1: actually I got the shitty class.
Speaker 1: the better class Does it with you program the Lego robots with a bunch of different languages one after the other.
Speaker 1: that's a much better way to go I think that's actually.
Speaker 1: I think the programming the robots in Python is CS 1 at MIT.
Speaker 1: now from what I've heard.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh But yeah, it's you know, that's that's how it should be.
Speaker 1: you should be able to use anything.
Speaker 1: You can have a preference.
Speaker 1: don't try to shove your preference on anyone else.
Speaker 1: You know if maybe you know your preference actually is objectively better somehow and you can see that it could benefit someone.
Speaker 1: But if they don't want to take it just fuck them.
Speaker 1: It's not worth it.
Speaker 0: Well, no, no, all you do is you point.
Speaker 0: you have to really like work them up to it.
Speaker 0: You know My computer is slow and you tell them will it be faster if you did this and that's true.
Speaker 0: and every time they ever complain About the computer just remind them, you know, it'd work if you did this.
Speaker 1: Yep That's a good way to go.
Speaker 1: But you don't don't sit there and be the zealot guy arguing with them saying Scott you've never done that.
Speaker 1: No, listen, you got to do it my way.
Speaker 0: I Think we've gone.
Speaker 1: I just berate people for being stupid is different.
Speaker 0: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.