Speaker 1: It's Thursday March 11th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: avatar Let's do this.
Speaker 1: I was gonna talk about your man pack for the opening But this is not an open.
Speaker 1: your Scott decided He wants his man pack to be the thing of the day not my man pack.
Speaker 1: well Not yet.
Speaker 1: apparently it should be your man now.
Speaker 1: It's man packs and apparently you need some.
Speaker 0: no I don't.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, this is what happens when we don't actually have anything interesting.
Speaker 1: I mean all I have to talk about that's meta that I could actually talk about.
Speaker 1: on the show is Stuff like the fat woman that prevented me from catching the train.
Speaker 1: I wanted to catch.
Speaker 0: I had an opening bit.
Speaker 0: I just forgot what it was and I had a second opening bit that I moved to news.
Speaker 0: and because I forgot the first opening Bit and then I you know well now what.
Speaker 1: oh yeah, well, I worry if I keep bringing up like in the in the morning You know every couple weeks.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, this fat woman got in my way.
Speaker 1: It sounds like I'm just I don't know like I'm attracted to fat women.
Speaker 1: or somehow fat women are like Central to my life, maybe a confirmation so large you can't not notice them.
Speaker 1: They have some sort of Gravitation.
Speaker 0: why is it always women?
Speaker 0: Why are there?
Speaker 0: you know fat dudes?
Speaker 1: There are.
Speaker 1: it's just they're never in my way on the escalator ever.
Speaker 1: hmm I don't know why.
Speaker 1: I don't think there's any difference between fat men and fat women.
Speaker 0: It's just except there.
Speaker 0: You know their ability to use an escalator quickly.
Speaker 1: I don't know but it You know.
Speaker 1: maybe I'll end this because today like for the fifth time I see the seven train coming.
Speaker 1: I'm going down this long escalator But I usually just walk down like every commuter does and there's one we just blocking the whole escalator and I'm standing behind her.
Speaker 1: I see the train come and then go and Then we get to the bottom of the escalator, and I stand there for like 10 minutes to wait for another train.
Speaker 1: I think next time I'm just going for it.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna like jump up on the rail and run past her.
Speaker 0: I remembered what my other opening bit was what I was talking about five minutes ago.
Speaker 0: Which is I considering?
Speaker 0: removing all hairs.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, well What I don't see.
Speaker 0: the proud the thing is here.
Speaker 0: the pro is the pro con rundown ready pro number one.
Speaker 0: I like less maintenance and not having any hairs you get the cool breeze.
Speaker 0: ah it's much easier to wear hats and helmets.
Speaker 1: I will say this right I don't plan to ever really cut my long hair But I have these vague memories of what it feels like to have short hair like I can imagine Like when I was like a great weight has been lifted.
Speaker 0: It's like a thousand million cross.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's cried out, and we're suddenly silence.
Speaker 0: No, okay, so the right now the thing is right is my hair actually right now.
Speaker 0: It looks all right.
Speaker 0: There's nothing wrong with it except if there's a camera.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: it looks like I'm diseased The way cameras pick up.
Speaker 1: especially.
Speaker 1: I think this camera in particular does some sort of color correction Like if you get the top of my head you can see this line down the top like when I have my hair tied back.
Speaker 0: No, they're like some pictures They saw of me on the Internet's where it looks like I have some you know like cancer or whatever And I'm like it doesn't look too.
Speaker 1: Good see now I'm thinking you.
Speaker 1: your options are one.
Speaker 1: keep it because you are primed for Aramaki hair.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the problem is Aramaki hair only looks good when you're old and gray which I have not me.
Speaker 0: I could do an Aramaki cosplay and then shave it up.
Speaker 1: Maybe you should.
Speaker 1: you have to grow that you throw out a little bit on the side.
Speaker 0: Well the problem is is the sides are basically the same as they always were.
Speaker 0: they're exactly the way the top used to be But the top is not what it once was.
Speaker 1: well Here's the trouble.
Speaker 1: Aramaki hair is awesome, but between Aramaki hair and current hair is clown hair.
Speaker 0: exactly.
Speaker 0: This is another problem.
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 0: is that if you if I shave it all off, and I let it grow back It's basically gonna be horrible in these in the in-between Stages as it comes back in.
Speaker 1: the next option is what one of my co-workers at IBM Did and he was you know he'd lost his hair kind of early in the same pattern you did But he still had the sides.
Speaker 1: He just kept the top to the bitter end and eventually at all the middle in the top went away And he had like trimmed a clown hair And it worked like a Costanza situation.
Speaker 1: yeah, it was basically a kiss man, that's not good.
Speaker 1: The other option is just to go all out.
Speaker 1: the trouble with all out is you do not know what the shape of your head Is remember Adam?
Speaker 0: It's not so much the shape of the head I'm worried about.
Speaker 0: what I'm worried about is some other factors such as You know You know it's sort of.
Speaker 0: first of all it's like a one-way street sort of.
Speaker 0: it's like if I go There's no turning back, so if it was the bad you know I don't like to do anything.
Speaker 0: I can't undo if I don't have to write.
Speaker 0: Secondly there's the the situation of.
Speaker 0: I was reading on the Internet's of course for help with this you know The situation of the pale scalp.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: so basically in that yeah, but I mean immediately right I have to go outside.
Speaker 0: You know the same day makeup.
Speaker 0: So It's like you go outside And you're gonna have this strangely colored head.
Speaker 1: Scott there are two optional three out for a couple days.
Speaker 1: makeup Baseball cap awesome hat.
Speaker 1: this would be an opportunity to start wearing like fedoras.
Speaker 0: Well, I definitely there's gonna be hats whether I have hairs or not You know there's.
Speaker 0: I'm definitely good because you know you'll find in my news I will discuss helmets.
Speaker 0: you know of course the bicycle variety which are for a guy guarantee.
Speaker 0: They're far more comfortable, and you have less hairs.
Speaker 0: because you look at Lance Armstrong.
Speaker 0: He doesn't be fucking hairs right yeah, and then Captain Jean-Luc Picard also no hairs right sexiest man alive.
Speaker 0: So you're already done with Neil Gaiman.
Speaker 1: Neil Gaiman has all game.
Speaker 1: It has kind of this.
Speaker 0: there was a Neil Gaiman house tour video.
Speaker 0: I saw the Internet's recently.
Speaker 1: He has this kind of roguish Britishness that I really like, but at the same time Patrick Stewart has command.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh so rim you like to you like to be taking command of.
Speaker 1: is that what you're saying if it's a Starship captain of the USS Enterprise?
Speaker 0: so Emily taking command of rim is the hella good.
Speaker 1: Emily does not look like Patrick Stewart.
Speaker 0: I Don't think she's gonna shave her head.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean remember Adam went through the exact same debate you went through and he was in a.
Speaker 0: but yeah He was in a. he was in a worse situation than I'm at now.
Speaker 0: if I was him I would have I would have gone over.
Speaker 0: you know if I was at his at the point at which he went for it I would have gone for it way before.
Speaker 0: yeah, but I'm not yet at the line.
Speaker 1: But the debate was you know what if you have a funny-shaped head?
Speaker 1: What if there's?
Speaker 1: the other question is right.
Speaker 0: you look right.
Speaker 0: one of my grandpa's you know my dad's dad.
Speaker 0: You know when I had all baldness just like my dad and crazy baldness right, but my mom's dad It thinned and then it stopped right.
Speaker 0: so it's like I could.
Speaker 0: it could be like this.
Speaker 0: it is now forever.
Speaker 0: It's possible.
Speaker 0: It could just like reach this point, and I could be 80 with the same exact thing.
Speaker 0: I got now.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's guy.
Speaker 1: it's like yeah history I don't know what I would do.
Speaker 1: you could try to get someone to photoshop you bald.
Speaker 0: that's I was.
Speaker 1: I Requested that a few times But you might have to start wearing like tiny little sunglasses because you could rock that look Maybe like the tiny little red sunglasses.
Speaker 0: I already bought expensive sunglasses.
Speaker 0: I'm not buying them again.
Speaker 1: No, you're wearing the expensive sunglasses when there's actually Sun where the other sunglasses all the time and don't actually look through Like the time because they look good bald guy with like tiny red spectacles.
Speaker 0: That's a pain in the ass Yeah, but it's a good idea is to reduce the pain in the ass, but it's a good look.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 0: beauty before duty no.
Speaker 1: Fashion before function no.
Speaker 1: So I don't know what you should do.
Speaker 0: I don't know anyway.
Speaker 0: No No So I already talked about my news a little bit.
Speaker 0: might as look all the way right.
Speaker 1: so something about bicycle helmets.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no no it's just that if I was bald a bicycle helmet would be comfortable.
Speaker 1: You know more comfortable than if I had half the reason I never wear helmets when I ski or bike or anything is because I hate putting my hair under the skiing helmets.
Speaker 0: I've never seen anyone wear a skiing home here, but it's not really a bad idea.
Speaker 0: How do you think about it now?
Speaker 1: actually all studies show that skiing helmets have in no way?
Speaker 1: Decreased the number of fatalities skiing.
Speaker 0: that's cuz most of it as true But it would reduce I guess.
Speaker 0: hey the primary the thing is skiing.
Speaker 0: head injuries are kind of rare even if you go completely Unprotected.
Speaker 0: it's mostly limb injuries actually.
Speaker 1: no It's not.
Speaker 1: and back it's primarily neck injuries if you're not wearing a helmet Or if you are wearing a helmet head injuries if you it's a head if you're not wearing.
Speaker 1: if you are wearing a helmet Whatever whatever regardless the point is the reason the helmets don't matter is because the primary factor in how severely you hurt yourself is The severity of the accident and almost nothing else has any effect.
Speaker 1: only three types of people wear helmets skiing Wuses snowboarders doing tricks and people skiing either in crazy hard stuff or ice and the latter two you should be wearing a helmet.
Speaker 0: who skis?
Speaker 0: and crazy hard stuff and ice?
Speaker 1: a lot of people I'll.
Speaker 1: in fact if I'm skiing on like a black diamond, and there's like straight-up ice I'll wear a helmet because I don't want to fall and hit my head on what I would wear a helmet on the ski jump.
Speaker 1: Ski jump actually not that dangerous compared to say it's really not as good thing is.
Speaker 0: it looks a lot higher on TV.
Speaker 0: Then it is in real life.
Speaker 0: You know it's not actually that high pretty high.
Speaker 0: Well the thing is is like it's got you go skiing.
Speaker 1: I do like a four-foot jump and holy shit Ski jump is not that high.
Speaker 0: ah it's it's less.
Speaker 0: It's like high dive high.
Speaker 0: It's not you know like.
Speaker 0: it's not like bungee jump high It's.
Speaker 0: I want to see a ski jump this bungee jump high.
Speaker 0: that'd be fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: There are people who do stuff like that.
Speaker 0: no, but I want to see that in the Olympics.
Speaker 0: Okay Anyway skid bicycling.
Speaker 0: so I've been looking at buying some bicycles.
Speaker 0: I've seen a few I got but the thing is I was gonna go actually like pick one up like tomorrow.
Speaker 0: You go you know just go to two or three different places until I found what I wanted.
Speaker 0: It's gonna rain like from now until whenever.
Speaker 0: so I was like well if you're delaying my my action here until forever Yeah, and my but my work You know there's a New York law about they have to let you bring a bike in the freight elevators.
Speaker 0: You know basically because if I had to leave the bike on the street I would not ride my bike to work At least not a bike that cost more than five dollars you buy one of those hipster fixies.
Speaker 0: not gonna happen fixies I can't even ride a fixie.
Speaker 1: fixies are only useful for two kinds of people old people little kids.
Speaker 1: No, I guess the third option kids.
Speaker 1: It's people who want biking to be horrifyingly painful and difficult and people who don't know how to use a real bike.
Speaker 0: Yeah Actually I saw someone sent me a link over to a bike that I was like.
Speaker 0: I can't get that bike It's a fixie, but actually what it has?
Speaker 0: it has Internal gears.
Speaker 1: those are your hub.
Speaker 1: those aren't really fixies.
Speaker 0: my dad at a bike has a planetary You know sort of gear system in the hub and then the the you know the.
Speaker 0: you don't have a derailleur.
Speaker 0: You know the bike.
Speaker 1: yeah, those are great.
Speaker 1: They're basically zero maintenance, and you get three gears.
Speaker 1: They're great.
Speaker 1: They're like what only there was one with seven years seven.
Speaker 0: Yeah, holy shit, right?
Speaker 0: But anyway this goes back to my news Which is that the at the the something hours of adrenaline solo world?
Speaker 0: Championship is a grueling showcase for the world's toughest bikes and such and such.
Speaker 0: It's in Canada and is dude a 37 year old firefighter right?
Speaker 0: he won the single speed division So basically the fixie division.
Speaker 0: on a bike with no chain.
Speaker 0: it had a belt a car a belt Just like a timing belt in a car a rubber belt, and I didn't even really know that it's like.
Speaker 0: well Why not do that, but so it was like one of those obvious ideas just no one had done until recently.
Speaker 0: And the thing that's interesting about the belt right is that obviously you don't have a derailleur.
Speaker 0: So if you want gears you have to use the.
Speaker 0: you know the planetary in hub system all right and to Know that when you usually ride a bike with you know a chain and gears right there's that catch.
Speaker 0: It's like you'll move the pedals like forward like you know a half a centimeter before the spikes on the gear.
Speaker 0: catch the chain.
Speaker 0: You know that the spike will be in between two links.
Speaker 0: You know so you don't get feedback immediately.
Speaker 0: It yet you have to catch.
Speaker 0: you know of course the thing with that with a with a belt.
Speaker 0: You move the pedal and it immediately starts moving.
Speaker 0: It's like an exercise bike.
Speaker 0: It's like vroom, and it's like whoa.
Speaker 1: but on most bike races especially long distance You're basically gonna work your way up to the high gear and then not come off of it.
Speaker 1: most of the time You're not gonna be changing gears that often.
Speaker 0: well It could be.
Speaker 0: if it's Tour de France and the hilly parts you're gonna be changing the gear.
Speaker 0: yeah If it's the flats you're not changing shit.
Speaker 1: I don't know how much of an impact that would make in the long run.
Speaker 1: it depends on the kind of race I guess.
Speaker 0: yeah, the thing is having gears at all whether they're internal or you know derailleur gears You know there makes a huge fucking difference.
Speaker 0: You know the.
Speaker 0: when they invented the derailleur this lady with three gears beat like the world champions of biking who had one gear.
Speaker 0: You know in this bike race in Italy and that's where they are that's when everyone realized the gears are worthwhile Those people on the big stupid ha ha ha bikes too, and she was on a small bike.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they were on the ha ha ha bikes.
Speaker 1: I think they were on the ha ha bikes.
Speaker 0: the point is is that gears beats no gears, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like a paper-rock-scissors situation.
Speaker 0: these belts are interesting.
Speaker 0: I think that you know in.
Speaker 0: you know it's a long ways out before we see gears.
Speaker 0: You know the belts not the key the belts being for serious.
Speaker 0: But right now it's like you can buy that.
Speaker 0: there's a trek makes a bike called the Soho that has the belt.
Speaker 0: Actually saw it in the store.
Speaker 0: It was pretty interesting, but I would not buy it now.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't bother with it.
Speaker 1: a standard like 21 speed bike is gonna be fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course, but you know I mean bike technology is so good.
Speaker 1: you buy a crapo Huffy.
Speaker 1: It's almost as good as my real mountain bike just as my real mountain bikes like 13 years old.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm done with the mountain bikes now.
Speaker 0: I'm in the city.
Speaker 0: I get a city bike.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm keeping my mountain bike for now, but I might buy a hybrid or a street bike Mmm.
Speaker 1: You're looking at a hybrid.
Speaker 1: I think I'm going straight up street.
Speaker 1: Tiny tiny wheels.
Speaker 0: well see the thing is what I'm looking at is technically not a hybrid.
Speaker 0: right?
Speaker 0: I mean you look the hybrids are like.
Speaker 0: you know when you go to the bike websites if you click hybrid it shows one Kind of bike, but that's not the kind of bike that shows.
Speaker 0: if I click on like city slash commuter It shows a different kind.
Speaker 0: you know it's basically like.
Speaker 0: the bikes I'm looking at are like structured like a mountain bike But they don't have suspensions or anything like that.
Speaker 0: You know at all.
Speaker 1: because you really want a front suspension on any bike.
Speaker 0: no front suspension slows you the hell down Is just annoying.
Speaker 1: front suspension slows you down only a tiny bit But it greatly increases your top speed.
Speaker 1: it makes a lot easier over curbs and traffic and things.
Speaker 0: I'm not interested in a suspension.
Speaker 1: That's a mistake.
Speaker 1: front what you don't want is a middle or rear suspension or a body suspension because those Kill your speed unless you spend crazy money on one of the special ones that has like this vertical stabilizer that Locks it when you're doing the fours and unlocks it when the ground is doing the phone.
Speaker 0: now everything I have checked suggest that a Suspension is no help in the city if you're just on roads all the time if you're on perfectly flat straight roads Which is New York City?
Speaker 0: Anyway the other thing is that they're basically you know they're they're just mountain bikes.
Speaker 0: But they had you know with like.
Speaker 0: you know a whole bunch of gears.
Speaker 0: But the tires are not.
Speaker 0: you know all nubbly mountain bike tires.
Speaker 0: They are you know like.
Speaker 0: you know they're not like they're not.
Speaker 0: they're not the super narrow Tour de France tires You know like honest for a road bike.
Speaker 0: They're a little wider than that.
Speaker 0: They're like 700.
Speaker 0: I think they call them like 700 CC tires.
Speaker 0: You know and they're looking pretty nice.
Speaker 0: I think that's what I need.
Speaker 0: and there's you know every manufacturer has at least one or two bikes in this category.
Speaker 0: So I just got to go.
Speaker 0: see what's out there check the prices See what the shops in town actually have available.
Speaker 1: so I guess my thinking is just that I already have a mountain bike.
Speaker 1: So since that's a specialized tool if I buy another bike and keep the old one I should get one that is specialized for city only Like crazy speed bike the ones that weigh like an ounce and have tiny wheels.
Speaker 1: yeah, I can't deal with a pebble.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the problem.
Speaker 0: is you know you that that's a very all well and good But it's not good for going to work every day.
Speaker 1: I'd probably go because if I go to work I'm just gonna be in the street You know going over the bridge and then going down like I don't know what's what Avenue or Street I'd take to get there to figure that out.
Speaker 1: find a bike lane now.
Speaker 0: You'd be surprised.
Speaker 0: I've been reading like you know people who own like five.
Speaker 0: you know huge bike people.
Speaker 0: I've been reading lots of blogs and reviews, and you don't want to take like a real road bike to work.
Speaker 0: It's not the best idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well the trouble is plus some of the bikes I'm looking at way like fucking nothing.
Speaker 0: I picked.
Speaker 0: I went in the store.
Speaker 0: There was one.
Speaker 0: It was four hundred something dollars.
Speaker 0: I picked it up.
Speaker 0: it weighed like less than half of any bike I've ever ridden in my life, and it was just normal bike.
Speaker 1: It's great when technology advances like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right, so I guess I do have a little bit of news though I actually I had the stupid ustream thing up.
Speaker 1: so now I gotta I gotta find my news again.
Speaker 1: All right, so Felix Ortiz.
Speaker 1: He's a Democrat from Brooklyn.
Speaker 1: now We don't talk about politics on this level that often on geek nights.
Speaker 1: I Thought I should bring this guy up because it's just so crazy Like it's very rare that a politician will surprise me with the level of like craziness that they put forth.
Speaker 1: He is arguing that what we should do is Ban the use of all forms of salt in the preparation and cooking of food in all restaurants and bakeries.
Speaker 0: Wait all salt period.
Speaker 1: now I don't think he was like the size.
Speaker 1: ban what kind of salt.
Speaker 1: I mean?
Speaker 1: our salts of mercury.
Speaker 1: Okay, is it just sodium chloride?
Speaker 1: What about MSG?
Speaker 1: Never mind the fact that he just see you.
Speaker 0: so he wants to use the word salt.
Speaker 1: That's sodium chloride as far as I can tell basically.
Speaker 0: He doesn't realize that.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: Iodized salt is a necessary nutrient to all.
Speaker 1: small iodine is the necessary nutrient.
Speaker 0: yes, and you're gonna get it in salt.
Speaker 1: Are you gonna get a goiter?
Speaker 1: But apparently it's a reaction to this move to.
Speaker 1: you know The fat tax to tax soda and things like that.
Speaker 1: and he was saying let's go one step further.
Speaker 1: salt causes crazy health problems.
Speaker 1: He leaves out the fact in people who eat too much salt.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you need salt.
Speaker 0: the problem is too much of it I think.
Speaker 0: I think that a regulation on like sodium content per you know would be okay if it was a Regulation that was devised by say the FDA or if they did what I mean New York.
Speaker 1: I think it was brilliant.
Speaker 1: We didn't?
Speaker 1: we legislated something that was obvious like trans fat.
Speaker 1: We said all right.
Speaker 1: No fucking trans fat stop it That's fine, but we didn't regulate a lot of other things like calories.
Speaker 1: We didn't say those donuts can't have more than 400 calories.
Speaker 0: said you had to write the number of calories down So I could see how much is in the dough.
Speaker 1: not just write it down You have to put it like right there like next to the price.
Speaker 1: You can't just like hide it like McDonald's used to do and that little pamphlet that no one read.
Speaker 0: I took my parents to the to the Pong Quo Tien where they had all the you know the calories.
Speaker 1: I love that place.
Speaker 0: I said the calories on the menu went there today for the baguette.
Speaker 1: Oh how the baguette.
Speaker 0: they and they saw the calories on the menu right and my mom was like oh my god The sandwich is 600 calories.
Speaker 0: I'm like yeah You see how small that sandwich is you go to eat at a restaurant in Connecticut where they don't list the calories?
Speaker 0: think about how?
Speaker 0: Many that is.
Speaker 0: it's probably like 1500.
Speaker 1: I remember when they when they finally put it in in Starbucks You know like when the grace period my one slice of pizza from the place around the corner from use probably as much calories.
Speaker 0: Is that sandwich?
Speaker 1: I go to stupid Starbucks, and there's this like red velvet cupcakes I used to get every now and then those things like 450 calories.
Speaker 1: It's tiny little cupcake.
Speaker 0: What do you think it's?
Speaker 0: it's just friggin flour and sugar crammed in real tight.
Speaker 0: I still eat like two sometimes and then they use fire and the fire crams the sugar and the flour and even tighter All right, so yeah.
Speaker 1: But I think they should do the same thing.
Speaker 1: if sodium is such a big problem make some law that says you also have To show with certain kinds of food how much sodium is in it.
Speaker 1: That's fun.
Speaker 0: But I think that the you know it would.
Speaker 0: it wouldn't be too bad if the FDA just sort of regulated like okay That is too much salt for that potato chip.
Speaker 0: bring it down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe at least in prepared.
Speaker 0: obviously banning salt is ridiculous.
Speaker 0: It's sort of necessary.
Speaker 1: what I wonder is this guy doing the smart thing like?
Speaker 1: it's hard to tell.
Speaker 1: I never trust Politicians when they make a crazy proposal.
Speaker 0: I could just be trying to get attention.
Speaker 1: is he is he honestly Suggesting that we kill the children of the poor and feed them to the rich?
Speaker 1: Or is he ironically suggesting it to point out the greater injustices.
Speaker 0: I don't know I had to talk to him.
Speaker 0: Why'd you call his office?
Speaker 1: I just don't trust people at all anymore.
Speaker 1: But I mean some foods require salt to make.
Speaker 0: yeah like potato chips or pickles.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you basically be a pickle ban.
Speaker 1: I Just and it's New York.
Speaker 1: There'd be riots.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean how could I like you know cure my hams or any?
Speaker 0: You know I cure hams, but you know You know what I would do.
Speaker 1: I would start selling salt shakers in the street.
Speaker 0: You know what they charge for salt.
Speaker 0: It's like if you want to get the salt shaker from the panko TDN they charge you like we're getting like seven eight bucks.
Speaker 1: Things of the day.
Speaker 1: So you know the exit sign the red exit sign.
Speaker 1: it's everywhere in the world.
Speaker 1: Oh wait wait in the United States not not the whole.
Speaker 1: the whole world doesn't speak English.
Speaker 0: No kidding.
Speaker 1: So in the US we have this exit sign for many of our listeners might not be aware of this.
Speaker 1: It's a red sign that says exit, and it's all.
Speaker 0: no It's a white sign has the word exit in red letters, and it's usually lit up with a light bulb.
Speaker 1: so oftentimes It's a black sign with the word exit.
Speaker 0: I've never seen that Often okay.
Speaker 1: anyway it says exit, and it's lit up, and there's laws about.
Speaker 1: you have to have these things.
Speaker 1: They have to be lit up.
Speaker 1: They have to tell people where the exits are because back in the day without those signs Building catches fire.
Speaker 1: everyone just died.
Speaker 1: they didn't know how to get out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: well I mean you know.
Speaker 0: let's say I'm in a building right.
Speaker 0: I mean if I'm familiar with the building and I need to get out right.
Speaker 0: It's like think about this.
Speaker 0: I've used the elevator all the time, but in a fire I can't use the elevator.
Speaker 0: so I stand up and I say I got to get the hell out of here.
Speaker 0: So I gotta look where's the nearest exit.
Speaker 0: so I've never used the stairwell.
Speaker 0: I mean I'm on the seventh floor.
Speaker 0: I don't use the stairwell in my office building.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: we even know where it is.
Speaker 0: so I'm gonna look for one of those red exit signs to figure out where the hell to get that hell out and if I That sign isn't there my exit will be much delayed.
Speaker 0: Well, that's also why if I imagine if I'm in an unfamiliar building like I'm go for a meeting in some building I'm a job interview.
Speaker 1: I don't know where the hell the eggs It is how many people I run into just going to work or in Grand Central like in the lower floor like the main and Just can't figure out how to get outside.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I took a whole class on this at RIT on like haptic design and you just interface design and all that.
Speaker 1: and then this Great example of a serious problem.
Speaker 1: if you have a stairwell and people are evacuating in an emergency They tend to just go all the way to the basement.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: They don't even think to stop at the ground floor.
Speaker 1: so a lot of places mandate putting a physical divider just Forcing you to stop and before you go into the basement say do I really want to go down one more flight?
Speaker 0: in the building That I live in the stairwell to the basement is actually a separate stairwell from the other stairwell.
Speaker 1: Man, you might be fucked if you don't realize you're on the ground floor and you run into that one.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: you run into that want to go down to the basement.
Speaker 1: there's no other way out.
Speaker 0: It's kind of hard because in order to get into the place where you enter to the basement stairwell from the first floor is Right near.
Speaker 0: you can see outside from there and if you're in the basement, you can also get outside from the basement.
Speaker 0: So it's actually you know, it's not the worst idea.
Speaker 1: my building, you know both my company.
Speaker 1: We have these disaster kits in case you know, there's ever a serious problem.
Speaker 1: Mmm, especially, you know, I didn't work there when this happened.
Speaker 1: remember the steam pipe explosion.
Speaker 1: Yep, that was outside the window of my office.
Speaker 1: All right, and from what old co-workers tell me Basically, one guy said the power flickered.
Speaker 1: What was that noise?
Speaker 1: Someone else says yeah There's smoke coming out of Grand Central and two seconds later.
Speaker 1: Everyone's gone.
Speaker 1: But we have like a repelling kit to get out of the building.
Speaker 0: now I would just use it for fun.
Speaker 1: We also have I have a written air supply.
Speaker 1: I have like a 20 minute supply of oxygen.
Speaker 0: that's very necessary under my desk.
Speaker 1: I can pull the button and wait.
Speaker 0: everyone has one under their desk.
Speaker 1: Well all the important employees do.
Speaker 1: I don't have one.
Speaker 1: You should tell your company you need a disaster kit.
Speaker 1: It is a flashlight.
Speaker 1: It has a rape whistle.
Speaker 1: It has all.
Speaker 0: what do you need a rape whistle for in case?
Speaker 1: I like the building collapses on me.
Speaker 1: I can be like help tweet tweet tweet.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not a bad idea But an air horn be better because then what if you couldn't?
Speaker 0: you know, you're having trouble whistling.
Speaker 0: you could just be like.
Speaker 1: I also have this this light.
Speaker 1: I can clip to myself that it's the craziest LED light I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 1: it is painful to look at.
Speaker 1: Mmm, I kind of want to use it just as a flashlight But I don't want to not have it if the building ever catches fire.
Speaker 0: That's all high quality stuff.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll get my own kit and just put it in my desk Yeah And then take it to every office.
Speaker 1: the coolest part is the way the gas mask works because they're like don't open it It'll ruin it.
Speaker 1: you rip it open and it activates.
Speaker 1: Yep, automatically and you stick it on your face and you've got like 20 or 30 minutes of oxygen But one where the gas mask probably expensive but a whistle and a light bulb became yeah.
Speaker 0: But the guys are telling kids probably also expensive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, only a few people have those and They're trained in its use to get everyone else down because they decided they don't want everyone to have one.
Speaker 1: in case Someone wants to quit the company an epic epic glory by repelling down the side of the building repelling down the store down the building fingers held high Tempted to do that.
Speaker 0: I would repel out the building and put graffiti on the side.
Speaker 0: Actually my you know, but my office, you know does have openable windows and it's like eight stories down.
Speaker 0: or repelling kit actually be pretty useful.
Speaker 0: It's a big window.
Speaker 0: I could get out it pretty easy.
Speaker 1: So what does the rest of the world use for exit signs?
Speaker 1: because much of the world does not have our fancy word exit.
Speaker 1: I mean our word is pretty good.
Speaker 1: I don't know what words you have elsewhere.
Speaker 1: I mean Sally dot whatever.
Speaker 1: that's way too long.
Speaker 1: So it turns out there is in fact an international standard.
Speaker 1: the entire freaking world uses the standard Except us like the metric system.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Screw you world.
Speaker 1: So the rest of the world has this picture of a green guy running out of door.
Speaker 1: Yep, it was designed by some Japanese Yukio OTA and Kind of recently like in the 80s.
Speaker 0: I think actually there's a new rule though Every like door to a stairwell in New York City has to have exit on it and they put the green man on a lot Of those.
Speaker 1: yeah, the green man is starting to crop up in major cities, but nowhere else.
Speaker 1: Yeah There's apparently a big fight between the Soviets and the Japanese over two slightly different.
Speaker 1: Basically, the Soviets were like your designs.
Speaker 1: Okay, but doesn't actually show a door.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna make one with a door and the Japanese.
Speaker 0: well I think what it was that they both simultaneously and separately designed really similar things and then well and then everyone was like.
Speaker 0: well Two people came up with this so it's a similar design.
Speaker 0: Obviously, they're on the right track.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they quibbled over details for a while.
Speaker 1: But my building has both.
Speaker 1: it is the exit signs and has a little green guy on the stairwells Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yep The green guy in the stairwells is coming really common in the u.s.
Speaker 0: But in New York City.
Speaker 1: the story behind this is just really interesting and my thing of the day It's just this just long article talking all about it and the people involved and the arguments and all the examples of it.
Speaker 1: It's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So my thing today is man packs Scott's man pack, right?
Speaker 0: So at you might know about Amazon subscription service, right and the way the Amazon subscription service works is let's say you know That you use right one roll of toilet paper every week Which means you use three or four rolls a month, which means you need 12 rolls every three months.
Speaker 0: You go to Amazon and you say hey Amazon send me 12 rolls every three months and they'll just send you 12 rolls every three months forever and keep charging you for it and You'll get a substantial discount.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you have to figure out your burn rate and be accurate.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, you know and they even have like a little system to help you figure out your burn rate and such.
Speaker 1: So how much do you poop?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you can you know, it's not just toilet paper You can use it for like, you know, pretty much anything they sell which is a large variety of non-perishable.
Speaker 0: You know, I just pick groceries type goods.
Speaker 1: I just I this vague image of some fairly wealthy trust fund kid who has an iPod subscription.
Speaker 0: But anyway, man packs calm is a similar thing You know you basically subscribe to man packs to socks underwear and under shirts and it's the cheapest plan is like $7 a month, but for just socks and they'll send you three pairs of socks Every three months.
Speaker 1: the coolest part of it.
Speaker 1: I was reading like the rationale behind it and the idea was Guys don't ever replace underwear and socks until they're forced to.
Speaker 0: and you were.
Speaker 0: I see I do it all at once Right, but if you do this You'll slide you'll always be slightly cycling in out with the old out oldest and in with the newest all the time.
Speaker 0: So you'll always have some new some medium and you'll never have some old old nasties because you'll get rid of them like like my loincloth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly, right.
Speaker 0: But what I've been doing is I basically everything's new everything's medium that everything's old that everything's new But you hold out with the old forever, right?
Speaker 0: But there's a situation where you're like everything is old and that's not a good situation to be in.
Speaker 0: You know, like what?
Speaker 0: if I have to do something fancy?
Speaker 0: I don't have any new Just fancy underwear party.
Speaker 1: well, no, you know socks or whatever, you know Party, I have white crappy socks that I wear under boots and things and then I have nice black socks that I wear.
Speaker 0: The point is like the price of this is actually ridiculously cheap.
Speaker 0: Look $33.
Speaker 1: Here's my question.
Speaker 1: How nice are these underwear and socks?
Speaker 1: You can shoot they're all like Hanes like I can't wear white socks.
Speaker 0: Well, no, they have choices of different colors and everything but it's like it's all Hanes stuff.
Speaker 0: It's all.
Speaker 0: it's all the same stuff.
Speaker 0: I would buy in the store, right?
Speaker 0: No different and You know, you just choose exactly what you want.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everything is Hanes and they have every different Hane variety of sock, you know standard sock under shirt underwear.
Speaker 0: You give you a wife beaters or whatever, but but what about my silica boxers?
Speaker 1: Can I get silk ones?
Speaker 0: let's see because they have a Classic woven but no only woven.
Speaker 0: they don't have silk.
Speaker 1: Granted, I don't know if silk is.
Speaker 1: I used to wear silk boxers like in middle in high school.
Speaker 1: I like eight pairs of silk boxers.
Speaker 1: I rotated through them every day and I washed him by hand because they were delicate.
Speaker 1: They were the best things ever Unless you sweated because then silk turns from the most wonderful fabric in the world into very finely ground sandpaper.
Speaker 0: So you can get like.
Speaker 0: the biggest pack they offer is the macho pack thirty three dollars every three months.
Speaker 0: So eleven dollars a month gets you three underwear three shirts and three socks.
Speaker 1: That's not bad.
Speaker 0: So just you know every.
Speaker 0: you know, three months you just get three more of everything and you get rid of the oldest three and you got to figure out the number you need total and You're set.
Speaker 1: that's really not bad at all.
Speaker 0: It's not a bad price considering, you know, what those things usually cost.
Speaker 0: so Pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: I know that they're marketing this only to man.
Speaker 1: I wonder I want to ask the listeners Is it just guys who will never throw away underwear and then be forced to by circumstance by the fact that half my underwear ended?
Speaker 1: Up being literally nothing more than sideways loincloths?
Speaker 0: I have a feeling that ladies will buy and are more likely to buy new underwear when their underwear is no good.
Speaker 1: Emily saying no.
Speaker 1: So that's hopefully.
Speaker 0: ladies need a greater quantity of underwear.
Speaker 1: When?
Speaker 1: now how could you say that they knew you?
Speaker 1: do you wear a pair of underwear more than one day?
Speaker 0: ladies by default if they have boobs need twice as much underwear, well Guys need unless they have some sort of one-piece underwear.
Speaker 0: I've never seen that so I'll say this.
Speaker 1: I don't consider t-shirts underwear.
Speaker 1: There's something different because I don't wear teeth like look, right?
Speaker 0: That's exactly what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: is that a bra is underwear there and a t-shirt is not.
Speaker 1: therefore But why I need twice as much underwear, what about a bros ear a man's ear a bro?
Speaker 0: Do you wear a bro?
Speaker 0: No, then why didn't?
Speaker 0: you're wearing half as much underwear?
Speaker 1: What about a really tight t-shirt?
Speaker 1: Isn't that just a sports bra?
Speaker 0: No Are you wearing it under?
Speaker 1: I mean luckily I get away with this and I look.
Speaker 1: I got like the blazer on right and I Got the dress shirt.
Speaker 1: Look no undershirt.
Speaker 0: Isn't it warm?
Speaker 0: still wearing the blazer while sitting usually take it off when you sit.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of used to it.
Speaker 1: Okay, but I wear these things every stupid day.
Speaker 1: Actually, this one's due for a dry cleaning.
Speaker 0: My thing of the day is done if you need underwear sign up and you're a man and you have a you can Woman who wears man's underwear.
Speaker 1: What about a man who wears women's underwear?
Speaker 0: This is not the site for you.
Speaker 1: So Avatar we went.
Speaker 1: we went and seen a movie that wasn't an anime wasn't an indie film wasn't in some weird theater.
Speaker 1: We went to see a normal mainstream movie.
Speaker 0: We only way late after it had been out forever.
Speaker 1: It was freaking sold out.
Speaker 1: every time I tried to say well cuz you kept trying to see in fancy 3d Cuz in the city, I didn't want to not see it in 3d.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean think about it.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of cities where you you couldn't see it in 3d.
Speaker 1: That's true Yeah, but the thing I was most surprised about was that instead of being about Aang and his adventures it was these blue people.
Speaker 0: I Also was very much confused, you know, not you know When all these talk of Avatar movies like what was what was what?
Speaker 0: but now I have it.
Speaker 1: now I have it sorted because I had that at first, you know I didn't.
Speaker 1: I don't pay attention to movie news.
Speaker 1: So I like to avatar the show and then people were like.
Speaker 0: I knew that.
Speaker 0: I knew there was a show named avatar.
Speaker 1: People were like avatar movie and I was like bald kid avatar.
Speaker 1: All right, then they're like James Cameron and I was like James Cameron's making an avatar.
Speaker 0: I didn't even know who James Cameron was really.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Wow people are like, but you know people were like, oh my god This movie is so popular.
Speaker 0: I'm like the movie of the cartoon that that rim likes is So popular it's taken over the world but way later I'm like I knew all right.
Speaker 0: So does it make that?
Speaker 1: there are two movies called avatar and then recently I realized they changed the name of the bald kid movie To the last airbender.
Speaker 0: That's a good move.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think.
Speaker 1: but now there's memorial.
Speaker 1: She also making a movie called avatar.
Speaker 0: That's an old movie.
Speaker 0: That sucks.
Speaker 1: Oh, I thought it was a new movie.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Oh awesome You know the one that you know, the one that we saw the the the it was like sweet is Swedish or whatever Austrian.
Speaker 0: what country did he make it in?
Speaker 1: Oh, but wasn't that called?
Speaker 0: What was it called?
Speaker 1: It was called something else And it sucked.
Speaker 0: it did.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry tomorrow.
Speaker 1: she I like your animes I don't like your real movies.
Speaker 0: Avalon I was close.
Speaker 0: a V began with.
Speaker 0: it was mama Roshi.
Speaker 0: You can't blame me for getting that one wrong.
Speaker 1: that movie was awesome And then it sucked and then it was awesome again for like five minutes and then it sucked and then it sucked if they just left Off that last twist.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So mama Roshi's Avalon is bad.
Speaker 0: Is he so?
Speaker 0: is he really making a new movie avatar?
Speaker 1: I heard something weird about that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so all that aside I Figured out that there was a difference between these two movies.
Speaker 1: a long time ago.
Speaker 1: I was on the train shortly before we moved to the city and this cool guy saw me watching bald kid avatar on the train On my laptop because I fucking love it and he's like, oh I have a tar.
Speaker 1: my kids were watching it But then it was actually awesome.
Speaker 1: So I watched it too.
Speaker 1: Isn't it?
Speaker 1: Awesome Funny how adults like us like it and we were talking about it and then as I'm leaving the train he's like, oh, yeah But did you see that?
Speaker 1: You know, they're making a movie about it, but it's all like weird and everybody's blue.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the fuck's going on with that and that I never saw the guy again So you couldn't.
Speaker 0: I'm sure he's figured out by now as we have either that he had the same confusion he had.
Speaker 1: Yeah He's not.
Speaker 0: he's not a stupid person.
Speaker 0: We're talking about.
Speaker 0: we're stupid.
Speaker 1: We're talking about blue people.
Speaker 0: 3d James Cameron Yep, so I pretty much knew what to expect based on internet rumblings.
Speaker 0: You know some sort of you know tree huggin type movie with a fern gully kind of plot But also but also robots in action and 3d and crazy special effects.
Speaker 0: Here's what I saw in dollars of Hollywood production one James Cameron.
Speaker 1: So I had a certain expectation already.
Speaker 1: that didn't give me an expectation because they mean anything to me But - I saw the internet hate machine Mobilized immediately on this movie and I don't know I mean a lot of our listeners are younger.
Speaker 1: But we were kind of like in the movie going like on our own.
Speaker 1: like I will go to the theater on my own As a kid when Titanic came out and never.
Speaker 0: I still never seen that movie.
Speaker 1: really Yeah, you know the Titanic and Avatar in the internet hate machine or back then it was pre before the internet hate machine existed.
Speaker 1: It was just the pop culture hate machine.
Speaker 1: The movies were crazy popular right away and just had like they were.
Speaker 1: just they kept Generating crazy revenues every weekend like every theater just had the movie going and going and going.
Speaker 0: That was Jurassic Park.
Speaker 1: Yeah dress is in the theater for years, but Titanic and Avatar almost immediately Had this weird like reactionary situation where it was cool to be like.
Speaker 1: yeah Titanic fuck that movie.
Speaker 1: that movie sucked ass and you know what?
Speaker 1: It wasn't the greatest movie in the world, but it wasn't really a bad movie.
Speaker 1: It was a solid movie But because it was so popular like the more popular it got the more popular it was.
Speaker 1: To talk about how it was stupid that it was popular and how everyone who likes it sucks in the movie stupid.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen that much hate for Avatar.
Speaker 0: I've just seen normal rumblings, but it's been a larger rumbling.
Speaker 0: But it's you know.
Speaker 0: But the thing is that phenomenon you just described.
Speaker 0: I've seen it myself on.
Speaker 0: We were at work and we saw some ads on the internet for Celine Dion stuff something something and I was like What the hell like.
Speaker 0: I don't really know who it is.
Speaker 0: I know it's some seeing lady.
Speaker 0: Everyone makes fun of.
Speaker 0: that's pretty much all I know right, so I'm like doesn't everyone make fun of this lady?
Speaker 0: How is she making money?
Speaker 0: Why is there advertisements?
Speaker 0: who?
Speaker 0: and the advertisement was serious?
Speaker 0: It was like come see her.
Speaker 0: and I was like if it seems like the whole world hates this lady nope She's one of those popular entertainers ever right?
Speaker 0: so if she's so popular right then what do all these crazy fans if she has so Many fans?
Speaker 0: what are those fans think when they see this huge hate machine against this person who I don't even I don't even know Any you know song she sings, so I don't even know like her or not.
Speaker 0: yeah But the point is is I was I knew that it was someone that was made fun of and it's like.
Speaker 0: There's like.
Speaker 0: there are these huge hate machines for popular things that sort of defy the popularity of those things And the people who it's like it's.
Speaker 0: I think what the the symptom is is that you have something that is genuinely popular.
Speaker 0: But it's popular among people who are not vocal and loud in Proclaiming their fandom.
Speaker 0: well.
Speaker 1: I think it's people who aren't necessarily cinema fans.
Speaker 1: They are just fans of that movie like oh that movie was cool.
Speaker 1: I liked it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're not gonna be like writing a review on the internet like Harry Potter fans.
Speaker 0: Harry Potter fans are loud.
Speaker 0: They write fanfiction they dress up like Harry Potter.
Speaker 0: They wait in line.
Speaker 0: They're loud fans.
Speaker 0: right fans of Celine Dion are not loud.
Speaker 0: You know maybe at the concerts.
Speaker 0: They're loud, but in public.
Speaker 0: They're not loud.
Speaker 0: They're not proclaiming, and you know I don't know.
Speaker 0: are there Celine Dion fanfictions?
Speaker 1: Well the same thing with anime.
Speaker 1: I mean anime fandom.
Speaker 1: like anime fans are real loud about like.
Speaker 0: yeah Maybe just because of where we are we hear different loudnesses, but because we are we are not paying it.
Speaker 0: If there was a Celine Dion loudness we would not be in a position to hear it.
Speaker 1: But it like the seriously look at I mean the situation with trying to have a really good example of this now.
Speaker 1: Well regardless.
Speaker 1: so the complaints I saw primarily about avatar were that one people would say things like oh It's just a fern golly ripoff which was kind of true.
Speaker 1: It was true, but only on like the most superficial surface level.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was also about you know tree hugging That's pretty much the only thing that has a common.
Speaker 0: or a lot of people would say it was the noble savage blah Just like and immediately dismiss the movie on that alone, but when you look at me But I mean you know that's a silly argument to make because you know there are only eight stories.
Speaker 0: How many stories is it you know?
Speaker 1: What's that like the hero comes or right?
Speaker 1: yeah stranger comes to town someone goes out of right?
Speaker 0: So there's only X number of different stories to tell.
Speaker 0: see.
Speaker 0: so any movie that comes out is gonna be one of those.
Speaker 0: that's like Saying oh, that's that one therefore.
Speaker 0: It sucks.
Speaker 0: Well then everything sucks.
Speaker 1: Their complaint wasn't really that valid in the movie because the movie was kind of yeah They're noble savages that are actually right about something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, kinda at least within the context of the movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, yeah Not the broader picture, but it's not like Dances with Wolves where well actually it was a lot like Dances with Wolves except the ghost Dance kind of work.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 0: I never saw Dances with Wolves anything really.
Speaker 0: I know it exists though And I know what it is.
Speaker 1: movies are very similar.
Speaker 1: It's a good movie.
Speaker 0: anyway I only have I don't know how many complaints I have but very few.
Speaker 0: complaint number one that I had with the movie is that the Part where he was sort of like learning to become a foresty person.
Speaker 0: you know the montage.
Speaker 0: ish It was like it was gonna be a montage.
Speaker 0: I don't really want to call it a montage because a montage has like more.
Speaker 0: cutting is like.
Speaker 0: you know Rocky is a montage the quick cutting between different training things.
Speaker 0: right this was slower like you know.
Speaker 0: They showed a scene learning to get on the horse and they actually showed a scene learning to get on the dragon.
Speaker 0: But then they went further learning to fall out of the tree and these are actually meaningful scenes.
Speaker 0: It wasn't a quick cutting montage.
Speaker 0: It was like a slow building montage And I think my complaint with it is that as a result it felt like that part.
Speaker 0: I didn't actually time how long that was but it felt long to me.
Speaker 0: So it felt like the large portion of the movie like I literally felt like I spent 15 minutes Sitting there watching nothing happen, and I would have been happier with an actual quick cutting montage.
Speaker 1: No now here's where I would make the opposite argument.
Speaker 0: at the same time every single one of those scenes did come into play later.
Speaker 0: You know they called back to them at some point later in the movie.
Speaker 1: well see I'm gonna make the oshi argument.
Speaker 1: think about Skycrawlers.
Speaker 1: the movie was in many ways Interminable, but it was a brilliant movie And it did a meta thing of like making certain scenes last a very long time and making certain aesthetics Just kind of repeat and repeat to put you into a mindset to then kind of experience.
Speaker 1: What's going on in the movie?
Speaker 1: Yeah, what did this movie do I mean?
Speaker 1: there's.
Speaker 1: the whole story is that the crippled marine has these two completely separate lives now with two completely separate bodies and During that whole sequence it keeps immersing you like long Physical time in that world toward that world and that reality of him is more real.
Speaker 1: And it's really jarring every time he wakes up in the real world.
Speaker 0: Oh the movie death.
Speaker 0: that was like one of the best things the movie did.
Speaker 0: period but you know it just felt to me.
Speaker 0: You know the.
Speaker 0: the side effect of that which was negative was that a large portion of the movie it felt like nothing happened.
Speaker 1: See to me it didn't it base to me.
Speaker 0: it felt like and I was like all right come on Let's get a move on.
Speaker 1: it felt like I became immersed in kind of just the subtle reality did.
Speaker 0: yes That is true, but as a side effect nothing happened for a long time.
Speaker 0: so while I was being a murder forget.
Speaker 0: But I would have liked to have been immersed while something was happening, but stuff was happening.
Speaker 1: He was becoming one of them basically which is basically nothing happening.
Speaker 1: the plot He was not progressing in any way, but that's the point by not progressing the plot.
Speaker 1: It makes you forget about the plot.
Speaker 0: It's the same, but I didn't forget about the plot.
Speaker 0: I was thinking about the plot, and I was simultaneously being immersed in a world good and being bored bad.
Speaker 1: See I think what it was supposed to do And I think I think it did it very well Was that it?
Speaker 1: the?
Speaker 1: the plot is in the back of your mind and every time you think about the real world you were like Every time he wakes up.
Speaker 1: There's the little like jolts between these long immersive scenes you're reminded.
Speaker 1: Oh shit Yeah, this is gonna get real bad real quick.
Speaker 0: I'm not disagreeing with you.
Speaker 0: that part was awesome.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying that did not distract me or pull me out of the movie at all And I didn't pull me out of the movie.
Speaker 0: the side effect of the fact that they did that Was that there was a stretch of nothing happened except.
Speaker 1: I think we're happening.
Speaker 0: No Nothing is that and it wasn't boring at all to me.
Speaker 0: felt to me that there were like 15 or 20 minutes where nothing happened.
Speaker 0: And second night my second complaint.
Speaker 1: I just I disagree with that whatever my second, but I do disagree with that I'm telling you.
Speaker 0: That's what I felt so you can't tell me that I was not.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying that I did not feel that at all.
Speaker 0: I was bored for a long stretch in the in the in the sort of after the beginning.
Speaker 1: I was bored for a long stretch until the middle at least as you point out the fact that Every single moment of that whole bit in the middle mattered.
Speaker 0: it did, but it was.
Speaker 0: you know that it was too.
Speaker 0: It felt too long.
Speaker 0: I don't know how long it actually was about.
Speaker 0: if I rewatch it and time it that will probably be like five minutes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think had you made felt had he made it shorter.
Speaker 1: It would have lost the the oceania, but he could have done.
Speaker 0: I'm saying he doesn't had to keep it shorter.
Speaker 0: He could have just done something else besides training in there You know had a side story or something and that would have you know preventing me from being bored and had the same effect.
Speaker 1: Well, they're kind of like three.
Speaker 0: That brings me to my next point which I think the other criticism had the movie is that the plot was incredibly simple.
Speaker 0: It was not that is flex or intellectually challenging and or or unpredictable in any way whatsoever.
Speaker 1: It was a little.
Speaker 1: we're not gonna spoil.
Speaker 0: It was a tiny bit Ridiculous.
Speaker 1: all right guys Within the next few minutes.
Speaker 1: We're probably gonna accidentally spoil stuff.
Speaker 1: So if you haven't seen the movie and you care just stop listening right about now.
Speaker 0: It's really it's hard to spoil.
Speaker 0: is the point?
Speaker 1: yeah, but we're gonna spoil.
Speaker 0: is it's so simple?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: but the only thing about that that really bothered me was that the marine like the bad marine guy.
Speaker 1: His character was okay because I could see someone being that way like it worked, but he was respected.
Speaker 1: But the stupid suit guy was just a shit.
Speaker 0: care dad They have those care.
Speaker 0: that character is so common and so many freaking you know movies.
Speaker 1: No look at him.
Speaker 1: He was a lot like the guy in district 9 except.
Speaker 1: They didn't do it.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: It was just.
Speaker 1: he was just shitty.
Speaker 0: There's always that guy who's the boss who's just like incompetent and jerky you know and only and it's like get you know I've seen that character too many times.
Speaker 0: get him the hell out of my face.
Speaker 0: now Look at like.
Speaker 0: Die Hard is a great example right?
Speaker 0: look at Die Hard.
Speaker 0: the boss of the the office in Die Hard You know is basically just like that you know, but the terrorist and Die Hard is like you know.
Speaker 0: He's smart you can you can you know give him your respects, but here's the kind of bad guy I mean.
Speaker 1: here's what they could have done that would have fixed that character for me 100% because he was you know that kind of Corporate jackass right yeah, imagine if at the you know he was like yeah, just do it just do it Just do it.
Speaker 1: when things fell apart and the military guys were like let's just murder all those people We'll deal with it blah blah blah, and he was like yeah sure go for it.
Speaker 1: If he had at that point been like whoa this is way too far.
Speaker 1: And then like there'd been a little plot about that that could have made the character more interesting if he'd been a corporate shill.
Speaker 1: But then when it really Seriously is bad.
Speaker 0: Well there was the one part right where they went up to him And they were like look you were going to kill babies.
Speaker 0: Do you want this blood on your hands?
Speaker 0: He was like all right fine.
Speaker 0: You got one shot.
Speaker 0: Let's go.
Speaker 0: So they yeah, they showed that this guy was not just you know the stereotypical retarded boss guy character.
Speaker 0: But they didn't use.
Speaker 0: but then they didn't use it.
Speaker 0: and then you know at the end of the movie He's like just frowning like oh, that's like well What do you?
Speaker 1: they really?
Speaker 1: they could have made a subtle change that part of the story and had him just at some moment be?
Speaker 1: Like this has gone too far and suddenly his character is a good character But instead it was just kind of a crap character that was actually distracting from the movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and two I would have rather there not have been a way to transfer him for real.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was that not been there?
Speaker 0: Well, it was so obvious when they tried it the first time yes that I was like oh well now I know the end of the movie.
Speaker 0: Thanks,
Speaker 1: but here two things Making it there like had it been there in the first part and failed if the end of the movie would have been He does some sort of sacrifice that will prevent him from doing that joining and like he knows that he cannot Do that and he gives that up to save them.
Speaker 1: that could have been more powerful Or if they hadn't had that at all and he sacrificed himself and all those people sacrifice themselves knowing that they could not ever Like.
Speaker 1: they basically were all going to die and they did it anyway.
Speaker 1: That also would have been a better ending.
Speaker 1: the fact that he had the option and that he was able to pull it off I thought was a little bit of a cop-out.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean the thing is you notice how the movie You know the people Who they either killed or made it appear that people were killed when they no longer needed the character in the story And then at the end they just any character that had died off-screen or you weren't sure was dead.
Speaker 0: They you know could bring back so they were able to choose who is dead and who is alive But they were able to just remove people they no longer wanted to show in the movie towards the end When they wanted to concentrate on the main characters They just took everyone else out of the picture who they didn't want around anymore.
Speaker 1: However, also all that aside the movie as it was While it was predictable to a degree I pretty much had even odds on him baking it or not.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean toward the you know, the exact specifics of what went down at the end.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I actually came up with some like better ways to do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the thing is my better ways are better in terms of like oh Well, it would have been a moral quandary or you know, it would have been a you know, something something.
Speaker 0: But it probably would not have been better in terms of making mad money.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: the way the movie is is probably the way it is and Resulted in its incredible box-office success.
Speaker 0: and if you know any of these slight Improvements like making the plot more intelligent or more complex or more morally challenging probably would have heard it in the box office.
Speaker 0: Well at the same at the same time is why I'm not in charge of those things.
Speaker 1: There's a problem that I've fallen forward before and I think a lot of people who are into cinema or into these sorts of things Or look at movies with more intellectual event You sort of get into this trap to where you always want the sad ending because the bad ending is more true or more likely Or more realistic or more interesting.
Speaker 0: I don't necessarily need a sad ending.
Speaker 0: I just need a more Unexpected and interesting ending.
Speaker 0: if I can, you know, I mean you need to have foreshadowing, you know Chekhov's gun.
Speaker 0: isn't this necessary?
Speaker 0: because if you don't have any foreshadowing there are like 10 Chekhov's guns Thousand Chekhov's penises, right?
Speaker 1: If you don't have however I did not.
Speaker 1: there was a non Chekhov gun.
Speaker 1: when that when they he runs off near in the middle like Toward the end to like do his thing in The like.
Speaker 1: they all escaped from prison and the marine guys like you assholes and just runs outside with a gun.
Speaker 0: One of the most obvious Chekhov's guns was the falling down a great distance But using the giant tree leaves to slow the descent and survive.
Speaker 0: but that was well done.
Speaker 0: right now The thing is right.
Speaker 0: that is necessary because they just showed him doing that without you know, showing you him practicing that.
Speaker 0: It's like oh give me a fucking break, right?
Speaker 0: What the fuck is this shit?
Speaker 1: Especially because they showed him sucking at it the first time.
Speaker 0: he had to do right exactly.
Speaker 0: So by you know by doing the Chekhov.
Speaker 0: it becomes believable when he does it for real, right?
Speaker 0: It's like aha I see what you did there But at the same time if you have too much Chekhov in the plot department Then it's like I know exactly what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: Why don't you just leave now?
Speaker 0: I could tell you the ending.
Speaker 0: What's the point to agree to do you?
Speaker 0: what you need to do right is the correct technique is to bring out Chekhov's gun And then right after you bring it out Another Chekhov's gun mixes with the first one in a way you didn't see coming because you can see Individual guns.
Speaker 0: you can't see two guns pointed at each other from a great distance.
Speaker 0: So that is the trick, you know It's.
Speaker 1: you know what that is.
Speaker 1: You don't you know what that is.
Speaker 1: That is the openers to Gundam seed.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, it's snatch right in snatch.
Speaker 0: It's like I see this is going this way.
Speaker 0: I see this is going that way But then two people open a door and they're standing in the hallway facing each other and it's like oh fuck, you know You silly fat bastard pull your socks up, right?
Speaker 0: So that's right.
Speaker 0: So that is the right way To do things in the book of Scott.
Speaker 1: the other way to do it and I've seen this done to great effect is to have the Chekhov's gun be so prominent and so Scooby-doo and Then just have nothing happen with it until everyone forgets it's there exact The comedian.
Speaker 0: you gotta have a comedian.
Speaker 0: figure that out for you because the comedian will tell the jokes early in the routine and at The very end the last line will be a callback to that earlier joke that you forgot about.
Speaker 1: Bill Cosby was the fucking master.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so many people are the master that you know, but you need to have a comedian.
Speaker 0: get that timing for you on that one.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, it doesn't work like Emily and I a while ago went to see who's afraid of Virginia wolf.
Speaker 1: It's a great play and there's I'm not gonna spoil it, but there's that Gigantic gun like over the fireplace and you just know someone's gay It's the.
Speaker 0: it's the guy dressed all in white who stands there not doing anything.
Speaker 0: You know, he's gonna do the crazy kung-fu, you know, but I'm looking at the gun.
Speaker 1: I'm like, that's the Chekhov's gun That's the Chekhov's gun.
Speaker 1: That's the Chekhov's gun.
Speaker 1: That's the chicken, but I totally didn't say it coming when the Chekhov's gun Chekhov Then he did it, right?
Speaker 0: That's the way it goes.
Speaker 0: But I only other thing I had to say about the movie is the three d-ness Right is I'm torn on the use of the three d-ness in this movie in
Speaker 1: half the scenes like it was Brilliant and in half the scenes it kind of stood out is like this is more 3d than it needs to be like it's kind Of silly 3d right.
Speaker 0: and then in other scenes it was like this scene.
Speaker 0: really the 3d isn't doing anything for this scene So why even have it?
Speaker 1: but at the same time if you're making a movie 3d just in general You don't want to just turn off the 3d whenever you're not gonna do something clever.
Speaker 0: Well, actually I peeked under my glasses at some points and you could see that some parts of the screen Were 3d in.
Speaker 0: some parts weren't you know?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Another thing is that the 3d technology is it's it's pretty good But it's not a hundred percent of the way there.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it still looks like, you know Multiple 2d things just at different set depths.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, it looks like two pieces of paper moving in front of each other so like South Park a little bit.
Speaker 0: and The other thing is that You know the 3d only really stands out right like when you go to Disney World and you go watch honey I shrunk the audience, right?
Speaker 0: It's like they fucking three because it's always like the needle in your eye like Now.
Speaker 0: doing it so much like that is obviously Distracting and unsettling and annoying and you want to be very light with it and subtle right to make it good for an extended Two hour frickin movie.
Speaker 0: You can't be doing honey.
Speaker 0: I shrunk the audience.
Speaker 0: or Muppet 3d or Michael Jackson 3d But at the same time if you're not really getting up in the face at all or enough, it's not really 3d ing You got to do it.
Speaker 0: I think a little bit more of it would have been appropriate but not too much more.
Speaker 1: Imagine a future where more movies are 3d.
Speaker 1: a lot of movies will have just like subtle Atmospheric 3d effects that are just enhancing without making them like integral to what you're watching.
Speaker 0: I think the one thing that's missing from 3d movies right now, right that I think could actually make you know Me say this movie's got to be fucking 3d.
Speaker 0: 3d is just better than 2d.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to use 2d.
Speaker 0: Is we need something from the back right?
Speaker 0: you think about watching Star Wars.
Speaker 0: What is the first thing you see in Star Wars?
Speaker 0: It's a super stardestroyer coming from over the top.
Speaker 0: well, just regular stardestroyer coming from over the top behind you down to the front right and They get the surround sound.
Speaker 0: they figured that out.
Speaker 0: you hear it coming from behind and you see it coming down from the top.
Speaker 1: Some of the directors control to force you like.
Speaker 1: this is the only screen you can see.
Speaker 0: I'm saying if I go to see Star Wars in 3d if a soup if the stardestroyer comes from the back of my head and comes down Over the front and I see it coming from behind if I look up and see the bottom of it on top of me.
Speaker 0: That is fucking 3d.
Speaker 0: That's possible right like you look and it is in the fucking movie theater right above Everybody going forward and not just coming down from the top of the screen.
Speaker 0: That is what we need for 3d movies possible.
Speaker 1: But that was one thing that drew me out of the movie a couple of times when something big like came out of the screen Ship or something, but then I'd see it suddenly disappear at the edges of the screen.
Speaker 1: That was is still in my field of view.
Speaker 0: Yep, yep.
Speaker 0: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 0: That's why I think you know a true IMAX 3d would be able to do something like that.
Speaker 0: You know because the IMAX the screen goes up above.
Speaker 0: so if you had a true Star Wars 3d IMAX You could actually make the stardestroyer come from above To the front.
Speaker 0: you it would sound like it was coming from above to the front and it would be in 3d.
Speaker 0: You know that is what we need to go for.
Speaker 0: one thing I do want to talk about because no one's gonna You know one's gonna watch that and say oh it could have been in 2d.
Speaker 0: But someone who saw Avatar and said oh it would have been the same in 2d.
Speaker 0: It's like well kinda almost you can you know you can't.
Speaker 0: just you know totally dismiss that argument You know.
Speaker 0: but with the IMAX from behind you could dismiss them easily.
Speaker 1: well a point I do want to make about the movie.
Speaker 1: cuz I'll you know I don't if we didn't say it I like the movie.
Speaker 1: I think it was a solid movie.
Speaker 1: I'm glad I watched it.
Speaker 0: It was okay.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna run on by the DVD or watch it again, or you know I think it was a great like pop.
Speaker 1: it think of this a very popular sci-fi like good Blockbuster movie it's.
Speaker 1: it's proved so much in the meta level like Piracy aside blockbusters still sell and things like that and it reminded I think some people in the industry.
Speaker 1: I hope that sci-fi can be very popular if presented properly duh.
Speaker 0: I think part of the problem though is that they Daryl Surratt he said something that I think I I think is true at least for me.
Speaker 0: It's like you want us to go see a movie of blue people versus robots and cheer for the blue people.
Speaker 0: Where is the?
Speaker 0: where is the movie where the robots are the good guy?
Speaker 1: Well well, but I what I do want to point out is that also the robots didn't really do enough.
Speaker 1: I think they weren't a big part.
Speaker 0: I know that's.
Speaker 0: I wanted to see more robot.
Speaker 1: I like robot, but what was Interesting is that what got me and you'd and a lot of people in our age group and a lot of people in general into Anime back in the day.
Speaker 1: it wasn't necessarily that it was animated that a lot of it was cool So it was just quality sci-fi leji Matsumoto, but what is a characteristic of a lot of that old-school?
Speaker 1: Anime sci-fi the mechanical and technical design.
Speaker 1: What did this movie do?
Speaker 1: they put the cut the level of detail into the stuff that only nerds would care about?
Speaker 1: Into a popular movie like you know the old leji Matsumoto with like the little designs on the train or the the mech show We're like all the sprockets in the mech actually matter and are self-consistent in the animation and that is true.
Speaker 0: I mean I said it has a simple plot, but really starblazers has an equally simple plot.
Speaker 1: yeah, you know and look at I mean the the mechs and the vehicles and the science and the the the flora and fauna.
Speaker 1: and There was very specific technical design like all the 3d displays.
Speaker 1: They had in the movie.
Speaker 1: There was a lot of Non-distracting but very self-consistent use of technology in the movie.
Speaker 1: hmm like every little display like there was kind of this consistent Os that they were using for everything and like all the little time stamps and date stamps and like numbers and things on screen all Matched up and made sense like model numbers on the sides of aircraft.
Speaker 1: matter They didn't matter, but they were self-consistent.
Speaker 0: all this nerd What you know.
Speaker 0: I'm sure that someone's gonna go through and they're gonna find errors in the movie.
Speaker 0: Everyone always does but you can find errors in gundam seed.
Speaker 1: But what did gundam seed do?
Speaker 1: the tech is there if you care about it?
Speaker 1: It's self-consistent, but it doesn't get in the way of the real movie.
Speaker 0: I also like how they didn't do any like Stupid restrictions on things just for the sake of the plot.
Speaker 0: You know it's like everything just sort of made sense.
Speaker 0: like they came in.
Speaker 0: It's like they push the button to wake him out of the thing and then Yeah, it didn't like.
Speaker 0: oh now.
Speaker 0: It's broken the.
Speaker 0: you know they didn't do anything silly like oh You can't use it between the hours of three and six.
Speaker 0: or you know.
Speaker 0: you know they didn't make any stupid.
Speaker 0: You know exceptions for no reason other than to create a plot point or plot device.
Speaker 0: They just you know they.
Speaker 0: they put all the plot devices into into things that were okay.
Speaker 0: You know as opposed to just Nonsensical arbitrary technical limitations for the sake of plot devicing none of that occurred which was acceptable.
Speaker 1: I will.
Speaker 1: it was though all plotting everything aside.
Speaker 1: It was pretty freakin beautiful.
Speaker 0: I think that's pretty much.
Speaker 0: You know it's one of those things.
Speaker 0: It's like the antenna movie.
Speaker 0: not you know it was better than you tend to movie But you know the art book ness of it is definitely well above the.
Speaker 0: you know the plot story ness of it.
Speaker 0: You know as an art book it gets like a plus plus.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's like at least in terms of the year.
Speaker 0: I wonder how you know it will hold up.
Speaker 0: Yeah in the year 2025 am I gonna look at this and will it look away?
Speaker 0: Will it look the way that like a PlayStation game looks now?
Speaker 1: well, I mean even I'm not.
Speaker 1: that long ago like a year ago I've randomly watched like a big chunk of the third Lord of the Rings movie a lot of that CG really doesn't hold up Really like.
Speaker 1: it kind of bothered me of course.
Speaker 1: I think part of the reason it doesn't hold up.
Speaker 1: is that it holds up if you watch it in the theater.
Speaker 1: But like on a TV a lot of stuff really stands out especially if you've already seen the movie And you're not kind of immersed in it in the big screen.
Speaker 1: this of it Mmm.
Speaker 1: I don't think avatar would hold up as well if you were watching it on a little TV without 3d.
Speaker 0: No, it would probably.
Speaker 0: it would probably hold up like you know for a few years.
Speaker 0: But I don't think it'll hold up in the long run, but look how far we've come.
Speaker 1: We have come far.
Speaker 1: this movie Was a huge jump in terms of the popular perception of what is possible with CG.
Speaker 0: the thing is right.
Speaker 0: Is that the thing with CG is like if even fancy Lord of the Rings CG?
Speaker 0: Right doesn't hold up after a few years.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like man.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it came so far and it's still not holding up.
Speaker 0: But the thing is the Pixar stuff like Toy Story 1 holds up cuz it's not as realistic.
Speaker 0: It's more stylized right, but 2d stuff even fucking snow white holds up cuz it's also stylized.
Speaker 1: the more stylized You are the long or it's kind of like taking something.
Speaker 0: So what you're saying when you try to make it realistic.
Speaker 0: Then you lose your ability to hold up whether it's 2d or 3d or even in computer or hand.
Speaker 1: you do this with culture stuff To like look at back to the future.
Speaker 1: Emmett and I were talking about this because it was made so 80s in the 80s.
Speaker 1: you know when it was in the 80s it was present-day future past.
Speaker 1: you watch it today.
Speaker 1: It's not present-day future past.
Speaker 1: It's 80s future past.
Speaker 1: yep very specifically 80s like late eight like it feels so late 80s Kind of me you know.
Speaker 1: and but other movies like there are a lot of old Hitchcock movies even that could be today.
Speaker 1: Yep Absolutely, I think we've talked about this a lot.
Speaker 1: We're not a movie review podcast.
Speaker 0: We just we used to need a Thursday show.
Speaker 0: We used to do a movie on Thursday once in a while cuz we used to watch a lot of movies.
Speaker 0: now We don't really watch so many movies that aren't a 9 and we're starting to watch man.
Speaker 0: We needed a Thursday topic.
Speaker 0: pretty badly, and I'm hungry.
Speaker 1: I think we should wrap.
Speaker 0: I'm also hungry.
Speaker 0: Let's go.
Speaker 1: this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos be sure to visit our website At front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.