Speaker 1: It's Wednesday, March 3rd.
Speaker 1: I'm Rip.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Deaknights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, the great momma hosted a movie, Summer Wars.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: We're kind of on a roll here anime show-wise.
Speaker 0: Are we really?
Speaker 1: We had that long, uh, I don't know how we ended up just not doing Wednesday shows for so long and suddenly we got like two in a row almost.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I think it's cuz we did.
Speaker 0: we did a Tuesday Wednesday week, right?
Speaker 0: Because yeah, those are the shows that we, yeah.
Speaker 1: We had all that unrelated stuff like snow and everything getting in the way.
Speaker 0: It's also weird because I've been, it's mostly like anime season right now for some reason.
Speaker 0: Like I watched every episode of Durara that is on Crunchyroll and I finished Hokuto no Ken 1.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize, I had like 150 something episodes of Hokuto no Ken.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize that like episode 100 something is actually the end.
Speaker 0: And then Hokuto no Ken 2 begins.
Speaker 0: I was unaware.
Speaker 1: Well, there's always like the movie, those terrible live-actions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and now I'm watching, uh, I watched Votoms episode 1.
Speaker 0: So.
Speaker 1: See what I mean?
Speaker 0: While I'm waiting for more Durarara.
Speaker 1: It's hard to, Votoms feels kind of like it's got that gimmick with like the eyes in the mechs.
Speaker 0: That's just for the toys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it feels kind of Gundam-y, but I know it goes way away from Gundam.
Speaker 0: At least the first episode is definitely Gundam-y because it's basically like, think about how every Gundam starts.
Speaker 0: Some guys are stealing a Gundam.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Some guys are, every, right?
Speaker 1: Except replace Gundam with girl in a suitcase.
Speaker 0: Well, that's, you know, that's Outlaw Star.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So all these, you know, I realize it's something that a lot of these big sci-fi shows have in common, right?
Speaker 0: A typical trope is that they want to start in media res with some action, but you can't really get any action if you don't have some sort of, you know, reason for a battle yet.
Speaker 0: So they can't do the battles right away.
Speaker 0: You know what they have to do.
Speaker 1: Unless they start in media res with the battle that they don't tell you why they're fighting or they explain it as it's going.
Speaker 0: I mean, Yamato sort of did that.
Speaker 0: Yamato did it with like, you know, the battle where Earth gets his ass kicked.
Speaker 0: And that's basically now the only hope left is, you know, the Yamato, because every all the other ships blew up and they start with the losing battle.
Speaker 0: But yeah, that's episode one.
Speaker 0: It's not a spoiler.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you know, the what, so what they do is they start with like an operation, like a single like operation of some like, you know, pirates or some thieves, but an operation that sort of like Navy SEAL operation.
Speaker 0: And then that operation unfolds into the greater picture, usually because it goes wrong.
Speaker 1: Something happens and the main character is spurred on by whatever that operation was.
Speaker 1: Either they killed their mom or they killed Rusty.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, it's basically there's some sort of mission that they begin with.
Speaker 0: And that, you know, mission unfolds into the rest of the show and Votoms and Gundam Seed and Zeta Gundam.
Speaker 0: And they all do the same thing.
Speaker 1: We're on a mission.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Mission from God.
Speaker 0: I think Idaeon does a similar thing.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I haven't watched any more Votoms than you, so I don't really have anything to say about it.
Speaker 0: But you watch.
Speaker 0: you watch more than one episode.
Speaker 1: I watched one and a half episodes.
Speaker 0: You watched half an episode more than me.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I still don't think I know much more than what you know.
Speaker 0: No, I actually I had to.
Speaker 0: He got away.
Speaker 0: I might have to rewatch the first episode and pay more attention.
Speaker 0: I was like eating dinner at the same time.
Speaker 1: What really happened?
Speaker 1: The guy is part of a mission.
Speaker 1: He's like, I don't know what's going on.
Speaker 1: And you're all acting really shady.
Speaker 0: Well, what I didn't understand really was the because I wasn't paying enough attention.
Speaker 0: was the?
Speaker 0: was they?
Speaker 0: there was some bigger picture stuff like he was fighting his own man and there was a war.
Speaker 0: And who were they fighting against?
Speaker 0: And they sort of explained it, but I didn't read it.
Speaker 0: I wasn't looking at the subtitles.
Speaker 1: Well, what happened was he got he was out.
Speaker 1: He got picked up by this other unit.
Speaker 1: That unit was doing shady shit, basically robbing Fort Knox.
Speaker 1: And they're like.
Speaker 1: they tell him, yeah, just follow orders.
Speaker 1: No, he's a superior officer.
Speaker 1: Technically help us out with this mission.
Speaker 1: And he's like, you guys are doing something shady.
Speaker 1: They're basically shut up and stand there and help us.
Speaker 0: And then he got tortured when he got caught by his own guys.
Speaker 1: Like, why'd you rob Fort Knox?
Speaker 0: And he's like, I don't know.
Speaker 0: And he really didn't know.
Speaker 0: But I didn't believe him.
Speaker 0: And, you know, who could blame them?
Speaker 0: But they still why were they all torturing?
Speaker 0: That's not good.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Clearly, the quote unquote good guys are actually the bad guys in both.
Speaker 0: That's that's what I'm figuring.
Speaker 0: Because you look and it's like, OK, there were guys who were traitors to the guys that he was originally with.
Speaker 1: And they are bad people.
Speaker 0: And they're bad people.
Speaker 0: And then the guys that he was originally with are all torturing him and not believing that he doesn't know anything.
Speaker 0: We didn't know anything.
Speaker 1: Also bad people.
Speaker 0: Everyone that he was with is bad people.
Speaker 0: And it seems like whoever they were fighting the war against and are now declaring peace with must be the good guy.
Speaker 1: Later on, he ends up with a Venus Wars style kind of crew of people on a planet somewhere.
Speaker 0: That could be cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's kind of what I'm waiting for, because I felt this urge to watch a lot of episodes.
Speaker 0: It's like seven episodes per disc.
Speaker 0: And it's like eight discs.
Speaker 0: It's mostly like 50 something.
Speaker 1: Well, Jess and Katsu watched like the whole thing at Wildwood.
Speaker 0: They're crazy.
Speaker 0: They didn't go to the beach and they sat inside and watched.
Speaker 1: But I kept walking by the TV throughout the week and seeing, oh, that show looks kind of cool.
Speaker 1: What is it?
Speaker 1: They're like, vote arms.
Speaker 1: Hey, what are you watching now?
Speaker 1: Vote arms.
Speaker 0: The only thing that makes me sad is like I'm really in a mood for the sci fi space anime shows and I'm running out.
Speaker 0: You know, I mean, there's still plenty to go, but they're not making more of these really.
Speaker 0: at a rate I can watch them faster than they make them one.
Speaker 0: And then what do I do?
Speaker 1: You've at least got Legend of the Galactic Heroes.
Speaker 1: That's like this gigantic blob just waiting for the last one.
Speaker 0: And then just kill yourself and then kill myself after I finish.
Speaker 1: But here's the trouble I have.
Speaker 1: The problem with anime right now is that what got almost everyone in our generation now into anime were these kinds of shows.
Speaker 1: Was it because it was anime or was it because it happened to be anime?
Speaker 1: But what it was was space, sci fi or people getting cut off all bloody.
Speaker 1: It was no.
Speaker 0: Well, it was awesome plots.
Speaker 0: It was, you know, movies with these, you know, intelligent plots that are as good as sci fi books.
Speaker 1: But I'll submit that we even liked, at least when we were getting into anime, really dumb stuff that was still kind of sci fi.
Speaker 0: We were also kids.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean, I thought Wind of Amnesia.
Speaker 0: We were just.
Speaker 0: we were just smart kids.
Speaker 0: And now we look back and some of the stuff was good and some it was bad.
Speaker 1: And we look back at the stuff that was Venus Wars when I was a kid was this great like war tragedy.
Speaker 1: I thought it was so serious business and awesome.
Speaker 1: And I think it's still kind of is except for the end with the tank.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But Emily and I finally finished Ghost in the Shell standalone complex again.
Speaker 0: Again, I was going to say I've seen it twice.
Speaker 1: But even then, I kind of forgot a bunch of stuff that happens at the end.
Speaker 0: I mostly remember like individual episodes.
Speaker 0: The overall plot is pretty much just like laughing man.
Speaker 0: Ha ha ha ha.
Speaker 1: You know, yeah, kind of.
Speaker 1: But something weird happens at the end.
Speaker 1: And I noticed all this stuff that now that I've seen second gig do, you know, watching it in retrospect, it really just sets up second gig.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it might be definitely.
Speaker 0: I could definitely see it being one of those intense situations.
Speaker 0: You watch it again and now suddenly you see more.
Speaker 0: But a second go.
Speaker 1: only in the last episode, the last episode, the major picks something up and looks at it like, I know what that is now.
Speaker 1: And something weird happens to someone I can't spoil.
Speaker 1: And I think that is like exactly what starts second gig.
Speaker 1: I got to watch the last episode again before we send the Netflix back.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So anime news, there actually is a tiny bit of anime going to do a news.
Speaker 0: I was going to do a geek bite.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I'm going to do a news because, you know, the Trigun movie is coming.
Speaker 1: And I got to admit, I'm actually really freaking excited about this.
Speaker 0: I'm not really freaking excited, but I want to watch it.
Speaker 1: Well, I think my prediction here is that the movie, coupled with the fact that Naito is doing another Trigun manga, there is going to be a resurgence of Trigun fandom, not in Japan, but in the rest of the world.
Speaker 0: That is very possible.
Speaker 0: I think it will.
Speaker 0: My prediction is that Trigun fandom will resume, will basically meet its former peak.
Speaker 0: You know, Trigun will become as popular as it was when it was popular and then go back down again and then they will make, you know, some more money off of it.
Speaker 1: So here's the thing.
Speaker 1: Go back down again is what I question.
Speaker 1: I wonder if because Trigun was really freaking popular and notice how even today, like anime cons, you still see the Wolfwood and the Vash cosplayers.
Speaker 1: You don't see as many Fullmetal Alchemist cosplayers until the new show came out.
Speaker 0: Trigun is a really, you know, good cosplay.
Speaker 0: You know, it has all the characteristics of what a good cosplay is all about.
Speaker 0: A character with a distinctive design, distinctive accoutrement, you know, it's.
Speaker 0: it's a, you know, recognizable character.
Speaker 0: It's like the perfect cosplay.
Speaker 0: So that is why it is frequent.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at the same time, I wonder if I mean, basically, if the movie does really well, I would expect there to be another movie or an OAV or even another TV show at some point.
Speaker 1: I think this is going to be the chance, because remember at Otacon, when the director they were talking about how Trigun was very not popular in Japan and crazy popular in the rest of the world to the point that it made a lot of money because of the rest of the world.
Speaker 1: And remember the very specific thing he said, we're making the Trigun movie for Trigun fans, not anime fans, not Japanese fans, Trigun fans.
Speaker 0: I just hope that it is not like the manga, because even though I have a Trigun fan and the manga is terrible, there's no question about it.
Speaker 1: Terrible isn't really the right word.
Speaker 1: Incomprehensible.
Speaker 1: I can't say it's terrible because I can't tell.
Speaker 1: I have no idea what's going on.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, in the early volumes, you can sort of tell what's going on, but I have all the volumes.
Speaker 0: I should actually try to finish the finish.
Speaker 1: It doesn't end.
Speaker 1: It just kind of loops.
Speaker 1: It maybe just repeats like 10 pages in a row.
Speaker 1: Would you even notice?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: But yeah, there's going to be a little Trigun manga that's going to kind of build up to the April 24th opening of Trigun Badlands Rumble.
Speaker 1: And in case anyone doesn't know, the Trigun movie is basically the Cowboy Bebop movie.
Speaker 1: It takes place after all.
Speaker 1: the basic plot is set up in Trigun the TV show, but then before stuff happens, before world affecting stuff ruins everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that actually Trigun would probably do better with a movie more similar to the Escaflowne movie, where you take these characters in this world that everyone likes and then you just tell a different story in it.
Speaker 0: that has nothing to do with the main story and it's not in the same universe.
Speaker 1: It's hard to say because they're doing this whole Vash versus Wolfwood thing with the movie, but all indications are that the movie is like the Cowboy Bebop movie.
Speaker 1: It's basically a standalone.
Speaker 1: You could just watch it having no idea.
Speaker 0: Well, it's got to be that you can't make a movie if you don't do that.
Speaker 1: One Piece 6.
Speaker 0: That's the One Piece movies as far as I know.
Speaker 0: I could be wrong, right?
Speaker 0: But from what I understand, which is probably wrong, they are not actually episodes that they are like, you know, compilations.
Speaker 0: So you could watch all the One Piece movies.
Speaker 0: And not watch any One Piece TV show and you would get the same thing.
Speaker 0: Is that wrong?
Speaker 0: Or do you have to watch the One Piece TV show and watch the movies in the correct spots?
Speaker 1: I've never seen one.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I ever planned to see one.
Speaker 0: Or are the One Piece movies side stories?
Speaker 0: I almost think I might like a One Piece movie, actually.
Speaker 0: Like maybe I should just watch all of them because...
Speaker 1: The fight can't last more than an hour and a half.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: There'll be fight scenes, but the fights won't take up the whole movie.
Speaker 0: It'll be, you know, a contained story with a beginning, middle and an end within the movie itself.
Speaker 0: And it'll have all the One Piece characters.
Speaker 0: And, you know, I just I just wonder.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe we should watch one of these movies.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe we should watch like the first One Piece movie and the second one.
Speaker 0: And then we'll be able to tell from that because I've seen like five or six episodes of One Piece and I've read 11 volumes.
Speaker 0: So if I watch the first two movies, that will probably give me a good idea.
Speaker 1: You know, along those lines, I feel like you realize I've never actually seen the Pokemon movie, not even the first one.
Speaker 0: I've never seen any Pokemon movie ever.
Speaker 1: I think we should watch the first Pokemon movie.
Speaker 0: The first one?
Speaker 1: Yeah, with Mewtwo and Mew, I think.
Speaker 0: Is that the one where you can't Snorlax can't live?
Speaker 1: It's got to be.
Speaker 0: Is it?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Someone tell me which one that was.
Speaker 0: That's the one I want to watch.
Speaker 1: Snorlax helping everybody.
Speaker 0: OK, are we good on this?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so that's, I guess, all the anime news in the world.
Speaker 1: that matters.
Speaker 1: I mean, if you're going to be at soccer account, I think they're going to premiere the dragon movie there.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: That's cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they'd better have it at Otacon.
Speaker 1: Jesus.
Speaker 0: So there's a comic book that I read that's relatively new and hot.
Speaker 0: The first trade paperback came out and I've talked about it on the Internet and on Scott's box.
Speaker 0: But I don't know if I've talked about it on geek nights.
Speaker 0: And if I haven't, now I am.
Speaker 0: And if I have, it's good enough to be worth talking about twice.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: It's called The Unwritten.
Speaker 0: It's published by Vertigo.
Speaker 0: And it's written by Mike Carey with art from Peter Gross.
Speaker 0: And basically what this comic is about is pretend that Harry Potter was written by a dude.
Speaker 0: That dude.
Speaker 1: So Harry grabs, grasps his wang and.
Speaker 0: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: That dude who wrote the author of Harry Potter disappeared mysteriously.
Speaker 0: No one knows where he is.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: He has a son.
Speaker 0: The son's name is Harry Potter.
Speaker 0: It's a coincidence.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: He's not really Harry Potter.
Speaker 0: It's just the dude's son.
Speaker 0: The dude made a series of Harry Potter like novels.
Speaker 0: And then he made he named the main character the same name as his son.
Speaker 1: I think I've looked at this, but I have not read it yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll give it to you.
Speaker 0: And basically this guy, you know, is now this guy who is the Harry Potter, even though his name is not Harry Potter.
Speaker 0: His name is Tom Taylor.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So Tom Taylor, the real dude who has no magical powers whatsoever.
Speaker 0: He's just basically making a living by going to conventions and signing autographs and, you know, doing that sort of thing, because, you know, imagine if there was a real dude named Harry Potter and he was the son of whatever that lady's name is, you know, he would go.
Speaker 0: He would be like a famous people.
Speaker 1: J.K.
Speaker 1: Rowling.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If it was J.K.
Speaker 0: Rowling's son and his name was Harry Potter, people would be like, oh, my gosh, whoo.
Speaker 0: And he'd be able to sign autographs and conventions and make a living on his own without even doing anything talented whatsoever.
Speaker 1: Just like Will Wheaton.
Speaker 0: No, OK, OK.
Speaker 0: So so this guy is at a convention, a nerdy convention, and he's doing a panel as people do.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And some lady stands up in the audience, some girl, and she's just like.
Speaker 0: so she has a question.
Speaker 0: She says, who are you?
Speaker 0: And he's like, Tom Taylor, what's you know?
Speaker 0: So she's like, no, really.
Speaker 0: Like your social security number is actually the security number of this person who died a long time ago.
Speaker 0: And he's like, he's just like, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Are you sure?
Speaker 0: And she presents all this evidence and it's mad conspiracy theory evidence, you know, but and he's just like, OK.
Speaker 0: And his agent basically hustles him out of there.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, basically, you get the idea that, yeah, he really isn't Tom Taylor, but he doesn't know it.
Speaker 0: It's like he's an identity thief impersonating someone, but he didn't set it up.
Speaker 0: He thinks he's Tom Taylor.
Speaker 0: He has no idea that.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So it's like, what the fuck is up?
Speaker 0: Oh, shit.
Speaker 0: And then there's some supernatural shit.
Speaker 0: Oh, my gosh.
Speaker 0: And it's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: Is it a series or a one piece?
Speaker 0: It's a series.
Speaker 0: So I got the first trade, which has issues one through five, I think.
Speaker 0: And then, you know, they come up with issues and trade.
Speaker 0: So I'll probably almost definitely get the second trade.
Speaker 0: And this is, you know, it's pretty amazing because, you know, it's a very original story.
Speaker 0: I've never read a story quite like this.
Speaker 0: It's also high quality, very suspenseful, very good.
Speaker 0: Mystery with a good pacing of reveals or a sour teas cock motherfucker.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The art is high quality and it's got lots of.
Speaker 0: you know, it ties in heavily to literacy, you know, literary works of the past and literary geography like, oh, you know, that's the.
Speaker 0: you know, they're in London.
Speaker 0: So it's like, oh, that's the building that was in Dickens something, something.
Speaker 0: And that's the building that, you know, is in 1984.
Speaker 0: You know, that's a very big part of it as well.
Speaker 0: So, you know, it doesn't it sort of, you know, goes off like that.
Speaker 0: And I enjoy it.
Speaker 0: And if you are a comic reading person, you should read the unwritten.
Speaker 1: God, this sounds so up our friend Scott Johnson's alley.
Speaker 0: No, it's almost painful.
Speaker 1: He's, you know, he's a big fan of the book of magic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's that's Neil Gaiman's Harry Potter.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: That was out before Harry Potter.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But I have a feeling people who like one would like the other.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I get this impression.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I'm just basing that on almost nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, I'll give you the book.
Speaker 0: You can read it.
Speaker 0: But yeah, this is a high quality new comic book.
Speaker 0: Go buy it at the store so that they don't cancel it and stop making new issues, because that would be like, you know, I mean, I don't.
Speaker 0: I'm not one of those people who goes crazy upset when they cancel something.
Speaker 0: But it's like.
Speaker 0: I need enough issues to come out so that they can tell me what the deal is.
Speaker 1: But I thought this wasn't a charity.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: You know, buy it because it's awesome, not because you're, you know, thinking charity of it.
Speaker 1: So things of the day, I got to admit, as I finally start reading Astro Toy on a regular basis, I'm surprised to find that there's a new guy doing it as of this most recent Astro Toy.
Speaker 0: Is Krauser still in it?
Speaker 1: There was no Krauser.
Speaker 1: However, I can understand why there would be no Krauser.
Speaker 1: I mean, you wouldn't want Krauser to get hurt when you're reviewing Duke Togo himself.
Speaker 0: Oh, shit.
Speaker 1: Remember way back on the show, I talked about this.
Speaker 1: It's the Duke Togo figure and the Figma.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's my thing of the day for two reasons.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 1: One, I did not realize that he comes with not one, but two suitcases.
Speaker 1: One has all the pieces, all the spaces in foam for you to put the pieces of his gun that assembles on its own to the other suitcase is full of hundred dollar bills.
Speaker 1: And the real reason, though, he only has two faces.
Speaker 1: You know, they have like the multiple faces on these things like smiling, Yotsuba and sad Yotsuba, something like that.
Speaker 1: Maybe they have four faces.
Speaker 1: Duke Togo has two faces, normal Duke Togo and slightly sneering Duke Togo.
Speaker 1: It's a beautiful thing to behold.
Speaker 1: That's all I got.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, Astro Toy under new management, Figma Deluxe, Golgo 13.
Speaker 1: That's David Cabrera.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, that is really deluxe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I told you, look at that thing, though, I was surprised to find out that room in the fit in the set.
Speaker 1: That was like a hotel room with an exhausted hooker and a window paper craft, not plastic.
Speaker 1: Oh, he talks a lot about how he basically could not.
Speaker 0: he did something funny.
Speaker 0: Look, go go.
Speaker 0: Thirteen's riding on some weird moe.
Speaker 1: I didn't say he didn't do anything funny.
Speaker 1: I said there was no Krauser.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: There's no Krauser.
Speaker 0: He does have the speech bubble, though.
Speaker 1: He does.
Speaker 1: Apparently there are two different versions of double exclamation point.
Speaker 0: This is a good toy.
Speaker 0: Looks like.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I almost bought it when we were hanging out the other day.
Speaker 1: In the city, I just didn't.
Speaker 0: Maybe I should know what he can do with it.
Speaker 1: Put it somewhere.
Speaker 0: I would buy it if I was going to make stop motion animations with it.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, it sort of just takes up room and money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I could put it like with numerous.
Speaker 1: it's humorous.
Speaker 0: But like, you know, that's the same reason I didn't buy the Hokuto no Ken figure of the guy getting, you know, what and exploding because it's like.
Speaker 0: that's freaking awesome.
Speaker 0: And it's a great conversation piece.
Speaker 0: But what am I going to do with it?
Speaker 1: Well, my new policies look around the studio.
Speaker 1: I have the Jigen because I think he's awesome.
Speaker 1: Just kind of there.
Speaker 1: I got my little house name, Miku.
Speaker 1: I got my Lupin.
Speaker 1: I don't really have that much else.
Speaker 1: I only have like the super high quality, very, very good figures in like key places around the house.
Speaker 1: The same way a welcome to my country home person is going to have the welcome to my country home device.
Speaker 0: All my toys are still in plastic bags on the floor of my bedroom, except for the Gundam models.
Speaker 1: You see, I had a day of reckoning when we moved.
Speaker 1: I actually went through all my little figures and put all the ones that weren't totally awesome away.
Speaker 0: Maybe what I'll do is I'll take out all the ones that I really just couldn't bear to get rid of and put them somewhere and all the other ones.
Speaker 1: I'll give away conventions or something, something I give them or anime Boston swap me.
Speaker 0: Oh, shit.
Speaker 0: I forgot.
Speaker 0: After the thing today, we'll discuss that a little bit more.
Speaker 0: So I saw this video.
Speaker 0: It was all over the Internet today.
Speaker 0: You've probably seen it already.
Speaker 0: But in case you haven't, now you have.
Speaker 1: Well, they haven't.
Speaker 1: They don't know what it is yet.
Speaker 0: They will soon.
Speaker 0: The title of the video is Every Day Looper, less ramens.
Speaker 0: And I don't think it's about ramen, the food, though it might be.
Speaker 0: It's in French.
Speaker 0: I have no idea what he's saying.
Speaker 1: The words were something about eating something.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, shit.
Speaker 1: That's that's about.
Speaker 0: that makes it even more awesome.
Speaker 1: That's about the extent of my knowledge of French.
Speaker 0: Basically, this is French kid.
Speaker 0: He looks, you know, younger than us, but older than a punk kid.
Speaker 1: He might be gave a qua.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, you're right.
Speaker 1: The accent was kind of funny.
Speaker 1: It was kind of.
Speaker 1: it was kind of like a Señor God.
Speaker 0: Regardless, he has an iPhone just like me and he's got just like you, just like me.
Speaker 0: And it's it's hooked up.
Speaker 0: He's got some, you know, plug hooked up to his headphone hole with some wires coming out.
Speaker 0: I got to figure out what that is so I can get it.
Speaker 0: And he's got this app called Everyday Looper.
Speaker 0: And basically all this program does, it gives you four loops.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And you can make music with it.
Speaker 0: So you can be like.
Speaker 0: you record on the first loop and you go, doo, doo, doo, doo, doo, doo.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: And then you record in the second loop.
Speaker 0: You're whistling, you know.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then you got them both playing at once.
Speaker 0: You know, that's and basically allows you to do on the fly, you know, music sampling and creation.
Speaker 0: And then it even gives you ways to like save the file and get it out of the phone.
Speaker 0: It actually has a Web server you can use to visit the Web server in the phone and get the file out, which is pretty neat anyway.
Speaker 0: So he, you know, in this YouTube video, he makes live in the video a pretty awesome song.
Speaker 0: So awesome that his video is passed all around the Internet's.
Speaker 0: And he was so awesome.
Speaker 0: I paid five dollars for this app because it's that one thing I can say.
Speaker 1: And I think you'll agree.
Speaker 1: he makes it look like it's really easy to do this.
Speaker 1: Not that easy.
Speaker 0: Also, you know, you have to do it in a place that's quiet.
Speaker 0: And that plug with the wires he has connected to it is helping him out.
Speaker 1: Oh, you need that.
Speaker 0: You definitely have to have a real microphone trying to do it with like, you know, just holding it up to your head like it's a telephone.
Speaker 0: Not too easy to do.
Speaker 0: It's going to sound like crap, you know, garbage and garbage out.
Speaker 1: So the meta minute, remember, before we forget.
Speaker 1: OK, it's coming up on Con season.
Speaker 1: We try to avoid talking about conventions where the season is usually heavy.
Speaker 0: August this year.
Speaker 0: It's like equal.
Speaker 0: It's like March, August, well, March, April, August, because it's over the March, April squishiness.
Speaker 1: Well, because remember, we used to go to what?
Speaker 1: Well, we had Katsucon in February and fail.
Speaker 1: Then we had a long break and then it was like May, July, August, oh, shit.
Speaker 1: And then we're dead.
Speaker 1: And then we ended everything with Pax.
Speaker 1: But now there's two Pax's and we dropped Katsucon because of all the fail.
Speaker 1: And we consolidated, moved around and now we get Anime Boston.
Speaker 0: So basically our conventions are Pax East, Anime Boston, Otacon, Pax West, New York Comic Con, New York Comic Con, New York Anime Festival combo and Kinetic Con.
Speaker 1: And, you know, like Zenkai Con because our friends were on it and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Oh right, the Zenkai Con.
Speaker 0: I forgot about that.
Speaker 0: But that's easy.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's easy to do, though.
Speaker 1: Anyway, when was it last year?
Speaker 1: You don't remember?
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 1: When did we do it?
Speaker 1: more or less than six months ago?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: So are we that old?
Speaker 0: I was not living in New York at the time.
Speaker 1: It wasn't cold.
Speaker 0: It wasn't that cold.
Speaker 0: You're right.
Speaker 0: It was sunny out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Could have been fall, though.
Speaker 1: How did we get?
Speaker 1: I think we took your car.
Speaker 0: We did take my car because he had board games in it and such.
Speaker 1: And we watched the Prince of Tennis musical.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: OK, so this meant a minute.
Speaker 0: We got to remind Pax East is at the end of this month.
Speaker 1: It is like March the last weekend in March.
Speaker 1: So March 26, the schedule is now available.
Speaker 0: We are doing for three and a half, three and one asterisk panel.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Beyond Dungeons and Dragons.
Speaker 1: Losing should be fun beyond Candyland.
Speaker 0: Fanatical devotion to the pope and Action Castle, which is actually Jared Sorenson, not us, but it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: It's Action Castle.
Speaker 1: And remember, Action Castle is us.
Speaker 1: One Action Castle is going to be one of the best things at Pax East, which is saying a lot action castle.
Speaker 0: You're not allowed to say it any other way than that.
Speaker 1: But more, you know, no one could see what you were doing.
Speaker 1: No, we're not doing a video show yet.
Speaker 0: We'll have to do it.
Speaker 0: I wonder if we could do Action Castle on Ustream.
Speaker 0: Some.
Speaker 0: But how would people line up?
Speaker 1: We'll figure that out.
Speaker 0: I'll try it.
Speaker 1: We assign everyone a number.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then no one else.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll look at the list of participants in the chat room and I'll only pay attention to the person who's next in the list.
Speaker 1: Or you just pay attention to whatever gets typed next.
Speaker 0: No, because they would flood.
Speaker 1: And then the game, you crash and you force the people to self-organize.
Speaker 1: And you had this meta element.
Speaker 1: Anyway, Action Castle will probably only take half of the panel time.
Speaker 1: Last Pax, the other half of that panel, me, Scott and Jared did a cut.
Speaker 1: It was weird.
Speaker 1: We did this like ad hoc Q&A.
Speaker 1: And we I've noticed this before.
Speaker 1: Whenever we've done the kind of panels at the last minute, like when we did that Advanced Wars panel at Otacon that one year again, we are not experts at Advanced Wars.
Speaker 1: You know, we're just some guys who Otacon is like, we need another panel.
Speaker 1: We're like, we'll do one on.
Speaker 1: How about Advanced Wars?
Speaker 0: Oh, well, I mean, we gave them so many suggestions.
Speaker 0: Advanced Wars, which is the most crab people of all of them, is the one they picked over many better choices.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we did it.
Speaker 1: And people, because we were at the front of the room sitting behind a table with microphones, people asked us the kind of questions that they would they should be asking, like the guy who made Advanced Wars.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, I don't know why you asking me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't write the code.
Speaker 1: But the same thing happened here.
Speaker 1: Like we're just three schmucks.
Speaker 1: I mean, no one in the audience really knew who we were.
Speaker 1: Action Castle was for that, like the second time in a row, the secret event at Pax.
Speaker 0: It's now it's not a secret anymore.
Speaker 0: We're going to.
Speaker 0: it's going to be so unsecret this time.
Speaker 0: You know, you know, it's going to be secret, though.
Speaker 0: Jungle adventure is going to be the secret event.
Speaker 1: There may well be a secret event.
Speaker 1: I'm working on that.
Speaker 1: But instead of secret, everybody is paying me for the door.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So but not.
Speaker 1: but we basically just did this Q&A.
Speaker 1: And who are we?
Speaker 1: Three schmucks.
Speaker 1: People ask us some pretty crazy questions and seem really interested in the answers.
Speaker 0: So I don't know if we'll be doing, you know, technically it's Jared's panel.
Speaker 0: Like, go let him go full on.
Speaker 1: What I want to do is I want Jared and Luke Crane to do at least the mini version of their games as mind control panel that Pax didn't want for some reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can do.
Speaker 0: I got some stuff to say about some related topics.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So we'll figure something out.
Speaker 1: So something will happen next Tuesday show.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Action Castle is going to be crazy.
Speaker 1: Something else is going to happen after Action Castle.
Speaker 1: that will also be crazy.
Speaker 1: And if enough of you are at Pax East, I know we have more East Coast listeners than West Coast listeners.
Speaker 1: We'll make something additional cool happen at some point.
Speaker 0: And Anime Boston go to it.
Speaker 0: It's going to be an awesome anime convention.
Speaker 1: April 2nd and 3rd and 4th, the weekend directly after Pax East in the same building.
Speaker 0: Nobu Uematsu is going to be there.
Speaker 0: Oh, shit.
Speaker 0: That Nobu.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it is in music by Nobu.
Speaker 0: I don't know what Otakon is going to do to compete with.
Speaker 1: Yes, you do.
Speaker 1: Your staff, you know exactly who Otakon has.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's not going to be.
Speaker 0: it's not being that doesn't beat Nobu.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's great, but it doesn't.
Speaker 1: Here's the trouble.
Speaker 1: Here's the one difference.
Speaker 1: If it's someone like Yokokano, like when Otakon had Yokokano way back, that beats Nobu.
Speaker 1: Yokokano is both crazy amazing in the Nobu sense and can perform herself.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I don't believe Nobu is going to perform.
Speaker 0: That's correct.
Speaker 1: He's going to talk.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter now.
Speaker 1: Maybe he's going to bring.
Speaker 1: I don't know this part.
Speaker 1: They don't tell us lowly staffers this.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Maybe he's going to have an orchestra.
Speaker 0: The thing is right.
Speaker 0: Nobu is such a great composer.
Speaker 0: I imagine he has the ability to play instruments.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's got.
Speaker 1: most composers can play the piano.
Speaker 1: OK.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's you know, so he can definitely do something.
Speaker 0: regardless is Nobu.
Speaker 0: And it's right now it's looking like anime.
Speaker 0: Boston is like ahead of Otakon when you look at, you know, Nobu.
Speaker 0: It's like, well, anime Boston is currently winning on the scorecard.
Speaker 1: Well, I think the reason is and this is going to be really, really meta.
Speaker 1: It's the meta minutes.
Speaker 1: The only time I can get away with saying stuff like this.
Speaker 1: Otakon way back used to give panelists and like people who did stuff weird special treatment like most kinds of most kinds of your panelists.
Speaker 1: They give you something.
Speaker 1: Otakon kind of stopped doing that over the years.
Speaker 1: Like we have to actually wait in lines and do all the same stuff.
Speaker 1: Normal people do it.
Speaker 1: Otakon anime Boston.
Speaker 1: We kind of don't.
Speaker 1: So we have this really skewed perspective.
Speaker 1: Like we didn't have to worry.
Speaker 1: Are we going to get into the concert in anime Boston?
Speaker 1: We basically just walked in and sat in the front.
Speaker 1: I don't know if we were supposed to.
Speaker 0: We didn't sit in the front.
Speaker 0: We sat in the middle.
Speaker 1: We sat in the front ish of like that middle area.
Speaker 1: We didn't stand in that crazy line.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: We didn't stand in the line.
Speaker 0: We just walked in and it just we happened to walk in and we sat at the, you know, far the, you know, empty seats.
Speaker 0: We didn't go to reserve seating area.
Speaker 0: We just didn't wait in line.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we saw and there's other stuff like that.
Speaker 1: I think we might have a skewed perception.
Speaker 1: So I'd take anything we say about comparisons between Otakon and anime Boston.
Speaker 0: You're saying that because anime Boston gives more perks with a grain of salt, that we may be biased towards anime Boston.
Speaker 0: Yes, it might be true because we see also because anime Boston goes late with the hotel space.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: There's more anime Boston and they also had a gaming room in there.
Speaker 1: So it's like, yeah, we have a really weird and skewed perception between the two kinds.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: But if you look at just the guest scorecard, anime Boston is winning.
Speaker 1: Depends if you scale that.
Speaker 1: Like if you look at the last several years, Lark, I'm talking about this year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this year, but only Otakon's track record is still like far above.
Speaker 0: I did not say it was not.
Speaker 0: I said this year, so far, anime Boston guest scorecard.
Speaker 0: Nobu is worth so many points.
Speaker 0: Otakon is not winning on that, you know, row on the rubric.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: The other factor, I think I didn't even think about this.
Speaker 1: The hotel fact, because my favorite cons way back in the day used to be the hotel cons like Asen and Katsucon because they went all night and crazy stuff happened all night long.
Speaker 1: And Otakon was always weird.
Speaker 1: That was the con where, you know, the fire alarm went off and we all had to leave at two a.m..
Speaker 0: Everybody out.
Speaker 1: Of course, at the same time, I have not been kicked out of Otakon at the end of Otakon for like three years running because I'm an old man and I go to bed.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: So I don't know.
Speaker 1: But anime Boston is going to be frickin awesome.
Speaker 1: Pax East is going to be frickin awesome.
Speaker 1: And we're doing like four or five panels slash events at anime Boston.
Speaker 0: And don't and remember, I didn't know this anime Boston has a swap meet.
Speaker 0: So if you have mangas, DVDs, video games, board games, toys, any stuff that you want to get rid of and trade for other stuff, bring it to anime Boston, because I did not know they had a swap meet and I'm going to bring a whole bunch of stuff and trade it with me.
Speaker 0: And the thing that's weird is it seems like a lot of shit.
Speaker 1: I keep forgetting.
Speaker 1: we're swap me to Connecticut no matter what.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't forget.
Speaker 0: It seems to me that like a lot of people at anime Boston go to the anime Boston forums and trade in advance.
Speaker 0: And I'm like, well, what's the point of a swap meet then?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, the point is that, you know, you right.
Speaker 0: So I'm not going to post anything in the anime Boston forums to show up with my stuff.
Speaker 1: So here's the thing.
Speaker 1: Should we cosplay for that?
Speaker 1: Because I have a mission for all of you out there.
Speaker 1: If you show up to the swap meet dressed as either sand people with a little, you know, something like a little robe stuff on.
Speaker 1: Oh, yes.
Speaker 1: And people are.
Speaker 1: And John was like, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, or if you dress as the shopkeeper from Secret of Mana or a shopkeeper from any video game, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think I could dress as old man.
Speaker 0: I could be like that.
Speaker 1: Take anyone you want.
Speaker 1: Anyone you want, except Europa, too.
Speaker 0: Does anyone ever cosplayed as old man?
Speaker 0: I've never seen one.
Speaker 1: If you get two people to cosplay as the fires.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: Or one step further, you take it fully meta.
Speaker 1: You dress up as old man pimp with hot lady fire.
Speaker 1: Much like the old poke pimp.
Speaker 0: So if I dress up as old man pimp, who's going to be hot lady fires?
Speaker 1: We know we know enough hot ladies.
Speaker 0: We need two hot lady fires that want to be.
Speaker 0: They want to get pimped by me.
Speaker 1: I'll be the moblin.
Speaker 0: You could be called grumble, grumble, grumble, grumble.
Speaker 0: You could have the two fires also.
Speaker 0: We would share the fires, man.
Speaker 1: It's total aside.
Speaker 1: meta Emily's play.
Speaker 1: You know, I gave her she's playing final or final fantasy Zelda three.
Speaker 1: You know, one of the last Super Nintendo Zelda.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You know, the link to the past.
Speaker 1: One of the last kind of old school Zelda's.
Speaker 1: She had never played Zelda one.
Speaker 1: She did not know that grumble.
Speaker 1: grumble is literally solved by a stereotypical piece of meat on a bone.
Speaker 1: I showed her a picture of that meat.
Speaker 1: I was like, that is the item in the game.
Speaker 0: That's fucking.
Speaker 0: I love that meat.
Speaker 1: I love the fact that if you use it, it does something independent.
Speaker 1: I'm not really, you know, a octorox will go walking kind of stand over it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but not really.
Speaker 0: It's not as strong as it.
Speaker 0: You know, it's not like a magnet, you know, that's like super strong.
Speaker 0: It's just kind of it just kind of suggests to them to walk that.
Speaker 1: It'd be really useful, except, you know, who doesn't go after it?
Speaker 0: Those dangerous bad guys, fucking knights.
Speaker 0: No dangerous bad guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Useful on the knights because they would all crowd around it.
Speaker 0: You just put a bomb on it.
Speaker 1: No, they just turn left right into me.
Speaker 0: I just like meat bomb.
Speaker 0: Boom.
Speaker 0: I win.
Speaker 0: But meat bomb meat bomb tricks knights.
Speaker 0: And do that's a great comic.
Speaker 0: You put down a meat, you show a blue knight walking over to it.
Speaker 0: Then he picks up the meat and it's like blue bomb pops out of it.
Speaker 0: Oh, it hits him in the front where, you know, it hits him in the back because, yeah, you can't.
Speaker 1: I just had this.
Speaker 1: I think my brain just went 4chan for a second.
Speaker 1: I picture the dongo saying something bad in me.
Speaker 1: That was like 10 things mashed.
Speaker 0: You can make a series of comics.
Speaker 0: like Link gets tricky with the meat bomb trick and you show link like sitting around the corner going.
Speaker 1: You know, that reminds me.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I wonder if high space is still there.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: I haven't checked that forever in high space.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Pause the show.
Speaker 1: Wow, that just reminded me how much I love high space.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it hasn't updated in years.
Speaker 0: Hasn't updated since 07.
Speaker 0: Does not understand why people enjoy old man attack.
Speaker 0: Have did setting up system of security with fire shooting.
Speaker 0: Yet people still try old man attack.
Speaker 0: This hurts old man's feelings.
Speaker 0: Wants to know the secret.
Speaker 0: After all, the secret I reveal is only right.
Speaker 1: I am to pop cap.
Speaker 1: You are as more like Shono to your maker, bitch.
Speaker 1: I am what?
Speaker 1: Oh, error.
Speaker 1: I love you almost as much as I love Bagu.
Speaker 0: If you are address typed in address bar, you are check if it is correct spelling.
Speaker 0: You are high space page of open and you are want links of information.
Speaker 1: I know that Dodongo does not smoke.
Speaker 0: OK, so about me, I'm humble spectacle is an entrance to death.
Speaker 0: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: So are we done here?
Speaker 1: No more matter.
Speaker 0: We're done.
Speaker 0: Let's get on with the show.
Speaker 1: So the other weekend, the Children's Film Festival in New York City, which gets international film festival.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Which the thing I can say about it that always amazes me and almost bothers me a little bit every year.
Speaker 1: If you take like all the movies that are released and then you have a subset of that, all the movies I care about, most of them end up at the Children's Film Festival.
Speaker 0: I think that's because, you know, we care about animation more than we care about live actions.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And the Children's Film Festival is primarily animation.
Speaker 0: And what's really weird is they even show.
Speaker 0: they don't show hentai or anything.
Speaker 0: But there are some animations that they show that are like, hey, this should be for like 16 year olds and stuff.
Speaker 1: I disagree.
Speaker 1: I think that they show a lot of things that are just fine for very young kids.
Speaker 1: They're just they're kind of edgy and they're good.
Speaker 0: No, but they actually say in their program, like, you know, only 16 and up should watch this.
Speaker 0: So the other thing is that they all they show very few live action things.
Speaker 0: But those are for children.
Speaker 0: So I guess it is a children's film festival technically.
Speaker 0: But, you know, maybe they should, I don't know, may just give up and make it an animation film festival.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: But like you misspoke before, I think we need a children's film festival, too.
Speaker 0: No, we don't.
Speaker 0: And when did I misspeak?
Speaker 1: You said festival instead of festival.
Speaker 0: When did I say that?
Speaker 1: All I could picture was Hokuto Hirakuretsu Ken.
Speaker 0: I didn't I didn't say that.
Speaker 0: I don't remember saying it.
Speaker 0: You said festival.
Speaker 0: OK, that would not be appropriate for the festival.
Speaker 1: But we actually we went to one.
Speaker 1: You know, we usually go to like one thing.
Speaker 1: Last year I went with Emily and we watched.
Speaker 1: or was it two years ago?
Speaker 1: I forget.
Speaker 1: But the girl who lived through time.
Speaker 1: And this year we went to see Summer Wars, you know, Mamoru Hosoda's movie.
Speaker 0: The same guy who directed girl at the time.
Speaker 1: But this time Mamoru Hosoda was there.
Speaker 0: So yeah, we're really good at showing up at anime movies when the director is there in New York City.
Speaker 0: That seems to happen quite often.
Speaker 0: What's up with that?
Speaker 0: And also, every time we show up, all the same people are also there.
Speaker 1: I know, like errands there, you know, Ninja Consultants show up.
Speaker 1: Pizza Terrace there.
Speaker 0: It's like the New York anime community is like these same people and they just always show up to every New York anime event.
Speaker 0: And we're just like, hey, I know you.
Speaker 0: What's up?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't want to review like the dinner gala afterward, though they had really good cookies.
Speaker 0: They had this the pizza.
Speaker 0: They got pizza from across the street.
Speaker 0: It was fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: Oh, my God.
Speaker 1: I went downstairs.
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh, wow, this gala is just pizza.
Speaker 1: Seriously.
Speaker 1: But then I ate the pizza.
Speaker 1: That was some of the best pizza.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And the place was directly across the street.
Speaker 0: So I know exactly where it is.
Speaker 0: So now I can go there and it's on the subway home so I can actually stop, get pizza on the way home, get back on the subway and go home.
Speaker 1: But the only thing I want to say about the whole gala and actually talking to him, I mean, you know, Emily talked to him kind of at length.
Speaker 1: And when they did the Q&A after the movie, he was very unlike a lot of other anime directors I've seen answering questions.
Speaker 1: He was so like, I'm a normal guy.
Speaker 1: It was almost disconcerting.
Speaker 0: He was just a really normal and friendly guy.
Speaker 0: He didn't give like strange answers.
Speaker 0: He didn't go, oh, oh, oh.
Speaker 1: It was like Ikuhara with all of his.
Speaker 1: Well, I couldn't tell you why Toga did that because I'm not Toga.
Speaker 1: So you'd have to ask him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, Satoshi Kon was also sort of a normal, friendly guy.
Speaker 0: But, you know, he still had a little bit of that, you know, artist-ness to him.
Speaker 1: Though here's the thing and we realize this and I want to somehow tap this for anime conventions when we ask questions at panels.
Speaker 1: The Film Festival for Children had a lot of like five year olds asking questions, as opposed to, you know, bigger events where it's adults.
Speaker 0: It was about like, I would say, if you looked at the the demographics of people asking questions, it was like 40 percent children, 40 percent otaku and 20 percent, you know, others like adults who brought, you know, parents or, you know, whatever.
Speaker 1: There's something about little kids to where they ask the direct, obvious question that no adult ever thinks to ask.
Speaker 1: But yet everyone wants to know the answer to.
Speaker 1: And but but half the time their little kid brains just ask questions that don't.
Speaker 1: It's not like they're dumb questions.
Speaker 1: It's that it's not a question.
Speaker 1: It was a bunch of random words that this kid strung together.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like half the kids ask these fucking great questions.
Speaker 1: Like, why did you call him love machine?
Speaker 1: And then I felt really stupid when he answered the question.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, whoa, that's a great freaking question, little kid.
Speaker 0: And then the next kid will come up and be like, so in the Cosmo technology stuff, like literally, that's what the kid will just put a bunch of words and proper nouns in the movie together.
Speaker 1: And then he'll be like, or they'll preface their question with this big global statement, like in light of the fact that you were technology and there was a lot of something, something, something, something in the movie.
Speaker 0: So, yeah.
Speaker 1: And then they wouldn't actually ask a question.
Speaker 1: And the translator would be like, I'm pretty sure the translator was saying to him, yeah, the kid didn't actually ask a question.
Speaker 1: Say something about Kim Cosmo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So and the thing is, the translator was pretty great.
Speaker 0: We got to I forget.
Speaker 0: I should have talked to her to be like, hey, give me your card.
Speaker 0: So we yes, we need you and we need a good translator.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm pretty sure Pete to terror got some information from her.
Speaker 0: I hope so.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but I don't want to get it.
Speaker 0: That was like about the movie.
Speaker 1: Yes, the movie Summer Wars.
Speaker 1: And I can't stress this enough.
Speaker 1: We're not going to spoil anything till the very end of the show.
Speaker 1: Then we'll have a spoiler.
Speaker 0: Are you going to spoil it?
Speaker 0: I didn't know.
Speaker 0: We don't even really need to spoil it.
Speaker 1: Not really.
Speaker 1: We'll see if there's a if there's a spoiler line.
Speaker 1: I think there's a couple of things I want to spoil the very end.
Speaker 1: But don't even bother listening to this review.
Speaker 1: Just go see the movie.
Speaker 1: It's an anime movie.
Speaker 1: There aren't that many that are good even or that are in America.
Speaker 1: Legit.
Speaker 0: Also, I want to point out, you know, this is a Madhouse production.
Speaker 0: So she cons doing Madhouse hosted as doing Madhouse.
Speaker 0: Madhouse is like, I get on top of the anime world right now, basically.
Speaker 0: Not that they weren't before.
Speaker 1: Look at Hosanna.
Speaker 1: He came out of the same kind of.
Speaker 1: you know, he's not one of those people who like director, director, director.
Speaker 1: He's key animator, key animator, key animator, key animator, director.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, key animator is not in between.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like key animators.
Speaker 0: Basically, you are the real animator doing the real animation work.
Speaker 0: You know, you're drawing all the most important pictures.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, it's not like he was a nobody.
Speaker 0: You know, he was doing all the real hard, important grunt work.
Speaker 0: And then he just kept doing it and kept doing it and kept doing it.
Speaker 0: And he made the connections and he networked.
Speaker 0: And then he got a directing job doing like a. did he do like Digimon movie?
Speaker 1: He did the Digimon movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And then from there, it's like, well, you did Digimon movie.
Speaker 0: Now you can do real movies and now.
Speaker 0: All right, you're good.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And for anyone who doesn't know, he actually, you know, he did The Girl Left Through Time.
Speaker 1: He also did Superflat Monogram, which you can just find that like on YouTube.
Speaker 1: It's a short.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's very Murakami.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, you know, Summer Wars is also very Murakami as well, even though I don't know if Murakami actually had a hand in it.
Speaker 0: But there was a lot of things that there is no debate that they are super flat.
Speaker 0: I think the world of Oz is super flat.
Speaker 0: There is no question.
Speaker 1: I think Oz just really like Superflat.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: You know, it fits.
Speaker 1: I like Superflat.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I really only used it like in the Land of Oz or is incredibly appropriate.
Speaker 0: And he didn't use it like out in the you know, in the the rest of the movie.
Speaker 0: And it actually created this really nice contrast.
Speaker 1: It did.
Speaker 1: I enjoyed both parts equally.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the Summer Wars anime movie has a pretty good like hook plot.
Speaker 1: It's basically this cute girl, you know, high school drama, summer kind of typical anime movie comes into these two nerds who have this kind of they're doing their summer.
Speaker 0: Basically, yeah, their summer job is like taking care of like the virtual world.
Speaker 0: They're like, you know, they got like internships at the virtual world.
Speaker 0: They're just doing like low level maintenance work.
Speaker 1: And she's like, I need someone to do a summer job for me.
Speaker 0: And they're like, we already have jobs.
Speaker 1: And she's like, you'll basically come with me in my grandparents house.
Speaker 0: And one guy's like, I'll do it.
Speaker 0: He's like, the other guys, they like fight over it.
Speaker 0: But he fight over it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Basically, she hires this guy to do some unspecified job with her and ends up taking him out into the mountains where her family lives in Ueda in a gigantic mansion.
Speaker 0: Oh, shit.
Speaker 1: And the movie just escalates from there.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: When I saw the trailer for the movie, right, I thought that it was.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize it was so much about technology.
Speaker 0: I thought it was going to be one of those like, you know, having fun in the country sort of summer can't feel good things, which appeals to me a lot.
Speaker 0: You know, I thought it was going to be like, you know, people playing flag football or whatever, you know, and having a good time in the summer.
Speaker 1: I didn't get that.
Speaker 1: I got this more.
Speaker 1: I don't want to say chocolate wars, but this kind of like.
Speaker 0: I didn't think it was like chocolate.
Speaker 1: No, but I expected this weird, like high level feeling conflict that occurs on a very low level among kids out with families.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it did have some of that, though.
Speaker 0: It did have some of that, you know, go to, you know, hanging out in the, you know, in the country during the summer kind of feelings.
Speaker 0: And I like those feelings.
Speaker 1: But the real plot is independently.
Speaker 1: Imagine a future, a real future, you know, from this point where my space and wow and all these things kind of Facebook and Second Life make a baby.
Speaker 0: And every single thing in the world is on that.
Speaker 0: People don't use websites or email like that is the Internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: This Facebook and Second Life had a baby.
Speaker 0: And that is it.
Speaker 0: Everyone just uses that on their cell phones, on their DSS, on their computers, on their TVs, everyone just, you know, telephones, interfaces directly through the Facebook Second Life thing.
Speaker 0: And they call it the land of Oz.
Speaker 0: But that thing independently is super flat Murakami all the way, which is really weird because it's like there are banks doing business here and it looks like fucking Murakami.
Speaker 0: It's like, really?
Speaker 1: I don't know if I can buy this, but I love how the movie opens with that whole like sequence about like, welcome to Oz, make your avatar.
Speaker 1: They like make a couple of avatars, the little monkey.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And, you know, they show you a lot about this world.
Speaker 1: There are so many different, like crazily different, cool avatars.
Speaker 1: They really kind of pulled off the.
Speaker 1: these are all real people, like what it would really look like if the Internet looked like that.
Speaker 0: Mm hmm.
Speaker 1: And the plot plot of the movie is basically that this kid, you know, was up in the summer camp and someone texts him that summer camp.
Speaker 1: It's not a summer camp.
Speaker 1: Text him this weird like math puzzle.
Speaker 0: So he answers it and he's like he was he always.
Speaker 0: it was a math genius, basically.
Speaker 1: And he kind of accidentally, by answering this question, hacks the whole Internet and then things go crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: If you are a technical, you know, I just read this book, Damon, which is written by like a network technology specialist, like a guy who actually knew about computers.
Speaker 0: So it was really great to read a novel that was actually, you know, technologically accurate, as in, you know, it did not offend me by just making up all this computer shit.
Speaker 0: that wasn't real.
Speaker 0: It was actually like real computer shit.
Speaker 0: Summer Wars is not that Summer Wars just makes no sense.
Speaker 1: If you know anything about computer, if you're a technological person, it's basically this kid was able to find the two prime like factors of a large number.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, no, no, not really.
Speaker 0: Sorry.
Speaker 1: But the movie is just this great kind of parallel where there's this conflict in the, you know, in Oz, in this meta world.
Speaker 1: But there's also a conflict in the real world.
Speaker 1: And there's this third conflict, the baseball game.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And all the baseball game is just sort of like this metaphor that they keep cutting away to.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: But all three kind of track parallel.
Speaker 1: And you follow all of them at the same time to this final end conclusion.
Speaker 1: And it it's a romp.
Speaker 1: It's just great.
Speaker 1: It was it's crazy fun to watch this movie.
Speaker 0: It's a whole lot of fun.
Speaker 0: And, you know, it's got something for pretty much, you know, like everybody, like if you're a serious, like if you're looking, you know, it doesn't have too much romance, I guess it only has a tiny bit.
Speaker 1: The thing is, the romance it has is, I think, really good.
Speaker 0: It's all right.
Speaker 0: And it's got you know, it's it's got like, you know, some serious parts.
Speaker 0: It's got a lot of stuff for kids.
Speaker 0: It's got a lot of, you know, like thoughtful things.
Speaker 0: It's got a really good animation.
Speaker 1: And the characters are all really, oh, my God, there are a million characters and every one of them is very fleshed out and very iconic.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And they're all you know, they're cool.
Speaker 0: It's like you like them.
Speaker 0: You know, you either like or dislike the ones you're supposed to like or dislike in the correct proportions almost right away.
Speaker 0: You know, they're not like, oh, who cares about these people?
Speaker 0: It's like you care about pretty much all of them.
Speaker 0: And even the ones that you might not care strongly about, you know, positively or negatively, they at least, you know, have something to them.
Speaker 0: So they stand out.
Speaker 0: They're not just like faceless, bland, you know, might as well be a stick figure.
Speaker 1: What I like is there's a lot of atmosphere around like the family house where they're staying and how the family is still like.
Speaker 1: they're a modern family, but they're so like proud of their ancient Japanese heritage and they're like the retainers of the family name and they make a big deal about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's like, you know, it's surprising that this is, you know, you know, I guess nominally, you know, Japanese like they're acting like a Japanese family would is really similar the way my family is.
Speaker 0: You know, they're hanging out in the house.
Speaker 0: All the ladies are in the kitchen cooking and all the dudes are watching the sports in the other room.
Speaker 0: But, you know, it's like it's just like my family is when there's some sort of family get together.
Speaker 1: Of course, there's the whole weird dichotomy later where, like all the guys and some of the girls are basically planning the war.
Speaker 1: And meanwhile, all the more level headed members of the family are just like, what the fuck is up with those guys while they're like chopping carrots in the kitchen and doing all the normal stuff?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's hard to say which character I like the most because King Cosmo just kind of I know it's like King God, even though he basically never wins anything, they make like this.
Speaker 0: Imagine if, like, you know, they built you're watching Fist of the North Star and they built up Kenshiro and it's like, oh, shit.
Speaker 1: And they show you Kenshiro killing like everybody.
Speaker 1: And then episode two, Kenshiro just never gets a break.
Speaker 0: Every has to fight a real bad guy.
Speaker 0: It doesn't work out, but it doesn't matter because he's still fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: King Cosmo is way cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the grandma is also way cool.
Speaker 1: The grandma is basically a gecky guy hero.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: In every sense of the word.
Speaker 0: And I also I really like, you know, all like, you know, the like the firefighter and the policeman,
Speaker 1: the fishing uncle with the squid,
Speaker 0: the fishing uncle with the squid is basically this is this array of uncles and the uncles are all like firemen, EMTs, policemen, all this sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: And they're all really awesome.
Speaker 1: Well, that's the thing.
Speaker 1: The family's so big.
Speaker 1: Everyone in the family has some crazy thing like their thing is the SDF secret guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but even even the bad family trader is kind of wobbly scared.
Speaker 0: I'll be scared.
Speaker 1: I like his character.
Speaker 1: And he kind of reminds me of the guy because he looks like, you know, an evil guy.
Speaker 0: You know, the visual designs of the characters are do a really good job of looking like real people and also matching the personality of the character and the avatars of the character.
Speaker 0: characters in the world of Oz match the personality and look of the real person.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're right.
Speaker 1: Like every character is so iconic of their personality.
Speaker 1: But then their avatar is the same thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like the sports girl who basically doesn't care about any of this and just trying to watch the baseball game.
Speaker 0: One thing that really gets me about this movie that I'm still trying to figure out is how they got away with so much trademark infringement.
Speaker 0: Usually when you watch like a U.S.
Speaker 0: movie, right, and they're drinking soda, it won't be Coke or Pepsi unless Coke or Pepsi paid for product placement.
Speaker 0: It'll always be like, you know, Cola X or something, you know, those make something up to use in the movie.
Speaker 0: They won't show any product logos or anything.
Speaker 0: In Summer Wars, they show the girls where it is wearing a Red Sox jersey, drinking Dr.
Speaker 0: Pepper one, the drinking Dr.
Speaker 0: Pepper, real iPhone, the real iPhones and other to other cell phones from Japan, real brand names on, you know, the televisions and all these sorts of other devices.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I guess there's the Dell computers.
Speaker 0: He has a Dell laptop.
Speaker 0: It says Dell on it.
Speaker 0: CNN is on the television.
Speaker 0: It says CNN, not like GNN or anything.
Speaker 1: I like this.
Speaker 1: I like this a lot.
Speaker 1: I wish more movies did this.
Speaker 0: If it was just real, I also wish because then it doesn't stand out like a sore thumb and take you out of the movie.
Speaker 0: But in because other movies take you out of the movie with it, I was taken out of this movie with it because I was like, how did they get away with it?
Speaker 0: Why didn't they get sued to all fuck?
Speaker 1: I thought that at first.
Speaker 1: But then there's no way.
Speaker 0: Apple and Apple and they had Windows, the computers had Windows seven on the desktop.
Speaker 0: Literally, King Cosmo logo and everything.
Speaker 1: King Cosmo just made me forget.
Speaker 0: Yeah, King Cosmo is the fucking shit.
Speaker 1: Also, the whole thing at the end with the Hanafuda.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Hanafuda is.
Speaker 0: I still don't know how to play Hanafuda.
Speaker 0: And I tried to learn at Zenkai Con because I read the rules, kind of.
Speaker 0: It looks like a stupid game, to be perfectly honest.
Speaker 0: Probably, but but it plays a major role in this movie.
Speaker 1: It is used to proper effect in this movie.
Speaker 0: It really didn't matter what game it was, you know?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I like that it was Hanafuda because it's like an old Japanese traditional game.
Speaker 1: that was the traditional game of the family.
Speaker 1: And then it matters in the end.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, you know, that also reminded me a lot of my family, you know, as we have all these games that, you know, we would play like my family likes to play Michigan Rummy, which is also a crap game.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: Michigan Rummy is also terrible.
Speaker 1: Scott, I'm from Michigan.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So, you know, I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: It's terrible.
Speaker 0: So, you know, there are other games you play, though, like Rummy Q. Rummy Q is pretty big in my family.
Speaker 0: It's also a terrible game.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know, that the game has a special traditional, you know, sentimental value in the family.
Speaker 0: So the fact that their family had Hanafuda as their sentimental game, it was like I could really identify with the family in this movie pretty strongly.
Speaker 0: And I think that actually because of that, I think that my actual family will probably like this movie a whole lot.
Speaker 0: I think when it comes out on DVD, they'll probably enjoy it.
Speaker 1: This is another one of those anime movies where I cannot picture the kind of person who would not like it.
Speaker 0: Like if you want to get a, you know, a moderately close idea to what my family would be like at, you know, like a birthday party or, you know, Thanksgiving or something, you watch this movie and, you know, minus the world changing computer events in the world of Oz, it's pretty close, you know, as close as any movie is going to get, I think ever.
Speaker 1: You know, I got to say, though, I really like Natsuki, the main character, too.
Speaker 0: He's he's pretty good because, you know, that's Kenji.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about the girl.
Speaker 0: Oh, the girl.
Speaker 0: You think the girl's the main character?
Speaker 1: Well, the girl and the guy are both very nice.
Speaker 0: The main character, the girls, the girl is like, you know, the supporting number two character.
Speaker 1: Look at all the cover art for everything.
Speaker 1: And the girl is the front because remember, she's the one who kind of like picks up the flame of the family and becomes like she's going to be exactly like the grandma was.
Speaker 0: That is true, is that she is perhaps the central character in the plot.
Speaker 0: She's the linchpin, but the it is told from the perspective of the dude.
Speaker 1: But that's it.
Speaker 0: He's and he has more screen time.
Speaker 0: And I guess he has a larger role in the, you know, the how the events turn out.
Speaker 1: See, I feel like the story is not about him because he doesn't really grow or change much as a character.
Speaker 0: It's just, you know, but what it is is like you're coming into this family.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But you're not in the family.
Speaker 0: So he serves as, you know, the outsider to the family that you can latch onto and also be the outsider to the family and learn about the family of care, you know?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they really the film really catches the idea, like the way you feel if you're staying with someone's crazy family and you don't really know any of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like if I just made a movie of my family, but it was from my perspective, right, you wouldn't really learn anything because I know all these people.
Speaker 0: But if you made the film from Rims perspective coming over to Thanksgiving, it'd be like, oh, I'm learning who grandma is.
Speaker 0: I'm learning who, you know, Aunt Cheryl is.
Speaker 1: I think she's the main character because you look at her and look at what happens, even while Biscay isn't really the main character.
Speaker 0: Now, what Biscay is, is not even close to the main character, but he's important.
Speaker 0: But he's basically just like a conflict item.
Speaker 1: What I would say is that look at what the history of the family, not spoiling anything and what had happened, you know, what 10 years ago and all that business and look at like the whole history of the of Sakai, the grandma, and how she ended up and who she was at the end.
Speaker 1: And you see that the exact same process is happening for Natsuki.
Speaker 1: Of course, like these events are what are making her exactly like her grandma, a bad ass with a grandma, a bad ass, the grandma pulls out that friggin telephone nogginada.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's it tries to kill and not to spoil anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think the telephone scene was even more bad as you know.
Speaker 0: Another thing is that the emotions of the people are very realistic.
Speaker 0: It's not melodramatic, like, say, you know, Leiji Matsumoto movies are.
Speaker 0: Everyone had very realistic real world emotion.
Speaker 0: They cry when it's appropriate to cry at the appropriate amount and type of crying, you know, the appropriate, you know, amount and type of anger.
Speaker 0: You know, everything was you know, it was slightly exaggerated because it is an animated, you know, movie.
Speaker 0: But, you know, it wasn't.
Speaker 0: it was very, you know, realistic, I think, in that sense.
Speaker 0: And thus, you know, it felt good to watch.
Speaker 1: Plus, the animation is just beautiful.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, it's a it's a madhouse movie, but I mean, with full, you know, Japanese anime movie monies from a high quality studio.
Speaker 0: So, you know, it's pretty much like, you know, Satoshi Kon movie level of animation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but especially they almost all the fights and things in the super flat world are just really, really well done.
Speaker 0: So and the other thing is that they used a lot of, you know, I mean, obviously they use computers to animate most of the movie as any anime these days.
Speaker 0: But the world of Oz is like computer generated.
Speaker 0: But it's supposed to be because it's, you know, the computer computer world and outside the world of Oz.
Speaker 0: You know, you can't really if there is computer animation, you can't tell.
Speaker 0: You know, it's it's all, you know, 2D animated style.
Speaker 0: So it works really awesomely.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Plus, the movie kind of just escalates and escalates and escalates.
Speaker 1: They're like four square bosses.
Speaker 0: That is the one flaw I saw in it.
Speaker 0: And that's it's sort of kept square bossing too much.
Speaker 0: I felt like they should have.
Speaker 1: They needed one less square boss.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They needed one or two less square bosses.
Speaker 0: And then it would have been, you know, but and just, you know, sort of extend the conflict.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, look at how it worked out with the first square boss, the castle thing they do.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: It's like, oh, that will take care of this.
Speaker 1: And then it all you know what happens after that.
Speaker 1: And it's like this frantic action in the virtual world, frantic action, frantic action of all the people doing the thing in the virtual world, in the real world.
Speaker 1: And then the thing that broke it all, it cuts back to the guy in the real world is really slowly kind of like, I don't want to be doing this there.
Speaker 1: Job done.
Speaker 1: That got that jerk.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, is there anything else to say about this movie?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: This movie is great.
Speaker 0: The music was, you know, pretty good.
Speaker 0: It's not like I get the soundtrack or anything because I can't even remember any song from it.
Speaker 1: But yeah.
Speaker 1: But you didn't remember any songs from Giant Robo, which has one of the best anime soundtracks in the history of anime.
Speaker 0: But I do remember that while I was watching it, that there was some music that I enjoyed.
Speaker 0: I just don't remember what that music was.
Speaker 0: So, you know, I'll give it.
Speaker 0: I'll give it a B plus on the musics and such.
Speaker 1: I will admit, I really not to keys avatar because everyone has their avatar is crazily cute.
Speaker 0: I like the guy who's the dumpling.
Speaker 1: I like that one, too.
Speaker 1: But I think hers and King Cosmo are the best ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, King Cosmo is, you know, King Cosmo is that character where he's.
Speaker 0: he's not ultimately, you know, deep or super important.
Speaker 0: He's just like wicked cool.
Speaker 0: He's there for the kids, but he's just so awesome.
Speaker 0: It's just like, all right, let's just make some character that is just fucking so awesome.
Speaker 1: Halsey was kind of like that, too, with all the kids, like he answered something about what character you like the most.
Speaker 1: And the kid was kind of like, oh, and he was like, I should have just said King Cosmo because they're like, you know, director of this movie.
Speaker 0: What was your favorite character?
Speaker 0: I think the grandma is my favorite character.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe I should have said King Cosmo.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, it's King Cosmo is just so fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: I got to admit, I also really like Love Machine's character design.
Speaker 0: He looks like he has a great character design is don't really.
Speaker 0: I didn't really like the character, except when he was griefing everybody.
Speaker 1: He was kind of doing it the way that, like, 4chan kids were actually like the love machine.
Speaker 0: better before he transformed.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, while he was still like, you know, before he transformed while he was still stealing Kenji's character.
Speaker 0: It was I think it was that was really fun.
Speaker 0: That part.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, well, there's the three levels of him.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's the, you know, demon at the end, big black thing.
Speaker 0: Oh, right.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Square boss style.
Speaker 1: He was creepy when he was just stealing and kind of comedic.
Speaker 1: But then he basically turned into the bad guy from a fighting game.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: I don't think it was the summer wars.
Speaker 0: It'll be on DVD eventually.
Speaker 0: You know, I mean, Girl Who Left Through Time is on DVD in the U.S Summer Wars will almost definitely be on DVD in the U.S.
Speaker 0: eventually.
Speaker 1: There's no reason for me to spoil anything.
Speaker 1: The final thoughts I would have to say about this movie are five minutes worth at most, and frankly, just there is no one who will not like this movie.
Speaker 1: If you find them, let us know, because there's something wrong with them.
Speaker 1: This movie is just great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to tell you that it's the best movie ever.
Speaker 0: Oh, my gosh.
Speaker 0: Citizen Kane, Akira, Paprika.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Ghibli level.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I think it's about the same as Topeka in terms of qualities.
Speaker 0: You know, it's it's that kind of.
Speaker 1: it's like a Tokyo Godfather's quality, like exactly the same awesomeness, same feeling, same like romp ride through just this this fantasy, awesome adventure start to finish.
Speaker 0: Like, you know, so, you know, if if I was giving, you know, numeric scores, it would give it the exact same numeric score of awesomeness.
Speaker 0: And it would be a high score, like at least nine out of ten as Tokyo Godfather's got.
Speaker 0: So Summer Wars is good.
Speaker 0: Go watch it by whatever means necessary.
Speaker 1: And of course, if you like it, I'd recommend checking out The Girl Who Left Through Time, which is very, very similar.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I still haven't watched it.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll get it.
Speaker 1: Oh, my gosh.
Speaker 1: I have to see it.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew dot com for show notes, discussion, news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows, SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.