Speaker 0: It's Thursday December 9th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek night.
Speaker 0: This is the year 2000 and y'all.
Speaker 0: Tonight on geek nights we discuss the book club book World War Z by Max Brooks.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Oh You managed not to say that the book sucks in the opening part of the show.
Speaker 0: You want to know why I was yawning.
Speaker 1: yeah We got some yawning issues over here.
Speaker 1: are they cleared up now?
Speaker 0: yeah, we got some opening issues, too.
Speaker 0: I think Scott is the perpetrator of the yawning.
Speaker 0: I think he started this whole thing.
Speaker 1: It's not you can't blame someone for a yawn.
Speaker 1: That's like blaming someone for pooping.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: It's natural.
Speaker 0: It's gotta happen much like that Katsu kind of way back.
Speaker 0: I mean we all got sick like everyone in the goddamn world got sick.
Speaker 0: But I do believe that you were the one who got sick first.
Speaker 0: Okay, you brought this illness upon the rest of us much like the yawning just now.
Speaker 1: yeah You know I mean you could blame someone for getting sick if they did something stupid.
Speaker 1: for example Rub sewage on an open wound and get infected.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: or you know sedentary lifestyle Not wipe their ass or swim in the Ganges.
Speaker 1: You know I mean there are plenty of ways someone can get themselves drink dirty water get dysentery right unpasteurized milk.
Speaker 1: Yeah, go out where all the nasty Malaria mosquitoes are and rub yourself in mosquito food whatever they eat.
Speaker 0: uh blood It's a.
Speaker 1: you know cut yourself so the blood comes out.
Speaker 1: so the mosquitoes You know can they smell the blood if you cut yourself?
Speaker 0: I don't even know.
Speaker 0: I think they smell the co2.
Speaker 1: you're breathing spray some you know mosquito pheromones.
Speaker 1: They come over to you, and then right you could do all sorts of stuff, but then they fuck your arm instead of eating.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: The point is is that there are a lot of things you can do to purposefully get sick.
Speaker 1: But if someone has not done any of those things and that is the vast overwhelming majority of human beings do not Intentionally do any of those things right.
Speaker 1: so then you can't really blame someone for getting sick.
Speaker 1: It's not something they do on their own.
Speaker 0: I do avoid people who have been exposed to children if the children are sick.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got a co-worker.
Speaker 1: his kid You know is going to daycare and basically is a germ magnet.
Speaker 1: But you know if you're if you are right if you have a kid you kind of want that because that makes a healthier Kid.
Speaker 1: I you know there are studies.
Speaker 1: Then they're pretty much Figuring out that most of the allergy type kids who are allergic to everything and get sick all the time later in life are because their Parents didn't let him roll around in the mud when they were smaller, so let him roll in the mud send him to daycare.
Speaker 1: They'll get sick early on they won't get sick later.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean as long as you know as long as they don't get you know the death sickness.
Speaker 0: I rarely got sick when I worked at the hospital hanging out with hospital people.
Speaker 0: well You also got crazy Vaccinated at the hospital only to one or two things and I did get sick a whole bunch right away when I first worked there.
Speaker 0: Then I stopped getting sick.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's how it works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, imagine if you worked at the hospital when you were zero you'd be like invincible.
Speaker 0: I mean I was in the hospital when I was zero.
Speaker 1: yeah me too Big surprise.
Speaker 0: I went back when I got the really bad flu when I was like two or three ish.
Speaker 0: I went back when my brother was in the hospital when he was there, but much more importantly Scott Warm today, and no it is it is it is quite warm out.
Speaker 1: I thought I was thinking of the joke But then I realized it's not.
Speaker 1: it is one of those jokes that all the listeners are gone man's, but I'll be like oh No, what is the joke?
Speaker 1: so basically?
Speaker 1: I was like man.
Speaker 1: You know what we should totally move somewhere That's way south like the Caribbean.
Speaker 1: You know what you know why live on a bar, you know why we should move there.
Speaker 0: Why should we move there?
Speaker 1: because there's no woman?
Speaker 0: No cry That wasn't that bad.
Speaker 0: we could have made more inside you know.
Speaker 1: But I figured listeners would be like oh you guys are gay.
Speaker 1: you want to move where there's no woman.
Speaker 0: I mean when was the last time we were like?
Speaker 1: yeah, yeah Because we haven't been playing NS.
Speaker 1: Cuz.
Speaker 1: NS2 is not doing so now.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: or what is the last time?
Speaker 0: you held ten somethings Yesterday couldn't hold ten something.
Speaker 0: what ten things did you all her?
Speaker 1: she kisses a variety of flavors.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I learned that we can both have and eat ten of those I got have.
Speaker 1: we got a whole bucket, but it's it's emptying quickly at the office.
Speaker 1: I don't think I'm refilling it not on my dime.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: It's a. it's a yawning Thursday show.
Speaker 0: It's a book club show and we don't want to kind of taint the book club by doing like 20 minutes of unrelated news because Then kind of lose the timeliness of the book club show.
Speaker 1: yeah People who care about the book club fast forward and get to the book get to the book.
Speaker 0: so should we?
Speaker 0: here's a point of Order Scott other than saying the year should we do the World War Z first or should we sell the next book?
Speaker 1: I think we should sell the next book first because there might be someone who has not yet read the World War Z doesn't want to Spoil it but might be listening and therefore they won't have to skip ahead and fiddle about in the show.
Speaker 1: But if you were World War Z first then someone might have to skip around, but I got a spoiler for you.
Speaker 0: Zombies.
Speaker 0: they rise up.
Speaker 0: It sucks.
Speaker 1: I think it says that on the cover humans survive in the end.
Speaker 1: I think that's why it's not a zombie.
Speaker 0: So when I was a kid when I was pretty young like 96 I got this book.
Speaker 0: I don't even remember how I got it or how I get interested in it.
Speaker 0: I don't know if my parents bought it for me, or if I just found it or a physics teacher I don't know, but I picked up Michio Kaku's hyperspace, and I read it and It was amazing and fascinating.
Speaker 0: like that was my first knowledge of string theory or hyperspace or Multidimensionalism or anything ever that was realistic.
Speaker 1: I mean I sort of knew about Multidimensionalism kind of but I didn't know of anything else, and I never read this book.
Speaker 0: plus when I'm talking like 1995 give or take I mean maybe ish.
Speaker 0: did you know about string theory theory and quarks and super symmetry back then probably in 97 and I knew they existed.
Speaker 1: So cuz I was yeah second year of high school I definitely definitely knew of those things.
Speaker 1: hyper not that I know any more of the Detailed information that I do now.
Speaker 0: Michio Kaku is a renowned and important Physicist and kind of like Carl Sagan he goes around promoting science and scientism and people caring about science.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's a professor at CUNY which is very in the city.
Speaker 1: I can probably see it from here.
Speaker 0: yep Hyperspace that the actual title is hyperspace colon a scientific odyssey through parallel universes time warps and the 10th.
Speaker 0: Oh, I guess it was made in 1994 so I guess or at least published in 94. so I guess I read it shortly after it came out, but it basically takes all this crazy string theory stuff and Breaks it down into really accessible and understandable chunks that anyone Intelligent can grasp.
Speaker 1: so it's a nonfiction book.
Speaker 0: It's a nonfiction book.
Speaker 0: I much prefer the non fictions over the fictions.
Speaker 0: Hey, you're the one who made me read fucking World War Z. you can suck not for you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely wasn't for me.
Speaker 0: You know what I guess nonfiction isn't for you.
Speaker 1: I like some non fictions.
Speaker 0: The cool thing though harpers.
Speaker 1: I don't like.
Speaker 1: they tend to like.
Speaker 0: you know reference non fictions I don't like to read them straight through is in the end the whole last question thing that I like to bring up all the Time.
Speaker 0: oh, yeah, I love this and it also brings up flatland.
Speaker 0: I think I was a lot of action to flatland by hyperspace.
Speaker 1: no flat You know what's good about flatland really tiny this really short book.
Speaker 1: You can read it in like a day.
Speaker 0: I thought you meant the flatland.
Speaker 0: worlds like.
Speaker 0: it doesn't say how long I'll be this.
Speaker 0: I mean we know Gandalf's penis is seven inches, but we have no idea how big flatland is.
Speaker 1: you know That's you know now.
Speaker 1: I can do.
Speaker 1: I could do a whole nonfiction book if it's the shortest flatland.
Speaker 0: Flatland was fiction.
Speaker 1: I know I'm just saying if a nonfiction book is the length of the flatland to fiction What was the last nonfiction book you read?
Speaker 1: well actually I read two.
Speaker 1: There's actually a certain kind of nonfiction that I can read straight through and I've actually read two of these so far in my life The narrative nonfiction.
Speaker 1: yeah the one where it's like you wouldn't know is nonfiction if they didn't say so right?
Speaker 1: so there was the star wars or Yeah, I actually forget the title.
Speaker 1: It's like devil in the white city.
Speaker 1: Is that what it's called the Chicago World's Fair?
Speaker 1: one right, and there's also the other one I read which is about one captain kid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, so they're basically it's like.
Speaker 1: those are true stories.
Speaker 1: This is true story.
Speaker 1: a captain kid.
Speaker 0: pretty much This is the true story.
Speaker 0: true story of of ten dimensions in hyperspace.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's not.
Speaker 1: there's not characters in a narrative, and it's not you know excited.
Speaker 0: It's basically the kind of non wait wait wait, so you don't find exciting the Fundamental unifying theories of all reality.
Speaker 1: oh, I absolutely do however.
Speaker 1: I don't find exciting Reading about them for hours.
Speaker 0: Did you enjoy cosmos?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but this is like that only for string thing.
Speaker 1: was Chicago cosmos right was short Number one this is not a long book.
Speaker 1: and number two Cosmos has a lot of stories of historical figures for you know story Einstein and chapter 6 is Einstein's revenge.
Speaker 1: and while I enjoyed cosmos, right?
Speaker 1: It wasn't like I was dying to turn the page as I am in frequently in various works of fiction.
Speaker 0: All right, so what what?
Speaker 0: what kind of book should I pick next time?
Speaker 0: Maybe the Count of Monte Cristo and all Pages?
Speaker 0: That is actually one of my favorite books.
Speaker 0: I've been meaning to pick it at some point.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna read a bridge.
Speaker 1: I'll read CliffsNotes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you really do yourself a disservice.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of good.
Speaker 0: You'll miss it like the chain mail and when he stabs the dude and all the poison, and I'll just.
Speaker 1: I'll watch the movie.
Speaker 0: You realize that the Count of Monte Cristo was kind of famous for the fact that no one has ever made a good adaptation of it.
Speaker 1: I know Actually, you know we should do.
Speaker 1: you should do.
Speaker 1: You know not the Count of Monte Cristo, but you should like go sideways.
Speaker 1: You should do like the man in the iron man who is much more badass.
Speaker 0: Uh The man in the iron mask is not even a quarter as badass as the count.
Speaker 1: What are you talking about?
Speaker 0: Have you did?
Speaker 0: the count is the baddest ass there ever was.
Speaker 1: the dude was locked up for that long.
Speaker 0: So was this dude?
Speaker 1: and then he busted out and got his awesome revenge.
Speaker 0: So did the count?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean the count wasn't locked up as bad.
Speaker 0: he was locked up worse Scott And he wasn't locked up for most of his life.
Speaker 1: Yeah dungeon, but the guy in the iron mask.
Speaker 1: He was supposed to be the king.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the count was just.
Speaker 1: that's why they but why they put the mask on him.
Speaker 1: So no one would see who he was.
Speaker 1: cuz.
Speaker 1: then they would know hey, that's supposed to be the king.
Speaker 0: What the cow was just a poor sailor guy who got shanghaied into some BS.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he was a you know Just some scummy guy.
Speaker 0: Oh, he was a nice guy actually.
Speaker 0: Then he grew up to be a badass and he took everybody else out.
Speaker 1: This guy was a king.
Speaker 0: He's helping everybody.
Speaker 0: He sails dude.
Speaker 1: We should we should.
Speaker 1: someone needs to make fan arts man an iron mask first kind of Monte Cristo fight.
Speaker 0: No, no, man in the iron mask versus the count of Monte Cristo versus Batman They're basically all Batman's.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Don't think Batman could.
Speaker 0: I don't know because reading Dark Knight Returns when he's old.
Speaker 0: He's still kicking some ass.
Speaker 0: I mean the kind of Monte Cristo.
Speaker 0: He's his 40s.
Speaker 0: when he's doing is awesome.
Speaker 1: Hmm man in the iron mask was younger so as he was indeed younger he must have been like 30s, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, not as badass Actually, I have no idea how old he was.
Speaker 0: Have you actually ever actually read the man in the iron mask part of it?
Speaker 0: Oh Really part part.
Speaker 1: I know I know what they're I know what you need to know about it.
Speaker 1: There's a man in a mess.
Speaker 0: No, and he was.
Speaker 1: there were two princes, right?
Speaker 1: And one wanted to become the king and so he freaking locked his brother up in there and put a mask on him.
Speaker 1: No, and he made it.
Speaker 1: he made everyone else believe that his brother was dead.
Speaker 1: So he became the king.
Speaker 1: meanwhile the brother older brother was supposed to become the king.
Speaker 1: He was locked up and even the guards didn't know.
Speaker 1: they thought he was just some prisoner.
Speaker 1: You know who was incredibly dangerous or evil or some shit and eventually he got out and yeah, it was awesome.
Speaker 0: Well, I could pick Ulysses.
Speaker 1: I know you don't.
Speaker 1: you don't even want to pick that.
Speaker 0: No, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I've got.
Speaker 1: I've got my next three picks lined up and they are all awesome.
Speaker 0: what the little prince One.
Speaker 0: that's a good one.
Speaker 0: I almost picked it a couple times.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, I got better than that though.
Speaker 0: Seriously as a kid when I was young reading hyperspace.
Speaker 0: I was enthralled.
Speaker 0: I remember once I started reading it I obsessively like skipped most other things in my life to finish it because all I remember thinking just Constantly throughout this whole book was these are the motherfucking secrets of the goddamn universe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but shit.
Speaker 1: another thing that was like how many of the things in hyperspace are still you know?
Speaker 1: The high-level theoretical physics is changing, you know, it's quiet.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of arguments and debates in that area, you know.
Speaker 1: So it's like is this right or is the other guy right?
Speaker 0: or you know, and I don't know Well, what other guy all the other different guys like there's a specific guy to whom you were referring.
Speaker 1: I Just forgot.
Speaker 1: I just remembered that there was a guy, you know Something reason I can't remember that.
Speaker 1: It's just like, you know when you got a thing in your brain like oh I remembered there was a guy who had some crazy theory.
Speaker 1: Oh, what the hell was that guy.
Speaker 1: and I can't remember those brown guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I see them all over the place anyway.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day those brown guys by the way are groundhog.
Speaker 0: Scott didn't know what they were and one day He's like, you know those those little brown guys.
Speaker 0: They like run away when I walk by the train station.
Speaker 0: We're like Brownhogs, he's like, yeah, I don't think those are groundhogs.
Speaker 0: Those are groundhogs.
Speaker 1: No, what are those guys who come out of the hole in the ground?
Speaker 0: There's also like woodchucks beavers and all sorts of little brown guys.
Speaker 1: But I have a feeling those are woodchucks and they were not because they weren't.
Speaker 1: beavers doesn't have a flappy tail, right?
Speaker 1: You know, they didn't.
Speaker 1: they didn't come out of the ground in the holes they weren't the prairie dogs.
Speaker 0: Prairie dogs are kind of tan.
Speaker 0: They're not really brown Whatever.
Speaker 0: They also don't.
Speaker 1: tan is brown.
Speaker 0: They also don't live anywhere near here and they stand up and they're much smaller.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway, so our friend Conrad this has become an affectation of his and it wore off rapidly.
Speaker 0: I feel like it's a very useful phrase But it caused me to google for some things that I recommend you all looking out.
Speaker 0: For example, Jerry Springer not that good of a show.
Speaker 0: Jerry Springer in India.
Speaker 1: Pretty goddamn funny, you know, I gotta say though I mean like I didn't watch.
Speaker 1: I haven't even thought about Jerry Springer since the late 90s.
Speaker 1: But one time I was in a bus trip full of you know, full of teenagers and you know High school kids and we were going somewhere.
Speaker 1: I forget what the hell we were going was this high school.
Speaker 0: Okay, because you were like I was on a bus with a bunch of high school kids.
Speaker 1: I was in high school It was a field trip somewhere and they watched Jerry Springer the movie and at the time in that environment.
Speaker 1: There was some hilarity.
Speaker 0: But so this this phrase how can she slap?
Speaker 0: how can she slap?
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: there's this like game show going on and this woman is yelling at this guy and he is kind of snarky back at her and she slaps him and He not taking that shit just slaps her right back.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And then he pauses and he looks at her and he has this look on his face Like he cannot believe what just happened and he just starts exclaiming over and over again Okay, she slept.
Speaker 1: how can she slap?
Speaker 0: as everyone else proceeds to beat the crap out of him?
Speaker 0: and there's this whole.
Speaker 0: it's just There's something about the way he says it.
Speaker 0: I feel like if I like I like Conrad apparently playing a video game like Pac-Man or something and suddenly like he loses or He messes up.
Speaker 1: Okay See, I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's like should you use the?
Speaker 1: how can she slap?
Speaker 1: or Should you do?
Speaker 1: how can she blank right?
Speaker 1: So like if you know, somebody trips over like how could you trip?
Speaker 0: You know if some How can you podcast?
Speaker 1: How can you podcast?
Speaker 1: You know, should you change the verb?
Speaker 0: also later on he says very eloquently under his breath fucking son of a piece of shit.
Speaker 0: But how can she slap?
Speaker 0: does it?
Speaker 0: How can you fuck?
Speaker 0: That's my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: use this phrase.
Speaker 0: Well, I feel like it will be very useful to you in the future.
Speaker 1: All right, so oh so check this out right this?
Speaker 1: everyone's on the internet is probably seen this already but this guy He did a mashup.
Speaker 1: He mashed up two amazing things Star Wars the most frequent mashup target in the universe and Dr.
Speaker 1: Seuss a pretty frequent mashup target.
Speaker 1: and he mashed them which I don't think they've been mashed before.
Speaker 0: You know funnily enough on College Humor today.
Speaker 0: There was a children's sci-fi book spoof and it was dr.
Speaker 0: Who in a dr Seuss style, uh-huh double doctor.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know, I'll just I'll just say a couple sentences here and you'll get the idea.
Speaker 1: but there are awesome Illustrations that accompany.
Speaker 0: they're pretty good.
Speaker 1: So already this body is old But it's all that I've got.
Speaker 1: when 900 you reach looks so good.
Speaker 1: You will not snap.
Speaker 0: It's a good Yoda - it's very Susean.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's basically dr.
Speaker 1: Seuss Yoda.
Speaker 1: They got dr Seuss Java the Hut.
Speaker 1: they got dr.
Speaker 1: Seuss Darth Vader.
Speaker 1: Dr.
Speaker 1: Seuss Wookiee.
Speaker 0: You know, it saddens me that just from DDR and karaoke combined Wookiee Wookiee.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anytime I hear or see a Wookiee my first thought is not I can't make the noise or that.
Speaker 0: My first thought is the guy who has that cabinet that sounds like a Wookiee.
Speaker 1: And then did the way to make a Wookiee noise is to think about that.
Speaker 1: No you think about that that door that cabinet door.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's what I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: My second thought is Wookiee.
Speaker 0: Wookiee in the kitchen macho man is on a mission.
Speaker 1: Yep, that's right.
Speaker 0: My third thought is actual Wookiee's from real Star Wars the documentary.
Speaker 0: So you picked this book?
Speaker 1: Oh, I did pick this book, right?
Speaker 0: So, uh Wow, we're the yawning show is just continuing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the book is World War Z. I think this is a subtitle, but I don't have an oral history of the zombie an oral history.
Speaker 1: Is that right?
Speaker 0: I don't want to make fun of it.
Speaker 0: I'm trying not to.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I picked this.
Speaker 1: I normally right, you know I could tell even before I read it or before I knew anything about it just based on the title I was by Max Brooks who I later learned is actually the son of Mel Brooks, you know of.
Speaker 1: you know comedy awesomeness of Blazing Saddles and producers and you know that the real Mel Brooks You know Spaceballs.
Speaker 1: His son is Max Brooks, even though that I couldn't.
Speaker 1: I didn't know that until later.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you think this would have been funnier then right so clearly did not inherit the jeans.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I knew just from the title of the book right that this was basically one of those books that appeals to nerds With its proper noun ness, right?
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's like you could take pretty much any you know subject matter that nerds like, you know Be it like Frankenstein's monkey robot pirate ninja zombie, right?
Speaker 1: Whatever is in at the given time right and sometimes when you take those think vampires Sometimes when you take those things and mix them all together You can actually do a good job of it, right?
Speaker 1: Dr.
Speaker 1: McNinja is the perfect example.
Speaker 1: axe cop.
Speaker 1: You know also, you know, you can definitely do things that are high quality With this, you know, it's all.
Speaker 0: but at the same time for example, dr McNinja has this very pure idea of what would be awesome to a 12 year old and he knows what he's doing.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying right so, you know, I knew that World War Z was one of those things, right?
Speaker 1: But there was a chance that it was good in the dr McNinja way, but I didn't really expect it, you know to be good.
Speaker 1: I expected it to be a lot like cowboys vs aliens which I'm really surprised is becoming a movie because that is the worst comic book that I have bought in like Years, that's one of those comic books where you see it at the show.
Speaker 1: I bought it off of the order form based on the title But that's it.
Speaker 0: The title is all there is seeing the title is the only thing you need to see.
Speaker 0: you've already read the entire comic.
Speaker 0: that Concept is the entirety of the idea.
Speaker 1: Yes, so I'm like, okay someone wrote a book about zombies.
Speaker 1: This is gonna be just like those, you know, Pride and Prejudice and zombies.
Speaker 0: I heard those are actually okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know how good they are because I haven't read them.
Speaker 1: But you know, I assume well, maybe I sort of the book club.
Speaker 1: I categorized World War Z in that same category right as the Pride and Prejudice and zombies and all that.
Speaker 1: and I think there's a Lincoln one now, right I put it in that same bucket, you know in my brain of yeah stuff They just you know is basically pandering to nerds without actually being good and being kind of shallow like the IT crowd.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I haven't I don't know.
Speaker 1: I can't remember this, you know, but there's the you know these sitcoms.
Speaker 1: I think there's one or two of them now where it's basically the same as every other sitcom except they just instead of you know Making a joke about.
Speaker 1: you know, whatever, you know, they guess the regular sitcoms make jokes about what a regular sitcoms make jokes about.
Speaker 1: I don't know cuz I don't watch them.
Speaker 0: I mean Seinfeld was a sitcom.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: But Seinfeld made jokes about nothing.
Speaker 0: So replace all the nothing with nerd proper nouns and there you go exactly right.
Speaker 1: for example, right Seinfeld has nerdiness But he doesn't come out right out with it.
Speaker 1: He's got Superman in the background just on his desk.
Speaker 1: He doesn't actually, you know come out with the Superman and make say oh man, that's like the time and Superman occasionally does anyway anyway, so I figured how well this World War Z book it was recommended if you remember when we interviewed, you know, the Mark from from vanilla.
Speaker 1: He said he liked it.
Speaker 0: You know, I don't remember that at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he did.
Speaker 1: He suggested it to us.
Speaker 1: I was like, alright this book, you know, even if I don't like it cuz I didn't expect to like it But I give anything a chance, you know, and I did have hope that it would be doctor.
Speaker 1: We didn't do whatever.
Speaker 0: I went in with low to moderate expectations, but not bottom expectation.
Speaker 0: No, I mean, you know and it wasn't bottom by any stretch.
Speaker 1: I'll say that now but you know plus I did a similar thing with Locke Lammer.
Speaker 1: right Locke Lammer is like, okay I'm gonna pick a book that I don't think a lot of people know about but it was highly recommended And I'm pretty sure is just pandering to nerds But will be you know a a fun wild ride.
Speaker 1: so I was like, okay this book I don't know if it's good or bad, but I know that it appeals to the audience.
Speaker 0: I have.
Speaker 0: we survived the zombie apocalypse But how many of us are still haunted by that terrible time.
Speaker 0: we have temporarily Defeated the living dead but at what cost?
Speaker 0: told in the haunting and riveting voices of the men and women who witnessed the horror Firsthand.
Speaker 0: World War Z is the only record of the plague years.
Speaker 0: Yep That little temporarily there that sums up 90% of my problems with World War Z. that he writes in this infuriating.
Speaker 0: I'm so clever style and every character has this little like wink and a nod to other stuff constantly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll get we'll get to that I'll get to that.
Speaker 1: but but I picked the book because it would appeal to listeners and get people to read.
Speaker 1: You know, and I hope it succeeded in that.
Speaker 1: And I read it Scott.
Speaker 0: So how does it succeed?
Speaker 0: All right, we got everyone to read a book.
Speaker 0: Let's say that they really liked it because your zombies whatever.
Speaker 0: All right, so we're like, yeah, you should read books.
Speaker 0: Try this one.
Speaker 0: They're like, yeah, I read it.
Speaker 1: I liked it and then we shit all over the book that we just told that's fine It's it even if you like if you like it good for you And that me if you're reading and it's not a sports page or a magazine It's a book.
Speaker 1: now go and read other books that we also won't like.
Speaker 1: that are similar But you will like them and you will be reading so often funny before you came over Aaron see we're hanging out.
Speaker 0: He walks in.
Speaker 0: he sees the book on my desk.
Speaker 0: I got it.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh World War Z. That's a good book and I was just like Right, so the book right.
Speaker 1: very my opinion.
Speaker 1: it's not terrible.
Speaker 1: It's not like.
Speaker 1: I was in pain reading it.
Speaker 0: a couple of moments though There were.
Speaker 1: there were.
Speaker 1: that's the thing right is there are moments of Throughout but I wasn't in.
Speaker 1: I wasn't like.
Speaker 1: I can't go on, you know, it's so painful.
Speaker 1: well, it's just here and there I'd be like and I At the same time I cannot say that it was a page-turner.
Speaker 1: I just sort of turned the page out of habit.
Speaker 1: I wasn't like dying to read the next page.
Speaker 1: There was nothing pushing me forward, but there was also nothing pushing me back.
Speaker 1: It was just a slow walk.
Speaker 0: What's interesting to me is that I started World War Z with pretty low expectations.
Speaker 0: I mean I went into this thinking this is gonna be pretty bad, but I was pleasantly surprised like the first I don't know 20 or 30 pages.
Speaker 0: I was like, this is actually pretty engaging.
Speaker 0: Well, I like pretty well done.
Speaker 1: Well, I sort of had a similar thing right and what engaged me about the early part of the book I think was mostly the format because We're no matter what the writing or the plot or anything the the format of the book is not unique But it is rare and sort of interesting and clever right is?
Speaker 1: you know, it's this oral history of the zombie world.
Speaker 1: So basically each chapter is.
Speaker 1: it introduces you to a new character who tells their story.
Speaker 1: so it's like a whole bunch of short stories all in the same universe and You never actually get the straight-up story of the universe.
Speaker 1: What you do is you get all these individual people's stories of.
Speaker 1: you know What happened to them in the zombie war and then you add them all together and as you read more and more stories You just learn by osmosis all these, you know things that you get the whole picture of what happened in the zombie war.
Speaker 0: It lets you get away as an author with a couple of things to say.
Speaker 0: you've got good vignettes You've got good ideas for like alright, there's a real zombie apocalypse.
Speaker 0: What are the interesting bits?
Speaker 0: Well, the last stand of the military is an interesting bit or what the fuck happens in North Korea like all these individual bits.
Speaker 0: and Then you can kind of skip the before and the after and every story can be in media res right at the good part.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it also sort of gets away from.
Speaker 1: You know the the ridiculous action movie sort of thing, right?
Speaker 1: Because when even an action movie all the interesting bits have to involve the main action heroes You have to come up with sort of this ludicrous winding path for him or her to always be in some ridiculously awesome Scene or daddy to heroes that's true.
Speaker 1: But or you know, you just thought that both of them always at the right place at the right time Where the big shit is going down.
Speaker 1: and here he doesn't need to do that He can just be like, you know.
Speaker 1: And it actually is a more realistic story.
Speaker 1: that way because there's no one who's always where the action is going.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he also gets around the fact that you know, it's improbable people would survive by well These are the few people who did.
Speaker 0: these are the people with the crazy stories.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, you know in general a zombie story.
Speaker 1: everyone needs to die.
Speaker 1: No, you know, you're not.
Speaker 0: well There's like.
Speaker 0: there's two separate genres of zombie story.
Speaker 0: There's the people make it out and people don't make it out and they're like two completely different genres.
Speaker 1: The thing is it's always.
Speaker 1: the thing is for me a zombie story.
Speaker 1: They never make it out.
Speaker 1: But what you can do is you can drag it on.
Speaker 0: It's all You've seen the original night of the living dead, right?
Speaker 1: I think so.
Speaker 0: Ah Scott do they make it out?
Speaker 0: shouldn't?
Speaker 0: Because that is that I think defines the genre of that movie, which I don't think you've seen.
Speaker 1: I don't think you don't know the dead bit of me.
Speaker 0: Dawn of the Dead is very different movie from night of the living dead.
Speaker 0: I like that better Than the movie you've never seen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay But so going into this one All right It's a head like that's a crutch an author can use to really like skip to the meat.
Speaker 1: and I was excited about that Because I yeah, cuz even though it's a crush it's still for the for the writer.
Speaker 1: It doesn't hurt the reader.
Speaker 1: You're getting awesome stuff in every chapters.
Speaker 0: I want to have to deal with the hairy turtledove situation where he tells interesting some pretty realistic fiction about.
Speaker 0: you know What if the Civil War didn't resolve itself, you know, how would the next hundred years play out?
Speaker 0: But because he tells it as a straight narrative.
Speaker 0: He follows these characters I don't care about and he writes these really awkward sex scenes all over the place.
Speaker 1: You gotta come you know, a lot of people come out, you know, look at urasao, right?
Speaker 1: He comes up with a character that in you're like Oh, I don't care about this guy until the next page.
Speaker 1: when you care about them more than anything even try again.
Speaker 0: I mean brado.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right so People got.
Speaker 1: if you're gonna be a writer and you're gonna have characters You need to have that skill.
Speaker 1: where you can make someone care about a brand new person You just made up within a couple pages.
Speaker 0: But I mean it was going strong in this because the narrative was good The characters were interesting and then four or five stories in I realized that all the characters sounded the same.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean, it's sometimes you know, a character would have an accent or a manner.
Speaker 0: It was always forced and affected like it stood out like he's trying to write this guy differently.
Speaker 1: yeah, and you know, the other thing was it's like Every character like.
Speaker 1: they didn't have like varying levels of Intelligence, you know, they all.
Speaker 1: even if they like you had seen the beginning of a chapter They would you know have this, you know affectation that was unique to the character kind of but then they would.
Speaker 1: this character would sort of fall back into explaining things in the same way.
Speaker 1: every other character explained things and the way the writer explained.
Speaker 0: but coupling that with I think the the Moment when I realized I really didn't like this book like when I went from this is pretty good to this is okay.
Speaker 0: I don't like.
Speaker 0: it was the story about the woman.
Speaker 0: I say woman here because I thought it was a man until the end just because the way it was written Who was shot down and like lost out in the wilderness that was actually a later on.
Speaker 1: that one wasn't.
Speaker 0: yeah It wasn't that far.
Speaker 1: It was pretty close to.
Speaker 1: it was beyond the halfway point.
Speaker 0: Was it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I barely remember.
Speaker 0: I just felt like that moment as I forgot the entire time.
Speaker 0: It was a woman because of the way it was portrayed it sounded like every other character and most of them were guys and The whole time like well at the end the oh there really wasn't someone you're just crazy Was but
Speaker 1: I know but I saw that coming a
Speaker 0: mile away Yeah, but it was telegraphed and forced and I realized then that almost all the stories have a sort of Quote-unquote clever wink and a nod like oh, well, here's the.
Speaker 0: here's the bit about this story.
Speaker 0: Here's the shtick on this story Here's the gimmick on this story and everyone had a kind of lame gimmick stuck onto it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, sometimes I mean the thing that bothered me the most right.
Speaker 1: we're sort of the forced Nerdisms that showed up around right the otaku.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean the otaku is a huge.
Speaker 1: it is a small example, right?
Speaker 1: When they were talking about the people in the space station, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they talked about like, you know, oh, yeah There's little robots who are outside the space.
Speaker 1: you saw all the different parts of the space station, right?
Speaker 1: And he's like, oh, yeah There's the Boba's that fly around with their little and I'm all the made-up acronyms and terms from this world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: it's like okay.
Speaker 1: They made a Star Wars joke.
Speaker 1: Obviously the little robots look like Boba Fett because they have little jet packs on them.
Speaker 1: But it's like, you know, he did that, you know throwing one of those in there, you know It might make sense if the guy in the space station being a nerd I could buy that like you did.
Speaker 1: But there were like one or two of those pretty frequently Figured it all out the sandalers the water boys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like because You know, he threw these references in there and it was just.
Speaker 1: they were just so obvious thumb sticking out You know appeals to nerdism and pop culture in there.
Speaker 1: It was just like every time he did that I was just like, oh, could you have made that you know less smooth?
Speaker 1: Not not funny and also not timeless.
Speaker 0: Well, he does that too.
Speaker 0: a lot of times he'll use a new term and he'll explain what it means or he'll have a weird Footnote about something.
Speaker 0: They're like.
Speaker 0: they're like shiro tasms, but not quite on the scale of shiro.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like that doesn't you know?
Speaker 1: if it's supposed to be about zombies It's supposed to be like, you know, there should be some suspense or there should be horror or you know Even you know, there's some gore in here.
Speaker 0: There was basically zero suspense.
Speaker 0: Actually, you know, it's actually much too Light-hearted like the people aren't really that upset and the ones that are upset are upset in this just kind of unrealistic and cliched way Like they're like he writes them like alright, this guy's obviously damaged psychologically.
Speaker 0: I mean I'm gonna write him Damaged.
Speaker 0: he's the damaged guy.
Speaker 0: Maybe see how he pauses all the time See how he looks wistfully off at the sunset.
Speaker 0: It just it hurt.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean technically speaking right this is supposed to be this one guy this character.
Speaker 1: You never get to know who goes around interviewing all these people.
Speaker 1: and these are all the interviews compiled You know that were taken out of his official report because they basically in the introduction It's like oh this guy did a report on the zombie war and they handed it into the government and they made him split it Up into the personal parts and the just straight flat boring government report part.
Speaker 1: this is all the parts that were taken out, you know of the non-existent fictional report and That had personal stories all compiled in order.
Speaker 1: So this guy that did the interviews right every time He went to interview someone.
Speaker 1: It's sorta was basically the same thing right?
Speaker 1: Remember in Gasaraki the guy with no eyes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was like okay.
Speaker 1: next chapter He goes into the room and there's the guy with no eyes.
Speaker 1: He tells them about the zombie war engine X chapter.
Speaker 1: He goes into the room and there's the person with no eyes And every chapter that's what it was.
Speaker 1: he was going to see the badass guy in Australia Or the badass person in the whatever, you know the badass otaku at his play, you know Right, and you could you could rationalize that that will.
Speaker 0: only the badass has survived.
Speaker 1: Well, that's true too.
Speaker 1: But the point is every you know, it seemed like every chapter It was going to see one of these people and it was like the same scene repeated and repeated Kind of modern like current political situation satire hand-fisted in like little winks and nods.
Speaker 0: So like yeah, well when they banned what's it, you know something or legalized?
Speaker 0: What's it things?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah When they were basically he had a huge You know a lot of the stuff he put in.
Speaker 1: there was basically huge social commentary.
Speaker 1: That was not smooth at all.
Speaker 1: Like the whole thing with the drug to make a comment about.
Speaker 1: you know, the pharmaceutical industry Selling a fake medicine.
Speaker 0: that really bothered me that character who was so literally like.
Speaker 0: I just did it for the money.
Speaker 0: screw everybody.
Speaker 0: It was just so painful to read because it was so poorly done.
Speaker 1: Yeah And then oh, you know what else is pretty painful all the whole The whole military efficiency thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they went to like great lengths to talk about the guns that don't jam and the shovels that can Kill zombies and the you know, the bodysuits that they can't bite you through and it's like you mean the obvious boring side.
Speaker 0: It is definitely one of those worlds where zombies rise up and no one has ever seen a zombie movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean.
Speaker 1: and the scene where they were the US guys.
Speaker 1: They get a square and they have infinite ammo.
Speaker 0: now see the square.
Speaker 0: the way he wrote that He must have just read some history books recently or like.
Speaker 0: maybe he was like I got to look up what old military formations were like Oh Squares, yeah, that's kind of how they were.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's just all the military stuff was really unrealistically kind of painful.
Speaker 1: He would have been like, yeah We just invented cyborg and that's another thing right is it?
Speaker 1: sort of felt some points.
Speaker 1: it felt like he was talking about a near Future like 10 20 years from now.
Speaker 1: Yep, but a lot of I mean we're making a joke about the water boy.
Speaker 0: It's like no one to make a joke about the water by 10 20 years from now now kind of like how Miraculously in Star Trek most of the references to culture on earth is from the 19th and 20th century, right?
Speaker 1: You know, that's why you know, the really good stuff just doesn't you know?
Speaker 1: Don't be topical ever and your stuff will last longer and be better, you know, cuz it won't depend It won't you know only be popular for some period of time.
Speaker 1: or you know That's what separates a genre from a movement.
Speaker 1: right a movement only sticks around for a little bit.
Speaker 1: But a genre is you know, it's just forever.
Speaker 0: Well a movie like Shrek.
Speaker 0: That's basically just haha celebrity name Haha celebrity name.
Speaker 1: and I think you know, I think definitely what we're seeing now is a zombie movement, right?
Speaker 1: I don't think it's.
Speaker 1: uh, it's really a genre.
Speaker 1: I mean it is been around since what this, you know the 80s maybe that you know.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe you should watch Night of the Living Dead.
Speaker 0: See what it should really be like.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know, it's really I think it's you know going downhill.
Speaker 0: I think the the most egregious example of just the style of writing and what bothered me about it plot-wise Not all the other things is the whole North Korea bit though.
Speaker 1: We don't know.
Speaker 0: check this out.
Speaker 0: I thought of something cool.
Speaker 0: We don't know what happened in North Korea.
Speaker 0: They're just gone.
Speaker 0: Yeah Okay, no one went to find out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no one would go to find out cuz they'd be landmines.
Speaker 0: Yeah Not gonna fly over.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna take a peek.
Speaker 1: Yeah, seriously Oh.
Speaker 1: and then oh man the stuff about the the boats and The zombies in the water really unrealistic submarine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the unrealistic submarine is escape.
Speaker 0: Oh, they came back.
Speaker 1: guys China's government the guys with the with the deep-sea diving stuff.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like you tried to think of like every remote location, right?
Speaker 1: It's like a James Bond movie.
Speaker 1: He's got a ski He's got a parachute into the mountain and then ski, right?
Speaker 1: And then he's got to drive a car have a boat race, you know, he went down the checklist, right?
Speaker 1: He's got the spay outer space underwater inception of an airplane.
Speaker 1: You know, I don't think was there any car such.
Speaker 1: I don't think there was a car situation That many cars left.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he had tank situations though.
Speaker 1: Definitely, you know in Humvee situations.
Speaker 1: So, you know, it's like he went through every possible environment, you know up in the mountains down on the beach You know every went off the whole checklist but they all kind of felt the same.
Speaker 1: it's like a video game, right?
Speaker 1: you got to have the forest level and the city level and the snow.
Speaker 0: also his whole thing about Cuba and how Cuba becomes a world economic power and somehow funds the world war.
Speaker 0: Not only is Cuba little but that Geographically where it is.
Speaker 0: There is no way it would have been.
Speaker 1: okay You know what?
Speaker 1: It is a lot like DMZ right.
Speaker 1: you come with something that is never gonna happen.
Speaker 0: What if Manhattan was the line you come up with?
Speaker 1: just some really, you know, quote cool idea That is completely unrealistic on an unfeasible right like Yonkers.
Speaker 0: Why was Yonkers the standoff point?
Speaker 0: Why did?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: but but it's just he just like Yonkers I don't know.
Speaker 1: but the I mean in DMZ.
Speaker 1: they get away with it because DMZ is really about the characters More so and it sort of also has these You know, it's like these shorter Stories about.
Speaker 1: you know in a very small environment, you know It's the same character is the.
Speaker 1: you're building on them and learning about them, but this was really more about the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is this is like a world building thing, which I think is why nerds like it, right?
Speaker 1: I mean nerds seem to love you know the world building.
Speaker 1: That's why they love all these like D&D campaign settings, you know so much.
Speaker 1: It's like oh my god.
Speaker 1: It's in that campaign setting Oh my god, this is dark Sun on it.
Speaker 1: It's the greatest even though it might be the stupidest story in the universe.
Speaker 1: It's in that settings like they get there, you know, I mean there's a place for settings.
Speaker 0: I think I the only thing I really agree with you with because I like some Forgotten alums books even though I haven't read I got it alums books since I was in middle school High school early high school.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, but with the world.
Speaker 0: I think nerds are generally obsessed with world building and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: in literature and in video games and everything I'm looking at me.
Speaker 0: people play D&D and they're obsessed with the rules of like building your keep and maintaining it and playing that Specifically playing sim keep.
Speaker 1: I think it's more that you know.
Speaker 1: It's like they'll be there.
Speaker 0: people get obsessed with like or they are the lore in World of Warcraft.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean think it's like people will read Star Wars novels right and it's because it's not because you know.
Speaker 0: I mean some of them are better than others obvious, but they're not reading them because they're paragons of literature unto themselves exactly.
Speaker 1: They're not reading them because they're great novels.
Speaker 1: They're reading them because they get their jollies off of the Star Wars universe.
Speaker 1: Like they're hopped up on a particular Fictional setting, you know and that setting is enough to like, you know turn, you know poop into gold for them Whereas me it's like gold is gold and poop is poop, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, I like.
Speaker 1: I like the Star Wars universe I think but it's like I can tell the difference in gold.
Speaker 0: Lamora books are surprisingly popular is that they combine the here's a cool fantasy world and I'm gonna tell you bits about it as time Goes on with an actually good story and good writing.
Speaker 0: Well adequate writing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and all those together work.
Speaker 1: It's better than World War Z.
Speaker 0: World War Z Tells gives me a kind of flat picture of a flat world with flat characters who all sound vaguely the same.
Speaker 0: I mean the crazy like nerd otaku hikikomori who somehow saves the day has the same voice as the military general.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's kind of you know, I Mean you could sort of be like wow, they were both hardened by the zombie war.
Speaker 0: So now they have a similar voice And his and his treatment of all the different countries was pretty flat and stereotypically almost everyone Japan just killed themselves.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's what they did.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's that is.
Speaker 1: one thing is while he traveled the world and showed you stories from all over the place there wasn't a lot of He didn't really take the cultures of the different places into account as much as he took into account the geography You know It's like, you know people around the world would react very differently because they are of different cultures and they have different Outlooks on life, but he really
Speaker 0: he tended to always rely on either.
Speaker 0: Yeah The less advanced barbaric cultures were more affected because they couldn't effectively deal with it.
Speaker 0: The dictatorships were very able to deal with it.
Speaker 0: The evil governments just killed people to save the day.
Speaker 0: the good government's tried not to kill people.
Speaker 1: You know, there's no doubt that when I'm pretty sure he when he was writing this book The first thing he started with was a map right, you know, like a like an actual map of the world.
Speaker 1: That's definitely how he started writing this book You know, whereas you're supposed to write, you know, I don't know how you're supposed to write cuz I'm not an author But you know, if it's a it's a fictional book that I'm gonna write.
Speaker 1: you got to start with the character relationship kind of thing You know where you say, okay, this person's married to this bird, you know That's the.
Speaker 1: if you start writing a book that way I feel like that that's gonna result in a book I'm gonna like more than a book where you start writing it by saying, okay Well, the country of hubba-dubba is next to the country of whoop-a-doo, you know.
Speaker 0: Well one thing he did like, you know, we keep saying it's ham-fisted, but I was flicking through till I found a good example of it.
Speaker 0: I noticed whenever he needed to affect a character and make them different from other characters.
Speaker 0: He tended to just swear a lot mmm, and The whole Cuba thing was crazy.
Speaker 0: This is some.
Speaker 0: this is just a short quote from one of the characters who basically Yeah, I don't remember a single character's name.
Speaker 0: He was in Cuba and he knew Castro when Cuba became a world superpower.
Speaker 1: I actually think I was right because all of these are technically interviews of the character.
Speaker 1: You only get the characters name once at the beginning of their chapter Right, so, you know to be like, oh I went in to interview so-and-so and that's the only time that person's name is in the Book, you know, but it doesn't repeat rarely, you know rarely if ever so you don't remember anyone's name.
Speaker 0: But listen, listen carefully.
Speaker 0: see if you can hear the ham that's gonna bounce off your ears.
Speaker 0: This is someone who worked under Castro in the new superpower.
Speaker 0: That is Cuba.
Speaker 0: Can you believe the cajones of that son of a bitch speaking of Castro to not only embrace the country's new democracy?
Speaker 0: But to actually take credit for it?
Speaker 1: who sorry who talks like that genius?
Speaker 0: I mean, right It's basically right to personally preside over the first free elections of Cuba where the last official act was to vote himself out of power.
Speaker 0: That is why his legacy is a statue and not a bloodstain against a wall, right?
Speaker 1: So first of all, you can tell nobody talks like that, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, he's basically writing it as you know, he was you know narrating it, but he had to make this character say it Basically was like oh well this guy has to say well Well, you say the word cajones at the front of it and that it'll sound like that guy saying this thing.
Speaker 1: That doesn't sound like real person dialogue, but there's there's.
Speaker 0: the ham didn't even start yet There's only one more.
Speaker 0: we have hundreds of political parties and more special interest groups than sands on our beaches.
Speaker 0: We have strikes we have riots.
Speaker 0: We have protests.
Speaker 0: It seems almost every day.
Speaker 0: You can see why Shay ducked out right after the revolution.
Speaker 0: It's a lot easier to blow up trains than it is to make them run on time.
Speaker 0: What is it that mr.
Speaker 0: Churchill used to say?
Speaker 0: democracy is the worst form of government except for all the others laughter?
Speaker 1: it Yeah, like if you're gonna write dialogue It has to sounds like a person is talking.
Speaker 0: Granted dialogue is from from what every creative person has ever told me who actually does creation as their job.
Speaker 0: Dialogue is one of the hardest things to write.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, absolutely Cuz.
Speaker 0: it's easy to think what if you play Matt mean imagine someone trying to write our conversation.
Speaker 0: We're actually writing down all the words that we're saying like yeah, that's what they would say.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think what you know could he could have done?
Speaker 1: just you know One thing that what I think would have significantly improved the book an editor.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm sure there was an editor.
Speaker 1: It was professionally published.
Speaker 1: Yeah is This guy who's going around doing the interviews, right?
Speaker 1: If instead of just you know, publishing the things that he wrote Give the the new perspective of sort of you know, this guy right.
Speaker 1: so show him Traveling to meet the people in the new world and then get you know what this guy's, you know Get something about this character.
Speaker 1: also, you know, you know, he probably goes in to see someone and goes wow I was standing here, you know get what he give me give me what he's thinking right what that was?
Speaker 1: I was in this room with this totally crazy person and I was gonna freaking out right.
Speaker 0: what that also would do is now you would have a way cuz right now all that like the Sandler's and the Boba's and all these silly kind of world references to flesh out the world if he had spent if there's one contiguous narrative through the world those things would have at least felt more fitting because you'd have a Consistent narrative of the world as it is after the war instead of jumping all over the place in time and space.
Speaker 1: Yeah but if we can follow this one guy we can get his Reactions to all these different characters that he's going to visit and that you know.
Speaker 1: get that a little bit Yeah, but I mean it would really I think you know I mean it's like okay we see a person and we hear them talking and we get their story But it's like if we also get how this guy reacts to the story.
Speaker 1: It's like oh that was totally you can tell even more so that that was a crazy person or that was a badass person.
Speaker 1: It's like oh I felt in awe in the presence of this great general.
Speaker 1: it would make him seem more like a general and less like the same voice as every other character.
Speaker 1: and if he was Totally afraid and wanted to get the hell out of there in the crate when he was visiting the crazy otaku It would make him feel more like a crazy otaku even though he wasn't really that crazy, you know.
Speaker 1: Then he would with the same voice as every other kid, right?
Speaker 1: So, you know He could show more about these people by showing a person reacting to those people and by making the the author of you know the fictional author of the book in the book a Non character.
Speaker 1: we sort of lost this whole aspect there.
Speaker 0: So as down as I'm on the book I mean, it's not a bad but it's not unreadable.
Speaker 1: It's not like oh god the horror It's crystal triangle.
Speaker 0: I mean I said and I said It is the worst book.
Speaker 0: I have read in recent like in the last decade or so.
Speaker 1: We don't read that many bad books.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like I said cowboys vs.
Speaker 1: Aliens is like the worst comic I've read in years because I don't buy really bad or read really really bad comic.
Speaker 0: I mean when I read Locke Lamora, that was one of the worst written books.
Speaker 0: I had read in recent memory.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're reading the second one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz they're Just cuz it's the bottom of my scale.
Speaker 0: doesn't mean that it's that bad.
Speaker 0: our scales really high.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is way high but part of it's that you know.
Speaker 0: Locke Lamora was written adequately and books like the Prince of Nothing or Kevlar and clay are written excellently.
Speaker 0: This is written mediocrely, but it also tells a pretty bland story.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like you gotta have at least one of those things.
Speaker 1: But if you're but you know, if you're a nerd who really gets you know Like I said jollies off of worlds, right and or jollies off of the fact that there are zombies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you want job and you think and you think that things like a bunch of guys standing in a square with infinite ammo Oh, man, it's just such a cool.
Speaker 1: You just think it's so cool
Speaker 0: or what happens in Antarctica
Speaker 1: And you're just like oh man, that's so cool and you know, I mean like if I was a teenager This would be the awesomest right because all you did when your teenager was thinking about awesome stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, some zombies weren't big back then.
Speaker 1: No, they weren't.
Speaker 1: but I was thinking about other stuff awesome like that, you know, so You know, it was big back then is from the 90s.
Speaker 0: You know action movies.
Speaker 0: a bunch of generic Libyan terrorists take over the building.
Speaker 0: Are you a bad enough dude to kick their ass?
Speaker 1: You know, I can I recommend the book to a certain audience?
Speaker 1: right the audience that will enjoy it immensely.
Speaker 1: But I don't you know put a stamp on it saying ah, this is good.
Speaker 1: It's you know, it's not worthy of any Prizes.
Speaker 0: this is not a book.
Speaker 0: I would have read to completion were I not forced to buy Scott.
Speaker 1: I Would not have read it period if I didn't think that you know, it would get people to read.
Speaker 0: I'm curious what you guys thought of it.
Speaker 0: I mean it was okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think that a lot of people you know liked it probably for the reasons that I just said and that I got them to Read and they're reading.
Speaker 1: reading is good.
Speaker 1: That was that is the goal is to get people to read but from now on I'm only gonna pick books that I actually Like.
Speaker 1: in fact, I'm going to pick my favoritest books of ever.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna turn the tables all the other way.
Speaker 0: I also can't fault max Brooks at all because this is the next logical step.
Speaker 0: I mean, he hasn't written that much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he wrote that zombie survival guide which sold so well plural right to the same audience.
Speaker 1: So now, you know, he could just come out with this.
Speaker 1: It was a New York Times bestseller, right?
Speaker 1: If you're making money keep it up, dude.
Speaker 1: I mean if I was him, I wouldn't change it a bit you wouldn't get me to buy World War Z Sequel, but my world war X is that he becomes a better author.
Speaker 0: and you know, I haven't written.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you only get better with more practice.
Speaker 0: There is no way in my mind that he goes back and looks at the books.
Speaker 0: He's like that is perfect?
Speaker 1: No, not at all.
Speaker 1: But if you're making money, what do you care right?
Speaker 1: I mean plus.
Speaker 0: maybe I'll get better.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll do something else.
Speaker 1: dude isn't doing anything.
Speaker 1: He's a published author.
Speaker 1: He saw his bestseller.
Speaker 1: I doubt he has another job besides writing.
Speaker 0: also everyone we talked to who we trust who said this book was good.
Speaker 0: on follow-up They all listen without exception to the audiobook which apparently takes departures from the novel and has really good actors.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 1: We are not audiobook people and you know, people are gonna say audio books are the same as reading.
Speaker 1: Well, okay Look if you want to get the story, right you want to know what happened you want to experience the drama or whatever?
Speaker 0: You want Morgan Freeman to read it?
Speaker 1: okay, an Audiobook is gonna be the same or possibly even better or maybe a little bit worse depending on the reading than the real book Right.
Speaker 1: It's not like watching the movie where you're gonna be missing all this stuff.
Speaker 1: You know if you watch Let's see, I don't know Lord of the Rings the movie versus reading the book, right you're Missing you're missing a whole thing.
Speaker 1: It's not even the same story really, right?
Speaker 1: Well, if you hear an audiobook of Lord of the Rings, that's well read and I'm sure there's plenty of them Right or the radio drama you're gonna get the same story.
Speaker 1: There's not like some fact that you don't know, you know all the characters, you know what they did Experience.
Speaker 0: now you're beholden to the interpretation of the person reading it in terms of their inflection their tone.
Speaker 0: They're true pause
Speaker 1: but I mean the real reason that I encourage reading over audiobook is because Reading the physical act of using your eyes to read a word and translate it to an idea in your brain Exercises a different muscle in your brain, right then does the processing audio into words into ideas?
Speaker 0: Also listening to an audiobook like even if the audiobook were word-for-word this book, which I don't think it is I don't know if I could listen to.
Speaker 0: we'll see.
Speaker 1: but I think most audiobooks are word-for-word.
Speaker 0: the book Yeah, but I heard that this one took some liberties.
Speaker 0: I don't actually know.
Speaker 0: possible because they got big actors.
Speaker 0: You don't get big actors to have them play a perfect part.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: I mean what made Star Wars great the fact that Harrison Ford changed the fucking lines.
Speaker 1: I know Well played Yes, but I was proud of that.
Speaker 0: But like when you read like reading cavalier and clay or the prince I just keep using they're good examples of the prince of nothing or even the count of Monte Cristo.
Speaker 0: the Physical words as they are printed on the page the way they are arranged the meter in the flow Can be a beautiful thing.
Speaker 0: like that is an artistry independent of the story.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean like I was saying the reason I want people to read a book and not the audiobook Even if the audiobook is good is to exercise that muscle in your brain.
Speaker 1: That is it.
Speaker 1: that is basically.
Speaker 1: what's the word for when a muscle is atrophied?
Speaker 1: You know, it's atrophied because you're not reading books, right?
Speaker 1: I mean reading the internet.
Speaker 1: It's not the same muscle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are studies about this.
Speaker 0: I read play a much more cynical role if you want to sound like a smarter person.
Speaker 0: Mispronouncing something is more kind of attuned to intelligent people or at least perceptive.
Speaker 0: It's perceived to be a trait of more intelligent people than misspelling something Because when you misspell things it implies that you have heard these words but not read them.
Speaker 0: if you mispronounce them It implies that you've read these words, but not heard them.
Speaker 0: Mmm, and the latter definitely has a perception of more intelligence.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean not true.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying I mean just.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: it's something that you can use that to your advantage.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you should you know reading is important.
Speaker 1: You need to exercise all the muscles.
Speaker 1: Okay, she read.
Speaker 1: Okay, if you just want to know the story the audiobook does the perfect job, right but Kind of like.
Speaker 0: look at Harry Potter.
Speaker 0: I like the story of Harry Potter.
Speaker 0: I cannot read those books, right?
Speaker 1: But if you want can't.
Speaker 0: so what I did?
Speaker 0: I read spoilers.
Speaker 1: if you want If you want the skill and the exercise part of your brain, you gotta read the book Even if you know audiobook might be better who knows.
Speaker 1: so?
Speaker 0: so if you like this and you haven't read any of the other books That we talked about I would recommend of all the books we've suggested in the geek nights book club Reading the lives of Locke Lamora next because it
Speaker 1: is the most the most similar of the book club books.
Speaker 0: Not that there are that many book club books but the difference is that Locke Lamora and World War Z Do the same kinds of things.
Speaker 0: Locke Lamora just does all those things as it like.
Speaker 0: the author does them better.
Speaker 1: it's sort of the same category of book.
Speaker 1: that is not serious, but it's fun and enjoyable, you know.
Speaker 0: But what you'll be able to do is if you don't if you're like why you're so down in World War Z it was fine.
Speaker 0: read Locke Lamora, which is the same kind of thing and Hopefully by the end of it It'll be obvious to you that is just as a book just as a book ignoring the story is better written That if that style or that like if good writing like that?
Speaker 0: Well, I keep saying good.
Speaker 0: if adequate writing like that had been used in World War Z World War Z would have been a much better Book, even if the story were word for word event for event the same.
Speaker 0: Yep I guess it couldn't be word for word the same.
Speaker 1: when you can see when you can you know begin to tell what writing is Better than what other writing then you'll.
Speaker 1: you'll begin to understand what books are better than what other books or in the very least you can Disagree with us intelligently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the only way that you can do that is by reading a lot.
Speaker 1: You know if you want to argue about books and you're not well read you basically have to shut up.
Speaker 1: So I suggest reading now.
Speaker 0: I mean consider this.
Speaker 0: I could make the argument that the bland and flat style of World War Z and that all the characters sound the same was Intended to convey the idea that the entire world all these people with different lives different cultures different Geographies because geographies so big we're kind of because of the shared experience of the zombies all became very similar like a world culture spawned Independently of location and was.
Speaker 1: it was a bit of a macross Ian watch many in situation.
Speaker 1: There was definitely that message was in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean I could make the argument that the way it was written was intentional Even though we might perceive it as bad if we understand it was intentional to convey that point on multiple levels.
Speaker 0: anyway I can make my skycrawlers a great movie Mamoru.
Speaker 0: She was very very boring and slow.
Speaker 1: Well, you know that's intentional right?
Speaker 1: Yes, the thing is but it was boring, you know that because of the matter, right?
Speaker 1: It's mamoru.
Speaker 1: She so, you know, he's doing it on purpose because you know the guy.
Speaker 1: but Max Brooks We know him.
Speaker 1: This is a guy who gets the cheap lulls and the big sales off of a zombie survival guide You know, so you can't.
Speaker 1: you know You have to.
Speaker 1: the burden of proof is on you to prove to me that Max Brooks is trying to be clever like that.
Speaker 1: But you don't have to do it to say anything to convince me that mamoru.
Speaker 1: She was trying to be all snooty Pretend.
Speaker 0: so while the quote on the cover from the Dallas Morning News is probably the most topical and literate scares since Orson Welles War of the Worlds.
Speaker 0: But on the back that the onion said something pretty hilarious was an onion AV Club, yeah Okay, they said quote an oversized version of hell.
Speaker 1: Guess are we done?
Speaker 0: I think we're done a good discussions, but yeah, okay Why she on?
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: Unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: I could talk about some technologies, but they're not.
Speaker 1: they're pretty boring.
Speaker 1: and it's not Monday.
Speaker 0: It's Thursday December 9th 2010.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: It's Thursday December 12 2010. it's not no it's not.
Speaker 1: it's December 9th.