Speaker 1: It's Wednesday August 4th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, and this is geek nice tonight.
Speaker 1: Final thoughts on me pilgrim.
Speaker 1: Let's do this clever girl.
Speaker 0: I Realized I do the opener disproportionately.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: it used to be kind of 50/50.
Speaker 1: I'm just lazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, plus it takes some effort to work up.
Speaker 0: You know doing the show we talk normally But during that open it's like hey, it's I can't take that much effort.
Speaker 0: yeah, so we know Scott robot it in the last show and Basically, you know, I'll save this.
Speaker 0: I won't talk about it in the meta.
Speaker 1: Am I roboting right now?
Speaker 0: No, you're sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're fine.
Speaker 0: I can see the levels But basically I did order, you know, we haven't upgraded our equipment in like two and a half there.
Speaker 0: No, it was even before that.
Speaker 0: It was fucking other than the new microphones.
Speaker 0: We bought last year.
Speaker 0: It was katsu Con the last katsu con we went to when we bought this fucking mixer.
Speaker 0: Remember?
Speaker 0: All right We lug that thing down to DC.
Speaker 0: So we haven't really upgraded in a long time.
Speaker 0: So we're going all.
Speaker 1: There's a rule we have to upgrade.
Speaker 1: we can't just stop we can't just reach the the necessary level and stop upgrading.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, we always do.
Speaker 1: maybe if this shit didn't break wouldn't have to upgrade.
Speaker 0: No, it's not that it broke It's that's a pain in the ass to have more than two people on the show.
Speaker 0: What with only having two inputs into the computer?
Speaker 1: Oh That's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean we're upgrading.
Speaker 0: so hold off, you know next week I'm gonna be on vacation and then the week after that Fire wire might be a little while before the show sounds the same again.
Speaker 0: Let's end the wires on fires might sound even better.
Speaker 1: house burns down.
Speaker 1: get too many wires They're burning but much more importantly not my new wires the new RPG.
Speaker 0: I got a gloat at least a little bit because I'm happy about this very excited because it turns out that Conrad and a bunch of our friends are also going to this.
Speaker 0: So Scott the other day last week was like hey rim There's some Twitter contest to win tickets to the upcoming Scott program pre pre-release, you know fancy You know see it ahead of time special tickets and all that.
Speaker 0: and I was like, oh really, huh?
Speaker 0: And I look at my Twitter and I see the things right there.
Speaker 0: So I just reply and I got a ticket.
Speaker 0: so I messaged Scott back two minutes later.
Speaker 0: I'm like, yeah great I got two tickets.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't.
Speaker 0: They're still doing the contest like I just tried again today.
Speaker 1: I didn't win.
Speaker 0: Ah So, so I guess Friday I could review Scott pilgrim.
Speaker 0: The worst thing is I'm going to Wildwood and you know Emily's not going.
Speaker 0: neither is Scott.
Speaker 0: so Everyone else who's going wants to go see Scott pilgrim.
Speaker 1: That's great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, hopefully it'll be good enough to see twice.
Speaker 1: Isn't it kind of interesting how it's like?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I never go see movies really unless suddenly we're going to movies all the time.
Speaker 1: No, this is ultra rare, you know occasion that I'll go see a movie.
Speaker 0: just went to see Inception.
Speaker 0: Now you're gonna go see Scott pilgrim.
Speaker 1: dude is not a trend man.
Speaker 0: That's a trend.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: I will say this.
Speaker 0: I've realized I will say this is something I say a lot lately.
Speaker 0: It's kind of replaced preface or to be sure or Suffice to say suffice it to say to be sure.
Speaker 0: I must say as A fan of the Detroit Tigers one is definitely a fucking winning streak.
Speaker 1: So the Tigers aren't that bad not anymore anyway Said lions.
Speaker 1: That's what you should have said.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you had this other far worse team in the same city.
Speaker 1: I would argue you lie in second.
Speaker 0: The Lions are better for fans than the Detroit Tigers.
Speaker 1: How so sure Tigers?
Speaker 1: I mean maybe just cuz football is better but Tigers are kind of middle-of-the-road like nothing special.
Speaker 0: They're not that great.
Speaker 0: They're not that bad.
Speaker 0: Lions are so bad.
Speaker 0: It's awesome.
Speaker 0: It's like why it's like rooting for the mohawk guy and fist of the North Star.
Speaker 0: You know, he's not gonna win.
Speaker 0: You're really just there to see how awesomely he loses.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So - does not a trend make?
Speaker 1: I think it's like okay.
Speaker 1: first of all I didn't even see the second movie and you know, who knows if I will if everyone else is going to see pre showings I don't have tickets to Sure, you know and all these other shore showings.
Speaker 1: What was funny is my not happen?
Speaker 0: when I said to some people like yeah I got to go find some strangers to go with I was like, I'm seeing Scott Pilgrim and then movie alone.
Speaker 1: That's so.
Speaker 1: that's scary.
Speaker 0: I used to do that a lot.
Speaker 1: I just get.
Speaker 1: when I lived alone Well, okay if you live alone alone I had I mean the only thing scary than going to a movie alone and you know is going to a restaurant said sit down Alone those old days before we did geek nights.
Speaker 0: I lived out in the mountains.
Speaker 0: No internet.
Speaker 0: I had to drive down the mountain for my robot in.
Speaker 0: I would know you're not haha, I Lived the life of a hermit.
Speaker 0: I had effectively more free time than I could possibly fit spend.
Speaker 1: and what did you do?
Speaker 0: I did a lot.
Speaker 0: I just didn't create.
Speaker 0: I basically had a sabbatical and I don't regret those days.
Speaker 1: You need some creating.
Speaker 1: if there's no creating is it's not good?
Speaker 0: now I was I was on sabbatical.
Speaker 0: that was my like resting time to build.
Speaker 0: I charged my laser for a year.
Speaker 0: I came out with the charging his fucking laser.
Speaker 0: ever.
Speaker 1: how charges your laser right now?
Speaker 0: right now My laser is going pretty full force.
Speaker 0: The thing is all this shit.
Speaker 0: I'm doing I can't talk about yet.
Speaker 1: I Think you shouldn't.
Speaker 1: his laser at the Mary gonna.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right, let's do some newses.
Speaker 1: All right, so check it out.
Speaker 1: The North America, I'm not gonna read it, you know.
Speaker 1: verboten but verbatim.
Speaker 1: Verboten Basically discotheque, which is an awesome Anime, you know and live-action movie distributor.
Speaker 0: So they've already said they're going to release project a co and galaxy express.
Speaker 1: What are you doing?
Speaker 1: That's my news.
Speaker 0: You use that news last time.
Speaker 0: Did I?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Oh fuck Wow I'm gonna find a new news not reuse my existing news.
Speaker 0: So so I'll give you some time here.
Speaker 0: Superman According to slashdot saved a family in no not Connecticut.
Speaker 0: that says comic connect.
Speaker 0: Never mind From having their house foreclosed upon.
Speaker 0: All right Apparently they found action comics number one just in the basement.
Speaker 1: That doesn't happen.
Speaker 0: That's like they're like, what's this?
Speaker 0: They sold it.
Speaker 0: They made money to cover the mortgage and all I have to say to that is they shouldn't let the mortgage fail and kept the Comic, it'll be worth more than the house like, you know, it doesn't really rise As far as I know what.
Speaker 1: the value of it doesn't really go up, you know It's just the condition of it can go down.
Speaker 1: I would argue the value of an original of this will go up or at least a static plus inflation plus the value probably just went down because the Quanta known quantity just went up by one which is a large percentage of the Known known quantity.
Speaker 1: It's like there are only five of these in the world.
Speaker 1: Okay, there are now six of them in the world.
Speaker 1: Well, the price just went down.
Speaker 0: So should I not?
Speaker 0: were I to own action comics number one hire hitmen to take out other action comics number ones?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you should collect them all into a bundle.
Speaker 1: That way you say there's one bundle of them and then you'd be like, well if anyone wants one you got to buy this bundle.
Speaker 0: Actually, here's a way to make copies all together.
Speaker 1: How many copies say?
Speaker 0: you have ten copies of action comics number one.
Speaker 0: can't have tank and say there's only 15 left in the world.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I've got ten.
Speaker 1: I don't know how many.
Speaker 1: there's probably a lot more than that.
Speaker 0: I'm just.
Speaker 0: I'm just making up numbers.
Speaker 0: So let's all right, so I make a YouTube channel I make a live TV stream and all this.
Speaker 0: I hold it up and hold up a lighter and I say for the next week.
Speaker 0: I'll be accepting donations.
Speaker 0: if I do not get $50,000 worth of donations.
Speaker 0: I'm burning it.
Speaker 0: I'm killing the hostage P.
Speaker 1: I don't think you'll get enough.
Speaker 0: I think I would.
Speaker 1: you would make more than that just selling one of them.
Speaker 0: Well, the real way to do that is to burn a fake action comics to prove that you're serious and then threaten to burn another fake one.
Speaker 1: And I wasn't able to find the news really in the time.
Speaker 0: I use this like fluff Superman thing to stall for time and you still got nothing.
Speaker 1: It's not easy to find news.
Speaker 0: is he watching any anime right now?
Speaker 1: Oh, you know, you want me to do that?
Speaker 0: Okay, we should we should get but you know, we did.
Speaker 0: we haven't talked about a lot of Current or even old anime lately.
Speaker 0: We haven't been reviewing a lot of shows.
Speaker 1: I've been busy as I check this out.
Speaker 1: I watched.
Speaker 1: I watched a bunch of animes, but I will talk about Space Symphony my tell, right?
Speaker 1: I watched the whole thing and Really?
Speaker 1: It's it's.
Speaker 1: it's kind of nice because it's modern animation and pretty good production quality.
Speaker 0: There's a big butt hanging here.
Speaker 0: What you said like it's nice and there's a it's.
Speaker 1: it's supposed to be a prequel to Galaxy Express 39 and literal prequel or Matsumoto Ian freak.
Speaker 1: No, it's.
Speaker 1: it's actually to the TV series.
Speaker 1: It's or the first movie you could.
Speaker 1: it's an actual prequel and it makes sense.
Speaker 1: The thing is is the first part of the show itself Isn't really consistent with itself.
Speaker 1: It's like what the hell is going on.
Speaker 1: It's like one second.
Speaker 1: It'll be like, you know Andromeda will be you know cool and then the next she'll be a bitch and then she'll be cool again and then a bitch.
Speaker 1: and It's like what is going on.
Speaker 1: and it's like it's clones, but then it's not close but then it's the real one but it's not the real one.
Speaker 0: and then it's like Could that is that really continuity or just characters being all over the place?
Speaker 1: It's just the characters of a. it's like the first part of the show.
Speaker 0: It's not so it's not continuity.
Speaker 0: Like the backstory was this.
Speaker 0: now, it's this.
Speaker 1: no It's like the just the show is all over the place for the first few episodes and then they eventually sort of get in line.
Speaker 1: And this day it's like, okay now we've got here's the actual thing Yeah, and then it stays can?
Speaker 1: it's like it like it fluctuates crazily and you're watching like the first handful episodes You're like just what what.
Speaker 1: I thought that she what.
Speaker 1: and then after a few episodes finally it settles down.
Speaker 0: It's like ah, well, I've been.
Speaker 0: I got to start up again But I was watching giant to robo with some people who haven't seen it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm due to the Natalie and Emily.
Speaker 0: So we got to watch the rest of that.
Speaker 0: But you know Scott finished hokudono Ken quite some time ago, and I've been Plowing along.
Speaker 0: I'm way behind.
Speaker 0: King Sama isn't even dead yet, but My favorite how do you know I'm gonna die?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure he's gonna die.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure he is already dead.
Speaker 0: I Love I'm at the ship part of the show where he's not just like yeah you go kill Ken true Oh, he's like fuck Kendra.
Speaker 0: Oh still coming But I think later.
Speaker 1: oh my god is.
Speaker 0: now we've gotten to the people.
Speaker 0: It's not just like mohawk.
Speaker 0: I show up attack kenshiro get killed now.
Speaker 0: It's mohawk.
Speaker 0: I show up.
Speaker 0: realize it's kenshiro.
Speaker 0: say something like there is a 100% chance.
Speaker 0: I will die if I fight him And run away, of course half the time they never just surrender.
Speaker 0: if they surrender It's always a trick and kenshiro's never trick.
Speaker 0: if you lay ground lay down you're like, I'm not gonna fight you kenshiro He's just gonna throw a boulder at you.
Speaker 0: I Don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm enjoying fist of the North Star.
Speaker 1: What do you get to arcs that are more dangerous in the first arc?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: the God army was pretty dangerous.
Speaker 1: God army is not dangerous at all.
Speaker 0: Jackal was pretty dangerous.
Speaker 1: Jackal is not dangerous at all Much like initial D.
Speaker 0: It is a show of escalating danger But the jackal gets points just for the fact that if they were initial D That is the equivalent of Shingo after he fails to do his thing Pulling out dynamite killing everyone at the finish line and then burning down Mount Akina.
Speaker 1: Yeah, where do you see guys like Souther?
Speaker 1: He's a dangerous motherfucker All right, yeah, I'm also.
Speaker 0: I haven't watched the Durara OAV.
Speaker 0: I don't even know if it's out yet.
Speaker 1: I don't think that's out yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm hankering for some more.
Speaker 0: That was like the best new show in a long time.
Speaker 1: I watched all of Eden of the East.
Speaker 1: you should watch that.
Speaker 0: I really want to.
Speaker 0: there's not that long is it?
Speaker 1: No, it's only like 11 episodes.
Speaker 1: I think I should finish it.
Speaker 0: We got to show on it cuz that and then I think I'm gonna buy or go proxy and we really have to review that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we only watched X number.
Speaker 1: We are on Netflix.
Speaker 0: I remember talking to Daryl Surratt and I was like, yeah, we were watching it on Netflix and we got far But we didn't finish it Yeah, and then we like, you know, we moved and all that stuff and we just didn't.
Speaker 0: but the trouble is talking to Daryl Surratt and he's like, wow, you stopped right before shit gets interesting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know that always seems to happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he was like there's a game show episode.
Speaker 0: It goes nuts Game show.
Speaker 0: Yeah game show episode.
Speaker 0: I think it goes all utenna meta.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, maybe Ava meta Maybe a big o2 meta tomatoes.
Speaker 0: Nothing, but tomatoes.
Speaker 0: Oh, whatever.
Speaker 0: Wow, that was like one of the like, I think that was the first show We did.
Speaker 0: a final thoughts on what show big.
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah, I think so.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so things of the day Cuz there's no anime news.
Speaker 0: that isn't an Alzheimer news.
Speaker 1: no, so check this out, right?
Speaker 1: There's a lot of bootleg shit out there and it's always funny when someone finds like a bootleg toy like Darth Vader riding the police Motorcycle toy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I remember I was at I think Pearl River Mart with Emily years ago and in the bait like downstairs They had these sandals with Naruto with the wrong colors like painted onto him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's always good stuff.
Speaker 1: So this is going around the Internet's.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what this is.
Speaker 1: It's like a deck of cards or something.
Speaker 1: But it's.
Speaker 1: it says like this LOG and it's got.
Speaker 1: it's sort of like a combination of two Batman logos.
Speaker 1: is LOG League of?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: and then it says DM - 104. it costs a dollar and fifty cents.
Speaker 1: It's got like two different Batman's on the cover and and two different pictures of movie Batman Just like, you know photographs from the movie like Photoshop You know cropped Batman out and it's got the Riddler from the movie the Jim Carrey Riddler.
Speaker 1: and also looks like Schwarzenegger, mr.
Speaker 1: Freeze's face in the bottom right corner, huh?
Speaker 1: And then it says 2006.
Speaker 1: Batman begins But on the back is the awesome part.
Speaker 1: This is what it says on the back.
Speaker 1: You ready?
Speaker 0: I'm ready.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna read the holdout.
Speaker 0: What's the danger level here?
Speaker 0: a thousand?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna read the whole thing.
Speaker 0: a thousand space dangers.
Speaker 1: It's a little bit long, but I'll read the whole thing.
Speaker 1: Batman begins.
Speaker 1: when being a child Bruce Wayne had witnessed with his own eyes the fact his parents of millionaire were killed.
Speaker 1: Cruelly So affected his strong desire of revenging his parents.
Speaker 1: However, God had never given him a chance to fulfill his will.
Speaker 1: following the advice of Ross.
Speaker 1: all Google Or raise I can't tell doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: they got it wrong.
Speaker 1: the chief of ninja group Bruce.
Speaker 1: come to Getty which was a corrupted city filled with Various crime groups.
Speaker 1: Bruce found a basement under his villa in which the equipments turned him into another person, you know Spider-man with this mask.
Speaker 1: with this mask Spider-man's stroke all criminal activates and criminals everywhere such as Tal gone the chief of mafia Dr.
Speaker 1: Jack straw the abnormal drug trafficker even a mysterious opponents quite familiar with him - - - - - Wow, that is you know, that's very reminiscent of I was made by the Presbyterian Church.
Speaker 0: Oh God No backstroke of the West the backstroke of the West.
Speaker 1: We gotta bring that back.
Speaker 0: we do got to bring that back very no Anyway -.
Speaker 0: So since we weren't at Otacon.
Speaker 0: But the things I always miss from Otacon like if I if well I guess always that this is the first look at
Speaker 1: the first thing you've ever missed from
Speaker 0: first
Speaker 1: Oh to kind of everything you miss the most not being there is
Speaker 0: the the art show because not people don't That often take pictures of all the art in the art show because you're not supposed to.
Speaker 0: So the other thing I always miss is the opening animation and sure enough It's not.
Speaker 0: there's no way to see it.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell I couldn't find any bootleg Like cam cap of it or anything, but I did fine randomly I wish I realized this was here the opening animation to last year's Otacon Otacon 2009.
Speaker 1: It looks like I was under the impression that there was some rights issues and they couldn't put it out.
Speaker 0: So it looks like they could.
Speaker 0: as far as I can tell looks like this was put out by Otacon and they couldn't put out 2008 and 2010 but 2009 has very few in literally put out by Otacon.
Speaker 1: Are you sure?
Speaker 1: that's pretty sure.
Speaker 1: you sure that's an official Otacon YouTube channel.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure but I don't know it was linked to by an Otacon staffer in the forum.
Speaker 0: not this video But this channel, okay, so that's good enough for me but this is the Otacon 2009 opening animation.
Speaker 0: in case you didn't see it and I really want all their anime cons to do this because the Daikon animation in this whole imagine of Otacon They showed the Daikon animation and then showed,
Speaker 1: you know The thing is, you know Otacon is basically using its its partnerships with Japanese animation studios to make What
Speaker 0: if they just got some fans every year to make one?
Speaker 1: What if they made it at the convention and showed it when the convention was over?
Speaker 0: Do you know how fucking impossible that would be?
Speaker 1: It could be like 30 second animation.
Speaker 1: It could do it.
Speaker 1: It takes a while to animate especially if you had guys like, you know with skills like the We're gonna have enough trouble editing our thing for PAX together by Saturday night.
Speaker 1: Some professionals are gonna do it.
Speaker 0: Yes Okay, anyway and also, you know, I have two things of the day two links here because that's cool.
Speaker 0: But here's a video.
Speaker 0: Uh, it is on the internet.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna link to it.
Speaker 0: It is video from the concert of Suguzo and Yoshiki.
Speaker 1: The concert where there are absolutely no cameras or recording.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: There are a million freaking videos from Otacon 2010's concerts.
Speaker 0: So if you missed the concert if you missed Otacon you can go see the concerts on YouTube even the Yoshita brothers one.
Speaker 0: I didn't actually look for that one.
Speaker 0: I just looked for the ex-japan one because that's the one I was interested in.
Speaker 1: I'm interested in the other one.
Speaker 0: I've got your shita brother.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll see.
Speaker 0: I'll look right now It's not.
Speaker 1: I'm sure.
Speaker 1: there's plenty of your shita brothers period all over YouTube.
Speaker 1: So even if the Otacon one is not there.
Speaker 0: Yeah panel panel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, here it is Q&A performance.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it looks like it's here.
Speaker 1: All right, at least enough of it's there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah So the meta moment.
Speaker 1: Are we roboting yet?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: Okay, Gen Con starts tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Oh crap, you should go and see Luke and Jared there.
Speaker 0: Yes, we will not be there.
Speaker 1: In Indiana I'm trying to cover the non New York things.
Speaker 1: Mozilla drumbeat is this Saturday in New York.
Speaker 0: In New York?
Speaker 1: Yeah, let's see.
Speaker 0: So you didn't make a list ahead of time.
Speaker 1: PAX is I'm looking at my Google Calendar.
Speaker 1: It's my list.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be there doing crazy shit.
Speaker 1: Recess is the weekend after that.
Speaker 1: Maker Faire is two weeks after that And then at 10 10 10 that weekend is is the burning con but also the New York Comic Con and also the New York anime festival and also nerd NYC board game night.
Speaker 0: Next week There may or may not be shows because I'm gonna be out of town at our annual writers retreat.
Speaker 0: Scott will not be at the writers retreat.
Speaker 0: So yeah, we'll see how much I write.
Speaker 1: and then magfest is next year.
Speaker 0: Whoo, magfest.
Speaker 1: I don't I don't believe we should ever.
Speaker 1: everyone has balls of Steve balls.
Speaker 0: We should never say woo in regards to magfest.
Speaker 0: There's only one appropriate response and that is hot.
Speaker 0: And like I said, we're upgrading the studio equipment.
Speaker 0: so give it a week or two and we're gonna start bringing a lot more guests on the show because I'll basically Quarter the time it takes to edit and like do post-production on guest shows Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So we're up in the ante there quite a bit.
Speaker 1: All righty.
Speaker 0: All right, so Thursday Scott Pilgrim opens for me next Thursday.
Speaker 0: Scott Pilgrim opens for everyone else.
Speaker 0: So I figure we should do a final thoughts on the comic because it's one of the great comics we've read in recent.
Speaker 1: You know, that was my show idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was not your show idea.
Speaker 0: It's a geek night show idea which shared responsibility Only comic that we had both read recently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is the reason that is the show.
Speaker 0: I can't believe you didn't even read awesome thoughts because we've already done a show.
Speaker 0: All right, here's the before we get to spinal thoughts and spoilers.
Speaker 0: Here's the review.
Speaker 0: if you were between the ages of 17 and 31 I know.
Speaker 1: the thing is I've got like 40 year old people who are reading it and digging it.
Speaker 1: It's sort of weird like okay.
Speaker 1: Let's discuss this whole issue, right?
Speaker 1: I was sort of under the the opinion that like, okay There's only certain people who will get this, you know.
Speaker 1: And and like if you're too young or too old you just is not incomprehensible and to an extent that's true My grandma would never get it.
Speaker 1: My mom probably wouldn't even really get it.
Speaker 0: But yet Emily's parents love it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it's like, okay It's not really you know, this there's no like.
Speaker 1: there is definitely a subset of people who will get it.
Speaker 1: Doesn't have a universal appeal of something like Star Wars where everyone gets it, you know, it definitely is limited but It is also broader than you would suspect like a lot of people are suspect, you know, it's would think Oh, this is only for like, you know 20 to 30 year olds who play grew up with any S's and no one else is gonna even understand anything.
Speaker 0: I think that's not sure who is really for is there's a kind of specific Culture and upbringing that together can create the kind of person who will appreciate Scott Pilgrim.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I definitely think even though some like Emily's parents might enjoy it There's no doubt that they view it differently than we view it They have to.
Speaker 0: but at the same time I would argue that the core message of Scott Pilgrim is Timeless.
Speaker 0: for anyone who had those experiences and the video game II all that Timeless message, but it's presented in a non timeless manner.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the core message I think comes through no matter what.
Speaker 0: so I think really anyone who is astute and Had those experiences Appreciated Scott Pilgrim.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is I have a feeling that unlike say a will Eisner or you know Carl Barks or You know a Tezuka, right?
Speaker 1: This is not a timeless work like a hundred years from now.
Speaker 1: Most people are probably gonna read it and go what the fuck, you know It's.
Speaker 1: it's not the kind of thing that people will be able to read a long time from now and it'll still work.
Speaker 0: Well, what'll be interesting is to go go back you know 50 years from now and see what else did Brian Lee O'Malley do and Will Scott Pilgrim be like.
Speaker 0: this is where it all began.
Speaker 1: Well, he's like in his mid late 30s, right?
Speaker 0: He's got some time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so, you know that there is definitely, you know, it's not like 31 To be clear.
Speaker 0: a lot of people don't realize he's done other stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: What was that other thing?
Speaker 1: He did The one with the sad girl on the cover.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I forget the name of it sad girl in snow.
Speaker 0: Wait, that's Fred Gallagher person.
Speaker 1: No, he's a comic artist.
Speaker 1: He's done a lot of comics.
Speaker 1: Yeah More.
Speaker 1: Oh, you know, you hope he doesn't just like roll around in his movie moneys But I don't think he's that kind of guy.
Speaker 1: I've met him a couple times and you know, he's just he's.
Speaker 1: you know He's chill.
Speaker 1: He's not one of those crazy kind of.
Speaker 0: I guess the best way to review not just the comic but before we get into spoilers.
Speaker 0: And the final thoughts cuz I really want to get right to that and just spoiled because it.
Speaker 0: you know That's the discussion.
Speaker 0: We all want to have The.
Speaker 0: the whole Scott Pilgrim franchise has been handled Almost I would argue maybe better than any other similarly potential franchise has ever been handled.
Speaker 0: We have to see the movie see the video game to see for sure.
Speaker 0: but look at what happened.
Speaker 0: the comic resonated among a certain fan group like many things do and Any time there's something like that.
Speaker 0: We're nerds.
Speaker 0: We sit around and say man.
Speaker 0: What if they made a movie about Scott Pilgrim?
Speaker 1: Well, it's weird because Oni didn't really do anything like to promote it that you know They don't do for any other comic right?
Speaker 1: It's not like they put Scott Pilgrim like all over the fuck, right?
Speaker 1: They just put it out just like they put out every other Oni comic, you know.
Speaker 1: And I've got other Oni comics like what was that one wanton soup, right?
Speaker 1: They put that out and they had the same promotion as you know, Scott Pilgrim did.
Speaker 1: they never really pushed it hard They didn't you know, it was just out the same as every other comic yet.
Speaker 1: It sort of picked up on its own and became Crazy huge.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not talking about crazy huge.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about more.
Speaker 0: So look at this.
Speaker 0: they make the comic.
Speaker 0: nerds sit around whenever there's a comic or something they like and say man Would it be awesome if they just made a sequel like this?
Speaker 0: What if they made the movie and got so-and-so to play?
Speaker 0: it seems like everything.
Speaker 0: nerds who were fans of this said wouldn't it be awesome?
Speaker 0: if is Basically what they did?
Speaker 0: what if they made a movie?
Speaker 0: Yeah, they should get like Michael Cera to star in it.
Speaker 0: Oh, they got Michael Cera.
Speaker 0: Oh, what if they made a video game and he was like, oh they made the video game.
Speaker 0: They made it exactly.
Speaker 1: we were saying with that that guy the the cabana battle guy We were saying he shouldn't.
Speaker 1: just you know, we were always disappointed that he basically made pirate and a cabana battle should have been a game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why wasn't it again?
Speaker 0: So nerd said man.
Speaker 0: What if the pirate baby cabana battle guy?
Speaker 0: wouldn't that be crazy?
Speaker 0: Well, it was like.
Speaker 1: it was like we wanted him to just make a game period and then we wanted a sky pilgrim game period.
Speaker 1: And then they combined to lack of two unfulfilled potentials into one.
Speaker 1: They you know that that would be like if you know, you made a new.
Speaker 1: You made the New Super Metroid game, right?
Speaker 1: But it was also Like, you know reviving some long, you know, well, that was a terrible example.
Speaker 1: I didn't think of any good example.
Speaker 0: I failed so but it's every step of the way, you know nerds man the video game.
Speaker 0: What if they got on a Monoguchi to do the music?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, they just fucking did that.
Speaker 1: You know, I don't like on a Monoguchi that much I do.
Speaker 1: I've seen him live a few times I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't understand why people know I really like them.
Speaker 0: I don't like them live But I like their music on its own.
Speaker 1: No, I've listened to it on the youtubes a couple times and not I'm not a fan.
Speaker 0: It's good music for Scott pilgrim though.
Speaker 1: Probably it's alright, but it's only for the video game.
Speaker 1: They're doing the music, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're not doing the movie music Someone else's but that's kind of.
Speaker 0: they've taken all the things that nerds would say.
Speaker 0: Would it be awesome if and done the equivalent.
Speaker 1: there are some nerds out there who are like, yeah They should have done a different thing, you know I'm not arguing there aren't but the majority of the kinds of things they did like Michael Cera.
Speaker 0: getting him was like the crazy nerd Choice and the fact that they actually did it was just surprising.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Yeah, I get the feel it's one of those things where you know, I don't I don't think it's.
Speaker 1: you know They did everything that nerds wanted perfectly.
Speaker 1: But I think it's definitely a situation where usually when a nerdy thing is adapted, especially into a movie the nerd They made the do movie.
Speaker 0: What did nerds want?
Speaker 0: They're like, yeah, is it gonna be set on Mars?
Speaker 0: Is it gonna be about a space marine?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it wasn't.
Speaker 1: You know, it's these kinds of things right Pete the nerds are like, you know How much does it match the original and it in this case?
Speaker 1: They have matched the original, you know enough to where there are no like Super huge complaints like even like Watchmen movie, you know people got something to complain about or spider-man movie.
Speaker 1: They got something to complain about but there's organic web shooters.
Speaker 0: I mean exactly right.
Speaker 1: so with Scott Pilgrim It's not.
Speaker 1: nothing is perfect, but there is far proportionally less to complain about than with any other nerd Adaptation.
Speaker 0: I mean the only person who could possibly play Scott Pilgrim better than Michael Cera's probably our friend Conrad.
Speaker 0: Oh I can think of few people that is that guy, you know, he doesn't really even movies.
Speaker 0: Have you seen with him in them?
Speaker 1: We saw you.
Speaker 1: he's there.
Speaker 1: I remember he's the arrested development kid, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think the one thing.
Speaker 0: so what else have you seen with him in it?
Speaker 1: I'm sure I know anything about him I'm sure I have but I just don't.
Speaker 1: you know, remember that you probably haven't.
Speaker 1: is that he's always sort of like He's?
Speaker 1: you know, Scott Pilgrim is sort of like excitable like hey, and he doesn't seem.
Speaker 1: you know He doesn't.
Speaker 1: he has all the other qualities of Scott Pilgrim except these sort of Excitable quality like you need.
Speaker 1: they need to give him like a caffeine injection for a few of the scenes and then it'll be alright.
Speaker 0: See, I think they will.
Speaker 0: this is actually I think a big test for him.
Speaker 0: They're good.
Speaker 0: We're gonna find out.
Speaker 0: can he alter his like milieu?
Speaker 0: Can he act differently?
Speaker 0: Can he pull off Scott Pilgrim or will he be Michael Cera as Scott Pilgrim?
Speaker 1: Well other people have seen the movie already, you know No one's.
Speaker 1: that's one thing that I think they were doing really interesting with this marketing right for the movie?
Speaker 1: is the movies been done Done for a while and there's so many screenings?
Speaker 1: are so many Pre-release screenings all over the fucking place like crazy, which I think is like a genius idea You know, like why isn't everyone doing that for anything that's popular, especially for something that's so nerdy You know is gonna be passed around the Pirate Bays, right?
Speaker 1: Obviously, you should just get the screenings out there.
Speaker 1: cuz what's keeping the movie from being released.
Speaker 1: It's well.
Speaker 1: Why don't they put it out a day earlier?
Speaker 1: Well, cuz they need to get the reels of film or whatever to every movie theater at once.
Speaker 0: I screw that deal.
Speaker 1: if they got they got they definitely have one made by now.
Speaker 1: They have a bunch just don't have enough for every theater.
Speaker 1: So as they're sending them out, they're like, okay, dude, do a previews you got one in your theater.
Speaker 1: I don't think that's a freaking previous.
Speaker 0: I don't think that's it at all because at least in all the cities I mean digital projection is becoming the standard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but even so you need to.
Speaker 1: they mail hard drives to every theater.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they don't do it where you download it from the internet.
Speaker 0: They've been doing pre screenings far longer than it takes to ship the movie out to everywhere.
Speaker 0: I don't think that's it.
Speaker 0: I think it's more a long-term buzz building system that also it's.
Speaker 1: it's a it's a multiple.
Speaker 1: It's many birds with one stone cuz.
Speaker 0: look what else.
Speaker 0: serenity did that too?
Speaker 0: There were a fucking million screenings of serenity before it was in.
Speaker 1: I definitely think you need to do that for nerd movies.
Speaker 1: Otherwise people just get their preview screenings on the internet.
Speaker 1: and at least when you do a preview screening in the theater You can get some monies.
Speaker 0: Now that you don't pay for these screenings unless you get someone else to pay for like the pre-screen tickets and give them away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean there what do you think the people were giving away?
Speaker 1: the tickets are not, you know.
Speaker 1: There's money being changed hands.
Speaker 1: Maybe maybe the movie theater isn't just letting all these people come in for free.
Speaker 0: Yes What what we don't know is who is paying.
Speaker 0: we don't know if the production company is paying or if like Midtown Comics Paid for the tickets.
Speaker 0: for you know, we don't know that.
Speaker 1: but you know what I do know Popcorn monies, they're making money as popcorn.
Speaker 0: notice an inception.
Speaker 0: the other than a few fat people.
Speaker 0: No one bought shit.
Speaker 1: Everyone smuggled stuff in and that's just because it happens to be next to a Duane Reade that particular Lot of the multiplexes.
Speaker 1: like thing about Tinseltown.
Speaker 1: right Tinseltown is out in the mat Scott.
Speaker 0: It's not a Plexus it's just multiplexes that aren't in cities.
Speaker 1: Yeah, look at any theater and they put him out in the woods separate from everything else with a giant parking lot So that there's no drugstore right next to it.
Speaker 0: No, they do that because the lands cheap and people can drive that too.
Speaker 1: But it's also that you know, there's.
Speaker 1: no I don't think there was a candy store right next to the movie theater.
Speaker 1: But like alright fuck we're screwed.
Speaker 0: So if Duane Reade were smart, they would open Duane Reade movie editions next to every theater and sell smuggleable goods.
Speaker 0: They basically have that.
Speaker 1: Okay, and you just have to be smart.
Speaker 0: I would advertise I'd be like smuggle this shit into the theater.
Speaker 1: I'd sell flat drink containers You're not you know, you can't get drunk in a movie theater.
Speaker 1: that's bad they can that's not.
Speaker 0: it's not a lot You can't just know.
Speaker 0: it's not any more not allowed than Smuggling in my dorsey does?
Speaker 0: I don't even know what a do-si-do is drunk on the do-si-do.
Speaker 1: I guess if I soaked him and get a make you're gonna make a loud do-si-do ruckus and barf the do-si-dos.
Speaker 0: We don't get in in New York.
Speaker 0: that bothers me.
Speaker 0: But the Texans get it the adult only theater with the fine dining and the movie at the same time Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Why don't we have that?
Speaker 1: Because the space versus money is not a good I know but I want it.
Speaker 0: I would be willing to pay a lot for that.
Speaker 1: not enough people will agree.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I do.
Speaker 1: I mean So, you know what?
Speaker 1: I got a guy got one for you.
Speaker 1: It's right over in the other room Don't only?
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you pay me whatever you were gonna pay that movie theater, okay But one thing if I pay you sparks money, I expect sparks quality.
Speaker 1: I'll just go to sell this, you know You got to pay me a little plus sparks money because you get a movie too and then I'll go to sparks and keep the Profit and I'll just go to the sparks.
Speaker 1: I'll just about bike it back over here or take a cab.
Speaker 0: Yes, now my steaks cold great.
Speaker 1: I'll put in microwave.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's gonna be a great steak.
Speaker 1: Actually, I'd be really good.
Speaker 0: probably not No Because the point of the run of the raw steak is that it's sizzling hot and blackened on the outside and it is cool And raw on my way over there.
Speaker 1: I'll mug the Pizza Hut guy and take his little in you know insulator.
Speaker 0: Nah, all right Scott Pilgrim We're going to spoil the ever-living shit out of the common volumes one through six.
Speaker 0: Yes all of it.
Speaker 0: We're going to spoil it.
Speaker 0: Do not listen.
Speaker 1: Seriously actually no just if you're.
Speaker 1: if you if you're like Haven't read it all what the fuck?
Speaker 1: Seriously, go read it and then listen to this episode like right now like pause the episode and read it all and then unpause the episode.
Speaker 0: I was not surprised when Scott Pilgrim died me either but I like how they handled that.
Speaker 0: He's like am I dead?
Speaker 0: No Actually, yeah, you are dead and then he only came back because the extra life.
Speaker 1: Yeah No, I mean the the extra life was such a check-offs extra life.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was.
Speaker 1: no, you know, the thing is it's.
Speaker 1: it's weird like I don't know if I should admit this But basically I read.
Speaker 1: I made a bit sort of a mistake.
Speaker 1: I read each volume as it came out and I never reread any volumes.
Speaker 1: So I forgot many details and rears basically each volume.
Speaker 1: I was almost like starting a new and I didn't remember everything from the previous volumes and I only remembered like the most You know biggest important information and I didn't really remember a lot of the small stuff.
Speaker 1: I remember the one up but I didn't remember like a lot of other things at all like had the glow, right?
Speaker 1: glowing.
Speaker 1: and I was listening to some reviews of that other people did of the early episodes like comedy speak just did a review of the first two volumes right because they never read it at all and They noticed they actually mentioned specifically having read only volume one and two.
Speaker 1: like why is she glowing?
Speaker 1: And I was like, I didn't even notice it and only in volume six did the right.
Speaker 1: But if I had read them all at once again And I probably will read all six just in a row plan to read them all again Then I probably it would stand out like a sore thumb Yeah, or things like.
Speaker 0: I think a lot of people actually forgot about Simon and that whole, you know prelude Cuz I came back in a big way at the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't really remember that either.
Speaker 0: What really know How are you gonna?
Speaker 0: What do you remember?
Speaker 0: It's like you never remember anything from stuff.
Speaker 0: We watch.
Speaker 1: I remember Scott pilgrim.
Speaker 1: he had banned he was going.
Speaker 0: I remember in the beginning the river city ransom where he saved came pine from Simon on the roof.
Speaker 0: Yeah in their backstory.
Speaker 0: Oh In the back story, yeah Remember at the end, you know what it turned out to be.
Speaker 0: He was just some nerd and it was just.
Speaker 0: you know The whole time we have all these like memories that we take is true Like that's the way it was and volume six basically said no, here's the reality.
Speaker 0: Here's what really happened.
Speaker 1: people just forget what happens when you read volume one like over a year before you read volume say I don't have this problem.
Speaker 1: So I had this problem.
Speaker 1: You know, you know, that's why I get trade paperbacks.
Speaker 1: I don't get the individual issues because you get the individual issues.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, you read, you know It's basically an issue a month.
Speaker 1: So by the time if it's something's five issues It's five months since you've read the first issue and you read so many comics, you know It's like.
Speaker 0: I will say I was wrong about the glow.
Speaker 0: all through this all through the whole series until the end when you find out what all that was about I Thought that the glow kind of symbolized going back to the real world and I thought this was all gonna be some sort of weird World.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I mean that's sort of.
Speaker 0: we're poisoned with that right from seeing too many things where anytime, you know dog I heard you like to dream so I put a dream in your.
Speaker 1: yeah I don't want to spoil like ten things right now, but there are a lot of.
Speaker 0: we can spoil whatever we want.
Speaker 1: You want to spoil I go Tana?
Speaker 1: Yeah Go big.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's something to go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's so many things that we've watched especially animes Where there's a world where crazy shit that magic happens and then at the very end of the show It's actually.
Speaker 1: no it's actually not.
Speaker 1: you thought it was a fantasy world this whole time, but you know, it's not a fantasy world It's a real world.
Speaker 1: and here's a real explanation for all that shit you saw.
Speaker 1: that was that looked like fantasy, but guess what is not fantasy?
Speaker 1: and So of course reading Scott Pilgrim when you've got people going like through dimensions to deliver Amazon I've already combined is a bird not Kim pine.
Speaker 0: when when she disappeared Ramona all I thought was she's in the real world.
Speaker 1: now Yeah, you know stuff like that, you know anytime magical shit happens like okay that one up actually just came out of nowhere.
Speaker 1: Okay, the skateboard proficiency thing, you know, it's like, okay, you know, there's obviously crazy magical shit.
Speaker 1: There's obviously some sort of real-world explanation for this.
Speaker 1: It's not actually for reals that no it's actually is.
Speaker 1: they live in some sort of magical world.
Speaker 1: That's that's what Scott pilgrims about.
Speaker 1: they let you know, it it looks a lot like the real world But it actually has video game fights in it.
Speaker 1: well one kind of place.
Speaker 0: one way to interpret all that though would be to interpret this, you know as That is the way the world is seen by the characters.
Speaker 0: I mean look at the otaku in the van in Dora their whole thing about how they see the world and like the way the World is through their eyes.
Speaker 0: You could argue the scout pilgrims the same way.
Speaker 0: I mean look at us.
Speaker 0: I think about the world in those terms.
Speaker 0: That guy's got an 18 charisma.
Speaker 1: The thing is I think it's got pilgrim.
Speaker 1: it definitely story wise like I think those things do literally happen.
Speaker 1: But that doesn't mean that they are also, you know, not a metaphor for you know Exactly and that is why utenna and big O and all these things are so good.
Speaker 1: It's like just something litter.
Speaker 1: It's like people think that just because like, you know, something has to not actually happen for it to be a metaphor.
Speaker 0: somehow They're like, oh, is it a is it a cigar or it is a car?
Speaker 0: Is it a cock?
Speaker 0: and you know what it could be both?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't have to be an illusion.
Speaker 0: There's cigar shaped cock.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have to be an illusion of a cigar on top of a cock.
Speaker 1: It can actually just be an actual cigar that someone actually smoked.
Speaker 1: and it's still a metaphor for a second.
Speaker 0: the car And this is why Scott pilgrim is.
Speaker 0: I think it's not one of the greatest comics of all time But I would argue it's a great comic.
Speaker 0: I'm not great in the you know, it is great sense.
Speaker 0: Not just oh, it was great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I'm not.
Speaker 0: it is self-consistent on both the direct level and the metaphorical level.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but obviously this was intentional.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the other things I like about it is it's it's sort of a penny arcade situation, right?
Speaker 1: You get to see Brian the O'Malley improve his skills.
Speaker 0: Yes, Deb.
Speaker 0: I flipped through Scott pilgrim one again, and I like it.
Speaker 0: It's still one of my favorite volumes, but the art looks way different in six.
Speaker 1: Yeah compare the early penny You know, I always how.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it was on purpose or not But at least at some point he figured out notice in the end how he showed you all the different ways He's drawn Ramona through the whole series and how he made that matter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wonder if he intended that going in or if he just sucked it dry.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: You know, it was exactly.
Speaker 0: it's clever.
Speaker 0: So it wins exactly.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: I mean Your highness is like a golden ray.
Speaker 0: Okay, I don't think anyone will get that.
Speaker 1: no Yeah You know, it's got pilgrim.
Speaker 1: I mean if I had to put it on like a chart of like comics like it wouldn't be anywhere near like an Eisner Or a Tezuka or even a black said right?
Speaker 1: It's down below all those guys, but it's above.
Speaker 1: like Spider-man.
Speaker 1: you read every week way above that.
Speaker 0: It's not saying that much.
Speaker 0: It's above a lot of the you know, what it's above a lot of the like good manga I've read.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: it's like you got urasawa.
Speaker 1: It's like one step under urasawa.
Speaker 1: Yeah pilgrim.
Speaker 1: It's like that's where he is.
Speaker 0: I put him in the same class.
Speaker 0: Like if urasawa is a b-plus then scout pilgrim is a.
Speaker 1: you know, it's just as good.
Speaker 1: It's equal to like yotsuba and I was among a dial.
Speaker 0: That's that's a level of enjoyment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's similar of I leave.
Speaker 0: they both speak to me on the same level.
Speaker 1: Of course yotsuba does not have the metaphor and the Right, you look at Scott pilgrim and there's some people who've actually been saying stupid shit Like Scott pilgrim is slice of life and it's like what the hell's wrong with you.
Speaker 1: See yotsuba is slice of life, right?
Speaker 1: You look at it and it's like yotsuba goes to the farm Yotsuba goes to the florist yotsuba rides a bicycle, you know, it's like there isn't a big story of yotsuba.
Speaker 1: There is no, you know epic tale where she's gonna get deported back to where the you know tropical island She came from or anything like that.
Speaker 1: It's just slices of life.
Speaker 1: They're all totally separate and it's just here's.
Speaker 1: they're doing this and here's a dude.
Speaker 1: I was among it.
Speaker 1: I was the same way.
Speaker 1: We're in high school and we're going on vacation.
Speaker 1: We're driving in a car.
Speaker 1: We're fighting over a pillow, you know, it's just random life stuff.
Speaker 1: It doesn't really have any over plot to it.
Speaker 1: Scott pilgrim has moments of slice of life that are slices, you know.
Speaker 1: But those moments are all to introduce you to the characters or to the plot.
Speaker 0: Yes to say that this slice of life is stupid.
Speaker 0: That's just.
Speaker 0: that's still like make these broad.
Speaker 1: We have bacon therefore everything does not suck.
Speaker 0: that is like my third favorite moment in the entire series.
Speaker 1: Right, that is a slice of life.
Speaker 1: is we're just chillin.
Speaker 1: Well now that was bacon breakfast.
Speaker 0: That was a slice of bacon?
Speaker 1: Yes, it but it is a slice nonetheless.
Speaker 1: but the there the whole book is not just slices of eating bacon.
Speaker 1: the whole book is Fighting seven evil eggs boyfriends.
Speaker 1: and there's a. you know, there's actual acts with.
Speaker 1: you know A climax and a dental mall and you know is a story.
Speaker 1: Yotsuba doesn't really have that, you know, it's a anything that's a slice of life is just there's no acts.
Speaker 1: I mean maybe each individual slice might sort of have an act.
Speaker 0: It's stupid to call a slice of life.
Speaker 0: It kind of it removes the usefulness of the term slice of life.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people are just they don't know what they're saying.
Speaker 0: size of that life is a code for something Yotsuba or something that sucks.
Speaker 1: There are slices of life that do not say there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the other thing is a lot of people get confused between like slice of life and autobiography.
Speaker 1: It's like look you can have an Autographical slice and autobiography isn't a slice of life.
Speaker 0: It's the whole life chunk of life Or chunks.
Speaker 1: I don't know chunks of you could have a slice of like life.
Speaker 1: that is autobiographical.
Speaker 1: If someone just tells you slices of their life, but doesn't tell you the whole life then it is, you know there's both.
Speaker 0: I guess it could be the whole life.
Speaker 0: if Nothing fucking happens to the dude then why would anyone read his autobiography?
Speaker 1: So lame?
Speaker 0: Yeah Ah Scott Pilger, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I really like Kim Pine.
Speaker 0: Kim Pine.
Speaker 1: Everyone likes Kim Pine.
Speaker 1: Kim Pine is number one.
Speaker 1: Yes, everyone else is number ten.
Speaker 0: I also really like Knives Chow.
Speaker 1: I don't really like Knives Chow.
Speaker 0: I really like Knives Chow for a lot of reasons especially in the end.
Speaker 0: I kind of like how the last volume like everything shifted and She kind of got her act together and I like how they had the closure in their moment.
Speaker 1: That's one thing that I like is how every there's no one, you know.
Speaker 1: Sometimes in the end of something it's like there's people who are still stupid, right?
Speaker 1: But in this Everyone is no longer stupid except Gideon, but he's not.
Speaker 1: he's not really stupid.
Speaker 0: He's dead.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I mean he's you know, he wasn't really you know, he was misguided and evil Yeah, but he wasn't you know stupid or he didn't have.
Speaker 1: he had a shit together.
Speaker 1: He just had a bad a bad goal.
Speaker 1: He was you know mean and bad.
Speaker 1: He was a bad dude, but he wasn't.
Speaker 1: he wasn't like a. he wasn't an incompetent bad dude.
Speaker 1: He was a malicious bad dude.
Speaker 1: He knew what he.
Speaker 1: we know what he doing more of an Accio.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right It's like he's not You're not like, you know sitting there going.
Speaker 1: Oh, man.
Speaker 1: I wish Gideon would turn good and or anything.
Speaker 0: You're like, oh man I wish Gideon would get the shit kicked out of it, right, but everyone else I love the scene at the end where he's like.
Speaker 0: were you watching me through the cat?
Speaker 0: Are you the cat?
Speaker 0: and he's like, no, I wasn't the cat.
Speaker 0: what you named the cat Gideon and Ronas like shut up Characters that you like.
Speaker 1: that were good people, but they had flaws and then they mostly all fixed themselves.
Speaker 1: You know when someone stays stupid It's just like you ever watch those the comedy movies like like dumb and dumber types Someone who's just so dumb and they stay dumb.
Speaker 1: It's just like I guess when I was in like a teenager.
Speaker 1: That was funny because it was just so poo poo poo puma, but nowadays it's like you seeing as someone's so stupid.
Speaker 1: It's like oh my god.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Stop being stupid.
Speaker 1: He's so stupid any Scott Pergam.
Speaker 1: It's like you got these likable people that are only a little stupid.
Speaker 1: So you don't have that that feeling.
Speaker 1: but it's like get your shit together.
Speaker 0: Well, everyone gets their their badminton moment.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: bad badminton scene is distributed.
Speaker 0: I mean the the way they handle envy.
Speaker 0: I really like her character in the end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like seeing how it all turned out and that I don't know that whole scene was pretty cool in the club.
Speaker 0: cuz I like How everyone else.
Speaker 1: just the club was pretty much that was.
Speaker 1: that was it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like everybody up in the club.
Speaker 1: Yes Awesome, even Wallace is up in the club.
Speaker 0: course Wallace was up in the club.
Speaker 0: Well, this is a man.
Speaker 1: Wallace is probably number two after Kim pine.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like she's way down.
Speaker 0: She's like number three hundred.
Speaker 0: She's down.
Speaker 0: She's up there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know why your knives chuffing.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I just I am.
Speaker 1: I'm a fan of.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'll take I'll take frickin like young meal over knives chow.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think my order would be it'd be a race.
Speaker 1: Why are we like ranking the characters?
Speaker 1: because we don't do that for like other stuff, right?
Speaker 0: We did for shows we really really liked in the past.
Speaker 0: I can do ten.
Speaker 0: Oh, we did the same shit.
Speaker 0: I think it's just that a toga was fucking show.
Speaker 1: Show really is about this cast of characters and there's so many supporting characters and they're all awesome.
Speaker 1: So it's like you're just so you end up caring about some of these supporting characters because they're so good.
Speaker 0: I think part of the reason we care about him too is that while a lot of them are kind of one-dimensional or they're not super characterized their interactions with each other and with Scott and with the other and with the other characters like the main characters We're very realistic in terms of that world like take their conversations and replace the proper nouns with your own groups inside joke proper nouns and that's Exactly how the front row crew interacts most of the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean.
Speaker 1: and the other thing is you look at Scott Pilgrim himself and it's like what does he really?
Speaker 1: Do so much, you know, it's like a lot of times.
Speaker 1: He's just basically You know like the bouncing off Target for every supporting character cuz he hadn't found his own.
Speaker 0: all the other characters had found their own or seeking their own.
Speaker 0: He was not seeking or so.
Speaker 1: It's like you're really looking at all these supporting people, you know Scott pilgrim is the one who's always got the camera on and most of the time.
Speaker 1: but you're really looking at all these supporting characters Bouncing off of him constantly, you know What you end up caring about them a lot because they are like, you know The the plot arcs are them and you know Nana did that too.
Speaker 0: We liked both Nana's and if time went on one Nana never fucking did anything and the other Nana was doing stuff.
Speaker 0: So eventually you're kind of like watching all these characters and you're kind of leaving the one character behind.
Speaker 0: Scott pilgrim had to come of age and you know all the metaphors that are obvious and Scott pilgrim Yes, many obvious things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's I guess that's one negative thing you could say about it is it's not really subtle.
Speaker 1: It's so it's just obvious.
Speaker 0: but it's it's while it's not subtle.
Speaker 0: It doesn't.
Speaker 0: it isn't just coming of age.
Speaker 0: it really gets into the nature of Relationships in that not for everybody not every culture goes through this.
Speaker 0: I think many people in the previous generation never had the same kind of scope of life, especially in the 20s to 30s.
Speaker 0: I mean look at all these people.
Speaker 0: they're a lot like us, you know, you have your awesome life or you're kicking ass You're the high school, you know nerd running around and then you get to college you live this nerd life in college and then you're in the real world and You still have like like your last set of relationships were the college nerd life And you haven't moved on to anything past that.
Speaker 0: and I think a lot of people have had relationships that went Very similarly.
Speaker 0: I mean a lot of people have the issue of I like every girl.
Speaker 0: I mean that was Gideon's problem in the end He liked every girl and he never gave up on any one of them.
Speaker 0: and you know what?
Speaker 0: Scott pilgrim had the same problem.
Speaker 1: Yep, exactly Straight up except Scott program had a much.
Speaker 1: Well, not that difficult the time I mean, he just walked out to Ramona's like hey want to go.
Speaker 0: I was like, okay Yeah But even then he's still like he had feelings for all these other people and there was no closure with any of those people.
Speaker 0: That's the dangerous combination.
Speaker 0: He had no closure with with people like knives or envy or even Kim and Simultaneously, he had no closure with his current relationship Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Nothing was done and everything was a loose thread.
Speaker 0: Gideon wanted every thread to be his forever.
Speaker 0: Scott pilgrim tied all the threads up.
Speaker 0: Yep, and totally made.
Speaker 0: actually May notice how he made out with almost everyone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's that's why he's awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's.
Speaker 0: I think that's a good way to get closure.
Speaker 1: to be honest You know, you didn't actually see Gideon actually making out with that with anybody.
Speaker 0: really no, but you know, yeah He was kind of a dick we got anything else to.
Speaker 1: uh, oh one other thing is a lot of people, right?
Speaker 1: They got to shut up as they're like, oh man, this comic is about these hipsters.
Speaker 1: Look these kids They're not hipsters.
Speaker 1: These are not hipsters.
Speaker 1: You do not know if you think that this is.
Speaker 1: those are hipsters.
Speaker 0: Those are Basically very.
Speaker 0: they're in the same like.
Speaker 0: they're on the Venn diagram with like the front row crew and like you listeners that is like Nerd 20 to 30 something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're not hipsters.
Speaker 1: if you don't know what hipsters are Go to like, you know, Google image search and look for hipster and there's a no just go to Park Slope.
Speaker 1: No Park Slope has got lots of Jews Also a lot of hipster rich people.
Speaker 0: All right cross the Williamsburg Bridge.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you'll see on a Friday Saturday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the thing is.
Speaker 1: the problem I think is this term hipster is being thrown around a lot.
Speaker 1: But a lot of people they don't you know hipsters live in cities.
Speaker 1: They don't really live anywhere else.
Speaker 1: so a lot of people who don't most people don't ever actually see hipsters ever and So they don't even know what hipster means.
Speaker 1: because you don't really see hipsters.
Speaker 1: I guess like, you know in popular culture, you know, like movies all that much.
Speaker 1: What's a movie with hipsters in it?
Speaker 0: There's a ton of hipster movies, but they're all.
Speaker 1: yeah, you don't see them in.
Speaker 1: like, you know major movies Really, you know that are in the movie theater.
Speaker 1: Inception didn't have any hipsters in it.
Speaker 1: No, it didn't, you know, so it's like, you know, Scott Pilgrim doesn't have any in it.
Speaker 1: So it's people don't really know what hipster is.
Speaker 1: They just start calling hipsters to something.
Speaker 1: They see that they think oh that must be hipster.
Speaker 0: All right I mean basically the characters in Scott Pilgrim.
Speaker 0: I'd qualify them as nerd or geek kind of hip not hip stir.
Speaker 1: It is cuz someone's hip doesn't make you a hip stir.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a hip stir.
Speaker 1: wears tight-ass jeans rides a bicycle That's you know got no brakes on it.
Speaker 0: drinks the pabs blue ribbon drinks a paps blue ribbon.
Speaker 0: works a job.
Speaker 0: That's dead end, but they don't care.
Speaker 0: because they make enough money They want or they are their trust fund.
Speaker 1: They got a trust fund and they sit around like playing, you know video poker and you know what also.
Speaker 0: this is an aside.
Speaker 0: There's nothing wrong with hipsters.
Speaker 0: I think the reason people are so threatened by hipsters and I see like talking to co-workers and people I get I figured it out They see a hipster.
Speaker 0: forget the trust fund.
Speaker 0: hipsters An actual hipster actual normal non trust fund hipster.
Speaker 0: All right, they have decided to issue some long-term corporate career.
Speaker 0: They're working at like Starbucks.
Speaker 0: All right, they're making enough money for rent and fun.
Speaker 0: They got like five roommates and they've decided rent and fun is gonna be their whole life.
Speaker 0: Mmm, is there anything wrong with that?
Speaker 0: Anyone who hates that is jealous of that?
Speaker 1: Well, I think the thing is the vast majority of them are the trust fund kind.
Speaker 1: There's almost none.
Speaker 0: that are the No, I think there's.
Speaker 1: I think it's about 50/50 I think I think you I think you are greatly Underestimating the number of people with trust funds.
Speaker 1: I've seen multiple Companies is actually a hot market of making things to help parents manage the trust funds because there are lots of them.
Speaker 0: No, so I think here's what's going on.
Speaker 0: I still think the majority of hipsters are non trust fund directly.
Speaker 0: However, I think every like core of hipsters like six hipsters living in one apartment I think one of them is the nucleus with the trust fund and the others are sponges.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're greatly I like.
Speaker 1: I know for a fact that they like.
Speaker 1: the number of trust funds is Number of hipsters.
Speaker 0: There's so many I think they really are.
Speaker 1: No, it's that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: It's pretty close.
Speaker 1: a lot of these kids They're just.
Speaker 1: you know Even if they don't have a trust fund they see their parents pay their rent and then all their stuff they.
Speaker 1: so they just bum Around but they don't live with their parents.
Speaker 0: So even with the trust fund what's better?
Speaker 0: the guy whose parents pays for him who lives the hipster life Or the guy who parents pay for him who eats bologna and white bread and plays video?
Speaker 1: Those are both, you know bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you should have your own monies.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 0: I've got free money forever.
Speaker 1: Because now you're.
Speaker 1: you don't have your shit together.
Speaker 1: who cares?
Speaker 1: you're like Scott pilgrim and kick your ass.
Speaker 0: What if I've got my shit together on every other facet of my life except money and money's coming in forever?
Speaker 1: You suck.
Speaker 0: Yeah Because you want that.
Speaker 0: no What if you won the lottery and you won that like $50,000 a year for life, I would do something with it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wouldn't sit around playing video poker and drinking paps loo ribbon all day No, but I'd sit around playing counter-strike and drinking chamois all day.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't you wait?
Speaker 0: that was me a waste and also podcast a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's doing something.
Speaker 1: Anyway, hipsters don't do anything.
Speaker 0: Sometimes they do.
Speaker 0: they go to bars and they talk about me.
Speaker 0: Maybe they're in a band I like in the end.
Speaker 0: how now Scott pilgrims band sucks?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that really like that was the coming-of-age.
Speaker 0: my band sucks and I don't care.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm You know, I don't think sex bomb was actually supposed to be that good either.
Speaker 0: No, they were powerful but not good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it wasn't like they were you know, touring the the country or anything.
Speaker 0: I think one thing I want to touch on.
Speaker 0: we've talked about this a couple of times.
Speaker 0: a lot of people have a very specific complaint about Scott pilgrim and the complaint they always make is The video game like they liked like most of us who like Emily's parents everyone like.
Speaker 0: maybe they get the references Maybe they don't but they like the core message the story the metaphor the world all that stuff.
Speaker 0: But I think a lot of people who were disappointed with the ending In fact, I think most people who are disappointed with the ending Didn't get the core message or didn't have the kind of life to where they would Understand on a personal level the core message and as a result Their primary enjoyment was the fight scenes and the humor and the video game references.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of people who enjoy it on that level and the people who enjoyed on that level.
Speaker 0: I can see why they would be very unsatisfied with the ending.
Speaker 0: They're like the end wasn't epic enough and That's bullshit.
Speaker 0: The ending was basically perfect.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, what other ending could you really have?
Speaker 1: I mean, that's the best ending you could have.
Speaker 1: but they're like.
Speaker 0: I wanted a big Wanted more video games thing.
Speaker 1: It was a big fight.
Speaker 0: They wanted a bigger fight and they want.
Speaker 0: They basically didn't care about the metaphor.
Speaker 1: I got a one-up.
Speaker 1: how much more video game do you want?
Speaker 0: They wanted more video game shit, and they didn't get the core messy.
Speaker 1: I think that's.
Speaker 1: the other thing is that you know You don't see having video game shit like that too often.
Speaker 1: There really isn't that much of it and it says a lot of it.
Speaker 1: like in.
Speaker 1: you know Volume one but a lot is like two or three half the people who make this like a pretty ransom coin and a skateboard And one up and I did.
Speaker 1: there's like three things.
Speaker 0: I Defy most of the people who have complained about the end of Scott Pilgrim from even knowing what clash at demon head is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So that's like, okay.
Speaker 1: So there are three video game things in a whole volume.
Speaker 1: There's not a lot of video game stuff going on It's just a little bit.
Speaker 1: but somehow people like, you know inflated to think like oh, there's so much of it.
Speaker 1: Holy crap It's just all about video game references.
Speaker 0: I do I think my favorite moment aren't that many.
Speaker 0: my favorite moment in the entire thing other than the cat thing at the end Was well now the bunch of room coming to my head.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, I could just talk about it forever.
Speaker 0: We'll do the movies.
Speaker 0: You should see thing where we just say all the things we liked and quote it.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I actually forgot what is very good now.
Speaker 0: bacon was good, but it wasn't great.
Speaker 0: It was when knives chow.
Speaker 0: her moment of closure with Scott Pilgrim was you will always be my clash at demon head Because that is such the perfect line.
Speaker 0: think about it the nostalgic First video game or memory of something that if you actually went back and played it for real is a piece of shit.
Speaker 0: But at the same time it was important to your development as a person.
Speaker 0: the memory of it is important to you and That's it.
Speaker 0: playing a game like clash at demon head Is?
Speaker 0: you don't want to play that now?
Speaker 1: But you don't watch him in there.
Speaker 0: your memory of playing it and your memory of watching it are very important and they shaped you As a person, yep, I had a lot of Master the Universe figures and when I see them I still go.
Speaker 0: I played a lot of really shitty NES and Atari games to the point of being scarily good at them.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, I wouldn't want to play him now.
Speaker 1: No Like if I break out the NES emulator like there's some games in there that I can play like Kirby's adventure or Super Mario 3.
Speaker 0: You're not playing.
Speaker 0: no Bunga's ambition.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean that's a difference.
Speaker 1: That's a different category.
Speaker 1: You know Megaman's I can play but Megaman one Metroid you can play Megaman one.
Speaker 1: Yeah But there are a lot of unplayable games like, you know Cheetah, man You know, what's fitting?
Speaker 1: I like Kung Fu Heroes, right?
Speaker 1: I played that game when I was a kid and I played it quite a bit, but it's pretty much unplayable now.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not totally broken as like the Cheetah men level, but it's pretty bad.
Speaker 1: You know and it's it's but I have fond memories of it, but I can't really play now.
Speaker 0: So I'm really looking forward to the movie like.
Speaker 0: I'm looking forward to this movie Almost as much as I was looking forward to like NS2.
Speaker 1: I'm not looking forward to that much.
Speaker 0: I'm more like not as much as I was looking forward to Team Fortress 2 you.
Speaker 1: the only movie I'm still looking forward to is Tron.
Speaker 1: I put all my eggs in one basket Tron.
Speaker 0: I'm looking forward to Tron, but I don't expect it to be better than Tron.
Speaker 1: Well much like clash at demon head right Tron.
Speaker 1: the story of the original Tron movies is there really?
Speaker 0: there's something that bothers me About Tron.
Speaker 0: So the arcade guy was complaining.
Speaker 0: He's basically like I made that game and that jerk stole it and now the kids are putting all their money Into his game in my arcade.
Speaker 0: It's his arcade.
Speaker 0: He's the one making the money.
Speaker 1: What the fuck.
Speaker 1: the story of Tron is really dumb.
Speaker 1: It doesn't hold up at all.
Speaker 0: It doesn't make any sense.
Speaker 1: These special effects don't really hold up that much.
Speaker 0: No They do.
Speaker 1: they were revolutionary at the time.
Speaker 0: They hold up in the same way that the daikon animation holds up.
Speaker 0: You watch it And if you understand what it is, it is awe Inspiring to see that what they pulled off.
Speaker 1: Yes, but the thing with Tron right is I don't expect the plot.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's a new trailer out that shows you some of the plot.
Speaker 0: It's a basically what I expect Some fucking light cycles.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a generic and black plot, you know, it's probably not gonna be something That's like oh my gosh It might have a twist ending or something like that But big deal.
Speaker 1: the reason that I'm holding all the eggs in the basket for Tron right is because a Daft Punk music B 3d IMAX.
Speaker 0: holy shit This scout pilgrim man, wouldn't it be awesome if they got like on him on a Gucci to do the music for the game Tron Man.
Speaker 0: what if they got like Daft Punk to do the music for Tron?
Speaker 0: they did.
Speaker 1: and Right fucking if I could go into any sort of world, you know that I would live in the Tron world.
Speaker 0: really Tron world.
Speaker 1: Yes, if there's any fictional world that I if they're not forgotten I would not pick Forgotten Realms You might you might be a peasant.
Speaker 0: What about Inception?
Speaker 0: No, yo dog.
Speaker 0: Yeah Of all the fictional old matrix if you're neo no, why not?
Speaker 1: No, I would rather be in Tron world.
Speaker 0: What if Tron is just the first the alpha version of the matrix?
Speaker 1: I've been Tron world.
Speaker 1: Tron world is the world to be in disc throwing by Scott Yahtzee.
Speaker 1: Plus didn't you see in the trailer?
Speaker 1: There's a new.
Speaker 1: it looks like there's a new flying thing.
Speaker 1: So it's like you might be a third Tron sport.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to play some ricochet.
Speaker 1: suddenly I want to play ricochet all the time.
Speaker 1: That's why I want to go to Tron world.
Speaker 0: I Also think that light water tasted really freakin good.
Speaker 1: Probably yeah, damn My water ran out.
Speaker 1: I'm getting warm.
Speaker 0: All right, I think we're done.
Speaker 0: So you have a pilgrim.
Speaker 1: Hopefully Brian Lee O'Malley will make another hit and not retire.
Speaker 0: I What I don't think I can do it.
Speaker 0: I wonder if I can get him on the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we only got like, you know a few hops away from him on the on the.
Speaker 1: you know The degrees.
Speaker 0: yeah, it was funny when I was like, yeah, I got movies to see the pre-screening and everyone was like Oh, yeah, because of geek nights.
Speaker 0: I was like no cuz I want a Twitter contest.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I read Midtown Comics.
Speaker 1: way to go Midtown Comics.
Speaker 0: Yeah Midtown Comics very good Ad with us by giving me tickets to Scott Miller.
Speaker 1: Midtown Comics like.
Speaker 1: they can have an ad anytime.
Speaker 1: It's a quality store.
Speaker 0: That's the thing.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: this is why We're so good at advertising things.
Speaker 0: when we do like burning wheels sells so much when we talk about it.
Speaker 1: I can advertise anything that is legitimately I believe in.
Speaker 1: if I don't believe in it and it sucks I can't advertise.
Speaker 0: so maybe our system should be you give us ten grand We review your thing privately and then we review it.
Speaker 0: Honestly if you if it's good No, we review it.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, your ten grand is on the whole.
Speaker 0: we review it honestly 100%.
Speaker 1: someone's gonna be pretty pissed off though if they passed, you know money to Advertise and we say we basically say they suck.
Speaker 0: so we review it honestly and we say here's what we said.
Speaker 0: Do you want us to put it up?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you paid either way, but we'll we'll just swallow it.
Speaker 0: the ten grand.
Speaker 1: They'll be pretty pissed.
Speaker 1: if they pay you money They expect you to say what they want you to say.
Speaker 0: I want to say the people who make it through the barrier like they I think those guys I'll talk about it.
Speaker 0: They're gonna make some bank probably.
Speaker 1: Yeah Whatever.
Speaker 0: All right, if anyone wants to give us ten grand, I'll talk about whatever you want me to talk about.
Speaker 1: We don't do advertisements on geek nights has to be on.
Speaker 1: something else would be an advertisement, okay a Paid review is an advertisement not if I'm honest.
Speaker 1: I Think it is so.
Speaker 0: this is so.
Speaker 0: so Wizards the coast gave me ten grand to talk about D&D.
Speaker 0: man You should really be playing burning wheel.
Speaker 1: Okay, I don't know.
Speaker 1: we need to.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think it's still an advertisement if you get paid.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Can't leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.