Speaker 1: It's Tuesday, November 9th.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight the lost art of the rented game.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So of course now that is the end of biking season no chance of biking until next year.
Speaker 1: I just bought all the lights that I needed for my bike to be biking at night.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I often buy things at a season and then the season comes around and then you know, yeah, it's weird I never thought to do it until like the very end of bike season.
Speaker 1: I'm like, oh bike lights.
Speaker 1: Now I got him sitting here.
Speaker 1: one thing though the one I got the rear light there was this like Amazon description of it and it was like this thing will annoy the ever-living.
Speaker 1: and then it was fuck kind of blocked out Of anyone behind you and no car will miss you.
Speaker 1: It is bright as fuck Alrighty, so it is bright as fuck.
Speaker 0: Oh god damn it.
Speaker 0: What kind did you buy?
Speaker 1: I bought that.
Speaker 1: the I fucker apparently Can't be legal.
Speaker 0: Well, it's.
Speaker 1: it's this bright on purpose for during the day You leave it on the solid beam.
Speaker 1: that'll basically blind anyone.
Speaker 0: and at night Why would you want to use it at all that has a patented annoying blink pattern?
Speaker 1: So no one can miss you.
Speaker 1: This thing is so bright.
Speaker 1: It hurts.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's two kinds of bike lights.
Speaker 0: right this see and be seen.
Speaker 1: Yep, this is this is be seen.
Speaker 0: it's the rear light only it is definitely be seen but that is like be more seen.
Speaker 1: Well, if I blind the driver behind me he might crash and then I won't have to worry about him into you.
Speaker 1: How annoying is this shit?
Speaker 0: this is great.
Speaker 0: So I went.
Speaker 0: Amazon had to sail where it was by two games.
Speaker 0: get one free to like any games.
Speaker 0: Well, no video games.
Speaker 1: and I was gonna say I'm gonna go buy some board game.
Speaker 0: No, and the thing was the list consisted mostly of pretty much every new video game for consoles, right?
Speaker 1: Almost all I should have paid attention.
Speaker 0: It was actually a rare opportunity to get a Nintendo game for cheap because if you bought three Wii games Even if they were the $50 kind published by Nintendo that never go down in price even after 20 years You could actually get 33% off.
Speaker 1: so because yeah If I enumerate all the game the physical media games I own for my Xbox that didn't come free with the Xbox I got Super Street Fighter 4 Mm-hmm Me too, so I ordered.
Speaker 0: I ordered a rock band three cuz I'm gonna get that guitar when it comes out in March.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm just waiting but I will get that.
Speaker 0: and I ordered The curvy with the yarn.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: I heard that was good.
Speaker 0: and the The Metroid one even though that's I heard it's not so good, but it's a Metroid game.
Speaker 0: So whatever.
Speaker 0: and I basically got one of the games for free because there was a sale.
Speaker 0: The thing was these games showed up and I hadn't yet replaced my Wii or Xbox.
Speaker 0: so on an Amazon and I bought a Wii and I bought an Xbox and and for the same price as you know, they came out just now with a Mario anniversary edition Wii that comes with the Mario Brothers Wii.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, isn't it like red or something?
Speaker 0: It's red and it also comes with a wiimote that has motion plus in it.
Speaker 1: Not bad.
Speaker 0: So it's the same price as the regular old Wii.
Speaker 0: so I bought.
Speaker 0: I got that It didn't show up yet though And I also bought an Xbox is basically the same as the Xbox I had before only the new slim kind and it comes with Forza and some other game.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got fours that came with mine.
Speaker 1: I've got it.
Speaker 1: I've never even opened it.
Speaker 1: I also came with like Halo something this comes with not halo.
Speaker 0: It's like Alan Wake.
Speaker 1: I think I got Halo something and fours is something and I have not.
Speaker 0: so the thing was I ordered the Xbox and then I Ordered the Wii and the Xbox is gonna come like this week.
Speaker 0: But after I ordered the Wii they combined them another coming in like two weeks.
Speaker 0: It's like ah you fucks I just bought these games now.
Speaker 0: I can't play them because you didn't send me the system.
Speaker 1: See luckily actually of all things I've been playing lately Scott Pilgrim.
Speaker 1: I've been actually working through.
Speaker 1: It's actually kind of hard.
Speaker 0: Oh the beating up game.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It's really hard.
Speaker 0: You need help to beat that shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've been trying to beat it on my own.
Speaker 1: just to get you know I was never that good at those kinds of games.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I'm working my way up.
Speaker 0: You're really good at just turning around and beating up your friends.
Speaker 1: I believe I was not.
Speaker 1: what I was not good at was Dealing with the fact that certain unnamed partners would jump in front of my goddamn lead pipe.
Speaker 1: Hey, I'd be beating a boss up and then scotch like her.
Speaker 0: better better More like you positioned your lead pipe, you know at the exact spot the other who I was gonna be.
Speaker 1: There's something wrong here because when you played with like Adam, it was fine.
Speaker 1: when I played with Adam It was fine when you played with me lead pipe face.
Speaker 0: I think it's just you're trying to do it Obviously.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 1: if I'm trying to do it, I just turn around and kill you which you did Sometimes all the time, but not all the time all the time sometimes.
Speaker 1: Actually, I was playing counter-strike yesterday, right and I kicked the terrorist.
Speaker 1: We're laying like dust and I just rushed in.
Speaker 1: I killed like three terrorists and I circle around back and I run forward.
Speaker 1: I'm doing great and one of my teammates literally falls down like from the ledge turns around sees me and deagle headshots me dead.
Speaker 0: Right that was on of course.
Speaker 1: All right team kill is like the best way to play anyway, and Yeah, that sucked.
Speaker 1: okay that anecdote didn't really go anywhere.
Speaker 1: I just played a lot of counter-strike And super meat.
Speaker 1: boy, I actually bought that.
Speaker 0: I was gonna buy it when I got my xbox.
Speaker 1: It's the best part about it is the fact that it's a hard console, but faster.
Speaker 1: It is hard but fair But it does the replay thing where once you finally beat something it shows simultaneously every failed attempt.
Speaker 0: No, that's awesome.
Speaker 1: So basically on some of the hard ones you see this sea of like a thousand meat boys dying One meat boy making it through.
Speaker 0: that's awesome.
Speaker 1: You'll see me like a hundred of them.
Speaker 1: Just barely missing the bonus.
Speaker 1: It's good times.
Speaker 1: actually.
Speaker 0: The game's actually really fun.
Speaker 0: I do I want to get.
Speaker 0: I just don't have an xbox cuz.
Speaker 0: No, poor xbox gonna take like a couple weeks for a new one to show up.
Speaker 1: So you got any goo.
Speaker 1: gaming news Xbox news Xbox news.
Speaker 0: so people don't realize this right.
Speaker 0: but like xbox games are actually sort of in like four or five different Categories and it's hard people to understand this.
Speaker 0: right this xbox games you buy in a disc.
Speaker 0: There's Xbox games that are full-on buying a disc games, but you buy them on the Xbox and you download them.
Speaker 0: You don't have to get this.
Speaker 0: Then there's games that are like.
Speaker 0: so like these live play games or it's like you don't have to download the whole game You can sort of play it.
Speaker 0: I don't understand really how it works.
Speaker 0: But anyway, then this xbox live arcade games Which is like it's sort of basically the same thing as we wear and this is what you get with your super meat boys and your Scott pilgrims, right and your whatnots.
Speaker 0: It's like a full-on game, but it's not a disc game.
Speaker 0: It's like it, you know, but it's not an indie game.
Speaker 0: It's actually a real publisher makes a game.
Speaker 0: That's supposed to be a downloaded game like puzzle quest is in there.
Speaker 0: You know that sort of stuff.
Speaker 1: a lot of them are basically just slightly better versions of flash games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then there's indie games that you're actually separate and it's like the indie games.
Speaker 0: You have to make them with XNA and there's all these limitations on what you can do.
Speaker 1: Apparently you have to make all of them abstract shapes jumping in rhythm because 90% of them are abstract.
Speaker 1: They're basically law of the ribbon.
Speaker 0: Yeah but basically these indie games just anyone can make one and then you have to submit it for approval.
Speaker 0: and basically approval means Like ten people.
Speaker 0: check it out to make sure there's no bugs or whatever and you meet certain Requirements.
Speaker 0: like it will work at different resolutions.
Speaker 0: It has a demo and what I might go for it.
Speaker 1: I've been learning the XNA.
Speaker 0: you just had to meet these requirements and then it's in and you can't charge more than five bucks.
Speaker 0: You have to charge at least a dollar, you know I forget exactly.
Speaker 0: and then it goes in.
Speaker 0: and basically what happened is they came with XNA for and the thing is there you They sort of they took silverlight which was originally competing with flash and now they're basically saying hey Make apps for the Windows Phone 7 using silverlight instead, you know.
Speaker 0: And so now instead of competing with flash which isn't gonna work.
Speaker 0: They're gonna be like, hey, it's a development platform And it kind of works that way There's a remarketing it and then they're like XNA.
Speaker 0: you there are.
Speaker 0: XNA originally was used to make Xbox PC and Zune games.
Speaker 0: It's not like well Zune is dead but make Windows Phone 7 games with XNA.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: and
Speaker 0: Yeah, they basically redid the whole XNA creators Club website to really target it at the phone development and the whole indie game development part sort of disappeared Mostly not completely but mostly and in the new Xbox interface which came out because of the Kinect they moved the indie games from one section to another and everyone was like Are you trying to get rid of us?
Speaker 0: So they caved and moved them back, which is good.
Speaker 0: But even so it's like It looks like Microsoft.
Speaker 0: they already treat these indie game people like crap.
Speaker 0: and then it's like why even have it in a separate section?
Speaker 0: just let people who make games make games and Let them put it in the Xbox thing arcade section with all the other game.
Speaker 0: what they're afraid of?
Speaker 1: even though it's not saying This is a legitimate fear.
Speaker 1: They're afraid of the old Atari situation.
Speaker 1: They don't want people to log in and go on Xbox Live arcade and be like I want to buy a new game and it's a sea of shit.
Speaker 1: Well, here's what you do, right if it's shit, you know You're gonna have a category for bad games.
Speaker 1: I Would say there's a. there should be a clause that if a game is bad enough Yeah You have to let them distribute it and it doesn't charge.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really matter because if you just go on the Xbox and you go to the Xbox Live arcade you say show me the Bestsellers and there's all the games that you want.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: You've had to go searching around.
Speaker 0: So none of the good game none of the shitty games are gonna show up there.
Speaker 0: So who gives a crap?
Speaker 0: and another thing that I don't like they should let people put up games for free.
Speaker 0: If I want to make a game for free, I should be allowed to do that.
Speaker 1: I know even evil Apple lets you do that Because I couldn't imagine ever making a game short of like a big-deal game That I would stick up there that I actually want to charge money for.
Speaker 0: even big companies might want to make a game purely for promotional purposes Like maybe they want to make a game that's solely for advertising like they make a game based on a movie That's about to come out and it's not a very good game Promotional game.
Speaker 1: No, no, they're not gonna give that.
Speaker 0: why would they?
Speaker 0: why would they want to charge money for that?
Speaker 1: They should just make it because promotional games get bought by grandmas who don't know better for nephews.
Speaker 0: But no, but this is Xbox Live Arcade.
Speaker 0: This isn't disc in the store Yeah, but grandma I'll do it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I can't possibly buy a game on the Xbox.
Speaker 1: I You know, we're gonna.
Speaker 1: someday we're gonna have the techno grandma at that.
Speaker 0: most grandma will give you Xbox Live points to buy a game.
Speaker 0: But you know if you want people to go let's say Tron.
Speaker 0: you make a Tron game a crappy little Tron game to promote the movie that's Coming up and you make the game free.
Speaker 0: They should be allowed to do that.
Speaker 1: Is there a minimum price?
Speaker 1: Can I be like a penny?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a dollar.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, it's not that bad.
Speaker 0: So would you pay a dollar for promotional piece of shit?
Speaker 0: That might not be a crowd.
Speaker 1: Maybe they don't want that stuff in there.
Speaker 1: But the thing is they can have that stuff in there and help them out plus at the same time one thing I mean, I can't imagine a game I would make Crappy, I mean, I'm not saying I agree with them.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying it's not that bad.
Speaker 0: The only thing is right is like on the one hand we look at the Atari example and we say oh man If you get a ton of shovelware, you're fucked.
Speaker 1: Ah, but on the other hand example look at 99% of NES games are shit.
Speaker 0: Look at every little shit.
Speaker 0: Look at everything since the Atari right?
Speaker 0: Let's see DS GBA.
Speaker 0: You know the.
Speaker 1: we see now Scott.
Speaker 1: Here's the difference.
Speaker 0: all tons of shop.
Speaker 1: the shovelware we get within it like with the old Nintendo seal of approval or seal of quality or whatever.
Speaker 1: Those games at least will boot and will play to complete even the Xbox live indie games.
Speaker 0: They force them to do that.
Speaker 0: the Atari games.
Speaker 0: someone wouldn't that's true But you know the most successful money makers are the people who are loaded with the shovelware iPhone.
Speaker 1: Come on that's all pay shovelware.
Speaker 0: I'm just know this free shovelware?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the pay shovel?
Speaker 1: where's where the money is?
Speaker 0: I'm just saying people if people are gonna pay for a fart app and then someone else is gonna make a free fart app They still pay because the pain is better.
Speaker 0: King Apple mad bank.
Speaker 0: Then Xbox should also have the free and paid fart app.
Speaker 1: Actually an Xbox fart app wouldn't be that on useful If everyone can see on the TV that you're making farts if you could run it in the background and bind it to a Key and then it would fart over the microphones.
Speaker 0: multiplayer.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna skip a lot of the details of this but this is an article from October 20th about how some dudes made hacks for Starcraft 2 to cheat at the game in single-player and some other people made ones to cheat the game in multiplayer.
Speaker 1: and There was the brouhaha where Blizzard was banning people for cheating in the single-player game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know this reminds me of something.
Speaker 0: be net D ha ha Fucking blizzard.
Speaker 1: Why do you always do the same stuff?
Speaker 0: But What amazed me was that most people don't even know what the hell be 90 here.
Speaker 1: We're old.
Speaker 1: That's why we're making that's.
Speaker 1: that's the theme of our new geek Back in the day.
Speaker 0: There was just as many be net D news stories on the slash dot as there were SEO stories.
Speaker 1: Wow, I feel really old suddenly and the show's even gonna make me feel older.
Speaker 1: but so the rationale for this which is amazing Is that if you cheat in the single-player game in an unauthorized manner?
Speaker 0: You can't get his authorized cheating.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we really need to get on that shit.
Speaker 0: That's so bad.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: do you see that college humor of like three?
Speaker 1: Okay Starcraft players against one like world champion.
Speaker 1: Yeah He's just like toying with them.
Speaker 0: I mean the thing is it's like It would be okay almost if it wasn't.
Speaker 0: I don't know It's like why is that?
Speaker 0: give me a bad feeling.
Speaker 0: but like Michael Jordan or Magic Johnson playing against a normal person Doesn't give you a bad feeling.
Speaker 0: it's like yep That's how it should be.
Speaker 0: but when a Starcraft died as it's like oh It's so wrong because Michael Jordan is to is to basketball.
Speaker 1: a pale comparison as to what these Starcraft.
Speaker 0: But if you go to play basketball against the worst guy in the entire NBA like The guy who warms the bench all season right and never never even touches the ball.
Speaker 0: You're get you're still gonna.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling Starcraft is like that too.
Speaker 1: Yeah anyone in a league.
Speaker 1: I got no chance.
Speaker 1: I'm I won't even get a unit built I don't.
Speaker 0: but it's like.
Speaker 0: why does it feel okay for it to per when it's like a sport or something legitimate?
Speaker 0: But it does.
Speaker 0: it feels like there's something cruel and wrong and amiss when it's Starcraft.
Speaker 1: Well big one.
Speaker 1: There's something hilarious about the.
Speaker 1: I may imagining the Detroit Red Wings playing against like some six-year-olds in South Park.
Speaker 1: Yes And two, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think it was because that video had the guy the guys playing.
Speaker 1: It's film.
Speaker 1: the two sides and the people trying to beat the expert are like, I think he's just toying with us.
Speaker 1: I think he could beat us at any time and it was true.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the rationale for banning people who cheated single-player with unauthorized cheats is that it messes up the achievement system.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't even have to say anything.
Speaker 1: yeah, let that go.
Speaker 1: the thing I want to point out is that blizzard is going one step further.
Speaker 1: in blizzard We met a bunch of your developers at PAX.
Speaker 0: I'm not a bunch of you guys.
Speaker 1: I know you guys are totally cool.
Speaker 1: this is not a disparaging of you.
Speaker 1: blizzard is suing and Pursuing legal action against three developers who made hacks.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty confident that if blizzard consisted of nothing but developers and artists that this would not happen, right?
Speaker 0: It's it's simply that you know, it's like go to any company.
Speaker 0: go to the evilest.
Speaker 0: come.
Speaker 0: What's the evilest company you could think of right now?
Speaker 1: It's BP All right.
Speaker 1: So you go to BP right and you find that what I just said is in no way an indication of any like actual Advice to invest in any company.
Speaker 0: I have to say things like we got it We go to BP right and we go and find like the guy who drives the truck to deliver the gas or You know the guy who makes the website.
Speaker 0: It's not evil.
Speaker 0: They're totally just normal Evil.
Speaker 1: dude watch maybe they are evil.
Speaker 0: The only is really just reliquor.
Speaker 0: You know, it's just a few maybe a few evil people or maybe just a couple people who are like, you know They don't like what they're doing, but it's their job.
Speaker 0: Like there's that web developer He's totally not evil.
Speaker 0: But then you know, the boss is like you got to improve the Google ranking.
Speaker 0: I brought in this evil SEO guy.
Speaker 0: You got to do whatever he does or he says you're fired.
Speaker 0: You're like, oh fuck.
Speaker 0: I don't want to do evil SEO that the S and it's like aha You have to do it and SEO guys like hey It's really easy to make a ton of money selling his SEO bullshit to companies.
Speaker 0: I don't care.
Speaker 1: Here's the trouble.
Speaker 0: I know it's evil whatever.
Speaker 1: from the first day I got my cable modem and I went online and I played quake one against other people.
Speaker 1: I Was afraid of cheaters, I wish cheating was illegal.
Speaker 1: I wanted nothing more than a way to punch through the screen at people who were clearly cheating.
Speaker 1: Yes At the same time it is not illegal to cheat.
Speaker 1: in most situations in the world.
Speaker 0: You can cheat a monopoly as long as you don't cheat in a casino.
Speaker 0: Hey, you know, it should be totally cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah I actually I think what most games need is they simply just need like what half-life has which is like hey This is a no cheat server and this is a cheat server.
Speaker 0: If you want to cheat on the cheat server go nuts.
Speaker 1: if you cheat on the non cheat server banned forever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's you know.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: I call it a day.
Speaker 0: I'm Welcome.
Speaker 0: Starcraft doesn't have the okay cheat server and the not okay cheat server.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is here's the trouble.
Speaker 0: I remember Diablo 2 actually had that.
Speaker 0: in Diablo 2 you could play on the Open battle net or the real battle and the real battle.
Speaker 0: that was harsh.
Speaker 0: It's like if you died if your guy died there you a dead dead.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: it was serious business to play in the real battle net.
Speaker 0: But if you play it on the open battle net it was just like hack your save file.
Speaker 0: Do whatever the fuck you want.
Speaker 0: It's open battle that it's multiplayer.
Speaker 0: do whatever.
Speaker 0: duplicating items.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah duplicating the whatever that ring that gave you +1 everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so how are they suing them?
Speaker 1: It's not illegal to cheat.
Speaker 0: It's not illegal to help violating the EULA maybe.
Speaker 0: uh
Speaker 1: so Quote when the users of the hacks Download install and use the hacks there They copy Starcraft to copyrighted content into their computers RAM in Excess of the scope of their limited license set forth in the EULA and the terms
Speaker 0: of the EULA to
Speaker 1: create Derivative works of Starcraft.
Speaker 1: So I bring this up on a Tuesday because this is this language almost word for word Comes up on Mondays a lot because this bullshit is the reason like fundamentally our laws are not keeping up with technology and to argue that you're creating a derivative work of anything in the course of copying into your RAM is Ludicrous to the point that is physically painful.
Speaker 0: Well, let me make an analogy here, right?
Speaker 0: So here's here's what's going on.
Speaker 0: So I have a vinyl record.
Speaker 0: Right, it would be one thing if I copied the vinyl record to a cassette tape or and then remixed it on there.
Speaker 0: Right, that is a derivative work.
Speaker 0: If I take a knife to the final record and just scratch it up No, it's not derivative work.
Speaker 0: No, cuz I didn't derive and make a copy.
Speaker 0: I just modified the work in place.
Speaker 1: Ah, but it's a copy in RAM because you have the code.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's the original copy.
Speaker 1: See, here's here's the trouble with this argument And this is I can bring it up on Tuesday cuz I could explain it again to people who might not know.
Speaker 1: When you run a program, there's variables and shit in your RAM.
Speaker 1: That's copied all over the place.
Speaker 0: To do anything with a computer.
Speaker 0: You must copy.
Speaker 0: the computer has bits and it puts the bits in like ten places at all time.
Speaker 0: That's how computers work.
Speaker 0: See all is impossible to compute anything without copying.
Speaker 1: So it's BS.
Speaker 1: for all the reasons I said, that's all I could say about that.
Speaker 1: You can look into this more if you care.
Speaker 0: I blame this Partially, I mean like Blizzard was against like the V net D in the olden days.
Speaker 0: But now I think if Activision had if they had not combined, I don't think it would be this bad.
Speaker 1: No, I don't think it would be this bad.
Speaker 1: And the thing is don't get me wrong.
Speaker 1: I am all for Blizzard and valve and any company that runs online games from making sure that When it is not allowed people are not cheating in multiplayer versus game.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I think you know, I think I'm gonna do.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: No, I figured out the way to stop all cheating.
Speaker 1: Uh Fist through screen technology.
Speaker 0: No, here's how you do it.
Speaker 0: You're ready.
Speaker 0: It's really simple.
Speaker 0: You see right now valve for example, right has cheating servers and non cheating servers, but the cheating servers, right?
Speaker 0: It's like they don't actually give you any cheats.
Speaker 0: You have to still go get some hacked up cheats from somewhere.
Speaker 0: Give people the cheats like sieve to give them a fucking cheat menu with every conceivable cheat imaginable.
Speaker 1: I believe Starcraft has something like that.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: just give them every cheats and no one has to hack or modify the game in any way ever.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to because we already gave you every cheat.
Speaker 0: works perfectly Scott.
Speaker 1: He's and then we'll turn him on.
Speaker 1: Don't kid yourself 90% of the people cheating in Counter-Strike don't want to play on a server where everyone's speed hacking.
Speaker 1: They want to be the one guy who at start appears on the other side and knifes everyone to death.
Speaker 1: All right, which is kind of hilarious the first time it happens.
Speaker 0: So here's also what we do.
Speaker 0: You ready?
Speaker 0: I in order to play our game, right?
Speaker 0: We get your address because that's what you need to get an account and then we come to your house.
Speaker 0: So we punch you in the face.
Speaker 0: I'm done completely like I'm not even joking.
Speaker 0: We actually come to your house.
Speaker 1: You didn't say if they cheat.
Speaker 1: you just said we come to your house and punch you in the face.
Speaker 1: Yeah Just regardless.
Speaker 0: That's the warning shot.
Speaker 0: So, you know that if you cheat we you know, we do it to everybody.
Speaker 0: it's like we know where you live.
Speaker 0: Punch you in the face if you cheat.
Speaker 0: We already punched you in the face.
Speaker 1: once we may do it again.
Speaker 0: So, I mean you didn't even cheat or anything To get hurt.
Speaker 0: So you just think about what will happen if you cheat on the non cheating server.
Speaker 0: I just want you to think about that because you know feel your face right now.
Speaker 0: now think don't even think of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go now right and if you want to cheat on the non cheating server, you may see me again.
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day we never get tired of these.
Speaker 1: I love it when you see middle and high school kids Elementary school kids playing football or baseball and Someone pulls the trick play.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean the thing is right is Trick plays don't work in professional sports.
Speaker 0: that well or pretty much ever right one.
Speaker 1: The rules are set to where it's basically impossible to get away with that because to Anyone who's being paid to play football and that is their life and that is their career They will likely never do anything else except possibly commentate on football.
Speaker 1: They are not going to be tricked.
Speaker 1: that whistle blows that ball moves they're hitting someone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know.
Speaker 0: the thing is is you know?
Speaker 0: in almost all sports right is because you know coaches know that You can trick kids.
Speaker 0: they teach their kids to trick the other kids for example a classic thing to do in very in Little League Baseball, right a Major League Baseball someone gets a walk.
Speaker 0: They just walk to first base and that's it.
Speaker 0: and Pretty much Little League Baseball anything lower than minor league baseball even high school baseball.
Speaker 0: You see this sometimes when you get a walk They run the first base and if the P the other team's not paying attention Let's keep running a second and it totally works a lot of time.
Speaker 1: nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 0: Nothing wrong perfectly legitimate.
Speaker 0: It's totally sweet.
Speaker 1: It's a situation much like how Stratego major league baseball.
Speaker 0: if you even tried that you would be out so fast It wouldn't work at all.
Speaker 1: Stratego a board game.
Speaker 1: This is like the crux of one of the panels.
Speaker 1: we used to do a pecs if you're not good at Stratego.
Speaker 1: It is a very like tactical game and there's all these like strategies you can follow in the sub game.
Speaker 1: That don't exist.
Speaker 1: if you're a good player because you know better and you know, your opponent knows better You know, they won't work.
Speaker 1: You don't even bother with them.
Speaker 1: it's an entirely different game with far fewer strategic options and Sports are basically the same way.
Speaker 1: if everyone's professional and athletic like good then 99% of the tricks just cannot work which is why I love this shit.
Speaker 1: What else can I say?
Speaker 1: it's just another trick play and I wish well I don't wish we could change the rules of major league sports to allow for some of this.
Speaker 0: Well, the problem is right is well anytime there's an optimal strategy.
Speaker 0: Everyone will converge upon, you know college football has some of this stuff Right, you know, there's some trick plays going on there.
Speaker 0: But if you a lot if you started to you know, lax up the rules in you know Professional sports to allow, you know, make it easier to do fancy trick plays and whatever It wouldn't really work because everyone would just adapt to it and it would just.
Speaker 0: it would just basically it would just break the game.
Speaker 1: Well, like I said, well they did anyway.
Speaker 1: ever in a sport where it matters where everyone is trying to win as hard as they Can even if no one ever cheats?
Speaker 0: Everyone will eventually converge upon an optimal solution because all Solution or random even in NFL football, but we know which is far more limited than college football and what you can do, right?
Speaker 0: There is still a huge huge variety of things you can do in formations and plays.
Speaker 0: you can you know.
Speaker 0: This is really a huge, you know ceiling unlike all the different kind of plays you can try to do.
Speaker 1: as opposed to say baseball where there is a relatively limited number of strategies and strategy most mostly in baseball comes down to What talent do you have and how do you best use?
Speaker 0: yet in NFL football, right?
Speaker 0: Even with all those possible things you can do there are most of the things and all know all you know They hardly ever do them because they're just a bad idea.
Speaker 0: Well, look at hot or they do them incredibly rarely because they're incredibly rarely a good idea and they'll pretty much only do them Like if it's a last-ditch effort, right?
Speaker 0: For example, did you know that in certain situations?
Speaker 0: Even if the clock has run out you can get a free kick through the uprights to get three points, right?
Speaker 0: when does that happen?
Speaker 0: almost never because Nobody right.
Speaker 0: you can actually do it at the half like if time runs out And a certain, you know Like and so it misses a field goal and it doesn't go out of the back of the end zone You can actually go and get the ball and start running with it.
Speaker 0: You know, how does that happen?
Speaker 0: hardly ever happens, right?
Speaker 1: Well, like look at hockey that you know The trap started to dominate play and then rules change to get rid of that.
Speaker 0: Hockey is actually the best professional sport in terms of just changing the rules immediately like that day.
Speaker 0: if they see something stupid They just fix the rules right away.
Speaker 1: Well, they also have the wonderful Centralized adjudication.
Speaker 0: that is also an excellent.
Speaker 1: soccer could learn a thing or two from hockey.
Speaker 0: soccer could learn a thing or two from anything.
Speaker 1: No, no soccer could learn a thing or two from the 21st century or the 20th century.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway, I guess you under my thing today, perhaps.
Speaker 0: So here's this website called inform seven.
Speaker 0: calm and what this website is?
Speaker 1: It's one more than inform six.
Speaker 0: Well, you know how when you're playing action castle, right?
Speaker 0: The computer is basically just a dick and it's like oh you said, you know get instead of pick up or you know It's very finicky much like a real text.
Speaker 0: adventure is incredibly finicky.
Speaker 0: You have to type in the exact right command to get it to do what you want.
Speaker 1: Actually quest for glory 2 was surprisingly lax.
Speaker 0: Anyway, well, I mean, yeah, but it wasn't really lax It was just we put in a bunch of synonyms.
Speaker 0: Yeah This is actually the beginnings of a system for interactive fiction, which is another way of which is the modern appropriate way of saying text adventure Novel exactly.
Speaker 0: And basically this engine is is designed to where you can actually have the text.
Speaker 0: adventures use Natural language as opposed to computer language, right?
Speaker 0: So you could just be like I go to the store You know, I walk around and you know and you can just type in normal stuff and you can.
Speaker 0: actually it's it's better than Thank quest for glory or Zork.
Speaker 1: I feel like they're two different genres.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know but the point is is that this is interactive fiction with natural language.
Speaker 0: They're actually making significant real progress.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 1: Check it out.
Speaker 1: Well think about it.
Speaker 1: someday we'll get to the point to where on their Kindle or Nook or whatever Someone's gonna download a novel that is basically a hyper advanced.
Speaker 1: choose your own adventure.
Speaker 0: I think they already have those on there and actually it's way easier because you don't have to flip through looking for the page.
Speaker 1: Just tell you just touch your you know, go but then I can't keep my finger in all the pages and read all the deaths.
Speaker 0: You can use the bookmark feature of the Kindle.
Speaker 0: Even I books, but isn't that cheating?
Speaker 1: That's like no clipping.
Speaker 1: How is that cheating using the bookmarks to go back?
Speaker 0: Okay, why is it cheating if there's no winning and there's no losing?
Speaker 0: you're just reading a book.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 1: So maybe blizzard should shut the fuck up about people cheating in single play.
Speaker 0: It's like I buy a book.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna read all the pages.
Speaker 0: Well, it's cheating if you leave you skip a page.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: I own this whole book.
Speaker 1: Well, you just read the end.
Speaker 0: It's not like if there was a trophy.
Speaker 0: whoever finishes the book first, but there is.
Speaker 1: it's an achievement.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, you need if you need a trophy to feel good about yourself finishing a book.
Speaker 0: You got bigger problems.
Speaker 1: No If you need a trophy to feel good about finishing a you need to feel good about.
Speaker 1: if you need to feel good about Ignites a self-addressed stamped envelope with $50 in it and I will send you a trophy.
Speaker 0: I Actually, I know we're more than one trophy store is in the city.
Speaker 1: I was looking at one of those trophy stores in Midtown because I was thinking it's probably the one I one of the ones I know might have been because I was.
Speaker 1: I was looking at other merch to start selling and I Thought about making a trophy for smart people.
Speaker 1: and then I decided it was a stupid idea and didn't pursue it any further.
Speaker 0: Very stupid.
Speaker 1: We used to have the idea of doing a are you cool?
Speaker 1: test to conventions?
Speaker 0: We could make.
Speaker 0: we could buy the cheapest possible trophy.
Speaker 0: You know the one that they use and they just give to everybody for showing up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and on it we could engrave Achievement unlocked bought the cheapest room Bought myself a trophy clever girl something like that.
Speaker 1: No We had our old idea of the surf.
Speaker 1: we would have Certified awesome people and you'd have you take our test.
Speaker 1: you got to pay to take it and you get a certificate and a t-shirt.
Speaker 1: Alright, remember that we never actually did that.
Speaker 1: cuz we're lazy.
Speaker 0: I thought you were just gonna start.
Speaker 0: we were gonna choose people that we knew that were awesome and just give out awards.
Speaker 1: Oh, that was the geek nights.
Speaker 1: That never happened either.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we need it.
Speaker 0: We need a sword.
Speaker 0: do that and they had to kneel before.
Speaker 1: I don't want to give away swords.
Speaker 0: No, no, you don't give them the sword.
Speaker 0: They you have.
Speaker 0: it's your sword.
Speaker 0: have a sword and they kneel before you and then you can get them.
Speaker 1: I have that bastard sword.
Speaker 0: The thing is it's gotta be real careful when you're connecting someone.
Speaker 0: cuz remember when they can they get they can niggits they're wearing armor So it goes clink clink, but if they're not more normal people don't have armor, they're wearing threadless.
Speaker 0: You're just gonna chop their fucking arms off.
Speaker 0: You gotta be careful.
Speaker 0: So the meta moment we are going to be at mag fast paxies pax west anime Boston conventions about the book club book is World War Z by Max Brooks, so I just learned is the son of Mel Brooks.
Speaker 0: I did not know that.
Speaker 0: Ah Some other meta news.
Speaker 0: you should go to our website because it's slightly updated and there's like.
Speaker 0: I actually Sort of drew more attention towards the secret Not-so-secret RSS feeds like there's an RSS feed of things of the day and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Yep Also our forum.
Speaker 0: you have to go to some subscribe page.
Speaker 0: you click on the top right of the front.
Speaker 0: recruit calm This is subscribe thingy, but we'll tell you what's up.
Speaker 1: our forum We haven't said this on the show in the while is Really rocking and way different from other forums on the internet.
Speaker 1: for those of you who don't know many of our new listeners one Grammar and spelling are required and you get fucking banned if you can't keep that up.
Speaker 0: She comes our forum and also I'm gonna start a mailing newsletter thing soon.
Speaker 0: ish and You know, a lot of people say I don't want any spam.
Speaker 0: Well, so don't fucking sign up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's pretty much all there is to it.
Speaker 0: I mean there are people who want it and they actually they work.
Speaker 0: Well, if you statistically speaking they scarily work well.
Speaker 1: So it'll also get me to start writing again because I haven't.
Speaker 1: I've got like 90 half-finished blog articles.
Speaker 1: I never uploaded yeah, and That's it.
Speaker 1: yeah, that's it.
Speaker 0: Oh you can just follow us on Twitter.
Speaker 0: - yeah twitter.com slash geek nights.
Speaker 0: It randomly tweets out old Old old incredibly old episode and things of the day.
Speaker 0: So, you know, if you're like someone who's new to the show, you can just follow that Twitter and every day, you know You someday you'll get the vaunted glorious masturbation episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it actually just tweeted out Fast karate for the keep them.
Speaker 1: Ah, that was a good up.
Speaker 1: I Still have to make my Tanaka mashup anyway, so When I was a lad, I remember very distinctly that we were po that we would.
Speaker 1: now we actually quite well off.
Speaker 1: At least we seem quite well off.
Speaker 1: We would go with my parents to the local video rental store.
Speaker 1: Not a chain, but a store.
Speaker 1: and in that store, they had a VHS section and a Betamax section.
Speaker 1: They also had a small laser disc collection in the back And I would go and I would rent one of the 10 or 11 NES games that they had.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Cuz where I was.
Speaker 1: it was a dollar a day.
Speaker 0: We had a VHS store and they pretty much only had VHS and then it wasn't.
Speaker 0: there weren't any other stores until Blockbusters showed up and one of the first really one of the one of the earliest Blockbusters was pretty near us and it opened up with like a crazy grand opening that was off the hook.
Speaker 1: actually way before Blockbuster came near me.
Speaker 0: We had mammoth video Wow And we had like a place.
Speaker 0: that was.
Speaker 0: there were only one of it was like video something or other.
Speaker 1: I don't know the history for all.
Speaker 1: I know they all like bought each other or whatever but as a kid mammoth video looked exactly like blockbuster looks now like blue awnings and everything and They gave you balloons with mammoths on them whenever you check stuff out.
Speaker 1: and they had consoles to rent and they had NES games To rent.
Speaker 0: Yes See the blockbuster when it opened it had the NES games But didn't have anything else and then it wasn't until later that they started to add more stuff like the console.
Speaker 1: It is telling me other games for other system that almost none of the places I went to before the blockbuster era had any Sega games.
Speaker 1: It was just NES.
Speaker 1: That was it.
Speaker 0: I think it's.
Speaker 0: I just had blockbuster earlier than anyone else and they've kicked everyone else out of town because the Blockbuster that opened up was so gigantic and it opened up way early in life.
Speaker 1: Scott I just realized when we got to RIT we would watch anime on VHS tapes because no one had a DVD player.
Speaker 1: Yeah, none of us had a DVD player or a cell phone when we got to college.
Speaker 0: Do you remember that the ps2 right when it came out?
Speaker 0: It was very popular because it also included a DVD player.
Speaker 0: I remember we tried to win one and - was released when we were at our IT it.
Speaker 0: that's when it came out.
Speaker 0: In fact, I remember it was crazy because they did not have ps2s before we were in college.
Speaker 1: Someone brought one to the RIT anime club at a social night.
Speaker 1: We played that one launch game on it for like ever Yep.
Speaker 1: Wow, I feel really old.
Speaker 0: But then when in a few years like everyone had one and there were Japanese ones and it was whatever.
Speaker 1: Yep, and now RIT anime.
Speaker 1: like no one has a VHS player.
Speaker 1: Those tapes are all useless.
Speaker 0: I know they still charge way too much money for the the slim one and it's still slightly troublesome to emulate.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I had this whole like childhood spirits book.
Speaker 1: Remember crystalis good game.
Speaker 1: you know the end day in 1997 and all that and I remember that I did not own it for a long time until eventually I bought it used at Funko land.
Speaker 0: There was a Funko land near us.
Speaker 0: We never went to it.
Speaker 1: I went to it all the time.
Speaker 0: It was basically free arcade because it wasn't that near.
Speaker 0: it was like an hour away.
Speaker 0: Oh god It was.
Speaker 0: I always saw commercials for it all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I sold Final Fantasy 1 to Funko land for $25 and a year later.
Speaker 1: I bought it back for $10.
Speaker 0: Isn't it funny to like gay, you know Funko land is basically the GameStop business before EB, you know EB was even older than that.
Speaker 0: Ah, but unlike GameStop EB started out as like Babbage's in more PC stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see game GameStop actually showed up way late in the game Except I wouldn't buy PC games at Babbage's because they were in the mall and overpriced.
Speaker 1: I would go to like cop USA.
Speaker 0: Well, you go to like software etc.
Speaker 0: Also the software etc.
Speaker 0: EB and Babbage's were all the same thing.
Speaker 0: eventually Yeah, and then GameStop bought the whole thing.
Speaker 1: Media play.
Speaker 0: it's like.
Speaker 0: why didn't Funko land?
Speaker 0: because it was GameStop before there was GameStop.
Speaker 0: Why didn't it become?
Speaker 1: because the used game market was so segmented and there wasn't enough money in it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Plus parents just dropped their kids.
Speaker 0: Funko land was obviously big enough but you know so that there was one in Michigan and in Connecticut one in Michigan.
Speaker 1: There were a ton.
Speaker 1: They're all over the place.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're all what happened to them.
Speaker 1: They were the only game in town.
Speaker 1: just there wasn't enough money in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Plus after they like the n64 like everything changed rapidly.
Speaker 1: It's amazing how much the video game landscape changed in the last 30 years because we've been playing games for almost 30 years.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: so I'd ever owned crystallis and what I would do is, you know every couple of weeks Well, you know my parents would say hey, let's go rent a movie and of course our badge of them to let me let me rent an NES game and I would rent a game That I didn't own and take it home and play it just for that weekend and I had to bring it back on Monday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, you know, it's like borrowing a game for a friend.
Speaker 0: So, you know except you had to pay and you had to give it back right away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you couldn't really beat an NES game in three days depends on the game depends on the game.
Speaker 1: Most games you couldn't beat in three days.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and did you ever rent a game more than once?
Speaker 1: Yep, like crystallis I read it like five or six times.
Speaker 0: I ran it.
Speaker 0: I think fix Anna doo doo two times.
Speaker 1: Ah, thanks Anna doo.
Speaker 1: I gave these remake but the coolest thing is they're like, I feel like there's this whole Segment of gaming like this whole world of game Experience stuff that kids today will never experience.
Speaker 1: not necessarily great experiences at times But it's something that you just don't experience.
Speaker 1: You don't rent games.
Speaker 1: Let alone even if you rent games All right.
Speaker 1: I've rented a game on a disc for my Xbox Crystallis.
Speaker 1: when I rented it had a save game.
Speaker 1: The guy's name was beer and he was like way leveled up and had all these items.
Speaker 1: I'd never seen.
Speaker 1: I Would like every time I rented a game the coolest thing was looking at the save games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, I mean it was always, you know Even if you borrowed like your friend Zelda and you hadn't beaten Zelda yet, and it's like whoa, what's this stuff?
Speaker 0: He's got.
Speaker 0: I were like, you know Best possible stuff is when you go to the GameStop and you buy like a used copy of Pokemon or something.
Speaker 1: Ah, there's Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Nothing beats that.
Speaker 1: I think I followed in the footsteps of a slightly older gamer because I you know the character.
Speaker 1: beer in Crystallis was like level 16 and like be almost beating the game and When I rented earthbound the power was beer in the save game.
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah Yeah, there's a whole.
Speaker 0: you know the thing with renting games, right?
Speaker 0: It's like basically we stopped renting games in the PlayStation era.
Speaker 1: Well after the PlayStation one Everyone rented PlayStation games from like what red octane?
Speaker 0: No, no back in the day remember High school my friend would go and he would rent like every PlayStation game a blockbuster copy them all no matter what the hell they.
Speaker 0: Yep, all right, and he had a mod chip and then he would return him and he basically bought every PlayStation game for like three Bucks each instead of 50 bucks each.
Speaker 1: I did the gigantic binder of like 200 PlayStation games like our friend Kevin had.
Speaker 0: like every ps1 game ever and it's almost every ps1 game burned them all even crappy ones That no one wanted to play.
Speaker 0: he would get him.
Speaker 1: Anyway, see I didn't bother with that because I used red octane which used to be just an odd.
Speaker 0: We need to do that until you get to college.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was a Netflix of video games back then.
Speaker 0: Realize that red out the same red octane that eventually made DDR pads and all that stuff and I think is now part of That like a conglomerate of you know Whatever those all those companies harmonics and mad cats and whoever the fuck I don't even know anymore.
Speaker 0: It got so convoluted, but they basically started out by being a Netflix of video games.
Speaker 0: You know while Netflix is still very young.
Speaker 1: but the biggest thing they had going for them is that they had a lot of import Games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was the reason that they made money is because of these import games Especially DDR at the height of its popularity.
Speaker 0: So people who wanted a copy DDR could get one easily from you know From red octane and then they would burn DDR.
Speaker 0: and because I think red octane saw that DDR was like this huge Incredibly popular game that was being rented from them.
Speaker 0: That's how they got into the DDR pad sell reselling and then making business.
Speaker 1: I remember very distinctly.
Speaker 1: I got my ps1 that I bought for 90 bucks at Kmart the summer after we were at RIT and I've installed my mod chip.
Speaker 1: never used it.
Speaker 1: I installed the mod chip before I booted it and Then I put in a game that I pirated from win MX Megaman legends, I think wow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just to see if it worked.
Speaker 1: It didn't work.
Speaker 1: I had to open it and re solder something that I broke and then it worked.
Speaker 1: and then red octane delivered DDR extra mix Copied it and I played DDR on that thing.
Speaker 1: Ah It's just.
Speaker 1: I feel like video game rental is going to disappear completely with the modern.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean there was that game tap thing, right?
Speaker 0: Which is yeah, not really rental, but not really buying either.
Speaker 0: It was like you pay every month.
Speaker 0: in a way We're going you can play all these games, but anyway paying you get to stop playing.
Speaker 1: We're going back to like the old share where kind of thing where people instead of renting a game to try it out Which is the primary.
Speaker 1: I've rented games for two reasons.
Speaker 1: either the game wasn't good enough to buy But I wanted to play it for a weekend or I didn't know if I wanted to buy the game.
Speaker 0: I think the two things that destroyed rental right or number one.
Speaker 0: I already mentioned the you know, the discs being copied right but to the digital distribution.
Speaker 0: But the digital distribution isn't what in and of itself what's hurt the rental?
Speaker 0: Although it has partially right because they still sell games on discs and whatever, right?
Speaker 0: It's the fact that not only are they distributing the games digitally so there's nothing to rent it's you know There's no physical thing.
Speaker 0: It's that you don't actually need to have the disc to play.
Speaker 0: you get the disc you install it with the CD key All right, so you can't even rent that shit out.
Speaker 0: But on top of that, right?
Speaker 0: What happens with the digital distribution is if a game becomes old they lower the price and lower the price.
Speaker 0: and lower the price because think about it if you if I make a game and I Sell you a copy to a store and the store rents it out a hundred times Then I only sold one copy, but really there's a whole bunch of rentals going on there And there's that.
Speaker 0: so the store makes money.
Speaker 0: But if I would just lower the price on the game to five bucks once it's old No one's gonna rent it from that store.
Speaker 0: They're gonna give me the maker of the game five bucks each to get the game for cheap.
Speaker 0: on seam.
Speaker 1: There's something I think a little more subtle, too.
Speaker 1: I would rent any s games primarily and I rented a few SNES games And that was kind of when I stopped renting games toward the end of the SNES.
Speaker 0: I only ever rented NES games and my friend rented PlayStation games.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 0: it was weird.
Speaker 1: I didn't rent any Genesis or Genesis selection at my blockbuster was smaller than the anime section.
Speaker 0: Wow Ours wasn't.
Speaker 0: but the thing was is like I had the Genesis games.
Speaker 0: I wanted I need to rent any of them.
Speaker 1: I never owned a Genesis.
Speaker 1: I rented one once for a weekend.
Speaker 1: Yeah, huh I just there weren't that many games on the Genesis.
Speaker 1: I wanted to play.
Speaker 1: I sort of played all the games that were on there that I wanted to play in the NES era And the SNES era because of and this is I'm not saying this is a good thing.
Speaker 1: Don't get me wrong I'm not on a nostalgia trip here.
Speaker 1: The majority of them.
Speaker 1: you could play them for a weekend and experience everything that was worth Experiencing short of fully beating them.
Speaker 0: I think another part of the thing was that the NES days right is.
Speaker 0: Every game is $50 and the prices on games didn't really.
Speaker 1: there were no demos.
Speaker 0: and there were no demos except for you would Get a rare store that had like a demo system.
Speaker 1: I remember I'd go to Meijer the supermarket every time my parents went grocery shopping and play the virtual boy while they walked around.
Speaker 0: I played before I actually ever, you know had a chance to play super magic cards there for Super Metroid.
Speaker 0: for real I played Super Metroid and the toys are us on a demo system, you know, and You know, so it's like if you're a kid.
Speaker 0: you were desperate to get another game and even a crappy game was good to you.
Speaker 1: Oh my god when my parents would take me to Toys R Us.
Speaker 1: They're like you and your brother can buy one Nintendo Nintendo game.
Speaker 0: so four hours of us standing there staring at the games debating which one to get so That would cost you 50 bucks to get one game that you play forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if it was a new NES first party so for like Zelda to 70 bucks.
Speaker 0: So to pay by 65 bucks five bucks for a Nintendo game for a weekend.
Speaker 0: That was amazing in those days in the late 80s early 90s.
Speaker 1: Holy shit Yep, and I just I remember it was interesting that I would re-rent games that were good But I wasn't willing to buy them because even if I read it five times It's still half the price of buying it at Toys R Us.
Speaker 1: Yep, especially if the game doesn't hat isn't the kind of game You need to own forever Especially now that I'm older and wiser and I have every NES rom ever and I you know going back and playing some of these Games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a lot of them not worth playing.
Speaker 1: Yeah takes five seconds to figure out how shitty they are.
Speaker 0: But see I think.
Speaker 0: part of it though, is that like Some take a game like Kung Fu Heroes, for example, right if I just rented that game It would have been like I return it right or if I would you know, if I load it up in an emulator.
Speaker 0: now It's like whatever but because I own that game and I did own that game.
Speaker 0: All right, I might still have the carcass somewhere Because I own that game and I had it for Evers.
Speaker 0: I actually put a lot more into it You know because I paid whatever for it was the one game that I got.
Speaker 0: I was gonna play the fuck out of it.
Speaker 0: And because I played the fuck out of it I actually dug deep on it and I sort of discovered more.
Speaker 0: that was in that game because I had more of a Investment and a reason to go for it, you know, whereas nowadays You could just you're so many games.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to try to extract all the goodness out of any game.
Speaker 0: But in those days if a game had anything good in it, you would have to work hard to.
Speaker 0: you know Get every last, you know Drop of water out of that's.
Speaker 1: you know, damp rag You only had so many games in the first place.
Speaker 1: I know right but I Maybe this explains because like you're really good at Megaman - I'm really good at bionic commando.
Speaker 1: I really like Megaman - and you like bionic commando, but you owned a Megaman - I owned bionic commando.
Speaker 1: I only rented Megaman -.
Speaker 0: the thing is when I got my Nintendo, of course day one I had Mario Duck on right day - Megaman - I see the game.
Speaker 1: the first games I got were Castlevania 1 and Castlevania 2.
Speaker 0: first game I got Megaman - Mario Duck Hunt after Mario Duck Hunt, obviously Yeah, Mario Duck Hunt Megaman - but it was.
Speaker 1: it was all I was all about the Castlevania.
Speaker 0: I picked the winner right away.
Speaker 1: Simon's Quest is one of the first games.
Speaker 0: I beat shortly after that Zelda 1.
Speaker 1: Oh my god I just had this like weird nostalgia flashback to holding that gold cartridge before I put it in the first time and then Hanukkah after it came out.
Speaker 0: Mario 3.
Speaker 1: I bought Zelda 2 before Mario 3.
Speaker 0: My mom put the Mario 3 in a Macy's box So it looked like it was closed.
Speaker 0: and then I opened it up and inside the tissue paper.
Speaker 1: I think every Nintendo game I ever got came in a Macy's box or some equivalent inside tissue paper.
Speaker 0: Mario 3.
Speaker 1: I just remember I had to choose my brother and I. one of the hardest decisions we ever had to make.
Speaker 1: our choices were Buy Zelda 2 or buy Mario 3.
Speaker 0: Can't go wrong with Mario 3 is the obvious winner.
Speaker 1: No, we got Zelda 2.
Speaker 0: It's not like you couldn't go wrong.
Speaker 0: Same thing as I. I did get Zelda 2 on a gray cartridge actually not gold.
Speaker 1: I got old.
Speaker 0: I had played Zelda 2 prior to purchasing.
Speaker 0: so I knew that it was different.
Speaker 0: So I knew that Mario 3 was like safe bet.
Speaker 0: I Mean you couldn't really go wrong with Mario 3.
Speaker 0: I mean that game sold like at the time.
Speaker 0: that was like the most selling is thing ever.
Speaker 1: There was just I don't know there.
Speaker 1: Games had a very different feeling back when you couldn't didn't have access to game facts or anything.
Speaker 1: So you'd rent a game and you got a game magazine?
Speaker 1: Oh Usually that game didn't come with instructions because the blockbuster didn't have him anymore.
Speaker 1: You just got this like Robocop game.
Speaker 1: You did not have played.
Speaker 1: you had two days to play.
Speaker 1: the fuck out of it.
Speaker 1: So you didn't go outside.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's no Internet's to get help from.
Speaker 0: yeah, you could pay money for the Nintendo hotline.
Speaker 0: But even as a kid, I was smart enough to never pay money anything over the phone.
Speaker 0: No 900 numbers.
Speaker 1: I sent a letter to Nintendo Power once and they didn't feature my question, but they sent me an answer back.
Speaker 0: I think I sent a letter to GamePro.
Speaker 0: The only thing I ever fell for and I sort of knew it was a scam when I was falling for it was the pandemonium contest, ah I was a really.
Speaker 1: I was like desperately obsessed with the Nintendo Power contest Because they always gave away crazy stuff like stormtrooper helmet.
Speaker 0: that got the pandemonium contest.
Speaker 0: was I vaguely so?
Speaker 0: basically in the in the game pro Magazine there was his advertisement every month and the advertiser it would be solve this puzzle and mail it in You know and pay with a dollar or whatever and you could win this.
Speaker 0: and it showed you the most ludicrous shit You'd ever seen which at the time was like a 50-inch rear projection TV and a satellite dish and every game Console and a surround sound stereo system and a pile of games and even a neogeo was in there.
Speaker 0: It was you know, everything Sega Genesis with a 32x and a CD and a Sega CD and a Super Nintendo and everything, right?
Speaker 0: It's like you could win all these things, you know, if you solve these puzzles.
Speaker 0: So I solved the puzzle and mailed it in and then they sent you another puzzle, which is harder.
Speaker 0: So I solved the puzzle and mailed it in with five bucks and then I and I solved the puzzle and mailed it in with Five bucks and there were five puzzles.
Speaker 0: so obviously I mailed in the fourth puzzle and then I got the fifth puzzle and the fifth puzzle was the hardest puzzle of All and without a computer I couldn't solve it.
Speaker 0: come, you know with the it was basically Uh, it was.
Speaker 0: it wasn't a puzzle where there is a solution and there isn't a solution.
Speaker 0: It was get the most points you can get and obviously to make the most money possible you ought to always pass all the rounds until the last round.
Speaker 0: and then I mailed in the last round with the subpar solution and Did not?
Speaker 0: you know, I paid like 25 bucks and did not win a giant mound of awesomeness.
Speaker 1: Hey listeners We have a trivia contest starting if you mail us five bucks Yeah with every.
Speaker 0: you have to mail five bucks with every answer and then if all your answers are right Then you have a will randomly select from all the people who get the fifth answer, right?
Speaker 1: What was interesting?
Speaker 1: just to get back to the the topic?
Speaker 1: Toward the end of the SNES era the local blockbusters at least by me started doing Tournaments and they had yeah, I mean blockbuster, you know after Toys R Us blockbuster was the gaming place.
Speaker 1: Like it was a hangout you would go and hang out there playing games with other people because they had a game demo machine.
Speaker 0: You know They had consoles and when it was there were big tournaments that they would have there plus all the kids in the neighborhood went to The same blockbuster.
Speaker 0: Toys R Us were only interested in selling games, you know, and they had demo units.
Speaker 0: But blockbusters actually tried to you know, get some gaming going on.
Speaker 0: It was kind of interesting.
Speaker 0: It was kind of half-assed that too.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean most of the problem right it I always notice with that kind of thing is like the in the marketing for it.
Speaker 0: They'll be like, alright This is gonna be a blockbuster tournament.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, right, but then you went to your local blockbuster and it was like There's like five people standing there.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like a false star.
Speaker 1: They're like, alright you two play Mortal Kombat and whoever wins will play against this guy.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, they because we all saw the wizard and we thought every video game tournament was exactly like yeah It's like they.
Speaker 0: the way they present it to you is they act like it's gonna be a real deal Like it's gonna be something amazing and awesome and perfect and power.
Speaker 1: It's just like my thing of the day from last week of video power Where you see those kids who clearly have seen behind the veil and realized that nothing is ever going.
Speaker 1: I think it was awesome as the wizard made it seem.
Speaker 0: I think of it more like a CCG tournament.
Speaker 0: right you look.
Speaker 0: if you go and look at like CCG tournaments or pictures of them online It's like all.
Speaker 0: look at these tournaments Whoa, but then if you go to like your local game shop and they're playing Yu-Gi-Oh, it's like our kids is Yu-Gi-Oh cards.
Speaker 0: Play a game.
Speaker 0: It's kind of coke is gonna kick IRS vanilla coke to be fair.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's alright, but my favorite part of all this was finding the save games like that Specific thing I feel is lost forever.
Speaker 1: I almost there.
Speaker 1: I want to make a game cuz I'm playing that retro game Challenge whatever on the DS that Scott is also playing.
Speaker 1: That's a good game and it tries to recreate these Experiences by having like video game magazines for it's made up game.
Speaker 1: It totally works.
Speaker 0: It totally works - it's great.
Speaker 1: So you get to experience the fun parts of the 80s and 90s without having to go through the bullshit of the 80s and 90s.
Speaker 0: Well, that's because they have.
Speaker 0: the games that they've made right is are basically faux NES games, right and what they've done Is they you know, they're in the style of old NES games, but they had modern people made them.
Speaker 0: They're actually polished, you know, modernly.
Speaker 0: so the controls aren't fucked up and they're not unfairly hard.
Speaker 0: They're just normal hard if they're hard at all, you know, and it's just the graphics and the styling and the game.
Speaker 0: You know the gameplay mechanics are retro, but you know the polish and the craft is modern.
Speaker 0: So it's not like yeah people it's not like that guy didn't even touch me.
Speaker 0: Why did I die?
Speaker 0: You don't have that bullshit going on.
Speaker 1: we and a lot of video game commentators often get criticized.
Speaker 0: It's like it's like if everything the AVGN yelled at a video game was fixed, but it was still the same game.
Speaker 1: I don't know for Cheetah Man.
Speaker 1: That wouldn't be anything.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying more for like, you know, Jekyll and Hyde Like Silver Surfer, but the common criticism we get is that we have this like fetish for old games.
Speaker 1: We are fully aware that it sucked back then.
Speaker 1: We don't want to go back to those terrible days, but there were specific small experiences that were good.
Speaker 1: that cannot be replicated in the modern gaming world and we have to.
Speaker 1: I want to find a way to replicate that the experience of playing a game where you have no access to outside information about it in it per se at least not easy access.
Speaker 1: or you choose not to access it and You can experience like that strange Exploration of finding a save game that has way more stuff than your guy like he has items.
Speaker 1: You don't even know what they do.
Speaker 0: I don't know how you can possibly do the no outside information.
Speaker 0: The internet makes that sort of impossible.
Speaker 1: Here's one way like the forest in in Mario 64 you have procedurally generated games.
Speaker 1: What if you had a retro game challenge that made games and codes up in a non easily predictable manner?
Speaker 0: It's possible but Theoretically, but and it's not realistic.
Speaker 1: but no it's not.
Speaker 0: well you could do though is I think Minecraft really needs to get on this?
Speaker 0: is we already have the ability to Save games in the cloud?
Speaker 0: quote right like on Steam or save right?
Speaker 0: You can save your game.
Speaker 1: We need shared save games.
Speaker 0: You can save your game on some server in the sky and that way you don't.
Speaker 0: if your computer gets wiped out your save game Is safe.
Speaker 1: I should be able to share my save game with anyone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well no Eve what you could do is you can artificially shuffle up the save game.
Speaker 0: So I play my game and I save and then I go to load and my games not there.
Speaker 0: I have someone else's save game.
Speaker 0: I don't have my save game named penis.
Speaker 0: You're safe So penis or and you're yeah, your save game is now gone.
Speaker 0: Someone else has it.
Speaker 0: you have someone else's save game So it's like whoa Or.
Speaker 1: yeah, there are a bunch of ways you could go about it.
Speaker 1: But there was an interesting idea of exploring a game where you could look at the save game and he's got items You don't understand what they do and because blockbuster didn't have the manual like no one knew what they did and you had no way To find out short of either playing to that point or starting this scary save game in the weird part of the world.
Speaker 0: Another thing you could do right is if you had a game that just had so many different aspects, right?
Speaker 0: So say for an example, you had an MMO and in the MMO all these different characters did different things, right?
Speaker 0: So it's like a you know, a crafting guy and a fighting guy an explorer guy, right?
Speaker 0: And each one is actually a drastically different game.
Speaker 0: that are all good games But when you sign on it's like you don't have a character.
Speaker 0: You're just gonna be assigned somewhere and if there's enough different characters right with it in enough different places in enough different games It's like you don't know what you're gonna get when you play this thing.
Speaker 0: and it'd be really it would take quite a long time For them to document it all in some sort of wiki, but it'll happen.
Speaker 1: I mean look at the advanced wars or even the emerging Civ 5 game facts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's no way around that No, but I mean it'll just take a while and even if it even if people look up the information It's still you don't know what you're gonna get when you sign it.
Speaker 1: I guess the only moral of this is like I said This is an aspect of gaming that is basically gone.
Speaker 1: the experiences that we had growing up And I'm sure people who played the Atari era have similar Well, no, I know they did have similar things that we didn't even have the ability to replicate.
Speaker 1: Until gaming converges in the future like every generation will have such a unique experience just by the fact of how fast gaming is evolving That there will always be this kind of weird lagging nostalgia That's just going to be increasingly affecting the way games are made and played.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean it's even worse right?
Speaker 0: think about some of the stuff that they had in different Countries or things that were so expensive to have them.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: remember there was a Sega Channel.
Speaker 0: You know what the Sega Channel?
Speaker 1: I know about it because I've read a Wikipedia about it.
Speaker 0: Sega Channel was basically you got this cartridge that goes in your Genesis and you hope that your cable provider Yes your cable television provider supported it.
Speaker 0: then you would take your cable television connect it to your Sega Genesis cartridge.
Speaker 0: that Was the Sega Channel cartridge.
Speaker 0: turn your TV to a certain channel and then you could actually play games.
Speaker 0: that came in over the cable.
Speaker 0: But that wasn't all in Japan.
Speaker 0: now yes, Zelda they had BS Zelda, which is a satellite.
Speaker 1: I thought that was a prank for the longest time is a real deal.
Speaker 1: Oh because as a kid there were rumors.
Speaker 1: There were two rumors.
Speaker 0: there are ROMs of it that you can play but they're nothing like the real thing.
Speaker 0: They're missing significant features because you just can't replicate the satellite system.
Speaker 1: There was I mean the two rumors I remember as a kid.
Speaker 1: one I knew the truth because I'd played a Phillips was the.
Speaker 1: there's all these other Zelda games.
Speaker 1: one of them you play Zelda That's true.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the other one was there's this special Zelda.
Speaker 1: You'll never get called BS Zelda.
Speaker 1: I was like BS, Zelda.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sounds like bullshit.
Speaker 0: So but no BS Zelda is totally real and it was a Zelda game that came out in Japan that was in the same style of Zelda 1 With different maps and different everything, but it was a game that had a time Element to it.
Speaker 0: like it was a real time Zelda.
Speaker 0: you had to get through in a certain number of minutes and such and you.
Speaker 0: basically it worked because the game was hooked up to a satellite system and you had to tune into the game at a Certain time when the game was being played.
Speaker 1: as Xbox Live needs to get on that shit You couldn't.
Speaker 0: just well they had that.
Speaker 0: they have one versus yeah But they need more.
Speaker 1: imagine if or Nintendo even canceled one versus 100. imagine if every week or every month there was a war a worldwide WarioWare Wernemann's.
Speaker 0: they had one versus 100 on Xbox.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they tried that shit and it's gone now.
Speaker 1: that sucks.
Speaker 1: That was in an entire avenue of gaming we could bring back.
Speaker 0: but now Yeah, I definitely think that you know, everyone played the game at this time.
Speaker 0: This is when the game is on is definitely pretty cool And I think one versus 100 is actually flawed.
Speaker 0: and that it was only versus 100 Why wasn't it one verse the entire world?
Speaker 0: You know, why not let everyone get in on it?
Speaker 0: Why keep some people out?
Speaker 0: No reason, you know, you could tell the computers can handle it.
Speaker 0: It'd be alright And that would actually be an MMO.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: geek nights is recorded live With no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.