Speaker 0: Hey, it's Wednesday January 13th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: some final thoughts for the great great anime master Keaton Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I discovered the one possibly the only problem of having a very short commute.
Speaker 0: What do I do for nine minutes?
Speaker 1: Well you can.
Speaker 0: I was playing advanced wars every day, but I've asked everything but three.
Speaker 0: so I think I listen.
Speaker 1: I have a podcast that is very short.
Speaker 1: You know like the ESPN Sportsy thing.
Speaker 1: So if I play if I start playing it when I'm in my house by the time I'm at work It's over you know or by the time I'm sitting at my desk.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much over cuz it's like 20-something minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah I just haven't felt the.
Speaker 0: you know go get my headphone thing stick him in the ear after I get on the subway or while I see you do it.
Speaker 1: I do it.
Speaker 1: I put them in while I'm in the house, and then I walk out the door.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like I put on my headphones, and I put on my coat.
Speaker 1: so and then I push play.
Speaker 1: so it's.
Speaker 0: I Considered that but I don't know.
Speaker 0: it is it's tired early morning.
Speaker 0: So I realized the best solution for me right now.
Speaker 0: I just I looked at that gigantic pile of manga that I had but I never saw in the old house because it was just Kind of in boxes out of the way, and I realized I have quite a large collection of slayers manga Reading.
Speaker 0: I'm reading the slayers manga the Lina and Naga slayers manga mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It's pretty great actually now that I'm finally reading it.
Speaker 0: It's basically the same as all the OAVs only in manga form.
Speaker 0: It's really well drawn.
Speaker 0: I don't know I'm digging it.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna review it or anything just yet, but It's pretty good, and I recommend you read it.
Speaker 0: mr.. Likes the Naga episodes more than the TV show, and I almost agree That's right.
Speaker 0: I don't fully agree That's.
Speaker 1: it's interesting that you are going back to something old because I Over the weekend you know there was some cowabeebop on a screen somewhere.
Speaker 0: Oh my god I forgot about that and so I was like oh, man.
Speaker 1: I'm done watching this here Master Keaton Let me watch something else, and I was gonna get a cowabeebop disc, and I was like you know.
Speaker 1: And then I saw you know some other discs in there like the old 60s Astro Boy, and I was like you know It's tough because.
Speaker 0: and then I saw my macross discs, and I was like ah Is it bad that we're rewatching things more rapidly than we're watching new things?
Speaker 1: doesn't take that long to watch especially since we have more Time in the day even with rewatching.
Speaker 1: I am still getting more done than I did with the commute.
Speaker 0: It is difficult though because I'll admit you know we were out for that party in flushing and We're someone in the group hadn't seen cowboy bebop.
Speaker 0: so we put it on and it was just there in the background Subtitled even and you know all I thought was all right.
Speaker 0: I'll hang out.
Speaker 0: I don't really need to watch this again.
Speaker 0: I've seen these first five episodes in particular at least 60 or 70 times.
Speaker 0: I don't need to see them again.
Speaker 0: I don't think I've seen them quite that many times maybe Six or seven times a lot of times because I'd always bring that one DVD and show it to people all over the place And it'd been many years since I'd seen any cowboy bebop, so it's odd.
Speaker 0: I'm like I look at it.
Speaker 0: I'm like all right cowboy bebop.
Speaker 0: the show is awesome And I ended up watching all five episodes wrapped because the show was.
Speaker 0: I don't know the show is great But you kind of always forget just how great it is that even watching it again and again and again It's like Star Wars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, ah it is like Star Wars like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know I feel like I want to watch all of cowboy bebop again.
Speaker 1: I almost rewatched the whole thing back when remember because we bought the brick yep And I almost but I didn't make it all the way through because I started doing something else instead.
Speaker 0: see luckily Emily wants to.
Speaker 0: well hasn't seen Ghost in the Shell stand-alone complex, so I'm rewatching that instead.
Speaker 0: It's almost on the same level and due to the Natalie haven't seen us Capone, so I'm gonna rewatch.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what the hell remember?
Speaker 0: They had not seen utenna until recently.
Speaker 0: and these for the listeners.
Speaker 0: These are two people who if utenna was ever up someone's alley.
Speaker 0: It is their alley in many ways.
Speaker 1: I think the alley had their name on it when it was made.
Speaker 0: It's Yeah, but eska flown a old up old anime not watching new anime not good What new anime gonna watch?
Speaker 0: Me to go and watching is super awesome.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 1: it's not new isn't that?
Speaker 1: like a year old or more alright?
Speaker 0: It's newer than cowboy bebop.
Speaker 1: Okay Anything else going on.
Speaker 1: We just get to some news.
Speaker 0: get right into it.
Speaker 0: It's been a long time so you'd think we haven't done an anime show since way way way way way back.
Speaker 0: I mean we were on hiatus for half of December and we were skipping episodes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there must be some anime news in all that time.
Speaker 0: If I had some crickets, I would have played him just then.
Speaker 0: good guy anime news network.
Speaker 0: It was like wow I might as we might we could skip an entire year And there'd probably be one minor thing to talk about.
Speaker 0: maybe and
Speaker 1: it's not like this that you know comic book news I mean the comic book news is all like oh this superheroes in trouble This superhero comics being cancelled and this one's starting up and this one right is not really anything of substance going on in that department.
Speaker 1: so What kind of news do we have?
Speaker 0: well luckily luckily while there's no anime industry news to speak of really there is always American pseudo meta side industry news.
Speaker 0: and remember way back when katsu khan exploded and all those staffers quit.
Speaker 0: and You know Scott and I were staff at katsu khan and we quit just because all the people we knew on the staff disappeared.
Speaker 0: The exact same thing pretty much has now happened to anime expo.
Speaker 1: Oh snap anime expo.
Speaker 1: the khan I've never been to I'm pretty sure lied.
Speaker 1: it lied about being the largest anime.
Speaker 1: Clearly and we always even though we never went to it got a sense that it wasn't so great.
Speaker 0: Well a number of our listeners would go and the reports They'd send back basically came down along the lines of it's really big and corporate and you stand in long lines.
Speaker 0: There's not that much to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but About 80% of the staff some 400 people according to anime news network have resigned.
Speaker 1: That's a lot.
Speaker 0: That's basically as far as I'm concerned the entire convention.
Speaker 1: How can you replace those people?
Speaker 0: They can't.
Speaker 1: if there's what is the convention?
Speaker 0: I don't even know when.
Speaker 1: it's sometimes less than a year away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot less than a year away, but I Realized something because the dispute came down to much like katsu khan.
Speaker 0: There's multiple executive or decision-making bodies and there's basically the convention arm and the kind of company arm and the CEO of Spj a. that has to do with all this.
Speaker 0: I don't know if he's a douche.
Speaker 0: I I can't say one way or the other.
Speaker 0: based on the text on the internet The words that have come out of his mouth according to the anime news network hints strongly that he may in fact Be a douche.
Speaker 1: Let us just say that if a real human being is truthfully associated with the words that are printed on the anime They are digitally printed on the anime news network then that person if they do exist would be King douche.
Speaker 0: I'll quote from this article.
Speaker 0: other concerns raised by certain ex staff members also included a comment made by let's Lattenzio the CEO at a November 14th meeting in which he compared volunteers to quote flies That must be shooed away if they don't abide by his rule.
Speaker 1: It sounds like a Japanese person for sure.
Speaker 0: Part of the dispute had to do with the fact that apparently he flew business class to Japan at The convention or the company's expense.
Speaker 1: Well, it was it for a trip to go do something for the convention?
Speaker 0: I'd assume so.
Speaker 1: So what's wrong with that?
Speaker 0: Well, apparently no, no one had ever done that business class for the convention before.
Speaker 1: no Mentioned poor I mean if it you know at the conventions got a lot of money.
Speaker 1: You should be going business class.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, he said something really aren't?
Speaker 0: I gotta find it cuz the quote.
Speaker 1: that's fucking uncomfortable.
Speaker 0: What he said regarding it was pretty crazy Although the details of his contract regarding travel stipends were not disclosed.
Speaker 0: He commented that business class accommodations were among the quote perks listed saying exact quote I don't know how many I don't know how many no CEOs in the business, but there are certain perks Privileges.
Speaker 0: he added that before we plan blah blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: that sounds real douchey to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I guess the way he said it.
Speaker 0: but I mean if you're a CEO and there's a lot of money Yes, but you're the CEO of a company that is you're pretending that there's still an anime industry in America.
Speaker 1: Well, you know if you guys technically there is yeah, they are it.
Speaker 1: they make all this money from this convention.
Speaker 0: See, that's the thing the conventions really have to realize that the way to make money off of anime in America right now is not To actually do anything with the anime But to deal with the meta industry the fans the punk kids who want to hang out.
Speaker 0: maybe the schlocky merch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the thing about volunteers though is a pretty bad.
Speaker 0: Well, I realized look at this katsu khan and anime Expo at the same problem.
Speaker 0: There was a dispute at the high level right and then a couple wondered like a small number of high-level Staffers said you know what fuck this and quit and as a result Everyone under them also quit.
Speaker 0: and I think it's a I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna pull a classic rim.
Speaker 0: It's an ancient Rome situation.
Speaker 0: The soldiers were all not loyal to the convention.
Speaker 0: They were loyal to the idea of conventions particularly staffing them and they were loyal to their generals.
Speaker 0: They weren't loyal to the Empire.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: You see the problem is is that you know, people don't really think about organizational structure.
Speaker 1: They sort of defaultly fall into a hierarchy not because the hierarchy is some sort of natural thing But because you know just that's like, you know If you don't think people just make hierarchies because that's what our society teaches you to make.
Speaker 1: it's always about, you know Who's in charge, you know, we live in a democratic society.
Speaker 1: There's a hierarchy from president on down, you know It's a federal structure.
Speaker 1: People are used to federal structure most things.
Speaker 1: most organizations have a federal Hierarchical structure.
Speaker 1: thus that's the kind of structure people make without even if they don't actually put in the extra effort to actually think about Doing some other sort of structure.
Speaker 1: and therefore when you have this hierarchy, right?
Speaker 1: like an anime convention you get some sort of board of generals at the top and Everyone else sort of falls off in branches from the side.
Speaker 1: Well, and the result is is that the branches don't mesh very well.
Speaker 0: Also think about the kinds of people who staff anime conventions as opposed to other, you know Generally the fan conventions.
Speaker 0: really they're mostly people who do it because they love doing it Like they enjoy being staff kind of like how there's the artist alley people or the like the gaming room people.
Speaker 0: These are the people who basically they're con experience.
Speaker 0: What they enjoy is being staff being like the overworked guy who puts in like 20 40 hours of work And they're all for like all their friends do the convention.
Speaker 0: Would you do all that work if your friends weren't gonna be at the convention staffing with you?
Speaker 0: Mmm, it's real easy to have this situation where if a few people quit a staff of a big anime con suddenly Everyone starts quitting.
Speaker 0: It's like a snowball.
Speaker 0: that only happens if people aren't actually loyal to the convention itself.
Speaker 0: There's loyal to their friends the idea of conventions to all that and it's really endemic.
Speaker 0: and anime cons I think because most anime cons treat their staff like shit.
Speaker 0: I'm not even gonna try to sugarcoat it.
Speaker 0: They treat their staff like garbage and it's so hard to become staff at a lot of these larger conventions.
Speaker 0: I mean you have to like oh well be a gopher first.
Speaker 0: And if you're okay, if you can go for really really well for like three years We'll let you be the guy in the staff who sent hands out badges on Thursday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and not only do they treat the staff poorly but like they really don't appreciate the staff, you know It's and the staff right will always complain that they're underappreciated like oh I do all this hard work and nobody cares Right, but meanwhile at PAX they're like, oh,
Speaker 0: that was the first thing they said at closing ceremonies.
Speaker 0: We couldn't have done this without all of you who took it upon yourselves to take up the black for us.
Speaker 0: Yeah And then remember back Otakon after the The interesting comments about volunteers in the feedback session.
Speaker 0: and then Aaron Clark said quoting exactly from his post in the forum Gophering is not supposed to be fun.
Speaker 0: You're put where you're put if you don't like it.
Speaker 0: Don't do it.
Speaker 0: It's as simple as that.
Speaker 0: if working in the same department all weekend is undesirable to you.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't recommend becoming a staffer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's why you're short on staff because you're telling people not to now.
Speaker 0: he recanted that statement later, but It tells that it was even said in the first place.
Speaker 0: I mean look at I hate to keep using packs as the example But look at packs because it's the only convention we've been to this doing it, right?
Speaker 1: What effect you where else that we've gone has done it right.
Speaker 1: every other every other place Right other than packs that we've been to at least right?
Speaker 0: One exception the New York Anime Festival did that.
Speaker 0: they tried as right they could.
Speaker 0: they called them heroes and the heroes all looked Like they were having fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah But no, but you know every other place is either, you know, they treat them like poop and they're volunteers or say like You know to baseball stadium, they're all employees.
Speaker 1: You know all the vendors that walk around selling cotton candy get paid so they don't need to be treated.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz they get money.
Speaker 0: So We'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: I predict that this convention Anime Expo this year is going to be an enormous cluster.
Speaker 1: I don't think it'll happen.
Speaker 0: I think it's gonna happen and I think it's gonna be a disaster and that might be the end of it.
Speaker 0: Maybe Meanwhile, we have it on good authority that katsu khan which you know had all of these similar troubles a while ago And then basically it's been radio silence.
Speaker 0: since then they've ignored.
Speaker 0: I've emailed everyone that I used to know and all the email addresses.
Speaker 0: No one's responded.
Speaker 1: But someone probably none of them work there anymore.
Speaker 0: someone as yet well I guess to be unnamed told us that basically they don't have a schedule yet.
Speaker 1: Isn't the con in February?
Speaker 1: Yeah, isn't it January?
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, I mean we're panel staff for kinetic on.
Speaker 0: we've already started scheduling panels.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's in August.
Speaker 0: yeah So we'll see.
Speaker 0: I predict that katsu khan is going to be an equally big clusterfuck.
Speaker 0: I may be wrong.
Speaker 0: I can't say I'm not staff.
Speaker 0: if Anyone on the katsu khan staff would like to tell us what's up or tell us the cons gonna be awesome I'd love to hear it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So Scott, do you have any undepressing anime news?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do.
Speaker 1: So You know Tezuka the god the most amazing almighty Tezuka, right.
Speaker 1: Even more amazing the fact that he made hundreds of thousands of pages of manga and also made animes You know many of which are revolutionary made animes made anime.
Speaker 1: Yeah And did all these other things right.
Speaker 1: he also Traveled the world and had friends all over the world.
Speaker 1: It's like how the fuck did he do all these things in one life?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: He cheated.
Speaker 1: I Guess he didn't sleep right?
Speaker 1: is X?
Speaker 1: that was always the joke.
Speaker 1: is the him people who work for Tezuka didn't sleep And there were actually two Tezuka's.
Speaker 0: it's kind of like Gallagher and fake Gallagher.
Speaker 0: You don't know which one you're getting.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: He probably had a twin brother who couldn't draw.
Speaker 1: Yeah But anyway Basically, you know Tezuka had friends all over the world like Fred Schott and such right in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Here.
Speaker 1: he also had a friend in Brazil someone named who I didn't know about ever but I am now very interested in.
Speaker 1: his name was Mauricio de Sousa and he is a Brazilian with a Japanese wife and he is pretty much like the Disney of Brazil and He made lots of awesome comics in Brazil.
Speaker 1: I think he's been doing it for what does it say here?
Speaker 1: 50 years and his works appear in over half of the comic magazines published in Brazil.
Speaker 1: So that's a pretty amazing person right there.
Speaker 1: I definitely have to go check out his comics find if any are in English and such.
Speaker 1: But anyway, he was friends with Tezuka very good friends with him.
Speaker 1: they often you know met when they were traveling and such and It says here on the a9 news network that they were going to create an adventure movie about world peace With astro boy and princess knight characters alongside DeSouza's characters.
Speaker 0: that sounds a lot like what happened with giant robo basically if you think about it, so they drafted these plans.
Speaker 1: By then Tezuka died because while being omnipotent and omniscient He is your news that this is gonna come to fruition.
Speaker 0: It was not.
Speaker 1: it was not immortal, but now DeSouza says at long last I am filling I am fulfilling our promise.
Speaker 1: So he's going to make this happen even though it didn't happen before.
Speaker 1: it's gonna happen now.
Speaker 0: I'm excited about that now.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna check it out for sure.
Speaker 1: See yeah, he went to.
Speaker 1: he met up with Tezuka productions And he was like can we make this happen?
Speaker 1: and they're like all right you were friends at Tezuka.
Speaker 1: So yes, we can make this happen.
Speaker 0: so things of the day.
Speaker 0: This is not a Wikipedia page.
Speaker 0: it is a user's Wikipedia page, so take that as you will.
Speaker 0: but I Like this sort of thing.
Speaker 0: it is a list of cats with fraudulent diplomas.
Speaker 1: Another thing that's interesting about a list of fraudulent diplomas is if you look at the names of the schools Right and you see what those you know especially.
Speaker 1: you know there are some generic schools like you know something Walla Walla University.
Speaker 1: Well that could be a diploma in fucking anything right, but if there's a specific one like the British Board of Neurolinguistic Programs Yes, see when you see the name of a school like that And then you find out that that school is giving illegitimate diplomas.
Speaker 1: you can use these things to figure out which Professions are illegitimate because the places that give out diplomas for those professions are illegitimate and there aren't really any Legitimate places giving out diplomas in that department.
Speaker 0: speaking of which if anyone would like a degree from RIT The RIM Institute of Technology for five dollars I will make this possible.
Speaker 0: if anyone would like a degree from You you were gonna make a joke and you just failed there.
Speaker 1: you got nothing.
Speaker 1: there was no place that had an S in it.
Speaker 0: How about the United Fellowship of Hypnotherapists or the Professional Hypnotherapy Practitioner Association?
Speaker 1: Hypnotherapy is BS.
Speaker 1: That's Randy.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 0: yeah, so is neurolinguistic programming?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty much the same as hypnotism.
Speaker 0: the cat's names are pretty good, too.
Speaker 0: Henrietta Goldacre was one of the cats.
Speaker 0: Tobias F. Schaeffer F stands for feline Mmm, my favorite is Kitty O'Malley.
Speaker 1: that could be a real name.
Speaker 0: good But apparently Kitty got a high school diploma from Washington High Academy.
Speaker 1: Oh, it sounds like a real high school.
Speaker 0: But so did a cat.
Speaker 0: it's known only as Spanky.
Speaker 1: That's definitely just a cat name.
Speaker 0: This seems to be a pretty good way to go.
Speaker 1: after these I had I think I'm actually gonna go see.
Speaker 1: this question is right these mail-order diplomas.
Speaker 0: What if you get them not for fun?
Speaker 1: And well, how much do they cost?
Speaker 1: are these places making big bank?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: cuz if it's cheap, I'll get.
Speaker 1: I'll be dr.
Speaker 1: Scott.
Speaker 1: I don't give a shit.
Speaker 1: if it's fake I get as long as I can call myself.
Speaker 0: All right, here's a quote Colby Nolan who is a house cat who got an MBA from Trinity Southern.
Speaker 1: I need one of those.
Speaker 0: Colby Nolan belonged to a deputy deputy attorney general.
Speaker 0: in looking to expose Trinity Southern University for fraud Some undercover agents had the then six-year-old Colby Nolan obtained a bachelor's degree in business administration for $299.
Speaker 1: That's too much money.
Speaker 0: on the cat's application.
Speaker 1: Let's start a fake.
Speaker 1: Everyone will pay us $300 for paper.
Speaker 0: Let me finish on the cat's application.
Speaker 0: the agents claimed that the cat had previously taken courses at a community college worked at a fast-food restaurant Babysat and maintained a newspaper route.
Speaker 0: the school then informed Colby that due to his job experience On the application.
Speaker 0: He was eligible for an executive MBA for only $100 more.
Speaker 0: No The Ted got a 3.5 GPA Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So who actually did it accent to do any courses?
Speaker 1: Correspondence courses or anything.
Speaker 0: I don't think so, but it's $300.
Speaker 1: Why don't we set up a fake phony University?
Speaker 0: Why even make it fake?
Speaker 0: just make a real University that's not accredited and just not claim.
Speaker 0: We're accredited.
Speaker 0: It's not even fraud.
Speaker 1: Oh Let's do it.
Speaker 0: It's not fraud at all.
Speaker 0: I can sell plumbers 50 bucks.
Speaker 0: I can sell you.
Speaker 1: I'll go to staples.
Speaker 1: I'll buy a stack of diploma paper.
Speaker 1: That's that cost less than 50 bucks.
Speaker 1: So as long as we get one customer we're set I'll.
Speaker 1: even if we make enough money I can use it by a color laser printer and then get someone to design a really nice diploma.
Speaker 0: You can even make a test just an are you awesome test?
Speaker 1: and if you pass it for some and we actually won't give it The people to people who fail we give you a diploma, but we still charge you an application fee, of course Let's do it.
Speaker 1: We should and then we can use all the monies for something awesome That is legitimate and good to make up for the fact that we're scamming all these morons.
Speaker 0: So what do you got for me?
Speaker 1: Oh, so I was reminded recently of this comic book that I thought I had but I must have given it away.
Speaker 1: I only bought the first issue and then I guess I don't have the first issue anymore and I never got any other issues because I was waiting for the trade.
Speaker 1: that never ever appeared.
Speaker 1: but the comic I believe we talked about in the show a long time ago Remember it was called I was kidnapped by lesbian pirates from outer space.
Speaker 0: I really liked that comic Yeah, but so I was like, huh?
Speaker 1: Why did the trade paperback never come out?
Speaker 1: So I searched on the Google and it's a webcomic.
Speaker 1: So you can read it for free which I'm gonna do.
Speaker 1: and I actually have another webcomic a double webcomic thing of the day.
Speaker 1: There's a webcomic called gun show gun show comic comm.
Speaker 1: I read their entire archive But primarily what you want to focus on here is they have in.
Speaker 1: you know, this comic is basically gag strips, but Interspersed throughout the gag strips.
Speaker 1: There is so far three parts right of an anime club saga.
Speaker 0: Is it on the same scale as my hope sky ties anime club saga?
Speaker 1: This is an epic for reals world mohotsukai tie.
Speaker 1: Oh my gosh Can she can anime club saga.
Speaker 1: it is great.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a show we got to watch again and talk about The original mohotsukai tie.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, good call.
Speaker 1: So Even you know, if you go to this site, right you can just read the webcomic like you read most comics You know, you click first to go to the beginning then you click next next next next next.
Speaker 1: However in the top right it says Refamiliarize yourself with the anime club saga and there are links to part one part two part two and a half and part three.
Speaker 1: So and each part is multiple strips, you know, so and I don't think it's over yet I think part four is coming but there are gag strips in the meantime.
Speaker 1: So And also the gag strips are funny.
Speaker 1: It's a gun show comic very funny.
Speaker 1: has an anime club saga.
Speaker 1: Read it.
Speaker 1: It's free.
Speaker 1: It's a webcomic.
Speaker 0: Yep So tonight we're gonna talk about an anime that I watched all the way through quite some time ago.
Speaker 0: Scott recently watched all the way through it.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure we reviewed it back in the day.
Speaker 0: We'll spoil but we're gonna hold off on the spoilers for a bit.
Speaker 0: if you're interested I recommend you check out that original review.
Speaker 0: But master Keaton is a the master.
Speaker 0: It is so such an underrated underknown under appreciated Anime and manga series that is by someone you may know you may know him.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, I mean everybody in the whole world is going crazy over the Pluto's and the monster and 20th century boys.
Speaker 1: Right, but nobody at least outside of Japan is giving any appreciation to nayoka.
Speaker 1: Ira saw was older stuff like, you know fashionable judo girl Yara and Master Keaton.
Speaker 1: master Keaton is a master.
Speaker 1: Keaton was on sale on DVD from genie on.
Speaker 1: that's how old this show.
Speaker 1: That's how long ago.
Speaker 1: the show was released in the US and basically nobody bought it.
Speaker 1: It did terribly in fact the show us.
Speaker 0: the show was on TV More than ten years ago in the United States or in Japan in Japan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if it was ever on I don't think it was ever on TV in the US.
Speaker 1: It was only on DVD in the US which is how we watched it because I bought all of the discs for like five bucks Each at a discount an ultra discount guy like three or four Otakons ago.
Speaker 0: Was it Otakon or was it?
Speaker 1: Otakon they had the $5 place but that $5 guy was also at anime next.
Speaker 0: Ah, because I think there's where I bought a whole bunch of stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we definitely bought the master Keaton at Otakon.
Speaker 1: I think it was the same year They had like the $20 Zeta Gundam box.
Speaker 0: If you want to see an urasawa that isn't just suspense building to some crazy client X denying Oh, wow, you're right.
Speaker 0: step of the way.
Speaker 0: This is the opposite of that.
Speaker 0: It is a slice of life.
Speaker 0: Let's follow this guy Completely episodic.
Speaker 0: I mean there's tension and cliffhangers, but every episode resolves itself and It's a very very different feel from any of his more recent works.
Speaker 0: It's basically the story of master Keaton.
Speaker 0: Hi, itchy Keaton.
Speaker 0: He's just this guy.
Speaker 0: He was in the SAS.
Speaker 0: He's a professor now.
Speaker 0: He's kind of half Inspector Gadget half Indiana Jones with a little bit of MacGyver.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, it's.
Speaker 1: it's really strange this character It's like because he's such a. he's a good person and he's a happy guy and he's really friendly.
Speaker 1: He's a little derp-de-derp and he's a little bit derp-de-derp, but in a way back way But he's.
Speaker 1: he's actually like an ultimate badass.
Speaker 0: You know what he is?
Speaker 0: He is the hachi fucking Roku in human form.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: He's the sleeper.
Speaker 0: No one everyone looks him.
Speaker 0: They're like that guy's not a threat to me.
Speaker 0: There's no way that can be my GTR and then he just beat you in the corners exactly And you know, it's pretty crazy cuz it's like.
Speaker 1: he was in the SAS.
Speaker 1: he was an instructor of the survival school right the ultimate badass.
Speaker 1: and Now he's just sort of like doo doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 1: teach in archaeology La la la la la and then you know, basically something happens and he ends up, you know Not being able to teach archaeology like he wants to and he has to take a job being an insurance inspector for Lloyd's of London.
Speaker 1: So, you know, he's doing all sorts of interesting insurance Inspections which are you know insurance inspecting is very detectivey work, but it's not and it is dangerous But not nearly in the way that it is portrayed in the show.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is look at who master Keaton is.
Speaker 0: everyone who works with him knows how much of a badass he is But no one else does they send him on what are effectively?
Speaker 0: Incredibly dangerous and shady mission which wouldn't really exist.
Speaker 1: I mean, would you really ever have to send an insurance inspector to find out like, you know If the Russian KGB terrorist guy is like you're gonna steal something that's expensive or something like, you know It's yeah, I think it was like episode two right away.
Speaker 0: It's bounty hunters and the German Red Army.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right It's like, you know.
Speaker 1: But is he really gonna have to go and find like some guy who's hiding out and you know from the police in?
Speaker 1: Order to like deliver him an insurance payment.
Speaker 1: He's supposed to receive from you know, someone who died.
Speaker 0: What's fun about watching the show though?
Speaker 0: Is that it's kind of this like when we watch the old Horatio hornblower series?
Speaker 0: There's a certain flow to every episode and you wait for the Duke Togo.
Speaker 0: moment We're Duke Togo has sex with the girl punches in the face shoots or shoot someone else and leaves.
Speaker 0: Now you wait for it and master Keaton the moment is How much did the bad guy underestimate him by and when is he going to find out that he underestimated master Keaton?
Speaker 1: I know I get you know.
Speaker 1: I think the episodic ness of it is what I like the most because you know so much Erissot.
Speaker 1: usually when you get your Urasawa you just had to read like a whole shit ton of manga volumes in a row and he's Like got you by the balls and he doesn't give you anything and you're just in constant suspense the whole time.
Speaker 1: But in this, you know, basically there isn't that much suspense.
Speaker 1: You just watch these stories.
Speaker 1: They don't have a lot to do with each other You know you get a little bit of continuity because you learn basically more about master Keaton and his history.
Speaker 1: And it's you know, his family.
Speaker 1: you never see his ex-wife though But like you see his daughter calling her on the phone and stuff You know and his father and his business partner and you learn all these, you know.
Speaker 1: You basically get a bigger picture of him and the things that surround him, but there isn't like a plot there.
Speaker 1: It's like oh is he ever gonna get back together with his wife?
Speaker 1: But that's it's not a plot.
Speaker 0: in a way It's kind of like cowboy bebop that there is this world and there are these characters.
Speaker 0: But the world plot is not the plot of the show or of the character effectively.
Speaker 0: Yeah The character is just there in this world doing what people do.
Speaker 0: So which in this case involves making odd laddles and totally kicking people's asses with them.
Speaker 0: Yeah But episodic wise it's Maybe a couple.
Speaker 0: you've off had the same thing.
Speaker 0: when I think about it master Keaton The episodes despite having the same kind of flow are very very different from each other.
Speaker 0: I mean some episodes.
Speaker 0: Keaton's hardly in him.
Speaker 0: It's just his daughter going around having an adventure or the grandpa going around having an adventure Yep, and everyone it's like.
Speaker 1: the kinds of adventures are so diverse.
Speaker 1: It's like basically what they're doing is they're writing all these separate stories That master Keaton just happens to be and all of them and they I mean they range as a way to tie them together.
Speaker 1: Right, if they just put these separate stories up it would be like, okay They range from hilarious tiger cages to dead serious people dying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the level of seriousness does vary quite a bit but not even within the same episode like the same episode will like have like hilarious jokes of like, you know, really silly drunk dudes and also horrible murdering and Evilness.
Speaker 0: the humor though is often very understated.
Speaker 0: It's very master key.
Speaker 0: like Keaton will say something clever or say something wrong or notice something weird or someone just does something weird.
Speaker 1: Mmm, also a lot of the things he does Are sort of MacGyver-y unrealistic.
Speaker 1: I would argue that like they're all you know, there's there's a lot of things that are based in reality.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's not like supernatural But it's basically like, you know, yes, you could you know do that, but you know in all seriousness that would not really be enough.
Speaker 0: I would say I've read a lot of Writings to the effect that many of the things he does are patently realistic like I know.
Speaker 1: I'm saying they are real things.
Speaker 1: You did those things.
Speaker 1: you would not, you know, you would not be the ultimate badass.
Speaker 0: the thing he did with the dog We'll get to the spoiler line a little bit is pretty much exactly by the book.
Speaker 0: what you do in that situation.
Speaker 1: It is an example.
Speaker 1: right like when he was When he was with the painter who you know was being forced to paint the forgery.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, he took like a light bulb and some other stuff and he made like a friggin grenade.
Speaker 1: It's like you can do that.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, you could do that But if you did would it really happen exactly that way and you would get away and the bad guy would be set on fire?
Speaker 1: Well, probably not.
Speaker 0: actually the flat replacing the light bulb like an incandescent bulb in a room with one That's rigged to explode is an old fairly common booby-traff.
Speaker 1: No, I'm saying it would explode but you would not be so fortuitous That would.
Speaker 1: it would explode in such a way that you would escape without being horribly burned and only the bad guy would be Burned.
Speaker 1: it depends.
Speaker 0: It would be more of a flash.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know it just you know the.
Speaker 1: the truth of that that mechanism is a real mechanism is correct.
Speaker 1: the the the actual Occurrence and you know execution of that mechanism is not a hundred percent in line with realism.
Speaker 1: master Keaton would be long dead if this was real.
Speaker 0: nine some of the episodes but by the same token in many of them like the Out-lottle, that's probably how it would have gone down.
Speaker 0: Maybe pistols aren't that accurate especially in wind like that against a moving target?
Speaker 1: No, no, but I mean it was.
Speaker 1: he really gonna be able to knock down that frickin arch, you know with the with the out-lottle You know, I mean he did.
Speaker 1: they did foreshadow.
Speaker 1: He was like, yeah This keystone is loose But well, I mean a rock.
Speaker 0: a little rock at it even with an out-lottle is not possibly what I would argue There is that there are two factors going on.
Speaker 0: There's the realistic thing that is done but then there is the fact that Keaton always ends up in a situation where there is the fortuitous luck that Augments the situation that pushes him beyond just a normal person and new kind of this legendary status kind of like Duke Togo.
Speaker 0: Dude, you couldn't really shoot people the way Duke Togo shoots people.
Speaker 0: but part is nothing supernatural about it.
Speaker 0: But at the same time the odds are the odds are low that Duke Togo could make all of those shots.
Speaker 0: He could have made one of them fortuitously.
Speaker 0: But the point of this master Keaton kind of makes a Duke Togo shot Every episode and any one of them would have been plausible all of them not plausible.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's what's like awesome about these kind of things right?
Speaker 1: even initial D has that where there's nothing supernatural, right?
Speaker 1: It's not magic.
Speaker 1: No one's using magic Nobody's.
Speaker 1: there's no, you know spirits or gods or spells or there isn't even any technology That's futuristic or science fiction like time machines or laser guns or anything like that, right?
Speaker 1: It's all real stuff.
Speaker 1: I mean this doesn't even take place in the in this, you know century, right?
Speaker 1: doesn't this take place in like You know the 80s or even older.
Speaker 0: It's well, yeah, I think it's the 80s 90s.
Speaker 0: That's what it feels like.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know.
Speaker 1: so this is yeah, cuz definitely during the Cold War.
Speaker 1: So I think it's 80s ish Or maybe you know, it's just after the fall of the Berlin Wall.
Speaker 1: Ah, you're right.
Speaker 1: You're right cuz that's part of the story.
Speaker 1: So yeah, it's it's.
Speaker 1: it's 90s early 90s ish not counting obviously flashbacks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so You know, it's fairly modern times but it's and nothing is supernatural.
Speaker 1: but even so the the the amount of the luck factor is Makes it seem supernatural because these things go his way Every single time, you know, even though he does, you know, they'll make him take some damage Like you make James Bond take some damage, you know Cuz he can't.
Speaker 1: just.
Speaker 1: you know It'll look stupid if he walks out of there like completely shiny Even though they're all these bad guys.
Speaker 0: you Duke Togo gets cut written up.
Speaker 0: Oh My god, we were at the comic shop in the city and they have one of those awesome figures, but it's Duke Togo.
Speaker 0: You know those have like interchangeable facial expressions and all this stuff.
Speaker 0: Duke Togo has two facial expressions.
Speaker 0: One of them is him with no facial expression and the other one has such a subtle Sneer that you might not even realize its difference.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it also comes to the speech bubble with ellipses dot-dot-dot.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway, so before we spoil, you know, this is the final thoughts episode We're not gonna talk about.
Speaker 1: really I didn't.
Speaker 0: master Keaton again, cuz we've reviewed this before.
Speaker 0: we're just kind of talking about it again Both of us having seen the whole show.
Speaker 0: if you have not seen master Keaton just go and get the first episode I don't care how and just watch it and watch the opener.
Speaker 0: because well I just want to say the opener to the show.
Speaker 0: I really like it.
Speaker 0: It's okay It's just.
Speaker 0: it has the appropriate level of kind of slice of life mixed with this epic feeling.
Speaker 0: Yes, good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like it.
Speaker 1: It's okay.
Speaker 1: It's a good opener.
Speaker 1: It's not like oh my gosh Opener for all time.
Speaker 0: I watched it every episode.
Speaker 1: I only watched it sometimes I mostly skipped over it Able to finish it.
Speaker 0: so quick just watch the first episode.
Speaker 0: you will know after the first episode if you like master Keaton or not.
Speaker 0: If you don't like that first episode, you'll hate master Keaton.
Speaker 0: Every episode is like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the other thing is that you really like.
Speaker 1: I was kind of.
Speaker 1: you know, there is that slight connection between the episodes.
Speaker 1: So I didn't want to skip around, you know, cuz I'd might miss something but really You can skip around to any episode except there's a two-parter.
Speaker 1: the last two episodes are a two-part.
Speaker 1: You have to watch those in order but every other episode in the whole show You can just watch it in any freaking order.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter at all.
Speaker 1: So you can just ignore episode numbers entirely.
Speaker 1: There's really no continuity to speak of.
Speaker 0: also don't really marathon it.
Speaker 0: It's the kind of show where you're better off.
Speaker 0: Just whenever you feel like it watch the next episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and to do not, you know, it's okay to skip around.
Speaker 0: Don't fall into this trap.
Speaker 0: If you look at what the next episode is from the preview or the title and think I probably won't like that episode And try to skip to one with a good title.
Speaker 0: Don't be fooled.
Speaker 0: Don't you're gonna miss some good episodes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, every episode is pretty much of the same caliber.
Speaker 1: Yeah, pretty much I mean, there's some episodes that sort of stand out as like better than the others.
Speaker 1: a little bit, you know, there's like the Like the one where he's got the annoying old lady on the train.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's a good one.
Speaker 0: It was okay, but the one with the other bombs in the mall I really like.
Speaker 1: but I like the ones with like.
Speaker 1: was it Charlie the other detective.
Speaker 1: Those are real good.
Speaker 1: I love Charlie's like double.
Speaker 1: good, you know.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's the one where the Mafia takes over the hotel and he's there with that old military guy.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's the hotel that's on the island and yeah I need the boat and the punk kids like.
Speaker 0: I got this but the punk kid was stupid.
Speaker 1: The punk kid was stupid.
Speaker 0: That was such a great episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the old man the drunk old man was the secret badass, but you knew that all along.
Speaker 1: Yeah The only thing about that ever said I didn't like was like.
Speaker 1: Even though he was the old man who was secretly badass He kept grabbing that girl's ass and then she actually liked him eventually.
Speaker 1: But if I tried that it totally would not work.
Speaker 0: Oh the wine.
Speaker 0: The wine episode was great only because of also the ghost in the shell wine episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think they might have stolen it from me.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah But I think that's just us cuz.
Speaker 0: Emily pointed this out for some reason.
Speaker 0: like ghost in the shell as an aside has fan service on multiple levels.
Speaker 0: if you're into like Futurism like pop sci philosophy the side, you know science fiction kind of stuff Ghost in the shell is just fan service for you.
Speaker 0: if you're into butts Ghost in the shell has fan service for you in the form of the major If you're like me and Scott the fan service for you in that show is actually Aramaki.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz I don't know why but it's just us.
Speaker 0: I mean look at him.
Speaker 0: He's a badass guy.
Speaker 0: Togusa gives some good But Aramaki always does the immediate Astro boy thing in every situation.
Speaker 0: That's right And he's Astro boy and the only time he doesn't is when he has a bigger Astro boy waiting and he doesn't want to spoil it.
Speaker 1: Watch out behind you Pluto.
Speaker 1: It's Bora.
Speaker 0: All right, but I think we're gonna have to skip to the spoiler line because I want to talk about What makes this show great.
Speaker 0: basically master Keaton is a show that every episode is great and there's kind of this vague Thread about why is he called master Keaton and the answer to that is worth discussing because I think the show is more than just An episodic slice-of-life MacGyver off.
Speaker 0: I think it actually says something pretty meaningful.
Speaker 1: Well, I found out right that the manga ended early because of a dispute between urasawa and the other creator.
Speaker 1: There may have eventually been like some sort of conclusion or something along those lines But there never was because they stopped working on it.
Speaker 0: snap snap huh If I ever ever am in a position to interview urasawa.
Speaker 0: My only question is going to be how would you have ended master Keaton if no one could tell you otherwise?
Speaker 0: Yeah And I know he's not gonna give me some BS.
Speaker 0: Well, I can't tell you.
Speaker 1: actually you might give you that BS.
Speaker 0: He won't say I can't tell you what master Keaton was thinking.
Speaker 0: because I'm not master Keaton you would have to ask him Yeah, you won't give me that.
Speaker 1: no But he'll say he's not gonna give you the a real answer.
Speaker 0: if you have not watched all of master Keaton Do not listen any further.
Speaker 0: We're gonna talk.
Speaker 0: We're gonna spoil fucking everything from this point forward.
Speaker 0: So last warning go watch master Keaton.
Speaker 0: You will like this show.
Speaker 0: I hope he's the master But he's not a professional.
Speaker 0: Nope first Spoiler we got to talk about the specific spoiler episodes in the Poland of the Polish episode with the hotel on the island.
Speaker 0: Yep, the moment where he's basically the old man is like, yeah, I'm totally gonna help you guys out.
Speaker 0: He punches the punk kid and he's kind of just having wine with the guy in the shirt and war stories.
Speaker 0: And then he's like, yeah show me your gun.
Speaker 0: The guy pulls out the gun points right at him.
Speaker 0: He's like.
Speaker 0: the trick I would use if I was gonna beat a guy like you would be to go like this guys like ha That's funny.
Speaker 0: and then he doesn't like.
Speaker 0: oh, yep that I cheered out loud when I watched that episode.
Speaker 1: That's pretty good.
Speaker 0: I'm done master Keaton like busting through the window like right there.
Speaker 1: It was just too proud when master Keaton jumped through the window.
Speaker 1: That was like it's basically master Keaton's is a weird dude because like, you know, usually when you have a guy who's got mad skills at combat, right?
Speaker 1: You know or combat, you know fighting or violent it's straight up.
Speaker 0: I mean he was like a master chief or something and he fought in the Falkland war like straight up as special ops.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So whenever you have someone like that, they usually portrayed as some sort of badass, right?
Speaker 1: Even if they're nice as opposed to like a hard ass you get like a diehard guy, you know, he's nice.
Speaker 0: He just you might get the.
Speaker 0: I'm too old for this shit kind of guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know you get the.
Speaker 1: I'm too old for this shit.
Speaker 1: You never really get someone who's just like ultra nice and like mr.
Speaker 1: Rogers jumping through the window and kicking you in the face.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you never.
Speaker 0: you never derp de der never kicks your ass except in master Keaton.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: So, you know when like, you know, he like.
Speaker 1: he doesn't really like violence.
Speaker 1: He doesn't resort to violence unless he absolutely has to but when he has to when he has to he just does it and he's All you need is fucking kicks people's asses, even though he looks like he's totally unassuming.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's pretty much every like the.
Speaker 0: I think the dog episode is still one of my favorites Because that trick like straight up.
Speaker 0: even my mom, you know, she's an expert in this thing.
Speaker 0: I showed her that episode and she's like.
Speaker 0: that is exactly what you should do and that would work very very well Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: But yeah, there's that Cali man of the desert episode you like so much.
Speaker 0: That episode just does it for me just because the whole thing builds to that moment where he stands up with that Spear in the desert over the horizon because he's trying to figure out what that you know.
Speaker 1: That's a good episode because it combines right and this is the thing like yet.
Speaker 1: What mr.
Speaker 1: Keaton is an archi a master Keaton.
Speaker 1: He's an archaeologist.
Speaker 1: All right and an insurance investigator and A former SAS badass, right?
Speaker 1: So how can you combine these things in any way?
Speaker 0: that makes most episodes only use two aspects?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the only one.
Speaker 1: but in the Cali man of the desert episode, right he goes somewhere because he's inspecting some insurance.
Speaker 1: That's why he's there.
Speaker 1: But there happens to be some archaeology going on and he's got this, you know, like archaeology.
Speaker 1: He's got this artifact and he's asking people what it does, but he doesn't know.
Speaker 0: of course I put out in that episode.
Speaker 0: He's asked for a boy there.
Speaker 0: There's all this dispute.
Speaker 0: He goes straight to the natives.
Speaker 0: He's like, what's the deal with this?
Speaker 0: Yep, right here.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So, you know he goes and he's just taking care of business and Something happens and he gets stuck out.
Speaker 1: He gets put out in the desert to die.
Speaker 1: So now he brings in his SAS survival school skills to survive walking back from the desert without dying.
Speaker 1: and You know, they're basically watching him and they're like, yeah, they'll be dead in three days and first they're like, they'll be dead tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Yeah, meanwhile, it's been like days.
Speaker 1: They're still alive still alive still alive and all the survival techniques they use would work.
Speaker 0: I just don't know like I don't think that I don't think anyone but master Keaton would have actually survived that that's true.
Speaker 0: Those other people could not have dealt with that.
Speaker 1: I also don't believe the degree to which they work.
Speaker 1: For example, he used various methods to get water in the desert.
Speaker 1: those work real Well, those work real well, but I did not believe he would have gotten the quantity of water necessary.
Speaker 0: You would be surprised.
Speaker 0: I've actually I've done that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: No, he would get water prop maybe even enough for one person, but I don't know if you'd get enough water.
Speaker 1: He was sharing it with all those other guys.
Speaker 0: I don't need that much water to keep yourself alive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I Question the quantity of why.
Speaker 0: I would say the only improbable part of that is that that other guy the complaining guy would have Died like right away immediately, of course.
Speaker 0: No in the real world, you know, what's unrealistic?
Speaker 0: the master Keaton didn't just murder him right away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, drink his blood.
Speaker 0: Plus you got to admit the end of that episode is was gecky guy when he stands there with the spear in the distance Because he figures out that the artifact is actually a spear throwing device.
Speaker 1: So, you know any?
Speaker 1: again the archaeology comes back and get right and he also knows that like the legend of the Cali man right Cuz?
Speaker 0: yeah He caught.
Speaker 1: you know master Keaton's the only one who knows about the local customs because he's so smart and he also knows that the people Who sent him out into the desert?
Speaker 1: The reason that they're in trouble is because you know the people that you know.
Speaker 1: The other archaeologists didn't weren't aware of or respectful of the local customs, right?
Speaker 0: They like we're destroying this very important and the young play on the people who put him out There is like why don't we just go shoot him?
Speaker 0: and then the the elders like no He's the Cali man of the deserts.
Speaker 0: go get him.
Speaker 0: Give him water.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That was gecky guy right there Super double gecky guy.
Speaker 0: That's why I like that episode.
Speaker 0: That's why I say that's the best episode, but I love a good half of the episodes in a big way.
Speaker 1: The other thing about this show is that like there were 24 or 25 TV episodes and the rest were OAV episodes.
Speaker 1: But you couldn't really tell the difference.
Speaker 0: not really the production values were watching it on DVD.
Speaker 1: You don't know that once some of these are directed discs and some of them were TV the production values remain Consistently high throughout the show is lushly animated.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this isn't like, you know, you would expect like with you know, 30 some odd episodes right that are you know?
Speaker 1: Some of them weren't?
Speaker 1: I've even on TV That you'd get lots of stock footage repetition.
Speaker 1: you'd get lots of panning across still shots.
Speaker 1: You know all the stuff that you see in shows like Rosa Versailles or antenna where?
Speaker 1: Even initial D just things, you know.
Speaker 1: and even Astro boy things.
Speaker 1: they do to save money.
Speaker 1: speed lines zooming in and out Right, none of that.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of money went into the show.
Speaker 1: It must have been pretty popular in Japan or at least I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 1: the manga was really popular, you know I mean, you know Urasawa, I think Yara came before this.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure this is another example of a show Where if you just marketed it right and just showed it to Americans dubbed and we're just like look at this.
Speaker 1: Well, I think that some people would like it, but I think it would for some people would be too slow and boring.
Speaker 0: You know, you'd have to market it to the right demographic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not the prime time HBO show.
Speaker 1: I actually think old people would like this.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: You put people watch a lot of TV.
Speaker 0: you put this on daytime TV like one o'clock on weekdays.
Speaker 1: Maybe not necessarily that but you know, maybe like primetime I'm like a cable network like, you know, TBS or USA or something.
Speaker 0: But what real I just remembered.
Speaker 0: remember the episode of that old man who's like hit.
Speaker 0: that guy shouldn't have died He didn't have the scent of death about him.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: I like that episode.
Speaker 0: But there's that one the episode where it's the flashback to Keaton's childhood like out of nowhere and the whole episode is just him As a kid and learning what it is to be a master of life.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's a god.
Speaker 0: That's when the show turned cuz.
Speaker 0: that's when they you know the whole time.
Speaker 0: They just call him master Keaton and they leave it at that.
Speaker 0: They don't like explore that and you don't think it's kind of like.
Speaker 0: you don't expect them to explore Why Superman is super after the origin story?
Speaker 1: Well, it's because when he was in the SAS in the survival training school, they called him the master.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you learn that and like the like the first episode it's like you're.
Speaker 1: I remember you you're master.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's a great flashback because it comes to that guy like laying on the ground sucking and Keaton's like suck it up Nancy boy and Keaton just like walking like it's no problem.
Speaker 0: Yep But they you you don't even think.
Speaker 0: why is he called master?
Speaker 0: It's kind of like a nutenna.
Speaker 0: You don't think.
Speaker 0: why is the school so fucked up?
Speaker 0: Like there's so many shows where you don't think.
Speaker 0: why X?
Speaker 1: because you assume because they build an unrealist.
Speaker 1: It's the old trick of building an unrealistic status quo and such that you will not question it because it is the status quo.
Speaker 1: and then you know It's at least within the context of the show.
Speaker 1: and then they say hello real world.
Speaker 0: Remember?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Now I'm gonna question that because it's not status quo.
Speaker 1: when you take it into the context of the real world Yeah, no did that pretty well and then you're surprised.
Speaker 1: But it's a classic trick.
Speaker 0: that episode brings it up because suddenly he meets that old man.
Speaker 0: There's the whole thing about being a master of life and what being a master of life means.
Speaker 0: and then later There's the references.
Speaker 0: the master Keaton's a master He's not a professional.
Speaker 0: and then in the last few episodes you start to run into Professionals and I think I'm just well I think it's.
Speaker 1: you know It's sort of runs throughout the show because like whenever master Keaton does something like, you know Say when he's doing the negotiating right in the in one of those early episodes to get the the kidnapped husband back.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah when he's dealing with the terrorists who are in that building right, you know All right, when the the other guys were like we'll do this by the book.
Speaker 1: and he's like, you know You should shoot the hinges with the shotgun not the doorknob.
Speaker 1: Alright, you know.
Speaker 1: so, you know, but people basically always when they once they realize that master Keaton is actually the master They're like, oh, he's a pro.
Speaker 1: They always say like Oh pro da You know that they say that like all throughout the show.
Speaker 0: So so many characters like ah Pro days, but I think the point of the show is just that master Keaton is kind of a master Like he's a master of life and that he's excelled in all these areas.
Speaker 0: He's become 90% badass and 90% derp to der and 90% like good father.
Speaker 0: like he's doing all these things He's enjoying life, but yet he is skilled.
Speaker 0: But the people who are the 100% badasses effectively the Duke Togo's or like the guy in the last two episodes Be by becoming the professional by becoming the ultimate badass the.
Speaker 0: I can kill people.
Speaker 0: I'm super badass.
Speaker 0: They lose out on being a master of life.
Speaker 0: They don't actually live their lives.
Speaker 0: their lives just are being the knife being the assassin being the terrorists.
Speaker 1: Yep, the other thing that the master Keaton does really well is the same thing that spider-man does.
Speaker 1: right is Spider-man was totally awesome because unlike say Superman right spider-man has failings.
Speaker 1: But what they?
Speaker 1: what you do when you want to make an awesome character with failings like spider-man or master Keaton is you put?
Speaker 1: The failings into a different aspect of life from the hero wing right?
Speaker 1: so when you watch an episode of master Keaton What's he doing most of the time?
Speaker 1: He's most of the time doing the things he's really good at archaeology insurance inspecting and SAS ass kicking and surviving right.
Speaker 1: so that what they did is they said okay?
Speaker 1: We need to make a show where the guy who's so badass or manga where he's so badass at all these things.
Speaker 1: But if that's all the show is about it'll just be Duke Togo, so what do we do?
Speaker 1: We make every other aspect of his life sort of fail right?
Speaker 1: he's failed at you know his wife.
Speaker 1: He can't actually get an archaeology job even though he's really good at archaeology.
Speaker 1: You know he's failing at all these things that don't actually matter in the show that much or even they just like they just present Them to you as a way to craft the character of master Keaton even though those things aren't part of the plot.
Speaker 1: So he's still an ultimate badass hero when it comes to the plot of any given episode.
Speaker 1: But his character is still you know an actual normal human being you can relate to Who has failings and such and such.
Speaker 1: well?
Speaker 0: Why is he a master of life?
Speaker 0: It's partly his outlook.
Speaker 0: I mean he's derp-de-der in all these aspects, but he's happy.
Speaker 0: He's really really really happy when he succeeds and when he fails and he really doesn't he doesn't really get upset.
Speaker 0: But look at the professionals in the show like I think is the first or second episode after Calum out of the desert when the Direct-to-DVD stuff starts where there's the where the bodyguards get killed and he's got that like KGB guy He's fighting with or the last two episodes all the professionals are miserable.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're absolutely Presented as you know miserable kind of guys.
Speaker 0: or they're.
Speaker 0: they're so tied up in their profession that if they fail That's their entire life They can't live life.
Speaker 0: and it all comes back to that flashback episode where what it is to be a master of life and The whole point of the show I think is that master Keaton is a master of life.
Speaker 1: You know he says he's not a master of life.
Speaker 0: if you want to be you know the Strider in the debt It's this burning wheel.
Speaker 0: if you want to be the loner badass you suck and your life sucks.
Speaker 0: You've got to be the cool guy with some flaws and some faults who just enjoys life, and yeah master Keaton
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean even like think about the episode where like someone who may or may not be his actual sister Right is like gonna kill themselves, and he doesn't really get upset.
Speaker 1: You know he go.
Speaker 1: you know like he goes to D deals with it But he's not like.
Speaker 1: he's not shaken at all not whatsoever He just he takes care of business.
Speaker 1: You know like he obviously doesn't want her to kill herself and when he you know realizes gonna happen He's like oh shit.
Speaker 1: How come I didn't see it sooner, but he's not like you know like okay He doesn't freak out or ever have like an attack.
Speaker 1: It doesn't really cry about anything unless it's like You know just something that's sort of you know like you know a normal reason.
Speaker 1: you know he's very emotionally like totally under control and usually as a pleasant and You know bright demeanor cheery demeanor.
Speaker 0: Remember the episode where there's the guy who wants to compose music again But he can't because his dad isn't a bastard anymore and the key has to make his dad be an asshole again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see how quirky the show is.
Speaker 0: it ranges from like dead serious Russian guy on the run like expert knife fighter might kill Keaton Professional blah blah blah - my dad's got to be an asshole or I can't compose music.
Speaker 0: Can you help me?
Speaker 1: Yeah?
Speaker 1: Make my dad be a jerk to me again Because that's the only thing that motivated me was showing my dad that he sucks.
Speaker 1: So now that my dad's a homeless bum right who's got nothing in the world.
Speaker 1: I have no motivation anymore because I've won.
Speaker 0: I Don't know if I'd ever watch the entire show again But I don't think I could definitely watch very specific key episodes again.
Speaker 0: in the process of showing them to other people.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling what it would be is it would be a long time.
Speaker 1: You know cuz I would forget them.
Speaker 1: so that way when I watched him again.
Speaker 0: It'd be like oh Remember next time we have to show people something out of the blue like we need something to watch.
Speaker 0: I just want to show people that the island hotel episode It wasn't wasn't like the island of the coward or the hotel of the coward.
Speaker 1: It was something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would.
Speaker 0: I want to watch that episode.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I just I'd like that episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah that in the wine.
Speaker 1: The thing is right is that there is a little bit of knowledge you need right?
Speaker 1: Even though there's no continuity There are certain episodes where it's like, you know Keaton is just there and then he's badass.
Speaker 1: And if you don't if you didn't watch an earlier episode and all you need to know is that he was in the SAS He was a badass.
Speaker 0: episode one takes care of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah show people episode one and then any other episode exactly.
Speaker 1: But it's like if you didn't watch at least the episode one and know that Keaton was a badass.
Speaker 1: It'd be like you wouldn't believe.
Speaker 0: it's like it wouldn't like watching mr Rogers and suddenly like a guy jumps through the window with a knife and Roger stabs him and then continues with the show You're like what?
Speaker 0: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.