Speaker 0: It's Wednesday November 17th.
Speaker 0: I'm Ram.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight Looney Tunes.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: 2010.
Speaker 0: no you jerk I point out.
Speaker 0: the listeners want it.
Speaker 1: They just want whatever.
Speaker 0: I don't want Ah, but they want it.
Speaker 1: I should have acted like oh, man.
Speaker 1: That was awesome.
Speaker 1: How you did the date, and then you would have.
Speaker 0: So is it awesome?
Speaker 0: should I keep doing it?
Speaker 1: no well Because now the cats already out of the bag so whether whichever way I go it won't work.
Speaker 1: You know what I want.
Speaker 1: You know I've revealed my true desires.
Speaker 1: therefore it can.
Speaker 1: there is no Possible way I can conceal them again.
Speaker 0: see now the important thing is that I win But you forget you you have to be a master of instilling doubt when there is no possible doubt.
Speaker 0: This is the art of the person who ran the RIT anime club.
Speaker 0: where?
Speaker 0: When a show was accidentally spoiled for someone you had to be able to instill doubt To where they wouldn't know if it was spoiled or not.
Speaker 1: yes That is that is thing is it depends on the specific thing right?
Speaker 1: so at this point?
Speaker 1: There is no way nothing that could possibly be said that would convince you that I actually are you sure?
Speaker 0: I mean I can Probably instill doubt in most of my most closely held ideals.
Speaker 1: if I really needed to Yeah, but it's like you've already told someone Very can be.
Speaker 1: even you do ranted about it.
Speaker 1: How could you possibly convince someone that you changed your mind so suddenly you know like maybe a year from now?
Speaker 1: I could be like yeah, you know looking back adding that year was actually a good idea.
Speaker 0: Here's why it doesn't work on me because if you said that I'd say awesome cool.
Speaker 0: We'll keep doing it Yeah, and you say no.
Speaker 0: I'll say I'm the audio editor.
Speaker 1: We'll keep doing it Yeah, anyway, so I went to this conference today, which sucked.
Speaker 1: I don't really want to talk about it.
Speaker 0: 99 for all you guys to go to anime cons and nerd cons and packs and everything.
Speaker 0: packs is greater than all cons and Like anime cons are greater than all cons that aren't.
Speaker 1: I mean it had some.
Speaker 1: it was Monday Tuesday and today right today was the Workshop day and there were good parts and bad parts and it sat and it apparently is.
Speaker 1: the workshop that I was not in Was probably a better workshop judging by the noises that were coming out of that room.
Speaker 0: wow that's like you're an anime con.
Speaker 0: You're watching some dumb panel on like I don't know Italia Crossplay making out and across the hall you just hear people screaming as gogo 13 shoots people and you can't go over there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's no way anime con you can switch hallways, but when you signed up for a specific workshop You can't switch the people sitting behind me our workshop so that workshop.
Speaker 1: They've got sniper rifles, and you're taking turns doing what go go well It was also interesting how like there are people there who obviously came from far.
Speaker 1: I really feel bad for anyone came from far away because it was not.
Speaker 1: it was only good for us.
Speaker 1: Cuz the venue for the one part was actually right in your office and the venue for the workshops was you know also pretty close.
Speaker 1: I actually there are people who were in there with their luggage And they picked it up and left like in the middle of the day.
Speaker 1: some people left like after the first break.
Speaker 1: They were like oh man fuck this.
Speaker 1: They just they.
Speaker 1: they bolted at the first chance.
Speaker 1: You know they just did not return.
Speaker 0: I found in my life that I almost every conference or convention I ever attend I Feel bad for the people who came that had to pay and travel to get there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean my work paid which is the only.
Speaker 0: yeah, yeah I would not go to SIFMA if I had to pay money to go to SIFMA.
Speaker 0: Yeah First instead SIFMA pays me.
Speaker 1: the thing is doesn't?
Speaker 1: doesn't SIFMA have like?
Speaker 1: it's the kind of thing where you walk around like a trade Show right you walk around the booth.
Speaker 0: No it also has workshops and lectures.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this was literally right.
Speaker 1: basically the first two days were two panel rooms.
Speaker 1: well actually two theaters right and The very limited programming in the second theater, and you basically had to choose between one of the.
Speaker 1: you know every slot.
Speaker 1: You either choose one theater or the other and that was pretty much it.
Speaker 1: and in terms of booths There was like five little stands with PR people.
Speaker 1: I didn't even talk to them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right and there weren't even booths.
Speaker 1: It was just like a guy at a table with a laptop You know trying to sell his dick I guess as much as we complain about.
Speaker 1: and then on the third day was a workshop all day And you had to pick which one beforehand.
Speaker 1: and a thing is Everyone sort of knew who the people running the workshops are but I didn't know who they were so I ended up picking a not good one just based on the title and It wasn't even a workshop is basically an all-day powerpoint And it's like the other people had a workshop where they fucking made something and I was like god damn it This isn't a workshop.
Speaker 0: Hey that was the one at least at Connecticut.
Speaker 0: We only had like two or three workshops that weren't actually workshop.
Speaker 1: the thing is these are all internet e people.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna write a blog post about how they saw how it's terrible.
Speaker 1: There were good parts, right?
Speaker 1: Obviously the other workshop was probably good.
Speaker 1: I didn't go to right and obviously it you know a lot.
Speaker 1: there were parts that I didn't like because I'm mostly a Programmer and it was obviously designer.
Speaker 1: It was a web design thing primarily.
Speaker 1: So a lot of it I was just like oh god, right and you know, so part of it was me and there were some good talks.
Speaker 1: I went to a bunch of the talks Monday and Tuesday and some were good.
Speaker 1: but some and even the ones that were Maybe I didn't like they were still well presented like they had speaking skills and presentation skills.
Speaker 1: It's just they didn't actually present any useful information there.
Speaker 1: Well, that's the.
Speaker 1: obviously they're basically pep talks.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm usually running into like look at packs where like some video game programmer people They have a lot of interesting stuff to say.
Speaker 0: they just don't know how to speak in.
Speaker 1: No, there were these guys.
Speaker 1: there are these designers and they had these their presentations like amazing because they're designers, right?
Speaker 1: And they're the things that their presentation skills were off the charts, right?
Speaker 1: They were enthusiastic and they they weren't, you know, only one person showed any nervousness You know.
Speaker 1: and they were exciting and energetic and like oh go get him, right?
Speaker 1: But all they were saying was like I'm not even a designer, right?
Speaker 1: I'm a programmer.
Speaker 1: and they were saying the same stuff like oh man Look at Apple and how they're designed so awesome and you know You'd know that something is right when you have nothing left to take away.
Speaker 1: it's like a G. I've never heard that quote before.
Speaker 1: why don't you devote another five minutes to it, right?
Speaker 1: They didn't actually I mean theoretically the room was supposed to be full of web designers, right?
Speaker 1: Why don't you?
Speaker 1: I guess this is the kind of stuff that's gonna be in the blog post, right?
Speaker 1: I don't want to waste it all now But you know the primary thing that bothered me above all other complaints is that listen This is a conference of designers, right?
Speaker 1: You have to assume that everyone is coming is already designer.
Speaker 1: These are not nubs These are not.
Speaker 0: people have never designed a day in their life Like, you know, we got X we do a lecture on you know game theory.
Speaker 0: We assume you've played some goddamn game, right?
Speaker 1: You have to assume that we're not like gaming these and in the fifth century Assume that the people in the audience have like, you know, some of them probably have like masters or degrees in design, right?
Speaker 1: so telling them this nothing stuff or just a pep talk that's really energetic is not worth the Price that they or their employers paid for them to show up, right?
Speaker 1: So What you need to do is you need to actually give us something of actual substance.
Speaker 0: So Scott, I've been to one I do not know already technology convention my entire life.
Speaker 0: that met that Pangorcon the second Pangorcon in Novi, Michigan.
Speaker 0: That was the best technology convention I've ever attended.
Speaker 1: I agree.
Speaker 0: What we should start speaking at tech conventions, I guess I
Speaker 1: think the thing is when it comes to tech and Meetups though the ones that I like the most the ones that I've been to right are these little things in the city We go to right where you actually where everyone says stuff to everyone It's like, you know, and it's just the networking right?
Speaker 1: Like something like open everything Talking about right is is the?
Speaker 1: you know, I mean it's something like what I went to.
Speaker 1: people might show up for the networking But it's like I even have the talking just have the networking and that's it just have like a meetup right?
Speaker 1: or you look at something like PyCon right.
Speaker 1: you go to PyCon, which is a Python conference usually in Europe and While there is there are talks and lightning rounds and all these sorts of things.
Speaker 1: There's also people coding.
Speaker 1: they do stuff there, right?
Speaker 1: It's the equivalent of like tabletop at PAX is coding and actually making stuff at PyCon.
Speaker 0: So it's desktop.
Speaker 1: So it's yeah, right So but there was no designing going on at least I think there was in the other workshop.
Speaker 0: But then I see that other workshop.
Speaker 1: that's where everything was I know but that was only one out of three days, right?
Speaker 1: So, I mean while there was good stuff that I was missing and what you know It was like there were problems at this thing and if I had paid for it with my own money I or traveled a great distance.
Speaker 1: I would have been very upset.
Speaker 0: What said is I can still say everything that you said.
Speaker 0: just change some of the proper nouns about many of the anime and gaming I've attended in my life.
Speaker 1: What well, you can't say that there's really good presenters with.
Speaker 1: you know, what useful information There are.
Speaker 0: there are as I will point out Daryl Surratt Jared Rathkal, they have useful information.
Speaker 0: You me Mike tool.
Speaker 1: We all have useful information.
Speaker 1: What are you talking about?
Speaker 1: Actually?
Speaker 1: No, except for you and me We don't have useful information now, but all the other people do we just?
Speaker 0: I think it was Luke Who said we have an amazing ability in panel rooms to bowl people over and whether they agree agree with us or not They feel like they should by the end even if we're wrong.
Speaker 1: But we're actually giving information or at least making a case the people.
Speaker 1: a lot of the talks I went to are pretty much just like rah.
Speaker 1: rah design.
Speaker 1: Oh and every single thing I went to there was ie6 hating.
Speaker 1: It's like that's all web designers could talk about all day long every all three days was we hate isaac?
Speaker 1: So I 60 and I six.
Speaker 1: it's like we know everyone here hates ie6.
Speaker 1: We don't need to keep saying it a thousand times.
Speaker 1: I hate it too.
Speaker 1: You hate it.
Speaker 1: We all hate it.
Speaker 1: Shut up, you don't need to say in every single panel and every single workshop 10 every 10 minutes Oh, but what about ie6?
Speaker 1: ie6 sucks?
Speaker 1: Ruins my day.
Speaker 1: What's you know, you know?
Speaker 1: Hey, what's the worst thing about your job ie6?
Speaker 0: This reminds me of back and way back.
Speaker 0: We were at an Otacon and we're at the feedback ceremony one by one.
Speaker 0: everyone comes up and they're like I've been coming to Otacon for 15 years and I've been coming to Otacon for 11 years and this is my 20th Otacon.
Speaker 0: and Our friend Pete goes up there and he's like I've been coming to Otacon for 500 years.
Speaker 0: And I feel like if you were talking at that conference, you should be like yeah mosaic that fucker.
Speaker 1: They talked about mosaic But they talked about it, you know, it's a historical thing.
Speaker 1: You know the way we'll.
Speaker 1: when we talk about something We'll start with the oldest thing to be historical and show you a progression.
Speaker 1: They started at mosaic when I wait whenever they needed to talk about progression.
Speaker 1: They tell you started with mosaic.
Speaker 0: I don't know why they didn't start with links at a web conference or everyone probably already knew anyway, exact I don't think the listeners on Wednesday night care much about that.
Speaker 1: No, that's just what bothered me today.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway Oh, wow That was a tangent actually because what I really wanted to talk about was that today when I was at the workshops on 59th in Lexington across the street.
Speaker 0: Holy shit.
Speaker 0: There's actually a link here.
Speaker 0: This is actually relevant.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Wow across the street from the workshops was the Argosy gallery.
Speaker 1: All right, you know what this is.
Speaker 0: I have no idea what the Argosy gallery.
Speaker 1: It is a store right which sells Argosy books prints paintings and maps right?
Speaker 1: I went in there.
Speaker 1: They had books from like the 15th century just on the shelf.
Speaker 1: I was like what it's like.
Speaker 1: this place should be a museum, but it's a store.
Speaker 1: There's a place like that the newest.
Speaker 0: Wait, wait, wait, you're on 59th Street.
Speaker 0: I think I know where you were.
Speaker 0: This place was that?
Speaker 0: wait this place also have Greek pottery.
Speaker 0: no, okay.
Speaker 0: There's another player.
Speaker 1: This is the place on the street view.
Speaker 1: see it.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: There's another place on 59th Street that sells actual Greek pottery.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, I gotta go there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we have to go to this place.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess technically I mean there is pottery from Greece in the 70s, but this Argosy place, right?
Speaker 1: Not only were they selling like books right and apparently the newest books they had were like As old as the books that are unlike my grandma's shelf.
Speaker 1: That was the newest books.
Speaker 1: They had were like 80s books, right?
Speaker 1: But they had stuff they're like, yeah Here's a letter from the desk of FDR's secretary in a plastic sleeve for $35 and it's just like it's just sitting there.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, no, not that much money No, but I'm saying is like they got that kind of stuff is like just all over the place.
Speaker 0: I should get something weird like that and just leave it out.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we had to.
Speaker 1: it's like we had to go to this place.
Speaker 1: You got to see it and it's it's weird because this build this building has many floors, right and it actually uses all the floors It's not and they have a really old elevator to go up.
Speaker 0: Oh, so this isn't actually linked to anime manga or comics.
Speaker 1: No, oh, I thought that it was just.
Speaker 1: that was the thing I actually wanted to talk about in my opening bit But I forgot because I started by saying I was at a workshop and across the street was the thing But I got stuck on the workshop because the workshop was.
Speaker 1: it took a while to get across the street.
Speaker 0: Yeah So there's a little bit of anime news But I do want to.
Speaker 0: I have two geek bite points to make Point.
Speaker 0: the first when we reviewed Eden of the East Scott had seen it all and I've seen all but the last two episodes.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: Oh, you've seen the last episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what the fuck.
Speaker 0: that was the most disappointing show I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: Because shows that are worse at least are not disappointing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean basically what.
Speaker 0: why didn't you tell me?
Speaker 0: Why didn't you warn me?
Speaker 0: You were like, yeah, it was B anime was okay.
Speaker 0: You were going along with.
Speaker 0: no fuck that show.
Speaker 0: Really that end was like.
Speaker 0: it was a B anime with a B end, but it could have been an a anime.
Speaker 0: That's worse than just being a B anime.
Speaker 1: Oh you think so.
Speaker 0: you could have been an a and you weren't because Kamehama just apparently is only good when he takes other people's works and reimagine them.
Speaker 1: I mean the situation is right.
Speaker 1: is that you got this?
Speaker 1: the beginning is so promising right in the end It does not live up to the promise right, but it's not a bad end.
Speaker 1: It just doesn't live up.
Speaker 1: But here's here's why it had lived up.
Speaker 1: it would have been a so because it didn't live up.
Speaker 0: Here's why it's a bad ending.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna talk about how the whole clothes like all the things I already talked about on the show.
Speaker 0: It's sad.
Speaker 0: reason number one They did the same bullshit that Gundam C did where they unkill a character for no reason except fan service.
Speaker 0: They unkill the character and they show them to you for two seconds to be like check it out.
Speaker 0: Not dead moving on All right, that was BS to the end.
Speaker 0: Didn't make sense it that none of that would have worked and nothing was resolved?
Speaker 1: Like no, I mean there was a result.
Speaker 1: I think the thing is is that there was so much that was unresolved, you know There's so many.
Speaker 0: the end was so stylistically beautiful Like it felt like the end of standalone complex.
Speaker 0: except imagine if the end of standalone complex didn't resolve anything at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah Fuck that show.
Speaker 0: That was the most disappointing anime I've seen in a day.
Speaker 1: I think it's like a Death Note situation.
Speaker 1: right people hate the second half of death.
Speaker 1: Some people do right, but I think but really if that second half of Death Note is actually good It's just the first half is great.
Speaker 1: So you think when you're putting and they're in the same work with the same title, right you go.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, this is terrible because you get your reference point is is shifted, right?
Speaker 1: So you see now in this case though if the second half of Death Note was its own manga on its own People wouldn't be like hating on it so much.
Speaker 0: First half of Death Note was an A and the second half was a B. this was a B show that the first three episodes were a and The entire second half of the show was C so it averaged out to a B. that's way different from like scrap princess, which was just a Standard generic B.
Speaker 1: and the thing is I will actually in my you know, my personal taste I will take that over these shows that are C C C C C C C C C C C or even F F F And then become a at the very end.
Speaker 0: fuck that go go go.
Speaker 1: I'm not sitting through right because I if it's good at least in the beginning and turns to crap.
Speaker 1: That's okay.
Speaker 0: I should have stopped cuz
Speaker 1: I remember it's like I got my goodness and that goodness will is like is like coal in the steam in The engine that will power me through and I can just sort of slide down the bad parts if I get before as long as It's not terrible for a very long time.
Speaker 1: Like if it was many episodes like let's say it was 50 episodes and it gets bad at episode 10.
Speaker 1: I'll just stop watching.
Speaker 0: Well, this show did like noir did this to the first episode of noir was one of the most awesome and promising things I'd seen.
Speaker 1: yeah, noir is the perfect example of gets bad like episode five six, right?
Speaker 0: That show was like a a B C F nuns with guns.
Speaker 1: It's like if it's bad for the beginning I mean if it's good from the beginning I can watch it and I'm watching good stuff.
Speaker 0: So what do I care?
Speaker 0: Heck episode 1 a. episode 2 B episode 3 through the end blah blah blah key over the Twilight.
Speaker 1: So if it gets bad, I can just stop watching and know that it's just bad.
Speaker 1: Right, but and I've still watched I only watched good parts.
Speaker 1: So I'm safe this show was so short that I was able to make it to the end.
Speaker 1: But if a show is bad and as a promise of being good, that means there's a chance I might be slogging through shit and at the other end more shit.
Speaker 1: So you can't right?
Speaker 1: so in that case, right it's like.
Speaker 1: You know the the the payoff you're basically risking a payoff and watching our ton of shit in the end.
Speaker 1: What is good at the beginning?
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter if it turns to shit because you can stop watching and you're not.
Speaker 1: you never watch the shit.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: there's the difference like we always say like a anime B anime C anime, but really B anime are in two classes.
Speaker 0: There's the B anime that's consistently B Maybe with some peaks some a episode some C episodes.
Speaker 0: and there's the B anime like Eden of the East.
Speaker 0: There's only B because the first episode a balances out the ease at the end.
Speaker 0: Ease whoa, not quite an E.
Speaker 1: I think if they're like C.
Speaker 0: It was a solid C at the end.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean at least gang kotsuo had the good graces to be really awesome Until the end and then just fuck up just the end as opposed to the long slow Peter out that even at the East head Any of these wasn't that long which helped it out.
Speaker 0: true last exile did that - it was awesome.
Speaker 0: And in the very end, which is kind of like what and notice how that show also unkilled someone for no reason.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the very it was thing is last exile was good right up into the final episode which didn't resolve enough Climactically enough.
Speaker 0: Yep, and also unkilled people and killed people stupidly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so anyway, so I News, let's do news.
Speaker 0: I got one more thing to say another geek bite.
Speaker 0: I'm rewatching try gun.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's good show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, however, I had not seen try gun since we were freshmen RIT.
Speaker 1: I seen it more recently, but even so it's been a while.
Speaker 1: But I watched it many times at the time.
Speaker 1: I did watch it.
Speaker 0: So what I want to say is that it's a good show, but I don't know if I still put it in a category.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it's b-plus.
Speaker 1: It was always at the bottom of the a cat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was but watching it again it It's interesting how.
Speaker 0: I think I remember I'd seen try try gun before I saw cowboy bebop all the way through.
Speaker 0: I think that is the primary reason why I held it in such high esteem.
Speaker 0: The only reason I bring this up is still a good show.
Speaker 0: I got to finish for about halfway through.
Speaker 0: We just got to the episode with the Cyclops.
Speaker 0: I really like her.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm But I think this is the first time I've had a show.
Speaker 0: usually, you know, I like Ava.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh I like that shows a kid, but maybe it's not good now that I watch.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh that shows brilliant.
Speaker 0: Yep, every show I've rewatched until now.
Speaker 0: I've been like, yes.
Speaker 0: In fact, not only is it brilliant It's more brilliant than I realized like Evangelion was way more brilliant than I remember or even irresponsible captain Tyler Like that is in my top three right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you didn't finish it.
Speaker 1: I don't put it up there.
Speaker 0: Ah, if you watch all the way through I watched enough.
Speaker 0: Ah, no, you didn't.
Speaker 0: Anyway, try gun a mine is b-plus.
Speaker 0: We'll see how it goes because I forgot how long the kind of Tezuka style non sequitur crazy Characters always going off model beginning was.
Speaker 1: yeah Well, there's also you know, there's a whole bunch of episodes really in the middle where it's nothing.
Speaker 1: but go to a new town You know a new bad guy, of course, then you get to dynamite Neon, that's.
Speaker 1: but I mean that's really really into dynamite.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's really just a two-parter with a bad guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but he was the great bad guy.
Speaker 1: I mean, they're all great bad guys.
Speaker 1: That's the thing like the sniper You know, every bad guy is great.
Speaker 1: It's just mostly go to town bad guy go to town bad guy slowly Reveal something's going on.
Speaker 0: We'll see though because I have watching it again I'm remembering that you that you don't know, you know what the show is until near the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so and I've never rewatched episodes episode 17, I believe.
Speaker 0: Yeah Where we stopped the show, we're like, did you download the wrong fan sub exactly?
Speaker 1: That's I believe that is the episode where it actually you know turns around.
Speaker 1: but so like but like, you know episode 13 is actually he.
Speaker 0: when is when he goes crazy, but like yeah with That's that's the one word, you know people actually die.
Speaker 1: It's like the demon episode.
Speaker 1: Yeah Diablo, yeah.
Speaker 1: So we'll see.
Speaker 0: I mean the other thing is I've just gotten to the point where I remember the show getting way dark and way awesome.
Speaker 0: So it might still be an a-minus but it might be b-plus.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: We'll see in anime news.
Speaker 0: very briefly Summer Wars is one of the one of my favorite anime movies just because it was great King Kong cosmon.
Speaker 0: So it's up for the Oscar, I mean pon you didn't win the Oscar last year, but it was.
Speaker 0: it was not.
Speaker 1: There's no way it's winning.
Speaker 1: So not a chance.
Speaker 1: Well if it wins I will bet money.
Speaker 1: It will not win.
Speaker 0: It's only up against among other movies how to train your dragon.
Speaker 0: despicable me the owl movies Toy Story 3 Story 3 already won.
Speaker 1: probably it's a horror And so I haven't even seen it.
Speaker 1: but I can guarantee I'm not even a movie person You know, he's not as not nearly as much as many other people in the world.
Speaker 1: It's Toy Story 3 is a lock for that category.
Speaker 1: There's no story.
Speaker 1: No way the stupid owls are winning ever know what the owls are in there?
Speaker 0: Right if Toy Story 3 was not in the running I would guess that how to train your dragon would win.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean while summer wars is great.
Speaker 1: There's no way it's gonna beat those Even though it's pretty.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's probably actually, you know, like Toy Story 3 is obviously the winner.
Speaker 1: I mean summer wars is right up under it But it is no way it can get up to that.
Speaker 1: next level.
Speaker 0: summer wars has seven of those little leaf things on the poster.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, absolutely.
Speaker 1: It deserves even more but it's not Toy Story 3.
Speaker 1: There's no way now it can't win.
Speaker 1: There's no chance.
Speaker 1: That's like it's like oh man who's going to?
Speaker 0: who's gonna win the ae86 or the ae85?
Speaker 1: No, it's more like all right rim, you know, who are you?
Speaker 1: Who are you putting in the ring?
Speaker 1: It's like I'm putting in Mike Tyson.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: There's no way he's gonna lose.
Speaker 0: Yes, Joe too bad I got Muhammad Ali.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, then so so Toy Story 3 is Muhammad Ali Summer Wars is Mike Tyson.
Speaker 0: So is Legend of the Guardian is glass Joe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the owls.
Speaker 1: the owls is not even glass Joe.
Speaker 1: the owls is the guy from super punch-out Gabby J. Yay All right.
Speaker 1: Oh Interesting thing right?
Speaker 1: Apparently there is a French Japanese thing going on.
Speaker 1: It's pay.
Speaker 1: It's some anime paid for by France's l'institut national de prevention de education, which is the National Institute That was the best French accent I ever heard preventative and health education.
Speaker 1: And basically they wanted to make a 10-minute don't smoke kids anime.
Speaker 1: So they got studio 4c to do it all high quality.
Speaker 1: Whoa And it's gonna be pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: I imagine I think you can actually watch it on the Internet's.
Speaker 1: yeah the complete short titled the attraction is now available at a website and it's got dubbed into Japanese or French and Then you get an English subtitles.
Speaker 1: Ooh So there you go.
Speaker 0: It saddens me that I think I still understand French more than I understand Japanese.
Speaker 1: What's interesting about this right is is two things.
Speaker 1: number one, right is like, okay They've got you know, usually stuff that's like don't smoke kids or don't do drugs.
Speaker 1: It's like low production value like remember all those raps from the 90s That'd be like, you know, don't do?
Speaker 1: they were the lowest when I was second grade value.
Speaker 0: I discovered that there was a place in the school library where you could check out instead of a book a movie Whoa, and I was like, oh man, and I saw this one called fast forward future Whoa, and I was like, this is gonna be awesome.
Speaker 0: It was Possibly the most pathetic anti-drug hour-long movie I've ever witnessed.
Speaker 1: Yes, I mean so but imagine if say they paid like Steven Spielberg to make an anti-drug movie, right?
Speaker 1: That would be like.
Speaker 1: no one does that everyone.
Speaker 1: I feel like there's a joke I could make or they got actual like in the 70s.
Speaker 0: I feel like I could have said he did it was called and said the name of some movie.
Speaker 0: that would have been what it.
Speaker 1: What if they actually made like Star Wars?
Speaker 1: Like like as good as episode four or five six anti-drug movie.
Speaker 0: well in Episode one he did say you shouldn't smoke because they were what cancer sticks or something.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was episode one not four or five six.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess it wasn't Star Wars Here.
Speaker 1: they basically got some of the best animes there are right, you know studio 4c To work on a 10-minute long don't smoke thing.
Speaker 1: So that that in alone is pretty awesome, right?
Speaker 1: The second thing that I find this really interesting is like smoking is actually as big a problem as it is here in.
Speaker 1: Oh in France in Japan in Japan, it's the worst everybody's and you can just smoke everywhere.
Speaker 1: You can smoke in your house.
Speaker 1: You can smoke in the restaurant.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It makes me not want to go there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even DC apparently, you know where we were at the rally, right?
Speaker 0: We went to a restaurant and well We thought it was a restaurant.
Speaker 0: They're like smoking or not and we're like what?
Speaker 0: because apparently if it's also a bar they can have a smoking section.
Speaker 0: So we left and we found another restaurant that didn't have that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we found a restaurant.
Speaker 0: There wasn't a bar.
Speaker 1: All right, but it's weird in New York City, like almost every restaurant you go to has a bar in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah anyway So what I you know, I thought was really interesting about this is right.
Speaker 1: I was like, I'm wondering how many cuz it takes a lot of people to animate something, right?
Speaker 0: So I'm like how many of those people were smoking?
Speaker 1: How many of these guys a studio 4c who worked on this animation smoke?
Speaker 1: Right and how ironic is that these non-smoking people these smokers made this non-smoke.
Speaker 0: it would not be ironic.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't know one of them quit smoking because they made this.
Speaker 1: I don't know if any of them do or don't you know, I mean they could all be non-smokers.
Speaker 1: It's entirely possible, but the odds are in these countries where smoking is just so prevalent.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: I did read a study.
Speaker 0: I read the abstract of the study.
Speaker 0: It was a couple months ago talking about how American cigarettes are actually Particularly more dangerous than cigarettes the entire rest of the world.
Speaker 0: Yeah because of the way they're made.
Speaker 1: Well, I think I think part actually part of the reason they make them that way right is a because burn more addictive cheaper more And the regulation isn't there but also because they're restricted.
Speaker 1: So I there are a lot less restricted in other places, right?
Speaker 1: It's not like 18 plus, right?
Speaker 1: So for if they could just sell them to kids or to younger people as they can and of many other places.
Speaker 1: Right, then they wouldn't need to make a more addictive because they get you early.
Speaker 1: So you're already addicted to just the regular amount of nicotine.
Speaker 1: but because because they're gonna get you so late They got to up the ante to.
Speaker 0: you know Japan also has the workaholic culture that I think drives the smoking pretty heavily.
Speaker 1: Well, it's also Francis France because they let people smoke anywhere, right?
Speaker 1: You're just exposed to it all the time.
Speaker 1: So it's a lot of you, right?
Speaker 0: So yeah, that's a catch-22 because if you're exposed to it everywhere, then no individual person is gonna be like, yeah Yeah, I mean it's just.
Speaker 1: it's a whole problem and you know, we should just ban it outright.
Speaker 1: You should only be allowed to smoke.
Speaker 1: I mean Smoke in your house if no one's around who doesn't consent.
Speaker 1: I'm fine with the way New York's doing it because the new laws I want to get it out of the sidewalk and out of the park.
Speaker 0: Ah, so the new laws that are basically crazily popular that are probably gonna pass also in addition to all the existing bands in New York City will ban smoking in boardwalks parks and any public plaza sidewalk.
Speaker 1: It's not banning the sidewalk.
Speaker 1: No, it is banned within 100 feet of any door and now I should be on the sidewalk all sidewalks period.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway So things of the day Emily showed me this and it was pretty badass.
Speaker 0: You can watch the whole thing on YouTube.
Speaker 0: This is a 2007 animated short by a Russian animation studio.
Speaker 1: Called the dog door was the guy who made it is his name Sergei.
Speaker 0: No No Oh That's terrible.
Speaker 0: Scott Gregory But Animos Studios Rasputin and it's actually based on a novel but it's.
Speaker 0: there's two YouTube videos.
Speaker 0: It's like ten minutes long.
Speaker 0: It's beautiful and while depressing it is as depressing as you could expect a Russian animation about dogs To be.
Speaker 1: does it have pockner styling?
Speaker 0: Uh No, it just has a really kind of like painted.
Speaker 0: You'll see it's a really Disappointed.
Speaker 1: how hot is he?
Speaker 0: it's about a bunch of dogs living it, you know village was destroyed and they're kind of feral and on their own and they're looking For the mythical dog door that it's kind of like, you know, I'll tell you where the mythical dog door is.
Speaker 1: You know, it is novel.
Speaker 0: it's basically the Russian equivalent of Wolf's reign only it does really close rain.
Speaker 1: It's not the it's not the the equivalent of like.
Speaker 1: all dogs go to heaven.
Speaker 0: What about all dogs go to heaven?
Speaker 1: - oh, what about Lady and the Tramp?
Speaker 0: the Tramp I think was a good movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was good.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen it in like 30 30 in like 20 years.
Speaker 1: It's actually I like it.
Speaker 1: Um, what's the other ones?
Speaker 0: Whatever I forget the other one the other once.
Speaker 1: there are all kinds of those like in our day.
Speaker 1: They're like ten different anime.
Speaker 1: You mean animated movies mean like the aristocats.
Speaker 1: No, there was one.
Speaker 1: it was like, you know the old dog and the in the puffy But I had names and then their names are the name of the movie.
Speaker 0: how about the fox and the hound?
Speaker 1: that's a good one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, one wasn't a fox.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I highly recommend one with a dog with sunglasses.
Speaker 0: watch the dog door.
Speaker 1: All right, the dog door is a good title.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like that.
Speaker 1: It's really say that in Pockner ease I have no idea.
Speaker 0: I can't read Cyrillic.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry Pockner.
Speaker 0: ish people Lebignon be pickin top in Denver Oblin.
Speaker 0: oh, oh I don't know if that's the name of it or if that's job a dummy.
Speaker 1: translate it for you something someone said.
Speaker 1: no You know, here's what it means.
Speaker 0: ready It was put up by the federal agency of culture and cinematography or the.
Speaker 0: we got to stop making fun of Russia.
Speaker 0: the oh, yeah Pana boho are a hit a boho.
Speaker 0: No crip.
Speaker 0: Oh type Nen the mechanism.
Speaker 1: Torpedo I'm just getting back at you for Francis listen to national day.
Speaker 1: So anyway this was.
Speaker 1: I saw a link to this early this morning and obviously it's sold out now, but Somewhat, you know rim when we lived in Beacon we had one refrigerator.
Speaker 1: We did have one refrigerator had all his magnets on it.
Speaker 1: I did and now we live in New York and you know who took all the magnets.
Speaker 0: my refrigerator doesn't even have a thing to Put magnets on it.
Speaker 1: You took all my goddamn man.
Speaker 1: You took the pac-man magnets.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're right here.
Speaker 0: You want him?
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: You can let me have I don't care.
Speaker 1: Okay, I want him.
Speaker 1: Yeah Anyway rim took all the magnets.
Speaker 1: so when I saw this I was like, oh fuck I'm buying that.
Speaker 1: but of course it's sold out.
Speaker 1: But anyway, you should see it wait.
Speaker 0: So you're thinking the day is something that everyone will want and no one will be able to get.
Speaker 1: hopefully this person will make another Bad.
Speaker 0: this is very reminiscent of back in the day when we did our panel Manga, you should read and we realized that 90% of it was not a print.
Speaker 1: You can still get it.
Speaker 1: Anyway It's on Etsy.
Speaker 1: This person named Kong's cut made some magnets for Minecraft.
Speaker 1: It's Minecraft magnets as a magnet for every kind of type of tile wood tree iron stone water lava lava.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have any animals.
Speaker 1: Here you got 18 stone 8 sand and dirt 7 leaves 6 grass 4 coal 2 water 2 clay 2 iron 2 tree trunks a diamond a redstone a mossy cobblestone a lava and a gold right?
Speaker 1: 64 magnets in total.
Speaker 1: The price was.
Speaker 1: did the price disappear?
Speaker 1: the shipping price was five dollars.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the actual item price was.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I would have paid a lot for this.
Speaker 0: Well, uh eBay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but basically we just got to wait for him to make another batch And then I'll be on that and plus his minecraft magnet set and it specifically says number one environment.
Speaker 1: so I imagine number two is gonna be all sorts of creepers and weapons and You know all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: All right, so is it?
Speaker 1: you know, you could have a lot more fun in your fridge with this.
Speaker 0: I want your fortress magnets.
Speaker 1: No, you don't.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do Plus, you know, you could always print your own magnets of this pretty easily right.
Speaker 1: you go to any magnet printer.
Speaker 1: They're just one by one inch squares.
Speaker 1: You already have the sprites in the game.
Speaker 1: You just copy and paste them right out of there and you're good to go.
Speaker 1: But this guy did it for you and he seems to be you know skilled at it.
Speaker 1: He knows whatever you need to know to get magnets printed properly.
Speaker 0: So so very briefly the meta moment.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be a Pax East Pax West probably anime Boston.
Speaker 0: We'll see about Otakon magfest.
Speaker 1: yes, the book club book is World War Z by Max Brooks and We are going to talk about it on the next Thursday episode of you guys.
Speaker 1: However, the next week after this current week is thanks to giving gobble gobble Go and we might just put it up as its own thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we don't know.
Speaker 1: So what will happen with that episode?
Speaker 1: it will be out as the next.
Speaker 1: you know Time.
Speaker 1: we're gonna do it.
Speaker 1: But will it be next Thursday?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: that's Thanksgiving So we'll see exactly when that will be but it will be soon.
Speaker 1: So read the book be it will.
Speaker 1: Also, it's Thanksgiving.
Speaker 1: if you would like to make me a geeky cornucopia I will again ask you kindly do we have the fan art section up on the side to show off the old cornucopia?
Speaker 1: Oh, no, right.
Speaker 1: I'll make it real quick.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you have some good cornucopias.
Speaker 1: They were actually really only two good cornucopias and the only really good one is the one with booze coming out of it.
Speaker 0: Oh way to really make the person who made the other cornucopia feel bad.
Speaker 1: Come on You just look at him and it's sort of obvious.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't remember what it was.
Speaker 1: I don't remember the other one over the boo one.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we need better and more cornucopias of geekiness.
Speaker 1: like pretend it's Photoshop Friday and it's like Photoshop this cornucopia and Add geekiness to it.
Speaker 0: or dicks geeky dicks Please don't.
Speaker 0: I don't think we ever did a show on Looney Tunes.
Speaker 1: I'm free.
Speaker 1: We might have discussed them as part of some show way back.
Speaker 0: We were like cartoons of our youth, but that was all he-man thunder.
Speaker 1: I think we actually did mention Looney Tunes in it.
Speaker 1: But why the hell not devote a whole show to something so important that I and the thing?
Speaker 1: other reason is not only is it?
Speaker 1: Very important and very awesome.
Speaker 1: I think it has actually been sort of neglected and forgotten.
Speaker 0: Well, I was looking around on YouTube and many of the classics were not easily available for free just online.
Speaker 1: No You gotta buy them on DVD or just a lot of money.
Speaker 0: and I was poking around Netflix and those and more importantly all the old Disney Equivalents like the Donald Duck cartoons and everything also really only available on DVD.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and none of them are in the Netflix streaming.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I think the worst thing about it though Is that I mean when we were kids you would come home and you would watch cartoons Or you watch cartoons on Saturday morning and the thing was there would all the cartoons that you watched would change over time.
Speaker 1: Right, you know, it would be Transformers and Voltron But then it would be Thundercats and then that Thundercats would go away and then you'd have pup name Scooby Doo And they'd keep cycling in and out.
Speaker 1: but from the time that I was very young like three To the time that you know, pretty much my entire childhood life.
Speaker 1: I was 18 Looney Tunes always had a time slot whether it was Cartoon Network or Nickelodeon or ABC Saturday Morning or something.
Speaker 1: there was cartoon slots and Looney Tunes always had a spot in there Somewhere, you know pretty much after that It was Rocky and Bullwinkle always had a slot somewhere most of the time.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 1: more important Looney Tunes always had a slot all the time.
Speaker 0: when I think back to watching Looney Tunes versus other cartoons I would never really want to watch an episode of like a pup named Scooby Doo more than once Exactly.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'd get stuck watching it twice because it was on and there was nothing else to do.
Speaker 0: But I pretty much never got sick of the good Looney Tunes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean that you could.
Speaker 1: it was refused reruns all the time, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz after a couple years if you're a kid you would seen them all.
Speaker 1: I mean, I've seen everything from Bosco The way through.
Speaker 1: I don't think you could find a Looney Tune all the way up to like Space Jam, right?
Speaker 1: So I don't think you could find something unless it was newer than Space Jam or older than Bosco that I have not seen Right.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean it depends.
Speaker 0: if we're just talking Looney Tunes merit melodies versus if you zoom out to count like the Max Fleischer stuff Tom and Jerry Doesn't count.
Speaker 1: the thing is those are all in the same time slots.
Speaker 1: we saw all those as well.
Speaker 1: All right, thanks Avery.
Speaker 1: We saw all of it, right?
Speaker 1: You know takes Avery had it.
Speaker 1: There was a text.
Speaker 1: Avery hour on fucking Cartoon Network for the longest time Scott because I know the answer to this.
Speaker 0: I think everyone who knows us knows the answer to this.
Speaker 0: It's your favorite Looney Tunes episode.
Speaker 1: Oh, you're you're I don't know how I know it, but I know you don't even know.
Speaker 1: you don't even know it.
Speaker 0: No, because I know you I was gonna quote it.
Speaker 0: I was I was modifying it.
Speaker 1: Oh, he's hiding in the store Just the line.
Speaker 0: when the dude comes on this stove he just coming.
Speaker 0: he'd be like, I know he's done it.
Speaker 1: That wasn't the same episode.
Speaker 1: nobody was the same character wasn't carries that the thing is the episode with the stove is the superior Episode to the one with the the closet right which is that I don't know how he's done at one.
Speaker 0: I actually prefer that one.
Speaker 1: No, the the stove one is is the best one by far anyway.
Speaker 1: So yeah, these things were on TV no matter what every kid knew him.
Speaker 1: every kid saw him, right?
Speaker 1: It was sort of like for me.
Speaker 1: It was a lot like Batman the animated series, right?
Speaker 1: It's like they were sir.
Speaker 1: It was weird.
Speaker 1: my whole like.
Speaker 1: there were things that I would be really enthusiastic about right like it back.
Speaker 1: Oh fuck.
Speaker 1: Yes Thundercats Yeah, but it was only on for a short period and meanwhile there were things which were just always there staples Right, and I never got sick of them, but I also never looked forward to them.
Speaker 0: I see it's like shit bugs bunnies coming on but bugs money would be on and it would be awesome always Yeah, and sort of like.
Speaker 1: it's same thing with food, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know bread is awesome, right?
Speaker 1: But you have bread every day.
Speaker 1: So it's like bread and steak.
Speaker 1: you have like once a week once a month Maybe right not it's rare but steak.
Speaker 1: You're like, oh it better be rare, right?
Speaker 1: But you're like, oh fuck Yeah steak, right, but you never.
Speaker 1: yeah, it's not until we're adults and we're wiser and we look back and we go Oh, yeah, right, you know, it's like when you have bread every day.
Speaker 1: It's just like bread.
Speaker 1: Looney Tunes is like that.
Speaker 1: It was just like Looney Tunes.
Speaker 0: part of it with Looney Tunes Is that the?
Speaker 0: I mean, especially you know, the original Looney Tunes and Mary Malick.
Speaker 0: You know They were like.
Speaker 0: quality was all over the place in those kinds of cartoons later on.
Speaker 0: Remember those weird like late 80s Tom and Jerry?
Speaker 1: Well, Tom and Jerry isn't Looney Tunes either.
Speaker 0: No it isn't, but I said those like that whole Cartoons like that.
Speaker 0: They got into weird eras, but Looney Tunes is pretty consistent and the early.
Speaker 1: There are some Looney Tunes that are not as good But you know most and some of them repeat the same jokes and you would totally see they repeated the same joke, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know the good ones were beyond good, you know.
Speaker 0: But it was mostly that the production values were way high because those things are Ancients.
Speaker 0: they were made for theaters.
Speaker 1: That was that's the one thing that like get.
Speaker 1: that was the reason that they were able to be on TV right for all.
Speaker 1: that time is because if you looked and it always confused the hell out of me because I was like Weren't these things made it like the 40s or even older than that and these are really old right.
Speaker 1: but that you look at them They look way better than any cartoon.
Speaker 1: Then you look at like Scooby-doo from the 60s or 70s and you're like Why is this Scooby-doo?
Speaker 1: look like shit and Don this Donald Duck cartoon from a hundred years ago looks amazing, right?
Speaker 1: Because these things are made for movie theaters.
Speaker 1: I these are.
Speaker 1: this is film right and then they were just put on TV later, you know Some of them were made for TV later years, you know, but well, they're all great.
Speaker 0: There are those weird really like they would make movie compilations of cartoons.
Speaker 0: There were all kinds of different formats but Daffy Duck and Speedy Gonzales ones Yeah, but awful.
Speaker 1: a good number of them were actually, you know made for theaters And they ran in front of actual movies.
Speaker 1: You would go to the theater to see an actual movie and before the actual movie started you would see a Looney Tune And then the movie would start right.
Speaker 1: and nowadays They only really do that if you go to see something like Space Jam, right where there's a loop a Looney Tunes stick going on.
Speaker 1: And actually if I made movies I kind of want to make movies for Warner Brothers just so I could Get them to make a Looney Tune in front of every movie I make no matter what movie.
Speaker 1: it is Not that I'm ever gonna make a movie But I really think they need to bring that back where every movie you watch as a serial before it or something before it You know, that's we got to bring that back in a big way.
Speaker 1: It's awesome.
Speaker 1: So, yeah Looney Tunes is wicked awesome and it's sad that is not really like from what I don't watch TV obviously But I'm pretty sure they're not really on TV anymore Like you have to watch like the boomerang channel to see them.
Speaker 1: I mean even then I don't know how much they're on there.
Speaker 0: Here's my question.
Speaker 0: Is that really true or do we just not watch TV?
Speaker 1: I'm pretty.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure that they're not on TV like every single day like they were when we were kids.
Speaker 0: You know it well, some of them are not on TV because they're little.
Speaker 1: that was also upsetting.
Speaker 1: It's like at some point during our childhoods.
Speaker 1: They took off like speedy Gonzales disappeared.
Speaker 0: granted I watched some speedy Gonzales again and and Bosco disappeared pretty racist.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it you know, I mean, it's not bad It's just you know, right?
Speaker 0: Well, it's it's bad for what it is But at the same time you don't ban the old works just because the world sucked back then.
Speaker 0: I know right just present them with context.
Speaker 1: It's like Nazi Disney, right?
Speaker 1: You know why you banning that shit or song of the south?
Speaker 1: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: That's the best example.
Speaker 0: That is a really racist movie.
Speaker 1: song of the south is awesome though.
Speaker 0: It is a good movie All right, at least I. I have not seen it since I was a very young child.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think you have to take the same approach that you take with the Tezuka's and all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: even Tintin right a lot, you know gives me Tezuka wasn't racist, but some of his depictions were racist depictions.
Speaker 1: But that's just was the style of the times and they put a note in front of all the his manga that have that You know some bad stylings in it Like look as it goes the exact opposite of racist, but that was the style of the time.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna edit it, you know, but you know, why would should we hide history?
Speaker 1: We in fact, that would be a disservice, you know We need to look at the racism of the past and that is how we know not to make that mistake again If we just wipe it off the head of history, that's even worse.
Speaker 1: Right then, you know making it prominent like look at the horrible racism of the past.
Speaker 1: You need to remember that the world was that way.
Speaker 1: so we don't go back to that way.
Speaker 1: if we just erase it.
Speaker 1: It's like that that's that's not a good idea.
Speaker 1: And the thing is even in cases like Tintin right where you know.
Speaker 1: There's actually probably a reason to believe least some reasons to believe that you know her gay was actually kind of racist.
Speaker 1: You know unlike Tezuka, you still shouldn't be censoring it, you know.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I think that you should still have Speedy Gonzalez, even though he is racist.
Speaker 0: Actually, I think one of my favorite ones overall as an adult and looking back is the kill the web killed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean all day.
Speaker 1: there were certain ones that were just you know Like the the ones that you could tell they put like the extra double effort into right the ones that stood out Right, you know like the opera one.
Speaker 1: I forget the name of it You know cuz it's got like and you could tell they were even better animated since some of the other ones, right?
Speaker 1: Well, how about the one with with Porky and Daffy in the hotel and the hotel guy who wants to Is Right or the bad?
Speaker 0: as a kid that one kind of scared me because it was weird and like.
Speaker 0: I was unnerved because a Lot of the things you wouldn't let him leave the hotel until they pay and a lot of the things that happen like.
Speaker 0: it's interesting watching old cartoons like that or like the ones that are set on farms where they kind of assume a lot of knowledge in the viewers about farm life or About the way the world worked back then.
Speaker 0: that just doesn't apply at all anymore.
Speaker 1: I mean some.
Speaker 0: it's like it's weird because on the one hand that hotel manager scared the crap out of me when I was.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some of the Looney Tunes stand up so well because they are timeless, right?
Speaker 1: But But some of them actually are not timeless.
Speaker 1: Right, like a lot of them will make jokes about famous people from a zillion years ago the same time I get the jokes, but a lot of people don't at the same time.
Speaker 0: Look at a lot of those old cartoons.
Speaker 0: It wasn't until Brett like in the last several years that I actually learned who Peter Laurie was But I recognized Peter Laurie through most of my life because he was.
Speaker 0: it was that face and that voice in the cartoons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean there were.
Speaker 0: I mean how many kids even when we were kids knew who Groucho Marx was and yet they found Bugs Bunny hilarious.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are thousands of graduate marks references in there like all the time.
Speaker 0: Right also know how Bugs Bunny was kind of Metrosexual little weird and a jerk.
Speaker 1: Yeah cross-dresser, you know, but the thing is Bugs Bunny.
Speaker 1: I don't know how he became like the pride like the primary guy, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you look at Disney and Mickey Mouse is the number one guy.
Speaker 1: But you know how he became the number one guy is because he was the first guy not because they used him a lot or Anything like that.
Speaker 1: It's cuz he was the first guy right.
Speaker 1: they say, you know, I mean you look at like Marvel Comics, right?
Speaker 1: Why is spider-man the guy?
Speaker 1: it's actually Fantastic Four was the first guys, right?
Speaker 1: Spider-man was after that but it was you know, spider-man was the one that was the huge hit, right?
Speaker 1: But it's like was big.
Speaker 1: was Bugs Bunny the first?
Speaker 0: yeah, not really.
Speaker 1: No, there was.
Speaker 1: there were there were.
Speaker 1: they were making cartoons before they came out there making cartoons.
Speaker 0: But I thought we were just talking about Looney Tunes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there were cart there were not.
Speaker 1: there were Looney Tunes with other non Bugs Bunny characters before Bosco.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even though you know, there are other ones right?
Speaker 1: He was not the first.
Speaker 1: very first one was not Bugs Bunny, right?
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure that.
Speaker 1: and on top of that was Bugs Bunny really the big hit I think.
Speaker 1: so cuz I mean if he was the hit.
Speaker 1: I'm like wow, you know Cuz he was the hit with another generation right?
Speaker 1: not our generation cuz I. Bugs Bunny was not my favorite guy.
Speaker 0: Who's your favorite guy?
Speaker 1: There was Daffy Duck my favorite guy.
Speaker 0: I really liked Daffy Duck cuz.
Speaker 0: he was such a just a goddamn asshole But he wasn't funny about it likes Bugs Bunny.
Speaker 0: He was just a jerk, but he was also crazy.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean the thing was right is like.
Speaker 0: it's kind of like an early rendition of Lewis Black in duck form.
Speaker 1: I don't know in terms of like, you know the coolness of the characters Right, like Marvin the Martian is like a cool character like, you know design and such.
Speaker 1: but in terms of like the cartoon Like if you took all of the cartoons involve it, you know and averaged them together.
Speaker 1: I like the Roadrunner ones.
Speaker 1: It was always.
Speaker 1: it was like above average every time.
Speaker 1: you know Some of the other ones like a porky pig.
Speaker 1: It could be up.
Speaker 1: It could be down.
Speaker 1: Right, some of them were better than others, but any Roadrunner is like solid, you know.
Speaker 0: There were later Roadrunners that were actually pretty crappy.
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: Like Lee?
Speaker 1: They're all the same joke every time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then they started moving like when they started.
Speaker 0: they could like the Wile E. Coyote would talk.
Speaker 0: that was only one episode retalked and I remember I never found the ones between Wile E. Coyote and the Sheepdog to be that funny.
Speaker 1: No, the Sheepdog one were not good.
Speaker 1: I'm only talking about the Roadrunner one.
Speaker 0: Okay, so just the Roadrunner.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then we're good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I actually have this like five foot tall stuffed Wile E. Coyote from like the 50s.
Speaker 0: That was my dad's.
Speaker 1: Oh really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the what, you know, which I?
Speaker 1: so which one did you like?
Speaker 1: you really did not like and do not want Did not like and did not want.
Speaker 0: There were the ones that were on TV all the time that as much as I liked them I just didn't want to watch them again Which usually was the Wile E. Coyote Roadrunner ones.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Like they were just always beyond and I'd seen like I'd seen The one where Bugs Bunny just tortures that opera singer like a hundred times.
Speaker 0: It was great, but I'd seen the Roadrunner ones like a million times.
Speaker 1: The ones that I don't like are the What's the stupid rooster's name?
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: Foghorn Leghorn?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't like Foghorn Leghorn.
Speaker 1: I love him.
Speaker 1: Those are great.
Speaker 0: And the Chickenhawk?
Speaker 1: I mean some of the Foghorn Leghorn ones.
Speaker 0: Now the thing is the thing.
Speaker 0: and now see him.
Speaker 0: Now see him.
Speaker 1: The ones where he tortures the dog, right?
Speaker 1: It was like the joke where he like would trick the dog into bumping into the fence.
Speaker 1: That was good.
Speaker 1: But like I when he was talking it's just like oh god, shut up.
Speaker 1: I can't stand him.
Speaker 1: No, he's no good.
Speaker 0: It was a good joke.
Speaker 0: It was a good shtick.
Speaker 1: No, and actually some of the ones that I did like were the Yosemite Sam on the boat with the.
Speaker 1: oh, man, they made the powder room joke No, I think.
Speaker 1: and then also the foreign legion joke.
Speaker 0: I think most people have not seen those as they were originally made Because a lot of those were added into those shitty compilation movies like Donald Duck and Speedy Gonzalez.
Speaker 1: Yeah It was actually weird right because like to actually see the Yosemite Sam on the boat or Yosemite Sam in the foreign Legion the only place I or like even some of the Tasmanian devil ones right.
Speaker 1: the only time I ever saw those was on the ABC Saturday morning, you know, like those ones, right?
Speaker 1: I never saw those on Nickelodeon.
Speaker 1: They might have been on there at some point, but I never saw.
Speaker 1: I don't remember seeing them Nickelodeon or on Cartoon Network.
Speaker 1: I only saw them on ABC Saturday morning.
Speaker 1: So it's like they were special like higher production cost ones Or something like that or newer or I don't know why they were only on that channel But at least in my day they were only on that channel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, can you can you think of any others that we may have neglected?
Speaker 0: I mean I can think of all a million.
Speaker 0: I think it's more I don't know.
Speaker 0: I feel I really have this urge to watch not just Looney Tunes but like the old Disney like Donald Duck's and Chip and Dale All that kind of old and Seen.
Speaker 1: well, I think you know, they're just first overall Donald Duck wins a car.
Speaker 1: They're just not as good as Looney Tunes.
Speaker 0: I Disagree.
Speaker 0: Donald Duck once made Huey Dewey and Louie's smoked cigars until they almost died.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was hilarious.
Speaker 1: it's not as it's not as you know, they're not as good.
Speaker 1: first of all, right and You know.
Speaker 1: the the other thing with them is that you know, they weren't they didn't have the same.
Speaker 1: You know, the production values were not quite as high and They were also.
Speaker 1: a lot of them were made for like, you know to buy on home video like the goofy sports.
Speaker 1: It's like buy this on VHS.
Speaker 0: It's like the goofy sports.
Speaker 1: However, we're brilliant Yeah, and they're alright, but it's like nobody bought those on VHS.
Speaker 1: I did you only you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we had them all in those huge like old-school clay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those big plastic clamshell things Nobody, you know, so they had a lot less reach than the.
Speaker 1: the Looney Tunes are just on all the time.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: and the Looney Tunes really the thing about it having something that's good That's on all the time.
Speaker 1: They just everyone watches without sort of realizing that they're a fan of it because it's not their focus.
Speaker 1: I think really helps to bring people together, you know more so than an individual thing.
Speaker 0: That's very popular among pop culture people.
Speaker 0: I mean American Idol is stupidly popular, but if you don't care about stupid things, you're not connected to that at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but having something that just everyone watches that's below the radar, but it's just you know pervasive, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know very for a long time.
Speaker 0: The Simpsons was like that exactly, right?
Speaker 1: It's like, you know that it brings people together much better than you know.
Speaker 1: Anything that's stupidly popular is going to be divisive actually, right?
Speaker 1: You know, it's gonna be like if you try talking about it Someone's either gonna be your best friend or they're gonna be your worst enemy, but Looney Tunes Everyone is just gonna be your regular friend.
Speaker 1: Those are is only a very few people who are that crazy.
Speaker 1: Right because by the at the point we are now right because remember think about it Looney Tunes is so old.
Speaker 1: even old people watched it even the old people grew up.
Speaker 0: I actually never liked speedy Gonzales, really?
Speaker 0: I just didn't find him funny.
Speaker 1: I mean, he wasn't as funny as the other ones, but he was.
Speaker 1: he was alright.
Speaker 0: But my favorite episode ever other than him torturing the opera guy and I just suddenly remembered it like out of nowhere.
Speaker 0: This is one of those for the brain.
Speaker 0: like suddenly found a reference.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm was haha turn duck, Perry Actually, you know what I never understood.
Speaker 1: Sylvester and Tweety really really most of them.
Speaker 1: I mean they were just sort of average always, you know That was never really like.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: I was like, oh, okay.
Speaker 1: Why didn't Roadrunner come on?
Speaker 1: And it seemed like there were just so many of them, you know, like it would always be semester
Speaker 0: I always saw the same one over and over again and it was all word that we're Sylvester and Tweety and the dog are all in the hospital with broken legs and the ladies trying to Take care of them and they keep trying to like kill each other from each other's beds.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's also because that one was part of one of those stupid compilation movies and it was always on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was an okay one.
Speaker 1: But I mean there was the.
Speaker 0: it's about that.
Speaker 0: They're trying to murder each other.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the hospital.
Speaker 1: but there was some other ones that would be like, you know It'd be the same thing every time just in a day.
Speaker 1: It was like, okay now we're in the house in the winter and To eat.
Speaker 1: he's in the birdcage the best to try to eat him.
Speaker 1: and now we're in the house in the suburbs and now we're In that different house and now the dog is there but now the dog isn't there.
Speaker 1: and now there's a mouse involved.
Speaker 1: It was just the same.
Speaker 1: You know, I was not, you know on with that.
Speaker 0: I just I always wanted Sylvester to win because I didn't like Tweety.
Speaker 1: That's another thing, right?
Speaker 1: It's like you actually look at it and it's like, you know, it's Elmer Fudd really a bad guy.
Speaker 1: He's just a hunter He's just hunting.
Speaker 1: He's not any worse than any other hunter.
Speaker 1: He's kind of dopey.
Speaker 1: He's dopey but Bugs Bunny He was actually a jerk, right?
Speaker 0: See at least Bugs Bunny I can understand why he'd be a jerk to Elmer Fudd because Elmer Fudd is trying to kill him.
Speaker 0: Sometimes that opera episode Bugs Bunny is just like he basically tortures that guy to insanity.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like sometimes he's trying to kill him But even then sometimes Bugs Bunny starts getting his revenge even before he's trying to kill him.
Speaker 1: You know or he'll like, you know, plus that gun never killed anyone.
Speaker 1: It just makes you look like, you know, you got exploded or whatever.
Speaker 1: So it's like you're basically just forcing the other guy to get shot with it.
Speaker 1: You know, some of it actually was just sort of cruel and I guess, you know, the ones that like the you know I the one I like the most the mafia one.
Speaker 1: It was actually like look these are bad mafia guys You know, it was actually.
Speaker 1: there wasn't really any cruelty and he he got them in a very clever way.
Speaker 1: Well, like Wile E.
Speaker 0: Coyote, who are you really rooting for?
Speaker 0: You wanted him to get the stupid Roadrunner.
Speaker 1: He was hungry.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the Roadrunner was just a bird It wasn't?
Speaker 1: you know that ran around really fast.
Speaker 1: It's like wow, if you can catch that fucking thing Look how fast things go.
Speaker 0: I think we're done here.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's the only moral of this episode is that if you haven't actually seen Yeah, if you're if you're younger than us that means that you know and you you know.
Speaker 1: Or maybe it means either a you don't really watch TV because TV the days of TV are over.
Speaker 1: or be Looney Tunes Just weren't pervasive throughout all you know People as they were in our day or the days before us.
Speaker 1: But it's like I feel like we should keep that thing alive because we can keep that going.
Speaker 1: That's even older than the Simpsons right?
Speaker 1: This is decades and decades old.
Speaker 0: The Simpsons is only That it's older than the Simpsons.
Speaker 1: It's like three or four times older than the Simpsons, right?
Speaker 1: So and it's all on pirate bay Yeah, if we can keep it going right and make sure that it's in everyone's consciousness, you know It's it's in everyone's brain somewhere that can be.
Speaker 1: you know, just what we need there always has to be something It doesn't matter if it's Looney Tunes or something else that everyone has in their culture that what if it was the belief in?
Speaker 0: Rationality in the than the beauty of science.
Speaker 1: That would be good - that'd be good - good luck with that.
Speaker 1: That's a lot newer than Looney Tunes.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night Like if you had a DS inside the cornucopia and on the DS there was a penis.
Speaker 1: That would be awesome.