Speaker 0: It's Monday, June 7th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm Rip.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, what if Ghost in the Shell, oh shit.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I got a new computer at work, finally.
Speaker 0: What was wrong with the computer?
Speaker 0: You had to work before?
Speaker 1: It was slow as balls.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: So I got a new one and I'm setting it all up, get my new email, and I didn't check my email for like a couple hours while I'm setting this thing up.
Speaker 1: And all my coworkers around me are laughing at something, but I'm kind of busy, so I'm going to ask them what.
Speaker 1: And I finally get my email back on.
Speaker 1: Now, I'm going to not say who these emails came from.
Speaker 1: Suffice it to say, there's some big names in the financial world, some very big individual names, and names of exchanges.
Speaker 0: Famous people know?
Speaker 0: Would these be someone normal people would know?
Speaker 1: Normal people wouldn't know, but imagine if the head of a technology group of a stock exchange was involved.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to say who.
Speaker 1: I'm not going to say who, however.
Speaker 0: There aren't that many stock exchanges.
Speaker 1: Can you name the stock exchanges in America?
Speaker 0: NASDAQ, NICE, Amex.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: No, there's more.
Speaker 0: What about bats?
Speaker 0: Do you want me to do foreign ones?
Speaker 1: No, what about bats?
Speaker 0: I don't know what bats is.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: NASDAQ was not a stock exchange until surprisingly recently.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, there's also, I can do foreign ones.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so basically what happened here was I get an email.
Speaker 1: In fact, as far as I can tell, pretty much every tech in the financial world got the same email and it was someone inside of an unnamed company who obviously had opened a ticket with some other unnamed company and they were at, they were having questions about this, uh, an upcoming technological issue.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to be vague because I don't want to get in trouble for talking about the specifics, but basically there's an upcoming change and there's this little email chain and somebody responds and he's like, yeah, that doesn't really answer my question.
Speaker 1: I think I need more information, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 1: He must've done the famous reply to all instead of simply reply.
Speaker 1: And the party involved that had originally addressed the issue did not have any protection on their internal mailing lists.
Speaker 1: So his reply to all, as far as I can tell, went to every high level technology worker in the financial sector in the United States.
Speaker 1: This is a big fucking email chain and you're, you're a tech, you've been in that situation where some jackass replies to all and then someone else starts replying to all and then the third person's like, I don't want to get these emails anymore, but they reply to all and then someone else does and it just goes on forever.
Speaker 1: So this was actually the two moments of hilarious.
Speaker 0: If you don't want to get them anymore, click the market spam button.
Speaker 1: So after the filter expanding the two hilarious moments, one, the director of a big department at a very large company respond, replied to all and basically said, I'm a very busy person and I really shouldn't be receiving these emails.
Speaker 1: You're clogging up my inbox, so please stop it.
Speaker 1: And immediately, immediately some other guy from some other company responds and is like, yes, I concur.
Speaker 1: But what took the cake was that the guy who originally did this obviously realized he had done fucked up.
Speaker 0: Oh, he realized it.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: So he replied to all and he's like, I'm sorry, I made a mistake.
Speaker 1: Now, nevermind the fact that they're all continuing to reply to all.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: And someone else in his company replied to all to say, yeah, also it was a mistake.
Speaker 1: Please just no one respond and this will just be done.
Speaker 1: But then the big up who had replied to everyone happened to be the same company as the person who fucked up in the first place.
Speaker 1: And there's all spiraled and spiraled and I don't even know where it left because I eventually left work and it was still going on.
Speaker 1: But my favorite moment was not this executive lady.
Speaker 0: You should have just replied to all like you had all the email addresses, right?
Speaker 1: I had the lists, right?
Speaker 0: So take the list of email addresses, make a new email from like a Gmail account that goes to all those email addresses and put up goat C or something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: The industry I work in, the FBI would be knocking on my door.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't do it for goat C. Goats.
Speaker 0: He's not against the law.
Speaker 0: It is not illegal to email someone goat C.
Speaker 1: I could probably get in trouble nonetheless because because the mailing list, it's complicated.
Speaker 1: The way the mailing list works, I would get in trouble.
Speaker 0: All right, well how, what if you emailed a little cat?
Speaker 0: So all that aside, that's not, it's definitely not illegal.
Speaker 1: My favorite, but what I just, you know, we're at work, we're like, what's the best thing we could do?
Speaker 1: And I suggested, why don't we send an outlook meeting notice to all meet up in Bryant Park and have lunch together.
Speaker 0: Is everyone in New York or were there people on the list?
Speaker 0: Not in the whole world.
Speaker 1: As far as I can tell, one of my other coworkers, like I should just put my resume, see what happens.
Speaker 1: Other guy was like, I should just put a personal ad up right now.
Speaker 0: Well, did that have any ladies on the list?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't even know.
Speaker 1: But my favorite moment was some guy from some like third yet unmentioned company who responded well after things was going on, who was like, yeah, you know, everyone says they don't want to receive these emails.
Speaker 1: But frankly, I also have this question that was raised originally and I'd really like to know the answers.
Speaker 1: So could we keep everyone in the loop?
Speaker 1: Now I got to tell all of you people who have ever been in one of these situations, if you ever replied all in a situation where that has already started, you're a jackass.
Speaker 1: You do not deserve email.
Speaker 1: You're only no, no, no.
Speaker 0: I think that unless you prank them all, there's nothing wrong with replying to all in that situation.
Speaker 0: In fact, it's awesome.
Speaker 0: And if you are someone who can't just make a mail filter, you shouldn't be using it differently.
Speaker 1: There are two kinds of people who reply to all people who have no business using email and people like us who are trolling everybody else.
Speaker 0: You, if you don't know how to make an email filter or mark something as spam, then this is pretty much inevitably going to happen to you and you need to be able to deal with it.
Speaker 0: Otherwise you shouldn't be using email.
Speaker 1: The real trouble is that this only happens because pretty much everyone responding to this list clearly has some sort of failing of understanding and technology in some manner.
Speaker 1: A lot of the emails were surprisingly poorly formed.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry.
Speaker 1: You are confused and such like that.
Speaker 0: You know, for example, I bet you a lot of money, right?
Speaker 0: Like Steve Jobs, everyone knows his email address is like sjobs@apple.com, right?
Speaker 0: I bet he doesn't have another email address.
Speaker 0: I bet that's the only one.
Speaker 0: And you know what he probably does?
Speaker 0: He probably has a filter that says if the sender is from at apple.com, meaning it's an employee, right?
Speaker 0: Or then delete it.
Speaker 0: Or if it's from someone on this contact list, you know, wife, kids, et cetera, right?
Speaker 0: Then bring it in the invite, right?
Speaker 0: Otherwise put it in the separate folder and his iPhone probably only goes to when someone on his contact list emails him, you know, which probably includes like other CEOs and other important people, right?
Speaker 0: And he doesn't need to have a separate email address or keep any secrets or anything like that.
Speaker 0: And then when he wants to, when he's bored, he can go and he can click, you know, intentionally on the customer email folder, which is probably flooded.
Speaker 0: and you know, just look at the subject lines and just see if there's anything fun in there.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like an RSS feed.
Speaker 0: It's like, Oh, that one looks cool.
Speaker 0: Let's see what's in there.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I'll reply to, you know, it's like a little pastime when he's bored instead of playing Farmville, you know?
Speaker 1: I mean like all the emails you guys send us to geek nights, they go into my email account, I can read them, but they don't make my phone buzz.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So that's, you know, if you don't know how to do email like that, you shouldn't be using email.
Speaker 1: It's the same situation, the same, you know, people use Gmail basically stopped having to deal with spam because the spam filters are so good.
Speaker 0: I would reply to all with a tutorial on making outlook filters.
Speaker 0: I mean, outlook has it right there in the left hand sidebar, rules, rules, and actions.
Speaker 0: It's a top level item there.
Speaker 1: I know for a fact that a good number of the people on that list use Lotus Notes.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: That's a much more powerful engine.
Speaker 0: Lotus Notes can do it even better than Outlook.
Speaker 1: That's one thing I can say about Lotus Notes because I'm one of those people who use Lotus.
Speaker 1: You know, I worked at IBM.
Speaker 1: I use Lotus Notes for like three years.
Speaker 1: It has a lot of pros.
Speaker 1: Like Outlook is good at what it does.
Speaker 1: Lotus is a lot more powerful in the end user's hands, but it also gives them much more rope with which to fuck themselves.
Speaker 1: So anyway, I guess we can't get around talking about fricking Apple and their new renouncements about phones.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I think we really need to go through like everything that was announced because...
Speaker 0: No, why would you need to do... Anyone can go and look it up.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: You guys don't come to us for the news because it's at least four hours after the news happens that we talk about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So let me just, let me just, you know, remember the things.
Speaker 0: So first of all...
Speaker 1: Farmville.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: It's the end of the world.
Speaker 0: Basically...
Speaker 1: I think Farmville is already on the downswing.
Speaker 0: I don't know about that.
Speaker 0: I don't know about that at all.
Speaker 1: I just, I have this feeling.
Speaker 1: It's hard to say.
Speaker 0: It's higher than Bejeweled.
Speaker 0: It's like, it's like shit.
Speaker 0: And as soon as now that people can play it when they're walking around, right, they're going to play it even more.
Speaker 0: And then there's going to be people who didn't play it before, but now because you had to like sit at a computer or Facebook or something, but now Farmville is going to be its own app.
Speaker 0: So these people who just have iPhones or whatever, iPod touches can just play Farmville while sitting on the couch, laying back and they can just play it as they walk around town.
Speaker 1: See now, that is an entirely, it's a fine point, but I'm going to make a highly generalized, possibly offensive counterpoint.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: You ready for this?
Speaker 1: A little bit offensive possibly, but I, I'm pulling this out of my butt and I'm, this is just me speculating a hundred percent.
Speaker 1: I did not mean to offend anyone.
Speaker 1: I will put forth supposition the first.
Speaker 1: The majority of people who play Farmville regularly are not terribly wealthy.
Speaker 0: I don't mean, yeah, but I would say that on average you can afford three kids to go to college.
Speaker 1: I would say on average, the people who are most susceptible to a game like Farmville are people who don't have a lot going on in their lives.
Speaker 1: I mean, on average, like many people, you know, the kinds of people are like, they're sitting there and they just need a serotonin boost constantly and they're on Facebook and their friend sends them a poke and then they make the farm and all that BS.
Speaker 1: I don't think there is that big of an overlap between current iPhone owners in the current economy and the people who are seriously actually addicted to Farmville.
Speaker 0: Yes, but maybe the Farmville people will buy iPhones and maybe the iPhone people will start playing Farmville.
Speaker 0: Now, my guess is that a large number of people who play Farmville and remember like the top selling app on iPhone was like fart machine.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So machine is universal.
Speaker 0: No, it's the same as Farmville.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing, though.
Speaker 0: They might as well call it far.
Speaker 1: So we're sitting in a restaurant, right?
Speaker 1: And you got your iPhone out and someone has an iPhone out and they just use the fart machine.
Speaker 1: You would laugh at least a little bit.
Speaker 1: Tiny amusement happens.
Speaker 0: No, it's more like they're sitting there, they're playing Farmville and they say, hey, I got some corn.
Speaker 0: You want some?
Speaker 0: You want some brick?
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh, shit.
Speaker 1: In fact, I would argue that fart machine is more of a game than Farmville because fart machine at least causes who farted to happen.
Speaker 0: Now it's a really bad.
Speaker 1: Well, it's like who Farmville?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't think this is going to be nearly as bad as a lot of people are making it out to be, because I don't think the people who are most affected by Farmville are the same people who in the next year or two will have an iPad.
Speaker 0: The things I think are most notable are, A, they didn't announce anything but the iPhone 4.
Speaker 0: They didn't announce a single thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: What about all your speculation?
Speaker 0: There was no Safari.
Speaker 0: There was no standalone touch pad.
Speaker 0: There was no nothing.
Speaker 1: The iPad mini, the iPad nano.
Speaker 1: It's called the touch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was.
Speaker 0: Well, no, but they didn't have a single thing except the phone.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And all the stuff that they had was in the phone.
Speaker 1: They didn't announce Verizon.
Speaker 0: No, well, that's not going to happen.
Speaker 0: I can pretty much guarantee that.
Speaker 0: But the the one thing that I think the overall thing here is that, well, look, every other phone still sucks.
Speaker 0: Yes, Apple is evil.
Speaker 0: It's closed, whatever.
Speaker 0: It's, you know, this is bad.
Speaker 0: This is bad.
Speaker 0: But every other phone sucks a dick compared to the iPhone.
Speaker 1: It depends on what you're looking to do.
Speaker 1: I mean, I still I like the form factor of the somewhat smaller smartphones compared to the iPhone.
Speaker 0: The iPhone is smaller than all the other smartphones.
Speaker 1: Not smaller than my pre.
Speaker 0: Have you looked at the size comparisons?
Speaker 1: I'm not talking about thickness.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about height and width.
Speaker 0: What do you need more or less height and width for like a tiny smartphone?
Speaker 1: I carry my phone everywhere, but I carry it like in my pocket while I'm running.
Speaker 0: Mine fits in my pocket while I'm running.
Speaker 1: It's bigger than mine, though.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, it's it's it's.
Speaker 0: it doesn't matter how big it just matters.
Speaker 0: You know what the whether that size affects anything.
Speaker 0: You could have an iPhone in your pocket and run.
Speaker 0: It would be no different.
Speaker 0: It would not.
Speaker 0: I you know, the size is not really that important either.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: It's not so much.
Speaker 1: I mean, while the iPhone, the new iPhone and even the older iPhones do a lot of things very well compared to other smartphones.
Speaker 1: And while the lack of openness really right now only affects people like us who ravel about it and it doesn't really affect the average user.
Speaker 1: Most of what they have is just polish, which matters a fuck ton.
Speaker 0: That's, you know, that's the whole point.
Speaker 0: It's like, oh, it's like me.
Speaker 0: If I bought it, I'd look at it like, wow, right.
Speaker 0: It's like, OK, so you look at, wow.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Compared to all the other MMOs that all the MMOs suck every single one.
Speaker 0: They're all fundamentally flawed.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Every single one.
Speaker 0: There is not one out there.
Speaker 0: that is that is awesome.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: And wow.
Speaker 0: Has the polish.
Speaker 1: So from a business perspective, I agree with you 100 percent.
Speaker 0: So therefore, if you're going to play one, it's going to be wild because all the other ones are intolerable.
Speaker 0: Like it's like they're all bad.
Speaker 0: This one's intolerable.
Speaker 0: So all smartphones, all phones, period, are fucked up and they suck.
Speaker 1: You keep saying things are so bad.
Speaker 1: What would the new iPhone buy me that I don't have on my pre iMovie?
Speaker 0: I don't really use that anyway because you go to a convention, you could take a movie of a cosplayer, push a button, it'll be on YouTube and you could edit the video right on the phone right there.
Speaker 0: That moment.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And nothing else even anything else.
Speaker 0: But it's a it's 720p.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's 30 frames a second.
Speaker 0: That's fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So you got you can't even do videos over there.
Speaker 1: Not actually I can.
Speaker 0: Can you do this?
Speaker 0: It is anywhere remotely close to to what to iMovie at in HD videos.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 1: OK, I'm saying for me, it's not a game changer because that's not something I need yet.
Speaker 0: OK, you said the same thing.
Speaker 0: I go I don't you know, I never need a smartphone.
Speaker 1: I always said I want a smartphone, but they're not at the right price point and functionality point yet.
Speaker 0: And the day they were.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I bought a smartphone.
Speaker 0: If you had the iPhone with the with the HD, you know, immediate YouTube, you would be using it like crazy at every convention.
Speaker 0: It is absolutely something.
Speaker 1: Probably not, because I mean, I use Twitter a lot of conventions and I tweet and do stuff like that less and less and less because I'm not really in.
Speaker 1: I've given up on the immediate cataloging of stuff I do and I'm much more interested in the post-hoc cataloging instead.
Speaker 0: So what about the.
Speaker 1: That's why I bought the Flip camera.
Speaker 0: So why don't you just get no smartphone?
Speaker 1: You'd save a lot of money because I use the smartphone for web browsing, Google Maps, and like I track my GPS, like my jogging, stuff like that.
Speaker 0: But there are phones that have that that are not smartphones.
Speaker 1: That's just a nice high resolution web browser.
Speaker 0: You can just.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, you're not going to get better resolution than the iPhone.
Speaker 0: That's for sure.
Speaker 1: It's high enough to read slash out and stuff on the subway.
Speaker 0: Why are you reading slash that?
Speaker 0: Oh, God.
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 0: So did it's still good.
Speaker 0: It's doing fine.
Speaker 0: You always seem to say this like is good enough is, you know, whatever you have is good enough.
Speaker 0: And then what's I mean, slash doesn't have like no ambition to get something that is better ever.
Speaker 0: So how long did it take?
Speaker 0: Wait, wait, wait.
Speaker 0: This is the same rim who was like, oh, I don't need to upgrade my my shitty old Mozilla to Firefox until like Firefox two or three came out to stop crashing my shitty old computer.
Speaker 0: No, no, it did not crash a shitty old computer.
Speaker 0: You're just far reluctant to go for anything new.
Speaker 0: And you'll always say that whatever you have is adequate until you actually get something new.
Speaker 0: You're just returning to your old something new.
Speaker 1: It's because something that I had before I stopped, you know, it was a killer app.
Speaker 0: You break your D.S.
Speaker 0: on purpose to get a D.S.
Speaker 0: lie and then you'll and then you'll say that the D.S.
Speaker 1: Guys, you seriously think I broke my D.S.
Speaker 1: on purpose.
Speaker 0: You break plenty of things on purpose.
Speaker 0: Uh huh.
Speaker 1: I remember when I broke my
Speaker 1: D.S.,
Speaker 1: we were doing the show and you were talking about something and I was ignoring you.
Speaker 1: I was loving up my Pokemon and the screen just like I said that I set it down on the desk because you stopped talking.
Speaker 1: I had to talk and the top screen shattered.
Speaker 0: Uh huh.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The point is, is that nothing else is even remotely close to the eye.
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 0: why can't anyone do it?
Speaker 0: I mean, all of these improvements right right down the line are just completely obvious.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Like put a gyroscope in there, make the camera not suck, make the video not suck.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like nothing here is like nothing no one thought of before.
Speaker 0: It wasn't like they had an original idea anywhere in here.
Speaker 0: You know, everything was just obvious ideas.
Speaker 0: They actually did it.
Speaker 0: That's all they did.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: That's the difference.
Speaker 1: Will do stuff like that, but they'll do it 80 percent there and then we'll give up on it.
Speaker 0: I could go to Google and I could tell them every single one of these ideas and I could tell them a hundred other obvious ideas.
Speaker 0: And if they did every single one of those, all they had, you know, just do them all, then they would destroy Apple.
Speaker 0: Apple would have no chance.
Speaker 1: I thought that Apple had Monopoly and all the good designers.
Speaker 0: This is what they just hired that design guy.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Why do they actually put them to work?
Speaker 1: Maybe they are.
Speaker 1: Maybe he's working on stuff.
Speaker 0: And that's another thing.
Speaker 0: How come no one can design?
Speaker 0: We've talked about this before.
Speaker 0: How come no one can design anything?
Speaker 0: There are.
Speaker 0: there can't be only one designer of phones in the whole world.
Speaker 1: I do want to point out that HTC is not there yet by any stretch, but they're there.
Speaker 1: They have the most promise of any hardware phone maker outside of Apple right now.
Speaker 1: Straight up.
Speaker 1: Like if there if anyone is ever going to dethrone Apple in the hardware realm on phones, it's got to be HTC because HP is not going to do anything, even with their Web OS.
Speaker 1: But in terms of just software, Web OS was probably, I think, a better contender than Android just in terms of polish and flashing functionality.
Speaker 0: But then again, they had the fucking iPhone guys.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Which is so crazy to me that despite no one can do it, it seems I don't know, they're just retarded.
Speaker 0: I don't know what's up with that.
Speaker 0: But here's someone actually wrote it.
Speaker 0: There was an article I was reading today about Android fragmentation.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: How people are complaining that, oh, if I make an Android app, I've got to either make it for Android one point five and not use any new features.
Speaker 1: Google announced that like two point two is going to be like the last quick release and then they're going to have a much longer.
Speaker 0: I didn't.
Speaker 0: I didn't say anything about that.
Speaker 1: Someone we were talking about that at work.
Speaker 1: Someone said that it looks like the plan is two point two will be a huge update and then there will be much longer cycles between like.
Speaker 0: that's not good because they need to catch up to Apple.
Speaker 0: They need big changes real fast.
Speaker 1: Maybe this pure speculation if you don't know what the time frame is on two point two.
Speaker 1: I haven't really looked into it.
Speaker 1: What if they got that designer guy working hardcore in an Apple style?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: But the thing is, right, is that people are talking about fragmentation and it's like it sucks if I have phones and it sucks.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Whereas it's much easier with the iPhone because only, you know, the so few and they all have the same OS and it just works.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: So the one guy was like, look right.
Speaker 0: The way the cell phone market used to work for a long time, you know, like HTC and all these guys, Samsung, Motorola.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They really didn't have any control over the software that they were putting on their phones.
Speaker 0: So what they did is they would just keep iterating on the hardware really quickly.
Speaker 0: That's why they're like 16 different razors.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: All running the same software because they couldn't do anything about the software.
Speaker 0: So they just kept updating the phone constantly.
Speaker 0: So these guys are really good at updating phone hardware rapidly, but they're not good at software.
Speaker 0: They suck ass at software.
Speaker 0: They have no idea.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So now they're moving.
Speaker 0: You know, now they get Android.
Speaker 0: They're actually moving to a different situation where you don't have to keep upgrading the hardware constantly of one hardware and use you upgrading the software.
Speaker 0: And they're not used to that.
Speaker 0: So these like as soon as they get used to it, it'll be all good.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But I think the big the core problem here is that you have this Android, which is designed to work on pretty much any, you know, phone hardware that meets like the minimum specs compared to the iPhone, where the OS is.
Speaker 0: the software is made specifically for one hardware, you know, and that's it.
Speaker 0: And on a computer.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, this.
Speaker 0: this buys you a little bit on the computer.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, the Mac.
Speaker 0: They have the software that is meant to go on that hardware and it buys them a little bit.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They have the nice like multi gesture touchpad on there.
Speaker 0: That's like the only thing on the MacBook that I like.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And it buys them that much.
Speaker 0: But it doesn't really buy them anything else because every computer, even Macs are still a mouse, a keyboard and a flat screen.
Speaker 0: And, you know, you know, all software Linux, Mac, Windows is made for that set of interfaces.
Speaker 0: And there isn't really much you can do to change the hardware, really.
Speaker 0: So that software wouldn't integrate well.
Speaker 0: But on a phone, you know, something small, the hardware is crazy different.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, the thing that got the iPod so big is the fact that has that little circle in the middle.
Speaker 0: And every other freaking one has something stupid that tries to knock it off.
Speaker 1: Nintendo's revolution was that D-pad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was a D-pad.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So all their stuff is made for the D-pad and everyone else has ghetto D-pad.
Speaker 1: To this day, the Xbox 360 directional pad is a piece of shit.
Speaker 0: It's the worst.
Speaker 0: Oh, God.
Speaker 0: I guess, you know, even at least the PlayStation has like the four separate buttons.
Speaker 0: So you can't fuck it up, you know, even though it's not as good as a D-pad on the Nintendo.
Speaker 0: But it's still.
Speaker 0: it's all right.
Speaker 0: It's better than the Xbox one.
Speaker 0: So the fact that Apple integrates the hardware and the software, you know, they don't have the fragmentation issue.
Speaker 0: They don't.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They solve all these problems at once.
Speaker 0: It gives them a huge.
Speaker 0: it's like imagine you're playing a board game.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And you've got like, you know, something.
Speaker 0: And it's like, OK, this thing is plus five, but only plus five in this situation.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, plus one.
Speaker 0: So in PCs, integrating the hardware and the software gives Apple plus one.
Speaker 0: But on phones plus five and the other people can't really compete with the plus five because they're not making the hardware and the software together.
Speaker 0: And that's it's.
Speaker 0: I think it's going to stay that way for a while.
Speaker 0: And I'm just like, oh, fuck it.
Speaker 0: I hate all this closed shit.
Speaker 0: I'll just but all the other phones suck so bad.
Speaker 0: This phone still sucks the least.
Speaker 0: I haven't made a mobile app yet.
Speaker 0: I don't see me making a mobile app in the future.
Speaker 1: It's possible where people like us might end up.
Speaker 1: I mean, I always say it, but the dark horse is still windows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's such a dark horse, but they're going in a different direction from everybody else.
Speaker 0: But they're still not going to have the hardware software integration.
Speaker 1: Now, unless they make some deal with HTC, that'd be my dream team.
Speaker 0: It's rough.
Speaker 0: Or if only HTC had gotten Web OS, because Web OS, if only HTC would learn how to do some fucking software.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: I mean, they keep trying to modify it, like do the sense UI thing.
Speaker 1: HTC needs to give up on all that.
Speaker 1: And they need to just get into a direct hundred percent partnership with someone who makes software and agree.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the thing is that they all.
Speaker 0: HTC only cares about selling hardware.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So what are they going to do?
Speaker 0: They're going to make phones that, you know, for every possible software, no matter which one you're using, you're going to buy an HTC phone will be the best.
Speaker 1: But I think they might sell more hardware if they combine with someone else.
Speaker 1: Like, you know, it's too late for Web OS.
Speaker 1: But if they bought Palm and then those two together made the unified environment like Apple did, and then they just they push that to try to make themselves the number two thing is to make unified.
Speaker 0: You'd have to start over again.
Speaker 0: You know, the palm is already sort of integrated with the devices.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They've got sort of that touch screen below the screen area, you know, and they've got the pixie really like that, like that little touch.
Speaker 1: I really like on the free.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not that exciting.
Speaker 1: I like it.
Speaker 1: It works really well.
Speaker 1: Also, the kind of feedback you get with that glowing orb and everything.
Speaker 1: Let's talk at least a little bit about some of the other things, because they announced I ads and it made me realize that I for as long as I've had a smartphone, anytime I've installed an app and it's so much you showed me an ad, I deleted it immediately.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And I can't imagine myself ever being at a point where I'll ever, ever, ever want to see an ad in anything ever again.
Speaker 0: There's ads in your mobile browser.
Speaker 0: You don't have ad block on your phone, do you?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know what?
Speaker 1: The ads, the Slashdot ads don't show up.
Speaker 0: That's pretty good.
Speaker 1: Plus, I use RSS readers whenever I can, too.
Speaker 1: I block the ads wherever I can.
Speaker 0: And an ad like being someone should make some sort of like Web proxy you can use on your phone.
Speaker 1: that would block the ads would be a good way to do it.
Speaker 1: But I had is interesting because I think it's going to cause and there's going to be a lot more submissions to the store initially, I think, from scummy, crappy companies making crappy little apps.
Speaker 0: Well, no, the thing is, right, I ads, it bothers me and it doesn't bother me.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It bothers me that they're trying to push ads on the phone.
Speaker 0: It's like, I don't want ads on my phone.
Speaker 0: Get the fuck away.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: There's already ads all over pretty much a ton of free iPhone apps.
Speaker 0: all have ads in them.
Speaker 0: And the ads are coming from other companies that aren't Apple and Apple, I think, said they're going to continue to allow those.
Speaker 0: They're not going to kick them off as long as they don't break the other rules that are going on there.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But the thing is, those ads are just really annoying and shitty and they don't work.
Speaker 0: Like I was once playing this free game and this ad showed up and then I uninstalled the game, of course.
Speaker 0: But the ad like pauses in your middle of the game, goes full screen and they're like, you try to push the next button and it barely works in there.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's it tries to play this video and you got to pause it and then wait for the look.
Speaker 1: They're polishing the experience of putting shit in your face.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: And then they're selling it to like, you know, much bigger brands instead of, you know, hey, play some online poker now, you know, which is what the ads are doing on the phones.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, they're going to be like, hey, go watch the latest movie in the theaters.
Speaker 0: You know, so it's good that the ads will be less, you know, bothersome, but it's bad that there's going to be more ads and I'll just have to avoid it as long as they're only in apps.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They're not putting them in the OS.
Speaker 0: So as long as you don't have an app with ads in it, you'll be all right.
Speaker 0: Which usually, I guess, means paying for apps or finding free ones that don't have ads.
Speaker 1: I don't think there's a lot more really important to talk about with this thing.
Speaker 0: No, it's just, you know, it's just more of a repeat story.
Speaker 0: It's like, look, yet again, everyone, why does everyone suck?
Speaker 0: This is, you know, if I just had a bunch of high quality designers and programmers and I was the boss of them and I could just, all I'd have to do is walk in on the first day, write a checklist and say, when you've done everything on this checklist, you can release the phone.
Speaker 0: Oh, and it has to be done within, you know, six months because if you don't, I'm going to have to add some more things to the checklist in six months as technology advances.
Speaker 0: And all they had to do is finish the list and Apple would be...
Speaker 1: All they had to do was write the software.
Speaker 0: And then Apple would be dead and that would be it.
Speaker 0: But no one can do it.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: And then they come out and they release phones where like the checklist is half checked and it's like, dude, no one wants that.
Speaker 0: You're not even half as good as what the other guy already has.
Speaker 1: See, I think part of the issue might be, look at what Apple does every time they release a new iPhone or something.
Speaker 1: They release missing a lot of functionality.
Speaker 1: people say they want, but because of the brand and because of the power and the polish, people will buy at much higher margins things that don't do everything on the checklist, which probably subsidizes development of the other things on the checklist to bring more of the people in and always stay ahead of everybody.
Speaker 0: But that's the thing is like...
Speaker 1: If you were like, I got my new phone, no one's going to pay what they pay for an iPhone for your awesome phone no matter how awesome it is right away.
Speaker 0: Well, it is true that Apple has not checked off every box on the list.
Speaker 0: Like, you know, remember they didn't check off copy paste.
Speaker 0: They didn't even have apps to begin with, right?
Speaker 0: And that is why they are beatable.
Speaker 0: Because if you do check off more boxes than they do, you can win.
Speaker 0: It's hard to say.
Speaker 0: If they actually checked off the whole thing, they would be invincible, right?
Speaker 1: Their brand name is really... Don't underestimate the power of that brand.
Speaker 1: It would take a lot to bring that brand down.
Speaker 0: Because part of the check... If you had everything on the checklist, that would be enough.
Speaker 1: So part of your checklist, I thought you don't agree with like coercing people through persuasive like argument and advertising.
Speaker 1: You're going to alter people's...
Speaker 0: You wouldn't need to because part, you know, it would have to be designed really well and it would be amazing in its own right.
Speaker 1: But isn't designing really well just a form of coercion just like politeness is?
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: In a device, in a thing that you are carrying with you, it's not about, you know, the design of coercing you.
Speaker 1: What if you have to trick them into buying it with advertising?
Speaker 0: You don't need to trick anyone into buying it because it's industrial design.
Speaker 0: It's obviously superior and a better experience.
Speaker 1: I point out obviously superior and better experience have often not meant much in the consumer world.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: When, when have they not?
Speaker 0: When is the, when is the obviously superior thing not been the consumer product of choice?
Speaker 0: Betamax?
Speaker 0: In the technology world.
Speaker 1: Betamax?
Speaker 0: But it was not obviously superior.
Speaker 0: It had less running time.
Speaker 0: And people don't give a shit about quality of the video or the audio.
Speaker 0: They cared about the running time and the price much more.
Speaker 0: So that is why VHS won.
Speaker 0: It was obviously superior to the consumer.
Speaker 1: Well, see, the thing is you keep saying obviously superior to the consumer, but different consumers do have different utility.
Speaker 0: The, the, the, the consumer as a whole, right?
Speaker 0: The, the, the mass populous, the, the, you know, price and running time were far greater utility overall.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there are many people who needed more quality video editing people and such, and those people bought Betamax, you know?
Speaker 0: But the vast majority of people, obviously.
Speaker 1: Plus what about Farmville over Counter-Strike?
Speaker 0: That obviously most more people want Farmville.
Speaker 1: So would you say therefore that from a game design perspective, Farmville is better?
Speaker 1: From a marketing perspective it is.
Speaker 0: No, from an industrial design perspective, Farmville is better.
Speaker 1: From a money making for me perspective.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: So things of the day.
Speaker 1: There was a prank at RIT that was oft talked about, but never enacted.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it would actually work on anyone, but we called it truck.
Speaker 1: I'm sure many of you have heard of this before.
Speaker 1: The idea was that you find someone who's asleep, possibly they've passed out drunk or something, so they're really asleep.
Speaker 0: Is this like the one where they do the fake buried alive thing?
Speaker 1: Ah, the fake buried alive.
Speaker 1: That was great.
Speaker 1: I think you're referring to that video in college here.
Speaker 1: Remember when the guy finally got out, he punched everybody in the face?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So truck, what you do is you wait for someone to fall asleep, you know, laying on their back, and you take two flashlights and you hold them far away from their face and far apart.
Speaker 1: And you have two other people standing in either ear just slowly mumbling truck, truck, truck, truck, truck, truck, getting slowly louder as you bring the flashlights closer and closer together.
Speaker 0: Don't you start the flashlights close together and bring them farther apart?
Speaker 0: Because that's what it looks like when a truck is...
Speaker 1: I think you start far away from their face.
Speaker 1: You start right in their eyes, it's going to blind them.
Speaker 0: No, you have the flashlights close together and far away, and you spread them out as you get closer.
Speaker 0: That's what it looks like when a truck is heading towards you.
Speaker 1: See, we never actually tried to do it.
Speaker 1: We only talked about it.
Speaker 0: I think a truck is coming at you.
Speaker 0: Two distant lights.
Speaker 1: But the point is, we have the lights getting closer, truck, truck, truck, truck, truck, and then you scream truck and hit them in the face.
Speaker 0: With like a pillow or something.
Speaker 1: And, you know, we always suspected that people would freak out.
Speaker 1: And we never did it, and the few times we tried it didn't work because it probably wouldn't work.
Speaker 1: But what does work, as this video will show, is waking someone up and yelling instructions at them.
Speaker 1: Because if you wake someone up urgently enough, and you give them instructions while they're still confused, they will probably just do whatever you tell them to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you just shake someone and go, "Oh my god, oh my god, oh my
Speaker 1: god!".
Speaker 1: Like, "Oh my god, bite this banana, now take this skin in the closet, we're all going to
Speaker 1: die!".
Speaker 1: And it's great.
Speaker 1: This video's worth watching.
Speaker 1: I suggest you try this on your friends.
Speaker 0: Alright, so I had an issue technologically this morning with SSH, right?
Speaker 1: It happens to everyone.
Speaker 0: Yes, I had SSH on one computer and on another computer and I had him configured identically and everything identical and I Accessation to one with the public key.
Speaker 0: It was all good.
Speaker 0: I station the other one with the public key rejected and I'm like, what the fuck retired.
Speaker 0: So I do SSH like for ultra verbose to see all the text doesn't tell me shit.
Speaker 0: I'm like, what the fuck?
Speaker 1: Well, you put like two V's in there.
Speaker 0: I have a three V's in there.
Speaker 1: I didn't do anything.
Speaker 0: You can always get more verbose Until you see every single deep level of debugging.
Speaker 1: I've always been more of a like.
Speaker 1: I'm the kind of person who will like tail varlog messages while I'm doing stuff.
Speaker 1: I don't tend to use verbose outputs from the.
Speaker 0: I was doing it on the client As this age whatever I was doing but with a - V in there to see some weird point about the kind of work I do.
Speaker 1: I'm almost never not like everything I. everything that ever matters to me is server-side.
Speaker 0: like if I have a client-side problem I'm like what I was just trying to get the information right about why I was being rejected.
Speaker 0: So I was like, I'm typing this command and I'm like, well, obviously the server should be telling the client why it was rejected.
Speaker 0: Yeah so if I do the right.
Speaker 0: but I didn't see anything and I couldn't for the life of me figure out what the hell it was.
Speaker 0: and then eventually right, I You know I went to server fault and I got the answer which was Go look in this log file on the server and you'll find the real answer which is like varlog Auth or varlog security something like that.
Speaker 0: and I found the answer which is like permissions on this folder.
Speaker 0: I check permissions on like all the SSH configs and all those folders.
Speaker 0: I didn't check permissions on my actual home folder which apparently matter which is I don't know what the fuck is up with that anyway.
Speaker 0: But the thing the reason I was messing with SSH is because of these three links that are my thing of the day collectively right, so one of them is SSH automatic reverse tunnels for workflow simplification.
Speaker 0: So what this does is, you know, you can do SSH tunnel right connect the port on this machine to this port on this machine.
Speaker 0: So you can make it so that you could telnet to localhost on Port 30 and that'll actually take you to port 80 Google.com or some other machine.
Speaker 0: you can SSH to and but it will be over SSH So it'll be all encrypted right.
Speaker 0: what this does is you SSH a new machine.
Speaker 0: You put some stuff in your SSH config file.
Speaker 0: it automatically makes a tunnel going the other direction.
Speaker 0: so then what you can do for example is you could you know, I could SSH the other machine and then SCP something to local and then it'll come back.
Speaker 0: so I can SSH I can copy files back over the line while I'm on the Other machine, you know, you could also.
Speaker 0: it's a useful thing.
Speaker 0: So this is a very useful trick.
Speaker 0: useful trick number two Transparent multi hop SSH, right?
Speaker 0: So you SSH into one machine and then you have agent forwarding all configured Which I'm not even gonna talk about.
Speaker 0: you can go find out about agent forwarding on your own and then you SSH from there To another machine to another machine to another machine, right?
Speaker 0: But let's say your network is configured in such a way Right to where you've got a whole bunch of computers and only one of them has a path out to the world Right, so you have to SSH to that one first and then to a second one.
Speaker 0: that's like hidden behind it.
Speaker 0: So you have to SSH two times every time you want to talk to this inside machine.
Speaker 0: even with agent forwarding You won't have to type in a password, but you'll still have to SSH two times.
Speaker 0: You can configure SSH in such a way using this transparent multi hop.
Speaker 0: So where you SSH directly to the inside machine and it'll automatically go hop hop into it right through the entryway.
Speaker 0: And here is the third SSH thing is this thing called BC VI.
Speaker 0: I haven't really looked at this too carefully to figure out exactly how it works But basically it's back channel VI and what it allows you to do is you SSH to a remote machine.
Speaker 0: You have no X forwarding none whatsoever.
Speaker 0: No X right, but you want to use your nice G VIM your GUI VIM on your local machine.
Speaker 0: You don't want to use VIM in the terminal.
Speaker 0: That's not as good.
Speaker 0: It'll actually you know over the forwarding back channel Whatever open up the remote file in the local Graphical VIM and then you can save it and it'll save to the other where it's supposed to save and that's pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: That's like I always like end up like installing X on machines that don't need X just so I can use Or I'll use like I'll mount remote file systems like using G VFS or some ridiculous thing like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, see if we finally added we have an X win 32 like that thing running.
Speaker 1: So yeah, because it has X way it has this live functionality, which is you have permanent persistent sessions Mmm, so I can basically disconnect.
Speaker 1: so I have like an FVWM custom with like, you know I'm a cessation like hundreds of boxes and all this stuff going on.
Speaker 1: some of it.
Speaker 1: I've like active processes.
Speaker 0: I don't know how people like work like.
Speaker 0: I see other people working and they have windows like a hundred tabs and they get a Hundred windows open and I'm like, I just close everything immediately.
Speaker 0: I have like one the tab I'm working on.
Speaker 0: if I'm not working on it, right?
Speaker 1: I leave terminals open in different colored background FVWM desktops to different environments in case I have to respond to something quickly.
Speaker 1: Those are the you know, I go to the red desktop, which is where I have like shells to all the key production Ready to go then.
Speaker 1: I escalate permissions to the user that can actually do shit.
Speaker 1: I don't stay escalated.
Speaker 1: So I don't accidentally, you know It's like other people's workflows.
Speaker 0: It seems like most people I've seen, you know, watch compute have a lot of stuff open.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's not even that I think the average person.
Speaker 1: they just leave all these fucking windows open in the background all over the place.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I feel like I'm the only one who ever like I just constantly closing things.
Speaker 0: I'm like close close close close.
Speaker 1: I try to close everything.
Speaker 1: I'm not using or expecting to use in the next few minutes.
Speaker 0: I close like even things I'm gonna use in the next few minutes and I open them again.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's you know, that's the way it is.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so there's three awesome SSH tricks for you.
Speaker 1: So we this was kind of a crowd people but I think it'll work especially since I'm watching Ghost in the Shell standalone complex again And goddamn is that not a great show?
Speaker 1: even if you're not an anime fan You don't listen to the Wednesday shows.
Speaker 1: if you care about science and technology and sci-fi You'll probably like Ghost in the Shell because it's basically straight up about Cyberization and what it means.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure like a lot of non anime peoples have seen Ghost in the Shell.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like Akira.
Speaker 0: It's like all kinds of people have seen it, but they probably don't realize it's not restricted to anime.
Speaker 0: There's a fact I would say it's more popular among non anime fan.
Speaker 1: They probably don't know.
Speaker 1: over that there are two 26 episode TV shows a motion to the movie.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: some of the people who watch the Adult Swim might have known because I think one of them or both of them Was on the Adult Swim at some point.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I do think that yes they are far less well known than the movie and there are many people who perhaps saw the movie back in the 90s and Did not know that there was more that had come out afterwards.
Speaker 1: But the show the main like push of the show and the movies is the ad, you know, what is consciousness?
Speaker 1: what are we?
Speaker 1: that sort of thing and It really raises the issue of cyberization.
Speaker 1: Like what will society be like when we can just start replacing Entire human bodies with robots that effectively are immortal?
Speaker 1: and the only thing we can't really Make immortal yet is an actual physical brain.
Speaker 0: I Think one thing will definitely be problematic right is that you know right now we have a you know issues of power and electricity All right, and you know humans are powered by food.
Speaker 0: So we if we get into some kind of world we stop making food.
Speaker 0: that saves us a bunch.
Speaker 0: But then we have to make more electricity.
Speaker 0: Otherwise you'll die when you run out of batteries.
Speaker 1: or at the same time I'm we already made a robot that kills flies eats them and then uses that to make more electricity to kill more flies.
Speaker 0: But is that you know, is that gonna be enough to power a whole human being forever?
Speaker 0: Well the whole you know the idea of you know in Galaxy Express 3 9, you know, what did the?
Speaker 0: the robot people eight people?
Speaker 1: Well, I think that the issue there is that you know The thing that's holding back technology at least technology that individual humans will use More so than anything now is the fact that we cannot make safe batteries that hold a lot of power.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's a completely separate issue.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's the same thing for cyberization.
Speaker 1: Like that's a hurdle that would love to be overcome.
Speaker 1: How do you power this stuff?
Speaker 1: I mean, we can't even make a laptop that lasts 12 hours and does anything useful.
Speaker 1: How are we gonna make a person?
Speaker 0: We're not right.
Speaker 0: we're the best that we're gonna get I think without advances in power that are crazy.
Speaker 0: is You know some just some robot parts, you know, we already got some of this going on.
Speaker 1: people biomechanical systems might work Especially if we have this kind of like.
Speaker 1: we make some sort of pseudo biological muscle tissue that we control with technology.
Speaker 0: I mean people already have pacemakers right plenty of them.
Speaker 0: that some guy just went home with a Artificial heart for the first time.
Speaker 0: other people have hard artificial heart.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, whatever took one home.
Speaker 1: a lot of people when they talk about cyber ization They either think you know goes to the shell right away.
Speaker 1: They don't realize that Humans, I've been cyber izing themselves like for serious where there have been cyborgs since we had the first prosthetic.
Speaker 0: our crutches are what?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: It's quite, you know, that doesn't count.
Speaker 0: They're not integrated though.
Speaker 1: Maybe it maybe cyborg requires integrated first hook.
Speaker 0: a peg leg doesn't count.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those might count.
Speaker 0: Why doesn't that count?
Speaker 1: Those are prosthetics.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, why does it have to be attached to you to count though?
Speaker 1: Well integrated prosthetics are very different from detached prosthetics.
Speaker 1: I mean the love I crutches.
Speaker 1: and by that logic a pencil is a prosthetic because I can write with it.
Speaker 1: I couldn't do that.
Speaker 1: Normally.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean neurologically it actually is a prosthetic right your your brain treats when you use tools.
Speaker 0: Your brain treats the tools as a part of your own body.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: so in that way, I guess it is sort of a prosthetic to use any tool.
Speaker 0: physical wise You know a keyboard is an extension of my body when I am typing.
Speaker 1: well by definition a prosthesis is literally just Something that replaces a body part that is now missing.
Speaker 0: Mmm, but I mean we're not talking about.
Speaker 0: we're not talking about.
Speaker 0: We're not talking about just prosthesis though.
Speaker 0: We're talking about any cyber ization.
Speaker 1: Well, that's gonna be the big push is that right now and I think this is kind of the most there is non prosthetic cyber ization.
Speaker 1: the most interesting Aspect of cyber ization is that there we're going to get to the point where people will do it voluntarily not to overcome a failure Of their body but to enhance an already perfectly functioning body.
Speaker 1: that's going to be I think the biggest tipping point in human history.
Speaker 0: Some people are already sort of doing well We have.
Speaker 1: that was surgery now with baseball players the biggest example that one surgery that makes them basically a better thrower.
Speaker 1: That originally was used to.
Speaker 1: I forget what problem it treated but it was found that by doing it You basically make them pitch faster.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean look people are taking steroids, right?
Speaker 0: What happens when we have like nanobots steroids?
Speaker 0: Yep, or steroids that goes around your muscles and it cleans up all the lactic acid faster.
Speaker 0: So, you know, it doesn't hurt when you exert yourself and then you can be like, ah What if we made steroids that have zero negative side effects?
Speaker 0: All they do is increase your little robots that go around making muscles and eating fats.
Speaker 1: So what do we do at that point?
Speaker 1: We've already talked but I want to get into the argument.
Speaker 0: everyone will turn into like like ultra buff.
Speaker 1: I don't want to get into sports because that argument we've had on this show more than once as to what that'll mean for sports.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, I guess I don't know what.
Speaker 1: at what point would you go for it?
Speaker 0: I'll go for it.
Speaker 0: Mostly Mike.
Speaker 0: The only reason I wouldn't go for it, which is a pretty big reason right is the safety issue.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like okay, so I'll install this Bionic eye.
Speaker 0: Oh fuck, you know, there was a camera in my bionic eye and someone else is watching.
Speaker 0: Great, that was awesome.
Speaker 1: That was a plot in Ghost in the Shell.
Speaker 0: Pretty much everything you're gonna come up with is gonna be a plot in something, right?
Speaker 1: Most of them will be in Ghost in the Shell.
Speaker 0: Or, you know, surrogates or something like that, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, I'll replace my arm.
Speaker 0: Oh shit, my arm got hacked and I did something I didn't want to do.
Speaker 1: I don't think surrogates brought up any issue That wasn't already brought up by Ghost in the Shell.
Speaker 0: I don't know, it had the stay at home.
Speaker 0: Well, so it's Ghost in the Shell with remote agents and Ghost in the Shell to man-machine interface.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know what came first.
Speaker 1: And in the TV show.
Speaker 0: I guess Anyway, didn't you know but it didn't have the.
Speaker 0: I think what surrogates has is the is the social issue of what if everyone's staying At home and a robot is going out right as opposed to it goes in the shell.
Speaker 0: It's like some people go out some surrogates go out.
Speaker 1: Well, that's the interesting thing.
Speaker 1: A lot of people they watch Ghost in the Shell They think of it as like.
Speaker 1: so that is a future world where we've reached this level where people are cyberizing.
Speaker 1: But really it's looking at this is a world where the technology is new and only the richest people are doing this.
Speaker 0: I mean think about this.
Speaker 0: Let's say I'm still using keyboards, right and I got cyber hands.
Speaker 0: Someone could figure out what password I'm typing.
Speaker 0: if they could hack my hand because they see me typing, right?
Speaker 0: They could see the signals go into the fingers.
Speaker 0: Just it would be like they have a key logger in my hand instead of a key logger in the keyboard.
Speaker 1: Well, that's one of the big one.
Speaker 1: of the biggest issues too is what if we get to the point to where you can hack A person the same way that you hack a computer.
Speaker 0: That's why you got it.
Speaker 0: I gotta be you know, here's here's my concern.
Speaker 1: I do not believe that in the United States the legal system we have in place and the government systems We have in place could ever deal with that situation.
Speaker 0: No, they couldn't human hack Yeah, basically become anarchy if it could never be addressed by because people who are cyberized and we're like Smart hackers would secure themselves.
Speaker 0: They couldn't be hacked and they would hack everyone else with absolutely.
Speaker 0: it would basically be like gods walking around.
Speaker 0: They could just control people.
Speaker 0: and you know, I mean we're already approaching a point where we can read people's, you know Actual biological brains.
Speaker 0: if people have digital brains.
Speaker 0: Oh, they're so fucked.
Speaker 0: They're so fucked.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So What?
Speaker 1: so let's say there weren't any safety issues like say let's say it's like ghost in the shell.
Speaker 1: So we're at the ghost in the shell world, right?
Speaker 0: There's so many safety issues.
Speaker 0: Oh my gosh the majors is gonna come and use my body to kill some guy and then I'll have to get it to pay a ton of money to get a new cyber body.
Speaker 1: But you saw that only happens to you know people.
Speaker 1: she's after she's not after us.
Speaker 0: There's plenty of security issues going on in the ghost in the shell world.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much all it's about.
Speaker 0: is everyone's getting you know hacked?
Speaker 1: I think everyone is in.
Speaker 1: the majority of people aren't.
Speaker 0: but you mean even look at like go.
Speaker 0: and even the first ghost in the Shell manga right there was that police officer with like a cyber arm and the software in it Wasn't even hacked.
Speaker 0: It was just like buggy software in it.
Speaker 0: So her arm wasn't working properly and then the major hacked her and was like, ah, this arm is all fucked up.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's got the shitty software in it.
Speaker 1: I've done that before.
Speaker 1: remember we were at RIT hanging out in Luke's apartment with Dave and Luke was not gone And we went to use his computer and it was locked.
Speaker 1: So I broke into it because we wanted to look on the internet and then we saw that he didn't have video drivers installed.
Speaker 1: He was running like 320 by 200 and I fixed it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It was the same thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: That's exact, you know, so but the thing is that's a bigger deal when it's your arm And you know right now, you know, it doesn't happen too often.
Speaker 0: But imagine if you get in a situation where it's like fuck I can't get the better driver and now your arm is all fucked Up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean What is usually something that's gonna be so awesome.
Speaker 0: Oh, man.
Speaker 0: I'm so strong I got some grip.
Speaker 0: I can punch real hard and type read crazy fast and You know play crocodile perfectly and throw real whatever but I'll fuck myself for is all fucked up And I can't fix it because of some reason now becomes an inconvenience.
Speaker 0: What you know, it's not.
Speaker 0: it's no longer a boon but a bane and I don't want to ever have a bane.
Speaker 0: It's got to be 100% boon or at least 99% boon.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So what about the situation of consciousness like say you're getting near the end of your life?
Speaker 1: Okay, physically your body is degrading your you know, you don't have more than five or six years to go.
Speaker 1: Okay What about when we?
Speaker 1: I don't think this will happen in our lifetime necessarily.
Speaker 1: But what about the kind of analog transfer of consciousness or at least of memories?
Speaker 0: Well if it's possible, right, you know It's a basic thing.
Speaker 1: I would argue that it is definitely possible to make an Effectively perfect copy of an individual person's complete set of experiences memories because they're just stored in Physical goop in our heads.
Speaker 0: It's all there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's a lot.
Speaker 0: See what is a lot?
Speaker 0: What could you store it in?
Speaker 0: that wasn't an actual brain?
Speaker 1: Well, let's say we could make something All right.
Speaker 0: So if your body is sucking real bad, I mean, it's better to have right eat Even if someone hacks your you know, get a new body.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and someone hacks it and it sucks.
Speaker 0: It's better than nobody right?
Speaker 0: So if I'm in a dying old geezer can't walk situation I'll take the hackable legs before I get you know, rather than the brain specifically.
Speaker 1: I mean think about this Alright, so say we can make us remember our better to have be alive and you know, continue your consciousness.
Speaker 1: Well, no, that's the interesting thing to be dead.
Speaker 1: You keep saying be alive and continue my consciousness.
Speaker 1: So, let me let me lay out a bunch of groundwork for this and then let's see how you answer now.
Speaker 1: So, all right, your consciousness is not a unified thing.
Speaker 1: We know that our human consciousness is all these disparate parts kind of talking to each other in Real time but not synchronized like one side of your brain Cannot know the state of any other part of the brain While that other side knows the state of it because there's propagation delays through the speed of light.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So the state our consciousness is not a unit.
Speaker 1: It's not a thing.
Speaker 1: It's this kind of analog overall structure.
Speaker 1: That is the like the temporal sum of all the interactions going on at once.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so there is no like unit of consciousness.
Speaker 1: It's just all these kind of independent systems hitting each other with huge delays between them.
Speaker 1: Sometimes variable delays between them Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So and it's a single thread your consciousness is the thread that is continuing.
Speaker 1: So if you move your consciousness to another structure So the and the analogy of your consciousness is 100%.
Speaker 1: every individual memory, you know every experience everything that is you.
Speaker 1: But that thread very likely could not ever itself be transferred because it exists in this physical medium.
Speaker 1: that can only exist on that physical medium if you Recreate it perfectly somewhere else.
Speaker 1: You're recreating its structure with a different underlying physical structure.
Speaker 0: Uh What you could do, right?
Speaker 1: Let's say you have so even if you have a person say you make an organic brain That is 100% identical to the brain.
Speaker 1: You're transferring out of right what everything all the memories can be transferred.
Speaker 1: But basically if you turn on that new brain It would pick up thinking consciously the exact moment where your previous brain left off.
Speaker 1: But it wouldn't stop your previous brain from thinking it would just be a new you.
Speaker 1: that's completely indistinguishable from you.
Speaker 1: Your threat of consciousness by the nature of physics very likely would not be able to inhabit any new big thing.
Speaker 1: we could ever build a Perfect copy if you could but you would still die That's true.
Speaker 0: I was gonna say like what if I went into like a real-time FMRI and in real time they built a brain that was identical to my brain Based on the FMRI, right?
Speaker 0: So now you got two identical brains like but that one's not you.
Speaker 0: But I would sit there looking at one that was me, but it wouldn't be me.
Speaker 1: But here's the scary thing.
Speaker 1: It would be indistinct indistinguishable from you.
Speaker 0: But what would I still but the thing is right?
Speaker 0: So, okay So now I they make it across the room from me, right?
Speaker 0: There's two.
Speaker 0: this is two rooms next to each other in the in the brain lab.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they make the copy of me in room number two, and I'm in room number one, right?
Speaker 0: Already as you know, we're in sync while they're making it and then we're done.
Speaker 0: So it goes.
Speaker 0: ha already Scott one and Scott two are in separate environments, so they diverge immediately.
Speaker 0: However, so we're not so I can think and talk to Scott too and it's not.
Speaker 0: it's gonna have a conversation with me It's not gonna be in sync with me.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna be like there's one Consciousness that is controlling both of these bodies.
Speaker 1: That's the interesting and also scary part.
Speaker 1: because alright So you have this copy of you it?
Speaker 0: Picks up and until it realizes basically it'll look around the room and realize and of course if it has a younger invent You know better body than the old dying Scott has right?
Speaker 0: It's definitely gonna have go on a different path.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, then, you know the car.
Speaker 0: they start at the exact same instant.
Speaker 0: They would diverge.
Speaker 1: but here's the thing Great, so they diverge.
Speaker 1: All right, it immediately knows I am the copy in the better body Mm-hmm, but otherwise it has every memory that you had.
Speaker 1: it is 100% you.
Speaker 0: it is this though But it's not me because I'm still thinking.
Speaker 1: yeah, so it is as though that moment you went into this new body But simultaneously your old body is still going the thread.
Speaker 1: So you get a new cyborg body and you copy make a copy of your brain into it.
Speaker 1: The you that got copied to the new one is still gonna die in the old body.
Speaker 1: It can never be moved to another body because it is the sum of its physical parts.
Speaker 1: The analogy can't ever know itself.
Speaker 1: The analogy can't be transferred but consciousness is the analogy.
Speaker 1: So it is possible with you know, the idea of cyber ization.
Speaker 0: In fact, it is likely very likely that the process of making you're saying that once the old, you know I make a copy of myself and when the the old Scott dies the the new Scott will also die.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, no that so you you've got your continuous threat of consciousness, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah So right now you're thinking stuff and you have all your memories.
Speaker 1: and so you're thinking I am here.
Speaker 1: I am here.
Speaker 1: You look at yourself.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm that thread of you you will let you know.
Speaker 1: you get a new cyber body.
Speaker 1: You won't wake up in the new cyber body.
Speaker 1: you go to sleep you wake up You're in your old shitty body and there's a new Scott over there who leaves an awesome life and then you die.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we already said that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah So what if you're near the end of your life and that is the only way to transfer?
Speaker 1: do you do it?
Speaker 1: Do you want to make a new copy of yourself that you will never experience to go off and do you forever?
Speaker 0: Well, you know, it depends right like if I'm Being super productive like let's say I'm like Norman bollock or something, right then.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because okay sure It's not gonna get me the huge benefit of still being alive You know, I mean you're already gonna die, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I mean, you know It's not really.
Speaker 0: if you can't avoid the death right in any way All you can do is make a new you.
Speaker 0: then oh, you know do it.
Speaker 0: if and if extending your life would benefit You know the world.
Speaker 0: but here's the icing thing, you know, if you're gonna die Anyway, what difference does it make it as a copy of yours the one you could make to use?
Speaker 0: Maybe is that is there gonna be a benefit to?
Speaker 0: to me's?
Speaker 1: of course, you know ghost in the shell.
Speaker 1: The only way they get around that is they say well, there's a ghost that we can't figure out how to transfer.
Speaker 0: I mean, it depends on the people right whether how many it'll be worth it, right?
Speaker 0: Let's say you're the best pitcher in baseball.
Speaker 0: You should make five use.
Speaker 0: you can pitch every day.
Speaker 0: Maybe you should make ten use.
Speaker 0: you can pitch in relief of yourself and you would win right and then make nine fielders Right of the same guy all hit home runs every time.
Speaker 0: six babe Ruth's lose Lose right, so, you know, it depends right?
Speaker 1: Whereas if you're say for example I Hitler no, we don't want to make more Hitler's.
Speaker 0: you're a great military general, right?
Speaker 0: You know a lot of military strategies and tactics, right?
Speaker 0: You only want one of you but you want the ability to make a backup if you die, right?
Speaker 0: But if there's two of you That's problematic because two of you are not gonna come up with something that one of you wouldn't have come up with But two of you that other guy.
Speaker 0: he could become a traitor and now you're fighting against you.
Speaker 0: You don't want that.
Speaker 1: now you could be a really good fucking movie.
Speaker 1: So the Russians steal the clone of MacArthur.
Speaker 1: that's leading our army and they wake him up and then they teach him Look how much better our system is.
Speaker 1: There's MacArthur us versus red MacArthur.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's you know, you get a super man.
Speaker 1: It's an awesome fucking movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you don't want that to be real life, right?
Speaker 0: You know, you just like you know, if you make five baseball pictures that are all you you don't want one traded.
Speaker 1: You're forgetting what if you do the dr.
Speaker 1: McNinja?
Speaker 1: so you make ten of your of you the great general and you send them to fight in ten different fronts in American wars on the quote-unquote, but dr.
Speaker 0: McNinja was able to reabsorb them.
Speaker 0: We didn't say that you could know.
Speaker 1: So you can't reabsorb them, right?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe we could by having by combined giving them all the combined.
Speaker 0: Oh, you get a whole bunch of people that are already awesome And they all get different training like each guy learns a different martial art.
Speaker 0: Then they all come back and they either sit on the Council of elders and debate among each other or they all teach each other Also now all of them that the thing is right if you can transfer your stuff, right?
Speaker 0: Why would you bother making ten guys to each learn one martial art then come back and all teach each other?
Speaker 0: The ten March the nine martial arts that they didn't.
Speaker 1: here's the other thing.
Speaker 0: you could in the same amount of time You could have one guy just go and learn ten martial arts Dies he can make another copy to continue on.
Speaker 1: would you want to?
Speaker 0: wouldn't take any less.
Speaker 1: would you want to take the full?
Speaker 1: Experiences of another person's life because you get everything you have all the skills they had but their consciousness You know.
Speaker 1: the new thread of their conscious that starts up in your brain Would theoretically unless you did something very clever be equal in strength to you And in fact you could not differentiate you from it.
Speaker 1: there just be one.
Speaker 1: would you do that if you were combining with someone awesome?
Speaker 0: Wait, so it's like I just added Einstein to myself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's two brains in my brain, but there is no you and Einstein There's just the you.
Speaker 1: that is the combat combination I mean goes to the shell.
Speaker 1: got into that one.
Speaker 0: Oh, right, right if I could do that It depends on who is but then it was never the one who was merged.
Speaker 1: all of humanity Have a perfect like to remind then go off into space.
Speaker 0: No, you can't merge all humanity because you get a bunch of shit in there.
Speaker 0: You gotta have a good filter on that shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so all I'm leading up to with this is alright.
Speaker 1: So we we know, you know, you make a new coffee view.
Speaker 1: the threat of consciousness dies.
Speaker 1: Here's a practical consideration because we keep going into the theoretical.
Speaker 1: What if so you now are at your peak mental capacity because you know, we're at the age where we're before the metal decline.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I hope not.
Speaker 1: So we're.
Speaker 1: eventually we're gonna get to a point like, you know, ten.
Speaker 0: I hope I got more room to grow.
Speaker 1: So let's say you're at the point you're 40 and Scientists told us now that your brain from this point forward is going to degrade.
Speaker 1: You won't be as clever and quick.
Speaker 1: you'll never know then why they're quick than you are now, is that true?
Speaker 1: Let's say it is.
Speaker 0: if it's true Then we got to change the Constitution because we can't be allowing anyone over 40 to be president.
Speaker 0: But they have a declining mental state.
Speaker 1: thing is well, we do human brains decline But we make up for that with the benefit of the memories.
Speaker 1: We have the additional experience, but then is it really?
Speaker 1: 60 year old right?
Speaker 0: was that a decline?
Speaker 0: if you know more well.
Speaker 1: But the thing is the physical part does decline but you have the memories Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: All right, so so that so we know this.
Speaker 1: so if we somehow could prevent the physical decline and keep the memories We would just get better over time forever like the elves and burning wheel do.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: All right, so we've got.
Speaker 1: we got all that.
Speaker 1: You know, this is why the 60 year old racquetball player can beat me.
Speaker 1: I'm faster than him, but he knows a hell of a lot more about racquetball than I do.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh I didn't realize racquetball was a knowledge game.
Speaker 1: It is more so than a physical game.
Speaker 1: much older men who are very frail can kick the shit out of me Uh-huh, but don't they have to hit the ball real hard?
Speaker 1: No Cuz they hit it with such precision that it goes into the corner or he sees where I'm standing and knows how fast I am.
Speaker 1: So he hits it perfectly to where I have to run Super fast and just tires me out and tires me out and then he just beats me Thinking everyone just sit around racquetball.
Speaker 0: This is a way.
Speaker 0: big tension.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you get two people in this little box hitting the ball.
Speaker 0: All right, so if but why don't you just like how do you not bump into the other guy?
Speaker 0: I would just stand where you needed to go and you bump into me.
Speaker 1: You're in my way.
Speaker 1: I can just fucking hit you and then I get a point cuz you were in my way.
Speaker 0: Oh, so why don't I just barrel into the other guy on purpose every time instead of actually trying to hit the ball?
Speaker 1: Uh, you could that's that's a valid stretch.
Speaker 1: You might get a foul depends on what kind of you know style you're playing.
Speaker 0: But if I if the guy who gets bumped is the loser I would just play bump every time I like push rim.
Speaker 1: It's more complex than that.
Speaker 1: So it's my but the balls coming at me and I got to hit it.
Speaker 1: if you're in my way and I hit you It's your fault.
Speaker 0: So but if I if you run up if you're like hiding in the corner, I come over and kick you in the shin.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, no No, no when the ball was going to the opposite corner.
Speaker 0: now good And so how do we?
Speaker 0: we need a referee to determine if I were you were actually in my way or not?
Speaker 1: So having played racquetball a lot.
Speaker 1: It's always obvious.
Speaker 1: But all that aside.
Speaker 1: All right, so we've laid all this ground rules.
Speaker 1: So practical question you're 40. science tells us your that you your physical brain is going to get slower over time But your memories and knowledge are going to kind of balance that for another 20 or 30 years, but the decline is real.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Let's say we can cyber eyes you we can make a copy of your brain into a cyber brain that will not degrade.
Speaker 1: So your peak physical brain will go on forever never getting worse and your memories will just increase.
Speaker 1: All right, but to do this we have to destroy your current physical brain and kill you.
Speaker 1: I would you would you kill yourself to create a copy of you that you will never experience.
Speaker 1: that is indistinguishable from you to all for every intent and purpose.
Speaker 1: the only distinguishing factor between the two is that one it is immortal and will be forever and awesome and - Your solipsistic mind will never experience that.
Speaker 0: All right, so here's the.
Speaker 0: the answer is kind of obvious, right?
Speaker 0: You already said that you you know, you're you're still gonna be good for so many years, you know with your memory.
Speaker 0: But the physical decline.
Speaker 1: so say you're saying you wait till you're 60 to do it.
Speaker 1: There's the decline of 60 gets transferred over because you're that's your.
Speaker 0: why does it have to?
Speaker 0: that's BS.
Speaker 0: That's how it is.
Speaker 0: We're gonna make shit up.
Speaker 0: let's make shit up to be awesome We're you.
Speaker 0: the cyber body is always a peak physical.
Speaker 1: Think about it the weight.
Speaker 0: so you want to wait to.
Speaker 0: you have all the memories of being way old.
Speaker 1: if you want to copy The state of your brain you're gonna copy the broken shit along with the working shit.
Speaker 1: But if we know that much about brains we can fix the brain - can you though because the the brokenness of the brain is In is an inherent part of your consciousness.
Speaker 0: Now we can fix the brain.
Speaker 1: If you want to skip that part, let's go to another question, let's say to do cyber ization.
Speaker 1: There's like a final deadline.
Speaker 1: Like if you get past a certain point of degradation, they can't fix it.
Speaker 1: Mmm, so like if you're 80 and you're a senile you can't undo that when you're making the copy of you You'd make a copy of you that will stay at that level.
Speaker 0: all these unnecessary complications realistic complications.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's a realistic complication.
Speaker 1: Well, they are for physics and everything.
Speaker 1: All right, so let's say that's not the case.
Speaker 1: We can still kind of fix it, but we can't fix death.
Speaker 1: Alright at what point would you accept killing yourself to make a copy of you?
Speaker 1: That is immortal.
Speaker 0: what I'm gonna die Anyway, all right.
Speaker 1: So what if you can't be a hundred percent sure?
Speaker 0: I'm in severe pain All right, I'm suffering.
Speaker 0: I can't really do all that much.
Speaker 0: You know, maybe it's like a Stephen Hawking situation, you know, I'm not too old, but I'm not really, you know I'd be much better off with a brand new body or I'm 90.
Speaker 0: I'm in a hospital bed I can talk but really, you know, I got some cancer some shit.
Speaker 0: I can't you know do anything.
Speaker 0: It's it hurts.
Speaker 0: They got me on some drugs.
Speaker 0: It's not looking too good.
Speaker 0: No, you know, that's a good.
Speaker 0: that's a good point.
Speaker 1: So here's the thing.
Speaker 0: the the in a perfect world All my everyone I know and care about is dead because I outlived them all those bastards.
Speaker 1: Perfect world question is not nearly as interesting.
Speaker 1: So I want to go back to the other question.
Speaker 1: Let's say it sucks.
Speaker 0: All right, I'll go with your hypothetical.
Speaker 1: I think it's more interesting.
Speaker 1: Let's say right now this world it sucks We know for a fact the day you turn 40 it Your brain is gonna start declining.
Speaker 1: and when you cyber eyes it kills you because they take your brain apart to do it.
Speaker 1: so it kills you.
Speaker 1: all right and The state of your brain whatever physical decline you've had of the physical brain cannot be repaired in the new brain.
Speaker 1: It's just a copy that will never degrade further.
Speaker 1: All right, at what point do you cyber eyes?
Speaker 0: It depends on me right like like.
Speaker 0: I'm asking what am I what?
Speaker 0: No, it depends on me, right?
Speaker 0: Like what are my skills?
Speaker 0: Like am I gonna be able to accomplish some awesomeness way by adding some memories despite the degradation of the brain, you know Is the rest of my life looking pretty good, you know, is it looking pretty shitty?
Speaker 0: Is it looking like I'm gonna you know make you know, it's like okay.
Speaker 0: I can do some pretty awesome with the rest of my life.
Speaker 0: I'll stick with it, you know.
Speaker 0: Or you know, it looks like I'm not gonna be able to do any awesome.
Speaker 0: But a cyber me can do so much awesome.
Speaker 0: It can change the whole world.
Speaker 1: So shit.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: Why so I'm looking online.
Speaker 1: I'll sacrifice myself for the greater good of the cyber, whatever brain power peaks at about 22 and Maintains steadily until about 27 and then declines irrevocably as bullshit.
Speaker 1: That's that's the reality of the world according to all these articles.
Speaker 1: I've been pulling up with.
Speaker 0: that's not true.
Speaker 0: That's what everyone says.
Speaker 0: No, it's not true.
Speaker 1: So Assuming that all these these like theses and all this research I'm looking at right now is true We're at the point at which we will never have the physical brain power again that we have right now.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: What are we gonna do?
Speaker 1: Because I think if we had cyberization right now, I Think within about five or six years.
Speaker 0: I would probably Kill myself to do that and to make a copy Right, like if like if you if you do that, it's like what do I care?
Speaker 0: Yes Scary part.
Speaker 0: that's like oh, hey rim.
Speaker 0: Let's do the podcast.
Speaker 0: All right, you're rim - the To me, it doesn't matter for me.
Speaker 0: This is the coolest
Speaker 1: Me about cyberization is the idea that the only difference between you that gets destroyed and perfect copy of you That is immortal The only person the only thing that could ever tell there ever was a difference at all is the solipsistic Consciousness that only ever existed inside of the old you in the first place.
Speaker 1: We just no other thing in the world could ever tell there was a difference.
Speaker 1: the thing is Sacrifice your own solipsistic existence for immortality for another you and for everyone who ever knew you.
Speaker 1: Isn't that the most selfless thing you could ever do?
Speaker 1: No, that's not the most selfless thing you'd ever do And saving babies from Hitler at the same.
Speaker 0: the most the most selfless thing you'd ever do is actually Completely get yourself killed, you know to save Or the universe?
Speaker 1: no No What about you?
Speaker 1: make you kill yourself at 22 your?
Speaker 1: Absolute peak to make a hundred copies of you that will live forever.
Speaker 1: and they keep coming back and getting internal memory for that.
Speaker 0: it's just the mechanism.
Speaker 1: and have the elf situation where the the Accumulated grief of all the painful things you've seen as you vow to spend all of eternity Enduring all hardship to make other people's.
Speaker 1: I think it's not understand.
Speaker 0: Why can't we just come up with a way to transfer the solipsistic you right to where Scott?
Speaker 1: but think about it?
Speaker 1: The solipsistic you is an asynchronous like basically Analogy that can't actually see itself.
Speaker 0: Well, it's a. it's a bunch of electrical signals, right?
Speaker 0: So you can have like a magnet and you could basically move all those electrons.
Speaker 0: It's got what electron.
Speaker 1: I mean Your consciousness is not any state.
Speaker 1: It's just like a process that kind of starts and stops.
Speaker 1: I mean it is very likely that any time you want anesthesia or you go to sleep even that you die Just the same as if you killed destroyed your brain and made a new copy.
Speaker 0: so maybe we should do it that way where you take a nap and Then they move it while you're sleeping.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then you wake up and then you wouldn't even know.
Speaker 0: so it'd be totally cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: say we say we determine.
Speaker 1: that's true.
Speaker 1: Say we you know.
Speaker 1: say we do understand everything that cognition is and everything the consciousness is.
Speaker 1: and we determine that yes Every time you lose consciousness You'd might as well be dead and a new.
Speaker 1: you starts up with the same memories.
Speaker 1: Whatever the process that you know starts that waking up happens.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm then yeah, you might as well cyberize right away Cuz you died anyway every fucking night.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or What if instead you use make sure you put the new one in my bed?
Speaker 0: So I wake up in the right place?
Speaker 1: This raises a really really interesting question that we're not gonna have time to talk about.
Speaker 1: So what if we you know that that military drug that lets you basically stay up for like a week straight.
Speaker 1: All right What if we come up with a safe way to do that forever?
Speaker 1: So you basically your threat you could have a. your personal physical threat of consciousness just never stops ever again.
Speaker 1: Okay, as opposed to currently now where it starts and stops all the time But the only stateful part is the memory set.
Speaker 1: what if the consciousness itself were able to be made stateful?
Speaker 1: Currently that drives us insane, but that might just be due to physical problems that we don't understand yet.
Speaker 0: So we overcome all of those problems, right and then I could just be up all the time and never sleep.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 1: Why would you?
Speaker 0: why would you want to sleep if you didn't have?
Speaker 0: I mean you could maybe like relax your muscles Cuz they would still hurt I guess Depending right.
Speaker 0: but and you could like take rest lay down and rest or whatever.
Speaker 0: But you wouldn't be tired and need to sleep.
Speaker 0: Why would you?
Speaker 0: you could just keep doing stuff?
Speaker 0: You can see already all night and work all day Raises the right now if you try to do that with this horrible side effects.
Speaker 1: So this raises the fundamental.
Speaker 1: I guess all debates about cyberization are really just practical debates.
Speaker 1: It's no different.
Speaker 0: What is the risk/reward ratio considering these consequences?
Speaker 1: It's no different than our debate about cell phones in the first half of this show.
Speaker 1: Do I do this or this?
Speaker 1: Well, this has this benefit this risk, you know, Apple whatever Do you want the Apple body or the HTC body?
Speaker 0: It's all.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 0: think about if you hey, all right, so if you had to get a body today, right?
Speaker 0: Which one would you get?
Speaker 0: Oh my fucking god if your body had to be a smartphone.
Speaker 1: So the Apple one's totally pretty.
Speaker 1: but Steve Jobs watches you pee.
Speaker 0: It doesn't watch you pee.
Speaker 0: He just tells you which you know, he doesn't allow 20 inch penises.
Speaker 0: He only allows the 10 and 15 inch penises.
Speaker 0: Yeah And they the 15 inch one cost five bucks more.
Speaker 1: But the blue one, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'd pay five bucks or 15 inch pain.
Speaker 1: so but here's the thing You know, this raises really.
Speaker 1: the final Cyberization is no different than any other debate Except it raises a lot of vitriol and a lot of people and people try to treat it as a different debate.
Speaker 1: From which cell phone do I do?
Speaker 1: and I don't think it is.
Speaker 1: I think the only reason Anyway treated differently from any other debate in the world Is that human people who aren't able to deal with transhumanism freak the fuck out.
Speaker 0: those are people who have some sort of spiritual or you know Idea of souls or something like that is.
Speaker 0: the only reason you would have a problem with it Is if you believed in anything like that that somehow Consciousness was special or non or not.
Speaker 1: just add We're somehow real if we decide to make it special or we find some reason that like we find something, you know There's this actual there's this magnetic field and that's your soul.
Speaker 0: Well, we can use a magnet to move the magnetic field to a different brain and you can maintain your consciousness.
Speaker 1: the only people for whom this is really controversial on some deep level are the people who Decided that being human, you know the same humans effectively that existed for you How different from being a raccoon and that why don't we just make something better?
Speaker 1: I think the future of human evolution is that our Information world the world we interact with information wise is already evolving faster than physical things could ever keep up.
Speaker 1: We will never evolve faster than our own information.
Speaker 1: So why don't we become the information itself?
Speaker 1: Why doesn't that analogy one level higher than us be the legacy of humankind and humankind will eventually disappear.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's that's the last question.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that's what I'm going for.
Speaker 1: I'll give up.
Speaker 1: I am so totally willing to give up my humanity for pretty much an iPhone at this point.
Speaker 0: But what I was but you're still but you're just arguing.
Speaker 0: you don't want the iPhone But you'll just buy a pre with money, but you owe.
Speaker 0: you won't buy an iPhone.
Speaker 0: You can buy an iPhone for money, but you're only good.
Speaker 0: You only give up your humanity, but I can't be an iPhone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can.
Speaker 1: I think we've exhausted this for now.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.