Speaker 2: Hey, it's Thursday December 30th 2010.
Speaker 2: I'm rim, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 2: Tonight we have the incorrigible Luke Burrage to discuss with us the historicity of the Bible.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 2: So I know we were supposed to do a Wednesday show this week But we were lazy and we've got some four hours of Luke writing into a microphone.
Speaker 2: so rather than do a normal show We're just gonna put up some of that discussion.
Speaker 2: We had you might recall the previous episode on Spiritual experiences in a thea atheism a theology.
Speaker 2: This is Luke ranting about a very specific problem that seems to come up more and more in At least among atheist speakers where they'll concede a lot of ground that at least in Luke's mind should not be conceded.
Speaker 2: We didn't really edit this so here it is in all its glory, and I hope you enjoy it.
Speaker 2: We'll see you in 2011 if Scott keeps letting me say the year
Speaker 0: Whenever Whenever I talk to people and this you know take it back to what we're talking about just before and I was at this this this conference last year and This atheist conference, and there's this one guy who was his weird speaker.
Speaker 0: He was actually do you know the Cottingley fairies?
Speaker 0: who the fair?
Speaker 0: Yes?
Speaker 2: Yes?
Speaker 1: I know I say the Cottingley fairies.
Speaker 0: is this woman who others woman these two little girls who decided to?
Speaker 0: Cut out pictures of fairies and take photos of them and they fooled everyone into believing that fairies actually existed.
Speaker 0: And you know really good photos.
Speaker 0: I think one and darling yeah, yeah look at a moment line It's actually pretty cool.
Speaker 0: And and they convinced loads of people and it was like it was one of those first big sort of like forgeries like photographic forgeries That people would investigate and work out how it is.
Speaker 1: They just they just made like they just like to go out like to And they put him no cardboard cutouts from a book.
Speaker 2: they and they put them on.
Speaker 0: They were actually I think they they copied onto bits of paper Pictures from a book like like you know they traced them and then drew them themselves And then put them.
Speaker 0: but because they were a bit blurry because they were fluttering in the wind in the old like long Exposions.
Speaker 0: they looked they looked a bit weird anyway.
Speaker 0: So the son of the one of the girls who did that was then was telling that stuff.
Speaker 1: so the people did this work.
Speaker 1: We're in little kids.
Speaker 0: They were They were like 12 and 16 or so.
Speaker 0: they fooled everyone.
Speaker 1: they kept the secret for a long time now.
Speaker 0: No they're dead now.
Speaker 0: One of them yeah the son of one of them was at this conference And he did this bit, and it was a quite interesting.
Speaker 0: But then he got offered to this weird tangent and people started asking him his opinion of some of the world From an atheist point of view.
Speaker 0: and I thought it was suddenly this this this talk went into a into into a weird direction Because there was somebody talking about.
Speaker 0: he was talking about Moses, and this really surprised me as an He's an atheist But he was talking about Moses as though Moses existed.
Speaker 0: and for me Who am a bit of a history nerd and once you know once I actually stopped being a Christian?
Speaker 0: I actually looked up.
Speaker 0: I was like okay So what is actually real?
Speaker 0: and I worked out that pretty much all of the Old Testament up until about 400 years BC Is all bullshit.
Speaker 2: Yeah, yeah, there were like 10 to know.
Speaker 2: this is that Commoginated together could be the crazy thing?
Speaker 0: no not even that not even that there isn't any figures.
Speaker 0: the whole you know people always talk About like this Moses was this figure and this figure.
Speaker 0: so no it wasn't.
Speaker 0: it's bullshit.
Speaker 0: It's all a legend.
Speaker 0: There's Absolutely zero evidence for anything that's in the Bible up until about that the reign of Josiah Which is like you know four or five hundred years BC.
Speaker 1: Yes?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I used to I used to think even up until really recently.
Speaker 1: I'm like you know oh, yeah There was a King David.
Speaker 1: You know because There's no evidence there was Not even close.
Speaker 1: there wasn't a King Solomon there wasn't anything.
Speaker 0: there wasn't.
Speaker 0: and this is a thing people and this is what really annoys Me about these about atheists this these days not just atheists But the whole level of discussion when discussing things with religious people or with people who are wanting to talk about.
Speaker 0: You know religions place in the world and the history of this and the history of that is that?
Speaker 0: Any atheist who gets into this conversation about history Seeds all this ground to the to the religious people and doesn't even consider is there is a guy.
Speaker 1: I forget his name.
Speaker 1: I could find you the book as I have.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this care a million fact right this guy.
Speaker 1: He yet does.
Speaker 1: he has a two-part Google video.
Speaker 1: You can watch.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it's what's his name.
Speaker 1: I can't remember.
Speaker 1: it might be he's Hispanic.
Speaker 1: I think might be DeSouza.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: okay.
Speaker 1: I'll give I'll post it in whatever links or whatever.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you after when I can get a computer right, but basically he wrote.
Speaker 1: He's a biblical Scholar.
Speaker 1: yeah, he studied the Bible, and he will tell you you know he has a two-part Google video And in the first part he basically does a lecture and the second party answers questions Yeah, and he basically says look there's no evidence for any of this.
Speaker 1: in fact the oldest New Testament We have is from the Middle Ages.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right these like none of this is you know he's like And he has a book called the end of biblical.
Speaker 1: That's the book that he wrote.
Speaker 1: It'll explain to you.
Speaker 1: all of you know these.
Speaker 1: this is the evidence we have like the Dead Sea Scrolls the oldest thing We've got.
Speaker 1: yada yada yada.
Speaker 1: You know Hector.
Speaker 1: It doesn't give you his last name.
Speaker 1: It is Hector.
Speaker 1: Whoever it is something.
Speaker 0: Yeah that kind of thing is.
Speaker 0: now I really enjoy reading the Bible especially you know.
Speaker 2: See I just read I find it very dry.
Speaker 1: no I just read the book of Genesis illustrated by our crumb.
Speaker 1: that is pretty awesome because You can see you know he all he.
Speaker 1: it's a straight illustration job even though It's our crumb right and it's in his drawing style because he drew it, but he says straight up look I'm not trying to be stupid here or make jokes.
Speaker 1: I'm attempting to just illustrate the book of Genesis.
Speaker 1: I'm not doing any not changing anything.
Speaker 1: You know you're here are the people I got my translations from because in English right yeah.
Speaker 1: And it's great because you can see just how stupid some of the stuff is like.
Speaker 1: at one chapter There's like a random chapter.
Speaker 1: first of all you see that there's two Genesis stories, right?
Speaker 1: It's like okay.
Speaker 1: God created the world and then chapter two so God created the world.
Speaker 1: It's like wait what?
Speaker 1: and that the great?
Speaker 1: the part That's like stands out the most to me after reading it is they tell this story about like someone who brought someone's sister And lied and said it was someone else.
Speaker 0: and then that happens three times.
Speaker 1: I tell it the same story again with the characters names change.
Speaker 1: I'm like who wrote this book even if they're just making it up a work of fiction.
Speaker 0: the way It works is that you've got in the bug in this and it comes at it.
Speaker 1: It's such a non sequitur chapter - every time it appears.
Speaker 1: exactly.
Speaker 0: let me put it this way This is the way to explain it.
Speaker 0: There's actually the things thing called the documentary hypothesis Which is where that Genesis and actually all the Torah is.
Speaker 0: it's pretty much four different documents Which have been spliced together, but each of those is fine.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: There's more.
Speaker 0: There's more of them.
Speaker 0: There's there's but there's the main four.
Speaker 0: you know those the apocryphal text yeah Yeah, but there's.
Speaker 0: and there's other bits of historical text in there.
Speaker 0: now if you really want to read a good book, which is the the history of the Bible explained I think it's.
Speaker 0: and the other one is and the The the Bible with sources revealed both by Richard E. Friedman.
Speaker 0: I think it is.
Speaker 0: I'm Amazon in as furiously as I can I'm recommending weird fucking typing type in the Bible with sources revealed, okay?
Speaker 0: and So this book it actually goes through and it says this is what this is and they can work it all out by the different Uses of the names of God and there's like loads and loads of different things.
Speaker 0: What's the name of the guy?
Speaker 2: Oh, it is Richard Elliott Friedman.
Speaker 0: Yes, Richard Elliott Friedman.
Speaker 0: So this book is amazing to read because you can you can actually read the different four documents in different orders like you can go And just read the J text and you can go through and read the E text and you can go through and read the D Text and you know and there's these different texts that you can go through.
Speaker 1: It's like you've got math, but if you just stick to one text it makes sense on its own.
Speaker 1: Yes, but when you mix them together it makes it makes That.
Speaker 0: you're saying that's repeated where it's it's.
Speaker 1: it's a story that appears in all the three texts slightly differently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but when they mix them together now the story is in there four times.
Speaker 0: They didn't pick one and okay in in the one of the best bits of this book is where they talk about the the Noah's flood, okay So how many days did it rain?
Speaker 0: and you've got three different accounts of Noah's flood being spliced together.
Speaker 0: And that's why at the end of it.
Speaker 0: They release a dove and they release.
Speaker 0: What else do they release?
Speaker 0: Raven.
Speaker 0: they release a raven and a crow.
Speaker 0: now in two different books There's a. there's a raven and a dove is released, but they would never do it twice.
Speaker 0: But they have to put it in twice.
Speaker 0: now The stories that you mentioned before they could put in three times and just change the names at the end of the flood story.
Speaker 0: the whole point of the flood story is God wipes out the Wipes out the the earth and then says I'm never gonna do this again, so they can't put that story in twice.
Speaker 0: So then just imagine the Bible being combined with another book where a great flood happens say the epic of Gilgamesh.
Speaker 0: They can't have another to another flood in there because God said he'd only ever do that once.
Speaker 0: then they'd have to put in.
Speaker 1: Why don't they just remove the sentence where he said he'd only do it once?
Speaker 0: These guys are not that bright.
Speaker 0: That's the whole point of the story.
Speaker 0: He wiped out humanity and then was gonna give them a second chance was never gonna do it again.
Speaker 0: That's the whole point of the story now.
Speaker 1: Just imagine this you guys who mix these texts together did not do a good job.
Speaker 1: They were not intelligent.
Speaker 0: The point is they weren't expecting that a few thousand years later that many people gonna read it because these were just texts that were Read out in the Bible.
Speaker 0: No, not in about in the in the by the priests and it was Time of history where no almost nobody was reading especially nobody from the other side like no atheists were reading.
Speaker 2: go These were all.
Speaker 2: there were Gnostic sects a lot of them to the notes is the idea that there is secret knowledge that we will Reveal to you.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, that's a bit later.
Speaker 0: That's a bit later.
Speaker 0: these books are in but the way that explain how the Bible was put together is Think that you've got Matthew Mark Luke and John.
Speaker 0: Okay, all of them have got different texts.
Speaker 0: I mean actually within within Matthew Mark Luke and John there's different, you know Documentary hypothesis of you know with source material and stuff from like and they do have some stories in common.
Speaker 0: now just imagine That there were better writers though than the.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's it's more modern writers.
Speaker 0: They rely on like the Greek novel tradition to actually like have structure to their stories rather than like the old epic Structures from like Mesopotamia, you know, there's different literary style, you know, if you read acts, you know Read the stories of Paul and then read like the Odyssey and you're like, hey, wait a second They're ripping loads of stuff on here in the Bible.
Speaker 0: The end of the end of the Odyssey.
Speaker 0: what happens?
Speaker 0: you get shipwrecked and ends up in Malta and this is the last thing he does.
Speaker 0: at the end of literally the last chapter of of acts.
Speaker 0: Paul gets shipwrecked gets swept up a Malta and then goes on to his final.
Speaker 0: and you're just looking at going Wait a second.
Speaker 0: the people reading this like who would been steeped in this Greek tradition and all the Greek classics.
Speaker 0: It's like that would have just burst out off the page at them
Speaker 2: as a purely
Speaker 0: literary device, you know They would have got so much more out of it because they'd have known all the Greek traditions way more than anybody in a church These days would ever pick up on
Speaker 1: that.
Speaker 1: Okay So are you saying that the books that we're writing today that are just full of pop culture references a hundred thousand years from now?
Speaker 1: If someone reads it like 10,000 years from now like a book that was written today Are they gonna think that it was true?
Speaker 1: because they don't realize that those are Clearly the people the Beatles or whatever it is.
Speaker 2: They worshiped the Bieber.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, it's not that but it's just it's.
Speaker 2: and then they'll conflate the Bieber and leave it to beaver and you've got these two Figures.
Speaker 0: and well, it's not that.
Speaker 0: what I'm saying about the documentary hypothesis Is that all of the books of the like all of the Gospels like mark was written You know first and then there was Matthew and Luke but they were written for different reasons.
Speaker 0: You know Matthew was very much a. yeah, okay We're the Jews we're gonna hang out together and we're the new Jewish sick Christian sect and Luke is about lot more.
Speaker 0: Hey, we're all Greeks and anyone can become you know A Christian.
Speaker 0: and then John is way off in the fairyland and he doesn't you know.
Speaker 0: in John It's sort of like he pretty much rewrites the whole history of Jesus.
Speaker 0: now Just imagine someone compiling these four books into one document and this is actually what you have with modern retelling.
Speaker 1: But in the New Testament, don't they just put them one after the other?
Speaker 1: they don't actually mix them together like the Old Testament.
Speaker 0: But in the Old Testament the the priests would have had this one text the southern priests had one text and then the northern priests from the northern kingdom.
Speaker 0: because there was you know two kingdoms there was Judah in the south and the Israel in the north and They had the same founding legends and they had a lot of the same stories, you know.
Speaker 0: And that's what if you read Kings and Chronicles.
Speaker 0: it retails the similar stories But from different points of view and judges has lots of judges.
Speaker 0: It's like the story of judges.
Speaker 0: all of that time should have fit into what it's sort of like.
Speaker 1: It's got John Marshall and what.
Speaker 0: And if you count up all of the stories and all of the people who do that There's no way that they could have all fitted into that one legendary period because they'd have been tripping over each other.
Speaker 0: They'd have been.
Speaker 0: you know Israel would have been invaded so many times and repelled so many times by these judges that it wouldn't work out.
Speaker 0: It's because they've collected different legends from all over, you know ancient Palestine, you know ancient Judah and Israel and collect them all into one place.
Speaker 0: From a literary point of view from a like source critical point of view this stuff to me is Fascinating because if you want you actually get in there and work out just say, okay It's all legend, but the legends themselves have history the legends themselves have legs.
Speaker 0: You can read through all of these different things and tease out the truth.
Speaker 0: Well, not the truth, but you can tease out the roots.
Speaker 0: You can say this was a legend from that culture and this was a legend from that culture And this was a legend from that culture as you can tell.
Speaker 0: I'm really enthusiastic about this But from a purely historical literary critical point of view and I find it fascinating.
Speaker 0: well, that's the So this is a thing so many other people say.
Speaker 0: oh So yeah, of course God doesn't exist which means that could have never been Noah's flood.
Speaker 0: However, there could have been.
Speaker 0: you know The Black Sea was blocked off at one point in the end of and I just saw another one of those the other day Like how the Reds he could have parted.
Speaker 0: Bullshit nothing about it is true.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to ever work out what Noah's flood could have been because Noah's flood is a myth.
Speaker 2: Noah's flood was a story.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no one's trying to work out where the Cyclops is hiding.
Speaker 2: That's the thing.
Speaker 2: No, well people are and people are looking for Bigfoot and they are looking for the lock desk.
Speaker 0: No, but I mean they're not looking at other fictional Nobody nobody goes.
Speaker 0: Where was where was this event in the Odyssey played out?
Speaker 0: It tells you because it says it happened on this island.
Speaker 1: No, but sometimes, you know, where were the sirens?
Speaker 1: they were just in the sea.
Speaker 1: They know which see they don't know what actually to be.
Speaker 0: the thing is There is.
Speaker 0: they normally named islands and you can actually go to those islands.
Speaker 0: I've been to Greece a lot and they're all like oh, yeah This is where this happened in the Odyssey and this is the entrance to Hades.
Speaker 0: This is the River Styx.
Speaker 0: You know that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: It does happen.
Speaker 1: It's actually the River Styx, huh?
Speaker 0: I've driven across it.
Speaker 1: Well, it's just got a bridge.
Speaker 2: Yeah, um, well the archaeology there there was a much more contiguous, you know people, you know pacing things.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean, I should go there I should go there with a ferry and a little and a little a little.
Speaker 1: you know a little stick and then you know Where.
Speaker 0: no it's the River Styx.
Speaker 0: you can go with the barge pole.
Speaker 0: is that you say?
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: That's I guess, you know.
Speaker 0: Okay So the point is that everybody all these atheists and everybody just assumes that Jesus existed.
Speaker 1: now a lot of I think I don't think a lot of people I think
Speaker 2: a lot of people know
Speaker 0: But I have met very very very very few people who if you say to them look there's actually no evidence that Jesus exists They don't buy it They say that there must be because they've been brought up all their lives in Jesus.
Speaker 0: for so many people
Speaker 2: Absolute like super yes, just they just like yeah Jesus and There is no evidence from the
Speaker 0: time until 120 years later when there was actually a first mention that someone called Jesus who wasn't a mythical figure because you know There are either his mentions is of someone called Jesus.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's a bit.
Speaker 0: it's a bit, you know weird that the the name of Jesus actually just means like Savior from Yahweh say Jehovah Savior is actually what his name means, you know, so it's a bit weird.
Speaker 0: I mean it was a name that lots of people had at the time because it was it was a cool still have that name.
Speaker 0: Company has that name.
Speaker 0: He's called Jesus.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so the point is is that there's no evidence.
Speaker 0: and the effort the first evidence that we do have I'm saying outside of the Bible which you can't take it as evidence because it wasn't written as evidence.
Speaker 0: It was written as a as a sort of like a text like a spiritual document Like from a mystery religion in that kind of way.
Speaker 0: and you know, there's Gnostics roots in it There's loads of different roots in it.
Speaker 0: However, you can't take that as historical.
Speaker 0: You can't take any of the Bible historical because it wasn't written as a history.
Speaker 0: It wasn't even written as a legend.
Speaker 0: It was written as a spirit.
Speaker 0: It was written as a text to be read out in a really it's
Speaker 1: funny though It's like even if you look at other Histories right things that were written as history is like well like Xenophon or whatever I any of those things and even though those were written as histories even those are loaded with all kinds
Speaker 0: of bullshit Like the earliest history isn't?
Speaker 0: they didn't even have a constant and even their author.
Speaker 1: I can't even have the number of histories that are like, okay, maybe some of this was true But it was written by a guy paid by the king.
Speaker 1: So everything is in favor of the guy who was in charge of that time.
Speaker 0: even in that way You can pretty much work out that the king who paid for the history to be written Probably existed.
Speaker 0: the thing is we have nothing like that in the Bible Absolutely, nothing like that.
Speaker 0: all of the texts that were written by like say Paul which were you know, the if Paul existed You know because there's I mean he would have existed as some kind of figure, you know.
Speaker 0: But even his name is a bit weird, you know, but there's lots of different, you know Theories about who wrote this book who wrote that book who wrote this book.
Speaker 0: by reading them You can see that there's loads of people have been reading some of them like in Romans.
Speaker 0: But read Romans 6 7 & 8 and there's like four different viewpoints being put forward in this one letter That was presumably written by one person and it was never a letter because people never used to write that letters that wrong.
Speaker 0: what you have is one person saying this is what I think the salvation means and somebody else goes ah Well, I think it should mean this.
Speaker 0: and in the next one someone goes Oh, wouldn't it be strange if it meant this?
Speaker 0: and you're reading it and only from a critical point of view Can you read it and it makes sense if you try and make it sense from a spiritual point of view or theoretic not?
Speaker 0: Not theoretical and from a theological point of view it can't make sense.
Speaker 0: And that's what the Christian faith has been listing the knickers in a in a mess.
Speaker 1: Well know what they did?
Speaker 1: was they had all those conventions where they decided right?
Speaker 0: That was way after any of that.
Speaker 0: well not every.
Speaker 0: all of this stuff was written because there's a lot of stuff which is written Very very late, you know.
Speaker 0: But even the earliest date for the earliest date anyone could ever say that mark could have been written is after the fall of Jerusalem, you know, so it'd have been after like 70 AD say like 80 AD or something like that.
Speaker 0: Yes way back last I mean, but that's a long time after Jesus is said to have died.
Speaker 0: But even then if you look at it How do we know how old Jesus dar was when he died?
Speaker 0: because none of the historical figures match up.
Speaker 0: We don't actually know his age.
Speaker 0: The only way they infer it is by how many times he went to the temple in Jerusalem after he turned 30.
Speaker 1: Speaking of the temple in Jerusalem, right?
Speaker 2: The fact that the Romans There's a lot of archaeological evidence and writings of the Romans and how this happened in this happen in this happen And they never really mentioned this Jesus guide.
Speaker 2: All I mentioned are a couple of Jewish revolts that they put down.
Speaker 0: There are people mentioned in the New Testament who did exist.
Speaker 0: some of the you know People John the Baptist probably existed.
Speaker 2: people argue with me will use things like that and say see it's historical.
Speaker 0: No, you can't do it.
Speaker 0: Probably the brother of Jesus or the the person who was called the brother of Jesus James.
Speaker 0: He probably existed because he's mentioned in other places.
Speaker 0: So now you're saying okay John the Baptist Jesus's cousin probably existed or someone of that name James the just who is called, you know, who is as portrayed as Jesus brother in the New Testament.
Speaker 0: That way he is a historical figure all the best we can tell.
Speaker 0: but Jesus is never mentioned until 120 years later.
Speaker 0: you're like wait a second and then you realize that if you look at it from it like a Historical point of view like with the growth of the early church.
Speaker 0: There was a cult of John the Baptist There was a cult of James the just and there was a cult of Jesus and the Jesus cult was growing and they were just Like.
Speaker 0: oh, didn't you know?
Speaker 0: Check it out guys John the Baptist Jesus cousin and they're like He was teaching the same kind of thing.
Speaker 0: look at this.
Speaker 0: He actually said, you know, John the Baptist baptized Jesus and said yeah You're the guy that we were waiting for.
Speaker 0: no great and they can join together and it was a way to grow.
Speaker 0: the church is because it'll have a diminishing cult in one area of the James the just call and a diminishing cult of John the Baptist and they Actually get together and they join in their little things.
Speaker 0: That's why the like the you've got the immaculate conception story, which is pretty much like repeated for James Repeated for Mary the son or no the mother of Jesus and Mary who's Mary's sister.
Speaker 0: I can't work it out how it works out.
Speaker 0: But also John the Baptist has his own like Narrative nativity story in a way that's been put in.
Speaker 0: I can't remember which of the Gospels it's in but it's right there.
Speaker 0: and you're like, this is obviously another cult leader or another Figure at the time who was there.
Speaker 0: So even if someone like Jesus did exist He was less important to everybody else at the time that none of the writings that we have now could have possibly been about him.
Speaker 0: because it because he started off as if you read the the the the epistles of Paul and they stuff he's Obviously spiritual figure first and then he was you know made into a real person, you know.
Speaker 0: He was obviously like a legendary thing like if you read any of the stuff in any of the epistles like any of the like the earlier epistles that you can actually Say are earlier rather than having gross historical inaccuracies in it It's like you can look at it and go.
Speaker 0: well that is it never even said that he.
Speaker 0: he walked, you know And there's all these different stories and you just look at it and go.
Speaker 0: this is not real.
Speaker 0: Nothing in here is real and yet so many people just give it away.
Speaker 0: They just leave the ground and just say everything.
Speaker 0: that there was this guy called Jesus and he wasn't a great guy.
Speaker 0: And I know some really staunch atheists who just presume Jesus was a great guy.
Speaker 0: They say oh, yeah is a good guy.
Speaker 0: He was probably some peace activist.
Speaker 0: Hey, there's nothing like that in the Bible.
Speaker 0: him saying he's a peace activist It's just they're reading into it were there like new they take all Those poor bankers and threw him out of the temple was up with that.
Speaker 1: I mean to go back.
Speaker 1: I want to talk about the temple of Jerusalem, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz I went there right and you know sure enough there was definitely at least one temple there because well part of it's still there And there's plenty of archaeological evidence.
Speaker 0: It was two temples, right?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean that's the thing.
Speaker 1: is they tell you right?
Speaker 1: This is the second one, but where is the evidence of the first one right?
Speaker 1: Was there a first one, right?
Speaker 1: The first one is supposedly built by King Solomon who did not exist.
Speaker 0: No, no, there was three because there was one built by King Solomon knocked down.
Speaker 0: There was another one, right?
Speaker 1: But what did that one really exist or did?
Speaker 0: then there was another temple which was built by someone like the rubable or So.
Speaker 0: I can't remember his name now, but you know read about it in like Josiah, you know, like the the later prophets You know, you can read about it there.
Speaker 0: Um, and that probably did exist.
Speaker 0: and then it was destroyed.
Speaker 0: and then Herod's temple which was actually built not long one That's actually that's the one that's the bits of remains of it there and then that was destroyed by the rest.
Speaker 1: Another another thing is that even Herod's temple right which really exists.
Speaker 1: the third one, right?
Speaker 1: That there's a small piece of still standing and there's plenty of archaeological bits remaining.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah that existed.
Speaker 1: If you go right I went to this place where they had basically it's like a little tourist attraction.
Speaker 1: They had a miniature Recreation of the whole thing as if it was never knocked down Yeah, and they basically it's like here's like a miniature place that it's like a model train set of old of old Jerusalem Right, and they're like, yeah see that little tiny tiny thing right in that corner, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah the the piece of the wall that's still standing is like the minor retaining wall like a section of it and I'm like Really?
Speaker 1: It was that big.
Speaker 1: Yeah bigger than like all of Manhattan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there is no way that Herod built a temple in those days That was bigger than like all the pyramids and all the whatever.
Speaker 1: and not only did they achieve that great feat of engineering But somebody else managed to knock down the whole thing except for this one tiny wall in Jerusalem the most defensible land in the world before they had any modern military technology whatsoever.
Speaker 0: You go to Jerusalem and you're thinking wait a second.
Speaker 0: I'm the Romans right breaking in here.
Speaker 0: You're looking at me going.
Speaker 0: no Thing is that if they say that's a third temple the temple that they should have built in Solomon's time would have been.
Speaker 0: It would have been like literally like you say.
Speaker 0: it's a rival like the hanging out on the Babylon.
Speaker 1: Yes I mean the Parthenon is still standing.
Speaker 0: So whatever temple If you go to the Parthenon You can actually look up at the walls and you can see the remains of previous temples actually built into those walls Which is really impressive.
Speaker 0: like old columns.
Speaker 0: See that they've made the new walls the new walls which are like 2500 years old.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they may remade these new worlds out of the ruins of the old temples.
Speaker 0: And it's amazing that you say this is an old temple But there was another temple before that.
Speaker 0: so there can be more than one temple on one side and more than one building on one Site, but if that site actually had been built like it's mentioned in the Bible like described in the Bible That would have been the focal point of the entire world like Babylon was you know?
Speaker 0: These walls of Babylon also probably still be around a lot better than it was It was.
Speaker 0: you know, they say that the Romans did a big good job of destroying it.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying that all of the stuff that's written about in the Bible This is this.
Speaker 0: it's not so much my theory But the idea is that the Bible was actually collected into a into a collection of myths and probably by the guy Ezra Who's mentioned in the Bible?
Speaker 0: He was the one who redacted all of the Bible into sort of like the story the narrative that we know it now.
Speaker 1: He took out all the scary shit like the demons.
Speaker 0: That's all still in there.
Speaker 0: There's still lots of God action and angel action and smiting and stuff like.
Speaker 1: no no no.
Speaker 1: But this guy's you know.
Speaker 1: if you the apocryphal stuff you got shit like like Moloch and like so sorts of Lovecraftian stuff.
Speaker 0: There's all kinds of gods in there.
Speaker 0: that was.
Speaker 0: the point is they wanted to have a unified history for a single.
Speaker 0: You know this they'd been invaded twice already.
Speaker 0: You know the Assyrians come down and then And they wanted to have they wanted to have a unified history of the people who live there.
Speaker 0: And he created not just him, but you know the priests at the time and they recreated a culture.
Speaker 0: It was like a Renaissance made it up silent.
Speaker 0: It's not all made up, but they took all the legends.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: What's your legend?
Speaker 0: Oh, you had a guy called Abraham in your religion now.
Speaker 0: Okay?
Speaker 0: We'll have him.
Speaker 0: who did you have?
Speaker 0: Oh, you had a guy called David.
Speaker 0: right we'll bring him in.
Speaker 0: well I had the legend of Michael Jordan and the legend of Tiger Woods Combined all these things and that's like saying all those guys were you know Michael Jordan Tiger Wood.
Speaker 0: they were brothers And they came from the same history and actually their son was David Beckham.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 1: And then two thousand years another go wait a minute Beckham was white.
Speaker 1: these other guys.
Speaker 2: Miracle miracle.
Speaker 1: it's a miracle check.
Speaker 0: this white baby was born of the white man the white the white baby.
Speaker 0: That was the mark of Cain you know.
Speaker 0: No, he was Esau the hairy guy.
Speaker 0: no So what happened is that you have this this bringing together all these cultures into one culture.
Speaker 0: And they needed this unifying document and for me That's amazing because it explained so much that they bring together all these different cultures.
Speaker 0: now Here's the cool thing is that there's this theory.
Speaker 0: well It's not.
Speaker 0: theory is actually written about at the time that when like the the Babylonians and the Assyrians And you know you know Darius and all these other people they would bring these people in and then move the people from one place to another and Then say we're moving you back to your ancestral homes and say work this ground We're.
Speaker 0: this is really cool because we brought you back to your ancestral homes and now hang out here And this is your land and all these other people who around you This is your ancestral home, so don't worry about these other people and guess what.
Speaker 0: they didn't take them back to their ancestral homes.
Speaker 0: They just supplanted people from one place kept them in captivity for like ten years And then sent them off somewhere else or for a generation then sent them off somewhere else.
Speaker 0: So there is a theory that all of the events that happened around about like pre four five hundred BC that are mentioned in the Bible never even took place in That you know in that area.
Speaker 0: I mean some of them.
Speaker 0: it probably did some of those fuckers because they did that.
Speaker 1: They're still fucking us today.
Speaker 2: I read this.
Speaker 2: it was a sadly disappointing book.
Speaker 2: it claimed to Discuss the archaeology of the Persian side of the Peloponnesian Conflict and it had literally like two chapters on that.
Speaker 2: then the rest was yes father But it talked a lot about that exact thing and like even the raising of the army from all different.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know you know the the whole.
Speaker 0: you know when you know in the in the in the Battle of Thermopylae You know that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: they brought forward this army, and then they brought forward this.
Speaker 0: I mean they different people from these different places.
Speaker 0: when they went home.
Speaker 0: They didn't.
Speaker 0: they didn't take these guys back to the land they went.
Speaker 0: well Do you actually want to walk home, or do you just want this bit of ground over here that we conquered?
Speaker 0: They're like oh, we'll have this.
Speaker 2: they're like okay And all the Persian kings would even go to the temples along the way and pray and be like look I am the safe.
Speaker 2: like they try to figure out what the Savior was of the area and be like I'm here.
Speaker 0: yeah There's this whole history of these.
Speaker 0: you know this Persian Empire and all these different empires from.
Speaker 0: you know that cradle of Civilization would do this to all the little tribes around them like.
Speaker 0: you know Judah was.
Speaker 0: it wasn't this massive nation with these old big temples and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: and you know like the the walls of Jericho.
Speaker 0: You know the whole story is bullshit.
Speaker 0: You know there was never walls.
Speaker 0: Jericho did exist at the time, but it didn't exist at the time.
Speaker 0: what they were said that they tore the gates down.
Speaker 0: It's like Nazareth.
Speaker 0: where Jesus comes from wasn't actually a town when Jesus was a boy.
Speaker 0: You know it's one of those things that people don't even point out that the only reason Nazareth actually grew up as a town.
Speaker 0: it Was a town in hit like before.
Speaker 0: Jesus was around But there was nothing there when he was meant to live there, and it was only after like the the sacking of Jerusalem and that like the all the Jews being kicked out and it was decided that that was the place.
Speaker 0: It's the same Jesus being called a rabbi.
Speaker 0: there weren't rabbis at the time when Jesus around.
Speaker 0: They were no priests because they went to the temple and they and he went into the the synagogue.
Speaker 0: there was no synagogues.
Speaker 0: They had the temple in Jerusalem, and he was that.
Speaker 1: so that's the thing that people don't know.
Speaker 1: It's actually kind of like you know if you believe Judaism right.
Speaker 1: it's like Technically that the real temple the one that doesn't exist right now is like an incredibly magical place Where you place it can go you can go there, and you can sacrifice shit to God, and he will give you real fucking power.
Speaker 1: It's like a fucking magic spell yeah, and because it's not there right now We can't do that, but we have to wait for the right time to build it again.
Speaker 1: And in fact if you go there the only people who like we're the only Jews who actually think about this and know it.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like the zenu of Judaism right?
Speaker 1: the only people who are in on this are the Hasid's in Jerusalem who have you.
Speaker 1: if you walk around In Jerusalem right you'll see things like a big golden menorah like a giant one in a glass case And they're like we're waiting to put this back in and you just go and look at it.
Speaker 1: If you're a tourist you go.
Speaker 1: Oh look.
Speaker 1: That's nice.
Speaker 1: You don't realize that that Kate like they're.
Speaker 1: they're waiting.
Speaker 1: That's for the temple the house.
Speaker 1: these are waiting to use it.
Speaker 1: You know it's like This little hammer and a fire axe inside, that's what that is you know they're waiting to Sacrifice lambs and shit and get it on.
Speaker 2: well They're like a lot of the Orthodox Christians even parts of you know Catholicism where you know if this shit is real the way the Book says then why don't we just do this and do the thing that the book says yes?
Speaker 0: Well, that's the whole thing at the end of the end of Indiana Jones isn't it where they go exactly?
Speaker 0: We just need to make this tent with this these dimensions and walk through in this way and open it up in this way and God will turn up.
Speaker 0: and then he fucking did which is awesome.
Speaker 0: But the point is they follow the instructions and it works, and if it really did work It would be that cool.
Speaker 0: so all of this different these different ideas.
Speaker 0: now I'm not entirely convinced that that is actually you know the whole Replanting a different.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not convinced.
Speaker 0: the sacrificing lambs in the temple I'm just going back from it.
Speaker 2: It's got a sacrifice $5 bills to me.
Speaker 0: I'm going back from a bit of the tangent when I was talking about like the the people who who were Settled again after you know the different exiles came back.
Speaker 0: They came back and settled in that area.
Speaker 0: I don't believe I from my own readings and my of history and actually my reading the text I think is it little bit too much site-specific to the places to the legends of you know these places because they're all going.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah and Abraham went there and he said an altar there and then he went there and he said an altar there and then he Went there and then Jacob went to this place And he said of an altar there.
Speaker 0: and these are all like name-checking all of the people who lived in those places And like you know it's sort of like people in America.
Speaker 0: So I'm like yeah George Washington went to this theater and this and then he was And then he lived here for a bit, and it's one of those kind of things it was.
Speaker 0: it's like to make the people Stayed in this hotel room.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's that kind of.
Speaker 0: therefore you should come to this hotel And that's why you know Abraham and Jacob and all these guys all these old patriarchs.
Speaker 0: They all go from place to place and have their own little adventures in these different places.
Speaker 0: They could have all just happened in one location and probably the original stories.
Speaker 0: that is what it happened.
Speaker 0: But as these stores are passed around someone said hey, did you know actually Moses?
Speaker 0: He was buried here?
Speaker 0: The New York Rangers, they're actually from Detroit Maybe not, but this is where they won their game, and they may have had a big celebration here.
Speaker 0: You know that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: so anyway to tie it all back to the thing that I wanted to talk about with this history And biblical history is that people have just got to get over it.
Speaker 0: They've either got to have a standard like a scientific standard of history Which is very difficult to have by the way because there's always you can never be even recent history.
Speaker 0: It's all over the place because you go okay, what actually happened.
Speaker 0: You know 50 years ago, and people like.
Speaker 0: So when you're dealing with history you're always always always dealing with probabilities.
Speaker 0: now the probability that Jesus actually Existed and did anything at all pretty close to zero.
Speaker 0: It's I would say I would say it's probably like a Three or four percent.
Speaker 0: You know just off the top of my head, but it's It's out of a hundred.
Speaker 0: It's probably four percent that the stories which the first stories that we get About Jesus may have been based on someone who might have actually existed And what I'm talking right back at the very beginning of the epistles the Paul's epistles because that's the first writings that we have about him.
Speaker 0: Anything after that is not based on a historical figure.
Speaker 0: It's only based on the stories that are already being told about this figure Which isn't based in history.
Speaker 0: as soon as you have a mention of a character Nothing after that point you can you take back to a real person if you want.
Speaker 0: Do you understand what I'm saying there?
Speaker 0: like I come up with it with a with a historical figure and like Uncle Sam I'm just saying.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying that you tell one story featuring someone called Uncle Sam.
Speaker 0: Every story after that person after that point is not referencing the real Uncle Sam.
Speaker 0: It's referencing the character of Uncle Sam and you can write anything that you want from that Ghost in the shell.
Speaker 0: But it's the same with like all these different characters like.
Speaker 0: there could have been someone called Odysseus But every time as soon as he was written about once You know everything after that was was based on the character that was written about the first time.
Speaker 1: So so the first story was the real deal and everything else after.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, that could be it but it's bombed on to it and it becomes canon in a way exactly canon.
Speaker 0: But there's loads and loads of stories that the infancy Gospels of Jesus where it's like.
Speaker 0: It's like Dennis the Menace.
Speaker 0: He's like killing people accidentally and then bringing them back to life.
Speaker 1: So the real Batman is.
Speaker 1: the real Batman is all dorky, right?
Speaker 0: I'm just saying that there's lots of histories of Jesus fictional histories of Jesus where he is the wonder kid Who's like, you know, like young Superman.
Speaker 0: he it's literally young Superman because yeah walking on water making fish The infancy Gospels in the stories that they tell of his childhood where he's like taking the piss out of his parents and stuff like.
Speaker 0: There's a little bit of it left in the Gospels, but any tiniest little bit there.
Speaker 0: Um, but yeah, that was all there, but they've got honor.
Speaker 0: that's not real.
Speaker 0: But like you say as soon as their character exists You can't take anything from him written from the point of view of people who believe in that character and who actually mean something to them from a spiritual and Theological point of view that can't be taken and face value or anything spiritual or anything historical anymore.
Speaker 0: so the first mentions of Jesus that we have are Complete fictions like mark is definitely the first gospel that the earliest versions of mark that we have.
Speaker 0: You know that the first I mean, there's.
Speaker 0: no now there's no nativity story there.
Speaker 0: It doesn't talk about anything It just talks about.
Speaker 0: it's like a collection of sayings which are from probably from this document called Q a few collections of miracles.
Speaker 0: And then he dies and rises again, but then once he dies and rises again But then he doesn't even come come back and then there's no ascension into heaven, you know in the oldest versions of it.
Speaker 0: So you even the earliest versions of the gospel stories like that are meant to be like this historical novel form about it.
Speaker 0: Isn't even the story of Jesus that we know today with like angels singing in his birth and all this kind of stuff, you know?
Speaker 0: and so it's really weird and I think that people should either have a historical view of Jesus or a mythical view of Jesus But never take the mythical view of Jesus and say there's a grain of history in it because there isn't.
Speaker 1: yeah Personally I think of Jesus the same way I think of like somebody or whatever, you know or anything like that.
Speaker 0: Now at the basis of legends there can be kernels of truth.
Speaker 0: But the basis of yeah, they were Greeks.
Speaker 1: they lived at the bottom of mountains So they wrote about gods living on top exactly, you know, then there is some couldn't really go up there exactly.
Speaker 1: They didn't have carabiners and ropes and that's myth.
Speaker 0: That's myth.
Speaker 0: Where is the legends of Greece like, you know, like Hercules.
Speaker 1: legends are legends, you know myths are about, you know Like, you know things don't it, you know, like gods or whatever exactly.
Speaker 1: I know legend is about like another person even if there might be a fictional person exactly.
Speaker 0: but what I'm saying is that legends and myths they have they fulfill different functions.
Speaker 0: and Because Jesus was either a myth, but he's turned into a mythical and not just mythical But also now a spiritual and theological person not historical.
Speaker 0: So I think that we should always get away.
Speaker 0: anytime anybody brings up a historical fact from the Bible You have to say it's pretty much a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: We're pretty much hundred percent positive that nothing in the Bible is true Except a few things which are also mentioned elsewhere.
Speaker 2: With that is that I agree and I do that all the time.
Speaker 0: I can't do that all the time because it pisses people off.
Speaker 2: Oh, see that's the thing.
Speaker 0: However, we need to in the same we need to rate what's that Dawkins has raised people's consciousness.
Speaker 0: Is that Jesus is a fictional character in the same way that all these other characters throughout history?
Speaker 0: Fictional in the just legends.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we can say spider-man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, there's a lot of parallels between modern, you know modern Organic web shooters.
Speaker 1: No, I'm just saying, you know fictional character.
Speaker 1: I wasn't trying to make an analogy.
Speaker 0: No, no, but there are lots of.
Speaker 0: I mean, I'm not into comic books and stuff But there is lots and lots of analogies in the development.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean I could pick any random fictional character and relate them to any because I mean think about almost every like Like at least 50% of novels you read.
Speaker 1: right there is a character who is a metaphor of Jesus, right you read like.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm like Lord of the Flies.
Speaker 1: There's the.
Speaker 1: there's the kid who's basically Jesus.
Speaker 1: No, that's the nerd.
Speaker 1: There's the other kid who's like the one who always takes fruit from the trees and gives it the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, yeah Jesus.
Speaker 1: right now how many how many animes or movies do you see where someone's on a cross at one point?
Speaker 0: I'm not talking about the characters.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about the development of characters.
Speaker 0: You have in Mark in Matthew and Luke and John you've got four different Jesus's written by four different people and then people identify them as one guy.
Speaker 0: it's like Superman.
Speaker 0: when he first started off was this character and then people who wrote this radio play gave him a power of.
Speaker 0: you know Cuz originally he jumped.
Speaker 0: you can't know buying buying.
Speaker 0: it sounds stupid on the radio.
Speaker 0: So they had him fly and then another guy wrote in the character that you'd see through walls and this other guy wrote in.
Speaker 0: That's what's happened to Jesus over the times.
Speaker 0: He started off as this one guy who fulfilled one function with one in one mystery religion Which was an outgrowth of some Jewish text, you know, you can say that, you know with some influence from some Gnostics You know ideas put in there as well and he had one guy.
Speaker 0: he was one guy He had one function in one story and then the ball began rolling and now he's this guy who does all these miracles.
Speaker 0: He's got all these functions.
Speaker 0: He's like he's he's got on earth, you know, even on the first in the first book He was God on earth.
Speaker 0: but you know He became more of a man and then he goes back into more of a God in the same way that Superman is sometimes way More human.
Speaker 0: and then other times he's like like this powerful figure who just punches all the problems out of the way and nobody can Do him.
Speaker 0: and then you know, and there's this whole different things There's all these different functions with Jesus that have all been brought now into one narrative which at the beginning wasn't there.
Speaker 0: Well, here is a quote.
Speaker 0: if it was there people were more knowing about it, you know, it is a question, right?
Speaker 1: So there's obviously this sort of you know Movement from polytheism right to monotheism, right?
Speaker 1: But what was it about, you know taking all the legends and combining them, you know to make a monotheistic.
Speaker 1: Why was why was that more?
Speaker 1: why does that appeal to more people then?
Speaker 2: because the Romans did it.
Speaker 2: We mentioned just before about the temple in Jerusalem.
Speaker 0: That was the only place where you could in the end worship God.
Speaker 0: now Why was that?
Speaker 0: was it because that was the only place.
Speaker 0: no wasn't.
Speaker 0: because it was because that's where the king was and that's where The priests were and they wanted to consolidate power and all income into one place.
Speaker 0: even in the Bible It talks about the different shrines to different gods.
Speaker 0: different, you know There's.
Speaker 0: there's the the shrine of Asherah.
Speaker 1: Asherah was the female counterpart a counterpart to Yahweh which was you know God they always talk about like oh you have your false idols or get your gods out of my house And they're always these different gods, you know smash your golden calf.
Speaker 0: Whatever the way that they brought everything together there in.
Speaker 0: if you read in the Old Testament There was altars everywhere and they were reading.
Speaker 0: and there was these people worshiping here.
Speaker 0: and these people see people saying we should worship in The valleys and other people say no we should worship in the hills.
Speaker 0: and other people say no we should worship by this Oasis.
Speaker 0: and other people say we should worship at the river and we should worship over here.
Speaker 0: and in the end They went right.
Speaker 0: fuck all you guys.
Speaker 0: what we're gonna do.
Speaker 0: We're gonna worship here in Jerusalem.
Speaker 0: This is you know, this is the financial center of the our kingdom.
Speaker 0: This is the power center.
Speaker 0: Everybody has to come here once a year and this is where they're gonna get atoned.
Speaker 0: This is where they have to give their sacrifice and that's where it comes from.
Speaker 1: Muslims use that same strategy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's not working - yeah, it works really well for them.
Speaker 0: Christians don't have that.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess Rome has it in a way like with you know with the Well, there's the schism and that kind of stuff for them.
Speaker 0: But I'm just saying even now people, you know It's still a place to go and all power resides in this one city One country in case.
Speaker 0: so in the case of the Roman Catholic Church is the Vatican so having a single God which everybody has to worship and There's nobody else to worship.
Speaker 0: So if they did have other shrines to other gods, it would be a bit stupid to say Oh, yeah, this is Yahweh is different.
Speaker 0: This is his place and it.
Speaker 0: but if you want to worship Ashera, it's okay.
Speaker 0: You can go and do that at any willow tree I mean.
Speaker 0: but that means you grow a willow tree in your back garden and you can keep.
Speaker 0: you can sacrifice your Lamb in your back garden and then keep the meat and none of it.
Speaker 0: None of your 10% tithe goes to the priests and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: So there is a really good reason why it's monotheism.
Speaker 0: Monotheism worked.
Speaker 0: it's because it centralized all the power.
Speaker 1: I mean, yeah, it worked it.
Speaker 1: it worked at centralizing the power.
Speaker 1: But why is it more?
Speaker 1: Why was it more popular, right?
Speaker 1: You could choose.
Speaker 2: did the same thing to the Roman Empire.
Speaker 2: This is what I was getting at with the Roman example that basically people in power We're very we're actively using it for these purposes to centralize.
Speaker 1: I mean Julian when he tried, you know, so because so because people who are already powerful used it.
Speaker 0: They just force on everyone the people.
Speaker 2: people wouldn't have chosen it over the other one for any particular One and different emperors and there were different movements to try to do the same thing with Roman paganism.
Speaker 0: Either way, they were like, okay Jupiter's the main guy.
Speaker 0: everyone come here to worship Jupiter and we're like, yeah, what about Mars?
Speaker 0: Yeah, Mars is the.
Speaker 0: he's the son of Jupiter.
Speaker 0: Come on over here.
Speaker 0: Jupiter's a great guy.
Speaker 0: They're going.
Speaker 0: what's the use?
Speaker 0: We're over here agree.
Speaker 0: No, no, Jupiter is the new name for Zeus.
Speaker 0: Come on over guys.
Speaker 0: It's the same thing.
Speaker 0: It happens over and over.
Speaker 0: now if you want to take like the the natural selection and evolutionary view of historical historical view of the Evolution of religion.
Speaker 0: that was a long phrase.
Speaker 0: if you look at religion as an evolutionary system They're not there to benefit people.
Speaker 0: They're better there to benefit themselves.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 2: The self is gene.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if they themselves have a gene which is beneficial to them They will thrive.
Speaker 0: now monotheism great gene you're gonna thrive, you know paying money to priests Best one if you an infidel.
Speaker 0: Right, yeah, I mean if because if you get if you conquer a land and go right everyone here You have to be Muslim or else, you know, actually early Muslim wasn't quite early Islam wasn't quite like that.
Speaker 2: Yeah, well look at the beauty of that.
Speaker 2: Oh, those specific people right there are people of the book.
Speaker 2: We're cool with them.
Speaker 2: Yeah, somewhat.
Speaker 2: Yep.
Speaker 2: So let's use them and then attack those bastards.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah now also a great one.
Speaker 0: What if you're an apostate?
Speaker 1: What if you leave the Islam faith in Afghanistan?
Speaker 0: You get stoned to death you get killed or you get you get put in prison and in the same Asylum, that's how powerful that gene is.
Speaker 0: or that meme is or that evolutionary unit that is in Islam.
Speaker 0: That's how powerful it is.
Speaker 0: And that's why Islam is very very strong because it's very self-serving and it will continue itself.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I don't know how we got onto that, but I think we've gone on long enough.
Speaker 2: I think that was a good one.
Speaker 2: Okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's do it.
Speaker 2: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 2: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening.
Speaker 2: music can't leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 2: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.