Speaker 1: It's Thursday, September 16th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, and this is geek night.
Speaker 1: It's tonight The rest of packs that we didn't spend playing games.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So we're back from packs.
Speaker 0: We did that experiment.
Speaker 1: We've been back for packs for two weeks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we are in fact back.
Speaker 0: We've only had one weekend since packs And I know what do we spend that weekend doing?
Speaker 0: playing games playing games at a con.
Speaker 1: I got to do some laundry possibly tonight because I have stuff going on.
Speaker 1: oh Shit, no Sunday, and I have no underwear, and I bought a bunch of underwears on the internet But they're not here.
Speaker 0: Do you have plenty of time on Saturday?
Speaker 0: We're not running the game until people show up.
Speaker 1: I guess I could do early laundry.
Speaker 0: now you got to come over and record that thing for project St.
Speaker 1: Okay, is that project shit talk?
Speaker 1: That means I don't have to do it because it's all shit though.
Speaker 1: project ast I guess Project anti shit perhaps or perhaps project NST no shit talk.
Speaker 0: So I figure we can get right into this since I know a lot of you wanted our actual packs review as opposed to Just the review of games at packs.
Speaker 0: So I have the littlest little news because it kind of links into one of the panels we did at packs.
Speaker 0: Kotaku has this thing what are the biggest selling?
Speaker 0: Super Mario Brothers games super.
Speaker 1: so Mario Brothers with the pipes doesn't count.
Speaker 0: no It's Super Mario Brothers.
Speaker 0: and like Super Mario Land Mario World Game & Watch doesn't count.
Speaker 0: Super Mario Land 2 Yoshi's Island Okay, and basically.
Speaker 1: so get the gate golden coins.
Speaker 1: Super Mario Land on the game boy doesn't count.
Speaker 0: what I can say.
Speaker 0: It makes me very happy.
Speaker 0: Are you that?
Speaker 0: no are your games that?
Speaker 0: The numbers here?
Speaker 0: because the plate.
Speaker 0: they claim to have done some research and they have the actual release numbers from Nintendo.
Speaker 1: so wait at this.
Speaker 0: all-time sales or release sales all-time worldwide sales, okay, and They pretty much match the numbers I had in the egregiously unrealized potential number one is Mario 3?
Speaker 0: right Mario 1 Has almost doubled the sales of all because it came with every NES.
Speaker 0: That's Unfair is it?
Speaker 0: is it?
Speaker 0: more people probably played it than played Mario.
Speaker 1: It's the same as with Wii Sports where it came with the system and that's why its numbers are off the chart.
Speaker 0: Yeah But I recall.
Speaker 0: but the point is this is interesting to look at because even if you remove Mario 1 Mario games don't sell as much as they used to no kidding.
Speaker 0: of course part of it is that there's this long tail.
Speaker 0: Nintendo keeps Re-releasing old Mario games for you to buy again.
Speaker 1: Oh So when I if I buy a copy of Super Mario Brothers Which because they re-released it identically for the GBA or if I buy it on the virtual console Is it adding?
Speaker 1: are they lumping all those together?
Speaker 0: So I can't tell in some charts.
Speaker 0: they do into some charts.
Speaker 0: They don't Bullshit.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: What do you mean bullshit?
Speaker 0: the game sold?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but one person bought it three times.
Speaker 0: Yeah One person buys a movie three times.
Speaker 1: So, okay So the so the packs and San Diego comic-con attendance figures are totally legit with their multiplying one person times three days.
Speaker 0: They would be if they were up front about that and they didn't say this.
Speaker 0: many people came if they said This.
Speaker 0: many people came over three days counting each day individually.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, but it does raise the interesting point that there's this huge perception in gamers about about what games are popular What games are not popular what games sell what games don't sell.
Speaker 0: and in that panel?
Speaker 0: I was sad to point out that the of the top five games played on Steam every day Counter-strike one six and counter-strike source are basically tied for number one.
Speaker 0: Yep, Team Fortress 2 is like number four and it's not even number.
Speaker 1: I wish they would put the effort into counter-strike.
Speaker 1: They put into Team Fortress 2.
Speaker 0: they started to all these.
Speaker 0: There's a been a whole bunch of updates lately and counter-strike.
Speaker 1: Why don't they update cs1.6 a little bit though?
Speaker 0: Fuck cs1.6.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: Why bother?
Speaker 1: because it's so many people playing it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can sell copies of half-life one.
Speaker 0: I don't think they would.
Speaker 0: they couldn't make enough money off a counter-strike one.
Speaker 0: six Because no one new is going to pick up one.
Speaker 0: six.
Speaker 0: No one who's like I want to play a game like counter-strike thing is.
Speaker 1: it's useful because you can play it on a shitty old computer.
Speaker 0: By now you can play counter-strike source on a shitty old computer.
Speaker 0: I can play counter-strike source on my laptop.
Speaker 1: It would be really nice.
Speaker 1: is you know how they could get a bunch of sales, right?
Speaker 1: They ported the source engine over to all the other computers like the Macs and whatnot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they said they're never gonna do.
Speaker 1: they said we don't have plans for Steam on Linux.
Speaker 1: that you know.
Speaker 1: That was X nade.
Speaker 1: but bring the half-life one Engine over to the Mac and such.
Speaker 1: that'll be pretty difficult But it'll be worth it.
Speaker 0: because you know, it's just interesting that when you look at sales numbers I mean, it's easy to say this game is popular.
Speaker 0: This game's not.
Speaker 0: this game's a blockbuster.
Speaker 0: but and like we pointed out at the panel people Gasped when I showed just a collection of sales numbers of various games Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So this is an interesting little graph and that's all I had.
Speaker 0: I wanted something quick before we talk about packs.
Speaker 1: My thing is quick.
Speaker 0: Also, apparently, you know the anarchist cookbook the book that basically should better be titled how to fuck up and kill yourself exactly.
Speaker 1: apparently this guy wrote it when he was like 19 years old, you know back in 1969 right and he basically did.
Speaker 1: he did it by going to the New York City Public Library researching things and just compiling Information.
Speaker 1: he researched and there you had it.
Speaker 0: So I should point out when I got internet access actual internet not AOL not prodigy internet for the first time in my life My whole family crowded around the computer.
Speaker 1: We sat there and I went a little search and I typed bomb making instructions And my dad was like, all right nice sweet but anyway This is whole thing on Amazon right has a from the author note on this book and he talks about how he wrote it.
Speaker 1: and now This dude, you know being now older and you know with a family and kids and being like it.
Speaker 0: Oh, is this a regret situation?
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's now like an Anglican something something, right?
Speaker 1: He's all religious and good goody-goody now, so he's like man.
Speaker 1: I wish they would take this book out of print because apparently what happened is He doesn't even get royalties cuz like the publisher just put them as the copyright and not him Even though he has you know, his name is on the book.
Speaker 1: He doesn't actually get anything for it.
Speaker 0: I hate to say it.
Speaker 1: It's his fault Yeah, but he's like I. he's like.
Speaker 1: I would be pleased and relieved to see his publication discontinued.
Speaker 1: It's like dude.
Speaker 1: I mean, seriously, no, here's the problem.
Speaker 0: When they discontinue that that just means that some much better book is on bit torrent.
Speaker 1: I know right this guy clearly is not aware of the the 21st century Very much and also has no respect for you know, free speech.
Speaker 0: really No, cuz he didn't say he's not trying to like sue people and force it down.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, but I mean, it's like you should use a lot of no matter how disgusting.
Speaker 1: I mean even a book like Oh, no.
Speaker 0: No, look what he's saying, though He's not fighting to actually get it taking down because the epitome of free speech is saying in the marketplace of ideas.
Speaker 0: This is what I believe.
Speaker 0: This is what I want.
Speaker 0: So what's he saying?
Speaker 0: I would rather this book not be out there bla da ba da ba.
Speaker 0: But because he has no power to enforce that he's exercising his own free speech.
Speaker 0: That's validating the fact that the book is.
Speaker 1: but I would not.
Speaker 1: you would never say right even the most disgusting book.
Speaker 1: What's that nymph at right?
Speaker 1: I would never say I want nymph at to be out of print, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would never wish for a work of art to cease being.
Speaker 1: that's like.
Speaker 1: That's like cheering while the Library of Alexandria burns.
Speaker 0: not everything in there was amazing Yeah, but at the same time in the marketplace of ideas that is his idea and as a bad idea They're their worst ideas.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I would rather have people making bombs and doing what's in the anarchist cookbook then trying to eliminate works of art no matter how disgusting.
Speaker 0: I agree because the anarchist cookbook is a is a device for removing dangerous and stupid people from Society and I really on their own.
Speaker 0: obviously sadly they might take their cat with them or something.
Speaker 0: But well, you know, maybe their parents basement.
Speaker 1: That's okay.
Speaker 0: So we want to get right into packs.
Speaker 0: I know that's what you're waiting for.
Speaker 1: So things of the day in better moments.
Speaker 0: So some things of the day are what the music just told us to do.
Speaker 1: So here's a guy.
Speaker 1: His name is Wayne Harris.
Speaker 1: He's a freelance illustrator slash character designer.
Speaker 1: All right, he's got a web page with a bunch of freelance illustration Character designs.
Speaker 1: most of them are characters that you know Drawn in his style and let me say he has the best style or one of the best style.
Speaker 0: I'm digging that mojo.
Speaker 1: Jojo is captain caveman is like the best captain caveman.
Speaker 1: I swear to God and also his top cat.
Speaker 0: This is good.
Speaker 0: in the same way that remember way back There was that bunch of characters done in the Powerpuff Girls style.
Speaker 0: That was like one of our first things of the day.
Speaker 0: Mmm, this gives me the same vibe.
Speaker 0: I get the same enjoyment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so he just drew a bunch of characters in his style and they are high quality and it'll entertain you for a few minutes.
Speaker 1: And that is very good.
Speaker 0: So what I've got here, I think this is pretty clever.
Speaker 0: It's a hoodie That's just a hand.
Speaker 0: But if you unzip the zipper, oh shit.
Speaker 0: It's a Vulcan whatever.
Speaker 0: It's pretty well done.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know you don't like Star Trek or Firefly or I didn't even know you were talking about Any of those or anything.
Speaker 0: that's good Babylon 5 which isn't that good.
Speaker 1: Even know that you're talking about those things that I don't like.
Speaker 0: so Vulcan means nothing to you.
Speaker 1: It's a Vulcan cannon like Not even Vulcan izing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can.
Speaker 1: Vulcan eyes, you know, you know a piece of metal.
Speaker 0: Yeah or a tire.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right Yeah, that's it.
Speaker 0: You know this thing this thing it does this thing with the hands where you've got the two fingers going in opposite directions in The middle kind of like a shocker, but the ring finger is moved toward the pinky.
Speaker 1: Yeah I know the thing.
Speaker 0: now that I see it Do you know anything about that thing?
Speaker 0: Can you tell me anything about that thing that I didn't already say?
Speaker 1: it's a Star Trek thing All right.
Speaker 0: Do you know what it means?
Speaker 1: It means I'm a Star Trek nerd.
Speaker 1: Look at me.
Speaker 1: do the thing.
Speaker 0: So very briefly them at a moment.
Speaker 0: we were at PAX.
Speaker 0: We have PAX coming up We're doing at two or three panels at PAX Boston and this is not official Announcements from penny arcade or PAX or anything.
Speaker 0: This is just me talking my personal opinion.
Speaker 0: Note that they are calling it packs Boston now and not PAX East.
Speaker 0: I feel like that is very telling of things to come Currently or as they called it at PAX Prime bitch packs.
Speaker 0: But up I'll have words with that.
Speaker 1: if there's a there's a third.
Speaker 1: if there is a third packs, Austin.
Speaker 0: Okay, Austin, okay.
Speaker 1: Let's let's go down the city.
Speaker 1: We're making them at a moment more than a moment.
Speaker 1: So let's let's not talk about that right now.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: You don't want to talk about that.
Speaker 0: Gotta be Austin cuz.
Speaker 0: that's the only good place.
Speaker 0: maybe Chicago.
Speaker 1: I think Austin is currently number one.
Speaker 1: Atlanta, Chicago are highly ranked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Vegas, hopefully.
Speaker 0: Now Vegas is where it ends.
Speaker 1: Vegas is lowly ranked But I want it.
Speaker 0: Vegas is where it ends.
Speaker 0: Vegas is what happened.
Speaker 0: Toronto when you've got too close to boss Once you've got 12 packs is a year all over the world.
Speaker 0: Then Vegas is kind of like the final packs like that is the big pack.
Speaker 1: France Germany, Tokyo, London, Sydney, okay Bear Lynn right.
Speaker 1: so there's some other events that you should be aware of Such as October 8th 9th and 10th, New York comic-con slash, New York anime festival double mega.
Speaker 0: We'll be there Friday night I don't know exactly what time doing a brand new anime panel and We're gonna spend most of the rest of our time that weekend at the other competing convention the burning wheel.
Speaker 1: 10 10 10 Oh snap.
Speaker 1: Oh shit All right Let's not tell about any other conventions, but there is an event that you should know about Apparently on September the 28th.
Speaker 1: There is going to be some sort of John Hodgman Jonathan Colton HBO television something something at the 168th Street Armory National Track and Field Hall of Fame in Washington Heights Not Washington DC, Washington Heights in New York City And there's a whole bunch of information here written in a John Hodgman style that you'll have to decipher in order to figure out the details Going to attempt to attend.
Speaker 0: They're not eminently decipherable.
Speaker 0: You can make good guesses as to what's gonna happen there But really I mean here's an example of the things you have to decipher.
Speaker 1: Quote.
Speaker 1: if you follow me on Twitter Then additionally you should say so and when you check in for the show you shall learn that you have received not only special Consideration but also a special surprise that I cannot discuss further at this time.
Speaker 0: I love quote and his second-person style.
Speaker 1: It's the greatest style Of all styles.
Speaker 1: all styles except for styles.
Speaker 1: who is pretty sure?
Speaker 0: horn blowers Wow, I wasn't sure where you were going with that.
Speaker 0: So packs packs prime 2010 was clearly the best.
Speaker 1: Oh, I thought you were.
Speaker 1: I thought you were extending them at a moment.
Speaker 0: now I'm talking about packs.
Speaker 1: Every packs is the best packs.
Speaker 1: yet.
Speaker 0: Yes, and that has been proven to me because every packs I've ever been to has been the best packs I have ever been to without exception.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: But this packs I've been to four packs is total.
Speaker 0: This packs really kind of stepped up the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah withstanding Tycho calling packs Boston bitch packs Judging by the greatness there, you know, every packs is better than the previous but you know by different margins.
Speaker 1: You know packs.
Speaker 1: Oh nine was only marginally better than packs.
Speaker 1: Oh wait, it was better.
Speaker 0: 2010 was way Better than any previous but it's interesting.
Speaker 0: It was better in a lot of very subtle ways because not a lot changed.
Speaker 0: It was these little touches that just made it better.
Speaker 1: There were some aspects that also decreased but the aspects which increased When you compared them and made a sum the total profits of greatness.
Speaker 0: It's one of those jumps like that year when Otacon just had like eight thousand more people than they had the year before.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess one of those.
Speaker 0: but I feel like unlike Otacon packs that this is momentum Mmm, because the changes are not dependent upon attendance.
Speaker 0: The changes are just basically Enforcers being badasses coupled with a thriving industry that's undergoing a renaissance.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay, so awesomeness number one.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess you already talked about game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's cover the big change like not the big changes But the big points of packs, okay So they moved.
Speaker 1: the main events has been Arroyo Hall down the road
Speaker 0: Which is where the symphony plays
Speaker 1: which was good in some ways in which because you could totally sit down and chill right, and they were able to you know, have two cues instead of this one big queue and It had the expo hall was greatly increased into the former queue room.
Speaker 0: I was disappointed about until I entered that expo hall and realized how off-the-hook it was.
Speaker 1: Yeah, usually the expo halls like okay as the expo hall, but this year the expo hall was OMG
Speaker 0: I was walking around kind of dumbfounded when I first walked in much like that first Otacon where I walked into that fucking dealers room yeah
Speaker 1: But yeah, the Benaroya Hall was was good But the two problems with it were that number one since there was seats and there was no general admission The capacity was greatly diminished was like way
Speaker 0: 2,500 just 1,500 or 3,000 something like that.
Speaker 1: So it was that it was hard to get in there.
Speaker 1: You had to line up way in advance to see any Benaroya Hall event last year.
Speaker 0: We would just wait until like 20 minutes after a concert started and just walk right in.
Speaker 1: no big deal Yeah, because it was one big empty concrete room that could hold probably 5,000.
Speaker 0: But when I saw people tweeting that the concert on Saturday had been going for an hour and they still couldn't let people in Yeah Yeah, there was no because once you got inside you weren't getting out now Right because they were limited seats and every seat was full.
Speaker 1: There was a butt in every chair.
Speaker 1: So that's that.
Speaker 1: The other thing I heard but I did not experience personally because I didn't go to any concerts Was that because it was where the symphony plays?
Speaker 1: Instruments and such were amazingly sounding but vocals were hard to hear which is Good for some like on a Monoguchi but bad for others like Jonathan Colton and you know, Paul and storm.
Speaker 0: So well, there's the third aspect of Benaroya Hall that there was talk about streaming and then it didn't happen at first.
Speaker 0: then it did but it looks like what was streamed was streamed over you stream and That's not so great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but apparently it was successfully streamed.
Speaker 1: I heard to the queue room and also to the bring your own PC area.
Speaker 1: So there were many people who were able to watch the concerts and enjoy them over the you stream.
Speaker 0: Yep I don't know.
Speaker 1: I feel like I was playing tabletop games.
Speaker 0: I don't know what to do about the main event situation of packs because it like anime cons It's such a different idea like the main events like a lot of people want to go But a lot of people pointedly do not want to go.
Speaker 0: So it's usually self-limiting and then like Otagan just has a fucking arena next door that holds like 15,000 people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, I don't know what packs can do.
Speaker 0: There's only like one other big venue and we have it on good authority that the venue consists entirely of dicks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well this it's called the sky something something and only does the capacity of it is not that much more than the capacity of The Benaroya Hall, but apparently they had some dumb requirements and it was.
Speaker 0: it was not an optimal solution.
Speaker 1: I heard they were no good those people.
Speaker 1: I really don't know what to do except leave Seattle or They can't leave Seattle.
Speaker 0: That's like telling the Romans to leave Rome.
Speaker 0: They just build in freighter Greater cities further away.
Speaker 0: build at PAX East that's twice as big as PAX Prime.
Speaker 0: build a PAX Austin That's twice big and PAX Prime is ends up being the exclusive club.
Speaker 0: You gotta buy the lifetime now.
Speaker 0: You have to be born into an admission.
Speaker 1: I think one thing they could do is they could just say look expo Hall we need to have main events over here.
Speaker 1: You're gonna force the expo Hall to be this size.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna let it grow anymore and we're just gonna charge way more money to be in here except for we're gonna set Aside this amount of space for the small guys so that they can get in still.
Speaker 1: they won't be kicked out.
Speaker 0: You know, here's the trouble.
Speaker 0: the expo Hall size.
Speaker 0: this year like last year I feel like there was space where there was stuff I was not excited about or didn't look too cool took up room.
Speaker 0: this year There was pretty much.
Speaker 1: every single booth with very few exceptions was crazy Yeah, but thing is most of the really big booths that took up a lot of space are the ones I had no interest in.
Speaker 1: I do like yeah, but that didn't.
Speaker 1: that wasn't that big compared to say Lego universe or you know Lego universe.
Speaker 0: talk about Disappointing game, but I already reviewed all the games we played.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna talk about games again or like, you know, like look at the size that brink booth, right?
Speaker 1: They didn't actually use all that space very well.
Speaker 1: It was just big to get your attention.
Speaker 1: It's spectacle Yeah, and I think that you know that if they cranked up the cost for those guys then some of them might shrink their booths to save money be a little less ostentatious right and That will allow more of them to fit in.
Speaker 1: you know the the space but the thing is you also.
Speaker 1: the other thing is bigger space in the expo Hall.
Speaker 1: also notice how we didn't have to really Worm your way around the expo Hall so much.
Speaker 1: It was nice and open.
Speaker 1: there Did not have crowd.
Speaker 0: basically there was no reason to wait in line to get into the expo Hall.
Speaker 0: We just walked in like five minutes after the con opened.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz the capacity was increased.
Speaker 0: So I don't know.
Speaker 0: part of that too I realized is that people went into the expo Hall and I think the majority got into one of like the five two-hour lines To do something crazy.
Speaker 0: Yep, like play Duke Nukem or play whatever.
Speaker 0: Yep whatever.
Speaker 1: So what else?
Speaker 1: what else went down?
Speaker 1: Let's talk about any events that we went to.
Speaker 1: did you go to any events?
Speaker 0: We went to the keynote which everyone should go to.
Speaker 0: that keynote and the omegathon finale were the only main events We actually went to.
Speaker 1: well main events.
Speaker 1: I mean the keynote.
Speaker 1: it was a good keynote, you know, it didn't blow me away But he you know, he did talk about sort of like this.
Speaker 1: Hey, you know gaming people you need to get over, you know this.
Speaker 1: Your whole problem.
Speaker 1: where you think that gaming is you know in the you know, it's sort of lower than anything else.
Speaker 1: Just you know.
Speaker 1: Just accept it and deal with it and move on and forget about it.
Speaker 1: People to die.
Speaker 0: the gamers tend to Be much like the stereotypes of gamers even at PAX as much as everyone's cool.
Speaker 0: There is definitely that I'm a gamer dude vibe as opposed to I'm a cool dude vibe.
Speaker 1: Yep yeah, and what he talked about?
Speaker 1: he made one other point about the.
Speaker 1: You know the fact that you shouldn't be looking down on the different kinds of games.
Speaker 1: You know the game is a game is a game, right?
Speaker 1: You know if it gets more people are playing games Even if they're playing bejeweled on the iPhone on the train, that's totally cool good and bad except I'd still I almost argue that by most definitions of game things like Farmville are not actually game now.
Speaker 0: But bejeweled is but jeweled is kind of a game.
Speaker 1: bejeweled is a game and Tetris is a game.
Speaker 1: Is Tetris a game?
Speaker 1: Tetris is a game and bejeweled is a game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Tetris is better game thing is.
Speaker 1: neither of them are game theory games except in multiplayer mode because single-player is not a game It's a puzzle.
Speaker 1: So I'm just saying yeah, but so just say Yeah, the keynote was all right.
Speaker 1: first Q&A, you know typical Q&A had a lot less of the.
Speaker 1: I Think it was because he went to PAX East right that we sort of got this feeling that the Q&A was starting to get A little mushy, you know what I'm saying?
Speaker 0: No, not at all Really
Speaker 1: really because the Q&A I think at PAX East had a lot more mushy Sentimental stuff because there were so many people out east who had not yet already released their mushiness Right, whereas the people at PAX West had released it in many years of PAX.
Speaker 1: So, you know the the PAX West I feel like there was.
Speaker 1: there was a lot less You know mushy crying sort of Q&A and a lot more normal Q&A going on.
Speaker 0: Yep, but there was also the fact that there are only microphones down low not up in all those balconies.
Speaker 1: That's a ball.
Speaker 1: The thing is at PAX East.
Speaker 1: It was one big Mezzanine so they were able to have microphones up there.
Speaker 1: You couldn't really have microphones in many tiny balconies.
Speaker 0: But at least in our usual fashion, you know, we were doing that late show.
Speaker 0: so we had John St.
Speaker 0: John like with us.
Speaker 0: he'd never been to PAX before.
Speaker 0: we just like dragged him along.
Speaker 0: We're like, yeah get up.
Speaker 0: You're gonna come with us to this keynote and then there's gonna be a Q&A.
Speaker 0: Just trust us.
Speaker 0: and I think he was surprised.
Speaker 0: He's been to like, you know bag fest other gaming cons PAX did not seem to be.
Speaker 0: I think the high production values were an unaccustomed thing to people who go to other kinds of gaming Cons.
Speaker 1: yeah, I mean, you know, he was probably.
Speaker 1: I don't know what he was expecting when he got inside You know just a room full of people sitting with a quiet stage and the microphone on it.
Speaker 1: But no it was news, you know They had packs 10 lights aimed at the ceiling with the video screen Hustling and the music and the craziness that makes packs so awesome.
Speaker 1: That was a that was perhaps like a top five hustles.
Speaker 0: It's one of those things were missing.
Speaker 0: the keynote in the Q&A would not ruin my packs But that would be the worst thing you could do to diminish my packs experience.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: I think that said that a lot of people their packs experience is diminished because they just couldn't get in that line.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and especially if they don't sell those DVDs anymore How are you gonna see the keynote thing as I heard that they weren't doing the DVDs anymore?
Speaker 1: But at their at the merch booth where we went directly after the Q&A they had the DVDs from the previous year Yeah, and from PAX East.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they're gonna have them going.
Speaker 1: I didn't see pecs.
Speaker 0: They're not doing them anymore that they're finishing it up and stopping them.
Speaker 1: We'll see again.
Speaker 0: Those are just rumors Yeah, so in our usual tradition, we have to do something to mess with those guys in the Q&A.
Speaker 0: I mean last year we did the action castle thing.
Speaker 0: the year before we asked about that stupid paranoia thing.
Speaker 0: So we got John saying John to go up and ask him if they had any bubblegum and the crowd loved it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was alright.
Speaker 1: It wasn't nearly as epic as it could have been.
Speaker 0: Yeah bean beans an ultra-rare cocoa bean.
Speaker 1: It was not anywhere near ultra-rare cocoa bean.
Speaker 1: It was like it was like wax bean.
Speaker 0: We didn't want to you know with John especially when it's someone else I don't want to tell someone else to do something long and awkward because you know the fine line between awesome and awkward Is raise our theme?
Speaker 1: I think the best part though was when he got in that blow it out your ass line Right at the end.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz cuz.
Speaker 1: Mike was like Sutton Sutton and he was like blow it out your.
Speaker 0: It was cool.
Speaker 0: I kind of leaned into the microphone and once he started talking the Enforcer who was standing there because he was just kind of standing there ignoring everyone like setting the microphone and Once John did the voice the guy backed up and looked at him being like is that really?
Speaker 0: is that really him?
Speaker 0: Or is this just a yeah?
Speaker 0: In the very least I was pleased that I got him to admit that PAX East is just bitch packs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was.
Speaker 1: we'll see how that goes over at PAX East.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see It was.
Speaker 0: it was a an emotionally charged moment.
Speaker 0: So I have to give him the benefit of the doubt.
Speaker 1: I Know like Mike distanced himself from those comments.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's all you physically Thing about better royal hall though every year there's the knuckle crack and this time that guy they did it like right the fuck away.
Speaker 1: Well pork fry just jumped in the line immediately.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz you can't let that fly can't let that pass?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I feel like better royal hall added something special to the acoustics of the knuckle crack.
Speaker 1: I was quite an excellent knuckle crack.
Speaker 1: Seems like there was actually less people cracking but it also seemed like each crack was amplified greatly.
Speaker 0: I can just imagine the guy who like manages better our Hall who's like watching these nerds doing their thing Just watching that going.
Speaker 0: What the fuck?
Speaker 0: You know, there's no gaming or doesn't know what this is about?
Speaker 0: I could see packs feeling like it's some sort of weird cult event.
Speaker 1: We should maybe we should take packs DVDs because we have a couple sets, right?
Speaker 1: Just show them to people who don't know and see like what they think.
Speaker 0: should that be an event at Kinetic on?
Speaker 0: Show your mom what goes on?
Speaker 0: We show Kinetic on DVDs and like Otakon stuff and just be like.
Speaker 0: this is what actually goes out at these cons.
Speaker 1: Maybe I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know we could turn that into something was it.
Speaker 1: Maybe it could.
Speaker 1: yeah I don't know what to figure that out.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that was the last time we went into main events until the very end of the con at the Omega thon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I just wasn't gonna try to run over and wait because how many hours would I have spent to wait in line?
Speaker 1: To get into an event and then if I didn't get in good God.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the only things I wanted to go to other than you know The opening and the closing were the concerts and only really what.
Speaker 0: the Saturday concerts were the only ones I was interested in and forget about it because I was much more interested in the Friday concert this year than previous years because Those concerts I like to just listen to the music but I get tired on Friday night.
Speaker 0: I don't want to stand there.
Speaker 0: I really look forward to sitting down in Benariah Hall in one of those like boxes at the top just ah Maybe with the DS jam into some tunes, but I didn't want to wait.
Speaker 0: I didn't want to get wristbands.
Speaker 1: No, yeah, the risk.
Speaker 1: I think that I heard that they're getting rid of wristbands entirely for now on.
Speaker 0: I don't know how that'll go.
Speaker 1: That's what I heard.
Speaker 1: I think it's actually it's kind of good because it's like look You wait in this line early in the morning so that you can be first in a line late at night.
Speaker 1: It's like it totally just doesn't make sense or work out.
Speaker 1: and I heard that this might just be for PAX East.
Speaker 1: I'm not completely sure but I heard that it's definitely for PAX East no wristbands and I I suspect this might be because The bcec is so big that they can just be like open the doors.
Speaker 1: everybody.
Speaker 1: and who gives a shit?
Speaker 0: I'm still trying to figure out what's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: visa vs food and fucking hotels for the bcec.
Speaker 1: We better get that soon.
Speaker 1: So we don't fuck up.
Speaker 0: It's not on the packs website.
Speaker 0: yet There's that hotel by the airport.
Speaker 0: We could just book it.
Speaker 1: a lot of people are like this.
Speaker 1: you look in the packs forums.
Speaker 1: A lot of people are getting hotels and things or discussing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's nothing official yet.
Speaker 1: So What they say?
Speaker 0: I'm worried.
Speaker 0: I'm a little worried about that because part of the energy of packs is going in and out hanging out like a pax prime.
Speaker 0: We got that one bodega that had a line out the door.
Speaker 0: The guy had to close it to go like smoke a cigarette.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was that.
Speaker 1: I walked up and he was like, yeah, I'm opening in a few minutes and I'm like, yeah not buying anything See ya Man, so Friday besides doing that and playing games.
Speaker 1: It was pretty much just late show, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, we did the late show.
Speaker 0: I got to give the huge shout out again to Robert Greg heel Matt Graham these guys And girl Molly made it happen for us.
Speaker 0: We we kind of bombed the first half.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean, I'm not gonna.
Speaker 1: you know, we don't get a lie.
Speaker 1: We're not someone who's the kind of people who say we did awesome when we didn't do awesome.
Speaker 1: The late show is not nearly as good as he wanted it to be or imagined it to be.
Speaker 0: Where's your teeth?
Speaker 0: caught us a little off guard and we did not recover eloquently or adequately.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we're not the types to blame others either, you know, we should have if we're making a late show, right?
Speaker 1: You know, it's like if we.
Speaker 1: I felt I mean it was my mistake I felt all along that we had too many guests, but I didn't say anything.
Speaker 1: right, you know We could have definitely removed a guest.
Speaker 1: I think it would have made the show a lot better.
Speaker 1: well all people in Retrospect.
Speaker 0: Luke Burge gave us the best advice at all cuz he pointed out that whenever you're doing a live thing That isn't a controlled lecture.
Speaker 0: because he made me realize something about our content.
Speaker 0: at packs and panels at conventions We really control the environment.
Speaker 0: Look at our panels.
Speaker 0: We lie and say we're gonna take questions and then we almost never take questions.
Speaker 0: We don't let anyone the audience talk.
Speaker 0: We control the narrative from start to finish like we make sure that nothing can get in our way.
Speaker 0: But us when we got guests on the show or something could go wrong and there's more than one person on stage You have to have a plan for disaster.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I think we had no plan.
Speaker 0: So when something goes wrong, we'd have the sideways glance at each other.
Speaker 0: But there's no way short of saying I got this to say I got this Yeah, and you can look up at the camera or the audience or the tech crew and every like every heartbeat.
Speaker 0: It's just like awkward meter going up and up and up by a million.
Speaker 0: So at least you know.
Speaker 0: Molly saved us with her awesome set and then for the second half We decided to change it up to see if we could you know salvage it.
Speaker 0: So we jumped on the couch with Alex Albrecht and John St.
Speaker 0: John and the second half is pretty badass I think.
Speaker 0: I think we pulled it off.
Speaker 1: It was alright I think.
Speaker 1: just imagine what the show would have been though If it was like Alex Albrecht then Molly then John St.
Speaker 1: John at the end or Swit, you know either any order Right if we minus the roosterteeth guys, it would have been a good show.
Speaker 1: I think much better.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I think the one thing that we do need to do is that when we get on stage for doing a panel, right?
Speaker 1: we have a topic and we're talking about the topic and It's something we care about or know about or both and we just go off and it works.
Speaker 1: but when you're doing a late show a lot of the talk we have to do is like introducing somebody or Milling about while someone shuffles around behind stage and we need to have things not necessarily Completely scripted but more scripted
Speaker 0: fast forward fast backward to a conversation like six months ago.
Speaker 0: Hey, we need to write like a bit for the opening now.
Speaker 0: Let's just wing it.
Speaker 1: Well, cuz I I learned a lesson.
Speaker 1: it was a lesson learned But
Speaker 0: suffice it to say despite all the like trying to prep prepare for this thing The set that they that they had for us in the camera like it was amazing Pulled through
Speaker 1: for us and there was no failure at any part you know of any enforcers or any of our tech guys or anybody.
Speaker 1: they were awesome and Thanks to them sadly.
Speaker 0: They've got the video up from the first half, but the video from the second half is not done yet.
Speaker 0: Ah, so the better part is not.
Speaker 0: a thing is right in which we kind of screwed him by, you know We realized like alright, we're bombing.
Speaker 0: we got to fix this.
Speaker 0: So we changed it up and we sat on the couch instead of at the desk and then they had to like scramble and change All the cameras around.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, I didn't even realize that that would be a problem.
Speaker 1: I didn't even realize that they would run out of film either like they were.
Speaker 1: you know that we pulled it off and fit within The.
Speaker 1: you know, the you had like an extra digital tape lying around but I didn't even realize that that was an issue.
Speaker 1: You know, there's a lot of things that we just did not know.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, we're good at live and we're good at audio video.
Speaker 1: We've got a lot to.
Speaker 1: we have no video skills.
Speaker 0: I guess T is gonna fix that.
Speaker 0: hopefully hopefully.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we if we if we if they let us do this again and I would not blame them for not letting us If they were our skills will improve every time and there's no way to improve them without failing though We didn't realize we had an idea.
Speaker 0: and actually John St.
Speaker 0: John we were talking about he was like really?
Speaker 0: Holy shit, if you guys do it at least I'll fucking do it at West.
Speaker 0: but you know what all those anime cons do that match Game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we've got that thing down to a fucking science.
Speaker 1: Yes So I was like, yeah We should do the match game at PAX.
Speaker 1: and he was like, oh man And he was like I. she said he said he should host it.
Speaker 1: and I was like Oh because I was thinking he'd just be a panelist.
Speaker 0: but then I realized that John St.
Speaker 0: John he's like.
Speaker 1: he's like.
Speaker 0: that's my thing He and the fact is he's a fan of the old match game.
Speaker 0: like we are he could do the voice.
Speaker 0: He's even making jokes about that stick microphone.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah He we need to get a match game at PAX hosted by John St.
Speaker 0: John And we had a long conversation with him about Bob Barker just unrelatedly who used the same stick microphone.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's the.
Speaker 1: you know, the game show host microphone is yeah, we should get 70s game show host microphone.
Speaker 1: They still use those today.
Speaker 0: I could get one that I found him.
Speaker 0: I was so after packs, right?
Speaker 0: I found some of those on Craigslist.
Speaker 0: how much like a hundred bucks get one.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking about it.
Speaker 1: I could totally use it.
Speaker 1: We could do a game show in the house.
Speaker 0: They're not that good a microphone.
Speaker 0: You're better had to be that modern day or better off with the lobs unless you're trying to 70s it up.
Speaker 0: I could wear that red blazer.
Speaker 0: We could.
Speaker 1: we could use a different microphone of the actual audio and then just hold it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, they remember that at the blade show.
Speaker 0: that was the one thing we're like.
Speaker 0: Oh, we don't have a fake microphone to put on the desk?
Speaker 0: No, and then we realized we should had a real microphone as the backup mic.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh, well, so yeah We did the late show.
Speaker 1: it was okay below expectations But we did it and we can say we did it and that's you know, yep Well, I think it was the biggest thing we've ever bitten off and I think it was the worst we've ever failed live.
Speaker 0: So if that's the worst we ever do, I think we're doing okay.
Speaker 1: We're doing all right.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess not counting our very first panel ever.
Speaker 1: That wasn't so bad.
Speaker 0: Ohio con.
Speaker 1: I don't even remember that was bad in the late show.
Speaker 0: Well, we didn't have any guests that's true.
Speaker 0: There was that one sad match game at the con.
Speaker 0: that didn't give us any guests or any equipment.
Speaker 1: Yeah So Saturday, I know before the late show actually while we were waiting for it There was the like a girls.
Speaker 1: and did you see any of that?
Speaker 1: It was like it was like an IGN.
Speaker 1: Oh Right.
Speaker 0: We saw that it was all like IGN.
Speaker 0: female game journalist.
Speaker 0: now I'm sorry to all of you who are on that panel, but I'm going to diss you And I hope I hope that you know people.
Speaker 1: this will be an easy.
Speaker 1: We'll make ourselves an easy mark to be called sexist by making fun of the game during the female game journalists panel.
Speaker 1: But you just got to be honest, you know, if you think it's sexist to be honest well, that's your problem, but the thing is you will not think we're sexist when we say this.
Speaker 0: and We only saw the end of the panel I saw like the last 10-15 minutes, but half of what we said seemed to boil down to.
Speaker 0: you know We're girl gamers.
Speaker 0: Don't objectify us.
Speaker 0: Don't think that we know less than all the guy gamers.
Speaker 0: Don't look down on our knowledge.
Speaker 0: So statement the first and Scott and I both agree You didn't know what the fuck you were talking about about half the games you tried to say things about.
Speaker 0: but to be fair You were correct in saying that you are not any less capable than the male journalist in the video game industry.
Speaker 1: Yeah at IGN if there's anything I learned right because on Saturday right before our game mechanics and mechanism design panel There was a a male game journalist panel that had big names.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like a guy crow and guy crow and Steven to Tilla who we saw at the Y who is that guy in the middle?
Speaker 0: I didn't look it up because he was the only one who seemed to know he was.
Speaker 1: there was only one guy in that panel Who knew what the fuck you talking about?
Speaker 0: We got to clarify that too and guy crow didn't say much.
Speaker 0: That's true while we were there.
Speaker 0: So I don't know.
Speaker 1: thing is right.
Speaker 1: There's other evidence for example to Tillo, right?
Speaker 1: We know for a fact because after we did the y+30 thing He made a post which I talked to him briefly about about how he'd never played doom.
Speaker 1: He was a game journalist on MTV for all those years and with Kotaku for all those years never played.
Speaker 0: My name's Roger Ebert.
Speaker 0: I've never seen Susan Cain.
Speaker 1: Casablanca Crow admitted long ago that he started gaming in the PlayStation era and he did not really had not played many of the old games.
Speaker 1: It's okay to grow up in a newer era.
Speaker 1: I mean I was born in the 80s, but if I'm gonna be a film critic I better have seen the fucking movies from before.
Speaker 1: I was born before my time.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, I need to shut the fuck up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I think what got me was the technical stuff too.
Speaker 0: at one point They were trying to list like the 10 greatest games of all time, which is be that was what the panel was about.
Speaker 0: You got to clarify greatest most influential.
Speaker 0: Like what do you what are you talking about?
Speaker 0: Best game most popular game?
Speaker 0: Those are two very different things.
Speaker 0: Yep sales what?
Speaker 0: so whatever?
Speaker 0: obviously we're ragging on them.
Speaker 0: big targets for ourselves.
Speaker 0: Here we go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at one point I won't say who but one of them says something to the effect of counter-strike.
Speaker 0: That was a really important game.
Speaker 0: It was the first game where when you died, you're dead.
Speaker 0: It was the first game with like the weapon buying mechanic.
Speaker 0: It was like this asymmetric versus game FPS Realism and he was just wrong.
Speaker 0: He was straight-up wrong.
Speaker 0: action-quake - I mean And I pointed it out to him.
Speaker 0: He was like, yeah, I don't know anything about action-quake - then you should shut the fuck up.
Speaker 1: What kind of game journalists are you?
Speaker 1: you're you're you're.
Speaker 1: you are like, you know Judging and critiquing video games writing journalists.
Speaker 1: You call yourself a journalist.
Speaker 1: You're writing about video games and you know less than me.
Speaker 1: I don't even call myself a journalist.
Speaker 1: I'm just yelling on some podcast and the fact is those girl game journalists from IGN Knew just as much about games as those guy game journalists in that panel Except the one guy who knew what he was talking about who we'll talk about in a second Which is not a lot right?
Speaker 1: They were all pretty much complete, you know from my perspective They knew a lot less about games than I did and if I was hiring game journalists I wouldn't hire any of them except for the one guy the one guy who was smart.
Speaker 1: basically.
Speaker 0: This guy came out at the guy in the middle the blonde guy with the kind of like fuzzy hair.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he ran out of the panel.
Speaker 1: I couldn't even get.
Speaker 0: I walked up.
Speaker 0: cuz you know We've we've had panelist badges our panels next to say hi and the dude literally like he was talking to someone.
Speaker 0: I turned my back to like say something to to Tillo.
Speaker 0: I turned around again guys gone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like not in the room anymore.
Speaker 0: But anyway, that guy remember later We're in the elevator and the hotel and we saw someone looked exactly like that guy and I'm like, hey Talk about your panel.
Speaker 0: He's like what panel?
Speaker 0: he wasn't the guy but then he knew who we were.
Speaker 1: It was really weird Anyway, but anyway this guy he bumped adventure off the list cuz some moron put it on the list I don't know why and he put on DDR and he was like spot-on with that, you know.
Speaker 0: And not just that but pretty much every word that came out of his mouth in that panel Contradicted someone else on the panel and was correct.
Speaker 1: That's right there.
Speaker 1: That's enough You know judging from those 15 minutes of hearing these people.
Speaker 1: He was smart.
Speaker 1: Everyone else was dumb.
Speaker 0: not smart and dumb.
Speaker 0: It's just now.
Speaker 0: when it comes to games and this is said a lot it's weird, but no one does anything about it I feel like video game journalism because the video game fans know even less.
Speaker 1: you heard though You saw those people walking up being like how come like Call of Duty isn't on there or whatever.
Speaker 1: It's like oh my god This is the top 10 games of all time.
Speaker 1: I mean, I understand that you like Call of Duty and it's very popular and pooping is good, but top 10 Not even top 50 dude, seriously Anyway, so this it was funny cuz I think.
Speaker 0: video at the girls panel.
Speaker 0: I hope we didn't disrupt anything because when Scott said the effect of no, they're not wrong They know just as much as the gay of the guys at IGN I like.
Speaker 0: I laughed so hard like I felt like I was gonna disrupt the panel.
Speaker 0: So, I'm sorry if you heard me and I'm sorry that we're dissing you guys so much.
Speaker 1: But the funniest part about that girl panel was when one of them was like, you know, we shouldn't be.
Speaker 1: you know Someday we won't be like, you know getting bikini pictures and other girls like, you know, I've done lots of bikini pictures.
Speaker 1: You know, I'm just you got to pay the bills.
Speaker 1: All right, that's how things work.
Speaker 0: How come I can't get paid bikini pictures?
Speaker 1: I don't know, but I felt guy crawl in a bikini.
Speaker 1: I felt that there was contention on the panel on that issue.
Speaker 1: There was totally tension on that pad and also hypocrisy at the same time and it was awkward.
Speaker 1: But also I wish the girls would have done the panel in bikinis.
Speaker 1: That was the only sexist thing I've said.
Speaker 0: I wish I wish all video game journalists did their panels in bikinis.
Speaker 1: It would.
Speaker 0: yeah, it would definitely I'd love to see an guy crawl in a bikini.
Speaker 1: No, you don't.
Speaker 0: So I'm.
Speaker 0: the video game industry has shit journalism and that we got to do something about this.
Speaker 0: We're no we're not great But we're not a.
Speaker 1: people have been complaining about shitty video game journalism for years and is and you know What even the shitty game journalists are complaining about shitty video game journalism and there's nothing we can do about it Except keep doing this podcast or our project st.
Speaker 1: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: Oh shit anyway.
Speaker 1: So, yeah, we those are the two panels that happen before our panels.
Speaker 1: then we did them.
Speaker 1: we did the game theory mechanism.
Speaker 0: I don't think this time to talk about our panels because while we didn't do so well in the late show I feel like game mechanics and mechanism design we hit that one out of the fucking park.
Speaker 1: You know who wrote that panel?
Speaker 0: Uh, you did that's right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was a good panel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no all the panels.
Speaker 1: I'm writing lately a plus panels.
Speaker 1: You're writing lately a minus.
Speaker 0: Well depends on which panel I got my out.
Speaker 0: my music panel for the anime cons is really good Regis.
Speaker 0: the problem was I had to rewrite the whole second pass.
Speaker 0: I have the panel at the con when we notice stuff at the con.
Speaker 0: Mmm, but I got an idea.
Speaker 0: So I'm splitting egregious into a new panel and we got this crazy idea I want to.
Speaker 1: I want to try to get the Miku panel at magfest because it is music related.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I proposed that and the anime openers panel both of them just to see what they want.
Speaker 0: mmm We'll see.
Speaker 0: we're probably gonna do two or so panels at magfest, but that's neither here nor there.
Speaker 1: would it be?
Speaker 1: Unprofessional to go to the New York Comic Con with our one panel and do a different panel than the one we're scheduled to do?
Speaker 0: That would be interesting I don't.
Speaker 0: the thing is that the title and description of the panel for New York Comic Con that I gave them is pretty damn generic.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: Let's let's work within those bounds and push it pretty far.
Speaker 0: We only have to talk about anime that people didn't think they'd like.
Speaker 0: that's pretty damn vague.
Speaker 1: All right, we could talk about shitty anime that you really won't like alright, so Game mechanics mechanism design.
Speaker 0: when we did this panel and it's funny because I have two questions that we took at the end were about The panel as opposed to like this meta stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know I put up Scott's rules of question asking which which a deleted a lot of question asking time, which is Purposeful, but then the question that you see it didn't actually violate any of your rules because everyone was really interested in the answer.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it was still off topic.
Speaker 1: It wasn't about the you know, it was about the panel.
Speaker 1: It was meta.
Speaker 0: It wasn't on but you didn't say no meta.
Speaker 1: It had to.
Speaker 0: you've got to add another.
Speaker 1: it needs to be about.
Speaker 1: You know the topic of the panel.
Speaker 0: Yes, you have to write another really about the panel.
Speaker 0: You have to make a rule.
Speaker 1: that doesn't need to be a rule.
Speaker 1: It's already part of the on topic rule.
Speaker 0: now because I'm interpreting the on topic rule too broadly I would argue that everyone interpreted that way.
Speaker 1: Only one guy asked about the panel, but
Speaker 0: the panel was enough that at least one unnamed studio Apparently the previous year a big game studio one of their employees saw one of our panels I think it was beyond D&D beyond Candyland and they told other people at this company to come to this panel this year and Then we were talking to them.
Speaker 0: They're totally cool dudes and we learned some stuff.
Speaker 0: there are some about some big games Not new upcoming games, but old games.
Speaker 1: They didn't tell us anything secret because they were very good at secret-keeping.
Speaker 0: But it was interesting to talk to them and we might have cool things to be doing with them in the future.
Speaker 0: Oh, that was very kind of touching and cool that that happened.
Speaker 1: Yeah They also told us about some other games that they don't even make that they thought were cool that we like.
Speaker 1: For example Uniwar is a really good iPhone game.
Speaker 1: if you like advanced wars with hexes Oh my god that.
Speaker 0: and I'm getting real close to the end of my sprint contract.
Speaker 1: Civ 5 comes out a week from today.
Speaker 0: Oh fuck.
Speaker 1: No Tuesday, so today's Thursday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's like countdown to the end of my life.
Speaker 1: All right, so five days.
Speaker 0: But we really like we hit this one out of the park Like the audience was on the edge of their of their seats the entire late show.
Speaker 1: The room was emptying as we did a late show But as we did the game theory making the design panel the room was filling as we did the panel.
Speaker 1: That's how you know, it's good when it fills.
Speaker 0: It was very hard to get away.
Speaker 0: We had to basically tell everyone to get out of the room and
Speaker 1: I Left a whole bunch of stuff behind because I had to get out because the next panel was setting up Yeah,
Speaker 0: and I was trying to leave the room and we were basically mobbed by people for the rest of the night as a result Of this panel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and for the rest of the con.
Speaker 1: no one came up and told us Oh, man, your late show was awesome or anything like that.
Speaker 1: They just told us.
Speaker 1: they kept telling us that our game theory make the design panel was awesome You know and they saw it.
Speaker 1: So that was totally sweet.
Speaker 1: So don't worry We need to get our quality panel on Friday instead of Saturday next time.
Speaker 1: that's all I want.
Speaker 1: Let's just put our best panel on Friday at like noon or one.
Speaker 1: That's all I want.
Speaker 1: Well, even if we only do one panel, let's do that.
Speaker 0: We are very likely at PAX East this upcoming year doing that panel again and either this obviously got to do that panel again Yeah, and either the sequel to it or the triple threat Maybe both.
Speaker 0: we'll see.
Speaker 1: we can't do a sequel to a panel at the same con as the prequel.
Speaker 0: I think you can because they're two standalone panels.
Speaker 1: now We should do something else as the other panel now because it's just.
Speaker 0: we're not calling it as an equal It's not actually a sequel It just it Covers all the things that people went to the first panel had questions about and it's basically its own panel.
Speaker 1: Whatever anyway.
Speaker 1: So then we did the very last panel of the whole con.
Speaker 0: We did egregiously unrealized our last panel the cons last panel.
Speaker 1: Literally this panel ended and then immediately after the omega-thon finale began And we got to thank Aaron see again for helping us get into the omega.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, basically now we finish the panel We tell everyone all right, we're out of here We run Aaron gets us and he puts us up in the VIP box and then immediately the omega-thon finale starts.
Speaker 1: That was the best I did it.
Speaker 0: I don't know what I would have done if I didn't make it.
Speaker 0: That was crazy, but I was very surprised that a lot of people came to that panel.
Speaker 0: It seemed like about half of them came because they saw the other panel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a lot of people there were repeat people.
Speaker 1: I knew that they were at the other panel.
Speaker 1: a lot of people just couldn't get an end to the omega-thon finale didn't want to bother or you know, whatever You know, it was in a smaller room the Raven theater.
Speaker 1: It was so late in the con.
Speaker 1: I think that's.
Speaker 1: another thing is the timing is very important.
Speaker 1: You know the timing of our game theory mechanism sign panel had a very good timing, right?
Speaker 1: But the late show I didn't realize how much packs clears out at night.
Speaker 1: it empties right and also Except tabletop except tabletop and also the.
Speaker 1: you know, the packs also empties, you know around towards the end.
Speaker 1: there You know, if you're not going to the closing ceremonies, there's only one panel and everything else is starting to shut down.
Speaker 1: So there weren't too many people around to go to our Egregiously unrealized potential panel.
Speaker 1: So the number that showed up was pretty impressive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we almost filled the room.
Speaker 0: There were only like 20 seats in the back that weren't filled.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was pretty good And it was more.
Speaker 0: it was definitely more of a us ranting about games.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think the educational panels are definitely way better and inspiring but the you know A ranting panel can be alright as long as you don't do too many of them, you know or rent too much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we can use the fine line because sometimes the pure entertainment panel is good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's good It's just you know, it's not amazing.
Speaker 0: well the thing is if you want to bowl people over you have to do the Amazing panel where people feel enlightened or you have to go all out and do the uncle yo Like I am doing.
Speaker 0: doing.
Speaker 1: doing the rant panel is more like playing the woo game.
Speaker 1: Right, cuz it's like I have this gripe.
Speaker 1: Whoo.
Speaker 1: I agree boo.
Speaker 0: I disagree Yeah, and that's you know, of course by talking about the woo game.
Speaker 0: We got people to not play the woo game.
Speaker 0: Very good Yeah.
Speaker 0: And also I don't think anyone had really considered the potential of a Pokemon MMO.
Speaker 0: like no one in the room.
Speaker 0: They're like, all right, where they going with this where they going with this where they going with this.
Speaker 0: Then we were like Pokemon MMO and they were like, oh shit change the world destroy the world.
Speaker 1: That's the I mean Civ 5 poop on a stick compared to Pokemon MMO.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Pokemon MMO is one of the only things that could possibly pull me away from natural selection.
Speaker 1: 3 tribes 3.
Speaker 1: Yeah, can't beat Pokemon MMO Even if it's a stupid grinding game that I hate and I will hate it.
Speaker 1: I'll play it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, this is Pokemon.
Speaker 1: It's the goddamn Pokemon MMO.
Speaker 1: I'll pay monthly fee.
Speaker 0: So the Omega thon finale was off the hook.
Speaker 1: now The thing is I have never successfully predicted the Omega thon finale, right?
Speaker 1: I mean the closest I came was when it was skee-ball right after they revealed it.
Speaker 1: I was like I should have known.
Speaker 1: Right, it felt like it was on the tip of your tongue kind of situation.
Speaker 1: But in fact the Megathon finale this year I had predicted a year in advance.
Speaker 1: However, you went actually wrong one.
Speaker 1: That's like betting.
Speaker 0: I like I bet that the Mets are gonna win this year and they lose and they win the next year.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: and then when we were actually sitting and we actually sat down or waiting for the curtains to open and reveal The the game I couldn't think of a goddamn game and save my life.
Speaker 1: It was just a drawing a total blank.
Speaker 0: and then he's like, it's an old.
Speaker 0: he gave three clues.
Speaker 1: He said the game was ancient.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I was trying to source man.
Speaker 1: It was so gather It was a it was a turn-taking game and it was a resource gathering game.
Speaker 1: And as soon as he said resource gathering game I knew that it was the crane.
Speaker 1: and I said it's the crane.
Speaker 1: And when he opened the curtain behold the Omega crane This was definitely the best I had guessed it correct with like five seconds before finale.
Speaker 0: to date it the the the fact had the little microphone.
Speaker 0: you heard the individual quarters going in it.
Speaker 1: that was that was whoever whichever tech guy was so smart to put a Microphone near the coin slot and to put a microphone near the speaker that played the carnival music and then like they had these prepared Jokes, but they pulled them off.
Speaker 1: So effortlessly like Tyka Tyka was like we have these quarters in our pockets much like your father.
Speaker 0: And then complicated world.
Speaker 1: and then every time the machine didn't work is like it.
Speaker 1: the world is a complicated place.
Speaker 0: But it was amazing especially it might have been Benaroya Hall that added to the air of excitement because it was silent and you just hear the movements and Then the crowd would just lose their shit every.
Speaker 1: and they filled the crane with the most amazing stuffed animals from various video game TV.
Speaker 1: yeah, of course Robert who was the only one who could pull out two toys with one crane press Sadly one of the Omega knots as is every omega-thon finale He was hopelessly outmatched, but was it really skill?
Speaker 1: or you know, I mean, I think it was skill.
Speaker 0: He kept going for some things.
Speaker 0: He shouldn't have gone for it's true.
Speaker 1: I mean look how many turns by when no one went for the lying sideways.
Speaker 1: Kingdom Hearts guy, right?
Speaker 1: They pulled it out and it was laying sideways but no one went for it.
Speaker 1: after all those turns They'll eventually they went like didn't Mike pull it out in the end.
Speaker 1: I think right?
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 1: The point was that they made the crane so epic, you know, even though you know Until the point where one guy was dominating it was so tense because like they would pull it's moving.
Speaker 1: He's got it lifted in the crane and then he drops it.
Speaker 0: Ah, and just the magnitude of the crowd reaction was it was actually kind of overpowering.
Speaker 1: I have an idea.
Speaker 1: We need an ARP, you know how dread uses Jenga set.
Speaker 1: We need an RPG that uses the crane game uses the crane game.
Speaker 0: Also, I know for the first time ever zero technical problems started immediately.
Speaker 1: I think a crane right.
Speaker 1: they had notice.
Speaker 1: It was a brand new crane machine that they had restyled to be the Omega crane.
Speaker 1: It was not an old skeeball machine.
Speaker 1: It was not an old Famicom right from Japan with a disk system, right?
Speaker 1: It was not Four separate Nintendo some of which weren't actual Nintendo's with different cartridges lined up in a row.
Speaker 1: This was something that had a very low chance of failure seeing it was a brand new machine.
Speaker 1: They set it up on time.
Speaker 1: You know, it was.
Speaker 1: it was good to go.
Speaker 1: It had extensive testing, right?
Speaker 1: I hope that in the future They will also do the same thing and not use incredibly old technology to run the omegathon finale Instead opt for things such as emulation.
Speaker 0: I really want the omegathon finale to be like nerf fencing or something.
Speaker 1: I want it to be one of those electro mechanical games much like you see in the retro arcade museum Huh?
Speaker 0: Wonder if we could try to perhaps a gun game.
Speaker 0: Ah It's shooting.
Speaker 1: Here are two clocks or perhaps pinball The oldest variety.
Speaker 0: Remember the trouble is you don't necessarily want a good game.
Speaker 0: You want a game where the reveal itself will have the crowd go.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: Ping-pong has well other Table tennis again the other fatal flaw.
Speaker 0: You can't use a game where someone who has some amount of skill Will completely and without question dominate the other guy like if it was a ping-pong thing.
Speaker 0: Someone who has played ping-pong before will just win completely against someone who is not.
Speaker 0: Yep, like there is no chance I think that's why.
Speaker 1: but even when they went with a come basically sort of a random game like the crane It's still one person dominated.
Speaker 0: because their skill and the omegathon is not good at selecting generic game skill?
Speaker 0: No, not at all.
Speaker 0: What they need to do is select for drama and drama alone.
Speaker 0: pick games that cause nothing but drama.
Speaker 0: But they can't be random because then it's no more drama than a roulette table.
Speaker 1: hmm roulette I thought of roulette, but I immediately cancel it out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe poker cuz I think doing roulette playing roulette for a prize a chess box Japan would not go over.
Speaker 0: Well, what about chess box?
Speaker 0: You would need the Gaming Commission.
Speaker 0: I would play chess boxing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can't have people going to the hospital either.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you get them to sign some waivers.
Speaker 1: I think that the big sumo suits would be a good choice.
Speaker 1: Right, I mean come on yeah or that the joust, you know not joust with it with the with the ostriches joust set.
Speaker 0: American gladiators American gladiators See my crab people.
Speaker 0: Well, no, remember we had that idea that the Build the agro crag behind stage or make a double dare set double dare set.
Speaker 0: Oh man double dare set.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 0: So I know packs was awesome and We didn't do much else other than play games and do all the things that we just said we did.
Speaker 0: I mean we hung out with John st John for most of Friday and then Saturday we let in Sunday.
Speaker 0: We let him go off and do his own thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah Oh, I can't I can't think of anything else.
Speaker 0: Well, we had all the weird meta stuff like on Friday, right a lot of people have talked about this.
Speaker 0: No, we we invited John st John and also the enforcers pulled in and brought him to packs of our own volition.
Speaker 0: None of us knew Duke Nukem forever was coming.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, but not at not a clue.
Speaker 1: We did it solely because we needed a guest for the late show.
Speaker 1: We knew that he went to bag fest and was amicable and he was awesome.
Speaker 0: So we give him a ring So and it worked out and we're hanging out with him.
Speaker 0: We're having lunch at Von's on like Friday afternoon and suddenly Twitter fucking explodes with Duke Duke and forever.
Speaker 0: Duke Nukem forever.
Speaker 0: And I'm like what Duke Duke him forever is trending and he looks at us.
Speaker 0: He's like, oh shit I didn't leak anything did I?
Speaker 1: and we're like, oh shit.
Speaker 1: He just said he was worried about leaking something.
Speaker 1: That means it's for real.
Speaker 0: and then he's like, yeah You guys have probably figured it out by now.
Speaker 0: And then we talked about the whole story that we didn't even fucking know.
Speaker 0: and he was like, yeah all these rumors started because of you guys in this late show, but And we had to wait for it and then if it happens and then of course right after the meal We went to the expo hall and sure enough turn up.
Speaker 1: There was Duke Nukem forever.
Speaker 0: There was.
Speaker 0: he snuck me into the back room.
Speaker 0: I got to play it and see the little spiel and everything.
Speaker 0: It's real.
Speaker 0: I played it.
Speaker 0: It's a game but that was quite a moment.
Speaker 0: packs has never trended before but packs now trended only because Duke Nukem forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Duke Nukem forever trended and then packs trended right after it on Twitter.
Speaker 1: Yeah Man, what other it's really.
Speaker 1: it's so cuz.
Speaker 1: I were just remember playing games so much.
Speaker 1: They don't really remember much else.
Speaker 0: We did a whole show on the games.
Speaker 0: We played.
Speaker 1: I know there was the hidden level.
Speaker 1: We could talk about the hidden level a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah over at the annex.
Speaker 1: So basically the annex.
Speaker 1: since we we went to the annex and packs away and then impacts o9.
Speaker 1: It was not used in packs 10.
Speaker 1: It was used again and had been renovated which is very nice.
Speaker 1: Excellent renovation Good job construction workers and architects and so forth.
Speaker 1: The thing was the only way to get there was to go through the secret elevator in the back of the expo hall and it Was cool because it was the hidden level.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yet a lot of people found their way to the hidden level no problem And it was pretty crowded back there and that was where all the watsy stuff was.
Speaker 1: and we're all the other Tabletop game people had like their booths and some gaming merchants were back there.
Speaker 1: It was it was a good area.
Speaker 1: But the thing that was disappointing Was that there was another area of the annex that was still unused and I think everyone agreed and sort of knows That if they had moved the free tabletop to that area, it would have been a lot.
Speaker 1: It would be much preferred, but we don't know if it's actually tricky.
Speaker 0: you need for good tabletop.
Speaker 0: Many smaller rooms is much better than the standard gaming con one big room.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 1: However, more space and more tables is always welcome.
Speaker 0: I would do both somehow or I would turn that other space Either I would try to make all of tabletop be in the annex like fill the annex and put like one more panel room over There.
Speaker 0: that is just for tabletop ERPG.
Speaker 1: Well, one thing I would do is I would put some tabletop into the Raven Theatre and move the Raven Theatre over there.
Speaker 1: That's a good idea.
Speaker 0: Well, we don't know how big the space is.
Speaker 0: I only poked around.
Speaker 0: We couldn't.
Speaker 1: it was ropes blocking off that extra unused.
Speaker 0: later I snuck over there and poked around but most of the doors were locked.
Speaker 1: So yeah Nothing not much.
Speaker 0: but or what I would do is I would use that area to just add one thing that Pax Prime is lacking the art show.
Speaker 0: That's the thing that Pax really needs.
Speaker 0: and if they get that extra space and they put it there It's just a people funnel to get people out of the rest of the con and it doesn't detract from anything else.
Speaker 1: Both Pax is.
Speaker 1: the one thing I think both of them are missing is some way cuz you know at Otacon you have Dealers room artists alley and dealers.
Speaker 1: room was people with money and artists alleys for everyone else, right?
Speaker 1: Pax has the expo hall of people with money and if you don't have money, that's it, right?
Speaker 1: They need to have that sort of sub expo hall.
Speaker 1: like me, you know That is where the normal people can go to get a booth or to put display there.
Speaker 1: do-it-yourself.
Speaker 1: You know user generated content kind of action, you know Really really really indie studios, you know the artists.
Speaker 1: all that stuff needs a place at Pax and it doesn't have one right now and Hopefully with the more space in the BC EC and the annex edition it can happen, but we'll see.
Speaker 0: Yep We shall see indeed.
Speaker 1: The big thing is they have a philosophy of do it right or don't do it at all.
Speaker 1: So I think that they're trying to figure out how to do except with the late shot.
Speaker 0: Now that was awesome
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: so the sumos a bunch of enforcers were taking them home and we just heard this from literally a Random guy and the total
Speaker 1: rumor from guy in guy in a lobby that
Speaker 0: the sumos might be not Appearing at Pax in the future because the sumo company kind of doesn't want to give them a discount anymore.
Speaker 1: Because yeah, I don't want to take me like five minutes to explain it all but there might not be sumos.
Speaker 1: We don't know the deal but a bunch of enforcers got to take sumos home.
Speaker 1: So good for them.
Speaker 0: See now what I would have done if I were Pax is let enforcers sign them out and keep them all year.
Speaker 0: All they have to do is bring them back to Pax.
Speaker 1: I think that's what they were doing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I don't know what they're doing now.
Speaker 1: It's getting weird.
Speaker 1: So we'll say.
Speaker 1: the thing is what'll Pax be without sumos?
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I didn't go in the sumos once this pass.
Speaker 0: I was too busy doing shit.
Speaker 1: I was playing games instead.
Speaker 1: Yeah tabletop instead of DS.
Speaker 0: There were scalpers in front of Pax.
Speaker 0: scalping is starting to be an issue So I don't want to get it.
Speaker 0: notice how.
Speaker 1: it's not an issue of Pax East only at Pax West.
Speaker 0: Well, it'll it'll be.
Speaker 0: if it issue of Pax East.
Speaker 0: you think so.
Speaker 0: I am so sure.
Speaker 1: I don't know So one.
Speaker 0: we were talking to enforcers and things and I'm sure there will be some way to make this a better.
Speaker 0: We got some cool ideas, but all that aside if you want to go to Pax or you think you want to go to Pax Just pre register the day it goes online.
Speaker 0: There's no reason not to.
Speaker 0: you can resell your badge and if Pax is guaranteed to sell out You're guaranteed to be able to resell the badge if you don't attend.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you if you have an inkling that you want to go to any Pax East or West the day the pre-orders go on Don't hesitate.
Speaker 1: just pre-order.
Speaker 1: boom immediately, right?
Speaker 1: You'll get the badge in the mail and if it turns out that something happens at the last minute You can't actually go sell the badge legitimately not like a scalper, right?
Speaker 1: You're only selling the one badge or two badges you bought.
Speaker 1: you're not scalping 500 like that jerk, right?
Speaker 1: The Cool odd.
Speaker 0: some in some enterprising penny arcade and packed staff decided that the best way to deter that one scalper Let's just walk out and start videoing him and taking pictures of him until he felt awkward and ran away.
Speaker 1: I heard a rumor that Robert coup like Emailed a bunch of Craigslist scalpers went and met them all in a parking lot and bought all their badges back from them all at once.
Speaker 0: God, I think at this point I have like a man crush on Robert coup who does not?
Speaker 1: Non men.
Speaker 1: Yeah, non men.
Speaker 0: Yes So we'll see that.
Speaker 0: buy your packs badges right away.
Speaker 0: If you guys do that The scalpers can't get you because it's not that easy to scalp packs badges that quickly.
Speaker 1: and also if all the badges sell out Faster that gives the scalpers less time to buy a ton of them.
Speaker 0: It also gives packs some advantages that are kind of behind the scenes advantage.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's better for the convention if the badges sell faster than if they sell slower because then they have more time to know things.
Speaker 1: You know more information sooner means better planning.
Speaker 0: One cool thing in the expo hall we did see was, you know geek chic.
Speaker 0: They make that awesome like heritage heirloom like all like crazy furniture for nerds They have.
Speaker 1: they have coffee tables now.
Speaker 0: They had the hoplite coffee table there.
Speaker 0: And now that I actually saw it.
Speaker 1: I want it.
Speaker 0: It's exactly what I need and it's not that anyone want my coffee table that it's like 1500 bucks for the fully loaded one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think I'm gonna get a very chilly barrel coffee table cost more than I'll get it eventually.
Speaker 1: Eventually not right away eventually because I was serviceable.
Speaker 0: coffee There's think of this.
Speaker 0: that table cost only slightly more than it cost to fly John st.
Speaker 0: John two packs and give him a hotel for three days.
Speaker 1: It cost slightly more than a computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah and it's so much better than a computer.
Speaker 0: of course.
Speaker 0: apparently the Geek cheeks getting popular enough to where there is like a nine to twelve month lag time.
Speaker 1: I realize there's a lag time with pretty much anyone who does any sort of furniture.
Speaker 1: that's custom because it takes them so long to Make it and they only have so many guys and it's hard to get more people and it's hard to get more Space and whatever.
Speaker 1: So there's always gonna be a lag time and that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: So one weird aside, you know Thursday We got to the con Wednesday night because it was cheaper to pay for a hotel Wednesday than it was to fly out Thursday.
Speaker 0: Yep And I feel like I should do this every year because being in town all day Thursday Proved to me one a couple of things.
Speaker 0: one Seattle's really fun to run around in for a day.
Speaker 1: Like we went to this Andy Warhol exhibit and this Kurt go bad Museum and we just happen to go in and it happened to be totally free that day.
Speaker 0: There was stuff to do.
Speaker 0: we went to the utility store store.
Speaker 0: We got utility kilts.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah forgot all about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that store tries so hard to be so manly.
Speaker 0: they give you a fucking beer if you buy one.
Speaker 0: Yeah they were really cool though and we got kilts and the the actual like skirts the actual like owner and creator and everything was there and He came over and personally fitted me and I got my kilt.
Speaker 0: Yep fucking love that thing.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna buy another one as soon as I feel like it.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I'd buy another one so fast.
Speaker 0: I need to for one reason one reason alone.
Speaker 0: I pretty much see myself wearing a kilt Anytime.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to work.
Speaker 1: Nah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like all I feel like I'm gonna go all kilts all the time.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I'll do that.
Speaker 1: You need to.
Speaker 0: you can't wear the same pants every day.
Speaker 1: I'll wear it when it's clean and then I'll wash it and I'll wear it when it's clean and you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but even if it's clean, you know if I wear it Friday, I feel a little weird wearing it Saturday.
Speaker 1: I could wear it Sunday though and Friday and Saturday.
Speaker 1: No, just Friday and Sunday.
Speaker 0: But what about Saturday?
Speaker 0: I'll wear shorts plus you could wear it to work.
Speaker 0: I could I can't.
Speaker 1: I don't know about the bicycling.
Speaker 1: They say I could bicycle with it, but I don't know I'd have to use that modesty thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but even with the modesty thing, it's still Yeah, but the other important thing I learned is that the Sheraton Lobby was full of people playing games all day Thursday all night Thursday all Night Sunday and there were reports of people playing games much of Monday.
Speaker 1: Did you research the cost of getting the the ballroom?
Speaker 0: I'm looking into it.
Speaker 0: I don't want to talk about it live because you know, we got to do this thing by mine.
Speaker 1: It might not happen.
Speaker 0: But yeah, if we can.
Speaker 0: we talked about this in the other pack show.
Speaker 0: We did.
Speaker 0: we are going to try to set up a non sanctioned geek nights packs pre and/or post party Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: the packs prime pre post party BB BB BB BB BB the.
Speaker 1: But with the G in the front is the geek nights.
Speaker 0: Yeah We're working on it because there were a lot of people playing games like it was.
Speaker 0: in fact I would say that if you don't have a badge to packs You can still enjoy a lot of packs because though the lobby of the Sheraton is better than most gaming cons.
Speaker 0: I've ever attended Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: That's sad, but it's true All righty Is there?
Speaker 1: was there anything else at packs that wasn't us playing a game
Speaker 0: other than the fact that I have to give huge shout outs to Every single enforcer at all of
Speaker 1: every single fan every single person who came up to us and told us our panel was awesome Every person who came to our event anyone who suffered through the late show
Speaker 0: the enforcers because multiple enforcers.
Speaker 0: I had conversations that went along the lines of blah blah blah tribes - and they would interrupt me and say oh my god Yeah tribes - oh And we would nerd about it for a while.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'd like mental orgasms.
Speaker 0: I ran into one enforcer who had never seen our panels before.
Speaker 0: He was like a new like theater or whatever enforcer and I was like, yeah You guys are awesome and I actually made him blush like he wasn't used to the praise.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think he was a brand new.
Speaker 1: apparently he was not paying attention at the closing ceremonies when gave an.
Speaker 1: taiko had their list of people that they remember to thank and They thanked all these people.
Speaker 1: right but only when they thank the enforcers did the entire room Standing up standing Lee ovate for like a minute and Otakon takes some notice.
Speaker 1: the way they treat their staff Yeah, and the way their staff treat the attendees and each other and people in general.
Speaker 0: Pax is I would go to 12 faxes a year if there were 12 I'll go to four packs.
Speaker 0: Well, I would go to four paxes in the as a panelist and entertainer and performer.
Speaker 0: I Could go to 12 as just an attendee depends how far away they are.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think I'm going to pack Sydney more than once.
Speaker 0: no I don't think I'm going to packs barely every every packs they ever make.
Speaker 1: I will go to once but every year I will only go to one packs repeatedly every three months.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I said it before and I got to say it again Robert Greg heel Matt Graham Everyone who helped us with the late show Molly 23 for coming out and doing that act Alex Albrecht Duke Nukem Even roosterteeth, even though you guys were drunk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, really?
Speaker 1: You showed up on time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, hey, you know, you came out you helped us with our show.
Speaker 1: We didn't pay you or anything.
Speaker 0: We didn't get to argue enough about machinima.
Speaker 0: machinima I want to actually argue that out when you're sober.
Speaker 1: apparently they didn't want to.
Speaker 0: I really wanted to though.
Speaker 0: Alright anyway, so What else can I say other than the packs?
Speaker 0: is pretty much the best con I ever see.
Speaker 1: step it up.
Speaker 0: Oh my god packs is in less than six months.
Speaker 1: You know what thing it you know what though packs East.
Speaker 1: You're gonna be able to place it five at packs with all other people.
Speaker 0: Oh my god I'll have to get a new laptop.
Speaker 1: You just go in the PC area and maybe you bring your own PC and we'll do sieve five in there.
Speaker 0: No, I'll bring.
Speaker 0: I'll get a laptop that can play it and then I'll bring my own PC double sieve Also weird.
Speaker 0: no, I got you know, Robert Koo gets a lot of shout outs But I have to.
Speaker 0: I really have to kind of publicly thank him for something because he you know makes packs happen.
Speaker 0: He makes all this stuff happen exactly made everything happen.
Speaker 0: I am pretty sure that he's not actually a person but some sort of clone cyborg from the future.
Speaker 1: we know that's a true fact, but
Speaker 0: Despite this that I've never seen him at a convention where he was not fixing something or on his way quickly to fix something and Despite always being in this state when we were in Thursday going to get our badges, you know Cuz they don't mail the panelist badges of all things which is cool.
Speaker 0: We were looking for cuz.
Speaker 0: they moved it.
Speaker 0: cuz there's this other con like where the reg was supposed to be.
Speaker 0: so they moved it.
Speaker 0: they hadn't like sorted all that out yet.
Speaker 0: and We look confused for no more than one second over.
Speaker 0: Robert Koo personally walks over says Oh, yeah, you guys are looking to introduce himself.
Speaker 1: He didn't know that we knew who he was.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you knew who we were.
Speaker 0: cuz.
Speaker 0: I think he knows what we look like.
Speaker 0: I don't know I don't know.
Speaker 0: I interact with him very sparsely, but he just comes up out of nowhere says Oh, you're looking for packs registration.
Speaker 0: I assume come with me and he just took us down to it.
Speaker 1: He escorted us personally, right?
Speaker 0: And then he said here you go.
Speaker 0: Enjoy it.
Speaker 0: And then he vanished in a puff of smoke.
Speaker 1: Yes, but I mean Concierge Otacon would never do that now.
Speaker 1: Well, it depends on the concierge in bowls would have done that maybe but you know When is he gonna meet you at the bottom of the elevator where you're looking lost?
Speaker 1: You know, not gonna.
Speaker 1: he's probably busy already with the con by that time.
Speaker 0: Also shout out again to Aaron see I love all you enforcers, but he's my favorite enforcer.
Speaker 1: Row you smacking row down.
Speaker 0: Oh credit know cuz row is our crew, but I guess Aaron's now also in our crew.
Speaker 0: So you're both my favorites and Jeremy shit see The trouble with shoutouts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm glad that we had.
Speaker 0: it was cool.
Speaker 0: We had a sort of Front row crew plus Azen posse plus West Coast front row crew Private after party at PAX.
Speaker 0: It was good because you know we're trying to find a restaurant that'll seat like 20 people in short notice and We actually found a place and they gave us a private room and they did.
Speaker 0: they did separate checks for every individual person.
Speaker 1: It was good.
Speaker 1: I like that.
Speaker 1: They didn't care either.
Speaker 0: Yeah, in fact they offered it but the funniest thing.
Speaker 0: so we're sitting there right and then we see spiky hair and we look Sure enough.
Speaker 0: Alex Albrecht and his post-pax party was right next to the private room.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah How about that coincidence?
Speaker 1: people at PAX doing the same late show eating in the same restaurant at the same time?
Speaker 1: Oh Man, remember when he went to the the hidden Indian place that was giving the packs discount.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but we went too early.
Speaker 0: We went Thursday, so we didn't get the packs this but instead he brought us that fresh naan that he made just for us Right then.
Speaker 1: so yeah, but it was totally empty and weird, but it was awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also the fact that on Sunday right we needed some breakfast and we didn't want to get double waffles again.
Speaker 0: So we go over and we're walking toward like the mall just to find some breakfast and we were gonna pass Vaughn's.
Speaker 0: and I say out loud man Scott Imagine if Vaughn's had some fucking bread and then sure enough they had it.
Speaker 0: Vaughn says breakfast.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: It's pretty damn good.
Speaker 1: It was it was a little pricey and there wasn't that much to choose from compared to say the far superior Breakfast buffet at the Connecticut Hotel.
Speaker 0: now that Connecticut Hotel stands far and above.
Speaker 1: but the flavor of say the potato Man, it was a good a potato.
Speaker 0: Oh in that frickin bacon with the maple glaze and pepper on I ate like a half a pound.
Speaker 1: I hunger so much.
Speaker 1: you want to order some food right now We're gonna cook.
Speaker 1: What are you cooking?
Speaker 0: Uh, I don't know chicken something.
Speaker 0: Maybe I gotta go put the rice on like I'm like Right the fuck.
Speaker 0: now, I'm gonna get that rice going.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: Oh shit up This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.