Speaker 0: It's Thursday, June 17th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and tonight.
Speaker 0: We conclude the book club for Carl Sagan's cosmos.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I realize what needs to happen with the fucking vuvuzelas.
Speaker 0: It's vuvuzela at the end.
Speaker 0: It's a schwa not in it not like an air and I'll pronounce it However the fuck you want.
Speaker 1: I don't care or lepata.
Speaker 1: Ta you know what the best pronunciation of it is shut the fuck up.
Speaker 1: no That's how you pronounce that shit.
Speaker 0: So I thought before I was thinking what can we do?
Speaker 0: because right now the vuvuzela is the thing like every Everyone in the planet.
Speaker 0: if do you really have to crinkle that bag while we're doing the show?
Speaker 1: captain I was investigating my M&Ms.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got some fancy M&Ms.
Speaker 0: I see there.
Speaker 1: Well, they're not fancy.
Speaker 1: Some of them have pretzel in them and some of them are dark chocolate and also peanut at the same time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know if the dark chocolate M&M is gonna be the best dark chocolate.
Speaker 1: It's you can tell.
Speaker 1: you can tell but it's not much different from the milk chocolate darker.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like oh that was slightly dark chocolate.
Speaker 1: Okay, great.
Speaker 0: I'll be honest I never liked M&Ms.
Speaker 0: what?
Speaker 0: even as a little kid.
Speaker 0: Will you stop the head?
Speaker 0: I never liked him.
Speaker 0: I liked peanut M&Ms and like Reese's Pieces Fuck M&Ms.
Speaker 1: Well, these are peanut dark chocolate and also pretzel.
Speaker 0: So that's okay.
Speaker 0: pretzel I don't know about because that that just brings me back to combos, which I also hated.
Speaker 1: Oh combos are just so disgusting.
Speaker 0: But the thing I never understood.
Speaker 0: all my dumbass friends would have like a gigantic bag of those things.
Speaker 0: Them and bugles in their life every day.
Speaker 1: the thing I don't like about those.
Speaker 1: I mean the combo.
Speaker 1: I like the pretzel part.
Speaker 1: I just don't like the fake cheese part, but the same with the bugle the worst pretzel.
Speaker 0: It was nuts It was butts.
Speaker 1: No, but I mean, you know, the.
Speaker 1: the idea of pretzel is not a problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the idea of shitty pretzel is a problem let alone shitty pretzel with fake cheese.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they should have had.
Speaker 1: they should make a combo where the inside is not fake cheese, but is instead like Cupcake frosting.
Speaker 0: I remember I'd be sitting there and Chocolate.
Speaker 0: Hey, I'll trade you my great white for some combos.
Speaker 0: Yeah, how about that?
Speaker 1: an inverse peanut M&M, right?
Speaker 1: It's a pretzel and chocolate on the inside.
Speaker 0: What about a peanut injected with chocolate?
Speaker 0: somehow?
Speaker 0: Some sort of mutant peanut.
Speaker 1: You can't really hollow out a peanut.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: It won't be much.
Speaker 1: Here's what you could do.
Speaker 1: Right, you know peanuts usually come in a shell, but if you buy planners, they get rid of all the shells for you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, yeah What if you made a chocolate in the shape of a full peanut shell and then you play?
Speaker 1: Inside where the two peanuts that are supposed to go in there?
Speaker 0: No No, you got to mix it up.
Speaker 0: if it's shaped like a peanut You don't want peanuts inside of.
Speaker 0: you want like capers or something just weird.
Speaker 1: Okay capers and chocolate.
Speaker 1: That's all you.
Speaker 0: But the vuvuzela.
Speaker 0: everyone knows about these things now, like they're popular culture even among people who don't care about sports or soccer.
Speaker 0: Notice my subtle joke there.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: So I was thinking what can we do now?
Speaker 0: Because if you make a joke about them like this like late show people are gonna be making jokes about these things like their pop culture.
Speaker 0: Someone's got to bring one of these things to a fucking golf game.
Speaker 1: Golf game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's a round.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna call it a game because I don't like golf.
Speaker 0: Okay plus alliteration.
Speaker 0: Don't you prefer alliteration golf game as opposed to golf match GM?
Speaker 1: No, that's not.
Speaker 0: Hey, let's go play a game of golf.
Speaker 1: That's different.
Speaker 0: I've never played golf.
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 0: Plus we say a game of putt-putt With the club at a hole And usually our scores are worse.
Speaker 1: it's it's what are you talking about?
Speaker 0: Well, if you average the front row crew, they're much worse.
Speaker 1: Okay, I was gonna say like The average like score you're gonna get playing around a putt-putt is gonna be a lot better than the score You would get playing actual golf.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I feel like with a lot of the people I play putt-putt with.
Speaker 0: maybe it's just because I played it a lot more as a Kid, but I know a lot of people where the an average of an entire group would be six.
Speaker 1: Okay, so let's say you are playing Golf right.
Speaker 1: golf has 18 holes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know, there's a some par threes fours and fives.
Speaker 1: So we'll say average of par four, right?
Speaker 1: So four times 18 is what 80 minus 18 times 2 is 16. easy answer to 64.
Speaker 0: the average score among most people who play putt-putt is gonna be 18 to 5 times.
Speaker 1: Uh, yeah, right.
Speaker 1: so 18 times 6 right is what is worse than 18 times 4.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So the thing is if you play if you're playing right regular old golf on an actual golf course.
Speaker 1: Right, you think you're gonna get it in the hole in six.
Speaker 0: It depends.
Speaker 1: No, not even close.
Speaker 1: You're gonna hit it.
Speaker 1: It's gonna go in the tree and you're gonna hit it.
Speaker 1: It's gonna go in the water if you're even lucky to even hit it anywhere near straight.
Speaker 1: But anyway, we're gonna go in another tree.
Speaker 1: They're gonna take a drop all my.
Speaker 1: you're gonna get like tens and 12.
Speaker 0: I feel like the way to make the vuvuzela Awesome right now is to bring it out in grossly inappropriate Context all the time.
Speaker 1: Well, I think you know, pretty much what's gonna happen is the vuvuzela is gonna be banned Everywhere.
Speaker 1: we already banned it like every soccer was banned at Wimbledon.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it's gonna be banned in like We can make some bank.
Speaker 0: we got to make a sniper rifle vuvuzela.
Speaker 0: that like breaks down into parts or collapses.
Speaker 0: So you can stick that in your pocket.
Speaker 0: You're sitting there Tiger Woods is up against Nicholson.
Speaker 0: They're about to do some things.
Speaker 0: you turn around you go go 13 it and then vuvuzela And then they just grab you and kick you out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then you're banned forever.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: You wait till hole 17 and you paid how much money for that?
Speaker 0: It might be worth it.
Speaker 1: It's all you.
Speaker 0: if you never want to go back there's no reason not to get kicked out of any event.
Speaker 1: at the very end At the very oh, you're gonna wait until the very very end to whip it out.
Speaker 0: I have one other phrase for you.
Speaker 0: This won't frighten you because we might not be going but Animacons, they're gonna sneak him in.
Speaker 1: No, they're gonna ban them.
Speaker 0: I know they are but they're gonna sneak him in.
Speaker 1: People just Right 26,000 people.
Speaker 0: even if they eliminate 99% of the vuvuzela as they get in the door, you're gonna get some vuvuzela.
Speaker 1: The problem is right is let's say banning a vuvuzela is really really really easy Unless anyone who uses it, it's gigantic, right and anyone who uses it.
Speaker 1: You can find them immediately because they're making a really loud noise and they can't really get away from you.
Speaker 0: The other way to go right.
Speaker 0: so we've got to make the collapsible ones.
Speaker 1: Their only hope is to abandon their vuvuzela and run and blend into a crowd in which case you win.
Speaker 1: now They're vuvuzelous.
Speaker 0: You got to plan this out.
Speaker 0: You got to have the I am Spartacus situation where you vuvuzela and while they're coming to get you someone on the other side vuvuzela Or in public places you just flash mob it and then disappear.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could definitely do a flash mob.
Speaker 0: You know people are hanging out like having lunch in one of those parks in Manhattan and suddenly there's like a hundred people Vuvuzelous for like I did.
Speaker 1: I did see a video of a flash mob.
Speaker 1: a whole bunch of people went down to like an amateur Soccer match like oh, that was awesome.
Speaker 1: And they just filled the stands Smoke bombs and then they got you know, they got naked and streaked across the field and That was pretty good.
Speaker 1: I like how the players and the refs tried to fight it at first Like a whole bunch of people to show up at like a little league and do that same thing even with the streaking and everything.
Speaker 0: see the thing Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, those people would get on the sex offender list would be so awesome.
Speaker 1: It wouldn't be me some other guy that wouldn't be you.
Speaker 1: he wouldn't know any better.
Speaker 0: See I real.
Speaker 0: but again The only reason this isn't gonna happen and we can never do an awesome thing with these things is that no one knows how to Fucking.
Speaker 0: use them in America.
Speaker 1: Yeah people know how to use.
Speaker 0: they're gonna just put their mouth up to it.
Speaker 0: Almost feel would be funnier if you didn't actually blow in it You're just yelling vuvuzela through it like it's.
Speaker 1: I think I think people would figure it out.
Speaker 1: It's kind of hard to do.
Speaker 1: it's not that hard to do it.
Speaker 1: See here's the thing right is that you you're you're making a lot of assumptions because you are a trumpet person.
Speaker 0: Right, basically the vuvuzela is constructed in such a way that basically all you know It's harder to keep to make a tone in that than in a trumpet, right?
Speaker 1: And here's the.
Speaker 1: this is this is the very problem with the.
Speaker 1: if you had one and you played into it with your trumpeting Skills, it would actually sound pretty good.
Speaker 1: The reason it sounds the way it does because everyone basically just looks and When you go into a vuvuzela, it makes that noise that it makes.
Speaker 0: well Actually, it really can only make a really flat like B flat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the noise it makes and all you have to do is go which everyone in there and their mother can do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't actually have to have a quality armature or anything going on.
Speaker 1: And if you do have a quality armature, then it would sound good It would actually make a solid note, let me tell you my vuvuzela which I called it a stadium horn.
Speaker 0: That thing did not make a pleasant noise about how good a trumpet player you are.
Speaker 1: Well the ones that from what I've heard the ones that they have down there That's how they work is.
Speaker 1: you basically need no skill whatsoever to get it to emit the droning noise.
Speaker 0: You have to at least figure out you have to go.
Speaker 1: everybody knows you don't even know you had to go.
Speaker 1: Just you don't even need to go, you know You have to get the resonance.
Speaker 0: I can show you You don't everyone Physics if it makes a sound at all, you're getting the resonance if you're not.
Speaker 0: if it if you don't make the resonance It won't make enough noise for anyone to hear.
Speaker 0: from what everyone is told I know you're saying just go and it works but it had but unless you get the resonance it won't make any noise.
Speaker 1: Well, it seems to be that it's incredibly easy to use because thousands and thousands of non musicians are able to make it make No in a place with no training whatsoever place where apparently it is the most popular pastime instrument and sport.
Speaker 1: You know, they've only been around since like Oh one.
Speaker 1: It's not like an old pastime Yeah, it's like, you know, I remember I was at.
Speaker 0: you know the stadium soccer games I go to was a kid right and they sold him and My brother and I got him because we were both trumpet players and we were in the crowd's basically being obnoxious.
Speaker 0: Everyone else bought him and hardly anyone was able to make him make a noise.
Speaker 0: I guess I just I don't have a lot of confidence in the average American to make a sound out of a booboozilla.
Speaker 1: You know, that's just That's just you.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So got anything to talk about like Mexico and Spain and France and North Korea and soccer.
Speaker 0: that I don't watch so much.
Speaker 0: But I watched the game between Mexico and France.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean the World Cup is we got?
Speaker 1: see I'm 20.
Speaker 1: So there's been a lot of World Cups in my life But the only one I ever paid any attention to it all was when it was actually in the u.s.
Speaker 0: The long time ago, this is actually the first one I paid attention to only because I have a lot of foreign-born co-workers.
Speaker 0: So they're all really.
Speaker 1: the only reason I'm paying attention to it so much is because it's actually available for watching.
Speaker 0: You know easily aren't you using a pirate stream though?
Speaker 1: Well, I'm using a pirate stream But it's also.
Speaker 1: there's a some free Spanish streaming on Univision.
Speaker 0: Is it?
Speaker 0: Okay for you?
Speaker 1: It's also on ABC which I get for free.
Speaker 0: Is it okay to use the pirate stream if a legitimate stream of the same thing was technically already available to you?
Speaker 1: Anyway, the pirate stream is in English and the Spanish one is not.
Speaker 1: so You know, I mean as far as I'm concerned, it's always okay to use a pirate stream.
Speaker 1: Why would it not be?
Speaker 0: Okay, I feel like it.
Speaker 1: this world They're not gonna charge you money if I go down to the bar and just sit there.
Speaker 1: right the bar won't even you know Technically can't force me to even buy a drink and can't kick me out just for sitting there.
Speaker 0: Well charge you a cover.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they don't.
Speaker 1: they say there's a guy out and he sees like free admission.
Speaker 1: Come on in free admission, right?
Speaker 1: So I could just do that.
Speaker 1: So why would it be illegal for me to just do the same thing in my apartment?
Speaker 1: Not anyone any money it is but actually it's not.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's illegal for me to watch the pirate stream.
Speaker 1: It's illegal for the pirates to pirate the stream because they are Re-broadcasting without the expressed written consent in all the stuff so far.
Speaker 0: No one has ever made a successful lawsuit for Using pirated media in that fashion only for distributing.
Speaker 1: Yes, exactly.
Speaker 1: So these guys and I know they're in Florida in California because I can see their local cable TV commercials You pay for the pirated stream.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure now you're breaking straight-up law.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not paying for it.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, but it doesn't matter Accepting money for the pirate stream.
Speaker 0: if you were pirating a pirate stream that was pay.
Speaker 1: I Think we need to do the Simpsons strategy with a barge that has major league rebroadcast major league baseball without expressed written consent and only implied verbal consent.
Speaker 1: So our implied oral consent.
Speaker 0: Well, one of my co-workers the other senior guy in my office right like we sit back to back and he's you know French and he expected France to beat Mexico obviously, but he doesn't expect No, but he did.
Speaker 0: he was like, yeah France isn't gonna win.
Speaker 0: you were doubting l3.
Speaker 0: They're not high in my bracket They're gonna choke because they're playing all defensively and bullshitty and whatever.
Speaker 0: So I walk out of the office and I'm you know, standing with someone else talking and I see Mexico score.
Speaker 0: I'm like, huh, and then I see Mexico score again a little while later.
Speaker 1: So that was a while later.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I was out of the office for a while.
Speaker 0: So I walk back in just after this and I looked at him and I just played dumb and I was like Hey, it looks like France is up to nothing.
Speaker 0: Hey, isn't this awesome?
Speaker 0: That's the best I could do.
Speaker 0: I don't have any humor to make with the World Cup.
Speaker 1: No, all the humor is in the in the vuvuzela.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that the World Cup will be like ten times more exciting once we're in the round of 16.
Speaker 1: You know the the group rounds, you know, there's some excitement like, you know Spain going down big surprise Stuff like that North Korea's goal, you know North Korea.
Speaker 1: It's like I. it's such a weird thing.
Speaker 1: It's like I'd obviously don't want them to win because that would be like but I want those players like.
Speaker 1: it's like I sorta I sort of feel bad for the North Korean players.
Speaker 1: It's like are they bad guys?
Speaker 1: Probably not.
Speaker 1: Well, the worst thing is I mean, they're sort of bad because I mean I'm sure that they're well-fed when the rest of the country isn't.
Speaker 1: so that's sort of.
Speaker 1: but at the same time do they even know?
Speaker 0: They're shielded from all that who knows?
Speaker 1: but they're obviously not bad people right?
Speaker 1: They're not evil dudes They're not looking to hurt anyone.
Speaker 1: They're clearly robots and you know, they're just.
Speaker 1: it's not their fault that they were born in North Korea.
Speaker 1: You know, they could have been born anywhere, you know, it was just born.
Speaker 1: So, you know, they're just playing to be a sport just like everyone else, you know, they're.
Speaker 1: you know, they're not being bad.
Speaker 0: I don't want them to win because I don't want North Korea to have that feather in his cap But I want them to score meaningful goals.
Speaker 1: Well, I'm pretty sure they're not getting out of the the group round So it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: actually what I would I would really hope for I know won't happen is if somehow They would all just be like we're not coming back.
Speaker 0: We defect.
Speaker 1: Well, I think that some of them like like two or three of them actually You know work.
Speaker 1: They're like play on real soccer teams Like and I think some one of them plays in like the Japanese League and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: So these guys aren't you know, like trapped in North Korea necessarily.
Speaker 0: They probably a family I mean most of them are.
Speaker 1: one interesting thing though.
Speaker 1: Is that you know, a lot of these others pretty much all the soccer teams Like for example the US team right.
Speaker 1: those guys don't really play as a team very much.
Speaker 1: They usually they're a bunch of you know, they play in MLS they play in European League They play wherever they play and then when it's time to do some US stuff, you know, like Confederations Cup or whatever You know, they all get together and they they play like that.
Speaker 1: So the thing is the North Korean team.
Speaker 1: the vast majority of the team actually plays together a lot.
Speaker 1: So if you compare them to the other teams you they actually have more.
Speaker 1: they're more unified and the you know More teamwork going on than pretty much anyone else still doesn't make up for the lack of talent but You know teamwork it counts for something.
Speaker 1: and you know If the team's with a lot of talent like Spain right had some huge teamwork going on They could.
Speaker 1: they would probably be like way more dominant and you know, not losing it a big upset the Switzerland.
Speaker 0: So before we get to cosmos things of the day, I don't know how long it'll be before this gets taken down.
Speaker 0: If it's not there by the time you click on this, I'm sorry, but I will never tire of watching downfall parody videos.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I feel like I have to watch this movie because it looks like it's an amazing movie.
Speaker 0: It's an amazing movie.
Speaker 0: I've never seen it.
Speaker 0: But that scene is just so powerful and when juxtaposed with Hitler complaining about the vuvuzela.
Speaker 0: I Laughed out loud like three times during.
Speaker 1: I wanted to you know, make my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: vuvuzela jokes.
Speaker 1: You know cuz there's so many good ones like the haters gonna have.
Speaker 1: And the And the music note the music sheet one, this is the one note.
Speaker 1: go right.
Speaker 1: so this is plan.
Speaker 1: What does the website you can go to that will add a vuvuzela to any website?
Speaker 1: There's a lot of good stuff out there and it the joke itself is not funny.
Speaker 1: But the clever, you know, it's it's the the cleverness of how you tell the joke, you know what it is.
Speaker 0: It's like the aristocrats or it's like the old Photoshop Fridays like the originals like here's a picture of four nerds And then everyone just like use.
Speaker 0: it's like variations on a theme like everyone has the same theme.
Speaker 0: What can you do with it?
Speaker 1: Some.
Speaker 1: I'm waiting for someone to make the vuvuzela video game like a playable game and all you do is push a button.
Speaker 1: and it was Text adventure.
Speaker 0: you have found a vuvuzela or?
Speaker 1: no, they should add in FIFA 20 You get from EA Sports, right you go in the options menu and this volume and it's like music volume sound effects volume announcer volume vuvuzela volume and the vuvuzela volume meter is three times longer than Anyway, so for a thing of the day.
Speaker 1: instead, I've got this video.
Speaker 1: I found this is actually I think a quality thing of the day because usually we find a thing of the day from some blog.
Speaker 1: Right, so we'll find a link on Boeing Boeing or a link on Kotaku or a link on College Humor to something else.
Speaker 1: This was I found it directly on YouTube itself.
Speaker 1: There was not a link from anywhere else except for the YouTube homepage.
Speaker 1: And what this is is the case of the poopy Nintendo.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, that was one of the funniest things I've seen in a while.
Speaker 1: It's it's basically a mystery of a Nintendo with poop.
Speaker 0: Another case this guy solves the mystery the telling of the story in this one and especially the diagrams As to whether or not it was feasible for one of the suspects to have poopy to the Nintendo.
Speaker 1: Yes, no court cases.
Speaker 1: It is really necessary here.
Speaker 1: You know, it's a pretty much cut and dry or cut and mushy Situation.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I can't imagine I would have had that been me and I went to play a game first.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't have noticed I would have put a game in it wouldn't have worked and I would.
Speaker 0: but that's the brilliance of the Nintendo poopy.
Speaker 1: But what if the thing is top loader has a poopy shield, yeah, it does but you can't.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no way but think of this.
Speaker 0: Here's here's the brilliance of the poop plan, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know if they even thought of this but it's a brilliant brilliant plan.
Speaker 0: So I go I stick Super Mario 3 in the Nintendo and it doesn't work which happens.
Speaker 1: So what do I do?
Speaker 1: I pull it out.
Speaker 0: I put the game.
Speaker 0: I've just put in right up against my mouth to go.
Speaker 1: Well, you would notice when it didn't pop right out cuz it was all stuck and squishy.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't think it would get stuck.
Speaker 0: I think it would pop right out and I wouldn't notice right to the mouth.
Speaker 1: And then you know the breathe in what the fuck Poop your face dude, if she gets it, we should sell.
Speaker 1: who was halas and put poopy in them.
Speaker 1: and then when someone?
Speaker 0: Actually, the super soaker is the best way to end the vuvuzela thread you just shoot it right up the the muzzle.
Speaker 1: There has to be something you can do to get it up.
Speaker 0: Anyway, like I said a gentle love tap to the end of the vuvuzela will cause severe extreme pain in the wielder.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Really cuz.
Speaker 1: I mean like you can put a mute on a trumpet and it's like whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the mute holds it in.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about tapping it like bop.
Speaker 1: Oh Basically punching them in the face basically a stick via the vuvuzela.
Speaker 0: I said, okay It's like who wouldn't to vuvuzela, whatever the meta moment.
Speaker 0: Would you get into it?
Speaker 0: Oh, this is a book club episode.
Speaker 0: We haven't been doing him that often because rim doesn't know how to read and you kids probably didn't read this book either.
Speaker 1: I think a bunch of people read the book.
Speaker 0: I hope so.
Speaker 1: Maybe they're.
Speaker 1: hopefully they'll read it now.
Speaker 0: But can I come July 9th and all that will be there.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be awesome focus too soon.
Speaker 0: Oh my god this weekend is the nerd NYC recess in Manhattan.
Speaker 0: You should go check that out.
Speaker 0: We'll be there Saturday all day.
Speaker 1: gaming action.
Speaker 0: We're gonna announce the next book club book.
Speaker 0: Maybe we should do it right now.
Speaker 0: right now I'm not gonna wait maybe for the people who didn't read this book.
Speaker 0: So at least there's a chance before they turn off the episode.
Speaker 0: They know what the next book is.
Speaker 1: All right, we could do that.
Speaker 0: So it's your turn to pick I believe basically right.
Speaker 1: so Gabe from penny arcade He only likes books that have pictures of rocket ships or planets on the cover right or Star Wars.
Speaker 0: so Star Wars books don't have pictures of rockets or planets on the cover in all cases.
Speaker 1: No, they usually do.
Speaker 1: but anyway, he He you know, he's he's slowly been getting away You know, he's played some RPGs and D&D and that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: So he asked on Twitter a while back like what book do I read?
Speaker 1: Right?
Speaker 1: So There were all kinds of suggestions being tweeted at him.
Speaker 1: So Someone sort went and combined all of the suggestions into like a sheet and was like up.
Speaker 1: this was suggested ten times and this Five times and this right, you know the X time.
Speaker 1: so you could see all the suggestions together and which ones were the most suggested.
Speaker 1: so I look at this list and I'm looking and a lot of it is like ra Salvatore bla bla bla or song of ice and fire And I'm like Dragon land something I'm like.
Speaker 0: What's funny is if you look at the level of those books like the forgotten realms ones were some of the least shitty of those Books.
Speaker 0: you can have a dragon Lance dear God.
Speaker 1: there was some pretty bad books suggested but there was one book that was suggested that had a great many suggestions many and I had never heard of it and it was called the lies of Locke Lamora.
Speaker 1: and I was like, what is this?
Speaker 1: So I look it up and Apparently it was a fantasy novel about some sort of con artist, dude Already up my alley.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, huh?
Speaker 1: That seems like the kind of book that is gonna have some sort of maybe American gods ish kind of action in it maybe something.
Speaker 0: so also, you know Scott was explaining it to me and It has one of the things that I'm an absolute sucker for.
Speaker 0: any time There's precursor technology in anything.
Speaker 0: I'm all about that shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know it's a sign of a good book when you've got.
Speaker 1: you know, there's some sort of world with all these mysteries.
Speaker 1: But the story is just about people living in this world and isn't about the mystery of the world like cowboy bebop Exactly.
Speaker 1: If you go to Amazon a hundred and eleven five-star reviews 56 four-star reviews only 16 three stars 12 two stars and nine one star.
Speaker 1: see whenever I find like that It's a pretty good.
Speaker 0: I always read every single one of the one-star reviews.
Speaker 1: Yep Just to see.
Speaker 1: the other thing is that you look in the front of the book where you know There's all the quotes from reviews saying how great the book is and there's like a ton of pages.
Speaker 1: all like it's like multiple.
Speaker 0: Wait a minute Scott.
Speaker 0: The book is called the lies of locked lab.
Speaker 0: Are you sure they're not all just lies?
Speaker 1: No, there's like multiple pages of you know pull quotes from positive reviews for the book.
Speaker 1: It usually they only put a few in like the back cover in the front cover.
Speaker 1: This is like a whole section of them.
Speaker 1: All right, so I'm like, all right, there is something up with this book.
Speaker 0: Well, especially look at the title.
Speaker 0: It's got pretty good alliteration.
Speaker 0: Yeah, very good Kind I like the lot and I like how it's like the definite article like it's there like the lies of locked lamera.
Speaker 1: So, you know, it's been out for a while.
Speaker 1: It's by this guy named Scott Lynch.
Speaker 1: It's actually been out so long that as a sequel the sequel is called Red Seas Under Red Skies.
Speaker 1: I bought the sequel but I haven't read it yet And they're both mass-market paperbacks.
Speaker 1: They've been out for a while and they're way cheap.
Speaker 1: So I got it and I read it and it was pretty awesome and it should totally be a movie.
Speaker 0: So what I'm curious about just doesn't get some perspective better or worse than say the prince of nothing books like the first one.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's not it's not like Prince nothing.
Speaker 1: It's not you know, okay It doesn't really have.
Speaker 1: you know, the the the deepness and intellectualness It is you know, it is.
Speaker 1: it is a story and it is about what happens in.
Speaker 1: the story is very literal There isn't like a huge deep Symbology and such and such.
Speaker 1: fine.
Speaker 0: I was just curious.
Speaker 0: I'm still down for it.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's you know, dude, there's some adventures and there's some fighting and lies lots of lies And you know, the thing is is like shit happens.
Speaker 1: you I didn't see coming for shit shit.
Speaker 1: It's like whoa.
Speaker 1: There was like two or three times in the book where it's like.
Speaker 1: whoa did not just happen.
Speaker 1: Oh my god spoilers.
Speaker 0: and I was really surprised at the end when he whips out the vuvuzela and brings down.
Speaker 1: So It's a pretty quality book.
Speaker 1: It's a good choice because I already read it and that means that we'll just wait for rim to read it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll order it on Amazon tonight and then You know I can read other things in the meantime.
Speaker 0: Actually, the problem is I just started reading a book that I should have read but I've never read.
Speaker 0: thus begs our threestra.
Speaker 0: So I got to stop that to finish Locke Lamora and then start that back up again.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't take that long.
Speaker 1: I mean Locke Lamora is.
Speaker 1: it's not a short book, you know, it's a pretty standard like the Prince of Nothing or like Hyperion.
Speaker 0: there's not.
Speaker 0: I doubt it's going to be Information and you know, it's not gonna have the density of one of those books.
Speaker 1: No, it's pretty much this happens.
Speaker 1: This happens.
Speaker 1: someone so says this.
Speaker 1: Hey, what's going on?
Speaker 1: It's just happens.
Speaker 0: It's lyrical and eloquent at least right?
Speaker 0: Not like lensman.
Speaker 0: Look, I mean The language was very direct and very like.
Speaker 0: this is what is happening.
Speaker 0: Is it like that or is it more like the Llewellyn kind of?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty normal.
Speaker 0: is there?
Speaker 0: no no prose like to the style stand out at all?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm just curious.
Speaker 0: I haven't read anything about it yet.
Speaker 0: Except the spoiler side about it's not.
Speaker 1: it's not exactly You know all poetic like Tokin or anything.
Speaker 0: Okay I'm just curious.
Speaker 1: All right, so that's that.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I think that's it for the meta stuff.
Speaker 0: If you if you're in the city come to the recess this weekend, we'll see ya.
Speaker 0: We'll probably all go out to a nice dinner somewhere cuz it's not like these events are super crowded.
Speaker 0: Nope We don't have to hide from anyone like we do some anime cons either.
Speaker 0: Hmm unless it's overcrowded Yep, and we might have a whole bunch of stuff coming up in the city in the near future.
Speaker 0: But we'll talk about that in a future metamoment.
Speaker 0: Yeah It'll be fun.
Speaker 1: Whatever.
Speaker 0: so the previous book that we finished the book that I picked Carl Sagan's cosmos We have both read it completely me for the second time Scott for the first time though I'll admit the first time I read it as a kid.
Speaker 0: I skipped a whole bunch in the middle that reading.
Speaker 0: now I wish I hadn't skipped.
Speaker 1: that did not really count.
Speaker 0: It wouldn't account in any way.
Speaker 0: I didn't remember half of this stuff.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh Anyway, the so cosmos.
Speaker 1: I think the first thing about cosmos Right is that this is like the best deal in terms of value for dollar.
Speaker 0: Oh my god this book for like four dollars.
Speaker 1: No, no, but I mean in terms of what you get right because you get a science book And History book and you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: it's like multiple books all in one book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not like, you know, you bought a book and it's just one thing.
Speaker 1: It's like three books at a time.
Speaker 0: Well, what really struck me about it now?
Speaker 0: I didn't think of it as a kid.
Speaker 0: I read it I was like, that's awesome.
Speaker 0: But reading it now it's amazing how well it tells you the story of the cosmos or the story of the universe to the point that it Feels almost like you're reading a novel like you're never bored or they're like always explaining some shit about neutrons.
Speaker 0: You're like then what did the Neutron do?
Speaker 0: Holy shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, usually like you read a nonfiction book of any kind, you know, and it's just like You can fall asleep pretty easily in the vast majority of them because you know They're stating a bunch of facts or it's a bunch of essays making arguments or even like Stephen Hawking books are pretty readable But it'll be like such and such and such.
Speaker 1: Here's a fun example.
Speaker 1: Such as such is a fun example.
Speaker 0: They're like Michio Kaku where it makes sense for a while But then the analogies get so complex that he starts analogizing the analogies.
Speaker 1: You just fucking lose me Yeah, but this book is like so readable.
Speaker 1: You can just keep going no problem.
Speaker 0: And the thing is I think anyone with you know, at least anyone without mental difficulties could understand everything in this book.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, like in the way it's presented I think there was one part of the book that had maths that some people might not be able to understand Where he's like, you know all the the how many the odds of alien civilizations existing anywhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's also some people might not be able to understand the you know, the the math of like the orbits, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess you're right.
Speaker 0: The math could be out of reach of some people but at least the concepts.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's any concept in this book that anyone with a hundred IQ could not grasp in a meaningful at least analogous manner.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know in fact, you know, like I grasp pretty much the whole book, right?
Speaker 1: But there were actually many things in the book that I just did not know or I feel like I should have known but was Quite stupid and just never because like I was never really into astronomy.
Speaker 1: I never thought about it really at all.
Speaker 1: You know, I knew things like.
Speaker 1: you have a telescope you pointed at the sky you look so you didn't know like pulsars versus quasars.
Speaker 1: Well, no, I didn't know that.
Speaker 1: but like the most basic kind of thing I didn't even know but like as soon as they said it I was like, oh that's really obvious.
Speaker 1: I should have known that is that you look up at the sky and the stars never move but the planets move around all the time and they move around.
Speaker 1: like And I was like, oh, yeah, that makes perfect sense.
Speaker 1: I never thought about it because I've never even thought about astronomy or cared.
Speaker 1: really it's interesting because when I was that's how Right, the people in ancient times were able to know that these things are planets and those things weren't even though they didn't have telescopes Or shit was because they were fucking moving around.
Speaker 0: the fascinating part when he gets into like even modern astronomy like he talks about how people actually figured these things out and just the attention to detail and the tiny things like, you know, You make a thousand measurements of like.
Speaker 0: this is where that star was on this day And this is where it was on this day and you have a thousand in a row and you think you've got it down and then one day it's slightly off from where you expect and You realize everything you thought was completely wrong and you have to kind of figure out the new thing and that people did that and we humans
Speaker 1: knew a
Speaker 0: Substantial amount of what we know today a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Well, I think part of it also right is imagine you had no TV.
Speaker 1: You had no books.
Speaker 1: You had no arts You had no nothing right and there's no lights either.
Speaker 1: So you look up at the sky every single night and you see all that shit all of it, right?
Speaker 1: No, you sit there for like hours.
Speaker 1: Just looking at it every goddamn day.
Speaker 1: You know what you're gonna notice.
Speaker 1: You're gonna remember what it looks like.
Speaker 1: you're gonna memorize the locations of different bits and you're gonna see if like the red dot moves around None of these dots move except that red one.
Speaker 0: Imagine - in a demon haunted world like in in an era when you we don't know what's out there You might mean there are people they would think, you know They're looking up at the gods or the faces of the gods or some like they had no idea what the stars were.
Speaker 0: but You know.
Speaker 0: imagine just the feeling of power of studying something like that back then when for all you know Those are gods you're studying.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like legit.
Speaker 0: But it's interesting to me that especially the astronomy stuff that a lot of this I knew from a kid because I was really really Really into astronomy and I had all these books and I read them all the time and I'd read this But I'd forgotten most of this because it doesn't come up in my daily life.
Speaker 0: yeah, like I just I'd never thought once about pulsars and quasars and the structure of the galaxies and all that until I Read this book again, and I remembered how absolutely fascinating it all is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know, I think the whole thing is like this great, you know, because people today right you try to like convince Someone of something that's all sciency like hey, you know micro-evolution or hey, you know freakin Quarks or something and they'd be like.
Speaker 1: I don't see that it ain't real what you show me a picture You know show me some fossils or whatever you got right and the thing is well This dude a bajillion years ago all he saw was a bunch of dots moving around and he figured out that the earth was round and he figured out all the Orbits of all the planets.
Speaker 1: and then when we made a rocket We saw and it was right.
Speaker 1: So it's the same thing.
Speaker 1: We can definitely absolutely using science figure out crazy shit and You know based on just like these like crazy Observations of the barest barest details and then later when the science improves We'll look and we'll probably be right just like we were right about all those things.
Speaker 0: I mean, isn't it just awe-inspiring that we've mapped places that probably nothing we ever do will ever affect.
Speaker 0: They're so far away?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, they're also probably no longer existing seeing as there's new things there.
Speaker 1: Was there anything in the book that like, you know, I mean the book is such, you know old and proven science, right?
Speaker 1: But so usually when you start reading about physics like you, you know My at least my brain does it likes to like come up with new physics like oh, what if this?
Speaker 1: yeah What if that right and it's obviously all usually wrong or figured out by some physicists already?
Speaker 1: So I try not to do that because I know that it's that it's wrong.
Speaker 1: But did you come up with like any like, you know things like oh, man I think this I might have had a a discovery of physics.
Speaker 0: Oh shit I did that a lot when I was a kid with black holes and stuff like that.
Speaker 0: And now the only thing that I thought of when I was reading this that I think was novel in my brain But then Carl Sagan said it straight up later was you know He's talking about the structure of the universe and how you know the center of the universe could be a point outside of anything we can experience like if it like if there's a four-dimensional universe and The Big Bang, you know the center of the universe could exist in a space that is not accessible to us and our three dimensions.
Speaker 0: You know things like that.
Speaker 0: And he points out that if the universe is infinite and boundless or sorry non infinite But boundless because it wraps around on itself and all that that light cannot escape it and that effectively the universe is from the outside a black hole.
Speaker 0: Yep, and That threw me for a huge loop this time funnily enough because I was thinking about the Prince of Nothing Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because remember the whole idea of causality and the idea of free will and Morality and everything at least in those books and in a lot of philosophy comes out of the idea that if one thing begets.
Speaker 0: Another thing there's an uninterrupted chain of causality from the Big Bang to the destruction of the universe if there is one.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm unless chains of causality from without are able to come within Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So imagine if the universe is just a big black hole or some equivalent of it or there is an outside that isn't.
Speaker 0: that is a separate causal chain.
Speaker 0: We've spawned everything we ever did from the Big Bang and that is the entirety of our experience that we could ever have our entire causal chain.
Speaker 0: But things enter black holes from the outside and cannot escape.
Speaker 0: so it's possible that things could enter our universe Sorry from the outside.
Speaker 0: It's got in the face.
Speaker 1: It's not doing it.
Speaker 0: who's the lifestyle.
Speaker 0: I Don't know.
Speaker 0: I was thinking about that the idea that you know What could our universe be like from the outside even though?
Speaker 0: Carl and every other scientist say that's not even a question we can ask because it has no relevance.
Speaker 1: one thing I was thinking about right is like, okay Everything is red shifted Doppler effect.
Speaker 1: Therefore.
Speaker 1: We know the universe is expanding, right?
Speaker 1: Anything you look at is red shifted.
Speaker 0: Well, either things are moving away from us because universe expanding or you know space itself is expanding.
Speaker 1: same thing base effectively, right?
Speaker 1: So here's the thing that I was wondering though.
Speaker 1: Nothing goes fast in the speed of light, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: So everything started in the Big Bang area and then spread out.
Speaker 1: Okay, so let's say you and I are standing next to each other.
Speaker 1: Right, I can see you and you can see me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, remember there's already a speed of light to lay between us.
Speaker 1: I know that you're a billion years.
Speaker 1: Let's say you're a billion light years away, right?
Speaker 1: Well, I see you but I see you a billion years ago because you were standing there a billion years ago, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so let's say you start right next to me because everything started right next to each other at the Big Bang, right?
Speaker 1: And then you start running away from me and this goes on forever, right?
Speaker 1: You can't go the speed of light.
Speaker 1: You can only go almost the speed of light, right?
Speaker 1: So let's say you go.
Speaker 1: I don't know 90% the speed of light.
Speaker 1: you're running away.
Speaker 1: Well, as long as I stand there and keep looking at you the light that hits you will pretend that light is always hitting you And bouncing off you and coming back to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's light always right infinite light.
Speaker 1: So Basically if I stand there no matter how much you keep running.
Speaker 1: I will always see you right no matter what.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I might see you as you were X years ago But I'll still continue to see.
Speaker 1: you will never disappear at any point.
Speaker 1: if you there's always light shining on you and you're not a black hole and I keep looking at you and such right nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, therefore would it not follow that?
Speaker 1: Everything that exists in our universe is visible and there is no.
Speaker 1: there's nothing hiding like beyond out somewhere else that we can't see.
Speaker 1: Because if something started next to us then we can still.
Speaker 1: either it's a black hole and it's absorbing light or something there could be.
Speaker 0: Here's one way one of the multitude of ways that can be broken.
Speaker 0: okay, there's an object that was shot out at 99% of the speed of light that was not emitting any light and Then due to its own internal reactions while it's moving it starts emitting light.
Speaker 0: What when it's already a billion light years away?
Speaker 0: that light won't reach us for a billion years plus the time that's added from the expansion of the universe in between us and it.
Speaker 1: that is very possible, but that my point is, you know that there be the We look out in the universe and pretty much.
Speaker 1: most things are emitting light, right?
Speaker 1: I mean, we don't know Radiation black hole.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're emitting something right?
Speaker 1: X-rays radio waves, right?
Speaker 1: This is you know talking about astronomy, right?
Speaker 1: There's all kinds of emitting going on.
Speaker 1: So I don't think you know, at least I'm not a physicist.
Speaker 1: I'm probably very wrong as you know But I'm not.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty convinced that there isn't that much stuff that is out there if we all started in the same spot.
Speaker 0: Well, it's got two things that we can't see.
Speaker 0: one is not a perfect universe and shit gets in the way of light.
Speaker 0: We're a tiny speck.
Speaker 1: shit does get in the way of light But it's like, you know the farthest away there.
Speaker 1: I don't think there's like some barrier like oh, it's a if it's you know The universe.
Speaker 1: let's say the universe is a billion years old, right?
Speaker 1: Then there it can't really be anything.
Speaker 1: that's two billion light-years away.
Speaker 1: can there be?
Speaker 0: well the Sagan.
Speaker 0: I think he pointed out straight up that I mean the universe is many more billions like.
Speaker 0: They saw two galaxies and for a while there was speculation that we were actually just seeing the Milky Way From the other direction.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: This isn't like the 20s.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then later Science taught us that no the universe is already clearly big enough to where light could not traverse the length of the universe In the time that the universe has existed.
Speaker 0: hmm Now that could be screwed up.
Speaker 0: by the way the universe expands because it's space itself that may be expanding.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess I can barely wrap my head around as it is.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, what about this, right?
Speaker 1: What if we both started in the in the Big Bang area, right and you I went do north I guess whatever north is and you went do south and we were both going in 99% the speed of light.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So It's possible that we would eventually run into each other?
Speaker 0: Well, no, but I'm not saying we're running into each other I'm saying would you still wouldn't disappear at any point right now because we'd both as if I'm moving away because you at the speed Of light and you're moving away from me at the speed of light.
Speaker 0: I think the mean difference in speed between the two of us would still be the speed of light because it's all relative to the Speed of light.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean think think about like two race cars, right?
Speaker 1: So you got two race cars and one guy's driving one way and one guy's driving the other way on an infinite track Right and they both got.
Speaker 1: look in the rearview mirror and they're looking at the other guy, right?
Speaker 1: Even if both guys are going real close to the speed of light, right the light will still right.
Speaker 1: You know light you think about it.
Speaker 1: Each guy is basically being chased by another car.
Speaker 1: That is the light car and the light car is going at the speed of light.
Speaker 1: So the light car will always catch you because you're going less than it, right?
Speaker 1: Even if you got a huge head start if I'm going one mile an hour There's still the catch you eventually.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there's still the propagation delay of the light has to bounce off and come back.
Speaker 0: So it takes twice as much time plus the fact that you're constantly becoming further away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it was you know, as long as the.
Speaker 1: but if this like an infinite stream of light cars one is catching you at Every moment.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, so you're for the car.
Speaker 0: the other car will never disappear further away when everyone hits you.
Speaker 0: Yes Of course the delay between each one coming back is the time.
Speaker 1: the time is absolutely relative But the other car won't disappear.
Speaker 1: It will always be there No, but the speed and thus two stars going in the opposite direction from the Big Bang.
Speaker 1: They will always be able to see the other star.
Speaker 1: They'll still see the star as it was a bajillion years ago But they'll still see it unless space is expanding at a rate that messes that up.
Speaker 1: That's so we don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: someone knows maybe not me.
Speaker 1: Probably not me.
Speaker 1: Definitely not me.
Speaker 0: What I noticed though that one thing about cosmos and this format works really well for this sort of book is notice how he'll Start with something where he's vague and he says hey, so here's a fact.
Speaker 0: Here's another fact.
Speaker 0: Here's another fact and they lead you in a direction of where you're like Wait a minute if those things are all true, and then he asks you so what if blah?
Speaker 0: What if blah?
Speaker 0: and he gets you trying to come up with the answer.
Speaker 0: then he's like well The answer is actually blah and you're like, huh?
Speaker 0: and then he talks about how they figured out the answer was blah and how awesome that story was.
Speaker 0: and then he's like So if blah is true, then what about blah?
Speaker 0: and he always ends everything with speculation and a question Mm-hmm, like everything he always gives you all these facts then he's like.
Speaker 0: but the odds are this or but what if this or what if that and what if this and the what ifs always get in The end toward the point of and there is.
Speaker 0: I don't have the answer for you.
Speaker 0: We don't know.
Speaker 0: we have to figure this out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I think it's very telling that the book is based on the TV show.
Speaker 1: right because you know in the introduction He actually says that they're sort of separate and complimentary or whatever and they're you know, whatever.
Speaker 1: But the thing is each chapter is totally its own standalone thing You know, but you can tell that because he knows that this is the book.
Speaker 1: some of the chapters will be like yeah Kepler Sutton Sutton because he knows that you will probably read the chap the Kepler chapter earlier on, you know.
Speaker 1: Whereas in the TV show, there's no guarantee that you saw the previous episode.
Speaker 1: So it was structured a little different there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, but it's it's pretty cool that it's like each and every chapter is its own Deal as if it were an episode.
Speaker 0: the show itself is really good Like each one is self-contained and follows that format and it starts out by showing you cool stuff and explains it all then asks you More questions than ends.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Good music and stuff too.
Speaker 0: And I just like watching Carl Sagan listening to his voice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's a cool dude.
Speaker 1: I was a cool dude.
Speaker 1: Yeah What else do you guys say about this book?
Speaker 1: I think you know the history parts of the book really helped me out because you know, I'm not too good at the chronologies.
Speaker 0: Captain who who I came first Knights or Romans?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know, it was.
Speaker 1: it was cool to actually because there's a bunch of science names, you know.
Speaker 1: And you know, I don't Kepler van Leeuwenhoek.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's like you already.
Speaker 0: did you already forget him?
Speaker 0: What Kepler do?
Speaker 0: I don't remember what van Leeuwenhoek do I don't remember.
Speaker 1: Ah, yeah, but you know, it's.
Speaker 1: It's cool that you know because that's not stuff that you're taught very much in school really, you know I wasn't straight up.
Speaker 0: In fact, all the physicists like the whole thing about wave particle duality with light.
Speaker 0: we in physics We actually did a history lesson on every single one of those people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, our science classes didn't really teach us so much about the people's, you know, they might have mentioned someone's name once You know or they'd like I learn more about like Copernicus and social studies class than science class and reading cosmos.
Speaker 1: What they told you about Copernicus is pretty wrong or at least lacking many important details.
Speaker 0: So there's actually a book that Emily's dad lent her that I borrowed and read.
Speaker 0: and if you like the history part of this Like what the scientists did now?
Speaker 0: They figured it out and what was going on at the time Bill Bryson wrote a book called a short history of nearly everything.
Speaker 0: And it's just that.
Speaker 0: it's like here's this scientist and here's what his deal was and some of these people were fucked up.
Speaker 1: So it tells you all about like the people themselves.
Speaker 0: Just you know in the science interspersed much like how Carl Sagan does it in cosmos like with Tycho Brahe You know, he's crazy but also like what was going on between him and everybody else.
Speaker 0: and you know, and It like my favorite part of it is there's one guy who he had two great ideas.
Speaker 0: There were actually terrible ideas But he had no way to know at the time.
Speaker 0: the same dude who invented CFCs that destroy the ozone layer was also like lead in Gasoline that solves everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, he just didn't.
Speaker 1: It's not that he was evil.
Speaker 1: He just didn't know.
Speaker 0: Well, he tested.
Speaker 0: he was like I gave these people all this lead and they peed most of it out.
Speaker 0: I don't think it'll hurt him.
Speaker 1: Let's go And that's true and it won't hurt you won't.
Speaker 1: you won't notice anything immediately, you know.
Speaker 1: And they you know, there's a lot of things where it's like people would have been cool.
Speaker 1: They just didn't know better.
Speaker 0: and it takes actually that I bring that up because I read an interesting article.
Speaker 0: This is speculation on behalf of a bunch of sign and you wonder like, you know Who now?
Speaker 1: will someone in the future look at and say we just didn't know better and you know currently what are we getting wrong?
Speaker 1: We just don't know yet.
Speaker 0: It'll be like giant robo.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly exactly like giant robo pretty much.
Speaker 0: So, I mean, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I feel like cosmos should be a textbook for like middle school kids and pretty much every science class ever like like every seventh grader should read cosmos or at least like big chunks of it as part of their schooling.
Speaker 0: because I think it Really?
Speaker 0: It inspires people like it's written in the same way that a religious text might be written But it's just facts and speculation based on facts.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm the other thing is you know, it's it's obviously like, you know, a lot of times the you know, These skeptical kinds of sciency people, you know They they're not very good at using the psychology and the coercion and all that, right?
Speaker 1: But he manages to write this in such a way that is not like offensive or off-putting and say a Richard Dawkins kind of way talking is like there's no God.
Speaker 0: What are you stupid?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at the same second is like isn't this awesome?
Speaker 1: But at the same time right, he's not really doing it in sort of a morally evil trickery way.
Speaker 1: He's not tricking you or like suckering you in.
Speaker 0: he basically like he'll explain like here is the beauty of this like this Facet of the universe of the cosmos, isn't that fucking awesome?
Speaker 0: now, maybe just some guy made it up or maybe this Look at this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or he's like, oh, you know aliens are cool.
Speaker 1: man wouldn't be awesome if they're aliens Let's figure out what the odds are.
Speaker 1: They're being aliens.
Speaker 1: What would aliens be like, you know, and then indeed approaches it, you know, realistically and then it's just like, uh-huh And now you know, it's like.
Speaker 1: well, okay now we've discussed aliens and that's pretty awesome and we've also Realized that people who think that their cows were slaughtered by you know, moon men are crazy But we don't need to even mention that because we have just discussed You know the real part and we did not include anything about.
Speaker 1: you know, moon men because there aren't any movement.
Speaker 0: I guess we can wrap it up here.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's not much to say but praise for this book and I hope you read it and luckily there's nothing to spoil.
Speaker 0: Spoilers Spoilers.
Speaker 1: the Big Bang is for real spoilers evolution.
Speaker 1: It works.
Speaker 0: It's real say is I cannot imagine the person who would read this book and still deny the fact that the Big Bang happened.
Speaker 0: We don't know what or why.
Speaker 0: there's a lot we don't know about it.
Speaker 0: But to deny that an event like that happened is just ludicrous
Speaker 1: like yeah I mean you'd have to like either not be able to understand you not understand the book
Speaker 0: or Anyone with an IQ of a hundred probably even like 70 could understand the majority of what is in this book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: or you know, you're just denying, you know, you have denial.
Speaker 1: You know, there are many, you know all sorts of reasons but You know or like a selective You know selectively choosing which parts to read and understand and which parts not to read and understand.
Speaker 0: there dot-dot-dot is Dot-dot-dot-dot-dot-dot-dot.
Speaker 1: God You know stuff like that, you know never underestimate the the ignorance of people.
Speaker 1: that is not something to be underestimated.
Speaker 1: I actually really like the last line of cosmos - Mmm, the other thing is that it's funny how the you know the book.
Speaker 1: most of the stuff in the book Right is.
Speaker 1: this is like old ultra proven science that you know, it was you know Determined over hundreds of years.
Speaker 0: I was watching through with Emily because she'd never seen it.
Speaker 0: some of like select episodes from the series, right and they had this introduction from a woman and then they had Carl Sagan come in and talk a few times where he was like.
Speaker 0: So here's like some updates on this like yeah this spacecraft did this and we learned this.
Speaker 0: But from everything I can read there is almost nothing that is wrong in cosmos or that we have figured out later was wrong.
Speaker 0: Speculation was later proven to be correct.
Speaker 1: Yeah it's the kind of stuff right in cut that's in cosmos is science that's so old and so rock-solid that if we're to if it Were to be unsolid did it would?
Speaker 1: it wouldn't be unsolid.
Speaker 1: it like oh my god suddenly it would take a long time for us to find something that is, you know contradictory to what is already in there and Also, you know the a lot of this stuff was just you know Was true in its day and it just needed updates right?
Speaker 1: For example, he's like, huh, you know, we we did this to Mars.
Speaker 1: What if we sent like a robot with wheels that could move around and shit?
Speaker 1: and it's like well, yeah, we did that.
Speaker 1: It's like 30 40 years.
Speaker 0: It was really cool to see some of the updates where it was Carl Sagan himself You know 10 20 years later saying things like yeah, check out what we learned since then.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know we it's pretty much.
Speaker 1: You know, we thought about doing this and then since then we did it and it was just like.
Speaker 1: I wrote mostly and there you go.
Speaker 0: So I think that's it.
Speaker 0: I hope you enjoyed cosmos.
Speaker 0: I hope you and I will enjoy the lives of Locke Lamora.
Speaker 1: I already read it.
Speaker 0: It was very good and I leave you with this.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows.
Speaker 0: sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.