Speaker 1: It's Tuesday January 19th.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm rim, and this is geek night tonight the secrets of Street Fighter.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So last year we talked a lot about PAX East and now we're looking forward to it.
Speaker 0: We're going to do some panels at it.
Speaker 0: We didn't really announce anything beyond that.
Speaker 0: It's finally time to announce that we actually are doing stuff at PAX East.
Speaker 1: no, we're not now.
Speaker 0: Now in Boston March 26th through 28th Pax is coming to the East Coast.
Speaker 0: in case you lived under a rock and didn't know Kansas, Boston, Massachusetts What was that?
Speaker 0: that I didn't use this thing that in college humor of the German people trying to pronounce, Massachusetts That was old like Mahasisht.
Speaker 0: But yes in Boston Mahasisht.
Speaker 0: March 26th 27th 28th the penny arcade expo on the East Coast.
Speaker 0: This is a grand grand.
Speaker 1: I love how they posted that.
Speaker 1: they thought that it would alleviate From the PAX West.
Speaker 1: when it's just I'm gonna boat you morons.
Speaker 0: Yeah We've been talking to them for a long time and way back when they were like there's gonna be a PAX East I believe I Said you're gonna get like 50 or 60 thousand people.
Speaker 0: you realize Everyone's gonna come out of the woodwork.
Speaker 0: There are so many more like.
Speaker 1: they basically thought that they.
Speaker 1: you know that anyone who wanted to come to PAX is already coming to Pax and they wanted to make a PAX East so that the people maybe who were traveling across the country to PAX West would just Stay home not go to PAX West.
Speaker 1: like okay We'll have two smaller conventions instead of.
Speaker 1: no the PAX East is bigger than the West.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be I can guarantee it because there's more cities closer to each other.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like population density an anime con in Baltimore gets 26,000 bodies.
Speaker 0: PAX West only gets like 20,000 bodies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so PAX East is far and away.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: the only reason it's not going to be some crazy enormous disaster Is that they're gonna cap registration?
Speaker 0: In fact badges are gonna be sold out Probably within a few days.
Speaker 1: Yeah, probably.
Speaker 0: so if you have not pre registered for PAX East and you want to go well Yeah, first of all, if you haven't already you are a fool.
Speaker 0: Yes, but pause geek nights and go pre register right now, or you're not going to get a badge and not even kidding.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know what year you're.
Speaker 1: you know, someone might be digging through the archives years from now digging this up listening to it.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what?
Speaker 1: You should do Year 2013 register for the next PAX East whatever it may be or else.
Speaker 1: You're probably not gonna get it.
Speaker 0: and PAX West.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel like the two are gonna be very different.
Speaker 0: I can't.
Speaker 0: I think they'll both be good But they'll serve different purposes and I feel like I'm going to have to attend both every year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, most I'm gonna be very curious to see what the culture of PAX East becomes, you know.
Speaker 0: So I do want to point out too they are looking for more enforcers.
Speaker 1: they need a lot of help and Yeah, a bunch of people I know signed up to be enforcers.
Speaker 1: In fact, even some crew Yeah, even some people I would not suspect of being Enforcers have been accepted and signed up and everything.
Speaker 0: So if you are willing to take up the black it is a bad.
Speaker 1: You just can't stop saying that because that's what they say.
Speaker 0: Think about that some anime con.
Speaker 0: You're a gopher You're a volunteer.
Speaker 0: PAX, you have taken up the black.
Speaker 0: You are an enforcer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's really corny when you say it over and over It's take up the black.
Speaker 1: It's far less corny.
Speaker 0: I take up the black you little guy to say it just once You know, however, I do want to announce because we finally have the initial tentative schedule.
Speaker 0: I hope this won't change.
Speaker 0: but we are doing Three and a half panels at PAX East this year on Friday in the wyvern theater It's the wyvern at 8 30 p.m We are doing beyond dungeons and dragons again again Again, we've already done it in that city.
Speaker 0: I know but for a different convention, we might be doing it of anime Boston, too.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's again in the same exact convention.
Speaker 1: I don't like.
Speaker 1: we got to retire the panel at some point.
Speaker 1: Well, we have to feel it is pretty much our number one panel.
Speaker 0: I know every.
Speaker 0: it's kind of like when we did that gecky goth panel and every stupid anime con for the next three years was Like yeah, could you run that horrible rape panel for us again?
Speaker 0: on Saturday Losing should be fun.
Speaker 0: I already know the days in at 1 p.m.
Speaker 0: In the Naga theater.
Speaker 1: Oh, how could we in the Raven theater or not?
Speaker 0: There is no Raven theater.
Speaker 0: There's a wyvern and a Naga and I don't know any other names But those are the two that all of our panels are in.
Speaker 0: Losing should be fun.
Speaker 0: 1 p.m.
Speaker 0: Naga theater on Saturday.
Speaker 0: on Sunday at noon beyond Candyland back in the wyvern and also on.
Speaker 1: It's either wyvern or wyvern I like with urn.
Speaker 1: it's no urn.
Speaker 0: it's urn Saturday sorry Sunday.
Speaker 0: action castle with Jared Sorenson.
Speaker 0: at 10 30 a.m The secret event for two years at Pax is finally on the schedule before packs.
Speaker 1: It takes a long time to get that on the schedule And we'll probably action castle is gonna be run by Jared, of course, but I didn't get game as mind control the schedule.
Speaker 0: Nah, we didn't get we.
Speaker 0: we only got four of the I don't know 11 events we proposed.
Speaker 1: So that's nice.
Speaker 1: We need more than that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll work on it.
Speaker 0: We'll work on it for Pax West.
Speaker 0: Yeah But action castle probably won't take the whole hour.
Speaker 0: So there will probably be something cool for the second half of that panel.
Speaker 0: Maybe some sort of discussion maybe involving Luke Crane and Jared Sorenson.
Speaker 1: one hour dealies.
Speaker 1: Yep And what I want?
Speaker 1: a two hour deal there are.
Speaker 0: there are only like 50 panels and packs.
Speaker 0: We already account for a surprising percentage of them.
Speaker 1: Did we get any gaming tables?
Speaker 0: I can't announce anything else yet.
Speaker 0: The only thing I have in writing that is done are the panels.
Speaker 0: So register for Pax East.
Speaker 0: it's already possibly too late.
Speaker 0: So go right now.
Speaker 1: It's likely too late.
Speaker 0: I mean they even tweeted they're like, hey, it's gonna sell out with Pax West also.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but think about how early it is sold out.
Speaker 0: I mean, they're not even gonna pretend they're already at the stage of there will be no badges at the door.
Speaker 0: It's just a matter of when they actually physically sell out.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: All right, so There's a lot of iPhone action lately, you know, there's some apps coming out that people I never thought I would see, you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know start with the generic statement and kind of bring it into whatever your actual news is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know how we do.
Speaker 1: that's how I do.
Speaker 1: so there's gonna be Something that you know, a lot of other portable devices have like, you know The n900 and the PSP things that people tend to like, you know They hack their device in order to get these things on there.
Speaker 1: This is gonna be totally legit Sega Genesis emulator for The iPhone made by Sega.
Speaker 0: now the thing is wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, so how do ROMs work?
Speaker 0: You just buy them for how much money?
Speaker 1: Well, Sonic the Hedgehog is $6 It's a little pricey and Golden Axe is $5.
Speaker 0: That's a little pricey.
Speaker 1: echo.
Speaker 1: The dolphin is $3 That's a little pricey.
Speaker 0: Shining Force is $3.
Speaker 1: I pay three bucks for that for Shining Force, maybe But on your on your iPhone.
Speaker 0: see here's the problem.
Speaker 0: Sega games for me have this situation of one.
Speaker 0: I was a Nintendo kid.
Speaker 0: So I have this weird Remembered latent hatred for Sega even though I owned a Game Gear and I love Sonic.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, but to rose-tinted glasses.
Speaker 1: Well the thing here, right something I've recently realized is that I don't know how much longer People are going to stand for this.
Speaker 1: maybe another year or so.
Speaker 0: It's simple.
Speaker 0: It's the exact same thing that happened With cassettes and with DVDs.
Speaker 0: when DVDs first came out everyone was like, oh crap I can buy that movie that I liked as a kid that you know I have a busted old VHS for again and own it in a modern format.
Speaker 0: but Nowadays, there's no reason to keep doing that.
Speaker 1: like if formats are digital I mean It's.
Speaker 1: eventually we're gonna get to the point once everything is in a digital format.
Speaker 1: if I've bought say an exe file I'm not gonna repay To get a you know Something else file for a different, you know, so it runs on something else.
Speaker 0: But they do planned obsolescence or just things change standards go away DRM servers shut down.
Speaker 0: There are ways to force that however with digital media the moment that happens is pirated because I already bought it.
Speaker 0: if I already bought It pirating the exact same thing again.
Speaker 0: What could you possibly say again?
Speaker 1: I mean it even extends beyond this right like look I just bought Street Fighter 4 for the PC on Steam, right?
Speaker 1: It's nice.
Speaker 1: it's basically 100% the same exact game.
Speaker 1: that is on Xbox, right?
Speaker 1: The only difference is that the PC version is They added some slight modifications like cuz.
Speaker 1: they need an options menu in order to you know Configure your video card settings, which you don't need in the Xbox and they needed an options menu to configure different buttons.
Speaker 1: Cuz you know computers have keyboards.
Speaker 0: They should put those Xbox games anyway, just to confuse you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, but I mean those are the only changes they've really made at all.
Speaker 1: Other than that, it's probably you know, they probably it's the exact same code.
Speaker 1: I know the Capcom has a system that they make can make games cross-platform very easily.
Speaker 1: that where it's 90% like the same exact game.
Speaker 1: So and even if they didn't they can.
Speaker 1: if you're making something in like XNA for the Xbox and the PC It's 90% the same exact thing even more than that.
Speaker 1: Maybe 99% the same exact thing.
Speaker 0: Well, that is why.
Speaker 1: so why should I have to pay again?
Speaker 1: I bought Street Fighter 4.
Speaker 1: Why can't I play it on the Xbox?
Speaker 1: It's the same exact thing.
Speaker 0: Well, here's here's brilliant.
Speaker 0: Yes So they do not do what if they you buy one version of the game?
Speaker 0: Whatever now the smart the nice thing to do would be now you have it for every system forever.
Speaker 0: Yep, what I would do is the business man and say all right you own it on the PC for $1.
Speaker 0: You can get the whatever you need to also play it on your.
Speaker 1: I mean That's something I think that they can do actually in the short term is they could say, you know, PC version $20.
Speaker 1: Xbox version $20 Version for both computer $30, you know that would work for a short time.
Speaker 1: I would even pay $30 for the double version instead of $20 individually for the you know Versions that only work on one platform, right?
Speaker 1: And that would actually also be good because all the people who are only interested in getting it for one platform or the other Would also buy more copies to save more money.
Speaker 1: and here's the thing right is that if you think about it having separate copies for separate You know platforms how much money that's not giving them any extra sales.
Speaker 1: How many people are buying the game twice?
Speaker 0: I know it would not too many people If they do well for them if they did the thing where the Xbox version has this tiny little difference.
Speaker 1: So the hardcore bands by both but you know If they that's what they do it like adding the characters and Soul Calibur on the different platforms.
Speaker 0: well, I mean, who do you who do you want link or How many extra copies do they sell?
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: I can't believe that they would sell that many extra copies of Because people need to buy both right, but if they sold a version that was the double version They would sell a lot of extra copies of people who would just say oh man That's such a huge bargain something that works on both.
Speaker 1: I'll totally buy that.
Speaker 0: I think the reason they don't probably boils down to a misunderstanding on their part of the market.
Speaker 1: Yes So I think in the short term you could make money with that sort of pricing model of having a double vert.
Speaker 1: You know selling a combined pack of you know stuff.
Speaker 1: But I think in the long term pretty much you're gonna be forced to just sell your game.
Speaker 1: This is my game if your game happens to be multi-platform You're just gonna have to give them the game on every platform at once in one package, you know.
Speaker 1: And the thing is right.
Speaker 1: you think about it.
Speaker 1: Let's say I make a game for Xbox three 360 and ps3, right?
Speaker 1: Okay, it doesn't cost me anything To you know print a CD.
Speaker 1: It's like a dollar not even a dollar to print another disc.
Speaker 1: So why not just put both discs in the same box and say, you know 50 bucks.
Speaker 1: That's what it is.
Speaker 1: Why why go through the?
Speaker 1: you're actually spending more money to print up two separate boxes with two separate instruction manuals.
Speaker 1: You would save money in the economy of scale Because the only extra cost is actually manufacturing be.
Speaker 1: the thing they had to worry about though With that specific instance is because these are you know physical media.
Speaker 1: I would buy the double version and my friend has a ps3.
Speaker 1: I have an Xbox now.
Speaker 1: We actually have two copies.
Speaker 0: That's why you have to do with digital activation, right?
Speaker 1: But with digital this isn't a problem anymore.
Speaker 1: if it's steam or something, right?
Speaker 1: So if Mike if my console hooked up to my TV is also steam and my iPhone is also steam and my you know Take that.
Speaker 1: that's the way we need to go is wherever you have a steam or something like it and it's just.
Speaker 1: all your Platforms of gaming TV your portable your PC all your gaming platforms all run on the same Store and you only buy a game once and you can play it everywhere.
Speaker 1: This is why I can buy Mario Brothers and I could play it on the Wii.
Speaker 1: I could play it on the DS I could play it on my iPhone.
Speaker 1: I could play it on my PC.
Speaker 1: I could play anywhere.
Speaker 0: This is why I'm not buying an Xbox in this general.
Speaker 0: I've decided not to bother with the Xbox 360.
Speaker 1: Well, the only reason is because I realized the Xbox 360 is gonna be around for years.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but I see This trend and I I imagine that it won't be that long before.
Speaker 0: much of the Xbox 360 Repertoire is available in Windows game.
Speaker 1: First of all, it already is most of the Xbox games that are any good, but not all of it.
Speaker 0: Yes, I can't play every Xbox game on my PC yet.
Speaker 1: Yep, and I the thing is the reason I got the Xbox is because it was mad cheap there's a big deal on it and Because there are a few games.
Speaker 1: I really wanted to play and I noticed I haven't bought any physical games for it whatsoever.
Speaker 1: And the other thing is that I already had controllers for it.
Speaker 1: So it was sort of like a double bonus, you know, and I can also make games for it, which is kind of neat.
Speaker 0: So how many games have you made?
Speaker 1: zero?
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah there is one.
Speaker 0: I think there are two separate days of reckoning.
Speaker 0: the first day of reckoning that they're just not addressing at all is The conversions of platforms, but there's a very specific phenomenon of selling retro games to people primarily based on nostalgia.
Speaker 1: There's also I think selling retro games to people who never played them.
Speaker 1: I mean how many people.
Speaker 1: you know, we played the fuck out of Mario 3, right?
Speaker 1: But there are a lot of people out there who didn't play Mario 3 and they could still buy Mario 3.
Speaker 1: So if Nintendo puts it up for sale, they can make some money.
Speaker 0: Yep However, this only works because of these weird market conditions.
Speaker 0: I mean say I have an original copy of Mario 3. until you know, not that long ago It was the biggest selling game in the history of games ever.
Speaker 0: now It's not even on the top 10 list But in terms of the thing about how many Mario 3 cartridges exist just in North America too many.
Speaker 0: So what if you bought all of them up for cheap or you acquired one somehow and you just dump the ROM and destroy the cartridge?
Speaker 0: You haven't committed a crime as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 0: So what if you didn't even copy the ROMs?
Speaker 0: What if you just sold the ROMs and everyone was perfect and no one pirated it?
Speaker 0: that would still destroy This whole.
Speaker 0: buy it for five bucks market.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I mean the cartridges.
Speaker 1: I mean there are some people with NES is out there.
Speaker 1: But really the cartridges no one's.
Speaker 0: very few people in this weird situation the cartridges direct where a lot of the media from the past that isn't just available in a completely digital DRM free format is Not competing with modern media as effectively as it could because there's an artificial price limitation.
Speaker 0: There's an artificially high price to get Mario 3. when the considering the supply Mario 3 It's harder to get a lot of things than it is to get a copy of Mario 3.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean you see like a cartridge ever for sale for like a dollar at some Chinese knockoff store.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: There are a ton of remixes of that Hitler movie where they'll just resubtitled.
Speaker 1: I'm so tired of these Hitler you make.
Speaker 0: you got to admit the first Hitler remix was pretty funny.
Speaker 1: Yeah So played out, you know and it's like alright.
Speaker 1: at this point guys The joke is not.
Speaker 0: there's always the trend where someone will do something clever like that.
Speaker 0: There will be a million copycats for a while and then someone will do something More clever with it to change everything and kind of jump up above the crowd.
Speaker 1: I don't think this is one of those cases.
Speaker 0: I think it is because rather than taking that one scene and just changing all the words which anyone could do They took that scene changed all the words and integrated it with Khan from Star Trek.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's just because you don't like Star Trek.
Speaker 0: I found this hilarious.
Speaker 0: Okay, mostly for the piss-off at the end for Hitler, yeah.
Speaker 1: So in gaming no matter what kind of gaming you're doing There is one shape.
Speaker 1: that is the most important shape in all of gaming.
Speaker 1: Do you know the shape?
Speaker 0: See, I do know but I'm not going to spoil your thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna spoil it.
Speaker 0: perhaps the the rhombus.
Speaker 0: No, maybe the the decahedron.
Speaker 1: It is it.
Speaker 1: a decahedron is double is a dough Decahedron it's not I don't know if you look at a double dough decahedron from a certain angle Perhaps it looks like a hexagon the most important shape in all of gaming.
Speaker 1: So here's a website Hall of hexagons.
Speaker 1: This website is about nothing but hexagons.
Speaker 1: It contains A cornucopia of maths facts about hexagons including the area lengths and angles number sequences tiling tessellation the Sizzles, you know I see Polyhedron, I think you can differentiate what kind of gamer and from what era someone is by what shape they actually say.
Speaker 0: because Remember when third-aid D&D switched to the square?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and of course, I thought you're thinking today was something else.
Speaker 0: I thought you're going to talk about the om nom nom a gone.
Speaker 0: What's the official name for the shape of pac-man?
Speaker 1: This is uh, here's a website all about hexagons And if you need to do something like it's really it's mostly useful.
Speaker 1: right if you're going to make a game You know Maybe you need to print a hex map or maybe you need to make a hex object or maybe you need to program a game involving hexes and you need like the algorithm to draw a Hex grid or you need to find the distance, you know Like if my battle mech is gonna move from this hex to that hex How much distance is there from the center point of this one to the center point of one?
Speaker 1: That's three up and two over.
Speaker 0: remember using the laser pointer on battle tech with lines of sight and be like It's just touching the edge of the hexagon.
Speaker 0: I can hit him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So here is here's the exact math you can use to avoid using a laser pointer.
Speaker 0: The sad thing is all through my high school career all through my middle school career all through my time at RIT What I wanted and needed more than anything was a hex map and a square math, but I just there were too much money.
Speaker 0: It was never worth it and I bought one on sale when I realized that if you buy these slightly imperfect ones They're like quarter the price, right?
Speaker 1: Cuz usually you go to the store and you want to buy a hex map and there's like a perfect hex map.
Speaker 1: It's all.
Speaker 1: they're all lined up in your straight, you know And there's a nice border around the edge of the map and the hexes are printed directly in the middle, right?
Speaker 1: so but apparently at the store they just have like these off-cut ones where it's just like they basically just slapped a bunch of hexes down in a big sheet and just cut it up into you know, sort of squares and They're straight enough and it's like way way way cheaper than getting the pretty hex map and it's just as serviceable.
Speaker 0: So we bought it and I've never used it.
Speaker 0: because I never needed it.
Speaker 1: because I don't play D&D anymore I don't bought it at like the last minute.
Speaker 1: It's like just as we didn't need it anymore.
Speaker 1: We bought it.
Speaker 0: It sat there in the living room and every day.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh man, I can't wait to play battle tech.
Speaker 0: I have not played battle tech since we bought that.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's time.
Speaker 1: It's time to live battle tech for a long time.
Speaker 0: I think we should schedule an FRC battle tech meetup.
Speaker 1: Oh snap.
Speaker 1: No girls I mean is the thing right?
Speaker 1: Okay, you know any girls who want to complain about no girls allowed in battle tech.
Speaker 1: I ask you do you actually want to play battle?
Speaker 0: I'll say a different.
Speaker 1: are you seriously saying you want to play battle?
Speaker 0: I will put it this way for reals.
Speaker 1: Like most people of my age back in the day arcades still existed.
Speaker 0: We kind of we're at the end of the arcade era.
Speaker 0: I remember going like Mortal Kombat 3.
Speaker 0: I'd stand there in line and lose my quarter to the one guy who was good at fighting games.
Speaker 1: exactly You know.
Speaker 1: and I played the street fighter - I played Street Fighter - I played Super Street Fighter - I mostly played Street Fighter 2 Championship Edition.
Speaker 0: when I was a kid I wondered if there was a Street Fighter 1 and I did not believe it existed.
Speaker 1: I had played the Street Fighter 1 at a young age.
Speaker 0: actually I had never played it until that katsu-kan where they brought it.
Speaker 1: really See I had played it much earlier than that because there was a an arcade in Milford that had the machine.
Speaker 1: There was pretty also had accused are there?
Speaker 0: there was precedent for that sort of bullshit?
Speaker 0: because remember goonies - no one remembers goonies won That's true.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: But anyway, so I had played my share of Street Fighter.
Speaker 1: I even had Street Fighter 2 Championship Edition for the Sega Genesis and the six button gamepad, you know I played it.
Speaker 1: now thing is I was never good, right?
Speaker 1: I would always just get my ass kicked by anyone who actually knew what they were doing.
Speaker 1: You know, even if I went to a convention and played open gaming I would just get my ass completely destroyed.
Speaker 1: people do these combos and then I would try to like even if I tried a little Bit like to read a combo in the book.
Speaker 1: I would try to do the combo.
Speaker 1: It'd be like okay jump in with a light punch do two standing light kicks a low-light punch and then a hadouken.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you're thinking that meanwhile the guys just like boom boom boom, right?
Speaker 1: Okay, so I was like I have no idea what to do and I had always assumed it's my reflexes It's something you know.
Speaker 1: And the thing is even beyond that.
Speaker 1: like I couldn't do most moves like I would see okay to do a shore You can I press forward down then down forward then push the punch button, right?
Speaker 1: So I try to do it and it wouldn't work.
Speaker 1: and I try to do it.
Speaker 1: It wouldn't work.
Speaker 1: and I try to do.
Speaker 1: I try doing the arcade it wouldn't work.
Speaker 1: I was just like what the fuck.
Speaker 0: I also had the problem if I learned a complicated move I would always try to use it at the wrong time because I could use it.
Speaker 0: So I wanted to use it all the time.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mostly be like M bison do psycho crushers back and forth because I was able to do charge moves.
Speaker 1: charging was easy Right.
Speaker 1: Just hold the button down for two seconds then push the other button and you know, then push two other.
Speaker 0: So I played guile a lot of the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those moves are relatively easier to understand that I could actually execute them, right, you know.
Speaker 1: But basically because I was never able to achieve any skill and I never had enough money to pump quarters into the arcade And I you know, I just I just couldn't get good at the games.
Speaker 1: You know, I just sort of stuck at my level.
Speaker 1: but Very recently steam had a big sale and Street Fighter 4 was cheap cheap cheap cheap.
Speaker 1: So I was like, you know what?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna buy Street Fighter 4 and you know what?
Speaker 1: I know That I am never going to be good at these games.
Speaker 0: the last time I had an illusion that would be good at a game is when the new Smash Brothers came out because I thought I will from day one practice and make sure that this is the game now Fucking that stops right right away.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I thought you know, I'm like, I'm never gonna win a tournament ever in my life.
Speaker 1: I'm never gonna beat anyone who actually you know It's like some young kid who's good at fighting games never gonna beat anyone who's like a Korean and who learned how to play Street Fighter from their elementary school teacher where they had, you know Street fighting class and Mortal Kombat class, right?
Speaker 0: A Starcraft class, I believe you mean Starcraft University.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: So I'm never gonna expect to beat them or be as good as them.
Speaker 1: But I would if I'm gonna buy this.
Speaker 1: I want to get to the point where I can get a combo off.
Speaker 1: You know, I can actually do the super move.
Speaker 0: I at least hit him one time before I go down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't just get pinned in the corner.
Speaker 1: infinite combo done I'm dead because I don't know what to do.
Speaker 1: I you know, I just want.
Speaker 1: I want to be able to go to PAX go this open gaming.
Speaker 1: I can go up to a game a fighting game.
Speaker 1: All right, and not just be embarrassed.
Speaker 1: You know if I'm doing a podcast about gaming I should be able to at least have a mildly Respectable amount of skill and there is no reason even though my reflexes probably don't compare to like some 13 year olds.
Speaker 1: There is no reason that I cannot practice this for a few hours a day and get some progress.
Speaker 1: You know, I can read these instructions on these special moves.
Speaker 1: The game has all the special move instructions in it.
Speaker 1: I can do this.
Speaker 0: plus I'll say this as a kid I at least had unrealistic expectations as to my skill because I was playing FPS is constantly and I was really good.
Speaker 1: and you're down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're dominating in other genres that weren't fighting games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't think as a kid that wait a minute I've spent many many years Practicing constantly at FPS.
Speaker 0: is why do I expect to be good?
Speaker 1: thing is well The thing is right.
Speaker 1: I did play a lot of fighting games.
Speaker 1: I owned Street Fighter 2 championship edition.
Speaker 0: You played them, but you did not grok them.
Speaker 1: Well, listen, I'm gonna tell you I Played probably Street Fighter 2 championship edition just as much as I played like fucking Mario 3 or Sonic the Hedgehog or whatever, but I'm way better at those than I am at Street Fighter 2, right?
Speaker 1: so I start playing Street Fighter 4 and You know, I can do a Hadouken.
Speaker 1: I'm already like just reading the instructions and how to do the moves and going into training mode and just sort of practicing Doing the special move over and over again.
Speaker 1: I'm building up a little bit of skill, right?
Speaker 1: I can do it.
Speaker 1: I can just do it.
Speaker 1: who can's over and over again like I do Right, and I'm like, alright, and if they get close I can actually most of the time do a shoryuken when they come into jump Kick, right?
Speaker 1: So I'm getting somewhere.
Speaker 1: but really That amount of skill is not any I can't on the game.
Speaker 1: if I try to play the game on medium with that level of Skill, I can't beat it without continuing right?
Speaker 1: So clearly I am NOT and if I play online I basically have a 0% win rate against random internet opponents.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So this was obviously not enough to achieve my goal, right, but I was having fun.
Speaker 1: The game is fun It's a good game.
Speaker 1: So I I'm able to stick with it, right?
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: So what do I do now?
Speaker 1: Well someone I get some advice from people I know on the internet.
Speaker 1: So I talked to someone who's you know, who has it for the ps3 and he's giving me some advice like hey You should stick with one character to learn all their stuff and I'm like, yeah You know, that sounds like a good idea cuz that helped.
Speaker 1: that worked for me in Soul Calibur, too.
Speaker 1: You know stick with one guy learn their stuff, right?
Speaker 1: And then he tells me, you know, like there's a trials mode now.
Speaker 1: Remember we were talking that there should be some sort of DDR for Street Fighter Shouldn't
Speaker 0: show you can
Speaker 1: do right where it's like the arrows and the buttons would fall from the top of the screen So that you would know what to push right and you would learn the timing from that.
Speaker 1: now Trials mode doesn't have that but trials mode is still pretty close to that.
Speaker 1: What it does is it'll tell you like, okay do a strong punch as you do it and it says yes.
Speaker 1: Then it says okay now do a crouching kick ha.
Speaker 1: and it'll get you say good.
Speaker 1: and then it'll say now do a fireball.
Speaker 1: So you do a fireball and says good.
Speaker 1: and then you know, you can just keep doing this and it gets progressively harder.
Speaker 1: It'll be like, okay do the super move.
Speaker 1: Okay now do Jump punch followed by a low punch followed by a fireball right and you have to do them really quickly.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, you can see Graphically, it'll show you like how long you have to do one move after the previous move and it's no time at all.
Speaker 1: Basically and when you do it properly, it'll be like punch punch arugan.
Speaker 1: It's like fast really fast, but I was able to do it eventually with practicing and I was like, all right I felt good.
Speaker 1: I mean to push the buttons and see him do three things really fast where you know As long it's a combo a real combo the first one hits and that he can't avoid you for like three more hits.
Speaker 1: That's it feels real good.
Speaker 1: It makes you want to keep playing, right?
Speaker 1: So eventually, you know, I'm playing just sort of random modes and doing some trials and playing against computers.
Speaker 1: right and The computer is based.
Speaker 1: one time I'm playing against the computer and also I saw a real person do this and they're basically going like sonic boom sonic boom Sonic boom sonic boom and I'm like what?
Speaker 1: how the are they cheating?
Speaker 1: Do they have a sonic boom button on the game?
Speaker 1: What are they doing?
Speaker 1: Right to do a sonic you have to hold back for two seconds And then to do a sonic boom the instructions say you must hold back for two Seconds on the game clock.
Speaker 0: I always said that from Street Fighter 2.
Speaker 1: then you have to push forward and then push a button right which means According to that all laws of physics say that you must wait two seconds between sonic booms.
Speaker 0: Am I actually two seconds plus I guess the Planck limit of time of you know, hitting all the other buttons, right?
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: Well the you know the time on the clock that the Street Fighter in-game clock is pretty much Seconds the real-world seconds.
Speaker 1: It's a pretty accurate clock, right?
Speaker 1: Maybe it's a little bit fast.
Speaker 1: Maybe a little bit.
Speaker 1: So how were they doing?
Speaker 1: one sonic boom per second, right?
Speaker 1: How is that even possible?
Speaker 1: You know, did you mean after the first sonic boom comes out?
Speaker 1: I shouldn't see another one for two seconds, right?
Speaker 0: So obviously there is some secret here that we are stupid.
Speaker 1: So usually right when it let's think about other games for a minute, right, let's take advance wars, right?
Speaker 1: I'll play against rim and advance wars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like ring you're cheating.
Speaker 1: How the fuck did you get three medium tanks in the same amount of time with the same number of cities and all I have For three mechs?
Speaker 1: and I'm like, there must be some gnosis.
Speaker 1: you have The secret knowledge right.
Speaker 1: that is Preventing me from being that good there is.
Speaker 1: I was convinced there is a secret knowledge.
Speaker 1: now rim in advance wars.
Speaker 1: Is there a secret knowledge?
Speaker 0: I fucking count how much money I've got and I plan ahead a couple rounds so that so we can Agree that there isn't really a gnosis in advance or no, there's just bad Right.
Speaker 1: So going by the you know, I mean I have complained of secret knowledges in many games But really I've never actually found a secret knowledge, right?
Speaker 1: What can you think of an example of a game that actually has Gnosis some secret secret things that aren't in the instruction manual where if you know them Suddenly the world opens up to you and you're on another level.
Speaker 0: One minor one is pay me for the fucking door, but that's that is a sort of a nose.
Speaker 1: What is minor?
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: it's not a game changer, right?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna tell you something I actually had to research very.
Speaker 1: it was surprisingly difficult to find this information.
Speaker 0: Did you try to just like do them?
Speaker 1: I tried to just go to game facts to see if I could find the nose.
Speaker 0: I mean you turn into guile and just try to like do a bunch of.
Speaker 1: I couldn't do more than one every two seconds right, so You know there were two seconds between my sonic booms when I tried to do it.
Speaker 1: So I tried to go to game facts.
Speaker 1: now there was some you know.
Speaker 1: in game facts I couldn't really find the gnosis but what I could find were some lingos.
Speaker 1: words like Cancel counter tech right like oh you got to tech out, you know.
Speaker 1: And I was like what the hell is tech out mean?
Speaker 1: is that something?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean I've seen the words tech flash across the screen when I'm playing.
Speaker 1: sometimes It's usually when I try to throw and the other guy tries to throw at the same time.
Speaker 0: see now I know in like for example spinning disk appears, and this is tech I've never brought.
Speaker 0: I think it means technique not technology is a good example because there's these Situations in the game that I could never take advantage of and I didn't even know about them to some fanboy told me about him.
Speaker 0: But like all right you can do a block in the air to like cancel out the timer on some move.
Speaker 0: You just did to do it again.
Speaker 0: But it was always so esoteric that I didn't care about it because none of our friends did any of that stuff.
Speaker 0: So I didn't need to worry about it.
Speaker 1: Yep, so I researched further.
Speaker 1: I was I was very very determined to learn the secrets right because I was just so convinced there was Gnosis.
Speaker 0: so came in.
Speaker 0: are you gonna tell me this fucking gnosis?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna tell you I have not learned all of the gnosis right I have only learned a little bit.
Speaker 0: so the core I will.
Speaker 1: they hit you, but let me tell you the gnosis is real.
Speaker 1: There are through.
Speaker 1: the rules of Street Fighter are not in any instruction manual or in any game fact And this is why everyone in the world is better at Street Fighter and similar fighting games.
Speaker 1: Then we are is because there is secret information That is not well published on the internet.
Speaker 1: the game doesn't tell you the secret information.
Speaker 1: Game facts doesn't even have it.
Speaker 1: It's only in.
Speaker 1: like these other facts We're kind of hard to find.
Speaker 1: I had to go.
Speaker 1: someone gave me a link to a something awful Forum thread that had links to some facts that had like inklings of the gnosis And I was able to read that and derive the gnosis by inferring things from that tag.
Speaker 0: It's tough.
Speaker 0: You're digging through the asartic library, but half of its burned down.
Speaker 1: I was also got a lot of help by watching YouTube videos.
Speaker 1: There was actually a YouTube video.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'll link to it right.
Speaker 1: that has that shows a lot of things from Super Street Fighter 2 Turbo, maybe I'm not sure if it's turbo or not But it's definitely Super Street Fighter 2 and a lot of those same things apply in future Street Fighter games like Street Fighter 4 Gnosis number one.
Speaker 1: This is the.
Speaker 1: this is the big one.
Speaker 1: you're ready you ready for this.
Speaker 0: lay it on me, okay?
Speaker 1: So let's say I want to do something real simple do a jumping punch followed by a hurricane right?
Speaker 1: So I tap up and forward my guys jumping forward I get close to you I press the punch button I land on the ground then I press down down forward forward And I press hadouken that is much too slow because I punch and then I have to do this whole movie.
Speaker 0: wait Wait wait wait do I?
Speaker 0: I think I see where you're going with this.
Speaker 0: do I not need to wait for what my guy was gonna Do to finish?
Speaker 0: do I just have to do the motions?
Speaker 1: no it's even crazier than that.
Speaker 1: you ready for this.
Speaker 1: So there are certain moves.
Speaker 1: It's called a cancel.
Speaker 1: right it depends on what the first move you're doing is.
Speaker 1: some things are cancelable and some things are not Right.
Speaker 1: if something is cancelable you can start doing stuff while that is still happening, right?
Speaker 1: So like your super moves are our quote-unquote infinitely cancelable.
Speaker 1: So you can input moves while the super move animation is happening and when the super move animation is done the moves will come out right.
Speaker 1: so If you do a cancelable You know attack You can do the hadouken while the animation for that cancelable attack is happening And then the hadouken will come out immediately afterwards.
Speaker 0: so sonic boom is cancelable and you can.
Speaker 0: just so you do it.
Speaker 0: so you
Speaker 1: do a sonic boom and then you me as soon as you let Go of it you pull the stick back to start charging the next sonic boom while the first one well He's still saying sir He's like it isn't even gotten to the onik and you're already charging right the second sonic boom.
Speaker 1: so it's like boom.
Speaker 1: Right it takes him like almost two seconds to do the sonic boom move especially if it's the fear sonic boom which is slower.
Speaker 1: So as soon as he's done with that one you let out the next one and start charging the third one.
Speaker 1: And you can just go sonic boom you only need the two second weight on the first one.
Speaker 1: But get this you can do a jump kick.
Speaker 1: so I jump forward.
Speaker 1: right to do the jump kick.
Speaker 0: is jump kick cancelable?
Speaker 1: No check this out.
Speaker 1: I jump forward right.
Speaker 1: I immediately before I even do the jump kick.
Speaker 1: I'm holding back I'm still and I just tap up and forward.
Speaker 1: I'm to jump into the air.
Speaker 1: just tap it.
Speaker 1: any jumps, right?
Speaker 1: So before I even reach the height of the jump I already have the stick facing backwards.
Speaker 1: then when I get close to you I tap some attack buttons and then forward in the sonic boom.
Speaker 1: and That those two seconds started while I was wet.
Speaker 1: before I even reached the peak of the jump I was already counting up the charge on the sonic boom.
Speaker 1: whoa I can do the same thing.
Speaker 1: I could jump forward and push down immediately and then do the flash kick Right and then while I'm in the air with the flash kick I can hold down.
Speaker 1: I land on the ground.
Speaker 1: another flash kick.
Speaker 0: You know we need to do.
Speaker 1: I could do a flash kick.
Speaker 1: hold Backwards while I'm in the air with the flash kick.
Speaker 1: land do a sonic boom.
Speaker 0: We have a holy mission in front of us.
Speaker 0: We need to organize the forumides to make a day Bible of.
Speaker 0: Here is all the bullshit.
Speaker 0: to end this tyranny once and for all.
Speaker 1: um ram.
Speaker 1: I'm not done with the gnosis.
Speaker 1: There is more Gnosis, are you ready for this?
Speaker 0: I see but I do not witness.
Speaker 1: that is correct.
Speaker 1: So I jump in for my punch.
Speaker 1: hadouken move right and while my punch is still happening I go down down forward forward punch right.
Speaker 1: yeah now if you want to do Let's say you're just standing there in Street Fighter, and you want to punch someone you press the punch button.
Speaker 1: Yes, if you want to punch them two times you must punch the punch button two times.
Speaker 1: punch punch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now if I'm a button measure I'll just keep hitting it until I've punched them through jobs.
Speaker 1: But you will do a number of punches equal to the number of presses right?
Speaker 1: yes.
Speaker 1: So if you wanted to do the game will tell you the instructions.
Speaker 1: to do a hadouken is to do down down forward forward Quarter circle that you know and then the punch button right.
Speaker 1: so you would think that to do a punch and hadouken You must need to press the punch button two times.
Speaker 1: that is incorrect.
Speaker 1: You only need to press the punch button one time to do a punch followed by a hadouken.
Speaker 1: Because if it is a special move You can use a button release to execute it.
Speaker 1: so I can press the punch button hold it down The while the punch is executing.
Speaker 1: do the quarter circle then let go of the punch button and that let go will execute the hadouken.
Speaker 0: This is becoming more and more like the way you learn how to play an open hold flute where they're like the the decks.
Speaker 0: dexterity of memorizing the combinations These very specific overlapping like what path should my fingers take a or B?
Speaker 0: Well if I'm going into move see I have to memorize path B instead of path a even though they're both otherwise equivalent.
Speaker 0: mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Huh here is some more minor.
Speaker 1: No C's.
Speaker 1: Are you ready for this minor?
Speaker 1: so in Street Fighter 4 They have the focus attack.
Speaker 1: you ready, so if you press Actually, I kind of like this about Street Fighter 4 is that if you want to do a throw You know it always be kind of hard to do with throwing old Street fighters You have to get really close and press hold forward and a punch or a kick or back in a kick right?
Speaker 1: You just push both light punch and light kick at the same time and that does a throw You know and the direction you're gonna do a throw forward or throw back.
Speaker 1: It's real simple to do throws now, right?
Speaker 1: You can do a focus attack by pushing both medium attack buttons at the same time and what this does is it makes your guys Sort of flash like right, and they'll start charging up like.
Speaker 1: And then when you let go of it they go Right it's a focus attack.
Speaker 1: the focus attack has armor.
Speaker 1: So that means that if you take damage during the focus attack your health meter will go down But it will still leave this sort of gray shadow up there, and you know where your health is miss.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've always seen that.
Speaker 0: I just assumed that was the way they drew it.
Speaker 1: No That gray shadow means that you got hit But your armor block the hit.
Speaker 1: see because if you actually get hit you'll see your guy take damage.
Speaker 1: He'll go out or fall down or something and then you've taken real damage.
Speaker 1: But if you take if you block the damage with armor Right then it's only sort of this half damage, and you can get that life back.
Speaker 1: What you have to do is just you know you if you hit with the focus attack the other guy is gonna be in trouble.
Speaker 1: So then you just sort of any.
Speaker 1: as the time goes on as long as you're not actually getting hit for real Your health will slowly fill in that space again.
Speaker 1: So if you doesn't matter how much damage you take if you blocked it with armor as long as you don't get hit before it Fills up again.
Speaker 1: that health wasn't actually lost.
Speaker 0: You know what that is in many ways battle balls.
Speaker 1: You're ready for more the focus attack because the focus attack has armor.
Speaker 1: You could you know.
Speaker 1: you can charge the focus attack up a little bit a little bit more or a lot.
Speaker 1: You know you can charge it up as much as you want and there are some moves that have armor break So that they'll break through and actually do real damage to you while you're doing the focus attack.
Speaker 1: But you know most people don't actually use the focus attack to do the focus attack.
Speaker 1: What they use it for is that armor property.
Speaker 1: so what they'll do is let's say Ryu is throwing a fireball at you.
Speaker 1: Let's say it's some guy.
Speaker 1: He's just throwing constant fireballs, right?
Speaker 1: What do you do?
Speaker 1: you got a. you know you got to slowly jump over the fireballs and get close to him right?
Speaker 1: or maybe?
Speaker 1: You can just hang back and continuously jump over the fireballs with timing until he's forced to do something else or the game clock runs out or something along those lines.
Speaker 1: You can use the focus attack.
Speaker 1: one fireball will hit you during with the correct timing will be blocked by the armor.
Speaker 1: Then you can tap forward two times to dash forward.
Speaker 1: You'll be right in his face Ready to punch him in the face, and he won't have the next fireball ready.
Speaker 1: yet you'll be able to just like throw him or do whatever the hell you want right and You didn't even have to jump in the air or dodge any fireballs.
Speaker 1: all you had to do is press these two buttons simultaneously to block a fireball and then dash right into him.
Speaker 1: and that's that's a move that works and Nowhere nowhere in the instruction manual is any of this explained whatsoever.
Speaker 0: I'm surprised that some nerd hasn't just written like a definitive.
Speaker 1: I mean look at there are that but the definitive guide.
Speaker 1: the thing is these definitive guides.
Speaker 0: They're written in an ancient language.
Speaker 1: They use a lot of lingo, and there was even a glossary right.
Speaker 1: so An example from the glass lingo.
Speaker 1: It's jargon right, but I mean they for example in the glossary it talked about.
Speaker 1: it talked about You know a cancel or a two-in-one right and it was like a cancel or a two-in-one is when you buffer up one move You know while the another move is still executing, and then we've you look up buffer.
Speaker 1: It says yeah, you basically input a whole bunch of commands You know getting ready for them to execute, but it that's not really specific enough.
Speaker 1: It took me a while to actually figure out.
Speaker 1: well like well When do I start buffering?
Speaker 1: you know can I which which things can I buffer up?
Speaker 1: And then when do I actually push the punch button?
Speaker 1: You know I mean even something so simple.
Speaker 1: if you tried to teach someone brand-new to do a Hadouken They've never played Street Fighter or any fighting game before right?
Speaker 1: you tell them Oh, it's a quarter circle, and then a punch button right you have to.
Speaker 1: what's the actual timing of that?
Speaker 1: How soon after the forward do you push the punch?
Speaker 1: Do you push it simultaneously a whole second after a microsecond after you know?
Speaker 1: Do you how quickly do you need to do the quarter circle?
Speaker 1: if you do it too quickly?
Speaker 1: It won't work.
Speaker 1: if you do too slowly then your guys just gonna crouch, and then walk forward a little bit.
Speaker 1: He's not actually gonna do the move you know and they don't tell you these things.
Speaker 1: Nowhere does it tell you these things.
Speaker 1: it is it is just completely Non-explained information because the audience is assumed to already have these ultra Fundamentals and even though I'm trying to practice and learn them I can only learn so many of them.
Speaker 1: I still can't do like Zangief's moves.
Speaker 1: We have to do a 360-degree circle and then press a button.
Speaker 1: I still cannot do that move with any reliability.
Speaker 0: well the noses Clearly goes deeper and deeper.
Speaker 0: you've learned two of the voices, but you don't have the third and utterable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of voices that are missing here.
Speaker 1: right but The point is that there is a gnosis here And it is like it.
Speaker 1: if you bought a video game and the instruction book was incomplete I mean, but by the same token Pokemon are the same way.
Speaker 0: I mean if you want to be the master you go to the Eevee and the IV training and the seating And all that stuff.
Speaker 0: it's basically the same thing the only difference right, but I mean in Pokemon.
Speaker 0: the facts to do this are Immaculately precise that a five-year-old could follow them, but the thing is this right.
Speaker 1: the kind of gnosis We're talking about here is a little bit different.
Speaker 1: right in Pokemon You're not really supposed to know Eevee training.
Speaker 1: You don't need to know Eevee training to beat the game.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: in Street Fighter 4 if you want to beat the game on hard you need to know this shit right that you can beat all of Pokemon without knowing anything.
Speaker 1: see one could argue that number two right something like the fact that you can let go of a button to Do a Hadouken instead of pressing one?
Speaker 1: That is not like some.
Speaker 1: you know Eevee training where you don't need to know that.
Speaker 0: well Well that is pretty.
Speaker 0: one argument they could make but I'll say why this is wrong is that you know that's the kind of Mastery that you start to play the game with the basic rules, and then you emergently figure it out, but because it's so Methodical like cancel uncancellable.
Speaker 0: It's so specific.
Speaker 0: It is clearly by design and really should be in the instruction.
Speaker 1: It is absolutely by design.
Speaker 1: You know the armor is a built-in thing in the game like nowhere.
Speaker 1: Does it explain that if your health bar goes down and there's a gray bar left behind that that's going to recover?
Speaker 1: It doesn't say that anywhere.
Speaker 0: Are you absolutely sure that's not in the instruction book?
Speaker 1: It's not in the instructions in the game.
Speaker 1: the game Barrett doesn't even have a tutorial.
Speaker 1: all it has that trials mode You know it's there is.
Speaker 1: there is nothing you know.
Speaker 1: and if you go to the command list right to say How do I do this move?
Speaker 1: all it says is do like you know.
Speaker 1: it says quarter circle forward with a plus sign And then a picture of a fist.
Speaker 1: that's all it has.
Speaker 1: it doesn't teach you the timing.
Speaker 1: it doesn't tell you if plus means Simultaneous or afterwards.
Speaker 1: it doesn't tell you anything.
Speaker 1: all it says is quarters.
Speaker 1: It gives you a picture of a quarter circle forward followed by a plus sign followed by a fist.
Speaker 0: I just I am surprised.
Speaker 0: There's got to be.
Speaker 1: that is not enough information for a nub Not enough.
Speaker 1: and the thing is if they gave out that information.
Speaker 1: I think that the level of Skilled play of nubs would go way up.
Speaker 1: I mean they still would get crushed by the Masters.
Speaker 1: right, but a notice.
Speaker 0: There's two sides.
Speaker 0: There's knowing, but they're still doing.
Speaker 0: and doing is not easy.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: I mean I can.
Speaker 1: still.
Speaker 1: there are still cases right where I just don't have the reflex And I'm trying to practice and build it up like this one trial where M bison has to do like a crouching fierce Followed by a super like super move, and I just can't do it quickly enough.
Speaker 1: I can't make it happen you know even though I I know that I can cancel and buffer it up and all this.
Speaker 1: there's no more noses left on this one.
Speaker 1: I just can't do it.
Speaker 1: no matter how much I try now I'm not like you know.
Speaker 1: um right now.
Speaker 1: I'm into this you know and I'm having fun.
Speaker 1: I want to figure it out But I'm not like hardcore into it like I. could I really justify like going to buy a stick?
Speaker 0: Well, it's the question.
Speaker 0: you want to at least find the knowledge to prove that you can do it.
Speaker 0: But then beyond that it's the.
Speaker 0: do you want to spend the time to achieve mastery?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you want to be a master or a professional.
Speaker 1: so I was thinking about if I should buy a stick.
Speaker 0: You really should at least everything.
Speaker 0: I read everyone even Conrad's into that stuff.
Speaker 0: He plays these games a lot.
Speaker 0: He has a stick.
Speaker 1: yes I was looking to buy a stick maybe and I was like oh I can't really justify buying a stick for one game.
Speaker 0: what like 40 50 bucks?
Speaker 1: No, they're more.
Speaker 1: That's like 70 bucks.
Speaker 0: I paid more than that for my flight stick Pro.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I played.
Speaker 0: you know what I played on that flight stick Pro tie fighter.
Speaker 0: That was worth all the money by itself.
Speaker 1: so at first I wasn't gonna buy a stick.
Speaker 1: right, but you know I'm using the Xbox 360 controller, but then right I'm actually starting now that I've learned things right.
Speaker 1: It's like because I did actually always sucked when using a stick in the past.
Speaker 1: I mean I played Street Fighter 2 championship vision on my Genesis with the six button gamepad You know.
Speaker 1: so a stick was never really good for me.
Speaker 1: I always kind of sucked in the arcade and not good with the stick.
Speaker 1: I would hurt my hands using all those buttons.
Speaker 1: You know get like the claw hand.
Speaker 1: You know hitting those six buttons like that.
Speaker 1: So I wasn't gonna get the stick and I started investigating and I started.
Speaker 1: as I played more I realized wow Now that I'm playing more properly.
Speaker 1: Now I understand why the stick is better.
Speaker 1: You know it's like the stick wasn't better for me when I didn't know these things.
Speaker 0: well think about that.
Speaker 1: I know these things.
Speaker 1: now this that it's like if you it's like a it's like a whole hog.
Speaker 1: Right if you're drilling a whole hog is probably just gonna destroy you.
Speaker 0: if you don't know Imagine a halo only console playing FPS guy Who is just put in front of a computer with a mouse and keyboard with tribes to mouse and keyboard?
Speaker 1: He's got nothing.
Speaker 0: it's gonna ruin him But if he understood the value of the mouse and keyboard then he would suddenly have this new tool Disposition that would make him a god.
Speaker 1: Yes, so I'm trying to justify buying like the $70 stick right?
Speaker 1: So this is mad cat Street Fighter 4 stick for the 360, and I'm like.
Speaker 1: well I bought Street Fighter 4 for the PC.
Speaker 1: so I researched.
Speaker 1: yep.
Speaker 1: It works on the PC.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: That's good, right?
Speaker 1: I found out that this stick is also like made to be moddable like it opens up, and it's Purposefully everything inside is all exposed and standard arcade.
Speaker 1: Why are you?
Speaker 0: you could have fun with that in your Arduino?
Speaker 1: I could do lots of stuff with that right also if I get you know like that You know like a computer plugged into the TV again, and you get some maim on there.
Speaker 1: Hello, this you know.
Speaker 1: so I think Because this stick is all moddable and such I could just get this stick and use it forever.
Speaker 1: I'd never need another stick you know I could.
Speaker 1: it's USB I mean what.
Speaker 1: I could use that for all Eternity.
Speaker 1: you know if super Street Fighter 4 comes out, which it is coming out.
Speaker 1: I'll be all set you know and maybe I'll have a new genre here the maybe I won't suck as much Me.
Speaker 1: I still haven't won against any online opponent who wasn't Scott Johnson.
Speaker 0: You've got a long way to go I mean you just.
Speaker 0: you just scratched the surface of the gnosis.
Speaker 1: I know, but the fact that there was actually a gnosis that was real because usually there isn't like.
Speaker 0: It's always the advanced war situation Game.
Speaker 1: since I was in like middle school right how old the Street Fighter 2 god You know I. I've been playing it since that was just Street.
Speaker 1: I'll admit I never knew these things.
Speaker 1: apparently these things have always been true.
Speaker 0: I always just assumed that I sucked And then I just wasn't good at these games.
Speaker 0: that I never would be.
Speaker 1: I thought it was like Reflexes or something that you know like with some sort of natural limitations.
Speaker 0: I was even worried that because Scott was playing this game again that maybe because we're past the age of 22 We're just getting too physically old, but no it's not.
Speaker 1: well We are.
Speaker 1: we are too physically old to achieve a certain level But our maximum level is still far higher than I thought it was simply because there really were just secrets Just plain old secret knowledge that was hidden from us.
Speaker 0: well Scott.
Speaker 0: It's a secret to everybody.
Speaker 1: it is a secret to everybody.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website At front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.