Speaker 1: Hey, it's Tuesday, June 15th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek night tonight games involving bidding.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: That's the best I can do with just my hands.
Speaker 0: I thought you said you had a.
Speaker 1: I do have one when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: You see, you know weird weird facts from rims childhood life.
Speaker 0: I can't believe this without any evidence being all skeptical.
Speaker 1: I lived in Michigan.
Speaker 1: I can probably find a picture of myself with it.
Speaker 1: I had one of these stupid plastic trumpets.
Speaker 1: It was the exact same one.
Speaker 1: They're using in South Africa, or maybe it was the South American one.
Speaker 1: That's slightly crook I'm not sure but it came into my possession when I was in elementary school and I used to go to arena soccer games a lot in Detroit and At those games a lot of people would have those things and it turned out they sold them at the games next to like the hot Dog stand.
Speaker 1: so I was a trumpet player and I convinced my parents to buy me one and I proceeded to be Horrifyingly annoying at all of these games forever because I could blow it louder than most people could Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And also I think maybe South.
Speaker 1: it's different in places where people have a culture around them and they know how to play them but People would buy them and then not know how to blow in them.
Speaker 1: One of my co-workers - he was like what I thought you just blow now, yeah, you gotta go Seriously, fuck those things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I like traditions and you know sporting things like that.
Speaker 0: That's my style, but I mean you got to have something clever like, you know in Europe They sang a song even it could be a clever dirty song like fuck the other team and Something like rip rip.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if you're just basically, you know, you could play a song like Drone.
Speaker 1: it just never stops and it's so loud It is actually damaging to the hearing of the people in the audience not to mention.
Speaker 0: There is also speculation that it spreads all kinds of disease around Spitting on everybody all the time.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 0: apparently the mean.
Speaker 0: if you just if you only played them when you scored a goal You know, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: so all right You got fans of two teams in the arena or basically like even if they only played it when the other team had the ball And then stop playing it when their team.
Speaker 1: What if you've got half fans of one team and half fans the other team.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the problem.
Speaker 1: But I mean as long as I'd fix this if it were anywhere other than South Africa Not enough people would know how to make it make noise and that would be okay.
Speaker 1: The problem is everyone knows how to use the stupid things down there.
Speaker 1: The other problem is if they were constructed just slightly differently It'd be more like a bugle or you could play like maybe two notes.
Speaker 1: two notes would be enough.
Speaker 1: Well, I did.
Speaker 1: you do do do do do do do.
Speaker 0: during some of the games, right?
Speaker 0: There was some drumming action you could hear and people.
Speaker 0: they weren't playing multiple notes.
Speaker 0: But what they would do is they would stop and start.
Speaker 0: so you'd be like You know, they play sort of a song on it, you know along with the drumming section.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but most of the people were just droning non-stop entire game.
Speaker 1: Luckily the BBC, you know, they're not gonna ban these things or anything.
Speaker 1: It's such a part of like the heritage and the culture of the game down there.
Speaker 1: But the BBC I think said the co-worker told me this that they're going to Stop playing the ambient noise from the game accepted certain situations and just show the game and then play a commentary track.
Speaker 1: And that's it.
Speaker 1: Mmm.
Speaker 1: We'll see if that happens.
Speaker 1: We will see because apparently I saw someone was passing.
Speaker 0: ESPN hasn't changed anything.
Speaker 1: There was an mp3 that some guy was like.
Speaker 1: It's the anti sound of the sound and it'll cancel it out if you play it at the same time.
Speaker 0: That won't work you don't think so.
Speaker 1: it'd have to be in the same phase.
Speaker 1: It wouldn't work at all.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: You couldn't just like record a sample and then you'd have to do a real-time like frequency analysis.
Speaker 0: Mmm, what if you?
Speaker 0: what if we put the game on like a two-second delay?
Speaker 0: we could do it, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it would not be that hard for some audio engineers to basically cancel that thing out.
Speaker 0: I mean it would mostly can.
Speaker 0: and then what they could do is they could have a little switch and Un-cancel it at certain moments.
Speaker 1: That'd be great.
Speaker 1: So they score a goal and just Mmm.
Speaker 0: But all that aside they can even have a volume knob like how much are we gonna cancel?
Speaker 1: Luckily, there are two things.
Speaker 0: they can make it louder.
Speaker 1: They could double it up to take heart with.
Speaker 0: it can move the phase back.
Speaker 1: the people playing.
Speaker 1: These are not professional trumpet players.
Speaker 1: So one they are cutting the fuck out of their lips and possibly causing permanent nerve damage.
Speaker 1: They do that too much.
Speaker 0: I don't think they care.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just same as people who go to like metal concerts that earplugs They don't care - or just light tap At the end of one while someone is blowing them will cause extreme pain Really?
Speaker 0: Yes, even like what?
Speaker 0: how?
Speaker 0: so?
Speaker 1: because basically you've got this thing up against your lips And if you're not like skill like a trumpet player has muscles and embouchure to be able to make the pucker I mean I can make the noise without even like having anything around my lips.
Speaker 1: It's not loud, but it's there just So in order to make it make the noise.
Speaker 1: if you don't have those muscles You got a really like push it into your lips.
Speaker 1: So you've already got a lot of pressure there.
Speaker 0: But maybe if these people go to a bunch of games and they every game they're playing it non-stop.
Speaker 0: Maybe they got they built up the.
Speaker 0: it's possible.
Speaker 1: It is possible.
Speaker 1: The thing is the more you abuse pressure Which is kind of like the quick way to make it work the less you develop the muscles and then you never really get anywhere And in fact you cause permanent nerve damage.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So we'll see.
Speaker 1: do I only have to put up with this for one year?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and for you Do they decide where it's gonna be in?
Speaker 1: 2014 if these things ever become popular anywhere else in the world.
Speaker 1: I don't know what to do.
Speaker 0: I don't know either.
Speaker 1: I don't think anywhere else in the world will bother learning how to make.
Speaker 0: no I think that pretty much It's like they're using the tradition excuse here and even so like a lot of South African people don't even like it, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, any place in the world where it's not already a tradition.
Speaker 0: They can just ban them with no questions.
Speaker 1: You know, there won't be any pollen storm actually had the most poignant thing to say about this.
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 1: I'm paraphrasing here I never thought I would think back on the days of something as innocuous as thunder sticks and wish we could go back to said Days, dude, I would take thunder sticks.
Speaker 0: The thing is though thunder sticks, right?
Speaker 0: They're kind of okay But imagine if they played the thunder sticks the whole game non-stop everyone thunder stick they did.
Speaker 1: luckily It was.
Speaker 1: it was so quiet.
Speaker 1: thunder sticks are not nearly as loud as an angry hooligan.
Speaker 1: One hooligan outweighs like ten thunder sticks unless you hit those thunder sticks in perfect unison.
Speaker 1: Plus they break like right away It's true.
Speaker 1: But over the weekend, I just want to mention this because it was totally awesome and we'll probably talk about it later.
Speaker 1: maybe I'll do a show with Emily.
Speaker 1: I want to have a board game con or a board game get-together at a Korean spa.
Speaker 0: I don't think that'll work won't be board games.
Speaker 0: get all night out.
Speaker 1: So Emily and I over the weekend to try this out went to a Korean like traditional bathhouse Spa castle out by flushing and like College Point.
Speaker 1: All right, so the way this this works really quick here.
Speaker 1: It's kind of awesome.
Speaker 1: So you go in and men and women go to separate areas.
Speaker 1: You get a locker I get a little watch with an RFID in it that opens all the different lockers and things and it's pretty nice night.
Speaker 1: I tech and you take a traditional Korean bath Which is a lot like the Chinese baths in the shower Or even a Japanese bath.
Speaker 1: So they've got hot tubs like super hot hot tubs and cold tubs and you take the bath and shower.
Speaker 1: You gotta be naked with all your you know, ever all the other guys.
Speaker 1: But that's just the way it works.
Speaker 0: a lot of old nasty guys in there.
Speaker 1: Actually, you know, what's weird?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Emily said that women's side was mostly just like older Korean ladies and like yeah That's that's what I would assume be old people on the guy's side.
Speaker 1: It was like two-thirds.
Speaker 1: It might as well have been packs.
Speaker 1: It was like tattooed normal gamer looking guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like people like me all right and then like a bunch of Korean really old guys with the balls out.
Speaker 1: But yeah, that's what I expect mostly to be in those kind of players mostly you chill you hang out like they're talking and playing Games and you know, it's really relaxing and they were like a sleeping area and a TV area.
Speaker 1: But then once you're all showered and clean and hot tub you get in the this uniform and you go up to the second floor.
Speaker 1: Now it's co-ed men and women and there's tables and chairs and lounges and saunas and food and restaurants and all this stuff.
Speaker 1: You're all just barefoot hanging out.
Speaker 1: You all just spod for an hour or two and bathed and it would totally be awesome to spend a whole day.
Speaker 1: They're like playing board games.
Speaker 0: Why why I mean like the thing is like what's the point of the hanging out part?
Speaker 0: I mean you could just go and take the bath and go home and hang out The traditional bath ideas you go.
Speaker 1: it's part of the community like you hang out with me.
Speaker 0: I mean, maybe if there was some cricket battles up there, you know, there's the equivalent You have to the third floor also co-ed whole bunch of pools Uh-huh and bar pool, I imagine they're not naked pools.
Speaker 1: No, no, I mean the gender separated areas are the only naked pools man.
Speaker 0: We need some co-ed naked pools.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess we could do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it'd be awesome.
Speaker 1: But I don't know I could foresee.
Speaker 1: if you don't want to come you don't have to come.
Speaker 1: but I think I'm gonna organize some Sort of crew get-together at this place because it was pretty badass.
Speaker 0: I gotta go Gets.
Speaker 0: I made the doctor's appointment.
Speaker 0: I go to the doctor before I can do any pools.
Speaker 0: I got some kind of fungus.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Oh God Like where I'm my back somewhere, huh?
Speaker 0: That's why I didn't notice it a minute.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute, but are you always saying like you never.
Speaker 1: you've never had a fungus like you never.
Speaker 0: I had one fungus.
Speaker 0: now I have two funguses.
Speaker 1: Okay That didn't expect that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Well, let me know when that's done and Got a doctor didn't give me an appointment until like July.
Speaker 1: so it's like, uh, uh Yeah, I don't know if you should go to the naked spa castle and risk spreading your fungus to people like me.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's a spreading fungus.
Speaker 0: I think it's a a one-person fungus.
Speaker 0: Okay, so 50 games Yes, the e3s, huh?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I forgot it.
Speaker 1: You know, I was gonna make a joke like yeah, I forgot about it.
Speaker 1: three three I really did forget about e3 until the news started coming out.
Speaker 0: Yeah Really there wasn't a big lead-up going on.
Speaker 1: Three is no longer a fan convention.
Speaker 0: Like it never was a fan.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean it was.
Speaker 0: Well, I think that's the thing right.
Speaker 0: is e3 was a. it was basically the only gaming video gaming thing.
Speaker 0: so everyone snuck their way in and They technically didn't let fans in.
Speaker 0: but they you know they appealed to fans and the kind of things they had there and Then they shut down and then they sort of came back and now they think they've managed to make it a non fan Industry only thing mostly because things like packs have taken the load off for them.
Speaker 1: Yeah packs is everything like.
Speaker 1: it has everything I would have ever wanted out of e3 because the only other thing to get out of e3.
Speaker 1: well, I guess two things are hobnobbing with industry people if that's the sort of thing you need to do and Getting all the news I can just see on Kotaku.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So really what e3 is all about now is basically Microsoft Sony and Nintendo all have press conferences at the same time.
Speaker 0: Pretty much it.
Speaker 0: but I guess other people, you know, like EA and Activision, right?
Speaker 0: But pretty much that's all it is is everyone at this time.
Speaker 0: We're gonna all do our thing at once okay, and they do it and As a result, there's a whole bunch of announcement type things.
Speaker 0: I guess we don't want to spend the whole show doing this.
Speaker 0: cover only the major major items.
Speaker 1: So Nintendo made a game.
Speaker 0: They made a lot of games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, when was the last time a game came out?
Speaker 0: I mean, that's the thing is they've had these same games like on the docket for a long time Like Golden Sun DS has been.
Speaker 0: they announced that forever ago.
Speaker 0: so we met right other M. they announced that forever ago.
Speaker 1: remember when the dwee came out and they were like We got this Zelda game that was gonna be on the GameCube, but now it's a Wii game.
Speaker 0: We were like, okay I wonder when the real Wii Zelda is gonna come out Now and not even it's gonna come out next year, yeah, maybe even holidays Holidays 2011 it could be.
Speaker 0: you don't know why Nintendo.
Speaker 0: Well, they're just so slow.
Speaker 1: Well, it's weird how rapidly Nintendo is just like.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't know if they're still printing money.
Speaker 1: Their sales definitely aren't as high as they were but the Zelda trailer wasn't even that interesting.
Speaker 0: yeah, it did not look like.
Speaker 0: it looks like it's probably gonna be like somewhere above the What's the one majora's mask but below the other 3d Zelda's like just judging from the trailer, which is not, you know, an accurate judgment at all, but The only.
Speaker 1: how could the trailer be so uninspired?
Speaker 1: Remember when they announced Twilight Princess and then like the first trailer came out and everyone was like all the Twitter whoo Look at that like it was impressive.
Speaker 1: It was dark.
Speaker 1: It was cool all these things and this one just looked like another Zelda game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was actually and the music to be honest was kind of shitty.
Speaker 1: sounding in the trailer like it sounded really like overly synthesized.
Speaker 1: You think by now you'd think they'd have a proper orchestrated soundtrack, but that was crap music.
Speaker 0: They you know, I'm no fan of like Metal Gear's really but actually there was the Metal Gear trailer at the Microsoft thing and that actually like Surprisingly impressed me with the cutting.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Well, did you see that?
Speaker 1: but can love blossom on the battle?
Speaker 0: But I like that cutting action that was like that was.
Speaker 0: I was like, whoa, I'm actually legitimately Intrigued by your cutting.
Speaker 1: it's funny how finally we've got all the effectively we knockoffs like finally coming to light.
Speaker 0: Yeah Microsoft one is technologically impressive, but it looks to me like I'd if I bought it right and it's gonna be like $150 if I bought it, right?
Speaker 0: I mean Wii Sports was fun, right?
Speaker 0: We played like the.
Speaker 0: even the newer Wii Sports with the motion plus is fun, but it's like how I'm not in college anymore I don't have a family.
Speaker 1: So even if I got it, I would play it so rarely, you know I think a lot of our listeners actually kind of have commented recently on how rapidly we went from.
Speaker 1: the Wii is the best thing Ever - we have Xboxes and really it comes down to what we've always go.
Speaker 0: Listen, anyone who says that can go listen to the earliest geek nights where we're saying PC gaming is dead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay So But now think about what happened.
Speaker 1: We no longer have four people in the same physical place ready to play a Wii game all the time.
Speaker 1: as soon as that happened There's no reason to play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean if I was living, you know in college still or with my family I would have a completely different, you know purchasing pattern, you know of what games I was buying.
Speaker 0: I mean, I have new Mario Brothers.
Speaker 0: I'd be rocking it with a whole bunch of people all the time.
Speaker 0: We'd probably like stay up playing it for a long, you know, you know what though?
Speaker 1: It's all gonna be good because Conrad it's gonna be living real close to us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know, we're already living close and we're not playing a lot of in the same house co-op type things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not really trying though.
Speaker 0: No, well, you know But yeah, that's like, you know, I don't begrudge anyone though like about because in our day we had different games.
Speaker 0: You know, we had DDR we had tribes - you know, we had Smash Brothers You know, they were out of strike, you know Mario Tennis.
Speaker 1: I'm still playing.
Speaker 0: You know we had the games for parties in our day and now this party games of the current day and the party games of the current day are no good to Us because we're not currently in a party situation.
Speaker 0: But if you are out there listening and you are in a party situation, you're in college You have family members siblings to play with Roommates, right and you want to play video games.
Speaker 0: Valsia Nintendo and Microsoft are providing, you know, awesome stuff for you.
Speaker 0: You can play.
Speaker 0: freaking that Xbox sports is looking good.
Speaker 0: If you don't have a Wii, you know, you get so that there's no new Mario sports at the Mario volleyball at hockey.
Speaker 0: That's looking like hot shit, right?
Speaker 0: It's just no good to me now because I don't have anyone.
Speaker 1: to be fair part of it too Is that?
Speaker 1: look at the party games?
Speaker 1: We still really really like.
Speaker 1: I mean WarioWare on the GameCube.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but how often do we play it?
Speaker 0: Would you buy it if it came out today?
Speaker 1: You know, I would if it were cheap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is.
Speaker 0: the other thing is that all these things are actually pretty expensive for what they are.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like Nintendo games never go down in price.
Speaker 0: That's the only reason I didn't get Mario Galaxy 2 yet because it's still 50 bucks.
Speaker 0: I'm not paying 50 bucks.
Speaker 1: I think part of it more.
Speaker 0: the only game that I'm actually looking to actually spend money on are like Some Xbox live arcade games that are looking cheap Golden Sun DS and the Metroid one, you know saying the curvy one.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: See, I'm thinking part of it too is just that I Never bought the Wii.
Speaker 1: So was it your place?
Speaker 1: I imagined I would bring people over more to play it if it were my place, but I don't want to buy one.
Speaker 0: I Actually got to send mine in for repairs.
Speaker 0: The disk drive has got the making a bunch of noise problem But they'll fix it.
Speaker 0: I just send it in.
Speaker 1: So maybe the trick is and I start organizing Wii nights and then just tell everyone show up at your place Then we show up and use your Wii.
Speaker 0: if everyone shows up at my place to use the Wii I'll go buy a whole bunch of new party games and we'll play them all.
Speaker 1: I think it's gonna happen because the what you're forgetting is seasons.
Speaker 1: What season has it been lately?
Speaker 1: nerd NYC's been bringing board games back.
Speaker 1: So we've had this kind of constant low-level board game season.
Speaker 0: I think it's role-playing game season.
Speaker 0: We got some dwarf coming up in a couple weeks.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's definitely role-playing season.
Speaker 1: I've also had a lot of single-player PC game season.
Speaker 0: It's definitely been also single-player season for sure and also internet play season.
Speaker 0: I've been playing Civ 4 I've been playing Super Street Fighter 4 games with the number four in them And then I'm gonna be I guess I'm gonna play Starcraft 2 when it actually gets released for not beta and then Civ 5 And then NS 2 whenever that happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're lucky.
Speaker 1: I mean with basically all these games are just to keep us busy until Civ 5 and NS 2 come out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've got all my eggs are in the NS 2 basket.
Speaker 0: All right I mean there's a lot of items but we can we don't have to discuss them all but we do have discuss I guess the 3ds that we can't avoid that one right now.
Speaker 1: I I don't think I'm gonna get one right away.
Speaker 0: I don't think so either, you know, I didn't get the DSI and the 3ds doesn't look like I need it right away either.
Speaker 1: Is the Kid Icarus game on it big deal, but the thing is it doesn't look like it's a platformer.
Speaker 1: It looks like a Zelda game.
Speaker 0: You know Nintendo released is coming out with a shit ton of platformers for the Wii so I can get all of those One at a time, but no
Speaker 1: every screenshot of Kid Icarus looks like it is Zelda Just with a different skin and maybe more action and less, you know, Zelda II puzzles.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't look anything like Kid Icarus.
Speaker 0: I think they would have been better better off with something like the Picross 3d You know for the 3ds instead of for the DS.
Speaker 1: I don't like Picross.
Speaker 0: you suck kind of lame.
Speaker 0: It's better than Sudoku.
Speaker 0: Sure, I'll give you that It's the same thing only better.
Speaker 0: What do you want?
Speaker 1: also I do not like.
Speaker 1: Now I will say we'll talk about the 3ds once we touch one.
Speaker 0: Yeah I guess you can't really talk about it because we haven't actually personally experienced the 3d parts of it.
Speaker 1: predictions though based on previous Nintendo bullshit.
Speaker 1: here are my predictions.
Speaker 1: Most games will not use the 3d or will use it in uninspired ways.
Speaker 0: There won't be a great number of games that are using it in an awesome way.
Speaker 0: There will be just a couple.
Speaker 1: just ones that do will be first party.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean look there's like, okay so the Wii?
Speaker 0: which games really use the Wii for reals?
Speaker 0: the two sports games and Yeah, and which games really use the DSI for reals?
Speaker 0: the one WarioWare do-it-yourself game?
Speaker 0: and Which games really use the 3ds for reals?
Speaker 0: Well the Kid Icarus game and maybe a couple others they come out with.
Speaker 1: The Kid Icarus game is going to add anything.
Speaker 1: It's just going to be visual style.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's it.
Speaker 1: The thing is it'll be hard to save the right.
Speaker 0: Here's the thing though, right?
Speaker 0: You can adjust the amount of 3D-ness, right?
Speaker 0: So could I play that game on a regular DS or a DSI?
Speaker 0: Or will a game only work on the 3DS?
Speaker 0: They haven't explained any of that.
Speaker 1: It's going to be a Gameboy Color situation.
Speaker 0: It will be a Gameboy Color situation.
Speaker 0: The thing is the graphics on it Regardless of whether they're 3D or not are vastly like PSP qualities, you know.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: So that I really don't think that 3DS games are gonna run on non 3DS.
Speaker 1: The thing is until they have a killer app game for it and also now that I don't have a commute I don't need the portable system right away.
Speaker 0: That is something that's actually right.
Speaker 0: It's like all about.
Speaker 0: You know determining which games are good or bad is really a lot more about your lifestyle, right?
Speaker 0: When I was on the train DS games were the shit but like a Phoenix ride or something like that.
Speaker 1: I had my DS with me every day.
Speaker 0: Nowadays I'm riding the bike.
Speaker 0: I can't even put headphones in Basically deleted like all the twit network podcast because I have no time to listen to them because I'm not honest even on a subway.
Speaker 0: Anymore, you know, yeah on the subway probably in the winter I might go back and get some more podcasts again.
Speaker 0: But now that I'm biking this I'm listening to like only a couple short Podcasts and they pile up quite a bit before I actually listen to them.
Speaker 0: So DS games are pretty much, you know relegated to like bedtime and they're competing with books and comic books Which is you know, whenever there's a competition for like that.
Speaker 0: It's not gonna work out too.
Speaker 0: Well, yep.
Speaker 1: We'll see I got.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna wait too because Nintendo has a history of making a slightly better version.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the other thing is I you know, I have so many Unplayed video games.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna be really slow to buy any more until I finish the ones I got.
Speaker 0: I'm like really, you know reeling back.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm having this anything Anything that does not have immediate multiplayer needs like NS2.
Speaker 0: I'm like waiting forever.
Speaker 0: It'll be five bucks on Steam eventually.
Speaker 1: media lately Like I don't because the thing it was weird is now that we live in the city We have a lot more free time.
Speaker 1: Like I consume way more media than I was before.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and yet Media is piling up like in the last two months faster than has ever piled up in my life.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So I think it's a very recent.
Speaker 0: this isn't even like counting anything that is illegally obtained.
Speaker 0: This is only like.
Speaker 0: This is like free streaming animes on the internets that are legal, you know comic books that I paid for video games I paid for Piling up books I've paid for.
Speaker 0: I think about that.
Speaker 0: like a book is like is the worst.
Speaker 0: because you buy a book It's like six bucks and it's gonna take you a good week of like reading before bed to finish a book.
Speaker 0: I don't know and I can get that that offsets a lot of other medias.
Speaker 1: I We should at least mention a couple other things.
Speaker 1: a Donkey Kong coming back.
Speaker 0: It's Donkey Kong.
Speaker 0: They had a lot of platformers and the one I'm I'm thinking about is the Kirby one that looks I like Kirby's a man.
Speaker 1: Donkey Kong is.
Speaker 1: when Donkey Kong Country first came out like way back in the day I never really liked those games that like it either.
Speaker 1: I remember like everyone I knew lost their shit about that game.
Speaker 1: So I was like, alright and I rented it cuz I didn't buy games unless they were good.
Speaker 0: It was alright, but it was not a huge fan.
Speaker 1: It was like an okay platformer with good graphics.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like it didn't blow me away.
Speaker 1: I didn't.
Speaker 1: I never to this day understood why so many people liked Donkey Kong.
Speaker 0: 64 was actually alright.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was People.
Speaker 1: people are talking about epic Mickey, but there's nothing else like new about that.
Speaker 0: I think Mickey has some good styling But it seems like it seems to me based on what I've seen that it's sort of like Gonna be some Okami action with the painting and unpainting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of manual labor.
Speaker 0: and it also seems to me like member Mario Sunshine where it has like cool parts.
Speaker 0: But the whole game isn't cool parts, right?
Speaker 0: Like they showed a part where is all side-scrolling steamboat Willie.
Speaker 0: But the whole thing isn't clever like that.
Speaker 0: Most of it is not that.
Speaker 0: well someone you know, they these people they're so creative They come up with like a clever part in a game like in Mario Sunshine.
Speaker 0: There was the old-school clever part That should have been the game.
Speaker 0: that shit.
Speaker 0: just make that the whole goddamn game clever shit.
Speaker 0: get rid of the other stuff.
Speaker 0: Make it only the clever part and if you come up with just clever part after clever part pile them on top of each Other one after the other and make that the whole game.
Speaker 0: don't put anything else in there.
Speaker 0: I actually think the sonic people have you seen this sonic colors thing?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think they figured it out after their stupid sonic werewolf shit and it seems like they're making a game Half the good part of the sonic werewolf game and half Actual 2d sonic.
Speaker 0: they replaced the werewolf with old-school, you know And I think that might actually be something.
Speaker 0: let's keep an eyeball on if you
Speaker 1: have a game that has a glue area Because I think the glue area like once it rose to or like the center area like in Mario Galaxy Like always go back to the home planet or go back to the fucking time palace, whatever.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: anytime you've got something like that like some kind of meta construct over your game.
Speaker 1: Your game had better be damn good and that part had better be engaging or 99% of players are just pissed off every time they're there trying to get to the game again.
Speaker 0: Yeah Pretty much.
Speaker 1: and last but not least.
Speaker 1: What do we always say?
Speaker 1: Why don't they just make a golden eye again and they're making a golden eye again?
Speaker 0: I don't.
Speaker 1: I never said that I we said it on the show a bunch of times.
Speaker 0: I think that this pretty much this game is not looking too little too late.
Speaker 0: I don't think this is ten years ago.
Speaker 0: I don't think this is looking very promising.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's gonna be a console FPS, which is already bad.
Speaker 0: It's You know, is it gonna be able to compete with the other?
Speaker 0: Well, but I don't think it's depending completely on the license property.
Speaker 1: No, it is also depending on nostalgia for the other golden eye game.
Speaker 1: yeah, here is how it could be a good game if they made it really really simple and They made it pretty much.
Speaker 1: I think I have a single player with original golden.
Speaker 1: I was real simple exactly if they made it just an updated version of the original golden I were.
Speaker 1: the primary purpose of the game is to have four player or more straight-up direct deathmatch.
Speaker 0: but why would you get that when you could get like halos instead?
Speaker 1: I Feel like this could be a more.
Speaker 0: it's like a low is pretty much the you know, replaced golden eye a long time ago.
Speaker 1: yeah, but if you made this like a cross between that style of game and more like Counter-strike because remember golden I was much more about ambushing someone and not so much about Halo.
Speaker 0: golden.
Speaker 0: I are pretty much the same thing except for the the the you know, the actual theme.
Speaker 1: No, I actually disagree.
Speaker 1: Do you remember playing golden?
Speaker 1: I it was pretty much strafe and then hit him with the moonraker laser.
Speaker 0: No, it was more like RCP 90.
Speaker 1: hold it down now and you had the thing aimed at head level always And odd job played you quit.
Speaker 0: I Never liked it as a kid because I had quake We I played gold nye, you know friends houses and it was.
Speaker 0: it was you know a thing of its day.
Speaker 0: It wasn't something that was you know, it wasn't timeless.
Speaker 0: It's not something you can go back to now.
Speaker 1: It was only good when I could played it back with something that was good in the moment.
Speaker 1: at the time I'm in the situation never land, but we can have an n64 in a TV and golden eye.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you play deathmatch late into the night.
Speaker 0: exactly you go to a friend's house.
Speaker 0: You'd be like oh shit We don't have four computers.
Speaker 0: It's not like.
Speaker 0: you know, a computer was holy shit and a lot of people's computers couldn't.
Speaker 0: he didn't even have 3d yet But you could have four controllers in it, you know thing so is much more accessible, but now right you have steam.
Speaker 0: So what the hell?
Speaker 0: and you have Xbox Live?
Speaker 0: So who wants golden eye?
Speaker 0: nobody?
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day since golden eye is back supposedly.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess not supposedly.
Speaker 1: now it's for real.
Speaker 1: I don't know if anyone saw.
Speaker 1: this is an old College Humor thing But I think Kotaku linked to it either because they were reminded or something, but college humor did a pretty good Take on golden.
Speaker 1: I actually enjoy this quite a bit.
Speaker 1: That's it I don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't want to spoil it Just watch it.
Speaker 1: and if you've never played golden eye for the n64, this really isn't funny.
Speaker 0: Okay, so basically here's this is a pretty cool thing here.
Speaker 0: the they had a it was called the Hayabusa Spacecraft.
Speaker 0: right and it went like a bajillion miles out into space to like a comet and It got a sample and then it came back to earth, which is pretty ridiculous Billion miles.
Speaker 0: Oh, it went to an asteroid named Itokawa.
Speaker 0: So this thing the Japanese set a rocket anyone and it went out into space 1.25 billion miles.
Speaker 0: Right, I guess that's you know, the total distance round trip.
Speaker 0: So it must have been point seven five billion miles away was out for a little over seven years.
Speaker 0: Yeah, seven years of going through space crazy fast.
Speaker 0: it got this asteroid and it you know nibbled off a piece.
Speaker 0: it came back to earth and You know, basically it came back into the earth.
Speaker 0: It was coming and then of course, you know, there's the re-entry situation.
Speaker 0: So it had basically it had the sample capsule with the sample in it and that piece has to land safely.
Speaker 0: But all the other parts we have to like throw them off and get them disintegrated in the air so that you know The sample is safe.
Speaker 1: It had actually a lander that was gonna do something to it.
Speaker 1: Apparently that missed.
Speaker 0: Anyway, well, you know take what you can get right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's better than exploding on the launchpad or anything.
Speaker 0: So here's a video of the re-entry and usually space videos.
Speaker 0: Like, you know the fact of what you're seeing is usually really cool But the visual of what you're seeing is usually not so cool.
Speaker 0: Usually the video will be like a dot that moves.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right or you're watching something actually taking off.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean rockets are always cool because this big fire coming out.
Speaker 0: but like, you know You watch like a star and it's like a star gets bright and then it disappears or something like that.
Speaker 0: or like you see a Dot moving across the sky and there's not usually a lot of visual excitement.
Speaker 0: or maybe they'll have to like apply false Digital coloring to something to make it exciting because it's a bunch of x-rays or some shit like that.
Speaker 0: this is actually just straight-up video and it's actually crazy cool the way the The re-entry stuff that's you know, the parts that are not the capsule are disintegrating in the air.
Speaker 0: It looks like some crazy awesome fireworks Yep, and of course the capsule.
Speaker 1: according to the news here quote the capsule was successfully retrieved at 708 UTC yesterday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was in the Australian outback and I guess the Australians let the Japanese take it.
Speaker 0: They didn't like.
Speaker 0: we have.
Speaker 1: You can have it back now.
Speaker 0: We will learn the secret of get a raise in the secret of whatever that asteroid is made of which is probably I'm willing to bet rocks.
Speaker 0: What do you bet?
Speaker 0: Ice you bet anything is made of ice and rock.
Speaker 0: ice, you know, and ice is just a rock, right?
Speaker 0: You know, it's just a water rock.
Speaker 1: Not really how not?
Speaker 1: it's a crystal not a rock.
Speaker 0: They're very different rocks are I mean, so a geode is not a rock You dude.
Speaker 1: No, it's commerce.
Speaker 1: they're made of ice.
Speaker 0: course is not a rock.
Speaker 1: Honestly one thing this brings up I just want to mention it, you know There's all this talk about the space program and what we should do.
Speaker 1: should we go to Mars the moon and a lot of people are complaining that we're kind of backing off of manned space exploration lately.
Speaker 1: and as a nerd and a geek unlike many other nerds and geeks I Pretty much say straight up.
Speaker 0: There's no point in manned space exploration at least for the next 20 or 30 years Unless we develop something such as hibernation or something, you know to make it more practical.
Speaker 0: Because really as soon as you add one person to a spacecraft Right, just the math of it really ruins everything.
Speaker 0: It's like well now we need to bring a life support system and a bag of ice and all this other and I gotta buy Four DS's and then I gotta get four friends to play the DS's with me, right?
Speaker 0: As soon as you add even one person you add all this stuff to the rocket, right and it makes everything incredibly less efficient.
Speaker 0: Whereas, you know, what's the person doing up in space?
Speaker 0: some experiments?
Speaker 0: We can just automate the experiment and it'll be so much cheaper just to go put a rocket up there.
Speaker 0: It does the experiment it comes back done.
Speaker 1: Well, plus look at the civilization for example, you know You can start researching like iron working like right.
Speaker 1: when you get it right away It's gonna take you like 20 years.
Speaker 1: in the meantime someone with some other civilization just busts out with all these little improvements and suddenly they've got X-men and all this other stuff and you're still working on the stupid iron working to build one.
Speaker 0: Me and Scott Jones are actually playing sit for co-op yesterday, right?
Speaker 0: And apparently the way that works is let's say I'm working on alphabet and you're working on horseback riding.
Speaker 0: I'm just picking two things, right?
Speaker 0: well I develop it in my in the amount of time it takes and you develop yours in the amount of time it takes and Then you know when I'm done you get what I got and when you're done I get what you got.
Speaker 0: We share all our technology automatically because it's co-op, right?
Speaker 0: So it's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: The thing is we're much better off both Researching the same thing at the same time, which means that it takes half the time as it would usually take because we're both Contributing our beakers simultaneously.
Speaker 0: Now.
Speaker 0: Why is that better, right?
Speaker 0: You think well you can get two technologies in the same amount of time that you could have gotten, right?
Speaker 0: You're getting the same amount of technologies per unit time, right?
Speaker 0: It takes you twice as long but you get two or it takes you half as long and you get one.
Speaker 0: The thing is if you do the if you both research at the same time Then you get one in half the time and then you can use that one during the second half of the time Whereas if you get two in the longer unit of time, you can't.
Speaker 0: you basically are stuck at your current state the entire duration.
Speaker 0: So you're basically putting off the bonuses and it's not.
Speaker 1: so yeah take the analogy real life.
Speaker 1: That's my feelings on the space program at least for now.
Speaker 1: So really quick met a moment.
Speaker 1: I'm in a moment the book book club.
Speaker 1: We're actually gonna do it on Thursday Thursday unless one of us dies or something get just buy a truck.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mr.
Speaker 0: Rim who had who bailed on when we were gonna do it last Thursday.
Speaker 1: I was sick.
Speaker 0: No, you weren't.
Speaker 0: you went did some work shit.
Speaker 1: No, I skipped something else for work shit.
Speaker 1: I think Thursday night, we also skipped a Wednesday.
Speaker 1: Remember?
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: No, we didn't skip a Wednesday.
Speaker 0: We did the pokemons show on Wednesday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we the previous Wednesday we were supposed to do it and we skipped it.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: the previous Thursday we and you skipped it for work.
Speaker 1: I skipped a Wednesday and a Thursday one because I was sick and one because of work that I remember skipping away.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the work thing was getting drunk and having an awesome time.
Speaker 0: But yeah, you're supposed to be doing podcast.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, any other meta thing?
Speaker 0: We're gonna.
Speaker 0: net icon is in a book.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah kinetic on July 9th, 10th 11th gonna be super awesome.
Speaker 0: anything else.
Speaker 1: Pack stuff will say very soon.
Speaker 1: We'll probably be able to announce our packs.
Speaker 1: panels.
Speaker 0: Okay, nerd NYC recess.
Speaker 1: Yes, you should go to that.
Speaker 1: It is basically a one-day gaming con.
Speaker 0: It's on June 19th in Manhattan.
Speaker 1: Go to nerd NYC comm which is this weekend.
Speaker 1: Oh, fuck me.
Speaker 0: I Needed this.
Speaker 0: I needed this weekend to like hey do that panel and also prepare some burning wheels.
Speaker 1: Alright, you know what though?
Speaker 1: It's only one day.
Speaker 0: it is I'll have to do all that on Sunday.
Speaker 0: I'm also.
Speaker 0: I'm also going to dentist on Friday so I could do it the second rest of the day on Friday I'm gonna spend the dentist the doctor you like going on the the Scott machine is wearing down.
Speaker 0: Well, I actually you know, I haven't been in the dentist in too long.
Speaker 0: I kept like, you know how many years like I've had a to-do list and I've keep putting items on and clearing them For the past four months.
Speaker 1: my phone every day has a reminder in the notification bar.
Speaker 1: If I click on that it says dentist and you're right.
Speaker 0: So today I actually did it.
Speaker 0: I went to the insurance company's website.
Speaker 0: I click find doctor.
Speaker 0: I called him up.
Speaker 0: I click find dentist.
Speaker 0: I called him up and apparently the dentist I'm going to was my mom's dentist when she lived in Queens and she was Very.
Speaker 0: we're gonna find out like this old Dennis, dude He's probably gonna be all cool with me because like he's a friend of the family in the olden days.
Speaker 0: Be cool.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think we have anything else on that front.
Speaker 1: Still working on video got a lot of stuff in the hopper.
Speaker 1: We're playing a lot of games with you guys lately like in the forum.
Speaker 1: So if you're looking for games to play like on weekends and weeknights just keep poking in the forum or make sure you join the FRC or they're the geek night steam groups because There's been a lot going on a lot of good counter-strike.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I haven't really been playing too much cat.
Speaker 0: I play counters like once but I've planted some more since I've actually been playing sieve for and sucking ass.
Speaker 0: but I've actually you know put a little bit of effort into learning to suck less ass.
Speaker 0: and Mostly it's just because I want to play Civ 5 and I'm pretty sure like Civ 4 is definitely flawed for me.
Speaker 1: But the skills will transfer.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes.
Speaker 0: I hope that these the lessons I learn will transfer At least if not the military stuff things like have an economy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, I pretty much figured out like, you know what a lot of this problem is is that you know, there's just so Many things that have you know effects and you can't really then they're not all out in front of you simultaneously So it's hard to keep track of all of them.
Speaker 0: You know like this gives me plus on that and this gives me percentage Minus on that and this then how you can't keep them all in your brain at once.
Speaker 0: So you really just need to like, you know Look at what your problem area is and then be able to find something to fix that problem And then that causes another problem then, you know fix that one and balance them all out.
Speaker 0: that way If you try to actually keep the whole game in your brain at once, you're just gonna fail.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's possible.
Speaker 1: Uh, I don't know I play.
Speaker 0: you're gonna keep the effects of every single technology.
Speaker 0: you have every single improvement.
Speaker 0: You have every single position of every single population point, you know working on a spot that you know Every single military unit you've got in their health.
Speaker 1: The only thing I don't keep immediate track of in all my cities is where stuff's allocated in terms Like what resources is working, you know, and then you could like you could turn a guy into a scientist.
Speaker 0: You can do so many possible things to keep track of your tax levels your your civics your religions.
Speaker 0: You're.
Speaker 1: yeah, I keep track of all that.
Speaker 1: Like I said, the only thing I don't keep track of is if I have a stack of units I consider it an army and I don't worry about the individuals within it and I don't keep track of what is working what around a city.
Speaker 1: instead?
Speaker 1: I'll use the buttons that say things like optimize for population growth or optimize for shields Yeah, and everything where those.
Speaker 0: where are those buttons?
Speaker 0: you open up the big city screen right right and down bottom, right?
Speaker 0: This is little tiny buttons in a cluster.
Speaker 0: There's a whole bunch of.
Speaker 0: it's a lot of.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of shit going on a whole lot anyway, so today we're gonna talk about bidding game.
Speaker 1: Yes, they games that have bidding mechanics, you know, we're talking about nerd NYC and the recess is awesome.
Speaker 1: But as are the monthly gaming nights that we're at pretty much every one of them They're on Fridays at this awesome like think wine bar coffee house.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's think coffee, but it has non coffee.
Speaker 0: It's basically a bidding game is a game that involves bidding, you know Like you auction stuff off and there are plenty of games that have bidding mechanics.
Speaker 0: even monopoly has auctions technically then even though no one uses them and we've talked about games on the show before like power grid and Almond Ray that have bidding parts, you know, like in power grid you bid for the power plants and then you play power grid You know, but you don't bid for anything else.
Speaker 0: But there are games out there right that are pretty much just bidding or almost all bidding and that's it.
Speaker 0: All you do is bid on things.
Speaker 0: That's the whole game Especially like the.
Speaker 0: there's the famous Rainer kinesia auction trilogy of modern art Medici and raw.
Speaker 0: we've talked about raw Which is mostly kind of bidding sorta.
Speaker 0: It's the bidding slot machine.
Speaker 1: Yep Well, it's weird because this this night, you know playing these weird bidding games Which we played kind of randomly because we need stuff to do after we played a whole bunch of Dominion.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm There should be some bidding cards in Dominion like a bidding thing like oh man suddenly there's no the province bid Some sort of thing.
Speaker 1: or you know, you play this card now, there's an auction for a province, but you might not get it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, everyone uses the money, you know, whoever has the most money in their hand right now gets province.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I don't know about that.
Speaker 1: Maybe we just add money Real money.
Speaker 0: Yeah Whoever gives the all you have to whoever, you know, everyone bid real money The amount you bid.
Speaker 0: you must give that amount to each every other player.
Speaker 0: So if I bid a dollar I have to give one dollar to each other player.
Speaker 0: whoever bids the most gets a province.
Speaker 1: But it was weird because we played these like fun bidding games because they were quick But as a result of playing them I remembered old games that we completely forgot about like Pizarro and Wherever.
Speaker 1: I haven't forgotten a bidding game, but we played it at the same time.
Speaker 1: We played Pizarro.
Speaker 0: Yeah, web of power is not a bidding game.
Speaker 0: It's a good game.
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 1: I liked it.
Speaker 1: you hated it, but you were undefeated at it.
Speaker 0: Yeah the.
Speaker 0: So let's just talk about the games we played to get that of the way.
Speaker 0: So the one we played is for sale, which is a really, you know, it was simple and kind of fun But I don't know how long it would last in terms of replay value.
Speaker 1: however I think I'm gonna buy it because it's a great game to whip out With some noobs or to whip out like where you're waiting in line somewhere cuz you can play it quick.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have a lot of pieces or whip out like at a convention if you're teaching people stuff.
Speaker 0: So basically the way for sale works is pretty much just bidding but it's two stages, right?
Speaker 0: So everyone starts with some money and you use the money to buy property and the.
Speaker 0: all the properties are auctioned off and then you use the properties to bid for Checks for money.
Speaker 0: So you basically buy properties with your starting money and then you sell the properties for other money And then you add your leftover starting money that you didn't use to buy properties to your ending money and you win.
Speaker 0: So it's like you auction and then you auction what you auctioned and you know.
Speaker 0: What you bought in the first auction becomes your.
Speaker 0: you know What you use to buy stuff in the second option.
Speaker 1: You can't just make a straight direct bidding game because bizarro as I recall was pretty much that you just you all bid.
Speaker 1: Then you all bid again.
Speaker 1: They carry victory points.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so, how do you win bizarro?
Speaker 0: You just bid on the best possible thing basically every time.
Speaker 1: cuz I was undefeated at that game I just bought Magellan every time and he got me so many points.
Speaker 1: I always won and no one really beat me in the bidding.
Speaker 1: It was stupid.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, I guess it's because you know, if anyone bid more than that, right then they would have had Magellan sure But they also would have lost because they bid too much.
Speaker 1: I think it was more than a lot of the people we were playing with were not that great.
Speaker 1: at board games I noticed that we tended to dominate back then.
Speaker 1: We don't dominate as much among ourselves in the crew as we did against those people.
Speaker 0: No, not at all, but I did.
Speaker 0: I believe I won a Dominion pretty bad pretty strongly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I won the first round of this game.
Speaker 1: But here's the trick for sales.
Speaker 1: really fun.
Speaker 1: Like I'd recommend it.
Speaker 1: It's cheap.
Speaker 1: I'm sure it's got to be cheap.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't buy it if it wasn't cheap.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would pay 20 bucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah most.
Speaker 1: but the cool thing about it is that it's not like it's a bidding game technically But really it's a game of chicken.
Speaker 1: Yeah Because the way this is the cool mechanic is that the second half is just a blind Simultaneous bid with the stuff that you bid on at the first half.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, but the first half.
Speaker 1: so I start the bidding.
Speaker 1: So there's you know a property out there to my or a check, you know a property.
Speaker 1: I might have some value between you know, one and thirty I think.
Speaker 1: So I have you know, say fifteen money.
Speaker 1: I can bid one or two or three or whatever.
Speaker 1: The next person has to either Beat the bid that I put out or pass.
Speaker 0: now if you pass you're out of the bidding Completely and you take those you take the shittiest property that is still available.
Speaker 1: So you take the crappiest property.
Speaker 1: if you had already bid something you pay half of what you would bid and keep right.
Speaker 0: So for example, let's pretend it's two-player right.
Speaker 0: pretend It's three-player a B Scott rim and Emily right.
Speaker 0: and there's three properties.
Speaker 0: Their value is one five and ten.
Speaker 0: I bid 1,000. rim rim bids 2,000.
Speaker 0: Emily says she's out so she gets the number one for free.
Speaker 0: Rim bid - I'm gonna up bid rim.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go for three or I did five Thousand.
Speaker 0: he bids five.
Speaker 0: I'm out.
Speaker 1: All right, I pay two thousand and I take the second low.
Speaker 0: No, no, I'm out.
Speaker 0: So I okay.
Speaker 0: Yes, I'm out.
Speaker 0: So I pay half of what I bid.
Speaker 0: so I bid three.
Speaker 0: remember so half of three rounded down is what one Right, so I pay one and I take the second lowest But then I am forced to take the highest one and pay my full bid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so he pays five.
Speaker 0: so I got.
Speaker 0: you know He pays everything.
Speaker 0: the winner has to pay every single thing that they've bid But the losers only have to pay half of what they have bid.
Speaker 0: So you're actually the way to win is to basically get really good Properties by only paying half and forcing someone else to pay the full amount for whatever.
Speaker 0: that way They don't have enough money to buy more good stuff and that's pretty much what it comes down to.
Speaker 1: so it's really chicken.
Speaker 1: more so than bidding.
Speaker 1: the second half is really bidding, but if you play games like Euchre or Bridge or anything like that if you can count cards and keep track of like who bid on what how much money they have Then you can basically play the game.
Speaker 0: perfect and how much money people have is just open, you know.
Speaker 0: And now you can memorize what properties everyone got.
Speaker 0: so and that's for sale.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much It's just two rounds of bidding one and then two and then that's it.
Speaker 1: It's a fun game You know, we whipped it out We played it a couple times and then after we played Dominion we were looking for something to do and we decided with the same guy to play Claws tubers hoity-toity.
Speaker 0: now hoity-toity was like a game I had heard of.
Speaker 0: it's pretty famous.
Speaker 0: All right, don't?
Speaker 1: often we got to talk more about the people like the design when this field is jar in 1990.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because we do that with the anime and we don't do it as much with the board games.
Speaker 1: I think it's just as important claws.
Speaker 1: tuber also made settlers of Catan.
Speaker 0: I think it's Klaus toy burr.
Speaker 1: I'm saying tuber.
Speaker 0: Okay Yeah, he knows he made hoity-toity before he made settlers.
Speaker 0: It's one.
Speaker 0: this field is yar.
Speaker 0: It was a very popular game.
Speaker 1: Hoity-toity is a game where the rich people decide what to do with that money and show off the things to other rich people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's basically a racing game.
Speaker 0: You're trying to race around this track to get to the victory area where you win and You you're basically.
Speaker 0: you're buying these different, uh, you know Antiques and then you buy antiques and then you exhibit them in castles and then you basically move forward by exhibiting Your collections of antiques.
Speaker 0: and but you have to buy them and you have to steal them from other people.
Speaker 0: You have to steal people's money and there's a whole thing going.
Speaker 1: it's tough.
Speaker 1: You basically play paper rock scissors and then you play paper rock scissors again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's sort of a Bracket of rock paper scissors, right?
Speaker 0: So basically every turn there's a there's a round of rock paper scissors.
Speaker 0: But it's not rock paper scissors.
Speaker 0: It's a sort of rock paper auction house or castle.
Speaker 0: So everyone picks auction house or castle.
Speaker 0: okay, then the people who did auction house they either pick bid money or thief.
Speaker 0: and Then so all those people do that and then all the people pick castle pick either Exhibit thief detective exhibit thief detectives.
Speaker 0: There's a rock paper scissors going on over there and then you just keep doing this.
Speaker 0: You know tree of rock paper scissors is over and over again until someone wins.
Speaker 1: Now, I don't think it's worth explaining the details of it.
Speaker 1: I mean now it's a fun game.
Speaker 1: I would actually say it's another game that if you're like really into board games, you'd probably want to keep it around.
Speaker 1: It's a good game to play with like newbies or play at once teach people about bidding and stuff But doesn't have a lot of staying power.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think it has much staying power at all.
Speaker 0: The big problem I had with the game is that having a big momentum in the game is really powerful.
Speaker 0: You know if you get a whole bunch of the antiques then pretty much no one can stop you.
Speaker 1: Well at the same time if you have all the antiques the only and you're already ahead The only way to win is to exhibit.
Speaker 1: at the end.
Speaker 1: You have to exhibit someone.
Speaker 1: everyone's basically gonna thief.
Speaker 1: you Steal all your stuff and now you don't have a big hand to win the end game at the end and then It's not a completely simple game.
Speaker 1: It's still solvable, but it's not like dead.
Speaker 0: So yeah the other big problem is is that okay you have a basically this branch of two and then one branch goes to two more and The other branch goes to three.
Speaker 0: but a lot of times you look at someone's situation where they are on the board Right what they have in their hand and most of those choices are ruled out.
Speaker 0: if you have a whole bunch of antiques There's pretty much no reason to go to the auction house.
Speaker 0: You're gonna go to the castle.
Speaker 0: and if you go to the castle and you're in the way behind You're best off being the detective or the thief.
Speaker 0: and if you're way ahead There's almost no reason to be the detective, but there's also no reason to be the theme.
Speaker 1: There's no reason to be the exhibitor.
Speaker 1: That's where.
Speaker 1: that's where the game is.
Speaker 0: yeah So it's pretty obvious what someone's gonna do.
Speaker 0: because okay?
Speaker 0: You can do that and you're gonna get screwed.
Speaker 0: you can do that, but it's gonna be useless to you.
Speaker 0: You're only gonna.
Speaker 0: You know you're the you're in first place.
Speaker 1: you pick the detective congratulations You move one forward one space big deal Which means really the only way to win is to play smartly to a degree, but every time decisions are remotely arbitrary or Anytime other players might try to second-guess you.
Speaker 1: you just need to openly and randomly decide what you're gonna Do.
Speaker 0: I think playing randomly is a choice.
Speaker 0: the problem is if you play randomly you're gonna end up picking Combinations that do nothing for you.
Speaker 0: You're like you'll pick.
Speaker 1: if you just don't play you don't you?
Speaker 1: basically you do randomly in terms Of all right.
Speaker 1: am I going to exhibit or thief like you narrow it down to like the two options?
Speaker 1: that would both be Reasonable decisions, and then you go randomly.
Speaker 1: yeah, but then the game is as the same problem.
Speaker 1: It's just who put the poison in the cup and there's no way to answer that question.
Speaker 0: my biggest problem in the game was I Started off pretty strong But then I had like you know four useless turns in a row because I tried to do the only useful thing I could do And I didn't win when I went to bid in the auction house.
Speaker 0: And then so I exhibited which is the right and then I couldn't possibly win at exhibiting because I had less.
Speaker 0: you know I had less proper antiques than everyone else.
Speaker 0: so I Uselessly exhibited and I was thiefed even though my exhibiting was useless and that I didn't have enough.
Speaker 0: so exhibiting was not even an option anymore.
Speaker 0: and because exhibiting wasn't an option I Couldn't get any more properties.
Speaker 1: One thing I do like those that this game has a lot of mechanics where you know there's a game or someone I was like well What do you do if you run out of cards?
Speaker 1: then the answer is always like oh you reshuffle.
Speaker 1: the answer to every question like That in hoity-toity is fuck you.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: What do you do if you don't?
Speaker 1: if no one has any more money?
Speaker 1: You're fucked no one has any more money, and that's the end of it.
Speaker 0: play the rest of the game jerks Yeah, and the other thing is that like if you do a thief and they get detective you still get to steal something But the thief goes away temporarily.
Speaker 0: So my thieves I died because thieving was the best option I had.
Speaker 0: I did it and I did it again and I successfully thieved twice and then I didn't have any thieves.
Speaker 0: so a whole option was removed from me and But that was still the best option for me to do.
Speaker 0: because I didn't have that many properties I was doing really well like that when we played.
Speaker 1: I had a runaway game for the beginning.
Speaker 0: me, too.
Speaker 0: I was running away.
Speaker 0: I was in first place like the whole beginning and then before I had the four useless turn And then
Speaker 1: I was in first place all after that until the fateful moment where I had to choose randomly because I do arbitrary options And everyone else chose the thief and stole my entire collection, and then I had no recourse.
Speaker 1: the rest of the game Yeah, I just detective ever round because there's nothing else I could do.
Speaker 0: yeah I think part of I think a good strategy might just be to hang back.
Speaker 0: just play casually Don't try to do anything strong, and then just come on strong in the end with exhibiting and such.
Speaker 0: Don't go forward early because you're just gonna ruin the rest of you if you.
Speaker 0: if you fail early You just know way to come back, but if you fail at the end You'll still be ahead, and you can get somewhere, but in general.
Speaker 1: I like bidding as a mechanic in games I always have.
Speaker 1: I love like dunes bidding for combat the blind bid with the troops.
Speaker 1: I love that shit.
Speaker 1: hmm or like I'm on ray You know it is a game, and there's all this other stuff.
Speaker 1: But if you're smart and you understand I'm on ray And you I'm.
Speaker 1: you've like you played the.
Speaker 0: so how much do you give to the gods?
Speaker 1: it pretty much?
Speaker 1: Just is really a bidding game.
Speaker 0: sacrifice to your god.
Speaker 1: Oh my god I want to play some.
Speaker 1: I'm on ray something fierce good game.
Speaker 1: love that game a good game.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think the thing with bidding games is that makes them so fun is That it's not in a lot of games.
Speaker 0: even look at something as great as Puerto Rico right.
Speaker 0: It's your turn.
Speaker 0: Let's say you're playing freaking you know.
Speaker 0: For five player Puerto Rico you've got all all possible choices of jobs out there.
Speaker 0: on the right You've got.
Speaker 0: it's like an eight-way choice.
Speaker 0: That's pretty good.
Speaker 0: But in a bidding game you've actually usually got like this whole range of choices right.
Speaker 0: like I could bid one Two three four dollars.
Speaker 0: now sometimes some games.
Speaker 0: that stupid it is.
Speaker 0: But you it's about the.
Speaker 1: I guess it adds a lot of psychology.
Speaker 1: like you have all these options and everyone else has these options And everyone's kind of playing simultaneously with this very like direct competition.
Speaker 1: like where was the guy with Maaz?
Speaker 1: Who you'd always mess with?
Speaker 1: I'll be the guy in a bidding game I'll bid two three Thanks Hey nine fine just take it.
Speaker 1: fuck all right I Love that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know and it actually you know it makes something that's pretty hard to think about right you have to actually Do.
Speaker 0: it's not just a choice between like well a and B It's actually a difficult decision like how many dollars is that worth to me?
Speaker 0: You know these dollars.
Speaker 0: I could get X victory points with them if I use this home But I could get X victory points if I use it.
Speaker 1: how many dollar victory points is it worth to my opponent?
Speaker 1: I might want to bid very high and harm myself to prevent the second-place player from getting something that could make them win the game.
Speaker 1: Yep, there's so much calculus going on that I guess I feel like the games that I've liked the most are the ones that have Very intense maths that I have to just like crunch through in real time.
Speaker 1: Not like games where I can plan my whole turn and then like I know what to do But like in a bidding game where I have to plan everything in real time like while the bidding is going on Like Scott throws me for a loop, and he bids 10 on something I didn't expect.
Speaker 1: I've got to like shift my entire calculus now and make a new determination like right then and there it like.
Speaker 1: It feels like a worthwhile use of the brain Like you feel the gears churning, and I don't get that with a lot of games.
Speaker 1: I play.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean you look at power grid right.
Speaker 0: you can bid any number of your dollars on a new power plant.
Speaker 1: I'll be like if you bid one too many dollars on a power plant that'll cost you the game.
Speaker 0: And it's like how do you figure out how many dollars it's worth right?
Speaker 0: It's like well Yes, okay, so that is the fusion power plant right there as a minimum bid of what 50 right?
Speaker 0: I think so if you can get it for 50 that's sort of duh right cuz then that's gonna win you the game.
Speaker 1: But if you get 63 all right did that deny you building the last property that you'll be able to power to win the game?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 0: should I you know the guy bid 65 on it, okay?
Speaker 0: Well obviously it's an awesome power plant I want.
Speaker 0: it would help me a bunch of put me to the front of the rock making me move last if I pay $67 for it or $70 for it.
Speaker 0: well those three dollars Make it you know be such a hurt to me that it's no longer worth it to have that awesome power plant You know.
Speaker 0: and then maybe though I don't actually want the power plant.
Speaker 0: so but I do want.
Speaker 0: I know that if he gets it for the current bid of 55 That's too good for him.
Speaker 0: He'll win, but then I need to make.
Speaker 0: I need to make him bid higher.
Speaker 0: But if I bid 60 will he actually bid 61 or will he realize that me paying?
Speaker 0: 60 will fuck me or mine.
Speaker 1: him paying 61 will fuck him and my bidding on a power plant I don't want because I want another power plant, but I didn't get to start the bidding.
Speaker 0: But if I pass I'm out forever, and I won't be able to buy any power plants.
Speaker 0: Yeah You know there's a lot a lot of clever decisions to make when there is an auction situation.
Speaker 1: It's also just the directness of it.
Speaker 1: I love direct competition in games.
Speaker 1: I mean I had this whole stint I think we both did where we really played a lot of indirect competition games.
Speaker 1: But I come back to really enjoying games or I can be like Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm destroying your troops I mean if you think about like an auction in real life right you go to you know.
Speaker 0: So you go to that kind of auction and the guys get a cow right and you're like I need a cow.
Speaker 0: And you say well, it's really easy to figure out whether you should bid for the cow.
Speaker 0: right it's like I've X dollars.
Speaker 0: the cow will make me X dollars in milk and meat and whatever.
Speaker 0: So I should pay.
Speaker 0: you know it'll.
Speaker 0: you know I'll have this much cost in cow food and barn Whatever's.
Speaker 0: so therefore that cow is this good a cow.
Speaker 0: It's worth X dollars to me.
Speaker 0: So you bid that X dollars.
Speaker 0: you try?
Speaker 0: You know you bid you know what you slowly bid up until you reach that limit of what you're willing to pay.
Speaker 0: And if it goes above that you stop and that you let someone else take the cow.
Speaker 0: and it's real It's real simple, but imagine it if you you add just a little bit of rules to that like okay Here's three cows.
Speaker 0: you can get one of them.
Speaker 0: You can't have all three right and suddenly It's real tough right?
Speaker 0: it's not as simple calculation as you know.
Speaker 0: how much money do I have?
Speaker 0: how much is it worth?
Speaker 0: Kind of thing it's oh shit, which one do I want?
Speaker 0: I want I need to get the most cow for the least money, and I can all in disease restrictions.
Speaker 0: What do I do?
Speaker 1: Oh no, but if I get the cow now?
Speaker 1: I can't afford the cow bell yep.
Speaker 1: So I'll leave you all with some parting advice.
Speaker 1: This is going on long.
Speaker 1: I guess we can end it.
Speaker 1: if you're playing a bidding game with incremental bidding power grid is the best example and You and you're playing against people who don't listen to geek nights And you want to get like win.
Speaker 1: you want to win the game?
Speaker 1: Your strategy is simple calculate if you can as early as possible before any bidding starts the absolute maximum.
Speaker 1: You are going to pay for something and know that and keep it in your mind.
Speaker 1: But don't bid anything like that right away.
Speaker 1: basically always immediately pull a Scott and increment the bid by one just like seven nine Eleven Thirteen, but just keep doing that and you'll exude this sense of like confidence And you'll probably intimidate people into backing off of the bidding.
Speaker 0: or you'll intimidate them and to be like yeah They'll be like yeah I'll play your game And they'll bid way more and if they get above and they'll just hurt themselves by bidding too much.
Speaker 1: You'd already planned like that was the most you were gonna play you just bail, and then they're fucked.
Speaker 1: yep So that's it.
Speaker 1: if you are able to do that consistently Unless other people also do that you will win the majority of bidding games you play.
Speaker 0: you've also got to take into account sometimes Special things like in for sale.
Speaker 0: you have that dividing by half thing yeah, so always bid an odd number.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to bid an even number ever.
Speaker 0: yeah pretty much It's.
Speaker 1: it amazed me how many even numbers still got bid.
Speaker 0: I know people didn't fit.
Speaker 0: I didn't figure it out until like the second game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well the first game you ran out of money.
Speaker 1: the second game I ran out of money But I was assuming the noob was gonna fuck up, and then he didn't fuck up, and then I lost all my money.
Speaker 0: Anyway All right bidding games are cool Just like miles Davis.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website At front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows.
Speaker 1: sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: bidding game bidding games.
Speaker 1: There's gonna cut that all bidding game Games whereupon you bid on items that may or may not be converted into tokens.
Speaker 1: that will claim victory for you.
Speaker 0: I didn't drink all my water.
Speaker 0: I would have scored you.