Speaker 0: It's Wednesday June 9th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm red.
Speaker 0: This is geek knives tonight the curse of the unknown.
Speaker 1: Actually, it's spell of the unknown or Lord of the unknown tower.
Speaker 0: Wait, wait, wait Lord.
Speaker 0: Is that was that like the Japanese title what they changed the title even?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Fuck Alright, well guess what to discuss that after news is and whatnots and all that crap.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So why are you tricking me by thinking making me think I'm doing the opening bit but we're still doing the opener?
Speaker 1: I did not at any point say anything like that.
Speaker 0: I simply Manipulated the natural flow of five years of routine.
Speaker 1: I was about to hit a Psychological trap and I simply pointed out that you'd gotten the name of the movie we watched and are going to review incorrect.
Speaker 0: I'll have to trick you by making it seem like a thing of the day is coming.
Speaker 0: But oh shit The thing is I have the power of post-production.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you get everything.
Speaker 0: I say you're just gonna make it.
Speaker 0: You know make me say like I'm stupid over and over again or something.
Speaker 1: If I was really gonna do it, I would just auto-tune you and only you.
Speaker 0: It's not too bad.
Speaker 0: It depends what song you get.
Speaker 0: auto-tune me to.
Speaker 1: I'll just auto-tune you to whatever note you're closest to.
Speaker 1: Okay, yeah Maybe some sort of Dorian mode.
Speaker 1: But anyway, it's Wednesday.
Speaker 0: It's anime.
Speaker 1: There's usually not much anime news.
Speaker 1: We try to avoid all the stories about the anime industry collapsing or the anime industry not doing well.
Speaker 0: They're all the same story.
Speaker 0: Yeah But anyway, there's this big story going around about the manga industry not doing so.
Speaker 0: Basically What this comes down to is there are 36 publishers, right?
Speaker 0: American and Japanese mostly Japanese manga publishers.
Speaker 0: All the big ones are included in a whole bunch of small ones and they've created a coalition against scan lation.
Speaker 0: I always thought it was scans lation, but I guess everyone calls it scan lation.
Speaker 1: Maybe maybe it's a cultural shift like OVA versus OAV?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I like a lot of 90s anime fans call them OAVs.
Speaker 0: I'm a fan of scans lation, but I guess I'll use scan lation as long as that's what's in this article.
Speaker 1: But basically I'm gonna keep saying scans lation.
Speaker 0: Yeah from what I've been able to tell from you know, manga people I follow on Twitter and people who've you know work for manga companies even like the.
Speaker 0: you know Kurt hassler the guy who's like the king of the US manga industry and all right It's basically they all seem to agree that like scan lation is horrible evil and it's like the bane of everything right, and it's that's why manga is failing and such.
Speaker 0: and I'm just gonna say, you know, I don't want to go too long on this because we've said it about a thousand times But it's the same story over and over again.
Speaker 0: First of all is complete bullshit.
Speaker 0: They've had 15 years to do everyone every publisher of anything.
Speaker 0: Is it 15 years to do something about the internet?
Speaker 0: and they've done nothing.
Speaker 1: and you know I don't want to say what I always say.
Speaker 1: so I'll abbreviate it take fucking kozuokoke's golf.
Speaker 1: Manga put it in Golf Digest.
Speaker 1: You'll make manga popular among 40 year old guys in America.
Speaker 1: Yep done It's such a sure thing anyway.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but yeah if they get rid of see the thing is they're really upset about scans lation.
Speaker 0: because like you can go on Google and search for Manga and like in the top 1000 sites Like there are these scan lation sites that even have like scans of American stuff and it right.
Speaker 1: That's how I read death note back when it wasn't available anywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right and you know The thing is what I have like death note or even thought about buying it without that scans lation I would have never even noticed it.
Speaker 0: No, but I bought it all.
Speaker 0: if they get rid of these scan lation sites You know what's gonna happen, huh?
Speaker 1: Wait, wait.
Speaker 1: two options one Piracy disappears and overnight the manga industry in America becomes a multi-billion dollar industry.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm or or pretty much.
Speaker 0: what's gonna happen is Sales will stay the same or decrease and readership will decrease.
Speaker 1: That's all they will.
Speaker 0: all they will achieve is making manga less popular.
Speaker 0: the punk kids reading it for free Have no money.
Speaker 0: if they do have money.
Speaker 0: They ain't spending it on manga.
Speaker 1: Well, of course.
Speaker 1: now, what are they gonna do?
Speaker 0: They're gonna go to Walden books or well I guess Walden book and say in the aisle and even if they do buy one They'll trade it with each other.
Speaker 0: You know everybody.
Speaker 0: or they'll buy in the discount bin or you know, if they had a zillion dollars They would buy it.
Speaker 1: I mean manga cow is a stereotype.
Speaker 1: for a reason.
Speaker 1: you go to any bookstore even today despite the Unpopularity of most manga and the whole collapse the industry.
Speaker 1: They're just punk kids sitting there reading it all.
Speaker 0: They just sit there and read Naruto one, two, three, four, five six seven while their parents and then Come back to the bookstore eight nine ten or they go to the library Libraries get you some sales because the library buys their copy, you know.
Speaker 0: so I think that pretty much the only way that they can make money if they insist on selling books made of paper and Insist on DRM and all that kind of stuff is to make all the mangas a dollar like a dollar a volume because you know What the kid will go to the bookstore and he'll see all these volumes for a dollar.
Speaker 1: Actually, I think a better way to make money.
Speaker 1: and why?
Speaker 1: to this day I cannot understand why people don't do this in America.
Speaker 1: They always seem to say.
Speaker 1: All right, we've got this market this demographic.
Speaker 1: We're gonna shoot for it.
Speaker 1: The demographic is people with no fucking money Infinite free time and the ability to pirate whatever they want also no scruples.
Speaker 1: So that is what they go after.
Speaker 1: That is the demographic.
Speaker 1: They say you know what fuck rim and Scott the 30 year old tool to spend money to get a comic.
Speaker 1: fuck 40 year old rich guys who like golf.
Speaker 1: We're gonna go after the least viable demographic their fucking is.
Speaker 1: and then we're gonna complain when we don't make any money.
Speaker 0: Are they like?
Speaker 1: are they just stupid.
Speaker 0: the problem is they go after us right and all of the us is by it But there's only a hundred of us is yeah, that's why they fail that way to know because it's a game of marketing.
Speaker 1: You cannot tell me that they just took Kazuo Koike's golf manga the example I always use and just put it in golf digest.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of money to get in golf digest.
Speaker 0: if you have enough money to get Digest you have enough money to be golf died.
Speaker 1: Digest.
Speaker 1: we're smart.
Speaker 1: they would do it and they would make all the money from the sales of this.
Speaker 0: But then what is the manga publisher get?
Speaker 0: fuck them?
Speaker 0: Yeah, see the thing is golf digest has to hire the manga car and while the publisher still fuck.
Speaker 0: So what's the publisher supposed to do?
Speaker 0: Well publishers are basically obsolete in the money Middleman no longer necessary if you're a middleman.
Speaker 1: They serve a very valuable purpose.
Speaker 1: if you are completely unaware of the world around you Publishers will feed you stuff and charge you money for it.
Speaker 0: Yes All middlemen Basically, you're all dead.
Speaker 0: give up now Don't you know?
Speaker 0: all they're doing is they?
Speaker 0: I think the big problem is is just Economically speaking any company that actually has something going on has a slow death, right?
Speaker 0: These companies actually died years ago You know, they already are dead.
Speaker 1: Oh my She popularized zombie.
Speaker 0: their corpses continue to move Yes, but they're not completely dead until they actually go bankrupt.
Speaker 0: So what?
Speaker 1: mostly dead right?
Speaker 0: It's you know, Ken sure goes what and they go.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, and then but they don't explode for like a few sec No instead they said in this case is that a few seconds as a few years they reflect on the crimes of their life.
Speaker 1: Well, they walk slowly backwards over a cliff.
Speaker 0: So they keep trying.
Speaker 0: they don't realize they're dead, right?
Speaker 0: So they keep trying to like, you know do something to revive or come back to life and they complain about oh We're going downhill.
Speaker 0: But you know why.
Speaker 0: you know, we do this then we won't be going downhill anymore.
Speaker 0: No, you're already dead.
Speaker 0: There's nothing that you can do.
Speaker 0: It's too late you can't?
Speaker 0: you're already got you in the late 90s when Napster came out.
Speaker 0: if you didn't do something That was your only chance.
Speaker 0: you can walk over the counter.
Speaker 0: You couldn't counter like the moose or a 10 say so that you know.
Speaker 1: Not that you can know.
Speaker 0: that was it.
Speaker 0: there was.
Speaker 0: you could have countered attacked at that moment But it hit you and that's it Ken sure just walked by the building and that was.
Speaker 0: that was Years ago.
Speaker 0: Napster is from like 98 99, you know, what's funny.
Speaker 0: remember the nap like it's like over ten years ago.
Speaker 1: I remember when Napster first became popular and you know a girl in my high school came up to me because everyone knew I was like the tech guy and she was like So, um, you know, I use Napster to get these files and they don't play that well That was some buffering issue.
Speaker 1: Like I knew where the problem was, but I remember thinking Napster.
Speaker 1: only stupid people use Napster because that was still when mp3 sites were the way to get mp3.
Speaker 0: No, they were.
Speaker 0: as soon as Napster existed mp3 sites were no longer a couple weeks before Napster was really usable.
Speaker 0: No, it was.
Speaker 0: it was pretty good right out of the gate.
Speaker 0: even on a 56 came out of mine was rocking like discographies.
Speaker 1: Thing is that like Napster was well and good but it was really the win mx days where I got most of my music.
Speaker 0: Well, that's just because you know, it wasn't.
Speaker 0: if we had Napster at RIT would have been way better than win mx.
Speaker 1: Yeah I think is direct connected.
Speaker 1: RIT Owned it all because we basically had access to all media ever created on a local land that no one could even peer into.
Speaker 0: Yep Anyway, the that is the demographic.
Speaker 1: They're trying to make money out of selling physical media - yeah Try something else guys and ain't give me DRM either.
Speaker 1: So I feel like I should talk about this.
Speaker 1: Scott will groan But I got to talk about a little bit because a lot of people are speculating and I have a little bit of insight I can.
Speaker 1: I will not.
Speaker 1: I will not right now speak on behalf of Otacon But if you haven't noticed Otacon has not sent out any panel Stuff yet at all.
Speaker 1: They haven't scheduled anything.
Speaker 1: and you know Scott and I are both panel staff and we don't know any more than you do.
Speaker 0: We know nothing.
Speaker 1: the email that you all you panel has got is the exact same email the sent to us the staff Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So I'll be straight up with all of you.
Speaker 1: We don't even know if we're gonna go to Otacon because they haven't.
Speaker 0: it's not.
Speaker 0: it's looking unlikely.
Speaker 0: I mean, I've been to Otacon every year since 2002 Otacon.
Speaker 0: Oh - that's went to Five six seven eight nine.
Speaker 1: So I've been to eight Otacon's in a row when we went to our first Otacon One.
Speaker 1: violent late-night movies were not our tradition yet.
Speaker 0: Yep Para-para was genuinely popular among anime fans and brand new hotness.
Speaker 1: Yep There was a para-para like summit at that con.
Speaker 1: We went to.
Speaker 0: Full Metal.
Speaker 0: Alchemist was not yet existing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the hot anime at the time was I don't even know - wasn't that like when?
Speaker 1: I don't even know I didn't care I don't even remember was watching like initial D?
Speaker 0: It was there and I think there was initial D at the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 1: Here's the biggest difference.
Speaker 1: There was an anime industry.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think was Gundam seed was the next year, right?
Speaker 1: That was later.
Speaker 0: Let me see.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no, no cuz.
Speaker 1: yeah, TMR was the next year.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I think.
Speaker 1: so I remember that was the Otacon where we entered that contest.
Speaker 1: We signed the forms that the booth babes gave us to win the car full of anime.
Speaker 0: That was a TV when they were before, you know, yeah, it's such a different world.
Speaker 1: But you know, I really want to go to Otacon.
Speaker 1: I enjoy you know Every time I think about going to Otacon The first thing I remember is that line sucks and the line alone would be a reason not to go to Otacon that Thursday line Or even worse the Friday line, but we've skipped that line every year either due to you know old rules that no longer exist in Otacon like panelists skip the line or Straight up just cheating and skipping the line and lying and getting a badge.
Speaker 1: But if I had to stand in that line, I would have stopped going to Otacon a long time ago.
Speaker 1: But that's all beside the point.
Speaker 1: I Don't do any panels.
Speaker 1: I feel like there's no point in going.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why would I?
Speaker 0: you know, it's weird I have this I'm torn right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: part of the reason of not going is simply our personal situation, right?
Speaker 0: It's like I'm in New York City now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have no car.
Speaker 0: I have to use a bunch of vacation days.
Speaker 0: That's a lot of hassle waiting in line.
Speaker 0: Is it you know, so those are the personal hassles, you know, my situation has changed.
Speaker 1: Yeah Was it was like it was just above this line before we didn't have cars anymore.
Speaker 1: Now it's just below this line.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, you know, so now because of the change in my life It is far more difficult to Otacon.
Speaker 0: so Otacon has to be that much better for me to go to it but at the same but it's sort of the same and Actually, it's a little less than it used to be.
Speaker 1: Well, here's the reason I think the only less for me because a lot of things are better like remember That's a rocker go panel last year.
Speaker 0: Is it actually coming?
Speaker 0: Is it come back for real?
Speaker 1: It's coming back And I was like 100% sure it's come back.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're staff, you know I guess you didn't go to the meeting where we talked about that.
Speaker 0: But yeah, is that public information?
Speaker 0: I don't know if you should be saying that.
Speaker 0: I don't I don't even care anymore, but they might sue you or something.
Speaker 1: Nope, they didn't make me sign an NDA.
Speaker 0: Oh, I guess not.
Speaker 0: Did you sign an NDA?
Speaker 0: I don't know I didn't I didn't sign anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so hey They might kick me off the staff But I haven't even done anything.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm gonna be honest with all of you and I hate to rag on Otacon.
Speaker 1: I've sent several emails basically to you know, the staff above me asking Hey, what do you want me to do?
Speaker 1: We're panel staff will help you with the panels that are obviously way behind and we have yet to get a response.
Speaker 1: I've just far as I know.
Speaker 1: The only reason I know I'm still on the staff is that I get the general staff emails like here's the whole thing.
Speaker 0: That's just a computerized thing right is they have a staff system.
Speaker 0: We're entered into it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right and therefore we get you can log into it and we get staff emails.
Speaker 1: We're still listed as panel staff.
Speaker 1: We're on the list of those people.
Speaker 1: Yeah But just staff stuff aside The things that we've gotten worse about Otacon is pretty much the Thursday line and the Friday line.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: they've been worse every year for the past several years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I remember, you know the entire front row.
Speaker 0: we used to tell people that give them advice like hey Just get in the Thursday night line, you know After like, you know eight o'clock, so then it'll already be died down.
Speaker 0: It didn't die down last year two years ago three years ago that advice was alright.
Speaker 1: And the people who are friends who couldn't get through the line on Thursday they got into the Friday line and I didn't know how bad that line was.
Speaker 1: Like I assumed it was an hour or two But it is basically like it itself outweighs all the fun of Otacon to stand in that line.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, you know, the thing is I think about being an Otacon like ah that building I've been there eight times the Otter Bean Lobby.
Speaker 1: I'm going to see a late-night violent movie Standing in line to get my wristband turn to the person behind me and saying hey you're going to see Tokyo Gore police.
Speaker 1: He's like nah, I'm going to see the hentai whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those are good times.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of good times We have a lot of friends, but and I want to have those good times, but I don't want to drive real far I don't want to wait in line and I don't want to deal with BS.
Speaker 0: Well, the other thing is a lot of money to stay in those hotels.
Speaker 1: The entire front row crew has bailed on us on Otacon this year.
Speaker 1: In fact, this is the first there's not a single person.
Speaker 0: Oh Johnson was saying he wanted to go.
Speaker 1: He's one of the only ones I think Judith and Natalie and maybe James and Lisa but the whole rest of our crew Not going to Otacon.
Speaker 1: and I remember I won't name any names But when this first came to light one of our friends was like, yeah I've been going to Otacon for almost a decade and I just I'm not going this year.
Speaker 1: and I was like what the fuck why?
Speaker 1: We're going.
Speaker 1: we got the hotel room and everything and he said and I quote rim.
Speaker 1: You've never stood in that fucking line.
Speaker 1: Fuck you.
Speaker 1: And now that I see what that lines like like that alone They just mail the badges.
Speaker 1: I'd go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they mailed the badges.
Speaker 0: that would put it slightly above the line.
Speaker 1: but there's kind of a meta reason why we really I hate to pull this sort of stuff because you know doing panels and being like staff and guests of cons is Not something the majority of you deal with and it's a whole different world and you probably don't care about this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this makes no difference in the calculation of an average attendee of whether or not to go but anime Boston pays us to Panels.
Speaker 1: the New York Anime Festival and comic-con basically ask us.
Speaker 1: Hey, what panels do you want to do?
Speaker 1: When do you want to do them?
Speaker 1: Let's go packs.
Speaker 0: They treat us like royalty cooperates with us like a year in advance to coordinate and Like we discuss logistics of all sorts of panels and all this kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: Constant communication months and months and months in advance.
Speaker 0: We've already all kinds of stuff our packs East panels.
Speaker 1: That is like April 2011.
Speaker 0: yeah, we don't even know when they haven't announced it yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and meanwhile, we've already talked about things as specific as like video recording of those panels right, so Like Otakon hasn't even the Otakon's real soon and they haven't even emailed us to say what panels were doing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and there's other issues that are semi private But we I'd say there's only about a 30% chance that we're actually going to be able to attend Otakon this year.
Speaker 1: This might be the end for us.
Speaker 0: If I could like just teleport there and skip the line and do a couple panels, dude I would pay a large amount of money to skip the line.
Speaker 1: Maybe I should pay some punk kid to stand in the line for me if we end up not being.
Speaker 0: just take your badge though And your money.
Speaker 0: then what do you do?
Speaker 0: And you need to show photo ID, right?
Speaker 1: Doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: once you get the badge it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: I'll just find some kid and be like, here's 500 bucks Give me your goddamn badge.
Speaker 0: Well, here's what you really want to do you you you basically get some kid put him in line, right?
Speaker 0: And then you you set you find some way that he will swap in out of the line for you And then he gets out of the line because you paid him to get out of the line But the people nearby won't be complaining, you know.
Speaker 0: And you do it before you get to the part of the line with the staff there Right, like just around the corner from the entrance.
Speaker 0: So, you know, basically you only have to wait in this tiny acceptable line and the people around him are like We don't care if you cut because you just swap this kid out.
Speaker 1: He's at the back of the line.
Speaker 1: I I feel like if we really wanted to we could pull the same bullshit We pulled for the last several years and just kind of worm our way in and then get our badges without having to wait In line.
Speaker 1: Yeah, probably it just it bothers me that Otakon is the only con where I have to basically fake it to avoid the Line that prevents me from getting the panel.
Speaker 1: I have to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like Otakon.
Speaker 0: why you know, they want me.
Speaker 0: I assume that they want me to come down there right and do panels for them and You know say good things about their con on our show.
Speaker 0: Not that we're that popular anything But I assume that they want that right but they make it as difficult as possible.
Speaker 0: Why should I spend a ton of money take vacation days and go through extensive travel and wait in a long line?
Speaker 0: You know, it's like I'm not working for you You're supposed to.
Speaker 0: it's the other way around right?
Speaker 0: every other con every single one even tiny ones.
Speaker 0: It's the other way around.
Speaker 1: Yeah magfest, you know, awesome.
Speaker 0: They've been your best tiny little con, right?
Speaker 0: Around the same geographic area as Otakon.
Speaker 0: They're like, please come to us.
Speaker 0: We will kiss your feet.
Speaker 0: It's like a couple thousand people.
Speaker 0: and they're like, oh, please come to us from far away We will make your a good time for you.
Speaker 0: Otakon is so big.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, fuck you Let's see what you what can you do for me?
Speaker 0: And I'm like, I'm not gonna do anything for you if you're gonna be like that.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's the worst thing cuz you know, we've done like 30 Otakon panels in the last several years.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we got eight Otakons.
Speaker 0: We've done panels at pretty much all of them Otakon.
Speaker 1: We did I think seven panels in a row like just Friday and Saturday.
Speaker 1: those women They even asked us to do extra panels at the con.
Speaker 0: Who was the panel runner that year?
Speaker 1: Ah Was it Omar?
Speaker 1: Meredith is awesome.
Speaker 1: Omar is awesome.
Speaker 0: Meredith is head of all programming now, right?
Speaker 1: I think I think she's.
Speaker 1: She won the election to be Like stat one of the at large positions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, she's like.
Speaker 0: she's like upper.
Speaker 0: She just moved up So but she left the vacancy Which was not filled.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, it was filled and the as far as I can tell the guy who was in charge of our panels department isn't in charge anymore.
Speaker 1: But no one told us until I emailed the entire panels department asking like hey So are we gonna schedule anything?
Speaker 1: and they're like, oh, yeah, I'm in charge of panels now And we don't need you to do anything just yet.
Speaker 0: What do you want me to do?
Speaker 0: because you know what.
Speaker 0: if even if I show up at the con if you say hey You know sit in these panel rooms and you know Make sure the panels follow the rules and fill out these piece of paper.
Speaker 0: I'm like, uh, no, I didn't.
Speaker 0: You obviously did not read the communications from when we originally became staff.
Speaker 1: So we'll see I don't.
Speaker 1: I mean Otacon is all is fun and it's a good anime con But I worry that it just we can't deal with it anymore.
Speaker 1: It takes so much more work to do and they never even let us do the awesome panels We have.
Speaker 1: they've never let us run our good anime panels.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we offer them all these high-quality panels and they always ask for like the advance Wars panel.
Speaker 0: That was the year we did the seven panels anime.
Speaker 1: You should see like Phil's multi-thousand person rooms.
Speaker 0: attention do they?
Speaker 1: not even of Course they let us do beyond Dungeons & Dragons that one year to fill the biggest panel room like yeah handily.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: They're not even paying attention.
Speaker 0: they don't even realize that that we fill the room for them and reduced all that traffic in the rest of the.
Speaker 0: you know, In the far-off Hilton most people didn't know how to get to yep.
Speaker 1: That was actually.
Speaker 1: I felt really bad because Fred shot deserved much more attendance than he got versus what we have.
Speaker 0: We filled we we put our butts in the seats for him.
Speaker 0: But yeah, that's that's you know, that's the fucked up way of Otacon, but that's all I got.
Speaker 1: I mean, I just I don't know what's going on with Otacon.
Speaker 1: We likely won't be attending I don't know.
Speaker 0: I'd like to attend but they gotta.
Speaker 0: they gotta you know, grease the the streets a little bit You know, they can't use the streets.
Speaker 1: I think they did that in 2001 You know, they got to pave the way.
Speaker 0: they got to make it easy for us to go to Otacon.
Speaker 0: They can't be you know, they put up roadblocks make it hard for us to go there.
Speaker 0: I'm just not gonna you know, don't put obstacles in my way.
Speaker 0: You got to make it easy for me to go.
Speaker 0: make me want to go.
Speaker 1: So I guess if there's any Otacon staff listening just tell us what's going on because we're staff and no one Responds to any of our email.
Speaker 0: we might have to start emailing like the highest ups.
Speaker 0: I don't like one email to the highest up before we actually like, you know The thing is Sean and Jim and all them like.
Speaker 1: I'm not wearing good terms with them But they're busy with you know, like Jim runs all the stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Jim is doing all the guest stuff.
Speaker 0: He's doing a good job.
Speaker 0: He's smart.
Speaker 0: He knows what's up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Otacon has the best guest relations department of any anime convention in America, but it's like it's not helping us out.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe because they're one of the only anime cons that doesn't just treat us as guests.
Speaker 0: Yeah Maybe you know.
Speaker 0: if you know, he has nothing to do with us in his guest relation role But he's the only person that like we know that will respond to us and doesn't you know We can guarantee is smart and in the business.
Speaker 0: Maybe we can email Meredith.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, just be like trying to follow like the rules and like we're panel staff Unnamed person who I don't want to call out.
Speaker 1: that is like in charge of panels as far as I can tell But I'm not really sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know who else is on the panels department anymore.
Speaker 0: Whatever we're done.
Speaker 1: But anyway, that was mostly of a rant of us complaining we'll get right on to the fun stuff.
Speaker 1: things of the day Oh shit.
Speaker 1: This was posted by a listener.
Speaker 1: I think it was sale.
Speaker 1: I forget who whoever it was.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry I forget your name because I didn't look in the thread to get it But I went to our.
Speaker 1: there's a thing of the day thread in the forum where people post like their own things of the day And I ignore it just because it's enormous.
Speaker 1: I don't have time to read it But I never look in there ever.
Speaker 1: someone told me that there was a thing in there and I looked at it.
Speaker 1: This sounds like it would be really boring Unless you're really a video gamer, which is why I'm making it a thing of the day for anything other than video games on Wednesdays.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: This is Japanese people playing Mario 64 and they have this weird challenge They get a one-up mushroom.
Speaker 1: and in Mario 64 when a one-up mushroom comes out it flies at you and it hits you.
Speaker 0: And yeah They didn't want because they didn't want to make it difficult to get because in Mario reg original Mario Right a one-up would like fall down a hole or something to be like, haha That was awesome in a Mario game.
Speaker 0: or it's 3d.
Speaker 0: it's hard, you know.
Speaker 0: So you don't know which way the one-up mushrooms gonna go.
Speaker 0: you might not even see it coming at you with a camera You know and that stuff.
Speaker 0: so it just homes in on you and you get the one up if you find it cuz they're all Hidden anyway.
Speaker 1: before there were achievements gamers who were dedicated would make their own Achievements like hey, can you guys pull off?
Speaker 0: this crazy shit beats all the one but no swords.
Speaker 1: So the crazy shit here is activate a one-up mushroom Which moves at a constant rate through the mat.
Speaker 1: it goes through all objects.
Speaker 1: It just goes in a straight line toward Mario through anything in this giant 3d mat.
Speaker 1: Activate the one up and then run around the map and get all the red coins without letting that fucking one up touch you.
Speaker 1: And that might sound like the most boring thing in the world, especially because the people playing it's in Japanese.
Speaker 1: You probably don't even know what they're saying.
Speaker 1: Just watch this video.
Speaker 1: It's funny.
Speaker 1: It is surprisingly funny to watch.
Speaker 0: Yeah All he's doing is trying to get all red coins Before the one up mushroom grabs it.
Speaker 1: and let me tell you that one up mushroom has never seemed more sinister to me.
Speaker 0: Like usually you'd want it to grab you but in this like but he decides no I don't want it to grab me and then it becomes awesome.
Speaker 1: But suddenly when you don't want it to grab you this constant unerring velocity through all objects toward you with no way to stop it It's really kind of scary.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like Watson in that other video.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe we should make a game.
Speaker 0: that's just that is you're a guy in a 3d area and It's like one two three go and then this thing just starts coming at you and it goes through walls.
Speaker 0: And is you know all kinds of shit?
Speaker 1: I think no matter what you made it look like even if it was like Yotsuba smiling.
Speaker 1: You'd be scared of that shit after playing this game enough.
Speaker 0: Well anything cute becomes scary when it's like that.
Speaker 0: It just had to be sort of normal looking just like a normal looking do like it's a bread.
Speaker 0: Yeah piece of bread.
Speaker 0: What's up?
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah somebody got for me.
Speaker 0: So, you know we've complained on the show often about everything in the world about.
Speaker 0: you know People in New York walking slow and I wish I could push him over.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I did it.
Speaker 0: I fucking.
Speaker 1: I said I would do this.
Speaker 0: you push somebody.
Speaker 1: no, no, no, so Yesterday I get on the subway and while I'm going toward the subway and I'm on the escalator, right?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and there's a fat woman and she's blocking the escalator completely.
Speaker 1: There's no way to step around her and I see the seven train pull into the station ahead of me.
Speaker 1: I jumped on the railing walked past her and made it to the train All right.
Speaker 1: The doors closed and then she walked up and just before the train left She was standing in front of the door looking at me and she had this moment where obviously she recognized I was the guy who jumped past her and I waved and the scowl on her face just as the trainers pulling away Was one of those beautiful things I've ever seen.
Speaker 0: that is glorious.
Speaker 1: Like I I will have few triumphs of that caliber again in.
Speaker 0: how would it given her the finger?
Speaker 1: No, the polite way.
Speaker 0: No, you can.
Speaker 0: you can hold up a sign that just says fat on it.
Speaker 1: See now that goes too far.
Speaker 1: I think the polite wave, you know the perfectly friendly smile like hey, I recognize you.
Speaker 1: Hello I'll admit that when I jumped up on the railing I almost fell off.
Speaker 1: you realize I was like one half an inch from hitting your head on the ceiling from being a YouTube video.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Don't know if I'll ever do that again anyway.
Speaker 0: improv everywhere our friends who do things like Grand Central Standstill and no pants subway ride and no pants to Ghostbusters busting into the library.
Speaker 0: They went over near the Flatiron building near the where there's a Sprint store on the corner and they got some sidewalk spray chalk And they spray-painted a line down the middle of the sidewalk and a little stencil.
Speaker 0: and the stencil said, you know, tourist lane New Yorker Lane No, and they had some guys stand there saying New Yorkers to the right tourists to the left stop You know stand still take all the pictures you want.
Speaker 1: Is it just me or is the beautiful part of that that if that were not a joke that were legitimate?
Speaker 1: I think the majority of New Yorkers would support it wholeheartedly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people seem to enjoy it quite a bit.
Speaker 1: I think what killed me in the video was when the woman pretending to be like a researcher for the Department of Transportation Had like a clipboard with a fake letterhead and everything asking people about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was good.
Speaker 1: Also, there's two guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the two guys they got to pretend to be like, you know workers to direct people.
Speaker 1: They were excellent actors and then hey, you gotta get in the line.
Speaker 0: Hey Yeah, and then at the end they showed like, you know, mayor Bloomberg thought it was cute, which is uh, you know Cuz he's a New Yorker - he knows he knows the tourists gotta get out of New York Like the mayor of some other city.
Speaker 1: He probably has like a private car something to get to work.
Speaker 1: New York.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter how rich you are.
Speaker 0: Even the really rich people take the goddamn subway I'm sure you know, he's got a car going around driving him like a Lincoln Town car.
Speaker 1: So what is faster to take the subway?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but he's he's subwaying it now and then you know I mean, I guess it's weird though, like if you take the helicopter off the building.
Speaker 0: It seems like the U.S.
Speaker 0: is one of the only countries, you know.
Speaker 0: Well, not maybe one of the only but it's one of the countries where the the higher-up politicians are really separated from.
Speaker 0: you know Everyday life, you know, like if you're in the House of Representatives, you know, you're probably you know an everyday person.
Speaker 0: But if you're a governor a senator a mayor of a major city, maybe a president, you know or something like that You're not in everyday life, you know, I mean well
Speaker 1: remember when George Bush senior the old one got out of the White House He had never seen like an automated checkout.
Speaker 0: But no that was Reagan.
Speaker 1: Was it Reagan?
Speaker 0: Yes, that was.
Speaker 0: the story was that he went to a grocery store after no longer being president.
Speaker 0: Oh, they had the they had the beep, you know that the barcode scanner.
Speaker 0: He was like, what the hell is that?
Speaker 1: No, I remember George Bush had a different similar technological thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah But you know It's it's that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: So but if you go to say France like the Prime Minister of France just like drives to work like with everyone else and he drives His own car, you know lives in an apartment building with a bunch of other people.
Speaker 0: He doesn't have like a gigantic security detail or bulletproof and you know, it's not like that.
Speaker 0: People are just normal people.
Speaker 0: Yeah So anyway, so Oh metamoment.
Speaker 1: Oh the meta moment.
Speaker 0: So metamoment number one.
Speaker 0: I want people to know that.
Speaker 0: basically, you know There was a problem with our computers servers for a long time where they wouldn't send emails.
Speaker 0: now that really only mattered if you had Signed up for the forums.
Speaker 0: because you sign up for the forums, you know, it sends you an email that says you are now registered.
Speaker 0: Congratulations.
Speaker 0: Also ID share has a as the same kind of thing going up.
Speaker 0: So it is now all fixed.
Speaker 0: So if you sign up for the forums You will get the confirmation email.
Speaker 0: if you had previously signed up for the forums and never got a confirmation email And sort of forgot to come back and sign in or forgot to whatever You can just come and sign in and if you get your password You can click forgot password and you'll actually get the email that will remind you of your password.
Speaker 0: So now is a good time to come back to the forums and all that We've never as far as I can tell denied a human access to the forum.
Speaker 0: Yeah we've only denied people who were obviously spam or Were spam, you know trolls and really really bad people afterwards.
Speaker 0: Yep We've been I think two people ever so yeah, actually I think one of the bands was like the person was being real bad But I think that it was just like a night of drunkenness.
Speaker 0: So it's sort of like I feel like I shouldn't have.
Speaker 0: but at the same time it was such a bad night of drunken posting Yep, that if they that had continued I would you know I had to assume that based on someone's posting that it will they will continue to post that way and would require banning.
Speaker 1: Well, you know as much as I love penny arcade.
Speaker 1: We're not the penny arcade forums.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: it's working pretty well.
Speaker 0: We've only had to ban a couple times.
Speaker 0: So yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: We got a good community You should really like if you like gig nights at all, you will enjoy the community.
Speaker 0: However, so please go to the website.
Speaker 1: There's this one asshole in the forums.
Speaker 1: You'll know him.
Speaker 1: just ignore him.
Speaker 0: Yes, just you know, you got to learn that if there's a thread.
Speaker 0: you don't have to read every thread.
Speaker 0: Just don't click on a thread if you don't care about but the other part at the same time if someone posts something stupid Just scroll past it and don't read it.
Speaker 0: But the other thing is good advice for the whole internet.
Speaker 1: if this doesn't entice you to join the forum Then this final node will we enforce proper grammar and spelling?
Speaker 1: and we found that that is actually made the forum.
Speaker 1: Awesome.
Speaker 1: I think that's the primary reason the forum is awesome.
Speaker 0: Anyway other meta news kinetic on.
Speaker 1: yep, kinetic on.
Speaker 1: I'm sending the schedule for kinetic on to the printers tonight.
Speaker 1: Oh shit So kinetic on is on.
Speaker 1: we're panels now.
Speaker 1: We took over the panels department about midway through the year So there's a lot of chaos and confusion.
Speaker 1: We mostly got it all sorted out.
Speaker 1: There is a schedule.
Speaker 1: It's all awesome.
Speaker 1: Starting at kinetic on, you know for next year.
Speaker 1: It is us from day one.
Speaker 1: You're gonna see like that's such a revolution of panels department running.
Speaker 1: You'll be amazed.
Speaker 0: I hope so.
Speaker 1: We figured all this shit out now.
Speaker 0: All right What are the other meta news?
Speaker 0: Book Club Thursday, but we both had finished the book and we were ready to do it But rim had to stay late at work.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So to be fair I had to stay late at work to drink with co-workers.
Speaker 0: It was it was a man.
Speaker 1: I had to go to it.
Speaker 1: It was like a function for mandatory alcoholism.
Speaker 0: So what if I work there?
Speaker 0: What would I have done?
Speaker 1: You didn't have to drink just come and you know talk.
Speaker 1: It was it was.
Speaker 1: basically it was a hobnobbing that I could not actually skip.
Speaker 0: you could only knob.
Speaker 1: I know I had to do a lot of knobbing and I would I would only hob.
Speaker 1: Yeah between the two of us Making a hobbit The.
Speaker 0: so the book club.
Speaker 0: the next Thursday, we'll do the book club of cosmos.
Speaker 1: Yes cosmos.
Speaker 1: Do you want to announce the next book?
Speaker 0: Maybe we should wait.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: Anyway, any other meta stuff?
Speaker 1: I'm not really.
Speaker 1: we got a lot of things in the hopper, but in true shit-talking form.
Speaker 1: We can't talk about them until we have you know, the official announcements for them, but I'll say this we've got something really cool and really like.
Speaker 1: Normally I exaggerate about this sort of thing, but I'm not.
Speaker 1: right now you're exaggerating.
Speaker 1: we're doing something pretty fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: It's awesome, but it's not pretty fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: What would it take to be pretty fucking awesome in your book, uh like we're gonna be on TV tomorrow like for reals or Depends on what channel won the Stanley Cup like us.
Speaker 1: That's pretty fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: I think I put that in impossible.
Speaker 1: I didn't say If I had a bagel two days ago, that was pretty fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, it would have to be like a bagel made of Kobe bread With some Fos grass and some chablis.
Speaker 1: nice car God.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if I get in like trilobite, so We know what trilobite tastes like.
Speaker 1: we had never ever Seen a Pokemon movie neither me nor Scott.
Speaker 0: Well, I see it seems like there's like, you know, we got to talk about how there's a shortage of anime movies But really there isn't this.
Speaker 0: there's a shortage of anime movies.
Speaker 1: They don't have a number next to them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's like Pokemon one-piece.
Speaker 0: I think there's Naruto movies.
Speaker 0: I think there's any.
Speaker 0: I these sorts of movies are coming out all the time, right?
Speaker 0: But we really pretty much ignore them completely.
Speaker 0: And we've never seen a Pokemon movie except for the small bit of one.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure which one it is.
Speaker 0: That is in the The.
Speaker 0: you know, you don't know shit about Pokemon video.
Speaker 1: I don't even know what Pokemon movie that is.
Speaker 0: Didn't they tell us that it was the second one.
Speaker 1: I think I think basically we'd never seen a Pokemon movie at all Not even the first one.
Speaker 1: No, not even, you know mu and mu - nope, nothing zero nothing.
Speaker 0: So so we're at a friend's house due to the Natalie's house.
Speaker 0: We need we need something to watch.
Speaker 1: we're bored and we're like, hey, why don't we watch one of those Pokemon movies?
Speaker 0: Well, it was more like looking through Netflix couldn't find anything saw a Pokemon movie joked about it then said hey Maybe we actually should watch it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: However, we did not watch the first Pokemon movie.
Speaker 1: We watched what is arguably the worst.
Speaker 0: I don't know which one's better or worse because I've only seen one but people say this is the worst one.
Speaker 1: Jackie Joe Bond pocketal monster cash at all no tail.
Speaker 1: and So that translates to what that translates to pocket monsters.
Speaker 1: the movie.
Speaker 0: It sounds so dumb But it has Entei which in the name of it as opposed to the one the we saw the English dub on Netflix secret or spell of the unknown.
Speaker 1: The unknown get it like spelling.
Speaker 0: but why was there?
Speaker 1: the original one translates to something like monsters the movie Lord of the unknown Tower Entei.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Lord of the unknown tower Entei.
Speaker 0: So that was basically, you know It was about one of the legendary dogs from the gold and silver series the fiery one who apparently goes around raping really?
Speaker 1: Get to that.
Speaker 1: Yeah This movie was surprising.
Speaker 0: It was surprisingly funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah for the right, but it wasn't surprising to me.
Speaker 0: It just was.
Speaker 1: but it started with a short and I didn't actually look into this.
Speaker 1: but it started with a short which is can best be described as Pichu.
Speaker 1: brothers almost die Pikachu saves them and they find the secret land of the hobo Pokemon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically, I didn't know this but every Pokemon movie begins with a short Pikachu only video, which is awesome Which is pretty cool.
Speaker 0: But apparently it seemed I couldn't tell if it was actually dubbed or if it was just a dubbed over, right?
Speaker 0: I didn't even try to find like the Japanese like I was watching it You know dubbed over and I got the feeling that the original was completely silent and contained only well not completely sound But contained only music and sound effects and Pokemon making noises But in English.
Speaker 0: there was this English speaking narrator talking over it saying Pikachu.
Speaker 1: It was basically Stan Lee like Pikachu was in trouble.
Speaker 1: now if he didn't get back in time, what would happen?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I got the feeling that the I don't know this that the original Japanese just didn't have a narrator period.
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: if it did have the same narrator then the people who make Pokemon think kids are stupid.
Speaker 1: Yes, if it didn't have the narrator then as we know the Japanese think that American kids are stupid.
Speaker 0: No, the American dubbers think American kids are stupid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but even like video games I mean, they always give us the easy shit versions of game.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, they yeah, well, you know, it's the same thing.
Speaker 1: But yeah, they know we're stupid.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'd like to you know see if the originals out there and see if it was the narration was added only for English or I'm sure that no more than Two minutes of research could have answered this question, but we did not bother.
Speaker 0: but you know all in all without the stupid narration It was just sort of a cute short thing.
Speaker 1: It didn't make a lot of sense though because why are there all these homeless Pokemon living in this basically garbage heap and Pikachu basically ruins the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know as a story wise it wasn't so good, but it was just.
Speaker 0: you know, it just cute It had a lot of Pokemon in it.
Speaker 1: I think what got me was that the whole time this narrator is just crazy Like it is.
Speaker 1: literally he punched the little guy Yeah, and then at the end all the Pokemon are helping everybody like everybody's helping everybody and there's no more narrator.
Speaker 1: and Scott says Wow, I'm surprised they don't have a narrator saying.
Speaker 1: and that's how they solved it all with teamwork and right then Narrator.
Speaker 1: Oh my it looks like by working together.
Speaker 1: They were able to save the day.
Speaker 0: I mean even three or I mean, I think that it's actually.
Speaker 0: not only are you insulting the intelligence of the three-year-olds by adding in That narrator and the five-year-olds too, but you're actually making them stupider by having the narrator.
Speaker 0: It's like doesn't anyone like?
Speaker 0: what are they?
Speaker 0: What were they thinking?
Speaker 0: to do a do a VGN Toss up there.
Speaker 1: So the movie starts and as far as I can tell here's the plot.
Speaker 1: So ashes.
Speaker 1: mom was clearly having an affair with Professor Oak, but that's common knowledge.
Speaker 1: She was having Professor Oak because dad's out of the picture.
Speaker 1: But independent of that she was also having a fair an affair with this other professor who was studying the unknowns Mm-hmm, so Independent of all this.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure that that mr.
Speaker 1: Mime watches and perhaps engages because he is a creepy motherfucker.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean if ashes mom is gonna have any Pokemon why mr.
Speaker 0: Mime really?
Speaker 1: Why mr.
Speaker 1: Mime?
Speaker 0: And I mean if you if you need like a practical Pokemon, I say here if you need a practical Pokemon It's like around the house, you know made kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: Which Pokemon do you get?
Speaker 1: I Don't know.
Speaker 0: You don't know.
Speaker 1: maybe a Lucario because he's humanoid or a binary because that's awesome.
Speaker 0: No, I would get a geodude.
Speaker 1: obviously I can't lose.
Speaker 0: no not just cuz it can't lose right cuz it floats and it's got hands.
Speaker 0: So it doesn't make the floor dirty.
Speaker 0: It's got hands.
Speaker 1: I won.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure rubble falls off that thing all the time.
Speaker 0: And then you know and like into.
Speaker 1: what do you do?
Speaker 0: It can float up to reach high up things and it can lift heavy thing.
Speaker 1: Have you ever seen a geodude open his fists?
Speaker 1: They're not hands.
Speaker 1: They're just fists.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: All do you do can do is punch.
Speaker 1: you know you tell him to clean the four.
Speaker 1: He'll punch in the floor until he thinks it's clean.
Speaker 1: No you dude is an asshole.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you're much better off with the binary.
Speaker 0: anyway Mr.
Speaker 1: Mime is just really really creepy and the way he kind of like is nervous and hanging around ashes mom.
Speaker 1: There's something going on there.
Speaker 0: There's a whole lot of innuendo to be made in this in this movie.
Speaker 1: But the weird thing is You does.
Speaker 1: it is surprising the strength with which I feel the conviction that ashes mom at one point had an affair with Professor Hale.
Speaker 1: Oh Spencer Hale now the oak.
Speaker 1: that was obvious.
Speaker 1: everyone knows that.
Speaker 1: no because why else was you know?
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: why else did this whole thing happen?
Speaker 1: Why did ash?
Speaker 1: Why do they all know each other?
Speaker 1: but Professor Hale in Greenfield?
Speaker 1: There's something going on.
Speaker 1: They had some sort of action a long time ago.
Speaker 1: I think they both try to pretend it didn't happen.
Speaker 0: all right.
Speaker 1: so Professor Hale is studying the unknown and the unknown kidnapped him or something whatever and His daughter.
Speaker 1: basically as far as I can tell that the people who are on with the egg with him on this expedition come back.
Speaker 1: They're like hey Molly You know you're like five years old your dad fucking disappeared, and then they just leave her alone in the mansion I guess to starve to death.
Speaker 0: I I'm just reading some internets.
Speaker 1: You don't care about the Pokemon movie Mmm.
Speaker 0: I do.
Speaker 1: I do have anything to say about it.
Speaker 1: Was it not strange that they tell her her dad has disappeared and then leave her alone in this mansion with the strange Artifact that they found after he disappeared?
Speaker 1: and no one thinks anything of this.
Speaker 0: You know it's it's.
Speaker 0: it was really the thing is right.
Speaker 0: it.
Speaker 0: that really gets me about the whole thing is that the unknown Like spell right where it's like the only reading the unknowns and like figuring out.
Speaker 0: You know where the secret is.
Speaker 0: It's like how come no one thought you know figured it out earlier.
Speaker 1: I don't think English exists in the Pokemon world.
Speaker 0: You know they write in like some different language they must.
Speaker 0: That's why no one could figure it out.
Speaker 1: But if you go back even further I didn't look this up either, but according to our sources The the Molly you know the the kind of main Character the little girl who's left alone in the mansion to starve to death with the evil artifact after her dad disappears.
Speaker 1: Dad who had an affair with with ashes mom She and all this stuff happens.
Speaker 1: But just before the plot starts her dad is basically reading her a story like about Entei and how awesome Entei is and she got.
Speaker 1: Entei is such a badass and They show a picture of her mom and they don't really say anything.
Speaker 1: But as far as you can tell her mom's just gone Apparently in Japanese.
Speaker 1: for some reason they explained that her mom's in an insane asylum.
Speaker 1: Yeah, her mom must have just gone nuts for some reason or other But clearly because her husband was having an affair with ashes mom and she found out about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe mr.. Mime told her no Mr..
Speaker 0: Mime made her insane with his mind powers So that she would you know forget and It was just.
Speaker 1: it was weird that they make a big deal about her mom being gone in the real plot And they just don't mention this at all in the English plot.
Speaker 0: They don't tell you whether she's dead or not.
Speaker 0: They just sort of show you pictures of her with a face covered up.
Speaker 1: I miss mommy and her dad's like yeah, yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: yeah I'm gonna go study some unknowns and then disappear, and you know it really just does.
Speaker 0: the motivations don't make a lot of sense.
Speaker 0: It's like okay the girl has some sort of powers because of Entei or something.
Speaker 1: So she wakes up the unknown because they left her with the weird evil artifact that made her dad disappear and don't think anything of It.
Speaker 1: yep, and the unknowns read her thoughts and create everything that she desired with their psychic powers.
Speaker 1: Mmm, and what she desired was a daddy, but apparently daddy is Entei the dog and not her actual dad.
Speaker 1: think her dad disappeared her mom's gone.
Speaker 1: The unknowns read her mind.
Speaker 1: She doesn't want her mom and dad back.
Speaker 1: She clearly wants Entei to be her dad.
Speaker 1: Why that doesn't make any sense?
Speaker 1: Why do I mean I?
Speaker 1: Guess unless she never really liked her dad, but she secretly blamed him for her mom going insane.
Speaker 0: Well, it's it's a movie situation right?
Speaker 0: she's basically playing the movie game, and she doesn't want to stop playing the movie game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, when would you know?
Speaker 0: now?
Speaker 0: so you know once someone's got the movie game?
Speaker 0: It's like well fuck you know the movie game can replace everybody and everything and the thing is yeah.
Speaker 1: There's one thing better than the movie game what?
Speaker 1: So the unknowns make a fake Entei, and she's like you're my daddy, and this is where the dub is awesome because he's like I'm Daddy or Papa or he says it really creepily.
Speaker 1: and let's fast forward.
Speaker 1: a little bit later She demands a mommy.
Speaker 1: so Entei of course kidnaps ashes mom And he hypnotizes her.
Speaker 1: and there's this scene where this giant Pokemon dog is staring at her And she's got the anime hypnotized eyes, and he's like you are now Mommy, and she's like I'm Mommy.
Speaker 1: And then the scene cuts away, and I'm pretty sure that he raped her right then and there.
Speaker 0: yeah And I the thing is right is so heavily implied.
Speaker 0: I cannot doubt that rape happened, but then how did ashes mom right like you know?
Speaker 0: She just sort of snaps out of it like with her own willpower.
Speaker 1: I saw ash because remember he was coming to do his bullshit like he always does.
Speaker 1: he just happened to be there.
Speaker 0: See the one part the best part of the movie though for me, right if I had to look at the whole movie and say Which part was the biggest day Lisa?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's when they met that random Pokemon trainer right away, and we're like just you know having a little poke battle.
Speaker 1: Okay, she's hot and awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, so why didn't she stick around and continue the awesome?
Speaker 1: well cuz I like that.
Speaker 1: battle scenes It was.
Speaker 1: it was like the good-natured combat.
Speaker 1: the credits are kind of playing the music's going.
Speaker 1: It's like a montage.
Speaker 1: And then why was she even there?
Speaker 1: She served no purpose.
Speaker 1: she basically stood around.
Speaker 1: yeah It based jack and shit and then was kind of in the background.
Speaker 0: the only reason they had her in the movies?
Speaker 0: because without her There would have been zero actual Pokemon trainer battles in the movie It was.
Speaker 0: the only other battles were were hacks where everyone versus the end day, and you know there was no.
Speaker 1: no.
Speaker 1: no remember When Lisa or not Lisa when?
Speaker 1: when?
Speaker 1: the little girl Molly?
Speaker 1: Basically the Entei and the unknown make her an adult Which is just kind of really.
Speaker 0: that was just like this random scene that made knows that was like.
Speaker 0: Why is this in here?
Speaker 0: It was just really creepy.
Speaker 1: this five-year-old girl is suddenly an adult and of course Brock is all about this.
Speaker 1: But They make her Pokemon.
Speaker 1: They're all basically hacks.
Speaker 1: She's got like a game shark.
Speaker 1: sure she wins no matter What.
Speaker 0: yeah the other thing right is the.
Speaker 0: the team rocket is there right?
Speaker 0: Oh apparently they're in every movie, and they never do anything, but it's not the cool team rocket with you know like Giovanni it's the other two stupid team rockets in the mouth.
Speaker 0: That's I like that.
Speaker 0: the mouth is good But I don't know about the other the other people.
Speaker 1: I like them.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's Musashi.
Speaker 1: It's fucking hilarious.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so you know it's like they're there in the movie, and they're doing funny trying to be like comic relief But it's like no one.
Speaker 0: they don't interact with any of the characters.
Speaker 0: They're like these observers.
Speaker 0: They're like they're like sticking off the side of the movie like a wart.
Speaker 0: You know they don't interact with the plot.
Speaker 0: They don't talk to the other characters.
Speaker 0: They don't ever see the other characters.
Speaker 0: No one sees them.
Speaker 0: They're.
Speaker 0: they're like the guys in the Muppet show who are up in the balcony Just providing comedy, but never doing anything.
Speaker 1: the thing is as far as I can tell the joke they always do is something stupid will happen and One of their Pokemon seems to somehow always get out of his pokeball just to go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like the wobbuff that comes up, but he just appears out of nowhere.
Speaker 0: He goes And then they put it back in the ball, and they look at him like Jesus.
Speaker 1: How the fuck did you get out again?
Speaker 0: One thing I learned watching this movie that I didn't know is that pokeballs shrink.
Speaker 0: It's like you put the Pokemon in the ball And then it's already the Pokemon is too big to fit in that ball.
Speaker 1: So he shrinks and they make a big deal about that in the cartoon.
Speaker 1: and then the pokeball.
Speaker 0: and then the pokeball shrinks again.
Speaker 0: So now it's like even smaller.
Speaker 0: It's like whoa.
Speaker 0: that dude is like dying in there.
Speaker 1: You see how big those things are.
Speaker 1: how would he carry so many?
Speaker 0: And you can fit like any size Pokemon in there.
Speaker 0: legendary.
Speaker 0: put him in the ball.
Speaker 0: You know yeah He's as big as a building in the ball.
Speaker 1: Wonder what would happen if you just use a pokeball on a person.
Speaker 0: How does?
Speaker 0: yes, they never explain like how a pokeball works.
Speaker 0: Why does it?
Speaker 0: you know?
Speaker 0: couldn't I put anything in a pokeball like your house?
Speaker 1: Right, maybe only organic matter Maybe just Pokemon and then things break at.
Speaker 0: the Pokemon can break out somehow, so it's like just that Pokemon But they cannot know.
Speaker 0: I mean like when you're trying to capture them it might not work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well then once they're captured you didn't hit a and B at the same time every time it stopped shaking at the third shake.
Speaker 1: Right I entered the Konami code.
Speaker 0: They need a pokey code.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: They do.
Speaker 0: But yeah, if I'm gonna judge all Pokemon movies based on this.
Speaker 0: I really don't want to watch any more folks.
Speaker 1: Okay, I want to know.
Speaker 0: tell us for a comic relief.
Speaker 1: Tell us what the best Pokemon is.
Speaker 1: we've seen the worst movie.
Speaker 1: I want to see the best like when Scott read the so-called best Star Wars novel and they were average.
Speaker 0: You know I mean everyone says all the best Star Wars novels.
Speaker 0: that Timothy's on Thrawn thing.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: Thrawn is awesome as a character.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but those books were just average.
Speaker 1: Ron is really just a cross between a lensman because he's basically perfect and Frickin the vampire Strahd from Ravenloft mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That's basically all he is.
Speaker 0: He's just a really smart awesome kind of dude.
Speaker 1: signal vice-admiral Thrawn to lashes tie squadrons immediately.
Speaker 1: very well oh My god this fucking.
Speaker 1: but I feel like if we watched a better Pokemon movie It would be less fun because we watched this with Judith and Natalie I think their friends.
Speaker 0: is there a Pokemon movie.
Speaker 0: That's very similar to the good Pokemon manga?
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: they should make a Pokemon adventure.
Speaker 0: is the movie like a you know separate from all the other movies like on its Own?
Speaker 1: what made this movie worth watching for us was primarily the implied rape.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all the hilarious like you know Innuendos and things that we wrote into it.
Speaker 0: because we're adults and because we're not children and we're watching a children's movie mr.
Speaker 0: Bucket you know this is it's a fun.
Speaker 0: It's basically like you know you had a little mermaid and get King Triton's penis situation.
Speaker 0: It's basically that times 100.
Speaker 1: so The only bad part of them in the movie was pretty awful, but it wasn't like bad.
Speaker 0: It wasn't OD No, it wasn't bad.
Speaker 0: It was just except it was Interminable.
Speaker 1: at the end right that like there's this fight scene and just before it comes up I think Judith is like yeah this fight scene lasts for fucking ever and sure enough it Lasted forever, and then it ended.
Speaker 1: yeah, then it started again.
Speaker 0: There really aren't that many plot points, but basically each thing is dragged out, and it's over all the plot points.
Speaker 1: So starting only things we see in the movie, so it starts with random Pokemon battle with Lisa.
Speaker 1: I guess it's not really a plot point except.
Speaker 1: She's the reason they go to this town in the first place.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I guess that's a plot point.
Speaker 1: Oh shit Molly's dad disappeared.
Speaker 1: Oh shit, Molly has the power of all the universe and has an Entei.
Speaker 0: Oh shit unknowns, right?
Speaker 0: It's the same shit.
Speaker 1: Molly kidnaps Ash's mom so Entei can rape her and make her her mom.
Speaker 0: yep Ash tries to save them and fails and then Charizard shows up, and he saves everybody.
Speaker 1: Basically yeah, Charizard saves everybody.
Speaker 0: that was so random too.
Speaker 0: it's like they just show you like they cut away, and you're like you're in the land of the Charizards and There's some lady there.
Speaker 0: You don't even know who she is.
Speaker 1: She looked fucking badass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well I want to see a movie all about the land of the Charizard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then you know it's like Charizard shows up and saves the day because he couldn't have done it without a flying Pokemon.
Speaker 0: So Deus Ex Machina.
Speaker 0: He shows up and the foreshadowing was we show you the land of the Charizards Shit.
Speaker 1: yeah, I learned something kind of unrelated turns out.
Speaker 1: Lisa Ortiz played Lisa in the dub.
Speaker 1: We watch lol.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's probably why they knew.
Speaker 1: yeah, she's in my LinkedIn.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she's cool.
Speaker 1: Okay I don't know and I was a fan of slayers.
Speaker 1: I'm a fan of her.
Speaker 0: I don't know anything else.
Speaker 0: I don't know this.
Speaker 1: this movie is worth watching.
Speaker 0: I feel Is it really worth watching all right?
Speaker 1: It's only worth as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: according if you're looking for a night of silliness and lols And you're you're like maybe drunken Maybe not drunk.
Speaker 1: according to Judas and Natalie the movies only worth watching if we're in the room with you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people like us.
Speaker 0: I think there's someone who's gonna provide a lol commentary to it.
Speaker 1: I think Dave and Joel could make this movie equally for those two guys.
Speaker 0: You can't live ten.
Speaker 1: Oh my god I would watch any media if they were narrating it.
Speaker 1: I know right I Don't know what else we can say about this movie.
Speaker 1: all right and crystals form and then go away.
Speaker 0: No, the crystals.
Speaker 0: Basically you're just you know part of the Entei kidnapping situation, I'm pretty sure that thousands died in the background of this movie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's one of those things.
Speaker 0: they show you huge collateral damage But they never show you any deaths.
Speaker 0: or you know actual permanent damage related to I'm pretty sure those crystals Collateral damage.
Speaker 0: you did not make it yeah, but they didn't actually show any person getting covered by them.
Speaker 1: Just a town Yeah, so all right and the Entei was fake and also there was an underwater Pokemon battle, but Missy didn't turn into a mermaid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, come on.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Missy really didn't do that much.
Speaker 0: You just sort of hung around Yeah carrying that togepi still same as Brock.
Speaker 0: and why was she carrying the togepi?
Speaker 1: she always carries that togepi because it's cute.
Speaker 0: Why didn't she put it in the ball with all the other Pokemon?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: like why doesn't Pikachu get in his fucking ball?
Speaker 0: Yeah Or Meowth, it's like dudes.
Speaker 0: You know Brock.
Speaker 0: He keeps all his Pokemon in the balls.
Speaker 1: No, you don't keep Meowth in the ball.
Speaker 1: Meowth is the one Pokemon who deserves enough respect.
Speaker 1: Or you never put him in a ball again.
Speaker 1: He put him in another Pokemon so much he learned English or Japanese I guess just to hit on her.
Speaker 0: you put him in a luxury ball so that he's all has like a couch and shit.
Speaker 0: But you don't you keep him in a ball.
Speaker 1: I never use anything, but dusk balls.
Speaker 0: Why not?
Speaker 0: why not any other ball?
Speaker 1: cuz it's always dusk I just wait till dusk and I use the dusk ball Or I set my time to dusk and then I use the dusk ball.
Speaker 1: why am I gonna buy a power ball or whatever the other?
Speaker 1: balls Mr.. Bucket.
Speaker 1: I think we're run out.
Speaker 1: We're done.
Speaker 1: It's over.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website At front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays Geek nights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.