Speaker 0: It's Monday, October 4th, I'm Scott, and this is Geek Nights!
Speaker 0: Tonight, the mysterious Electron.
Speaker 0: Ooooh!
Speaker 0: Let's do this!
Speaker 1: You know, it might be lame to complain about the weather, but today was perhaps the shittiest day in the history of days.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my co-worker, the other Scott, he was like all happy with this weather.
Speaker 1: I was like, "Fuck
Speaker 1: you!"
Speaker 1: But you wanted to be cold and shitty.
Speaker 0: I was like, "Look, we were walking down the street on the sidewalk towards the burger
Speaker 0: truck.".
Speaker 0: And I'm like, "Look at that!
Speaker 0: There's that bike rack, usually loaded with bikes.
Speaker 0: One
Speaker 0: bike.".
Speaker 0: I'm like, "You see that?
Speaker 0: That's
Speaker 0: bullshit.".
Speaker 1: Kinda rainy, but not actually raining.
Speaker 1: Kinda cold, but not snowing.
Speaker 0: It was like, so bad.
Speaker 1: I feel like an old man to complain about the weather, but shit woman.
Speaker 0: Woman is coming soon.
Speaker 0: It's almost woman time.
Speaker 1: See, if woman were here, I could go skiing.
Speaker 1: It's not proper woman.
Speaker 1: This is just like some bitch hanging out.
Speaker 0: Some little girls.
Speaker 0: How much for your little girl?
Speaker 1: But at least we got some South Park coming up.
Speaker 1: We got some Monster Madness.
Speaker 0: Oh, Monster Madness, yeah.
Speaker 0: It's good times for media consumption.
Speaker 0: Video games are coming.
Speaker 0: Holidays are coming.
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 1: video games are coming?
Speaker 1: Civ V already came out.
Speaker 0: There's more video games coming.
Speaker 1: No, there aren't.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's the patch for Civ V. It'll make multiplayer work.
Speaker 0: It really doesn't work that well at all.
Speaker 0: No, but there's more games coming.
Speaker 1: That was so sad.
Speaker 1: It was like Russian roulette trying to get that game going.
Speaker 0: I know, right?
Speaker 0: But anyway, a couple weeks ago, I haven't talked about this yet because we didn't do a Monday show.
Speaker 0: I went to the Maker Faire in New York City.
Speaker 0: You did not go.
Speaker 0: No, I did not.
Speaker 1: Luke Burrage also went.
Speaker 1: Your mom went.
Speaker 0: Yeah, my mom did go, literally.
Speaker 0: You know, there was basically like, I wasn't sure exactly what to expect because this is like a California event.
Speaker 0: I was like, what's it going to be like in New York City?
Speaker 0: Are they going to get all these people to show up?
Speaker 0: You know, are they really going to make the trip like Pax does?
Speaker 0: I mean, I wasn't too sure about it.
Speaker 0: But actually, it was way more awesome than I expected, right?
Speaker 0: I'm not going to go deep on it.
Speaker 0: But basically, you go in.
Speaker 0: It was at the New York Hall of Science in Queens, which I had been to when I was very young with my grandmother.
Speaker 1: It's over by where the World's Fair was back in the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, first of all, right, that museum has not changed.
Speaker 0: There were things, exhibits in that museum that I remember that are unchanged in at least 20 years.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: There's a hall of mirrors and there's one of those things.
Speaker 0: you stand in front of it and it leaves colors behind you.
Speaker 0: All these same exact science exhibits are still there after all these years unchanged.
Speaker 0: Oh, my God.
Speaker 0: Anyway, as for the Maker Faire, right, it had all sorts of stuff going on.
Speaker 0: First of all, there's a craft fair, totally awesome craft fair.
Speaker 0: I bought an awesome T-shirt that had robots and castles and knights on it.
Speaker 1: It's a good shirt, I will admit.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: The guy had other good shirts, too.
Speaker 0: But there was all sorts of yarn and basically there were all sorts of stations where you could learn to knit and or solder, soldering.
Speaker 1: I feel like knitting is really for nerds on the upswing.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: It's big time, way big time.
Speaker 0: There was some corporate promotion stuff like Ford had a thing and Martha Stewart Living was there, but those didn't really get that much attention.
Speaker 0: Most of the attention was on the home brewed stuffs.
Speaker 0: The MakerBot guys were there.
Speaker 0: There were some other people who were professionals that had a multi-thousand dollar machine that did the same thing as the MakerBot, only better.
Speaker 0: But it was much bigger for companies, not for regular people.
Speaker 0: All sorts of like hundreds of tables of people who just had some project they made and they were showing it off.
Speaker 0: One guy had this wooden box that had various different things on it, like a piece of wood and a piece of metal and a bell.
Speaker 0: It basically had these solenoids that would bounce up and hit these various things and it made music.
Speaker 0: A lot of different musical things.
Speaker 0: It was in fact like a room of music inside the Science Center.
Speaker 0: People from the Tesla Museum out in Long Island had a little area in there.
Speaker 0: Basically all outside and all inside the museum there were just tables in every empty space with somebody who was showing off the thing that they made.
Speaker 0: Whether it was electronic or what not.
Speaker 0: I don't think I've ever seen this many Arduinos in one small space in my entire life.
Speaker 0: There was also chariot races, which I think we should totally do because we could totally beat all of those guys.
Speaker 1: I was amazed.
Speaker 1: You said there was a chariot race.
Speaker 1: You sent me the link.
Speaker 1: Those are some shitty chintzy chariots.
Speaker 1: I made better soapbox derby cars when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: There were many heats in the chariot races.
Speaker 0: That was the particular heat that I saw live.
Speaker 0: There was a great crash.
Speaker 0: And everyone's chariot broke except for the human powered British invasion.
Speaker 1: Were there some rules we don't know about like you can't make it good?
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: Because a lot of those, much like when they have those...
Speaker 0: I don't know if there's a rule, but I think making it good is against the spirit of the chariot race.
Speaker 1: Kind of like how there's a lot of those flying machine contests where you try to make the most absurd thing possible.
Speaker 1: Or like the bed races that happen at a lot of local fairs where you put a bed on rollers and race it down the street.
Speaker 1: I feel like, however, if it is against the spirit, we should be team evil.
Speaker 0: We should be evil team.
Speaker 0: We could dress up as the evil team, the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the chariot races were cool.
Speaker 0: The guys who did the Coke and Mentos were there, but I didn't watch their shtick because I've seen it on the internet.
Speaker 0: It was a life-sized mousetrap, which is pretty impressive.
Speaker 0: You can see that on the internet.
Speaker 1: Supposedly the last time they ran it, instead of dropping a cage on the mice, they dropped a safe on a car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they did.
Speaker 0: They dropped a safe on a car.
Speaker 0: I watched that.
Speaker 1: That seems at least a little wasteful.
Speaker 1: I'll give them that.
Speaker 0: It was an old shitty car that was all busted.
Speaker 1: What about the safe?
Speaker 0: The safe?
Speaker 0: Because they kept you reusing the safe.
Speaker 0: But, you know, there was all sorts of other cool stuff going on there.
Speaker 0: The one thing that they were lacking was food vendors.
Speaker 0: There were only a few.
Speaker 0: So even the shitty hot dog stand had a huge line, and the burger truck that was there, which is one I'd never seen before, had a hugest line.
Speaker 0: Someone should have driven up there with their fucking food vending truck.
Speaker 0: They would have made mad bank, yo.
Speaker 1: Of course, if you'd walked out and go to the street, like right at the edge of the park, there's a ton of shitty restaurants right there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's true.
Speaker 1: If you want some really bad lunch food, there's food there.
Speaker 0: There was.
Speaker 0: No, but Maker Faire, totally worth spending a day at and checking out everything that was going on.
Speaker 0: Even non-nerdy people would have fun there.
Speaker 0: In fact, non-nerdy people would have more fun because you would not be so...
Speaker 1: I feel like kids, nerdy kids between the ages of 8 and 18.
Speaker 0: Oh yeah, there were so many kid activities.
Speaker 0: They had multiple stations where you could learn shit if you were a kid and do kid crafts and kid activities.
Speaker 0: There were different labs you could go to, so it was definitely all about kids going on there.
Speaker 1: So I got a really old news, but I bring it up only because it's so old, and therefore slightly more relevant now.
Speaker 1: This is from about a year ago.
Speaker 0: It's not really news then at all.
Speaker 1: And it was a project at MIT called Project Gaydar.
Speaker 1: And this may remind you, remember at RIT we found that thing online where you submit a small sample of text, and with a surprising degree of accuracy it would say if a man or woman wrote that text.
Speaker 1: Well, this is that for if you're gay or not.
Speaker 0: Oh, a text?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it actually was a little more advanced than that.
Speaker 1: The idea on this is to analyze all the information about someone on social networks, and then figure out their sexuality based on that.
Speaker 0: Actually, I remember something, I thought this is what it was going to be about, but I guess not, is that they could tell people's sexualities with a high degree of accuracy based on the gait of their walk.
Speaker 1: The gait of the walk and also a factor is the length of difference between the index finger and the middle finger.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but I mean the thing is I thought that the Gaydar would actually just sort of use multiple webcams.
Speaker 1: Well, then it would be the Gaydar.
Speaker 0: And look at everyone in the vicinity and then provide some sort of heads-up display.
Speaker 1: But see, that's not so useful if you're trying to figure out people on the internet.
Speaker 0: That's true, but you want to figure out people when you're walking around town like, "Oh,
Speaker 0: homo.".
Speaker 1: Do you really need that?
Speaker 0: No, but it would just be hilarious, especially because it's basically you don't treat it as something serious.
Speaker 1: I have a nerd detector.
Speaker 0: It's like one of those fart detectors, right, where it's like you hold it near someone's button, you push the button and it goes beep, beep, beep.
Speaker 1: It's like, "I know who farted, it was
Speaker 1: Rym.".
Speaker 1: And this is real.
Speaker 0: I know, but maybe if you had a real fart detector, how awesome would that be?
Speaker 1: The reason I bring it up is that I've had numerous arguments with people lately about privacy and the internet and anonymity.
Speaker 1: And while Anonymous is still being very anonymous and doing its anonymous thing, I think they attacked the European equivalent of the RIAA or something like that.
Speaker 1: And it's funny that Anonymous attacks don't even gather press anymore.
Speaker 1: But people always try to make this argument that you can somehow protect your privacy.
Speaker 1: And I guess I bring this up for anyone who's having similar arguments recently, that it'll probably within the next few years, because this is an old article, be trivial to figure out way tons of information about someone, even if that person doesn't have a Facebook account or anything.
Speaker 1: Because mentions of them by their friends alone will likely be enough to figure out who they are, where they live, their sexuality.
Speaker 0: The only way to be private is to don't say anything and don't be friends with anybody and don't go outside.
Speaker 0: And then nobody will know anything about you.
Speaker 0: If you just walk out of your house in the morning, on your way to your car, people can see you.
Speaker 0: And if people can see you, they can take your picture and they know your address.
Speaker 0: And they can take your picture and they know your address, they can know your name, and then they can know pretty much everything about you just based on looking at you, looking at your car, looking at your license plate.
Speaker 1: They record a physical thing.
Speaker 1: I think a much more, I guess, scary to many people hack is the fact that statistical analysis will probably be able to figure out based on, all right, this post was made by this person.
Speaker 1: This post was made anonymously on an unrelated site, but was very likely to have been written by the same person.
Speaker 1: And this third post has a name and now we know exactly who it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, it takes so little information to extrapolate a very large amount of information because it's all so associated already.
Speaker 0: There's no point in fighting it.
Speaker 0: Instead of trying to eliminate this situation, which is impossible, in my opinion, you should instead learn to live with it instead of trying to return to an ancient time.
Speaker 1: I had a revelation, I was reading this and I was thinking about another argument I have had where if you have ubiquitous internet that is effectively untraceable, then organizations like the so-called anonymous could be a lot more powerful.
Speaker 1: They could exert real influence if they were organized in a non-directed way.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, analysis like this makes something like anonymous impossible because if they post more than a couple of times, you figure out who they are and now they're fucked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got GPS data, you got so much fucking data.
Speaker 1: But I realized a way to maintain anonymity and think about this.
Speaker 1: Right now, the problem would be, alright, I post on 4chan and I get people to do stuff and I'm part of this thing.
Speaker 1: But then statistical analysis of the way I write eventually based on the volume of my post figures out who I am based on other things I've written in my life.
Speaker 1: If your posts in the manner of 4chan or whatever are, like if your persona is indistinguishable from anyone else on 4chan, like if you can have an alter ego.
Speaker 0: The only post you ever post is first.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean sure, I can say alright, we know to a reasonable degree that one of these 40,000 people is that first post guy.
Speaker 1: And then you have safety in the crowds again.
Speaker 1: So, coming back to the more practical thing like this, if you're not trying to be some sort of internet future 4chan terrorist, safety in the crowds is the safest way to protect yourself from the fact that you cannot have privacy in the modern world.
Speaker 0: The thing is, okay, so I'm gonna seek safety in the crowd on 4chan by basically saying the same kinds of things everyone else is saying.
Speaker 0: Well, what that means is- What's the point of even saying anything if I'm just saying what everyone else is saying?
Speaker 1: No, what it means is that 4chan, or Anonymous at least, would evolve over time such that the large number of people who are posting in it basically have the exact same personality and desires, at least in the context of Anonymous and 4chan.
Speaker 1: So, it's kind of like gods in Dungeons and Dragons.
Speaker 1: Remember how the gods in D&D are basically people who are like-minded, they all kind of merge together into one thing.
Speaker 1: that does what all of them individually would have done?
Speaker 0: Mmm, okay.
Speaker 1: Well, that was at least implied heavily in the re-release of Planescape.
Speaker 0: Alrighty.
Speaker 0: I'm probably the only one who didn't own those stupid boxes or read those books, unlike all you nerds.
Speaker 0: So anyway, I got a news that's related to what I was just discussing about the Maker Faire, and that is at the Maker Faire, they launched a new Arduino, right?
Speaker 0: If you don't know already, the Arduino is basically this little tiny computer that has a USB port and a power connector and a bunch of digital and analog inputs and outputs to make it very easy to create electronic projects of varying shapes and sizes, you know, if you're a total nub.
Speaker 0: You know, you can't make like a DVD player with it, but you can make all sorts of stuff involving LEDs and sound and all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 1: You could probably control a DVD player with it.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, remote control, totally.
Speaker 0: And it's, you know, you can get all sorts of attachments for it and there's all sorts of companies making stuff for it.
Speaker 0: So they came out with a new one.
Speaker 0: It's very similar to the previous one.
Speaker 0: It's basically a slight upgrade in the memory and that sort of thing with, I think, a smaller firmware and some other stuff like that.
Speaker 0: But the biggest thing they changed was the marketing on it, right?
Speaker 0: It's now they have like cool graphic design, like it's the Arduino Uno and the Arduino, I forget, Duo, I think is the other one.
Speaker 1: Because I recall back in the day, remember all those like box you could buy at Radio Shack that had a bunch of resistors and a breadboard and had projects and taught you about this stuff?
Speaker 1: Those things had very awesome like lasers, check out the awesome stuff kids can do with this thing.
Speaker 1: Holy crap!
Speaker 0: No, no, there's a Uno, a Nano.
Speaker 1: So who is this graphic design marketed at?
Speaker 1: Like what kind of...
Speaker 0: I don't know, look, it's like a cool, it's like an infinity sign with a plus and a minus in it.
Speaker 0: It's, you know, they got a new marketing shit going on.
Speaker 0: So I think it's going to work out for them pretty well here.
Speaker 0: As opposed to, like the previous marketing was pretty much like, it looked really nerdy.
Speaker 0: Now it looks like a friendly, fun thing to do.
Speaker 1: The thing is, as we're probably going to get into in the second half of the show tonight at least, I don't think it's still that friendly to most people.
Speaker 0: It's surprisingly friendly, it's actually being used by tons of artists more so than programmer types.
Speaker 0: Because programming people and nerds, they just have a computer, a real computer, and they program that.
Speaker 0: But Arduino is good for people making like, I just want to put lights on this thing.
Speaker 0: And it's really hard for them to, you know, control lights on it or make Halloween decorations do stuff.
Speaker 0: You know, it's hard to do that with a computer that you buy like on a Mac or anything like that.
Speaker 1: But it's really easy to do with a stepper motor and a couple of gears.
Speaker 0: Yes, very easy.
Speaker 1: But then you don't need the Arduino.
Speaker 0: Actually no, the Arduino makes it easy to program the motor and the gears into a routine.
Speaker 1: It is surprisingly easy to make a simple routine happen with just a stepper motor and some gears.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about stuff like, you know, the guy who's got like a Halloween thing where his house like lights up in sync with the music, you know, that kind of shit.
Speaker 1: That's tough, but if you want like a skeleton face that pops out every 30 seconds, you don't need an Arduino to do that.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, no, but you know, this is, we're talking about real...
Speaker 1: You need your little brother tied up in a box.
Speaker 0: We're talking about real business here.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna keep saying it differently every day.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: So I saw this video on the internets and I see a lot of videos on the internets.
Speaker 1: Ah, you do.
Speaker 1: I see a lot of videos on the Internet.
Speaker 0: I see maybe more videos on the Internet than there are drugs being sold in this community.
Speaker 1: But Black Dynamite.
Speaker 0: Anyway, this video is like one of the best videos I've seen on the Internet in a long time.
Speaker 0: At least that I can remember.
Speaker 0: Like, you know, you know how I can tell that is even though...
Speaker 1: By the pixels.
Speaker 0: Well, no, I can tell.
Speaker 0: I can tell because of, you know, remembering it's like, can I remember anything that was better than this?
Speaker 0: And not really, because if it was so much better, I would have remembered it.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So and this I'm definitely not going to forget this.
Speaker 0: So what this is is a supposed homeless man or a guy pretending to be a homeless man.
Speaker 0: It's hard to tell.
Speaker 0: And it doesn't really matter whether he is or isn't.
Speaker 0: But what he does in this video is he has two Kermit the Frogs.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they are like, you know, I don't know if they don't have like control of the arms and legs.
Speaker 0: It's just a put your hand in it kind of Kermit.
Speaker 0: But it's still a pretty high quality Kermit the Frogs.
Speaker 0: He's got two of them and he's sitting out in front of a building with his homeless chair and his homeless son.
Speaker 0: And he's got the song Under Pressure on a box.
Speaker 0: But apparently whoever did this video, you know, redubbed the song over it.
Speaker 1: So kids, that's the doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo song.
Speaker 1: in case you didn't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, hopefully they know.
Speaker 1: I don't think kids know anymore.
Speaker 1: They might know it has been a lie.
Speaker 0: If you don't know this song, just kill yourself.
Speaker 0: Anyway, and basically in his left hand, which is your right, is Kermit Mercury.
Speaker 0: And in his right hand, which is your left, is Kermit Bowie.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And he proceeds to have, you know, Kermit Mercury and Kermit Bowie rock the house.
Speaker 0: And this video is just so awesome.
Speaker 0: And if it actually is a homeless dude, it's double awesome.
Speaker 0: But even if it's not, it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: It's still like the greatest.
Speaker 1: He really gets points for how into it he gets.
Speaker 1: One of the comments Kermit's like hanging off of his neck, singing at you.
Speaker 0: One of the comments was like, where is it?
Speaker 0: It's like he put all he had into that one.
Speaker 1: Well, it also speaks very highly of the power of Muppets because these are like the lowest grade of Muppet.
Speaker 1: They're basically just a hand puppet shaped like a Muppet.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: He is able to put so much perceived emotion into something where all he can do is waggle it, open and close the mouth.
Speaker 1: That's all he's got.
Speaker 1: Waggle, open, close.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: And I'm feeling Freddy by the end of this.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, this is an excellent, excellent Internet right here.
Speaker 1: So the meta moment, nice and quick.
Speaker 1: The book club book that we just finished was Ray Breiberger's Golden Apples of the Sun.
Speaker 1: The next book club book is World War Z by Max Brooks.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: Zombies.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 0: It's weird because it's like, it's zombies.
Speaker 0: The guy also wrote the zombie survival guide.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: The expectations based on that information is that this book is going to be just a shallow zombie book.
Speaker 0: But at the same time, people are saying good things.
Speaker 0: But those could be shallow people.
Speaker 0: It is tough to say.
Speaker 0: But regardless, I picked this book because I believe that people will read it.
Speaker 0: And after this, I'm going to go back to picking good books.
Speaker 1: See, I worry the people who are saying they like it and they want us to read it are the same people who want us to do a goddamn zombie survival guide again.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: We've done what, like three or four of those things?
Speaker 0: If you really want one, go read Zombie Survival Guide and World War Z by Max Brooks.
Speaker 0: Read a book.
Speaker 1: Max Brooks?
Speaker 0: I mean, even reading Brooks, reading and even reading a zombie book is reading a book.
Speaker 0: It's not a sports page and it's not a magazine.
Speaker 0: So read it.
Speaker 0: It's all good.
Speaker 0: It's better than reading nothing.
Speaker 1: So this weekend we will be at the Combined Double New York Comic Con New York Anime Festival.
Speaker 0: I'm probably only going to be there Friday because Saturday and Sunday I'm going to go to 1010 the Burning Wheel convention, which I think is full now.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So you can't go.
Speaker 0: Sorry.
Speaker 0: Unless you're going already.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anything that happens after that, we'll let you know.
Speaker 1: Kineticon panel submissions will be opening within a month or so.
Speaker 1: And we're going to be at PAX East doing at least two panels.
Speaker 0: We'll probably be at Anime Boston.
Speaker 1: Possibly three.
Speaker 1: We will likely be at Anime Boston, but we have not determined what we're doing there yet.
Speaker 0: No, you know, just and we will very we will very, very likely be at MAGFAST.
Speaker 0: There's no way that I'm going to miss MAGFAST.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So, you know, in light of all this Maker Faire Arduino kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, I wanted to do some sort of show on electronics, but I am not an electronics expert.
Speaker 0: I mean, I know more than the average person on the street.
Speaker 0: But my PVs, my NRTs and all that.
Speaker 1: I have not actually soldered anything to anything.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, that's not even the right.
Speaker 0: That's like the ideal gas laws.
Speaker 0: And it shows it's like, you know, vehicles are or whatever.
Speaker 1: The last time I wielded a soldering iron for purposes of soldering was more than three years ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, I've actually got some soldering skills now because I've been putting together some kits, but I'm not capable of like designing my own thing.
Speaker 0: I can just follow the instructions and I have crafting skills.
Speaker 0: So to solder something, you just put something together.
Speaker 0: It's like Legos.
Speaker 0: I can do that.
Speaker 1: I haven't built a Rube Goldberg machine or anything in at least a decade.
Speaker 1: And the last project I had that was anyway electronic was when I built a hard DDR pad.
Speaker 1: And that was what that project alone.
Speaker 1: I harken back to and I realized why we need to do this show.
Speaker 1: It's not so much we can sit here and talk all day about like when to use transistors and why they're cool and like how to make cool stuff.
Speaker 1: But really, I think people just aren't curious or interested in electronics.
Speaker 1: And I think that is actually going to really prevent people from doing really awesome stuff.
Speaker 0: I think so also.
Speaker 0: And, you know, the thing is, is it's one thing to, you know, when you have electronic stuff that's already put together, like your laptop and your computer and your TV and your DVD player.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: People are really good at using electronic things.
Speaker 0: But because these things are just built in factories and mass produced, no one ever actually has to know, you know, how what a resistor is these days.
Speaker 0: You don't need to know that at all.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And you can still totally do all this crazy stuff.
Speaker 0: And because you can we have software.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's really the invention of software meant that you can now program devices without knowing a single thing about hardware.
Speaker 0: Remember, computers work on electricity.
Speaker 0: That is the thing that makes a computer go is electricity.
Speaker 0: And most people using a computer, they can program ridiculous shit and harness like the power of God over those electrons.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Without even knowing a single thing about the laws of physics and only knowing math.
Speaker 0: Because we have extra somehow magically abstracted that completely away from necessary knowledge.
Speaker 1: Of course, most of those people end up trying to make a game and then that game will involve some sort of physics.
Speaker 1: And then they have to learn physics to make their game work.
Speaker 0: OK, maybe.
Speaker 0: But they don't.
Speaker 0: usually they don't need to know electricity physics.
Speaker 0: They just need to know, like kinematic physics.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And, you know, those are laws of motion and maybe thermodynamics.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, people who go that route, that's well and good.
Speaker 1: But as a kid, I was building very complex burglar alarms for my bedroom because I was bored.
Speaker 0: I actually you know, I never was really interested in electronics until I went to summer camp where I took electronics, you know, as nerd summer camp.
Speaker 0: So I chose electronics as one of my elected science things.
Speaker 0: And that is where I learned to solder from the Australian guy.
Speaker 0: And I made, of course, a burglar alarm.
Speaker 1: That seems to be the first thing kids make.
Speaker 0: It was actually pretty cool because, you know, I actually learned to make a circuit board.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: They gave you this piece of, you know, a piece of material with copper on one side.
Speaker 0: You took a Sharpie and you drew your circuit on the Sharpie and put a circle where the holes are supposed to be.
Speaker 0: And you drilled the holes.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And then they would dip the thing in acid for you overnight because they didn't let you play with the acid.
Speaker 0: And then they would take it out and you would get, you know, you'd see, oh, my God, that's how it's done.
Speaker 0: Oh, shit.
Speaker 0: And it was like it was like a total revelation for me.
Speaker 1: See, I didn't use.
Speaker 0: And I also learned that Sharpie blocks acid.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: For a lot of the things that I was doing, what I ended up having to use were not so much circuit boards, but it'd be like for a big Rube Goldberg machine or something like Science Olympiad in middle school.
Speaker 1: So I'd have to like wire up a power bus and then control solenoids and things.
Speaker 1: I'd put like one.
Speaker 1: I'd basically wire together these logic circuits that were just wires connected to each other.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, the other thing is this is something I still have problem with.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: As I know, basically what a lot or the vast majority of the electronic, the basic fundamental electronic components do.
Speaker 0: I know that a capacitor stores and or releases a charge.
Speaker 0: You know, I know that a resistor resists.
Speaker 0: Well, I think that's why, you know, I know that that, you know, a depends on what you want to do at that point.
Speaker 1: What's important is there are two paths where minimal knowledge in either will greatly expand your hobbying abilities, because the path I went down with.
Speaker 1: one path is the.
Speaker 1: I want to program circuits.
Speaker 1: I want to do complex things.
Speaker 1: That's when you have to know, like what an oscillator is and how to make a simple one.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: How to make like an adder and a subtractor out of just, you know.
Speaker 0: Well, that's getting into computing, right?
Speaker 0: You don't even need to do that sort of computing.
Speaker 0: You don't really need gates, you know, unless you're doing, you know, a logic stuff.
Speaker 0: And usually most people don't, at least in modern times, if you're like the Arduino.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really have any logic parts on it because you don't need to know about those.
Speaker 0: You just buy a chip, you know, a microprocessor, and then all your logic is inside of that and you write software for it.
Speaker 0: And the only electronics you actually need to know is the, you know, the input and the output electronics.
Speaker 0: You need to know how to hook up like a temperature sensor to the analog input, you know, properly.
Speaker 0: You need to know how to hook up an LED to the digital output.
Speaker 1: The Arduino has opened up kind of a third path because that path, before there were things like Arduino, that path of doing, of implementing fairly simple logic on your own kind of unlocked all sorts of crazy things you could do.
Speaker 1: Like it was really easy to take a serial port and have it interact with a physical thing, even without an Arduino back in the day, as long as you could, like you could figure out the basics of logic circuitry.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And you know, before they had a microprocessor that you could just buy, you had to make your own logic circuitry and there would be switches.
Speaker 0: Like a pinball machine is a good example, right?
Speaker 0: It's a, you know, it's an electronic device and everything is done with relays and switches, you know.
Speaker 0: And, you know, there's no, all the memory is just relays.
Speaker 0: There's no microprocessor in an old pinball machine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but think about the crazy things you can do if you understand logic and you have basic skills.
Speaker 1: Like say you're a kid, you're in Science Olympiad, which is always a common thing.
Speaker 1: And there's always some sort of Rube Goldberg-like event.
Speaker 1: It may or may not, I'm not admitting to anything, have been really trivial to cheat by setting up a power distribution bus such that the entire device was actually controlled from a centralized location.
Speaker 1: And the Rube Goldberg aspects of it were totally staged.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know.
Speaker 1: And you totally won a bunch of medals with that.
Speaker 0: No one noticed that there were wires going everywhere.
Speaker 1: Well, the first year, as an aside, they didn't have any rules against parallel processes, right?
Speaker 1: So we had the Rube Goldberg machine just set something up and then wait.
Speaker 1: And then at the apportioned time, we built a clock out of wood with a pendulum that ticked down exactly two minutes and then hit a button.
Speaker 1: that finished the thing and we won.
Speaker 1: Next year, they're like, "No parallel
Speaker 1: processes.".
Speaker 1: So we hid the parallel process.
Speaker 0: That's pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the tech I really want to focus on, at least for my enjoyment and how I've been able to do things, is the practical electronics knowledge.
Speaker 1: Not so much building circuits or Arduinos or everything, but knowing things like what constitutes a conductor, what does not conduct, how to insulate against electricity, what a stepper motor is, why you might want to use a stepper motor.
Speaker 1: Because even if you have the Arduino skills, if you want to interface with the physical world, if you don't know how to solder and do basic electronic stuff, you're fucked.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, the Arduino doesn't do anything unless you know that stuff, right?
Speaker 0: Because all it is, is basically it's a microprocessor that you can load with some software that's pretty easy to write and then it has digital inputs, digital outputs, analog inputs and analog outputs and that's it.
Speaker 0: So you need to hook up those inputs and outputs to electronic things that are of your own making, right?
Speaker 0: Or you can get a book that gives you designs, but what's the point of just following instructions and doing a kit?
Speaker 0: You might as well just look at someone else do it.
Speaker 0: You got to actually come up with your own new thing or at least try to do something without instructions and then you're actually learning something.
Speaker 1: But I worry that kids just don't have this basic knowledge and I was about to say anymore, but there's an article on Slashdot about the mystification and demystification of electricity back in the day, like when we were rolling out electricity to America, how people kind of didn't understand it and were afraid of it and how eventually people get used to it.
Speaker 1: and the article is interesting, but it made me realize that I don't think, you know, the common argument that old mechanics will make is that back in the day a car was simple and everybody knew how to take apart an engine and put it together because there's a rubber band and like one cylinder.
Speaker 0: No, back in the day the mechanic, the stupid mechanic knew how to take apart a car and put it back together.
Speaker 0: Nobody else did.
Speaker 0: Now the mechanic, right, doesn't even understand the car because he's got all the stuff that he doesn't get.
Speaker 1: I'm making a much simpler argument.
Speaker 1: My argument is that the people who decry the fact that increasing complexity and electronics and the things we have today have removed simplicity such that now the average person can't fix their own stuff, I don't think since the Industrial Revolution the majority of people in America have ever been able to fix their own stuff.
Speaker 0: I don't think in much of the world people haven't been able to fix their own stuff.
Speaker 1: Pioneer days, people had to fix their own stuff or die trying.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know, there are some places, right, in Cuba there is a huge culture of making these old cars work because they don't have any new cars there, you know, so there are a lot of people there who really know how to fucking make a car work.
Speaker 0: but the cars they have are old cars.
Speaker 1: Hey, hey, business idea, because Castro is going to die someday and eventually, you know, probably in our lifetime, Cuba is going to, we're going to normalize relations.
Speaker 1: If you want to make a buck, be ready to jump in as soon as it's legal, grab every goddamn mechanic in Cuba, bring them over here and make the awesome car shop for every rich person.
Speaker 0: For every old car.
Speaker 1: Yeah, every old car.
Speaker 1: They're not going to be working on your brand new Lamborghini.
Speaker 0: No, it's not going to happen.
Speaker 1: Of course, they could probably figure it out.
Speaker 0: Maybe, but the thing is they wouldn't figure out anything with a computer on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: but I feel it's like the people who complain the most about kids don't know anything today are the people who knew something when they were kids and most people don't know or care and I feel like people know about as much about electronics now as they did 80 years
Speaker 0: ago.
Speaker 0: I think it's also there are people who had a specialized knowledge in the past, their knowledge got outdated.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And they complain that something got too complicated.
Speaker 0: Really, it was just them not keeping up with the times.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Or them being unable to give up for the times.
Speaker 0: So it's sort of like, you know, they don't know it anymore.
Speaker 0: I used to know I used to be an expert on cars, but now cars are too hard and I'm not an expert anymore.
Speaker 0: But there's some other guy who is.
Speaker 0: So it's your problem, not the problem of the car.
Speaker 1: Thus, I want to present to you something I like to call the melancholy of the DDR freaks hobbyist forum.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Because I wanted to make a hard DDR pad dance dance revolution.
Speaker 1: This is before.
Speaker 0: you could buy a hard DDR pad.
Speaker 0: You can only buy soft ones.
Speaker 0: And we had a couple soft ones and we take a couple every few months.
Speaker 1: We had to order a couple.
Speaker 0: At least they're only like 20 or 30 bucks.
Speaker 0: We duct taped them to the floor and that helped.
Speaker 1: And then when they break, we just duct tape new ones on top.
Speaker 0: And we would open them up and repair them.
Speaker 0: And the thing was, is that the main part of the DDR pad would not break.
Speaker 0: the part that was actually a basically a bootleg PlayStation controller was perfectly fine.
Speaker 0: It was the part of the pad, the physicality of it, the actual foot sensing area that would break.
Speaker 0: It was so shitty.
Speaker 1: So I had this pile of basically PlayStation one controllers with if I soldered wires onto them, I can make anything a PlayStation controller at a pile of them.
Speaker 1: And like Scott said, there were no.
Speaker 1: not only were there no hard DDR pads you could buy, except for a couple of very boutique things that were very expensive and shitty.
Speaker 1: You couldn't even buy good soft pads.
Speaker 0: No, they didn't.
Speaker 0: You know, it's not like today where you can get the like the ignition or whatever, which we have.
Speaker 1: And I recall thinking, I'm just going to make one.
Speaker 1: I know how to solder.
Speaker 1: I got these controllers.
Speaker 1: I can totally make a hard DDR pad.
Speaker 1: And I go to DDR freaks, which I assume is still around.
Speaker 1: And they had a whole forum thread dedicated to people's hard DDR pad projects.
Speaker 1: Now I'm going to skip the whole story.
Speaker 1: The people there would put their instructions like here is like Jojo's instructions for making a hard pad.
Speaker 1: These instructions had zero chance of success.
Speaker 1: These people did not understand the barest basic minimum of even like the simplest electronics.
Speaker 0: I mean, the thing is, if you already have a PlayStation controller, you don't actually need to know any electronics.
Speaker 0: All you need to know is, OK, look, the way this thing works is there's a circuit that is completed on this pin, right?
Speaker 0: And if it's completed on that pin, that pushes the X button.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: That's all there is to it.
Speaker 1: So one, these people, they didn't know how to solder and their explanations for how to solder to these cards to interface with them were disastrous.
Speaker 1: Absolutely disastrous.
Speaker 1: I don't think anyone in the forum knew how to solder with a dam.
Speaker 1: And half the questions were things like, yeah, I soldered together.
Speaker 1: Now it doesn't work.
Speaker 1: And they post a picture.
Speaker 1: And it was obvious that they had melted the entire board like they just melted a hole through it or their solder blob covered like five of the wires.
Speaker 0: What the fuck?
Speaker 1: And they'd be like, why doesn't it work?
Speaker 1: And all the other responses would be like, I don't know.
Speaker 1: It looks like he soldered it.
Speaker 1: Maybe try buying another one.
Speaker 1: It must have been broken when blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 1: And one for one of the things like the electricity goes over metal.
Speaker 0: If the if that metal is touching the other metal, then the electricity goes over.
Speaker 1: Oh, they thought they knew about electricity going over metal.
Speaker 1: So most of them, the way they suggested that you make the actual steps where you step, they didn't suggest like boundaries, switches or anything like that.
Speaker 1: You know, a smart way to do it or even micro switches.
Speaker 1: Their idea was get to like metal plates and cut them to be the right size and just solder the end of one of your long wires to one of them and solder the end of one of your long wires to the other one.
Speaker 1: And then put like insulation between the two and cut a hole in the middle.
Speaker 1: And when you step on it, the two plates will touch and connect the circuit.
Speaker 1: And then people would connect these dodgy wires with shitty soldering to two aluminum plates and then stay and be like, yeah, even when I touch the plates directly together, it doesn't work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wonder why.
Speaker 1: And the thing is, this project would be simple.
Speaker 1: It would take me about a week to make an awesome hard DDR pad today.
Speaker 0: Except for the actual physicality of the pad.
Speaker 1: Actually, that was the easiest part.
Speaker 0: Uh huh.
Speaker 1: Because I have basic woodworking skills.
Speaker 0: Are you going to make a wooden DDR pad?
Speaker 1: It was wooden, but then to get the top.
Speaker 0: Dude, we should make one with wooden arrows, like completely wooden.
Speaker 1: Actually, what I did was I took, you know, I made a base, right?
Speaker 1: And then over it, I made a frame that was in the right shape and it had nine holes where each individual like bit would fit.
Speaker 1: So you put either a button there or a plate there.
Speaker 1: To make the plates, I bought some thin sheet metal and I pounded it around pieces of wood that were the right size and shape.
Speaker 1: And it looked perfect and it was great.
Speaker 0: Did it work?
Speaker 1: It actually worked pretty well.
Speaker 0: I don't remember you ever actually using this thing.
Speaker 1: Because I used it when I lived at IBM and it worked pretty well, but it was too fragile and every time I moved it, it broke.
Speaker 1: So I threw it away eventually.
Speaker 0: Uh huh.
Speaker 1: I couldn't, literally I put it in my car, I took it out and like the back just cracked and three of the soldering points popped off.
Speaker 0: I remember seeing like a few arrows.
Speaker 0: I don't remember seeing the whole thing.
Speaker 1: I'll try to find a picture of it.
Speaker 1: Alright.
Speaker 1: I mean, I used it to play some DDR.
Speaker 1: It just, it was too fragile, but my failings were failings of the fact that I didn't have enough money to buy good components.
Speaker 1: But it was amazing to look at all, like hundreds and hundreds of people who were dedicated to making a hard DDR pad who failed.
Speaker 1: They had, they made beautiful looking pads.
Speaker 1: They look way better than mine.
Speaker 1: They failed solely because they did not understand the basics of electricity, let alone electronics.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: I feel like basic electricity should be required in all schooling, not just in like physics class.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe what we should do, right, is I don't want to do like a, like a how something works episode, but I kind of want to like encourage people to learn electricities.
Speaker 0: So maybe we should like, you know, uh, like teach the most basic parts of electricity in a humorous fashion and hopefully then people will go and study it for reals.
Speaker 1: I am an electron.
Speaker 0: I go if there is something there to go for, but, and a voltage gradient that pulls me along.
Speaker 0: If there is no voltage, I'm sitting my ass still.
Speaker 0: And then I will only go if there is actually something that is metal.
Speaker 0: If there's like a piece of rubber, I ain't going that way.
Speaker 1: I had an idea.
Speaker 1: This is kind of a tangent.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: You know, the anarchist cookbook, the instructions are kind of dubious.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Why don't we make instructions that look like they'll make something cool, but really they just make a laden jar and then they zap you.
Speaker 0: You know, you get to kill someone with that though.
Speaker 1: You can make a week one.
Speaker 0: Uh, the thing is someone, you know, someone's going to be like, Oh, why does it matter what size jar I get?
Speaker 0: I'll use my tomato jar.
Speaker 0: That's enough.
Speaker 0: Like if you use any jar bigger than like an eight ounce can, it's going to fucking, you know, it's dangerous shit.
Speaker 1: I remember when we locked the door to the physics room one day in high school and just we put the Van de Graaff generator behind it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean, there was once a teacher of my high school science teacher who picked up the laden jar off the table and he didn't know that it was charged up.
Speaker 0: And he said it felt like someone hit him in the chest or the hammer.
Speaker 0: He's lucky it wasn't fully charged.
Speaker 0: He would have been dead.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But yeah, basically, you know, electricity likes to go.
Speaker 0: It goes in a circle, right?
Speaker 1: Well, only if it has a reason to.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: If it doesn't have a reason, it won't go.
Speaker 0: So at first you need the electricity to go on the wires and then you need to direct the electricity to go to the thing you want to go to.
Speaker 0: You know, everyone I think everyone knows that hook of a battery to like a light bulb.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 1: You know, because I like I feel like the way we'd have to do this is even do some videos because I imagine.
Speaker 0: Well, there's plenty of videos on the Internet that are already existing from Make magazine and many other places.
Speaker 0: We don't need to make videos.
Speaker 0: It's redundant.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, I feel like most kids would look at a micro switch and not really know why there's three spots on it.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, really.
Speaker 0: I just I don't know.
Speaker 1: Tell us.
Speaker 1: Do you guys know like?
Speaker 1: do you guys actually like without having to look it up, know how to just like wire a micro switch into something?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't think they know how to wire.
Speaker 0: They make.
Speaker 1: Do you know what a real stat is?
Speaker 0: I don't know what a real stat is.
Speaker 0: Really?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 1: I guess I use them to.
Speaker 1: I'd make circuits that would go.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: I don't think my parents liked it when I got into electronics.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the other thing is that back in the day would be totally chill to make dangerous like, you know, here is some electronic stuff, kid.
Speaker 0: People take shit apart.
Speaker 0: Nowadays, even the stuff like Lego Mindstorms is in a plastic box.
Speaker 0: It's sealed shut.
Speaker 0: Kids don't know what's in there and they don't never open it either because it's an expensive thing.
Speaker 0: You're not open to that, you know, and even Radio Shack, you know, the chemistry sets and the electronic sets have been severely diminished.
Speaker 0: And it's only the Arduino kind of people that are pushing it back to the way it used to be.
Speaker 0: But even then.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: A lot of the stuff that you do is because you have this microprocessor there.
Speaker 0: A lot of the stuff you're doing is in software.
Speaker 0: Almost no one's doing anything completely in hardware anymore.
Speaker 0: You know, where you have to program by putting, you know, transistors on the thing.
Speaker 0: You don't put down a single logic gate or a single transistor anywhere.
Speaker 0: You know, every almost everything you do is just, you know, the resistors, the capacitors, the input devices and the output devices.
Speaker 1: I feel like the best way to learn is to want to accomplish something very simple where you don't need the logic so much, but you do need the electronic apparatus.
Speaker 1: Like when I made my burglar alarm for my room as a kid.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: First, I made one where if the wires touched, you know, the circuit was completed, the alarm went off.
Speaker 1: That's basically just a speaker hooked up to a battery.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And that was well and good.
Speaker 1: But it wasn't that practical.
Speaker 1: Like as a kid, I was like, this doesn't really work.
Speaker 1: It is trivial to defeat this.
Speaker 1: So I thought really hard and I figured out how to make one that only tripped when the wire was disconnected.
Speaker 1: Oh, and figuring that out taught me way more about electronics than I think anything else in my life.
Speaker 0: It's like a trick.
Speaker 0: Like, I don't think most people could figure that out.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I got a little bit of help because, you know, I asked.
Speaker 1: There's this gnome we knew.
Speaker 1: Basically, he was a gnome.
Speaker 1: He was like the smartest engineer I've ever met in my life.
Speaker 1: He was.
Speaker 1: And him and his wife and his daughter were all like super electronic engineering nerds.
Speaker 1: And their house was just a sea.
Speaker 1: I looked like a mad scientist house.
Speaker 1: They were awesome people.
Speaker 1: And I remember I asked him and he would never answer a direct question because he wanted you to figure it out on your own.
Speaker 1: Any time you asked him a question how to do something, he would ask you another question.
Speaker 0: Oh, shit.
Speaker 1: And I learned a lot from him.
Speaker 1: And I asked him a question or two.
Speaker 1: I don't remember really what I asked him.
Speaker 1: And he was like, well, what if you blah, blah, blah?
Speaker 1: And I was like, huh?
Speaker 1: And I made an awesome burglar alarm.
Speaker 1: And the next day when it worked, my mom was like, you hiding something in your room that you don't want me to know about?
Speaker 0: That's pretty good.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I just I see.
Speaker 0: That's the thing is I've always followed directions on any electronic thing I've made, you know, and I pretty much, you know, only know, you know, so much like I know.
Speaker 0: Hey, look, this led only says it needs this much voltage going in.
Speaker 0: And I got this much voltage from my battery power source.
Speaker 0: I got to put a resistor.
Speaker 1: But if you set up something different, you can blow it up.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 1: And I could be cool.
Speaker 1: I think that the most learning in this realm occurs the second you have to go outside of the kit.
Speaker 1: The moment you have a thing that you made from a kit and then you say, oh, but I really wanted to do this.
Speaker 1: one other thing.
Speaker 1: What if I?
Speaker 1: and then you'll figure you'll learn so much more.
Speaker 1: Maybe the key is to make kits for kids, right, that will do something cool but are so close to doing something so much cooler, but you don't tell the kids how to do the thing cooler or you purposefully remove a feature.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you don't tell them it's a feature.
Speaker 1: You don't advertise it.
Speaker 1: It's like you build a solenoid thing that will like shoot like it may.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to think of a good example.
Speaker 1: You build a device that will use like make a nail hit a bell out of a solenoid and you can make a little keyboard with it.
Speaker 1: But if you construct it in the right way, it'll be obvious to a kid that make a nail gun if they tweak it just slightly.
Speaker 1: so nail gun.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then the kid will figure that out.
Speaker 1: But he won't know how to do it because the book doesn't tell him.
Speaker 1: He can't ask his dad or his teacher, hey, I want to turn this into a weapon.
Speaker 1: So he'll try to figure it out himself.
Speaker 1: And the smartest kid is going to have a nail gun.
Speaker 1: So kids, the secret to making a nail gun, the gimp, there are two.
Speaker 1: Because I figured this out as a kid and this worked really well.
Speaker 1: First, I was like, all right, if I power the solenoid, it pulls the metal rod in and holds it there.
Speaker 1: That's not good.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 1: What if I make a timing circuit that as soon as the nail is in the middle, it turns off the solenoid and then it continues.
Speaker 1: And it worked OK, but it's kind of gimpy.
Speaker 1: And then I was like, what if I just use a magnetic pole in the middle so it gets pushed all the way through?
Speaker 1: And suddenly I was in business.
Speaker 0: Actually, the way I would do it is I would I would just have it a physical thing, sort of push, you know, like a little hammer hit the nail.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: And I'd basically leave the magnet uncharged.
Speaker 0: I would charge up some capacitors and then I would unleash the capacitors into the magnet at the same time that it hits the nail forward.
Speaker 1: Scott, here's the problem.
Speaker 1: So the nail is coming into the solenoid, right?
Speaker 0: And because it's just sort of sitting in there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So no.
Speaker 1: So you hit it and you energize the solenoid.
Speaker 1: The solenoid and the force of the hitting pull the nail into the center.
Speaker 1: The solenoid now resists the nail, leaving the center for the same reason that it pulled it in.
Speaker 0: You know what else you could do is you just take a car door lock.
Speaker 0: Those are wicked powerful.
Speaker 0: Rip it right out of a car door and use that fucker.
Speaker 1: Scott, this is why you've got to think.
Speaker 1: I mean, as a kid, you're trying to figure out how can I shoot this nail out with what I have?
Speaker 1: I have the solenoid.
Speaker 1: How do I make it shoot out?
Speaker 1: It always holds it in.
Speaker 1: And if I turn it off halfway through, it shoots out gimpily.
Speaker 1: And then the kid will eventually realize that if you have a magnet being pulled in, north-south and north-south, you know, south and south always oppose, you'll push the thing all the way through.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: The idea, I think, stands still.
Speaker 1: You want to give kids something that does a kit that does something awesome.
Speaker 1: It has to actually do something that they care about, they think is cool, like burglar alarm for my room.
Speaker 1: And you want to just leave just the hint to the smart kids.
Speaker 1: only that, wait a minute, I could totally make this into a paintball gun instead of just a burglar alarm.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I think the thing is, right, is they've already, you know, more recently, all the electronics projects that have been given to kids are all robot kits, right?
Speaker 0: Even before Arduino, there is Arduino robot stuff, is they had like, you know, basic stamp stuff.
Speaker 0: There are all these different things you could use to make robots.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, robots, you would put together the robot following a kit, but you would pretty much do the same thing every time.
Speaker 0: You hook up a motor, you hook up the wheels, you hook up some lights, maybe.
Speaker 0: Maybe an infrared sensor.
Speaker 1: Not everything's like that.
Speaker 1: I checked.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: The Radio Shack Electronics Learning Lab is basically unchanged from 15 years ago.
Speaker 0: That's pretty good.
Speaker 1: It costs the same.
Speaker 1: I'm looking at it right now.
Speaker 1: And look at this thing.
Speaker 1: This thing is not a robot.
Speaker 1: It is literally just everything you need to make mischief.
Speaker 0: Oh, shit.
Speaker 0: And you should get one of those.
Speaker 0: The thing is, most Radio Shacks probably don't have that in stock.
Speaker 0: You have to buy that on the internets, you know.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but yeah, everyone gets these robots to learn electronics.
Speaker 0: And the thing is, when you get the robot, you basically put it together and then you never modify.
Speaker 0: All you do is modify the software because you're programming it to like, OK, robot, look, when you see a wall, then you need to turn around until you don't see a wall anymore with your little sensor.
Speaker 1: But that's basically just playing with logo, but in Meatspace.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: But that's what they've been teaching kids as far as electronics go for many years now.
Speaker 1: Well, part of it is maybe shop class is more the way to go because I was much more interested in that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Like logo, when I was really little, I was like, I don't care about this.
Speaker 1: And then in CNC class, I was like, oh, I can program a drill press to drill stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And suddenly it got really interesting.
Speaker 0: I actually think the place to do is art class.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: If you look, most of the people who are doing the exciting stuff with electronic, you know, simple home electronics these days are all artists making installations of various things.
Speaker 0: Go around the Maker Faire.
Speaker 0: What do you see?
Speaker 0: You see someone making musical things.
Speaker 0: You see someone making, you know, putting LED lights to blink in a pattern on some clothing.
Speaker 0: You see somebody making some sort of, you know, magic mirror with some, you know, it's almost all art.
Speaker 0: It's hardly anyone is, you know, making, I mean, there are some people, but they're, you know, it's making like video games and other nerdy sorts of things.
Speaker 0: A lot of it is art and is like a whole, if you go to like NYU, you're not going to see any Arduinos in the CS department.
Speaker 0: You're going to see them in the art department where they're making cool, interactive shit for people to, you know, play with, you know, making toys, making all these sorts of things.
Speaker 0: So I think that we just need to introduce it in the art class and then maybe, you know, people get interested in it instead of being scared of it because they'll view it as they view like a crayon.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe part of that, too, is just giving them some sort of reason to want the end result, but no easy way to get to the end result.
Speaker 0: The thing is, people follow the path of least resistance, right?
Speaker 0: You need to, you need to give, but at the same time, you need to give them something easy that they will do and find fun to get them interested.
Speaker 0: And once they're hooked, then, you know, they can get the challenge for learning.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess there are two different problems.
Speaker 1: The first problem is get people who wouldn't otherwise be interested, interested.
Speaker 1: And the second problem is getting people who are already interested to become masters, not professionals.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: I don't know, that was kind of rambling, but it's a shitty day and I'm really tired.
Speaker 1: What do you want from me?
Speaker 0: People aren't learning electronic stuff enough, including, you know, us, so...
Speaker 1: I kind of want to make a DDR pad again.
Speaker 1: I think this time...
Speaker 0: You have one, though.
Speaker 0: Why would you make one?
Speaker 1: I want a hard one so I can wear my shoes on it and do my double taps.
Speaker 0: Why don't you just, you know, there's got to be something better you can make.
Speaker 1: So here's what I wanted to do, right?
Speaker 0: I was thinking about making a cheating joystick where I could push one button and do a Hadouken.
Speaker 1: Well, what I really wanted to do way back, but I obviously could not afford this since I couldn't even afford basic electronics to make a good DDR pad.
Speaker 1: I had to scrounge.
Speaker 1: But what I wanted to do was make a hard DDR pad where everything's metal and where you step for the footing is literally just depressed a little bit, but solid.
Speaker 1: And have a little laser array in each one that detects... Basically, if you step inside, it interrupts the laser, and it's a huge reflected laser, so anywhere you step in there is going to work.
Speaker 1: And you only have to step in, like, if you lift your foot up even, like, half a millimeter, you're not detected anymore.
Speaker 1: You could make a DDR pad...
Speaker 0: So there's no moving parts.
Speaker 1: No switches, no moving parts.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: That would actually be really cool.
Speaker 1: And I kind of have the money to do it, but I'm not going to say I'm going to do it because that would be the biggest shit talk in the world.
Speaker 0: With extra steps, you have to clear the lasers, go out and in again.
Speaker 1: Exactly, so I'd have to make the laser component very low.
Speaker 0: It'd be very, very tiny.
Speaker 1: Or what I could do is have the lasers go through some sort of Lexan material, so you still have a glass-looking step, right?
Speaker 1: But there's no physical switch.
Speaker 1: Instead, the lasers are bouncing through the Lexan, and use whatever kind of Lexan or figure it out to where, if the Lexan is compressed by any amount, it disrupts the laser's path.
Speaker 1: That wouldn't be that hard to do at all.
Speaker 0: Interesting, very interesting.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen anyone on any electronics things using anything that involves lasers and getting them cut.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen that part for sale.
Speaker 1: I actually used that a lot in middle school.
Speaker 1: I got a laser pen way early because I thought it was awesome.
Speaker 1: And it was awesome for like 10 minutes, then I got bored with it.
Speaker 0: What you could use is you could use the Hall effect sensor, which is my bike computer.
Speaker 0: There's a magnet on the spoke that spins around.
Speaker 0: And there's the Hall effect sensor, which knows that a magnet has passed by.
Speaker 1: Well, you can do that with a magnet switch, too.
Speaker 0: Right, so what you could do is in the DDR pad, you basically put a magnet on each square, and you put a Hall effect sensor, and when you stepped, the magnet would get closer to the sensor.
Speaker 1: But at that point, I could just use a capacitive plate to do the same thing.
Speaker 0: But even if it got a little bit closer, the capacitive plate, you need to touch it with skin, right?
Speaker 0: You get to touch it with your foot with a shoe on.
Speaker 1: No, because the way a lot of microphones work is the air or something moves the thing, and the thing itself is separated by a gap from another thing.
Speaker 1: And that's where the capacitive gap is, not between you and the thing.
Speaker 1: Between the thing and the thing.
Speaker 1: Double thing.
Speaker 0: Two things.
Speaker 0: So you'd have someone's finger in the DDR pad, and you would step on their finger.
Speaker 1: But what I would do is, actually, that was when we got disqualified, because we had the chemical reaction, where you mix two clear liquids, and they turn opaque yellow.
Speaker 1: And that blocked a laser, which then tripped a circuit, which did something awesome.
Speaker 1: But the pressure resulting from the reaction exploded the vessel we had put it into, and sprayed lead, mercurial, something.
Speaker 1: What was it?
Speaker 1: It was lead something.
Speaker 1: It was bad news, whatever it was.
Speaker 0: So anyway, what I did is, you know...
Speaker 1: Yeah, chemistry nerds.
Speaker 1: Try to guess.
Speaker 1: I'll look it up.
Speaker 1: Guess what reaction I used.
Speaker 1: Two clear liquids, mixed together, almost instantaneously turned opaque bright yellow.
Speaker 0: Alright.
Speaker 1: It was real.
Speaker 1: I did it.
Speaker 1: It involved lead.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I put together.
Speaker 0: so far, in terms of electronic stuff, I made that ice clock, which actually worked on the first try.
Speaker 0: And then I made the minty boost yesterday, and it worked on the first try, because I'm just so good.
Speaker 0: But these are all kits following instructions.
Speaker 0: I ordered one more kit, which is basically a mini POV.
Speaker 0: It's basically LED lights, and you program it to say something, and you wave it around, and it will draw whatever it is that you drew in the air.
Speaker 0: You know how they do the thing with the bike spokes, going around in a circle, with the LEDs?
Speaker 0: It's like that, only you hold it in the air and just wave it.
Speaker 0: And it knows how fast you're waving, I guess with an accelerometer maybe, so it can write things up.
Speaker 0: You can see it on YouTube in action.
Speaker 0: So I ordered one of those, but I also, because I said, alright, it's enough kit action, I need to make something, right?
Speaker 0: Just for learning purposes, I ordered one of those tiny LCD screens.
Speaker 0: It's like 16x2, right?
Speaker 0: So I can get some outputs, and I ordered a $2 temperature sensor, so I'm going to try to detect the temperature, and then write it to a screen, and make a thermometer.
Speaker 0: And then I looked online, and there's so many sensors, and I was like, dude, if I buy every sensor they have, I could make a weather station better than the expensive ones for maybe 30 bucks.
Speaker 0: Get a humidity sensor, I can get all sorts of shit.
Speaker 0: I can use the hall effect sensor to make an anemometer.
Speaker 1: I think that hall effect sensor, Scott, is an example of, you've got a hammer, and everything looks like a nail.
Speaker 0: No, I mean, that's right.
Speaker 0: It's the same as the bike wheel, right?
Speaker 0: You have a spinning anemometer, and I would put a magnet on it, and I would know how many times it spanned around.
Speaker 1: There are many times better ways to go about that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: To know how fast something is spinning?
Speaker 1: Well, it depends on what you're trying to do.
Speaker 1: You don't rely on the hall effect sensor for everything.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying, they've got all these sensors that you can buy, and there's plenty enough of them to detect all sorts of weather.
Speaker 0: I saw a digital barometer I can buy for a few dollars.
Speaker 0: That's pretty awesome.
Speaker 1: See, as much as I want to make my hard DDR pad, I'm pretty sure I'm not going to do that anytime soon.
Speaker 0: Well, this is something that is very small that can go on my desk.
Speaker 0: It is not something that is big and requires a wood shop.
Speaker 0: It is very good for New York City, whereas a DDR pad would be good for the country in the barn.
Speaker 1: I kind of want to do something with home automation, now that I've got this apartment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is, the things you can buy are so much better than anything you could...
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but basically I want to automate the shades going up and down.
Speaker 0: You could just hook up little motors to the shades.
Speaker 0: It would be pretty strong, though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, stepper motors.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then just make a remote control infrared, something like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then I'd control it, because I want to be able to... My ideal thing is I would have a temperature sensor, and it would basically figure out if it's too hot or cold.
Speaker 1: When we're out away from home, and it would razor-lower the shades.
Speaker 0: You could actually use a solar cell, and if it's getting all charged up, it would lower it down after it charges.
Speaker 0: And then, when it's starting to get dark, it would...
Speaker 1: Oh, Scott, so that's actually how old audio compressors worked.
Speaker 0: With the solar cell?
Speaker 1: There'd be a light and a photo cell, and the light would get brighter as the sound got louder, and then the photo cell would detect.
Speaker 1: That's basically how that old shit worked.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, well, there you go.
Speaker 0: You could totally do that.
Speaker 1: You want to know how echo chamber, like an echo, like a reverb device used to work?
Speaker 1: It was literally a rack-mount device with a bunch of space inside of it, and a speaker on one end, and a microphone on the other end.
Speaker 0: Whoa.
Speaker 1: We are definitely spoiled by our digital world.
Speaker 0: We are indeed.
Speaker 0: And you should learn how our digital world works, so you aren't a caveman.
Speaker 1: But you should also know how to goddamn solder.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Solder, eh?
Speaker 1: Not sold out?
Speaker 0: Solder.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: Oh, what are we going to call this bitch?
Speaker 0: Oh, let me make my headphones good.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Ooh.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: It's Monday, October 4th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm Rim.
Speaker 0: And this is Blinking Light at the Window is Annoying.
Speaker 1: Scott is easily distracted.
Speaker 0: All right, let's do an actual opener.