Speaker 0: It's Tuesday July 13th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight a new game the legend of Zelda.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Sweet Jesus, we're back from Kinetic on.
Speaker 0: Yep, that was a. you know it's one thing to do like eight or nine panels at a con.
Speaker 0: It's another thing to take over an entire panel room for an entire con.
Speaker 0: It is yet another thing to be the heads of panels for an entire time.
Speaker 1: Usually the heads of panels are don't actually do any panels so having to do panels and be the head of panels was quite Well actually wouldn't have been so bad.
Speaker 0: the only trouble we ran into which will be rectified for next year Is that we had to deal with all situations and be doing panels which meant I had an earpiece on while I was doing panels And periodically I would be interrupted and have to go respond to something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got to do something about that.
Speaker 0: already sorted that out.
Speaker 0: We're getting operational head to handle that radio.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we need.
Speaker 1: we need a radio like at a disk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we'll talk more about Kinetic on on Thursday.
Speaker 0: cuz Kinetic on.
Speaker 0: it's not really a gaming con or an anime con though it has Everything awesome about both anime and gaming gaming cons at it But really you know it's kind of an everything console.
Speaker 0: Thursday is really the only place for it.
Speaker 1: No, that's all right.
Speaker 1: kill off a Thursday episode with a con review doesn't kill Thursday episodes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we should plus.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty much done with the book club book.
Speaker 1: Oh wow we're getting.
Speaker 1: that'll be like the fastest book club ever.
Speaker 1: What are the listeners gonna do?
Speaker 1: There's no way.
Speaker 0: I guess we'll have to wait at least a couple more Thursdays.
Speaker 1: yeah one or two.
Speaker 0: yep All right, you got anything anything fancy anything going on.
Speaker 1: well I you know we go into Kinetic on and I wasn't able to get laundry done before we went.
Speaker 1: So I was gonna do it last night Fascinating yeah, so I go down to do some laundry and I put in one of the laundry machines.
Speaker 0: They have a screen that tells you this is really you're gonna keep going with this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay They have a screen that tells you how much money you got to put in.
Speaker 1: so I go to the first one and the screen Is off.
Speaker 1: which is we?
Speaker 1: So I put a money in and it says okay add another dollar.
Speaker 1: so I put in a second money Nothing happens, and then it resets and is like yeah, give me a dollar 25.
Speaker 1: I'm like what I'm like pushing the coin return nothing.
Speaker 1: I Already put my clothes and detergent in there by the way all right so it was detergent.
Speaker 0: because there's two situations.
Speaker 0: Situation one you put the clothes in put the detergent in the top.
Speaker 0: if you fail you pull the clothes out.
Speaker 0: Situation to certain kinds of washers.
Speaker 0: detergent is already leaking out of the clothes.
Speaker 1: detergent is not leaking up.
Speaker 0: It is past the point of no return.
Speaker 0: you son are fucked.
Speaker 1: now the detergent is not on the clothes.
Speaker 0: I did that once not that long ago.
Speaker 1: So anyway I Know.
Speaker 1: I go again and I go to the second washer which looks like it which the screen was on.
Speaker 1: it was looking normal.
Speaker 1: I put a quarter and nothing happens.
Speaker 1: Like how could both washers be broken?
Speaker 1: so I called the super today, and he said he was gonna fix the why.
Speaker 1: you know Some of the guy was coming to fix the washers today, so I'll do laundry when I get home tonight, but Here's the thing that happened.
Speaker 1: all right I bring the baskets back upstairs, and I just put them on the floor.
Speaker 1: cuz I'm gonna drag them back downstairs You know as soon as they're fixed or maybe to a laundry batter who knows usually I'll just leave my stuff down in the laundry room.
Speaker 0: if like all the washers are all being used yeah There's only two in my you know.
Speaker 1: so I bring it back upstairs anyway.
Speaker 1: You know I go to live in bed.
Speaker 1: I'm reading some stuff.
Speaker 1: You know I get up.
Speaker 1: I go to the bathroom, and I notice that the The detergent bottle is upside out in the laundry basket, so I'm like oh, I better turn it upside right.
Speaker 1: you know It was not a complete disaster.
Speaker 1: Cuz it is a big thing of detergent.
Speaker 1: if the whole thing were to spill out.
Speaker 1: It would be doom.
Speaker 0: What's tough is what are you gonna clean that up with?
Speaker 0: I mean water?
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was basically like it was in the basket.
Speaker 0: I spilled a bit of detergent in the trunk of that Sun fire I used to have.
Speaker 0: it was there until the day I got rid of that car.
Speaker 1: It is basically a millimeter You know detergent.
Speaker 1: It was only a little bit like less than a cup.
Speaker 1: You know, but you know I I basically had to take all the clothes that got detergent on them out.
Speaker 1: I put them in this I cleaned out the kitchen sink And then I pretty much watered them in the kitchen sink until they were detergent bliss.
Speaker 0: I don't know if we've just been doing gig nights so long that it's just like a job or what but That was perhaps the most mundane Anecdote we have ever had on this show.
Speaker 1: What's Monday?
Speaker 1: Hey?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was trying to do Detergent spilled.
Speaker 1: it was crazy.
Speaker 0: usually we got things like and it exploded or a hobo came in.
Speaker 1: there was a hobo hanging out Hung up my show about living in the washer.
Speaker 1: I hung them all up to dry in the in the bathroom And then I put the laundry basket in the sink to clean the detergent out of it.
Speaker 1: Still going yeah, and now I got to go home and see what the situation is.
Speaker 1: Alright, I might be up like all night doing laundry.
Speaker 0: I feel like now I got at least.
Speaker 0: so I'll pull this out of the kinetic on show on Thursday.
Speaker 0: I got an anecdote from kinetic on.
Speaker 0: hopefully we'll bring this back.
Speaker 0: laundry related not at all.
Speaker 0: So we had stuff scheduled right and we had a little half-hour looking for game workshop which was scheduled over in these workshop rooms and You know our friend like Wyatt and much of the game masters and all these people are gonna go over there and tell people like Hey, if you want to play a game play Puerto Rico or burning wheel.
Speaker 0: Hey, you know that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: So I'm really tired.
Speaker 0: I'm kind of dazed.
Speaker 0: It's I'm wrecked from the whole con.
Speaker 0: I walk into a panel room.
Speaker 0: a panels about to start in a half-hour but it is currently the time when they're looking for game panel is starting in another room as There's all these people in this room and I look at him.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh You're here for the looking for game panel, right and no one says anything.
Speaker 0: I'll just kind of look at me.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, oh well, sorry.
Speaker 0: No one's here.
Speaker 0: Give me a second.
Speaker 0: I come back in
Speaker 1: and for
Speaker 0: a half hour I run this panel and like hey if you look at I just ran it Myself, you know covering at no point in my tirade Did anyone have the courtesy to tell me that no they were in fact waiting for a completely different panel and that I was in fact in the wrong room
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I Did actually bunch of them said they're gonna go play these games.
Speaker 0: but So what were you in the wrong room, yeah, I was in the wrong room.
Speaker 0: I was in panel five and I should have been in workshop one Workshop one or two or whatever was handled by Wyatt as he should have handled it.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh I was gonna have props to Wyatt because I gave him that stupid radio like the con radio For like three hours on Saturday right as a million people were calling for rim.
Speaker 0: Yeah Whatever I was like Wyatt everyone's asking for me pretend you're me and sort it out.
Speaker 0: then I disappeared.
Speaker 0: Okay game night Tuesday night Scott's a little.
Speaker 0: uh, I don't know I'm tired but Blair Why is it Blair?
Speaker 1: Cuz I was trying to do my laundry and go to bed But then I had to wash a bunch of clothes in the sink.
Speaker 0: How long could that possibly have taken?
Speaker 1: it took a while dirt.
Speaker 1: it doesn't come out easy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it takes a lot of water.
Speaker 0: so you got any gaming news, I don't know.
Speaker 1: There's no gaming news But I do there is some gaming news.
Speaker 0: Pax West.
Speaker 0: Pax Prime is pretty much gonna be sold out any minute.
Speaker 0: So if you haven't bought your passes and you want to go why probably too late?
Speaker 1: Why didn't you buy the pass when they originally went on sale also?
Speaker 0: I'll point out if you bought your passes, but you haven't like done your travel arrangements yet.
Speaker 0: It's about the time when like doing flight arrangements around now is not so bad like that.
Speaker 0: That's perfectly reasonable.
Speaker 0: There's only one hotel left.
Speaker 0: cuz I just logged in to change something to my hotel reservation and there's one hotel left.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know why people wait so long.
Speaker 1: It's like it's a. you know, it's.
Speaker 1: so it's.
Speaker 1: it's what?
Speaker 1: two months or now Less than two months, right?
Speaker 1: This like, you know when they announce the dates for the convention?
Speaker 0: That's the day now like only if the hotel blocks are set up.
Speaker 1: you want but I'm just saying you buy the badge at least Right, you don't don't wait if you decided to go Decide to go and go.
Speaker 0: a lot of people don't actually decide to go until later.
Speaker 1: or they say you don't decide Yes, right away.
Speaker 1: The answer is no no.
Speaker 0: or they say I will go but and then there's some sort of Precondition that they can't decide.
Speaker 1: right if you have a precondition the answer is no you're not going to make it someone else is gonna make.
Speaker 0: what it really comes down to is and What I'm about to say all of you out there could easily just come back and say no room.
Speaker 0: This is just because you have a ton of money.
Speaker 0: A lot of people don't have the money to pre-register right away.
Speaker 0: What's the one kid in the forum?
Speaker 0: He was like, yeah, I don't get paid until Thursday.
Speaker 1: Oh crap Why don't you have a credit card?
Speaker 0: Not get into that.
Speaker 0: a lot of people just reading kind of the Otacon forms and everything They do like.
Speaker 0: their primary concern is they don't have enough money to actually get the badge Early enough if you don't have up if you don't have that much money don't go.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: No, that's not it.
Speaker 0: You do have that much money because I used to be so poor I couldn't even really afford to eat an anime conventions and I and I with no money and basically nothing to my name Because I wanted it.
Speaker 0: I got that money for the Otacon badge.
Speaker 0: somehow Somehow man, I actually didn't pay rent that month.
Speaker 0: Literally, I didn't pay rent and I had money to go to Otacon as a result.
Speaker 1: The point is is that if you know don't listen to rim, right?
Speaker 1: You just listen to me the reasonable first university if you are if you're in a situation Where like 50 bucks which is usually like, you know, a pretty high price for a con badge Usually if you order them early enough, it's 30 40 ish, right?
Speaker 1: If 50 bucks is like an amount of money that you have to like, you know, tear yourself over like you're not confident.
Speaker 1: You know, you don't just have 50 bucks.
Speaker 1: You probably shouldn't be spending your money on a convention.
Speaker 1: That's probably an irresponsible This thing to do.
Speaker 1: you should probably be using your money for food and rent Being you know several hundred dollars.
Speaker 0: But remember the old days when we were poor all like, you know people in the crew were various levels of porn.
Speaker 0: Is we'd go to Otacon and I remember we calculated if you stay in the Renaissance eight people can sleep in each room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's pretty cheap to go to a con if you crime eight people in and you basically eat nothing but garbage for the entire Weekend.
Speaker 1: the point is is that if you know if 50 bucks is is tight for you Conventions are not the thing you should be doing unless it happens to be like in your town or something like that.
Speaker 0: You know see I still say 50 bucks.
Speaker 0: You should forego more important things and go to the con if you want it.
Speaker 0: that badly.
Speaker 0: I wanted Otacon more than I wanted to continue to have an apartment.
Speaker 1: Eating well is and you know sleeping in a comfortable warm sheltered place is more important than going to a convention of which there Will be one for every year the rest of your life.
Speaker 0: So Scott if you had to face some some sort of small period of homelessness at some point in your past But as a result would have had gone to all the paxes as opposed to just the ones we went to What if you would have had even homeless for a month while you're at RIT and then for that?
Speaker 0: You went to every pax up to that point.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: No, I would not be homeless now.
Speaker 0: No, why not understand someone's couch?
Speaker 1: Oh I was talking about sleeping out in the woods.
Speaker 0: That's more my side of the mountain Or Sleeping on the street.
Speaker 1: I mean if I'm on someone's couch and not really homeless Emma.
Speaker 0: So no gaming news.
Speaker 0: you got nothing.
Speaker 1: No, I have a non gaming news.
Speaker 1: It is a huge news.
Speaker 1: You ready for this?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I I don't know why you didn't think this is your news.
Speaker 1: You obviously probably didn't go and look at any headlines.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I know a lot about news.
Speaker 0: You know part of my job is to know what's going on.
Speaker 1: All right This is a huge news because this is this is almost the level of partying news.
Speaker 1: It is almost level of DMCA struck down parting news.
Speaker 1: It is like one.
Speaker 0: Oh, you're talking about the FCC is one level under that news.
Speaker 0: You're talking about Massachusetts and the FCC thing.
Speaker 1: FCC indecency rules struck down by appeals court.
Speaker 0: How about which?
Speaker 0: which courts got?
Speaker 0: is it my man?
Speaker 1: Let us go and see what.
Speaker 0: why is it the Ninth Circuit Court?
Speaker 1: Oh the Ninth Circuit Court actually did a dick move the other did the dick move on the on the first sale, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm not talking about that.
Speaker 1: No, I don't.
Speaker 1: it doesn't say let's see US Circuit Court Judge Rosemary Pooler, I don't know who that is.
Speaker 1: I don't know who that is either she but I know that she's a US Circuit Judge.
Speaker 0: I remember it slashed out actually that an article that talked about that and the Massachusetts law that basically says Anything that could be harmful to minors and this vague description of it can't be on the internet if minors could ever see it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm well, anyway, basically They said hey, look, this is so vague, right?
Speaker 1: The big problem with it was the vagueness, right?
Speaker 0: Okay, so it's okay to do this but 75% or more of a nipple from a front on to 30-degree angle that we need.
Speaker 0: we need laws like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, so basically they were like look this is too vague side nipples.
Speaker 1: It has a. it is a let's see ruling that the policy was quote Unconstitutionally vague and created a quote chilling effect.
Speaker 0: Well, fuck chilling effect.
Speaker 1: I'm constantly vague.
Speaker 1: Get it out of here now, can we please get some other thing now, you know, this is great.
Speaker 1: I mean, how often is it that we actually get rid of one of these shitty laws?
Speaker 0: Well, well, well, it's gonna.
Speaker 1: well It's not even.
Speaker 1: it's not even a law.
Speaker 1: It's it's a. it's a regulation.
Speaker 1: It's gonna get appealed Of course, of course, but this was an appeal.
Speaker 1: So we'll see what they said.
Speaker 1: they said they they felt confident.
Speaker 1: the Supreme Court would you know?
Speaker 0: I'm confident.
Speaker 0: the Supreme Court is going to do whatever causes the least change.
Speaker 0: The Supreme Court has really been balls-less for the last like 15 years.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty sad.
Speaker 1: It's like whenever anything if you look like lately whenever anything goes to the Supreme Court They'll basically like here's an opportunity to make a big, you know to make a big ruling that will set a good precedent.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do as little as possible.
Speaker 1: You know, there'd be a case about like, you know that some guy with like Miranda rights or whatever and they'll be like, yeah He's guilty.
Speaker 0: Okay, where's John Marshall when we need him?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I would give anything to bring John Marshall back from the dead and just throw him in the court me like hey fix everything He's dead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we gotta get him back somehow.
Speaker 1: Well, we should just have John Marshall the second right.
Speaker 0: So I was hanging out in the.
Speaker 0: I guess we should.
Speaker 0: we'll have to hold out and see what happens with this because if it Makes it all the way and we win.
Speaker 0: I think it deserves an entire show the whole show.
Speaker 1: I think so The show will just be vuvuzela's and me going Your mom Hopefully, I mean, I hope this means that we can like they'll be swearing on TV tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Right, it's our park gonna say fuck in the next episode.
Speaker 0: I mean that Park isn't going on even right now I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's been an episode since the whole Muhammad thing.
Speaker 1: How did a?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: by the way, if you guys didn't realize the the little geek nights guy, you know our logo.
Speaker 0: He is actually a depiction of the Prophet Muhammad of the Islam faith.
Speaker 1: You Just decided that right now.
Speaker 0: so I was in the the panel ops room.
Speaker 0: well, really the con ops room of kinetic on right and Scott was up dealing with some crisis and I'm working on something.
Speaker 0: and One of the ops people who's like monitoring all the computers.
Speaker 0: He's also got Firefox open because there's not you know fires to put out all the time.
Speaker 0: He says, huh?
Speaker 0: Civ 5 deluxe box a hundred bucks and they're like eight staffers in the room.
Speaker 0: We all same Simultaneously say shit.
Speaker 0: I already pre-ordered And then we all walk over and see and yeah sure enough There's a hundred dollar like Civ 5 awesome box and I didn't think I'd want it.
Speaker 0: But now that I'm looking at a picture of it this art deco kind of like aesthetic that it's got going I don't.
Speaker 1: I don't see this on steam.
Speaker 0: It's it's not on steam as far as I can tell not yet I don't even know if it's available to purchase.
Speaker 1: Well, if it's not the steam one, why do I want it?
Speaker 0: Basically, it's $100 and It comes with a big art book like a hardcover art book five pewter or some sort of metal like casts of Military units from the game and the soundtrack and I think that's all it up.
Speaker 0: I think there's a DVD behind-the-scenes thing too, and that's it All right big deal and it cost double.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not worth it.
Speaker 1: I just want the game is the same, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, the game is the same.
Speaker 0: So what would have made the hundred dollar bonus pack worth it?
Speaker 0: You also get civilization six I don't know.
Speaker 0: I just want a wall size poster of Washington from the art in the game.
Speaker 1: Just print one out Wall size.
Speaker 0: I need a high-resolution copy.
Speaker 1: go down to any of those printing guys in the city.
Speaker 0: No, I need a high-resolution master or you can't just blow stuff up Scott You can just get it right out of the game Depends on how high-resolution it is.
Speaker 1: usually like civilization.
Speaker 1: Actually, the games have a tendency like the game itself obviously is an open source But usually like all this like the resources in the game.
Speaker 1: I'll be like odd audio or Python, you know Six foot tall poster, right?
Speaker 1: So you would get the 3d model out of the game Which would probably.
Speaker 1: you could probably load it into something and then you know, just render it out.
Speaker 0: It's hard to say.
Speaker 1: It is hard to say.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but maybe if it imagine if it came with a six-foot poster of Like your choice five of the leaders from the game.
Speaker 0: I just love that Washington so much.
Speaker 0: I want him to tuck me in at night.
Speaker 0: I want him like glaring at me while I'm asleep keeping the British away.
Speaker 0: So things of the day I'll often cop out with the College Humor because they're you know Pretty much it's a. there's always something worth seeing every day on the College Humor videos But that's kind of lame, but you know smart listeners know to just go to College Humor and watch that stuff.
Speaker 0: So yeah, and I did.
Speaker 0: the secret secret is that when I need something on a cop-out I just go to BB spot because no one goes to.
Speaker 0: because he goes the old websites of a decade ago like Slashdot and BB spot and me because no one goes there and BB spot like within a given week There'll be one thing on BB spot.
Speaker 0: That wasn't everywhere else.
Speaker 1: I can't believe the site still updates.
Speaker 0: I know what kind of traffic who goes to BB spot you do, you know, it doesn't update me.
Speaker 0: pool Yeah, people's been definitely what I like to mean pool back in the day It was kind of a weird and eclectic thing, but I think that whole idea is obsolete.
Speaker 0: But anyway This is a is an odyssey through what happens when you look something up on Wikipedia and You start following the links on Wikipedia to other links.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna tell you a short story.
Speaker 0: It's the the melancholy of Peter Puck.
Speaker 0: Okay, you know who Peter Puck is?
Speaker 1: His last name is Puck.
Speaker 1: That's pretty.
Speaker 0: no his last name is not Puck.
Speaker 0: His name is Peter Pocklington, okay, so I'll preface this by saying there's only one person one name on The Stanley Cup, you know Lord Stanley's Cup that was after the fact X'd out.
Speaker 0: there are X's engraved over.
Speaker 1: why don't they just?
Speaker 1: why don't they just sort of you know smooth it?
Speaker 0: I really can't do that.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: I don't want to get into the details.
Speaker 0: They can't do that.
Speaker 1: Well, you may get some heat and you melt this little bit of silver.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're ruining the Stanley Cup and then you polish it and you know get some sanding in there.
Speaker 0: You know anything about silversmithing buffing Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: Now it's engraved pretty deeply.
Speaker 0: Have you seen the Stanley Cup?
Speaker 1: Give me a Dremel.
Speaker 1: I'll take it out.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, there is an X engraved into every single letter of one and only one name.
Speaker 1: So they put an X over each letter instead of just a line through the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Yes, they really wanted to get rid of it.
Speaker 0: Okay, and There are like 12 or 13 other like tiny typos all over it.
Speaker 0: There's a whole history of like all the different things.
Speaker 1: They just fucking fix it.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't make a mistake in the first play.
Speaker 0: well There's.
Speaker 0: it's not easy to get rid of these mistakes and also since they've been there and since the replicas are replicas of it You know, it's like kind of like the history like this is this mistake.
Speaker 0: This is when this happened.
Speaker 1: This is this guy and I'm sure if a guy makes a mistake to get a new fucking jeweler I mean, you know actually there's been a lot of.
Speaker 0: there's whole stories about like how they couldn't afford to get another band Once they filled up the first band back in the day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the story of the Stanley Cup is crazy.
Speaker 1: They have enough money.
Speaker 0: No, they didn't.
Speaker 0: and you know what when there was the strike.
Speaker 0: There's actually a space where they engraved.
Speaker 0: no one won because there was the strike No one played hockey.
Speaker 1: I thought that they just sort of didn't put anything.
Speaker 0: No, there's this hole because they write every time they add.
Speaker 1: if they add a new one they add they write the year on it Right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it should just be like, you know, 2000 whatever and then if it's the there's no.
Speaker 0: actually says You know there was nothing this year like they made a point of being like look you assholes Look what you did.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they cuz remember.
Speaker 0: it's kind of a record.
Speaker 0: It's like an engraving.
Speaker 0: This is the record of the Lords of the realm or at least the Lords of hockey.
Speaker 1: So why doesn't you just have my name every time like you can't even skate.
Speaker 1: I'm the Lord of the realm though.
Speaker 0: So if you look at the names on the Stanley Cup, there is crazy stuff.
Speaker 0: They're like, they're the first woman My name is 8 equals equals equals D. Marguerite Norris was the president of the Detroit Red Wings in 1954 and 1955 and they happen to win the Stanley Cup both those years.
Speaker 0: So she was the first woman to have her name on the Stanley Cup and she got it on there twice.
Speaker 0: One guy has his name on it 17 times.
Speaker 0: Did he win 17 John Beliveau?
Speaker 1: He just kept switching the teams that won.
Speaker 0: no ten is a player and then seven is management Trickery and also a Vladimir Konstantinov also on the Red Wings.
Speaker 0: if you read through a Surprising number of the like weird stories about the Stanley Cup our destroyed Red Wings, you know six and everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean an original six teams are going to have.
Speaker 1: you know the predominant You know coverage on the Stanley Cup because other teams weren't even around on the early rings.
Speaker 0: Yep But well, they're also.
Speaker 0: they're like there's engravings inside the bowl of the original cup because ran out of room and people didn't know what To do.
Speaker 0: one team that won a whole bunch of times never engraved their name on it Konstantinov who was on the Troy Red Wings Red Wings and they won the Stanley Cup after the huge drought in 1997.
Speaker 0: He didn't play the full 40 games because he was horribly crippled in a limousine accident during the season Mm-hmm, but they went on to win and the NHL basically said while he didn't play 40 games He is going to get a special dispensation and his name is on there.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah and brought him out in a wheelchair and he held it up and it was kind of a. it was a really emotional moment For the team.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: But let's talk about Peter puck aka Peter Pocklington.
Speaker 0: Okay, he was basically a colorful popular happy dude.
Speaker 0: What are the wealthiest men in Canada in the 80s?
Speaker 0: like super rich guy in 1982?
Speaker 0: He basically lived through a tiny Canadian version of diehard.
Speaker 0: Him and his wife were kidnapped and held hostage by a man in the gigantic like hostage Ransom scheme.
Speaker 0: All right police raided and saved him and the only person wounded in the raid was him who was shot by the police by Accident.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Was he dead?
Speaker 0: No, he's fine.
Speaker 0: Okay, so Some years later.
Speaker 0: He got some infamy.
Speaker 0: He was the manager of the LA Kings and he said, you know what let's get rid of Wayne Gretzky Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: He was the one who did that.
Speaker 0: Yeah a little while later.
Speaker 0: He owned the Oilers and he kept threatening to sell them to the United States.
Speaker 0: More recently federal marshals invaded his home in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Multiple times.
Speaker 0: He currently has numerous lawsuits against him.
Speaker 0: He seems to owe at least 20 million dollars, but claims.
Speaker 0: He only has three grand to his name.
Speaker 1: He's still alive.
Speaker 0: Okay, right now He's in jail and his bail is set at a million dollars, dude I won a lottery.
Speaker 1: I would get him out of jail just for low.
Speaker 0: So he's a colorful dude and there's this crazy history behind him, you know, big hockey guy big industry guy.
Speaker 0: He was in fact in charge of gainers food during the gainers union issues.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: You know the gainers strike?
Speaker 0: No, you have no idea about that.
Speaker 0: No clue.
Speaker 0: It was a pretty important labor prop.
Speaker 0: Basically.
Speaker 0: He was on the bad team.
Speaker 0: Okay, but all this aside Peter Pocklington's name is not on Lord Stanley's Cup.
Speaker 0: His father's name basil Pocklington Mysteriously appeared on the Stanley Cup.
Speaker 0: How good it when he you know, his name was supposed to.
Speaker 0: you know He was supposed to go in the cup and he submitted the list.
Speaker 0: Well, so he was the manager of a team and the team submitted the list And he just put his dad's name in with all the players and no one noticed.
Speaker 0: and it was there.
Speaker 0: When the NHL find I found out they were like, ah, no, no, no, no, no, no exes exes for you.
Speaker 1: So wait, so they caught it before.
Speaker 1: it's the way they.
Speaker 1: they caught it when it was already engraved.
Speaker 0: It was done.
Speaker 0: So they went back and they engraved exes into every letter of basil Pocklington's name.
Speaker 0: He's the only person ever redacted from the Stanley Cup.
Speaker 1: So then his name was Peter Pocklington.
Speaker 1: Yes He never got his name on.
Speaker 0: no, he was just.
Speaker 0: he was the one who tricked any lie.
Speaker 0: He was like, I don't know how my dad's name got on the list.
Speaker 0: The engraver must have made a mistake.
Speaker 1: So they just never.
Speaker 1: so he's got his dad's name on there.
Speaker 1: His dad's name got ex off, but then they didn't put his name on there either.
Speaker 0: His name's on there.
Speaker 1: Oh, is it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay He should have been on there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you don't want you don't want him on there.
Speaker 1: I figured they could have kept him off cuz he was a jerk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but he's also beloved at least according to Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Right Beloved by who?
Speaker 0: jerks I guess Edmonton.
Speaker 1: This is a jerk star called.
Speaker 1: They're all out of Pocklington.
Speaker 1: He's in jail.
Speaker 0: Well, of course, I mean you're the biggest seller.
Speaker 0: So you should check out the Wikipedia article on Lord Stanley's Cup and That is my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: All right My thing today is I didn't expect to be interrupted that many times in the course of this.
Speaker 1: My thing today is perhaps the I don't know the most divisive video ever posted on the Internet's.
Speaker 0: Had a tax kid, but it no.
Speaker 1: but it is so epic.
Speaker 1: Right, they're like, I don't even know what to make of it, but it's got eight and a half million views on YouTube.
Speaker 1: I think it needs Yakujo.
Speaker 1: No, I know it doesn't.
Speaker 1: it has 345,000 views.
Speaker 1: it needs eight and a half million views.
Speaker 0: Wait.
Speaker 0: So where did you just make that number up?
Speaker 1: No, I was looking at the wrong video, uh-huh So what video has?
Speaker 0: eight and a half million views.
Speaker 1: just the actual video for I will survive the song.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay, but this is a video.
Speaker 1: obviously using the song I will survive.
Speaker 1: but in the video there is a man his daughter and his three grandchildren and they are dancing and The I will survive.
Speaker 1: song is playing and they dance in front of many locations.
Speaker 1: It's one of those, you know multiple location videos like, you know, when Luke Burge does the juggling in many locations I saw or when the guy was dancing in multiple locations around the world.
Speaker 0: nothing controversial.
Speaker 0: Nothing interesting.
Speaker 1: all of the locations are either Nazi concentration camps or you know memorials or other such places.
Speaker 1: Alright, but the man is a holocaust survivor.
Speaker 1: So it's like whoa, so epic win.
Speaker 0: What else can I say?
Speaker 1: but half the internet is like, I don't know if this is offensive or awesome.
Speaker 1: They can't tell.
Speaker 0: I don't know about half the internet cuz I had no idea this was going on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's pretty much what it is.
Speaker 0: So so apparently 350,000 people have their opinions on this.
Speaker 1: Yeah so there's gonna be.
Speaker 0: Yeah, wait, is it the original song or the cake version?
Speaker 1: No, it's it's the original.
Speaker 0: Okay All right now Scott's playing it.
Speaker 0: So the meta moment.
Speaker 0: if you can tell we're kind of dragging here, you know, we're.
Speaker 0: we just got back from kinetic on.
Speaker 0: We're a little.
Speaker 0: we're a little wrecked.
Speaker 0: I'm still right This is definitely cut one of those crab people shows.
Speaker 0: But the meta moment the book club book is the lies of Locke Lamora, which was also recommended to be ready.
Speaker 0: I think it's Lamora.
Speaker 1: I think it's Lamora.
Speaker 0: I don't Lamora sounds because it flows with the lies of Locke Lamora.
Speaker 1: I think it's lies of like Lamora.
Speaker 1: sound is better.
Speaker 1: I'm better in the mouth.
Speaker 0: It's weird because he doesn't really lie that much except in specific cons.
Speaker 0: He's actually a hundred percent truthful all the rest of the time.
Speaker 1: That's why it's awesome.
Speaker 0: We're going to be at the penny arcade expo Labor Day weekend 2010 in Seattle.
Speaker 0: We cannot announce all of the programming we're doing because it is not better than we can announce any program.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we can't because now we've officially two of our panels are already set.
Speaker 0: We are going to be doing a panel called egregiously unrealized potential Right, which I think you can get.
Speaker 0: that I call that x-rays or the panel.
Speaker 0: Okay, and we're doing game mechanics and mechanism design.
Speaker 0: basically every panel we've done up at this point has in gaming has been kind of a like.
Speaker 0: we talked about some topic and we always come back to like game mechanics and Mechanism design and every time all the feedback we get basically comes down to yep.
Speaker 0: That was awesome.
Speaker 0: But could you go into more detail?
Speaker 0: or we're just gonna go hardcore and see if packs can handle it.
Speaker 1: We'll find out.
Speaker 0: and other programming is of course TBA, but we got one or two more things in the hopper alrighty packs East.
Speaker 0: we're gonna be doing stuff at anime.
Speaker 0: Boston New York Comic Con New York anime festival and the burning wheel.
Speaker 0: 10 10 10 are all on the weekend of October 8th 9th and 10th.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Oh and October 8th is happens to be a nerd NYC board game night.
Speaker 1: Also also this Friday is a nerd NYC board game night.
Speaker 0: July 16th dirt NYC thinks cafe You should totally come check it out.
Speaker 1: Well, I think there's.
Speaker 1: the August is an August and September one, but you can go to the nerd NYC website and find out.
Speaker 1: and On Monday, there's some sort of gaming thing.
Speaker 1: I'm going to it's.
Speaker 1: it's got like the CEO of take two is gonna be there.
Speaker 1: It's on Kotaku.
Speaker 1: Oh, I don't know.
Speaker 1: It seems pretty interesting as ten bucks is downtown.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 1: I Think that's enough meta.
Speaker 0: Yes I think.
Speaker 0: so energy levels are low.
Speaker 0: We got to bring him back up uh-huh, so Why everybody old man attack?
Speaker 1: I am giving the secret but you still try old man attack gonna do a show on high space.
Speaker 1: Oh my gosh.
Speaker 0: I Wonder if it's updated.
Speaker 1: it's it's not updated but it still exists All right.
Speaker 1: This was Scott's idea.
Speaker 1: Oh So you just like I say anything.
Speaker 1: no, no, no, no, no, but basically I was like I went through it.
Speaker 1: I'm like why do we need something to do a show on that?
Speaker 1: We've played and we haven't played anything recently.
Speaker 1: So it's got to be you know, something old.
Speaker 0: I've been playing Counter-Strike almost every day.
Speaker 1: We've done a show on that though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it has to be something we haven't done a show on.
Speaker 1: actually I was playing on militia and I bought a new board game But rim hasn't played II and I only played the solitaire version of it.
Speaker 0: So basically Yahtzee.
Speaker 1: You don't know that you it's good Trust me.
Speaker 0: I know but I read the board game geek reviews and people like yeah, it's Yahtzee.
Speaker 0: Where's then?
Speaker 1: It doesn't wear thin.
Speaker 1: Oh, it was pretty good even by myself.
Speaker 1: It was fun.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 1: anyway the Yah, right.
Speaker 1: So I'm like, hey, what about like the Absolute basics like have we done a show on fucking like, you know, Zelda 1?
Speaker 1: and sure enough We had done a show on four swords and that is it.
Speaker 1: We had never done a show on Zelda 1.
Speaker 0: So what's interesting is that alright finally, you know geek knives We're gonna have this show on the Legend of Zelda straight up and we start talking about the game More than halfway through this show.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 0: I'm surprised you're all even still listening at this point or you're just anticipating.
Speaker 0: you're waiting.
Speaker 0: You want us?
Speaker 0: What are you gonna say?
Speaker 0: get that you get the Triforce?
Speaker 1: So, yeah, you saw that you get it twice.
Speaker 1: Anyway, no, so I got you know.
Speaker 1: thing is Zelda 1 like?
Speaker 1: I still think it is the best Zelda.
Speaker 0: No one else does but I I still think Zelda 2 is well.
Speaker 1: No one agrees.
Speaker 1: even less people agree with you than agree with me.
Speaker 0: Of course They're in different genres like Zelda 1 and Zelda 2 fought like they were.
Speaker 0: they were different Genres from the control and from a lot of aspects, but in many ways They're also the same genre of you know Explore this world get the Triforce pieces or something of that ilk.
Speaker 0: go save the princess in some manner Bosses along the way.
Speaker 1: most people will say that ocarina of time or link to the past is the best one But I think they're almost they're in a different genre.
Speaker 0: They were.
Speaker 0: they opened up this whole different idea of what a Zelda game would be.
Speaker 1: hmm I think that what's makes all the one simultaneously great but also so painful for anyone who's never played it before to play it now is that it really Doesn't give you like the helping hints so much as are you kidding?
Speaker 0: It as a full-color instruction book with a comic in it.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, but I mean most people who play it today are not gonna get those things Right, like when I got Zelda 1. first of all I had some extra knowledge because I had watched other people play on their Nintendo's.
Speaker 1: so I had that hid.
Speaker 1: I had those secrets.
Speaker 0: I started from nothing.
Speaker 1: I also had you know It came with a map of like the beginning area of the game.
Speaker 1: that helped me out a lot.
Speaker 1: it came with you know all this stuff and Came with an instruction book.
Speaker 1: that it all sorts of information.
Speaker 0: You might not recall this but remember the beauty of the Legend of Zelda.
Speaker 0: The map that came in the instruction book showed you where you start and it showed you where level 1 is.
Speaker 1: Right, it even shows you.
Speaker 1: I think we're level 2 and 3 were.
Speaker 0: it shows you where level 2 is But it does not show you how to get to the spot to get into level 2.
Speaker 0: So you have to go around outside of this map.
Speaker 0: They've given you.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I mean check that out.
Speaker 0: That is some good like give the kid a hint but then make oh no No, no, that's the map that's in the book.
Speaker 0: That's what I said.
Speaker 1: Mine I had that - mine came with a separate map that was on its own piece of paper.
Speaker 1: That was quite impressive and it showed you like the location of certain things like the.
Speaker 1: the power bracelet I think was even on that map.
Speaker 1: It was a very high quality map.
Speaker 0: But what people also forget is that if you look at the story in the beginning of the book There is in fact a map of the entire game right there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it is not a Detailed enough map but it is a. it is a high quality map.
Speaker 0: Actually them if you look at it the map is detailed enough to figure out how to get to anywhere in the game Really?
Speaker 0: It even shows you where that secret shit is way off on the right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is right is that if you look at a modern Zelda game say for example Twilight Princess right you get the hookshot.
Speaker 1: every place that you can use the hookshot like clearly has like a hookshot thing.
Speaker 1: It's like here you can hookshot right to this spot.
Speaker 1: It's like they don't make.
Speaker 1: keep any secrets about it.
Speaker 1: You know, it's not like you have to experiment hookshotting.
Speaker 1: You just have to look around and you'll be able to see any hookshot able spots.
Speaker 1: You know It's the same thing with the bow and arrow like.
Speaker 1: there'll be a fucking eyeball if you can shoot it with the bow and arrow.
Speaker 1: In Zelda 1.
Speaker 1: I mean occasionally they might put some cracks in the walls where you could bomb But that they.
Speaker 1: there are plenty of places you could bomb that look just like every other wall.
Speaker 1: They didn't stand out in any way shape or form.
Speaker 0: you don't forget the second quest.
Speaker 0: We could also just walk through certain walls.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you just walk right through the wall.
Speaker 1: So you have to try to walk through every single wall that you come across.
Speaker 1: that isn't already.
Speaker 1: You know that walks into the black part of the map just to make sure that there isn't like a secret room back.
Speaker 0: Well, I think part of it is that the for us at least for the generation that played Zelda 1 There was nothing to compete with it.
Speaker 0: I mean every other game like there was no game.
Speaker 0: There's nothing even close to this and it really you know Even the creator like it was.
Speaker 0: the idea was you're exploring like though like you're in a kit You're a kid in the woods and you're exploring with a ton of free time.
Speaker 1: This
Speaker 0: is a game to explore but while it seems so like opaque and obtuse to a lot of modern gamers This instruction book like you read it and it gives you all these kind of Oblique hints like it doesn't tell you straight up where to find the bosses and all the dungeons But it names all the dungeons and it shows you the shape of like a monster or a thing.
Speaker 0: And if you explore these dungeons you start to realize that they all follow the shapes intuitively.
Speaker 1: yeah, most of the dungeons like the bad guy is in the nose or the eyeball.
Speaker 0: or Do you remember the names of all the dungeons?
Speaker 1: I don't remember the names of the dungeons.
Speaker 1: I could say the names of the bosses all of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right, let's go.
Speaker 1: All right level one Aquamentous.
Speaker 1: quite level two dodongo.
Speaker 1: All right level three.
Speaker 1: Oh god, I know it.
Speaker 0: You're forgetting Mon, Hanla.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Damn it.
Speaker 1: I knew it, but I didn't.
Speaker 1: I didn't know it.
Speaker 1: No anyway Level four is the hydra and his name is Gula.
Speaker 1: Oh glia.
Speaker 1: Yeah level five is dig dagger.
Speaker 1: Yeah level six is gliok with an extra.
Speaker 1: Level seven is Aquamentous again.
Speaker 0: Oh shit level eight.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: No level six I got it wrong.
Speaker 1: level six does have a gliok with an extra head, but the boss is red Goma.
Speaker 1: I was wrong.
Speaker 0: I go.
Speaker 1: level eight also has a gliok with an extra head and his blue Goma.
Speaker 1: and then level nine has Ganon.
Speaker 0: Don't remember the names of dungeons do ya know?
Speaker 1: not at all.
Speaker 0: Eagle moon manji snake lizard dragon demon Lion, and then just death mountain.
Speaker 1: Well, I could have told you death mountain.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but note the death mountain.
Speaker 0: the skull is shaped like the rock that you have to bomb.
Speaker 1: Not really.
Speaker 1: I mean kind of not so much.
Speaker 0: I'm on the instruction book and All these little hints that some of them weren't even relevant to us as kids.
Speaker 0: like Paul's voice it says in this instruction book a ghost With big ears and a weak point.
Speaker 0: He hates loud noise and I remember as a kid There's a million of them in the room try to whistle.
Speaker 0: I tried the whistle and do anything and the sword didn't hurt him.
Speaker 1: But the arrows hurt him just fine because the Famicom had microphones in the controller Yeah, but the NES did not and they didn't change it.
Speaker 1: So yeah, you would shoot the arrow and it would.
Speaker 1: that was the way to kill him.
Speaker 0: But there's so many just like hints and things to where a kid, you know You read this book and puzzle over it and the book was really part of the game And a lot of people kind of forget the instruction book.
Speaker 0: This game was sort of a puzzle and the book and the game together Guided a young kid's mind through this exploration.
Speaker 1: I think that what really makes the game is just that you know when you're still Discovering it when you're still a kid and you've never played it before and you don't know the map.
Speaker 1: Everything just feels so mystical.
Speaker 1: It's like oh my god the graveyard.
Speaker 1: Holy shit.
Speaker 1: There's a fucking oh my god.
Speaker 1: Look at this and it's all like woo the graveyard.
Speaker 0: That whole upper left area of the map scares me to this day a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know you shouldn't be up there.
Speaker 0: There's nothing over there.
Speaker 1: It's like you uncover all these things and it's so like it just has this feel to it Like you're.
Speaker 1: you have uncovered something mystical.
Speaker 1: I don't know what it is, but it just did.
Speaker 1: no other game has really pulled that off so much You know.
Speaker 1: I think it's a combination of like just the way The areas are presented to you and the way you're well Very like.
Speaker 0: every region kind of has this feeling.
Speaker 0: every dungeon has its own like aesthetic to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's like there's no one.
Speaker 1: there's no one really out there.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's like you can talk to people But you know old man and old woman, but that's pretty much it and they don't really help you that much.
Speaker 1: They're.
Speaker 1: so, you know, they speak in sort of rhymes and stuff.
Speaker 1: It's almost like a more like a labyrinth II kind of thing than a Metroid kind of thing, you know, I'll buy something.
Speaker 0: Will ya?
Speaker 1: All right, that's not old man or old woman.
Speaker 1: That's fat guy merchant fat merchant Yeah, and then it's like you.
Speaker 1: just you sort of like discover these things that like the game didn't tell you about them But you discover them on your own.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like you just find this power bracelet out there.
Speaker 1: It's like oh shit power brace.
Speaker 0: Let's remember there's never again.
Speaker 1: You find like the secret shortcuts under the rocks.
Speaker 1: It's like oh shit.
Speaker 1: The game didn't tell me about this.
Speaker 0: You just discovered the whole game.
Speaker 0: You're playing around keep seeing these like docks and you try to walk on them and nothing happens.
Speaker 0: And then later in the game you find a raft and you run around all these docks and there's crazy shit out there.
Speaker 1: Like you go to the east and there's just a hard container sitting out there.
Speaker 0: It's like whoa, you're looking at you're trying to hit it with the boomerang.
Speaker 1: Yeah And it's just crazy stuff.
Speaker 1: and like you can just walk through walls and there's a hundred coins and all these.
Speaker 1: There's just so many things in the game that you'll stumble across that the game didn't tell you about.
Speaker 1: So you feel like you really discovered something?
Speaker 1: It's not like Metroid where you found a secret that you sort of had to find or they there's like, you know Basically big glaring shiny things that say secret here.
Speaker 1: You need an item to get it.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like you actually discovering like these completely hidden things.
Speaker 1: It's like the same kind of feeling you get if you get the minus world and Mario Brothers.
Speaker 1: It's like that's the feeling you get all over Zelda 1 no matter where you are.
Speaker 1: It's like you get a red ring.
Speaker 1: They didn't even tell you there was a fucking red ring, but you get it and you turn red.
Speaker 1: It's like holy shit.
Speaker 1: He turned red and now things barely hurt.
Speaker 0: me though little known secret.
Speaker 0: you get the red ring And that's why Zelda has a red dress on.
Speaker 0: she'll be whatever color your ring is.
Speaker 1: Yep Well, whatever color link is she'll match you right because there's only so many.
Speaker 0: you must have a green ring on.
Speaker 0: There's only have a red sword.
Speaker 1: There's only so many colors in the in the palette, you know, it's kind of had an argument.
Speaker 0: this is one of the epic arguments of the front row crew hanging out in colony back at RIT and You swore it was the wooden sword.
Speaker 0: I did and I knew it was the red sword.
Speaker 0: No, you didn't and we argued forever.
Speaker 0: and finally I realized no we're arguing the whole front row crews there Yelling and we're kind of splitting the two camps red sword versus wood sword.
Speaker 0: And finally, I remembered that I had the instruction book and I got it and I opened up to the page.
Speaker 1: Could I just check the internet - and uh back then?
Speaker 0: Yeah as we could have I think we poked around.
Speaker 0: We didn't see anything obvious.
Speaker 0: Thanks.
Speaker 0: We didn't trust the game facts.
Speaker 0: We needed like a definitive source.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm And it's not the master sword.
Speaker 0: It's the magical sword.
Speaker 1: I knew that Yep, and then the white sword which is just the white sword is basically the master.
Speaker 0: So and then it's just sword.
Speaker 1: Well, it's sword white sword magical.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I've never.
Speaker 1: that was one of the most anticlimactic moments of my life You know, what always bothered me is how the magic sword It always it looked like a diagonal kind of thing right in the picture up top.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but when you actually used it in game, it just stab straight.
Speaker 1: It didn't stab in any particular, you know, it wasn't diagonal like it was.
Speaker 1: it was.
Speaker 0: it was longer Made it look cool and mystical.
Speaker 1: I don't know whatever it was weird but yeah Zelda 1 is is totally sweet.
Speaker 1: and then it has a fucking second quest that the game doesn't tell you about and where everything is Totally fucked up and even more mystical.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: The second quest is actually really fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I got about One tenth of the way through Zelda see before I gave up.
Speaker 1: Oh fuck Zelda.
Speaker 1: see, you know I never beat the second question.
Speaker 1: I was a kid because we could never find level 8 and You know what.
Speaker 0: now I wrote a letter to Nintendo power.
Speaker 1: Now that I know we're level 8 in the second quest is it's bullshit?
Speaker 0: I beat the second quest legitimately.
Speaker 0: The only thing that I didn't figure out was I actually couldn't find the fucking silver arrows in death mountain Really?
Speaker 0: So I sent a letter to Nintendo power.
Speaker 1: Did you find level 8?
Speaker 1: level 8 is like there's no way you could find Nerd, I'd spent a lot of time playing.
Speaker 1: There was no way.
Speaker 1: level 8 is just oh my gosh The scariest.
Speaker 1: I found level 9 but I couldn't get in cuz I didn't have the fragment from level 8.
Speaker 0: You'd be easy to find later dungeons and hard to find earlier dungeons.
Speaker 0: You go into later dungeons whiz robes ever that everywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: Oh good But you go into a dungeon just like 10 mummies and you don't have anything.
Speaker 1: give dough to stab gibdo like 20 times.
Speaker 0: I always loved the gibdo who's got the key and him.
Speaker 0: you're like, all right, but the bombs in him Yeah, suicide bombing mommy gibdo except he didn't light it.
Speaker 1: I know you put him in.
Speaker 0: he wrapped up.
Speaker 1: She should have lit it and jumped and just followed you.
Speaker 1: really if any bad guy actually good AI and followed you and had a Bomb in them watch out.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: some of the the Knights were.
Speaker 0: the dark nights were a little hard to get.
Speaker 0: The whistle felt so like powerful and the magic wand like.
Speaker 0: I was so crazy excited to get it till I realized it was basically Just a white sword.
Speaker 0: Well, no what the magical wand allows you to do is a white sword And once you get the book it says the fire.
Speaker 1: that's right It sets fire but it's like you won't use yours.
Speaker 1: if you wanted projectiles without having to be fightful health Yeah, if these arrows which cost money, but if you have the magic wand, you can have a projectile at any time.
Speaker 0: It's only a white sword projectile.
Speaker 1: That's true But it doesn't matter because you know It's still a projectile when you don't have full health and doesn't cost money like the arrow does.
Speaker 1: So that's a good deal.
Speaker 0: I just always laugh as a kid about pee hats.
Speaker 1: You know painting for the door charge Laughed at that.
Speaker 1: painting for the door pair.
Speaker 0: Don't laugh at that cuz you're a kid.
Speaker 0: I got my like 300 rupees.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna buy that white ringer in the white ring the blue ring that door charge.
Speaker 1: I swear to God know cuz he had a system as soon as you had enough for the blue ring you buy it.
Speaker 1: You don't stop anywhere cuz you know, the door charge might be lurking.
Speaker 0: I didn't know I'd never run into it.
Speaker 0: Think about it.
Speaker 0: You don't know.
Speaker 0: there's no way for you to know if you've never found it.
Speaker 1: I guess there was a time when I got fucked by it.
Speaker 1: But you know what?
Speaker 1: You can just push the reset button and you go back to you save and you're good now.
Speaker 0: now you don't do that.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: you don't do that?
Speaker 1: You got to do that especially in a game that's a jerk like this.
Speaker 1: if you don't know what you're doing I mean you got to use every advantage you can get to uncover the secrets.
Speaker 0: I do feel like they're.
Speaker 0: you know Flipping through this instruction book that I'm holding my hands yet again.
Speaker 0: Anyone who's gonna play Zelda 1 today read the instruction book like literally read every.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean you don't want to use game facts because that ruins all the mystical parts because you basically know you would already know Everything and I guess you kind of don't want to spend time burning every bush like I did.
Speaker 0: But I guess you don't need to burn every bush because you can.
Speaker 0: that the bushes that have stuff that really matters They're the bushes that are kind of standing out like a sore thumb.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like oh I went on this screen and there's a bunch of bushes and there's one bush out on its own.
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 1: And make sure you get the red candle so you can actually burn that's way later in the game and I don't wanted money now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well the if you use the blue candle you're gonna be walking back and forth.
Speaker 1: burn a bush didn't do anything.
Speaker 1: leave the screen Come back burn a bush.
Speaker 0: It was worth it.
Speaker 0: I found that money.
Speaker 1: Yeah But yeah, you gotta.
Speaker 1: you gotta have at least some hints which are the hints that the book provides for you.
Speaker 1: You know the beginning map area location of level one, right.
Speaker 1: without that you're and you just try to play from nothing.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be pretty impossible and frustrating.
Speaker 0: but if you have the book I mean the one thing I will say is as a kid I beat this game Like not that without that man.
Speaker 1: when I beat this game was so epic Like I had some friends were over and they were watching and the first time I beat it I thought that you had to use the silver arrow only.
Speaker 1: so I beat Gannon using only silver arrow.
Speaker 0: and no so really I did The same thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then later it was like no dude, you can just use sword You only to use silver arrow after he turns red Spoiler.
Speaker 0: I guess I don't think there's spoilers for that.
Speaker 1: You don't think so.
Speaker 1: Nah, I wonder is Gannon any harder in the second quest?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I got the once I got the silver arrows.
Speaker 0: The only thing that really Gannon was a lot easier.
Speaker 0: those fucking petros all over death mountain petros are easy, dude Not in the second quest.
Speaker 0: other different their heart.
Speaker 0: They take more hits.
Speaker 1: Oh fucker.
Speaker 0: Yeah Plus petro with wiz robes in the room.
Speaker 0: Oh god, fuck that blue ones.
Speaker 1: Oh Nothing's harder than blue wiz robe.
Speaker 0: fucking blue wiz robe.
Speaker 1: I mean people are complaining about like blue night.
Speaker 1: You can be blue night with friggin magic sword and bomb.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: I remember you can get into like the back way of the later dungeon to get the book But I would always bust into like a later dungeon to get the magic key and I'd go in there with like a white sword Maybe not even the white sword and just like try desperately to get through the game to get the magic key Never to deal with bullshit getting keys for the whole rest of the game.
Speaker 1: I like how like there are things that are not, you know, they're optional items, you know.
Speaker 1: It's not like you need to get the item to beat the level.
Speaker 1: nowadays right the way the Zelda games are structured It's like you got to get the item and without that item There is no way you can get the big key and you need the big key to go to the boss in the old Zelda's like you just go straight to the boss Kill him with the red sword, you know kill him with the arrow, you know You don't.
Speaker 1: even you could do the the sword list.
Speaker 0: I kill a lot of the Knights with bombs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right.
Speaker 1: It's like you can just do your own thing.
Speaker 1: You don't need to get the items.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know like you need the raft you need the ladder to get to some you could.
Speaker 1: you could neglect to get the bow in level one.
Speaker 1: Go all the way to the end of the game get the silver arrow go to Ganon and then be unable to kill him Because you don't you cannot have the bow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't need the magic boomerang.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I love that magic.
Speaker 1: You don't need the regular boomerang.
Speaker 1: You can just skip it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the only things that you need to the compasses in the maps and the letter to the little old lady Yeah, it actually says letter to little old lady.
Speaker 1: in the book you could you could basically Ignore.
Speaker 1: like the vast majority of the game all you need to do to actually make it through the game is kill the bosses somehow with bomb, you know with something see or well, and you get the Triforce pieces behind them and That's it.
Speaker 0: I mean, well, I mean I bet you'd like to carry more bombs.
Speaker 1: I bet you would.
Speaker 0: you're gonna give up a heart container.
Speaker 1: No, that's that man.
Speaker 1: Take anyone.
Speaker 1: you want red potion heart container.
Speaker 1: I mean seriously Seriously, what kid?
Speaker 0: I watched my friend Joe fucking Ogilvy take the red boat.
Speaker 0: He took the red potion.
Speaker 1: just punch him in the face.
Speaker 0: I was like what is wrong with you?
Speaker 0: He's like red potion takes a lot of money.
Speaker 0: and I was like I was like.
Speaker 0: you realize there's no other way to get that heart container ever.
Speaker 0: You just fucked it.
Speaker 0: I Don't think I said fucked it.
Speaker 1: He's obviously that person is not going far in life.
Speaker 0: I don't know what I knew him when I was in like.
Speaker 1: he's working a gas station.
Speaker 0: That's why I went to Catholic school.
Speaker 0: We lived in downtown Detroit.
Speaker 1: people with full heart containers get get salaried real jobs.
Speaker 0: I Would often beat the game without full heart containers.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I guess early on, you know.
Speaker 1: But now I know where they're all are.
Speaker 0: So Would you play Zelda like?
Speaker 0: do you feel like you should play Zelda 1 again?
Speaker 0: Like now?
Speaker 1: I've played it recently How recently pretty reason.
Speaker 1: less than a year ago.
Speaker 0: I burned through Zelda 2 not that long ago.
Speaker 0: I burned through Zelda 3 recently.
Speaker 1: Zelda 2 is a little more painful.
Speaker 0: I like Zelda 2 a lot.
Speaker 1: You're the only one good game.
Speaker 1: It's all that he sucks But it doesn't suck.
Speaker 1: but it's you know one thing so much more painful than any of the others one thing Zelda 1 Does not have.
Speaker 0: that is good that Zelda 2 has The epic the single epic journey to get that motherfucking hammer good.
Speaker 0: Just the feeling everyone every kid I knew Like everyone had gotten to the point of I gotta go get the hammer and no one could get it.
Speaker 0: Do you believe tonight?
Speaker 0: I got a plan.
Speaker 0: I think I know where the hammer is.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna try and get it.
Speaker 0: There was no game facts back then.
Speaker 1: No You need you need a little map to get through all those caves and every cave you go in.
Speaker 1: that's unnecessary Cost you health and you got to use the magic and no kid was gonna tell anyone else the pads He'd found.
Speaker 0: that got him closer to the hammer because he wanted to get it before everybody else got it.
Speaker 1: Yep And the thing is the thing that always hurt me is I would.
Speaker 1: I played these Zelda games at other people's systems with other people's Carches before I played them on my own system.
Speaker 1: So what happened was I would I would always like have the hammer already or have stuff already and I wouldn't really know You know where to go or what to do next because I was in the middle of someone else's game And it wasn't until I got them on my own that I really knew what was going on.
Speaker 1: I mean the game even had a mystical quality in the gold cartridge, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, there were only two gold cartridges and one silver cartridge.
Speaker 0: Zelda and Zelda 2 were the gold ones.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like no other game had that.
Speaker 1: so it's like it felt like some sort of magical and special game and it kind of was Probably still the best game.
Speaker 1: I know it was the best game ever, but it's definitely one of the best games ever.
Speaker 0: It's an important game.
Speaker 0: I feel like there's still a lot to learn from Zelda.
Speaker 0: I feel like it for someone who's never played it before.
Speaker 0: it is well worth playing.
Speaker 0: Of course Emily now is going through that transition.
Speaker 0: I mean she's playing it, you know, she's played the new Zelda plays.
Speaker 1: I'm like she played Zelda 1 not yet But she's playing Zelda 3.
Speaker 0: All right, cuz that's that's a more accessible Zelda.
Speaker 0: I think than Zelda 1. definitely It's easy to forget how balls hard that game is.
Speaker 0: if you were not awesome at video games Super Nintendo Zelda is not really that hard for someone who's not awesome at video games.
Speaker 0: It's pretty awesome video games.
Speaker 1: Mario one's gonna be hard.
Speaker 0: I mean, come on How many people have beaten Mario 1?
Speaker 0: I'll bet if we go to PAX and we're like how many people in this room have?
Speaker 0: Actually beaten Mario 1 maybe sadly surprised The same number of people who watched Evangelion at the anime convention or people who hadn't seen Star Wars.
Speaker 1: Yeah God, we're old Yeah, but actually it's like I'd.
Speaker 1: you know what I bet most people at a gaming at any convention have not played Zelda 1.
Speaker 1: I'm beating it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess even I guess Zelda 2 until RIT when I announced it.
Speaker 1: Oh, I thought you said that you beat it before that you're just beating again at RIT.
Speaker 0: No, I'd gotten up to the Thunderbird not past.
Speaker 1: Oh Well, then How about that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you'd ever beat it.
Speaker 0: I beat it when I forget, uh-huh You fight the shadow link and then you wait All right, who else is standing on the screen after you fight the shadow link?
Speaker 0: like who talks to you?
Speaker 0: I Think we're petering out here.
Speaker 0: This is kind of a lazy show.
Speaker 0: I'll be honest.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the point is that Zelda 1 is awesome and like if you haven't played Zelda 1 seriously what?
Speaker 1: and plus I because I just know in my heart that a Scarily small number of people have played Zelda 1 and a scarily even smaller number have beaten it.
Speaker 0: go find a scan to the instruction Book.
Speaker 0: scout look at this cute link just kind of standing there like the instruction book.
Speaker 1: art was so great.
Speaker 0: Oh my gosh, and if only there had been a Zelda anime that was just the anime looking art from this book.
Speaker 0: Excuse me artist.
Speaker 0: So the one is win, all right, I think by Thursday we'll be awake and back on track with the more energetic geek nights as usual.
Speaker 0: Hmm This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.