Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, May 18th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight a genre at which we suck ass real time strategy games.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I'm sitting at work today.
Speaker 0: You know doing my work thing.
Speaker 0: It's getting around lunchtime.
Speaker 0: I'm kind of hungry and The front desk calls and says there's someone here with the package for me.
Speaker 0: alrighty I don't.
Speaker 0: I don't know what this is.
Speaker 0: I haven't ordered anything and I didn't recognize the name They said from it.
Speaker 0: so I go up there And it's a pizza delivery guy who has three like gigantic pizzas from a really expensive nice place And he says they're for me.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: He said they're for a name.
Speaker 0: That is very similar to mine Uh-huh, but at the same time he had my extension like he knew my phone number at work And it was delivered to our office with the right address from some guy.
Speaker 0: I have no idea who it is.
Speaker 0: I even like went through my outlook stuff and old business cards.
Speaker 0: I could.
Speaker 0: I have no idea who this is.
Speaker 0: I'm assuming it's some vendor trying to get you know into my good side, but for the life of me It's kind of like that those artist alley people who had little ghosties And we forgot who they were but we remembered the ghostie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's the same thing.
Speaker 0: someone got me a really nice pizza but I have no idea who they are.
Speaker 0: but I'm still not convinced that it wasn't just poison.
Speaker 0: pizza Got trouble yawning.
Speaker 1: I yawned again.
Speaker 0: Yeah story was that boring no mystery random pizza.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure there's probably a reasonable explanation for it.
Speaker 0: or someone's trying to get me pizza?
Speaker 1: Maybe there wasn't a reasonable explanation.
Speaker 1: Maybe it was like some accident or some hackers or a computer error in your favor.
Speaker 1: collect three pizzas.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I never considered the idea.
Speaker 1: do not do not pass go.
Speaker 0: I never thought of like hacking Grubhub to just have them send me food.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I mean think about right you Chipotle.
Speaker 1: you can pay with the credit card online.
Speaker 1: walk into the Chipotle and get food Right.
Speaker 1: so you don't even need to hack Chipotle to put in fake orders.
Speaker 1: You can just figure out what orders are in there.
Speaker 1: go in say yeah This should be a burrito here for Joe And you know that Joe ordered one.
Speaker 1: you get there before Joe and you take his burrito and no one ever checks.
Speaker 0: nope In fact the thing is if I were homeless what I would do is you know Starbucks.
Speaker 0: There's always that a counter and everyone's waiting for the drink.
Speaker 0: No one really pays attention.
Speaker 0: You could pretty much just walk up stand there You know kind of a little bit away, and then they're like got a tall double frappe aca aca
Speaker 1: That's me
Speaker 0: yep, just like
Speaker 1: yep, and then someone else goes hey, I ordered a double what the weather would do with it and they go oh Okay, and they make another one for you.
Speaker 0: They pretty much do you know how many times they've given me a free drink just because they're like yeah You waited too long.
Speaker 0: They give me a little coupon for a free Starbucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they like bend over back.
Speaker 1: I don't care cuz you're already paying like 500%.
Speaker 1: It's like in the movie theater gave out a free popcorn.
Speaker 0: It's like yeah, thanks That's more per ounce.
Speaker 0: we're talking gold Jerry.
Speaker 1: The other thing is we just read about that Pandora Pandora Panera.
Speaker 1: I'm sort of box the Panera dude Pandora's bread.
Speaker 0: We should make a Pandora that you go in and they give you different kinds of bread that they think you'll like.
Speaker 1: What is in this box?
Speaker 1: Oh?
Speaker 1: No you have leashed upon us the evil.
Speaker 1: Possibly put it back in the box.
Speaker 1: It is soup in a bread bowl with an apple next.
Speaker 0: That's in fact one of the most important things the world has ever invented.
Speaker 1: Bowl.
Speaker 1: they started these.
Speaker 1: nonprofit.
Speaker 1: Panera is where you can get anything and you pay what you want.
Speaker 1: So it's like I would just pay a dollar every time I would be like yeah Give me a whole lunch dollar.
Speaker 0: so you know you're not thinking outside the box The box.
Speaker 0: If I went to that Panera, maybe I should go to that Panera.
Speaker 0: I would order everything in everything in the store and say I want everything I take it all with me in a big sack.
Speaker 0: Maybe a bunch of sacks may look at someone to help me.
Speaker 1: I think they might say no to that would they though?
Speaker 0: because as soon as they try to stop me I'll say well I'm going to give this to a homeless person, and I plan to pay exactly what I want for it.
Speaker 0: There's a dollar zero one penny One penny.
Speaker 0: you realize you know I take my pants off every day when I get home and money just have to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, how much more money falls out of my pockets?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I put that money in a jar.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the jars full so I can then use it.
Speaker 0: Actually, Emily's been yelling at me.
Speaker 0: She wants me to go cash in the jar.
Speaker 1: Go cash it in.
Speaker 0: We actually the movers moved it here.
Speaker 0: It was too big for me to just carry on the train.
Speaker 1: All right, that's enough of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well there is one more important bit of you know Meta kind of open event news for those of you who are unaware.
Speaker 0: I actually bought an Xbox kind of.
Speaker 0: basically I bought a Street Fighter 4 machine.
Speaker 1: You got more games for it than I do actually yeah, because the Xbox came with two games.
Speaker 0: So I have a time.
Speaker 0: mine didn't really game is.
Speaker 1: my came with a rebate, so I basically Yeah, it's funny.
Speaker 1: I paid less money, but you got free game.
Speaker 0: I paid the actual MSRP for the elite, but then I got like Grand Theft Auto not Grand Theft Auto.
Speaker 0: I got like.
Speaker 0: I think for is this something?
Speaker 0: and I have some halo game.
Speaker 0: I haven't even opened the boxes for those yet.
Speaker 0: yeah, I basically brought it home turn it on put in Street Fighter plugged in my Street Fighter stick and Preceded to realize what do you do?
Speaker 0: suck?
Speaker 1: What are you doing?
Speaker 1: You're bored of Street Fighter ah?
Speaker 1: regret regret spending so much money.
Speaker 0: use it as an replace the Roku box.
Speaker 1: I Guess what the Roku actually does more than yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I'm not sure what I'm gonna do with it yet.
Speaker 0: I figure I will play enough games with the listeners And you know basically it's a way for me to interface with all the people and that whole gaming side of the world that I've basically ignored Because you know you and I are both PC gamers primarily like that's where our gaming at least that's where our video gaming is and The Wii is only great when you have four people around reliably
Speaker 1: Listen to an early geek nights where it's just like PC gaming is dead.
Speaker 1: Nintendo Wii Nintendo DS Fuck the Xbox like the ps3.
Speaker 0: the thing is back then fuck the Xbox.
Speaker 0: You know what did?
Speaker 0: the Street Fighter 4 is why I bought the Xbox and any other games.
Speaker 1: Was that a long time ago?
Speaker 0: super Street Fighter 4?
Speaker 0: Yeah, most of that just got it to interface with that whole other community And I guess as at least a pretend journalist in the video game world I need to at least have a ps3 or an Xbox.
Speaker 0: I guess so anyway plus It's not like it cost that much money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, my laptop is in Kentucky.
Speaker 1: it says it's like warehoused until like someone checks it out, which I assume means customer customs.
Speaker 0: But didn't it come in through like Alaska.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't do Alaska.
Speaker 1: first They didn't check it in Alaska even though it came from China.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe it came in and went out and then the relax is like oh shit I think that was from China.
Speaker 0: They emailed Kentucky.
Speaker 1: They're like hey The exact text says this shipment is warehoused until it is released by clearing agency, huh?
Speaker 0: All right, that's interesting.
Speaker 0: maybe they accidentally sent you one of the weed laptops.
Speaker 1: it says, you know the status exception Ship to New York shipped on the 14th product world ease.
Speaker 1: Huh service expedited special instructions.
Speaker 0: signature acquired Alright, but video games.
Speaker 1: Okay video game video game news kind of this isn't a big news.
Speaker 1: There's not really much to say about it.
Speaker 1: But remember we went to the New York Tokyo Music Festival a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, the whole Memory of that night just flooded back into my head.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the New York Tokyo website basically I realized is a good place to like learn about events that are New York Tokyo related usually in New York relating to Tokyo.
Speaker 0: So that website's still there because I thought the festival like died not long after we wake a lot more going.
Speaker 1: it wasn't?
Speaker 1: You know, New York, Tokyo is an organization.
Speaker 1: The music festival is just one event.
Speaker 0: I think they tried to do it again the next year and we didn't go and then that's probably why they cancelled it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the thing is they do lots of other stuff, right?
Speaker 1: Like they have a game night where they play Street Fighter 4 and such and I think I might cause money and be 21 plus I'm
Speaker 0: not going to a game night plus people play Street Fighter 4 plus it'd be
Speaker 1: all Asians and we would have no chance Like yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: Let's play perfect.
Speaker 1: Not me.
Speaker 0: No I think I would do just fine because I would consider it against people who are actually good at Street Fighter 4. if I get so much as a jab in I consider it that I want.
Speaker 0: you can get a jab then I won.
Speaker 1: as far As I'm concerned any moron can get a jab if you just jab like crazy.
Speaker 1: You're gonna hit.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't plan online there.
Speaker 0: There's some people not a jab Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, t-hawk is like the heat just fucks me up right now.
Speaker 1: You know, it's so easy to beat I know but I'm not good at this game when you just got a jab him like crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was trying to do that.
Speaker 0: I'm working on my Ken my Vega my doll seam and my guile.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you got to pick just one other way to learn because there's so many subtleties.
Speaker 1: You got to pick just one guy that you can learn all the subtleties.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, you're gonna not look you're not gonna learn anyone deep enough to actually be good.
Speaker 1: Well, basically, I'm I got to pick one of those four, but you do have to play Everyone at least a little bit.
Speaker 1: so, you know what they got.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean basically of those four.
Speaker 0: I'm playing them all like through the single player and a little bit online to figure out which of the four is going to be My go-to guy like my number one guy.
Speaker 0: cuz I'll seem not cutting it like you did in Super Street Fighter 2.
Speaker 1: He was pretty strong.
Speaker 1: Yes, but Seth is pretty is very dalsim ish.
Speaker 0: They'll seem strong.
Speaker 0: It's just.
Speaker 0: it doesn't suit my.
Speaker 0: maybe it's just cuz.
Speaker 0: I've been corrupted by like Soul Calibers and all the other games I played for so long, but the style I got to use with dalsim does not jive.
Speaker 1: I'm much more style of anyone you got to use is nothing like Soul Calibur.
Speaker 0: No, I'm not saying it's like Soul Calibur.
Speaker 0: I'm saying just it feels weird to me.
Speaker 0: I guess I need the guys with like charging moves more so than I need guys with like tech moves.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so on their website this little announcement here that says UT X MGS colon PW which translates to Uniqlo UT t-shirt program Uniqlo t-shirt.
Speaker 1: What are you so excited?
Speaker 1: You're getting excited at the wrong part.
Speaker 0: I like Uniqlo t-shirts.
Speaker 1: They have Metal Gear t-shirts.
Speaker 1: Ah, and they have Metal Gear Peace Walker t-shirts.
Speaker 1: It says Kojima will be at Uniqlo on June 11th.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: Whoa That's interesting.
Speaker 1: Maybe I've got my eyes.
Speaker 1: I just be like, hey coach.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're any he'll be like.
Speaker 1: fuck that.
Speaker 0: No, you're what I'll give it to me.
Speaker 1: Like he'd be like I didn't make that.
Speaker 1: What is this?
Speaker 0: What I would say to him is I would present it to him and say you could either sign this or destroy it in front Of my eyes and I'll be happy with either one.
Speaker 0: I Apologize on behalf of my nation for this.
Speaker 1: The point is you know, oh no the Kojima have started to kind of I go and be like, hey, yeah your games I don't like them.
Speaker 0: No, you know what.
Speaker 0: this is a perfect opportunity.
Speaker 0: ask him if he actually in fact is Masamune Shiro.
Speaker 1: Hey, do you know Masamune Shiro?
Speaker 1: Yeah, are you him?
Speaker 0: There's a chance.
Speaker 0: they're the same person I don't know.
Speaker 1: He can't I don't think coach him.
Speaker 1: I can draw.
Speaker 0: Ah Yeah, but he can crazy.
Speaker 1: they can take him both crazy.
Speaker 1: They're equal in the crazy town.
Speaker 0: So, you know all that news about how Farmville is like the biggest game at.
Speaker 0: well I gotta qualify this because I don't think it's actually a game.
Speaker 0: I don't want to get into that.
Speaker 0: I don't want to talk about Farmville the game.
Speaker 0: I want to talk about all the money meta around Farmville because Farmville has been making the news like the mainstream news for being gigantic like Millions and millions and millions and millions of players like the biggest game ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah gaming gaming It's one of those situations where they're counting the same way that like second life is counting.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah, okay active people Whatever BS.
Speaker 1: It's one person with 20 accounts.
Speaker 1: You're gonna shit.
Speaker 0: and all the news so far is primarily talked about how big the game Is now it's only getting bigger and how everyone's mom is playing it and my mom's playing it.
Speaker 0: It looks like there's a strange trend as of about a month ago.
Speaker 0: They claim here.
Speaker 0: I'll read from the Kotaku article Zinga's losing subscribers, whatever.
Speaker 0: two weeks ago Zinga lost 3.1 million active users across all their games.
Speaker 0: last week alone They lost 4.2 million.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I Think is they have.
Speaker 1: they have so many millions.
Speaker 0: Well, so many millions of accounts that have ever been touched by anyone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but so what's going on?
Speaker 0: Why are all their games suddenly collapsing?
Speaker 0: Well, it turns out that the only people who play these games are people who do it because they're Pavlovian.
Speaker 0: They they play because they're spammed into playing.
Speaker 0: They don't actually like these games.
Speaker 0: They play because they get a notification that says hey farm something mafia something.
Speaker 0: click here to make the thing happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and people?
Speaker 1: I used to think that the notifications in those games were just to get you into them.
Speaker 1: It would be like, you know You would go into Facebook and all you'd see all your friends would be like farm farm farm.
Speaker 1: So then you would sign up for the farm and then you would be addicted to the farm.
Speaker 1: But the thing is is not how it works.
Speaker 1: It's actually you sign into Facebook and it notifies you.
Speaker 1: Hey fix your farm notify you Hey fix your farm.
Speaker 1: and basically if you don't get these notifications that constantly remind you to fix your farm People aren't signing in to go fix their farm.
Speaker 1: They're not like intentionally clicking on Farmville They're just waiting for notifications that tell them Hey You have to do this and that's why they're doing it.
Speaker 1: because someone tells them to.
Speaker 1: it's like they get a task and the task Manager, you know a letter comes in the inbox and they have to handle the letter and out of the inbox and put it in the outbox.
Speaker 1: But if nothing comes in the inbox and they're required to actually go to Farmville of their own initiative They just don't know it because it's not a game There's there's not that it did.
Speaker 0: by like four different definitions of game Farmville does not meet the requirements to be called a game.
Speaker 0: You know, I guess the only one it meets is the loosest loosest one of you know, any sort of enjoyable pastime?
Speaker 1: I don't think it's enjoyable Is it is an activity.
Speaker 0: The losses are being attributed pretty much straight up to the fact that Facebook changed the way it handles their gift requests and they eliminated The notifications that Zingo is using to basically advertise their game to people who are remind people to keep playing.
Speaker 1: basically Yeah, the advertising part.
Speaker 1: I don't think is you know was has changed.
Speaker 1: just the reminding people to acts that they've ordered already playing.
Speaker 1: They're not Constantly reminded to continue playing so they don't.
Speaker 0: it says a lot about Who is playing these games and and why
Speaker 1: and for what reasons and I would
Speaker 0: I would posit that it's really kind of the modern advertising equivalent of a Ponzi scheme where they make something that Tricks people into clicking on things and then they misuse statistics to say to prove to other people who also don't understand statistics We've got ten point six trillion people playing this game Advertised with us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right and it's just this gigantic scam from start to finish.
Speaker 1: They're making everything is a gigantic scam.
Speaker 0: Not everything.
Speaker 0: We provide exactly what we say.
Speaker 1: We're yeah, which is why no one gives us any money because our numbers are legit.
Speaker 1: They're not inflating.
Speaker 1: I point out.
Speaker 0: at least a few people have tried to give us money.
Speaker 0: We just don't.
Speaker 1: why didn't give us enough money?
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah people look people try to give us money.
Speaker 0: They don't give us money.
Speaker 0: We can't want to give us like five Yeah, or those advertisers who keep like hey, we want to ever don't want to give us.
Speaker 0: they want to give us $10 Maybe 11 if we give them like a 20-minute ad in the middle.
Speaker 0: It's not happening, but there's other weird news on Farmville.
Speaker 0: And this is why I think this is interesting Facebook's changes that basically wrecked Zinga's games Probably this is just me speculating might have had to do with the fact that Facebook and Farmville were kind of fighting with each other Over this whole Facebook dollars or Facebook currency system Facebook credits They're called uh-huh, which is kind of like this currency in Facebook for microtransactions.
Speaker 1: All right, I'd even know they existed.
Speaker 0: I know I'd either.
Speaker 0: but apparently what the deal is that in mafia wars and Farmville and all these bullshit Zinga quote-unquote games Why do people say quote unquote and then the word shouldn't?
Speaker 0: they say quote games unquote?
Speaker 0: Why am I just opening and closing quotes like in the middle of my anyway?
Speaker 0: So basically Facebook will facilitate these microtransactions for these games.
Speaker 0: when you buy your bullshit like you have four more points to spend on mafia in in the city and the proper noun proper noun.
Speaker 0: and Then Facebook gets a 30% cut of the money that changes hands through these transactions.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: This is real money or just like Warcraft gold.
Speaker 0: It's Warcraft gold, but I think you can buy it for money.
Speaker 0: I haven't dug into that at all.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and there's hints here that there were rumors at least that that Zinga was talking thinking about with Farmville trying to make Farmville a standalone portal and get people to just go into that which At least from that other article wouldn't work at all.
Speaker 0: No one's gonna go to Farmville.
Speaker 0: a Farmville is Farmville by itself.
Speaker 0: They only go because their Facebook friends force them to.
Speaker 1: but there's also people are only on Facebook to get Farmville.
Speaker 1: It's like they're tied together.
Speaker 1: You know, there's people who are on Facebook, but they're not there for Farmville.
Speaker 1: You're there for Farmville, but they're not there for Facebook.
Speaker 0: We'd have to know how many like what percentages and I have no way to know that.
Speaker 1: I think the thing is by joining together, right?
Speaker 1: They're basically this symbiote where you know The people who are only interested in Farmville are upping Facebook's numbers and the people who are only interested in Facebook and are getting pestered By Farmville are upping Farmville's numbers.
Speaker 1: So they up each other's numbers by combining these two really powerful things.
Speaker 1: It's like imagine there are two TV stations and they just merged right?
Speaker 1: So now they basically both have double ratings.
Speaker 1: That's basically what it is.
Speaker 1: You know the people who would have watched You know show A and you're watching show B are now watching both shows.
Speaker 1: So now, you know one show had a million viewers.
Speaker 1: the other show had a million viewers.
Speaker 1: now They both have two million viewers.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's totally cheating.
Speaker 0: one thing I would say to all of you out there If you're if you care at all about the video game industry Any of the news and numbers about Zynga and all this?
Speaker 0: I don't think it's actually the game.
Speaker 0: I don't think gaming has anything to do with this whole, you know, Facebook Zynga, whatever They're not games and they're not made for gamers.
Speaker 0: There's this wholly separate industry.
Speaker 0: That's basically create a psychological trap to trick eyeballs and then sell those eyeballs to advertisers.
Speaker 0: at least.
Speaker 0: World of Warcraft is Technically a game.
Speaker 0: It's more.
Speaker 1: it's more of a game than Farmville.
Speaker 1: There's some.
Speaker 1: it's not much more but it's more To its credit.
Speaker 0: there's stuff in there to do.
Speaker 0: if you like that sort of thing You know, you can play it.
Speaker 0: and they're still selling the game.
Speaker 0: They're selling the the carrot stick machine directly to the user.
Speaker 0: They're not using the carrot stick machine to trick a user in and then sell him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess World of Warcraft doesn't message you and it's like hey, you didn't finish this quest.
Speaker 0: I mean, hey you need to level up today, dude It's the difference between an HBO series versus a regular broadcast TV series.
Speaker 0: Broadcast TV the TV show is not the product and the watchers.
Speaker 0: the viewers are not the consumer.
Speaker 0: The product is the viewers and the consumers.
Speaker 0: the advertisers and Zynga games are basically the same thing with the added basically the added revenue stream of microtransactions Mmm, so they're basically selling the people that they trick in with the machine World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: They sell them the machine.
Speaker 0: So it's basically Soma.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but a lot watered-down shitty version of Soma.
Speaker 1: But the thing is Farmville does make a lot of money from Tricking people into just buying like plows and also getting people to do stupid offer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but think if they do it through Facebook with the Facebook currency Then the people will have well, they'll be able to give them currency for dollars.
Speaker 0: They'll also be able to give them currency through other Facebook things if Facebook wanted to do that.
Speaker 0: So they could basically direct these eyeballs in all sorts of different directions Like hey click on this ad follow this, you know, listen to this guy's updates and we'll give you X Facebook credits.
Speaker 0: Mmm, I don't know if they'll do that.
Speaker 0: That's what I would do.
Speaker 1: Yeah Alright things of the day you actually put that in the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why are you so corny?
Speaker 1: you stand Lee now?
Speaker 0: I am now talking into the microphone you little guy.
Speaker 1: So, you know, I always get bothered because they put out these lists of like, you know What anime are out this season.
Speaker 1: and the thing is those lists never include like the ongoing anime, right?
Speaker 1: You don't see like one piece on that list right because one piece is always on It just always is right.
Speaker 1: and and the result of that always will be yes The result of that is that there's a lot of shows, you know Basically the Simpsons equivalents in Japan the shows that never end They just keep going and going.
Speaker 1: and if anime fans in the US don't hear about them because no one's fan subs them No one talks about them.
Speaker 1: Nobody, you know, they're just always there.
Speaker 1: So one of those shows is Doraemon which you know is a kids show.
Speaker 1: it's for little kids But it's it's a lot better than a lot of the kids shows we have here.
Speaker 1: come you know, good God I mean, you know, it's basically like the SpongeBob of The Asia but it's a lot of way 10 million times better than SpongeBob because SpongeBob is retarded like the character.
Speaker 1: He's a retard.
Speaker 1: Doraemon is like a really smart dude always brings out like wicked awesome gadgets and shit to save the day to this.
Speaker 1: Also fuck up the day.
Speaker 0: I understand a little bit but I mean I understand the appeals of like venture brothers and all those things there.
Speaker 0: most comedy I understand the appeal of but I would rather watch like the bad Three Stooges then watch SpongeBob.
Speaker 0: SpongeBob I just can't deal with it.
Speaker 1: But anyway, Doraemon is pretty cool.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's a kids show that you can probably watch and tolerate and not just kill yourself And it's also a manga.
Speaker 1: But anyway, somebody made took the Doraemon theme song a very famous theme song Yep, and they recreated the entire song Using only sound effects from Street Fighter 2.
Speaker 0: It's pretty amazing.
Speaker 1: even have like the video from Street Fighter 2 to go with the sound effects for Hindi.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know this got posted all over the internet because it's pretty cool in and of itself.
Speaker 1: But a lot of people who watched it didn't realize that it was the Doraemon theme or if they did they didn't know what Doraemon Was.
Speaker 0: so it was funny.
Speaker 0: You know I Yuko and Athan Conrad and John were all hanging out over the weekend and I showed that to them and immediately Yuko was like Doraemon.
Speaker 1: Yep Yep, the people they don't know.
Speaker 0: Well now they know.
Speaker 0: So along the lines of a video game related thing of the day that is also on College Humor.
Speaker 0: I have another video game related thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Can you please look at like a different website.
Speaker 0: yours is also on College Humor.
Speaker 1: I saw it before.
Speaker 1: it was on College Humor.
Speaker 1: Curse them, curse them.
Speaker 0: They're pretty much you know.
Speaker 0: I'll let you all in on the secret.
Speaker 0: once again I skip a lot of them because I try to avoid going back to College Humor as my go-to place for things of the day.
Speaker 0: But there is at least one good video worth watching on the internet every day on College Humor.
Speaker 0: That's the best video aggregator on the entire internet right now that I have found.
Speaker 0: yes If you know of a better one let me know.
Speaker 0: and if you say dig you're a damn dirty liar.
Speaker 0: So this is 8-bit Starcraft I think.
Speaker 0: what does this fun?
Speaker 1: This is also on every other website before it was in College Humor, so it's okay.
Speaker 1: The graphics is linked to a non College Humor source.
Speaker 0: work out really well.
Speaker 0: I think you should link to the College Humor.
Speaker 0: we had to let him know that it's us driving all this traffic to them.
Speaker 1: So much traffic because they need.
Speaker 1: so it's such a flood of traffic.
Speaker 1: We're sending.
Speaker 1: Holy shit.
Speaker 1: Oh you guys.
Speaker 1: It's unbelievable All right.
Speaker 0: Wow actually you know now that I never really look at it.
Speaker 0: I never look at the stuff on College Humor except for the video.
Speaker 0: if I scroll down though You know what's at the top of recommended videos?
Speaker 0: You'll like right under this Washington mmm-hmm.
Speaker 0: yeah awesome, but I think what does it for me in this video is the sound that the little Marines make when they're running.
Speaker 0: Hmm no no I guess we should do the meta moment.
Speaker 1: Oh fuck meta moment.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh shit book club is cosmos.
Speaker 0: We're gonna do the show soon, so uh read the book.
Speaker 1: probably then not this Thursday But the Thursday episode after that is probably gonna be it.
Speaker 1: yeah after all this time What multiple months of not doing the book means you have no goddamn excuse?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I didn't even start reading it, but I got a copy and I'm gonna start reading it real soon And I'll have it finished that quickly.
Speaker 0: so the geek knights coding club is still a project Dorf.
Speaker 1: It'll probably be that I gotta I gotta do some stuff on that there.
Speaker 1: I've been I've been doing some other stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got to jump in on it.
Speaker 0: I've been by Java.
Speaker 0: They'll probably be a huge flood of stuff this weekend.
Speaker 1: cuz look at the new laptop, and I'll set the shit up Awesome.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I'm not gonna do anything until after kinetic on is completely.
Speaker 0: until until I send the schedule to print for kinetic on I'm not gonna work on project Dorf at all.
Speaker 0: If any other medicine that we're doing the live streaming shows you can watch those if you want.
Speaker 0: They're nothing special.
Speaker 0: you just see what we look like.
Speaker 0: you know looking into our microphones Just go to the.
Speaker 1: actually is a secret.
Speaker 1: if you go to front row crew calm which I'm gonna start doing some more work on pretty soon the use stream is embedded in the front page so you can just go There and sort of.
Speaker 1: you know and if you know what day of the week It is just you know around six seven ish just wait and eventually you know probably six.
Speaker 1: If you want to start watching six Eastern 6 p.m.. Eastern just wait and eventually it'll be like tada live now And you push play and you'll be all set.
Speaker 0: yep now also Bit by bit we're gonna start doing our I guess proper video shows where we'll actually be looking at the camera.
Speaker 0: There'll be video content as the primary thing as opposed to audio that we happen to be filming ourselves doing.
Speaker 0: I mean this new stream is basically What like watching Howard Stern do his show?
Speaker 0: It's just you know guys microphones pop filter.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is I hope that it gets us some exposure because if we get enough viewers that are simultaneous Then we'll get on the front page of you stream, and then we'll get viewers that weren't coming for us specifically.
Speaker 1: They're just coming to you stream And they see us there and then they discover geek nights.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 0: is the way to do that really for us?
Speaker 0: You know meta is to do Actual straight-up video shows because remember how many people we had when we scheduled ahead of time a video show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was like we had like over a hundred people's as a lot of people's.
Speaker 0: yeah Especially considering the short notice we gave on that one.
Speaker 0: I mean Plus.
Speaker 0: that got us on the front page of you stream which proceeded to fill the channel with basically the most vile shit cockery I've seen.
Speaker 1: that's all right because the new you stream now has better shit cockery protections.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's almost too good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 1: It's a little too strong.
Speaker 0: Scott and I we pride ourselves in being very good gamers at certain things like German board games have mad skills At many things we don't have like you know like art.
Speaker 1: We have good FPS skills, but we're not exactly.
Speaker 0: you know I mean fatality level.
Speaker 0: yeah, we're not.
Speaker 0: we're not like planning it up in the quake 3 arena or anything But you know we're solid like counter-strike.
Speaker 0: We were some of the better players than the RIT servers back in the day yeah, and like German board games You've got no chance against us unless you're.
Speaker 0: I mean it said when we go to like all these board game meetups And we basically just wreck everybody all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is despite our high level of skill at many kinds of games which point out confirmation bias We talk about the games.
Speaker 0: We're good at a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: it might seem like we're full of ourselves,
Speaker 1: but there are many kinds of games that we are no good at
Speaker 0: chief among them Chief
Speaker 1: among the kinds of games we suck at our fighting games though the skills are improving
Speaker 0: yeah
Speaker 1: and Most of all real-time strategy games and fanatical
Speaker 0: devotion to the Pope.
Speaker 1: We're just the worst Real-time strategy, I just fucking like back in the day I would play Starcraft Starcraft 1 against the computer right.
Speaker 0: I could even beat the computer.
Speaker 1: I would just do.
Speaker 1: I would just do a skirmish.
Speaker 1: It was just straight up like Terran vs.
Speaker 1: Zerg computers controlling the zergs right.
Speaker 1: I would start building a base a Wave.
Speaker 1: a little zergs would come like 10 of them.
Speaker 1: Maybe Probably less than 10. most of the time.
Speaker 1: that little tiny wave would kill me now.
Speaker 1: Sometimes what I would do is I would go okay I know that little wave is gonna come right away.
Speaker 1: It happens every time and I would rush to build a barracks in some Marines So that I could hold it off, and it would work.
Speaker 1: I would hold off that little wave right and then I would keep going and going and going and the Second wave would come with like friggin big-ass zergs Before and I'd still have that little bunch of Marines and no matter how hard I tried to build more guys it Wouldn't do mean anything, and I would just get host
Speaker 0: command and conquer.
Speaker 0: was the first one I really like?
Speaker 1: played hardcore really I played Warcraft 1. well What was the first?
Speaker 1: I mean you.
Speaker 1: I usually tend to think that the first real-time strategy was Warcraft 1.
Speaker 1: But I mean is metal Marines was sort of a real-time strategy.
Speaker 1: and wasn't it a dune game for the PC?
Speaker 1: That was sort of a real-time strategy.
Speaker 1: was that older.
Speaker 1: You know.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure which one came first.
Speaker 1: I don't know really matters.
Speaker 0: I tried to just type RTS into Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: mm-hmm and Real-time strategy game is not the first thing that comes up.
Speaker 0: the first thing that comes up is rape trauma system.
Speaker 1: That's fantastic.
Speaker 0: That's just great great.
Speaker 0: All right precursors and early Genesis.
Speaker 0: here rim goes to Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Herzog's way for the Sega Genesis 1989 is the earliest example of a game that falls under the contemporary definition of a modern RTS.
Speaker 1: really Herzog's we.
Speaker 1: I've heard of that game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, 19.
Speaker 1: I thought it was like a space shooter.
Speaker 1: I guess I was totally wrong.
Speaker 1: control only never played.
Speaker 1: I just I just it.
Speaker 1: doesn't that sound like the name of a space shooter to you?
Speaker 0: it that totally sounds like her zog's way.
Speaker 1: That's definitely a space shooter name.
Speaker 1: Okay, see a dune to the building of a dynasty right.
Speaker 1: so I was right.
Speaker 1: and then Warcraft in 94 was like the first one.
Speaker 1: that was like for reals.
Speaker 1: and then command and conquer.
Speaker 0: and then Well cool Wikipedia command and conquer became the first popular RTS.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well Warcraft 1 was really but it was no.
Speaker 0: But the thing is command and conquer was the first one that I wanted to be good at like.
Speaker 0: I was like you know What and I've said this many times in my life about many things like Smash Brothers.
Speaker 0: I am going to put forth the effort.
Speaker 0: It will take to be good at this game and I Could not beat either Campaign in that game or red alert.
Speaker 0: Furthermore when I play it online.
Speaker 0: I just got hosed.
Speaker 1: see I could actually beat that.
Speaker 1: beat the campaign in Warcraft 1.
Speaker 1: I could beat the campaign in Warcraft 2.
Speaker 1: I just never owned it.
Speaker 1: man It's got to be cheap to get that game now right.
Speaker 0: sure there's got to be a steam pack or something.
Speaker 1: Warcraft 2 is good.
Speaker 1: Well, no no blizzard stuff is on steam.
Speaker 1: They do.
Speaker 1: they roll their own but then Command and conquer.
Speaker 1: I was able to beat command and conquer red alert.
Speaker 1: I beat you know on single-player, but playing multiplayer like.
Speaker 1: I played multiplayer Warcraft 1 and 2 But I played against like people I could dial up with so it was sort of even ish.
Speaker 1: When I you know it wasn't.
Speaker 1: until I try to play red alert dialing up against someone I knew that I learned just how much I sucked because basically it was they're playing red alert.
Speaker 1: I was the allies.
Speaker 1: They were the Soviets.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: this is the first red alert on DOS.
Speaker 1: We dialed into each other the game totally worked, and we're playing.
Speaker 1: and then eventually I use the spy Plane to see what they had.
Speaker 1: and basically their base was so packed with tanks that nothing could move And they just had like tanks like just spilling out completely filling their area
Speaker 0: And then at some point those tanks that
Speaker 1: moving and yeah at some point They just select it all and clicked on my base
Speaker 0: all tanks roll,
Speaker 1: and I had like a handful of dudes And it's like what the hell.
Speaker 0: of course Scott to be fair you have the same problem in turn-based strategy games But not not.
Speaker 1: you know not to that extent.
Speaker 1: You know it's a completely different situation.
Speaker 0: Well my problem really was that I wasn't so good at the campaigns But the campaigns were often not fun.
Speaker 0: at least knows early RTS is I actually?
Speaker 1: I like the campaigns like in Warcraft one.
Speaker 1: you get The campaign.
Speaker 1: we're like.
Speaker 1: you have the one guy.
Speaker 1: he's like the famous guy And you got to protect him while you walk through the dungeon.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like a real-time dungeon crawly bit almost like a hero quest where you don't have to wait and take turns.
Speaker 0: I guess I just I've always really only played games like this or any game like this just to get to the multiplayer.
Speaker 0: and What really messed me up was that the multiplayer you know dial-up?
Speaker 0: I only played with people that you know.
Speaker 0: we dial into each other's modems and play like command and cock.
Speaker 1: yeah I never played the multiplayer's.
Speaker 1: Real RTS is for real like that much at all ever until very very recently, but we were all Stupid.
Speaker 0: it's kind of like.
Speaker 0: imagine if you saw a bunch of people playing like tag But they all just like sucked at tag like no one tried to tag back But usually like okay.
Speaker 1: So we all play like a German board game against each other and we all don't know how to play it at all and we Keep playing and we keep playing keep playing we get better and we learn things about the game.
Speaker 0: I do that now with RTS is too But when I was a kid with video games for some reason sometimes I just wouldn't do that like there's some video games when I was very young But I just never got better at.
Speaker 0: and now that I'm older and I'd like play a game like that again I get better because I try to get better.
Speaker 1: the thing is with RTS is.
Speaker 1: it's like I try to get better and no amount Of effort that I put into it just on my own Like.
Speaker 1: if I just sit there playing an RTS against the computer over and over and over again I just can't get better.
Speaker 1: I need someone to like tell me like I was playing Starcraft 2 because I got the beta key because I pre-ordered an Amazon right just because I'm in this phase where I want to try To play games that I suck at and get better at them on purpose.
Speaker 1: Yeah to see if I can and for a change of pace in terms of the games I'm playing.
Speaker 1: So they give you like these five practice games And then they give you like these five games where it determines like your league ranking or whatever.
Speaker 1: And I'm of course in the worst possible league though.
Speaker 1: I'm not in last place in the worst possible league.
Speaker 1: start Yeah, you're beating guy who logs in and then being guy who's even worse than me by a little bit.
Speaker 1: You're beating
Speaker 0: like guy whose mouse stopped working
Speaker 1: and the thing is I won some of those games But they were against people who were just as bad as me and the thing was the reason I was able to win it
Speaker 0: all
Speaker 1: Is because the first guy I played against actually talked to me and he actually helped me out and he was like, dude You are not building nearly enough of the basic resource getting guy You need to build like a shit ton of them.
Speaker 1: and I was like, well how many he's like.
Speaker 1: for each pile of rocks Build like three and for each, you know little gas factory build three.
Speaker 1: So what I did is the next time I played I just built a ton of those guys and the thing was it was really hard to build a ton of those guys and to also build the stuff and I'm still doing it really shittily.
Speaker 1: But at least I'm not doing it so shittily that they come over with a huge army and I have nothing.
Speaker 1: I have something you know that gets destroyed and You know, so when I played against people who were you know, actually good I still had basically no chance.
Speaker 1: but when I played against you know people who were just as shitty as I was it was like in sometimes it was even and Once I even like, you know defended and then came back and destroyed the other guy.
Speaker 1: And because this is playing against people equal skill And I think what it is is that they have a system set up to where you don't play against people Who are way better or way worse than you, but it'll still mix it up.
Speaker 0: I think part of my problem was that back in the old days, you know with the with the modems you had this kind of Closed ecosystem of your friends like, you know, you see this with things like air hockey We're like one guy and a group of friends can get good But no one like the group doesn't get to the next echelon with command and conquer, especially in games like it.
Speaker 0: We would always end up just playing these really dumb Strategies that were fun because the fun part for me was like building a gigantic base.
Speaker 1: that is you know I think that Actraiser is like the best thing to look at in terms of how I feel about RTS is like if you could just gave me an RTS and it was only single-player.
Speaker 1: It's so fun because it's like well, I'll just build a base and which is totally fun right and then building all these units is totally fun.
Speaker 1: and Then you know like the actual ordering of the units is not really that fun.
Speaker 1: It's really actually kind of boring and I wish they wouldn't have that part of the game.
Speaker 0: Well, you mean the part of the game where you play a shitty side scroller to get back to the fun farming game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly I Guess it's weird that like me and all my friends at least when I was young playing this game over a modem all felt the Same way, we'd always play kind of a gentleman's agreement where we were just Nobody attack each other.
Speaker 1: so we can have lots of fun building bases and then we'll attack each other.
Speaker 1: It was basically once we built our bases 100% completely.
Speaker 0: The trouble was it was basically sim based because we build the bases and like a half hour went by and then we'd finally decide To fight and usually around.
Speaker 0: then is when like one of the motives would crap out and the game would break.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing that bothers me is that like I'm as I'm playing Starcraft a little bit more not that much I'm still busy with other things but a little bit more I'm learning all these things that people do like.
Speaker 1: what they'll do is they'll send one of those nothing guys over to your base Right away, and if you don't build like a marine or something right away It'll walk in and take a look at your base and there's like nothing you can do about it.
Speaker 1: So it's like oh fuck get the hell out of here.
Speaker 1: You get this thing pestering you and looking around and they can see all your shit.
Speaker 1: and it's like.
Speaker 1: and they can see how far Along you are and everything.
Speaker 0: and it's like You know what that is?
Speaker 0: That's the equivalent of tapping the prodigal sorcerer, you know There's all this kind of like stupid little.
Speaker 1: you know tricks like that that are just like really annoying.
Speaker 1: It's nothing to do with military strategy.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't say nothing that you know, I wouldn't say that they're necessarily stupid.
Speaker 0: It's that we have this problem that RTS has become this very defined genre among most people and I feel like The kind it's kind of like MMOs.
Speaker 0: when people like MMO they think of games like World of Warcraft But an MMO could be you know any sort of massive game.
Speaker 0: We need more real-time strategy games that have vastly different paradigms from the Starcraft style click sequence games that we have now.
Speaker 0: I think those games are good.
Speaker 0: I just think I would like other kinds of RTS's.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean people.
Speaker 1: We know how much we've talked about this game on the show.
Speaker 1: There's a game called metal Marines.
Speaker 1: I would reckon it was for windows.
Speaker 0: Actually that good of a game because I think it was a great game.
Speaker 0: Round one awesome.
Speaker 0: round two pretty fun.
Speaker 0: the rest of the game Horrifying and tedious because it was poorly designed.
Speaker 1: No But I mean go it's for this get it.
Speaker 1: the best way to play is to get it for a Super Nintendo or Super Nintendo Emulator.
Speaker 1: just play the first like two missions to see what we're talking about and you'll see it is a real-time strategy game But it is not anything like Starcraft.
Speaker 1: I mean you do build a base and you do build units and you attack.
Speaker 1: But the way you control the units and the way you build the things is not like Starcraft at all.
Speaker 1: It's it's barely like it and and you know, but it is still a game that is real-time and has strategy.
Speaker 1: So I think that's you know, that's the thing is like.
Speaker 1: I want a game that is real-time and has strategy.
Speaker 1: because a non real-time Game, that's good.
Speaker 1: I like my turn-based games like the Wesnoth and the advanced wars and such but they take a long Time and you spend all this time doing nothing when it's the other person's turn.
Speaker 1: So if it's real time be better.
Speaker 1: the problem is is when it's real time It's all about who can go really fast with the clicking and not who can you know.
Speaker 0: So it's like even if I can think in my brain the strategy Implementation is part of the skill of a game like this like that.
Speaker 0: I mean Street Fighter.
Speaker 0: All right, let's pause it.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna do sure you can and then I'm gonna do this and then up I've got a pause and change this thing before we take our next turn.
Speaker 1: No, but it's it's.
Speaker 1: it's more that.
Speaker 1: okay if it's a strategy game, right?
Speaker 1: I mean Street Fighter is a fighting game.
Speaker 1: It's about fighting and the speed is.
Speaker 0: this is what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: We we've conflated like RTS.
Speaker 0: real-time strategy became this very narrow genre.
Speaker 1: Yep, but it's like the game should.
Speaker 1: the ideal game should be about your strategic decisions Even though it's real time.
Speaker 1: It should just be about the decision you make.
Speaker 1: did you make the good decision or the bad decision?
Speaker 1: So here's the thing, right?
Speaker 1: So my decision is to a good strategic decision might be like, okay I'm gonna have the tanks You know flank and I'm gonna send in some planes as a decoy to distract your anti ground planes and then I'm gonna rush in with These guys from the south and that's that's my strategy.
Speaker 1: Well, so I click and I say tanks do this.
Speaker 1: I say tanks go here planes go here units go here and they do it.
Speaker 1: But they just go like in a straight line and it totally doesn't work.
Speaker 1: I have to go to like each unit and be like click move two feet.
Speaker 1: this way click move two feet.
Speaker 1: that way click.
Speaker 1: you Constantly click.
Speaker 1: crazily.
Speaker 0: that was what really got to control each Individual unit.
Speaker 1: as if I'm playing a game of control the single individual unit and control all of them like a man in conquer.
Speaker 0: I just always try to like make a strategy like that.
Speaker 0: You know an ambush or whatever.
Speaker 0: and then I watched a good player playing and he basically just selected all his tanks and clicked On the enemy base.
Speaker 1: No, I watch guys like play like Starcraft or even like, you know The heroes of new worth type type of games which are basically real, you know Same kind of thing.
Speaker 1: and they may say click like nuts.
Speaker 1: They're like, you know move to the left move to the right move up move down Attack that guy once back up attack that guy once back up.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: That's not strategy if I have to control each and every limb of each and every unit, right?
Speaker 1: That's a much lower level interaction.
Speaker 1: That's like even more lower level than an FPS where I'm controlling the aim and movement of one individual unit.
Speaker 1: That is enough to occupy an entire human brain, right if I had to do it for an entire army Fuck that.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 1: if I'm controlling an entire army the extent to which I should have to interact with that army is you Do this done, you know you ten guys attack base.
Speaker 1: That's that I shouldn't have to control them any more than that.
Speaker 1: I should do it as best as it possibly can be done.
Speaker 0: another style of RTS that I've been playing again a lot and then Stopped playing very, you know again for involved.
Speaker 0: There are the games like medieval total war where you have like the real-time ness of an army battle And it's much more well on the surface strategic like that.
Speaker 0: But as far as I can see almost everyone who actually plays these games skips that part and plays the shitty turn-based game.
Speaker 0: That is kind of just around the real-time part of the game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't even know why.
Speaker 1: I mean that if you look at The previews for all those total war games.
Speaker 1: I played the demo of the first one in like the late night Like all of them on a steam.
Speaker 1: really Wow Yeah, so the thing is you look at the demos for those games.
Speaker 1: They always show you the big battles with tons of units.
Speaker 0: That's what I want That's what I play.
Speaker 0: But as far as the thing is every win every battle if you have more guys than the other guy by just clicking on all Your guys and saying attack.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they didn't actually implement the strategy part.
Speaker 1: They only implemented the graphics part of those battles.
Speaker 0: Well, even worse what got me is that the stupidest meta strategies work just because the games are so poor.
Speaker 1: Games are so rock-paper-scissors.
Speaker 1: It's like oh just use the archers against those guys and you win.
Speaker 0: Well, the AI is so shitty that I can do tricks like have my guys to advance pull back advance pull back.
Speaker 0: events pull back advance pull back and like Trick an enemy move unit into not moving while the horses just walk around behind him and then charge Yep, like that.
Speaker 0: None of that would really work and it's just kind of silly and fiddly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not implemented really well at all.
Speaker 0: What would make RTS is that I want great.
Speaker 0: This is why natural selection is such a great game to me.
Speaker 0: It's for one player at least.
Speaker 0: It's an RTS where every single unit you control has a human level AI because it's an actual human.
Speaker 0: but in a game like a man in college imagine if you could give units more meta orders like you give them a zone like say you draw a zone on the map and say control this zone or Protect this zone or bombard this zone and you give them orders and simple macros and then let them go.
Speaker 1: Well, I think that's the one one thing that you can do to help.
Speaker 1: RTS is out Right is right.
Speaker 1: now if you let's say I'm playing Starcraft right and I've got something that drops bombs I click on a spot and it drops the bombs on that spot.
Speaker 0: exactly right now There's a valid place for a game like that.
Speaker 1: The thing is what they should do is They should make the get the RTS right like look at that 8-bit Starcraft video, right?
Speaker 1: That's how it should be.
Speaker 1: break the map up into sort of a grid that doesn't have that many squares in it Just a few areas.
Speaker 1: then I would say hey you bomb this area, you know and then the guy would do a bombing run in that area and I could give a lot more general orders because They don't have to you know, pick individual spots I can say okay we're gonna send 20 infantry to this square on the map and 30 tanks to that square on the map and we're gonna you know defend this square on the map.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't say they because you don't want to change Starcraft like that.
Speaker 0: Starcraft has to be Starcraft.
Speaker 0: I mean Starcraft is a genre in and of itself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not saying it has to be Starcraft.
Speaker 1: I just said it should be an RTS.
Speaker 1: you get.
Speaker 1: it would be better if instead of clicking Individual point XY coordinates on the map you had this sort of lower resolution grid.
Speaker 1: That's you know has not that many squares like maybe like like a 10 by 10 grid.
Speaker 1: and that's the whole map.
Speaker 1: and it's all about you know controlling the different squares on the map and It's really easy to give orders when the only positioning that goes on is which one of the hundred squares are you clicking on?
Speaker 0: Yep, or even if you don't have the squares I do like the idea of having an RTS or you know I think it had to be hexes.
Speaker 0: well where you can draw an area on the map like you have to like you're examining the Train looking at features and you can draw areas.
Speaker 0: you basically define your zones and define zones of control and Bombardment and all the kind of.
Speaker 1: I guess the only thing with that right is like maybe that would be cool.
Speaker 1: I'm like a like an iPad kind of thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah mouse drawing Yeah, but if you're trying to draw with the mouse or something, right?
Speaker 1: You're gonna see the amount of time that you could have spent drawing your little area, right?
Speaker 1: You could have clicked on your base a whole bunch and built a whole bunch of buildings and units and all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean I guess part of it's that if we really break that sound to its root most of the RTS is out today are aimed.
Speaker 0: it's kind of like fighting games like they're aimed at a certain kind of gamer and there are so many other possibilities.
Speaker 0: and RTS is that either aren't possible due to Technological limitations of things like AI and aren't possible because no one with resources is Experimenting in the genre.
Speaker 0: that much supreme commander did a lot of cool stuff.
Speaker 1: There's that ruse game that's experimenting But like it's it's a little bit better because you don't have to click on the exact Positions as much and the map is a little different.
Speaker 1: and it's got some sort of interesting things Like you can send out fake stuff and you know, it's the thing is the game was still I played it and it's like, okay There's some good ideas in here But the implementation really isn't polished and a hundred percent enough and there's way too much going on And there's no.
Speaker 1: is I gotta tell you about something just in general here, right?
Speaker 1: People making betas of games and such right the two.
Speaker 1: if you're making a video game that's big.
Speaker 1: The tutorial is the first thing that you should make.
Speaker 1: I get a Starcraft 2 beta.
Speaker 1: no fucking tutorial, right?
Speaker 0: It's why the only people play in the beta.
Speaker 0: people already know about it doesn't?
Speaker 1: it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: The tutorial is the first thing you make.
Speaker 1: what if they don't want noobs playing it.
Speaker 1: Why do they have practice mode in?
Speaker 0: Why make the tutorial if you're gonna probably have to change it as you change things from the beta?
Speaker 1: The same reason that you mean you're making like, you know software.
Speaker 1: you make tests for things Even though you have to change the text the tutorial.
Speaker 0: it should be a part of beta testing But I think it should be part of the end of beta test.
Speaker 1: I think the tutorial should be the first thing that you make because basically a game without A game without a tutorial is basically useless.
Speaker 1: And also if you don't have a tutorial you at least need a fucking instruction book.
Speaker 1: There's no instructions.
Speaker 0: Are you sure?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't find them hundred percent sure.
Speaker 0: I cannot.
Speaker 1: I cannot find any help Whatsoever right in Starcraft 2 I basically have to learn by trial and error.
Speaker 0: All right Just you look pretty funny.
Speaker 1: if some of some listener like emails and someone knows what the manual is Feel free to send it to me, but I have not found it.
Speaker 1: I have poked every menu.
Speaker 0: I just I disagree with the methodology.
Speaker 0: if you're at the point of just beta testing I mean beta testing is so I make I make a little board game, right?
Speaker 1: I'm making a brand new board game and I give it to some people to test.
Speaker 1: I'm not there right to help them and I didn't put any instructions in there.
Speaker 0: No, I'm saying you give them like a basic instruction or rule, but there's nothing in there.
Speaker 1: Nothing I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'm just talking about the tutorial part.
Speaker 0: I think the idea of making saying that you know The tutorial should be finished before you release the beta is ludicrous.
Speaker 1: doesn't be finished, but you got to have it in there.
Speaker 0: I don't think you do.
Speaker 1: tutorial is the first thing you need.
Speaker 0: I disagree.
Speaker 1: Otherwise your game is basically unplayable.
Speaker 0: Uh Apparently it's not because plenty of people are beta testing Starcraft just fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people are nuts.
Speaker 1: I can't even know what half the shit does And there's no way to play single-player at all.
Speaker 1: It's multiplayer only.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the only way I can figure out to learn and what anything does is basically to lose while experimenting with some weird thing.
Speaker 1: I don't know what.
Speaker 0: you don't want an unfinished game.
Speaker 0: You should probably just not play in the beta and wait for the real game to come out.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter They need that shit in there.
Speaker 0: Why Starcraft is gonna sell like crazy.
Speaker 0: They don't need that.
Speaker 0: Just what would it do for them?
Speaker 0: What would it do for anyone?
Speaker 0: but you no one cares.
Speaker 1: plenty of noobs out there Trust me.
Speaker 1: who would very much like a tutorial but they're gonna buy the game.
Speaker 0: Anyway, there's.
Speaker 1: no they already bought the game.
Speaker 1: It doesn't think about.
Speaker 1: they would sell a lot more.
Speaker 0: I Highly doubt.
Speaker 0: having a tutorial in the beta that you only get into if you were an alpha tester or if you bought the game Already is somehow going to cause more people to buy the game.
Speaker 1: Okay, take this example, right?
Speaker 1: Okay, so look at let's say Heroes of Newerth, right?
Speaker 1: That's the beta did not have a tutorial.
Speaker 1: if the beta had a proper tutorial that actually taught The purpose of the beta test is not.
Speaker 0: I mean some people conflated.
Speaker 0: some people use the beta test when they're making game Also as a marketing tool to get the word out and get newbies in.
Speaker 0: But the primary purpose of a beta test is still to make sure game mechanics work and to test basic functionality.
Speaker 1: Yes Okay, so if you have a tutorial and someone actually knows how your game is supposed to work Then they'll actually be able to tell you when something's not working.
Speaker 1: Someone who has no idea what the what the fuck if it's even broken or it doesn't know how to play Will be incapable of telling you what's working and what doesn't work.
Speaker 1: You need to teach them how it's supposed to be in order for them to tell you.
Speaker 0: if it's not correct depends on what kind of beta testing you're doing and what you're looking for.
Speaker 0: and you also.
Speaker 0: part of the thing is watch how People play see what trouble they have and then use that to tailor the tutorial.
Speaker 1: They don't.
Speaker 1: you can't watch how people play though.
Speaker 1: All they can do is send in bug reports They don't have like.
Speaker 1: the only people they have they watch play are the physical testers that are there at their offices.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they probably did a lot of that testing there.
Speaker 0: They don't need this extra feedback.
Speaker 0: I just I don't think the tutorial is that high on the purveyors or a beta is the number one thing?
Speaker 0: of Newark.
Speaker 0: that is the game aimed at people who already played dota and Noobs, but you don't really aim a beta at noobs unless you're doing a very specific marketing strategy.
Speaker 0: You aim the finished product at the noobs.
Speaker 1: I think about this.
Speaker 1: if they had the tutorial if they had the beta aimed at the noobs and they actually gave a tutorial To the noobs right the noobs would not be.
Speaker 1: plus that was even worse right than the Starcraft one because that was a free beta.
Speaker 1: Right, so you get these people.
Speaker 1: they're playing this free beta Which is basically even better than the demo don't.
Speaker 1: and then because you didn't give them a tutorial they turned away And they're just like oh fuck this.
Speaker 1: and then they don't buy it.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem.
Speaker 0: here's of Newark is a terrible example because it was aimed at a specific group of people.
Speaker 0: someone gets Free Scott.
Speaker 0: it was also handled horribly and is a horrible game with a horrible can.
Speaker 1: so someone gets the Starcraft demo for the beta For free.
Speaker 0: got it for free?
Speaker 1: some some noob.
Speaker 0: Why would they get it for free?
Speaker 1: because you can just sign up and get it.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 1: So he signs up.
Speaker 1: he gets to the Starcraft 2 beta.
Speaker 1: all right No tutorial and there's no help.
Speaker 1: and now he doesn't know how to play.
Speaker 1: he plays.
Speaker 1: He just gets his ass kicked.
Speaker 1: He doesn't know what's going on.
Speaker 1: He says I'll fuck this now He never buys it whereas if you had given him a tutorial he would have learned the game Maybe learn to like it and eventually bought it.
Speaker 0: But at the same time they're gonna make so many sales from people who will buy the game anyway that there's probably not worth it To spend the early resources.
Speaker 1: are they gonna make a tutorial anyway?
Speaker 1: probably then you should make it first.
Speaker 0: I think that's stupid.
Speaker 0: You're not stupid.
Speaker 0: fundamental changes to the game in the course of develop.
Speaker 0: So you change a tutorial.
Speaker 0: why waste the effort?
Speaker 0: I don't think you're vastly overestimating the value of a tutorial.
Speaker 0: I think you're vastly under estimating the value of a tutorial especially in a closed beta.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't be giving noobs your beta if you're gonna unless you're beta testing the experience of completely you know unknown.
Speaker 1: That's the number one people you should be getting the experience of.
Speaker 1: is the is the noobs who you know?
Speaker 1: if Nintendo has proved anything It's that appealing to the noobs and the people don't know what the fuck They're doing gets you 10 billion times more sales than appealing to the nerds.
Speaker 0: Stupidly simplistic view of the game development process.
Speaker 0: the the the aspect of like.
Speaker 0: well.
Speaker 0: How do you teach a new player to play?
Speaker 0: What's the tutorial?
Speaker 0: What's the learning curve in the beginning?
Speaker 0: You know all that stuff you track and test separately from basic beta testing like bugs and multiplayer and bet game balance.
Speaker 0: So why I don't think there's any reason to prioritize the former or for the latter because the latter fails.
Speaker 0: the game fails no matter What.
Speaker 0: if the former fails at most you lose the water to people?
Speaker 1: The people who come in.
Speaker 1: I think I think you're underestimating how many noobs are in the beta.
Speaker 1: I think you're overestimating the number of highly skilled people.
Speaker 0: right and Yeah, it depends on the game for one.
Speaker 0: Starcraft is going to sell to so many people if a game is not complicated enough.
Speaker 0: right got Starcraft could have no to no instructions and no tutorial.
Speaker 0: when it really releases and Still make tons of money and sell them it
Speaker 1: would make it made make sell a pittance compared to something like World of Warcraft Right which they probably make a bajillion times more money on because it's easy and the tutorial and any moron can play it Right.
Speaker 1: that is what the gate in Farmville.
Speaker 1: any moron can play this tutorial.
Speaker 1: It's easy Starcraft hard.
Speaker 1: I think Starcraft sales are actually going to be quite disappointing if they don't make it a lot fucking easier.
Speaker 0: I Disagree with that compared to the potential.
Speaker 1: if they had made it all compared to a made-up Potential that you're making up in a potential of World of Warcraft or Farmville it would sell millions and millions of copies.
Speaker 0: But is it compared to the size of my penis?
Speaker 0: I can just make stuff up like you're doing.
Speaker 1: I Think the evidence is clear.
Speaker 1: Games games.
Speaker 1: you look at the track record of the games that have sold in recent history And how many they have sold.
Speaker 1: easy games games tutorials games that anymore?
Speaker 0: there's a difference between an easy game and a game with a tutorial.
Speaker 0: and You're still forgetting the fact that we're talking about Finnish games there versus beta tests.
Speaker 0: They're very very different worlds.
Speaker 1: the more accessible a game is the more it will sell.
Speaker 0: The game is not accessible, but it doesn't necessarily need to be polishedly accessible in alpha and beta testing.
Speaker 1: Yes It does because you're gonna want to test if you're looking to pick up the people.
Speaker 1: Right if you want to get the big sales you need to appeal to not the hard core But to the other people and depends on your game.
Speaker 1: You can't test for those people if they're not playing and those people can't play.
Speaker 1: and there's no to get your oversimplifying.
Speaker 0: I mean you can have an open beta versus up close beta.
Speaker 0: most products will have different phases of the beta like the only reason They have phases of the beta.
Speaker 1: you don't want to know why they have phases of beta.
Speaker 0: some people do it for marketing reasons.
Speaker 1: No, there's only one reason that anyone does betas and phases and the reason is this.
Speaker 1: you do beta phase one, right?
Speaker 1: Everybody reports the one bug the same exact bug.
Speaker 1: you fix it.
Speaker 1: Okay If you don't have another phase of the beta none of those people usually most people report one bug.
Speaker 0: if they report any bug What do you have any evidence of this?
Speaker 0: because I'm at beta test a lot of games I report a shit ton of you're the only one.
Speaker 1: go look at and go look online for like statistics.
Speaker 1: There's plenty of people talking about their beta tests and then the statistics.
Speaker 0: For me some guy on the internet.
Speaker 1: It's not some guy.
Speaker 1: in the Well known beta testing, you know statistics and everything straight up don't believe you?
Speaker 1: Well, that's fine.
Speaker 1: But the truth of the matter is we do a beta test.
Speaker 1: the vast majority of people report zero bugs.
Speaker 1: People who do report a bug report like the first bug they come across and that's it.
Speaker 1: So you do phases of the beta because that way the people sign up they're in phase one.
Speaker 1: They report the one bug in phase one that they all know.
Speaker 0: one example the old MMO the realm.
Speaker 1: If you don't have a phase two or more people those people will just stop playing or they won't report another bug Ever again, so you need a phase two.
Speaker 1: all these new people come in when now that first bug is fixed.
Speaker 1: So now they discover the new bugs.
Speaker 0: They made a new like vert like they're making a new version of the game and they open up the first day of the alpha Testing and they all they started you know, they'd like did many many many phases of the alpha and then the beta and Each phase.
Speaker 0: they were kind of.
Speaker 0: they started with the hardcore players and the developers and people like that to work out kinks and game Balance and then they brought in, you know a wider swatch But still only the kind of experienced players who didn't need any hand-holding and guidance just to get the game polished after all that.
Speaker 0: Then they set up tutorials and all those sorts of things.
Speaker 0: Then they open the beta up to pretty much anyone in the already had an account.
Speaker 0: who wanted to do the beta and how many?
Speaker 1: People did they sell this game to Back then comparatively.
Speaker 0: I don't know offhand.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay, and how many do the really easy moron game?
Speaker 1: But Scott Farville loses millions of players and they're just like, okay, we still have millions millions more.
Speaker 1: so your base It's a moron.
Speaker 0: So you're gonna just completely come.
Speaker 1: no I'm saying is you know?
Speaker 1: because the thing is when I Suggested right that they should have a tutorial the only argument not in the beta The only are you first thing in the bay?
Speaker 1: The reason the reason you gave for they shouldn't have it is that there is no financial incentive.
Speaker 0: No, I said that's a reason why they do.
Speaker 0: that was just a secondary.
Speaker 0: like they don't need it They'll sell just fine.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the real but they won't sell just fine.
Speaker 1: Anyway, easy moron games sell more.
Speaker 1: tutorials make the game easier and more accessible and will increase sales Vastly, there is a huge financial incentive to have this guy.
Speaker 0: I'm talking just about Starcraft.
Speaker 0: I don't think a tutorial make the game sell anymore.
Speaker 1: I think a tutorial make the game sell a lot more.
Speaker 0: but that aside my main the only issue I take that you're taking this weird position on is that Prioritizing the tutorial as the first thing in your alpha and beta testing is ludicrous.
Speaker 1: Why is it ludicrous?
Speaker 0: for all the reasons I said for the last 20 minutes.
Speaker 1: Tutorial is the app you cannot.
Speaker 1: I think you can't even have a game without a tutorial.
Speaker 1: don't even let anyone play unless there's instructions In tutorial, okay.
Speaker 0: I disagree with you 100%.
Speaker 1: Well shows that I will see how well your game sells.
Speaker 0: What about your game?
Speaker 0: Why are you even doing anything in project?
Speaker 0: or if you need a tutorial because there's nothing you can't play it.
Speaker 0: yet There's something there.
Speaker 1: you don't have a tutorial because it's not a game that we've given to anyone.
Speaker 1: So when you get what point are you gonna make the tutorial when we say hey, this game is playable There will be a tutorial.
Speaker 0: so you're so when you do the beta test.
Speaker 0: Hmm as opposed to the alpha like you're gonna I don't think you just have any idea of how game development actually works because this is first of all This is an open-source game with that doesn't have any direction.
Speaker 0: So it's an exception.
Speaker 0: We don't need a tutorial right away.
Speaker 1: You can't even make a tutorial when there's no game to tutorial.
Speaker 0: All right, so when are you gonna make the tutorial?
Speaker 1: There's a game.
Speaker 0: that's got to be the first thing you do as soon as the game is in any way playable Before anyone says here come play this game.
Speaker 1: There will be a tutorial and instructions.
Speaker 0: Alright, I just I think Prioritizing tutorial above other more basic beta testing is a poor way to go about beta testing.
Speaker 0: a large game.
Speaker 1: You don't you know, you're not understanding.
Speaker 1: what I'm saying is you don't hand out the game to people and say hey play Instructions, I mean who do you hand it out to?
Speaker 0: a lot of people do a very closed alpha and then a very closed beta And then they open up the beta more and more as the game gets more polished and they add more of the new friendly stuff As they get to the point where they want to introduce noobs to the more polished game.
Speaker 0: They only want hardcore people testing the shitty version of the game because hardcore people understand that it's a beta.
Speaker 0: new people show them Any beta of any game.
Speaker 0: they'll say what the fuck is this and never play the game again?
Speaker 1: Anyway, let's talk about RTS.
Speaker 1: is we already have kind of mostly?
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't know.
Speaker 1: Is there anything left to say about RTS?
Speaker 1: is that we haven't said you segue back to nothing?
Speaker 1: Well because you turned my minor point into a huge tangent taking up the entire show Because for some reason you think it's moronic to have a tutorial and to make more money by making a game.
Speaker 0: Tutorials are great in Finnish games, but they shouldn't be prioritized at the top of the queue in the beta test.
Speaker 1: I think that you just shouldn't put out a game any of any kind bored video RPG of any kind.
Speaker 1: You should not hand it to people and say play this whether it's beta Anyone in the world you should.
Speaker 1: you should not make your game, you know and tell people play this.
Speaker 1: There are no instructions or tutorials.
Speaker 0: I mean one things about one thing you do in like HCI when you're developing interfaces for things, you know non games for example is You bring people in off the street and do basically Close betas with no tutorial just to see how they flounder and then use that as guidance to make better Interfaces and to change things in.
Speaker 0: whatever it is you're building.
Speaker 1: That's not that's user interface - it's a completely different thing.
Speaker 1: That's like having a focus group.
Speaker 1: you can come in with a focus group and ask people questions about what kind of game For game development, that's what they do.
Speaker 0: They'll have like an in-house beta not even a closed beta where they give out keys But a beta where you can only play the game if you're there and they watch you play it and they ask you shit about It while you're playing it, you know what.
Speaker 1: I would like to point out right that the perhaps most successful Right software and you know design and development companies in the universe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like Apple Nintendo Etc.
Speaker 1: No focus groups.
Speaker 1: No betas.
Speaker 1: No nothing, right?
Speaker 0: You're a hundred percent sure that Microsoft doesn't test beta.
Speaker 1: I didn't say Microsoft.
Speaker 1: Microsoft sucks at design.
Speaker 0: So Apple doesn't test interfaces.
Speaker 1: No focus groups whatsoever zero.
Speaker 1: So what they don't beta?
Speaker 1: test anything to the sky ever.
Speaker 0: Uh, I didn't say to the public.
Speaker 0: you said no beta test at all.
Speaker 0: They beta test but the only difference is they hire people to do the beta testing rather than bringing in people off the street And then making they don't hire people to do the testing.
Speaker 1: They already have the people.
Speaker 1: it's the people that are already there Scott.
Speaker 0: That's a stupid pedantic distinction.
Speaker 1: That is a very important.
Speaker 0: They've hired.
Speaker 0: They have people on staff to do the testing.
Speaker 1: No They're the same people who are or making the thing.
Speaker 0: actually.
Speaker 0: that is against all Principle of HCI is having the same people who designed something tested.
Speaker 1: Yes, but you know what?
Speaker 1: That's what Apple does.
Speaker 0: I don't think that's what they do.
Speaker 0: and unless you cite some evidence.
Speaker 0: I'm calling bullshit on that to go Look it up.
Speaker 0: No, you you're the one who made the claim.
Speaker 0: big cite your bullshit.
Speaker 1: I gotta go find the article but it talks about Apple's design process and basically they just have a Roman Apple employees.
Speaker 0: It's certified as being legit.
Speaker 0: or is this just some like?
Speaker 1: yeah, they're books.
Speaker 1: They're pretty much you can say Apple so secretive, but they're books about Apple And basically it's just a bunch of geniuses and they just do it and then they hope they release it when it's done.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh with zero internal testing from non designers whatsoever.
Speaker 0: It's the people Highly doubt that and I think you're full of shit.
Speaker 1: The point is they don't do beta tests.
Speaker 1: They don't have anything without instructions.
Speaker 1: They don't have anything without a tutorial Nintendo, right?
Speaker 1: Nothing's.
Speaker 1: open everything.
Speaker 1: They do on their own Scott and you want.
Speaker 0: so what's their internal process?
Speaker 0: because they do have beta testers.
Speaker 0: They have closed betas on things internally.
Speaker 0: Why do you think they get all those special?
Speaker 0: Thanks on some of the games?
Speaker 0: They've made in the past?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so but they so they do what you just said.
Speaker 0: they don't.
Speaker 1: everything has instructions and a tutorial.
Speaker 0: How do you know what they gave those original beta testers?
Speaker 1: Everything has instructions.
Speaker 0: You're just making shit up Enough with your tangents, right?
Speaker 1: Oh someone says here that they saw the documentary and it's true.
Speaker 1: They saw the same thing.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: Apple does no betas and they have designed better than anybody.
Speaker 1: They're the best Right, so don't be you know, these people doing this thing.
Speaker 1: That's all.
Speaker 1: that's against the stand.
Speaker 1: They're doing it wrong.
Speaker 0: I'm small.
Speaker 0: I was saying was that internal Apple?
Speaker 0: How do you know that?
Speaker 0: you know person, you know?
Speaker 0: Engineering team designs their face that at some point they don't have someone who is not a member of that engineering team Specifically test the.
Speaker 0: it doesn't matter because that's what I was saying.
Speaker 1: All because the original argument is about tutorials.
Speaker 1: right and the fact is is the Apple the best?
Speaker 1: no one comes even close Blizzard not doing things the way.
Speaker 1: Apple does therefore not as good they should do it.
Speaker 1: Everyone should do things the way the people who are doing it the best are which is tutorials Easy instructions making things more accessible.
Speaker 1: Those are the priorities.
Speaker 1: That's what gets you bigger sales.
Speaker 1: Look at all the things that have come out in recent history the accessible easy thing.
Speaker 0: So then why make a difficult game?
Speaker 0: why make a game?
Speaker 0: That's hard because by definition very difficult games become Inaccessible.
Speaker 1: if I was a big company trying to make money like a public company like Blizzard I wouldn't if I my goal was money.
Speaker 1: I would not make any hard games ever.
Speaker 1: Okay, so my goal was to make awesome games.
Speaker 1: Then I would make a hard game because I like but then you're gonna violate all this stuff you just said.
Speaker 0: So what if Blizzard's just trying to make a good game with Starcraft?
Speaker 1: They're just trying to make a hard game.
Speaker 1: I would still haven't struggles as an easy time But I wouldn't prioritize that as the first thing I would because I if I am I still.
Speaker 1: am I trying to make any money At all or am I doing it as like a labor of life?
Speaker 0: I have.
Speaker 0: I highly doubt that the experiences in the beta test are going to in any way negatively impact the sales of a large game like that.
Speaker 1: I Think that they impact the sales a lot more than you think.
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: Well, you think we're especially not for Starcraft.
Speaker 1: I think for Starcraft definitely.
Speaker 1: There are a lot of people right.
Speaker 1: they sign up for betas because they're the same poor kids who want to pirate the game.
Speaker 1: They just want to play for free before it comes out and then if they don't like that's a bad experience We're gonna buy the game.
Speaker 0: Anyway, they're gonna pirate it.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: Those are people right if they had their.
Speaker 1: Basically, it's like a demo for them.
Speaker 1: Right and if they have a bad experience, they're not even gonna pirate the game.
Speaker 1: They're never gonna play it ever again.
Speaker 1: And if they have a good experience then they're gonna pirate it.
Speaker 0: you make no money either way They can't.
Speaker 1: but the thing is Starcraft has like the whole battle net thing.
Speaker 0: So they're gonna pay for it Scott I know but several of my co-workers have the pre beta that they already pirated and play against each other all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's the beta that they can play against the Pirate the new one and crack it.
Speaker 0: Maybe they can't use battle net.
Speaker 0: They'll still play against each other.
Speaker 0: That's all they care about.
Speaker 1: Then they weren't gonna buy the game.
Speaker 0: Anyway, exactly matters We don't care about them, but they're not.
Speaker 1: are there if they're pirating the game though to play against each other.
Speaker 1: They're not the noobs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just I just think it's a silly design methodology to put a tutorial above every single other thing in your closed beta test.
Speaker 1: So you don't put it above?
Speaker 1: No, I said you absolutely have to have one before you go.
Speaker 0: Wait, I actually have to have one before you start the beta.
Speaker 0: Yes, then you prioritize it above everything else in the beta.
Speaker 1: Not necessarily.
Speaker 1: You need to have the game in there, too.
Speaker 0: I have the tutorial.
Speaker 1: absolutely must have the tutorial and the game in the beta.
Speaker 0: how much of the tutorial?
Speaker 0: so the tutorial says play The game because I didn't finish it yet.
Speaker 0: It's still in beta.
Speaker 0: Does that count?
Speaker 1: the tutorial needs to teach you how to play the game.
Speaker 1: It might have bugs in it because it's beta but it has to be in there.
Speaker 1: So does the game also has to be in there.
Speaker 1: the options menu also has to be.
Speaker 0: you know When I play the a lot of things have to be in when I play the alpha of the realm.
Speaker 0: Just another example because that was the longest beta I was ever in.
Speaker 0: The.
Speaker 0: the first alpha release did not even have characters.
Speaker 0: You were just basically blob sprites walking around.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you shouldn't be releasing something to beta if you don't.
Speaker 0: Yet that was alpha.
Speaker 0: that was yeah.
Speaker 1: alphas are not for the public.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it was just for the hardcore people there.
Speaker 1: they were doing it wrong and That's why they're dead now.
Speaker 0: I think they're dead now because they were the first MMO and all the MMOs that came out from that time died at about the Same time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if Blizzard though had made the first demo in his World of Warcraft It would be where it is now be even bigger than it is now.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is that would have been impossible with technology back then.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it would have looked like Warcraft.
Speaker 0: one Thing is they made it back then.
Speaker 0: I think it still would have died.
Speaker 0: They would have made another more polished version of World of Warcraft later because back then well That's what they've been doing right.
Speaker 0: back then the only people who played MMOs were hardcore gamers.
Speaker 0: already.
Speaker 0: There was no casual market for stuff back then like that.
Speaker 0: PC gaming was this kind of niche area.
Speaker 1: The thing is I think the casual market did exist.
Speaker 1: It was just no one made the casual game to actually open it up.
Speaker 1: So not a single case back then.
Speaker 0: just that the amount of PC ownership was low.
Speaker 1: No, but all those people were still playing solitaire waiting for a different game.
Speaker 1: All those people were playing Tetris waiting for a different game I'm pretty sure.
Speaker 0: all the people who played solitaire However, never moved on to playing anything but solitaire.
Speaker 0: because I see people to this day.
Speaker 1: Those people are playing Farmville now.
Speaker 1: They're playing Farmville and they're playing Bejeweled and they're playing World of Warcraft.
Speaker 0: I think Bejeweled is still like ten leagues above things like Mafia Wars and Farmville.
Speaker 0: Those aren't games.
Speaker 1: Those are just Bejeweled is the same exact thing.
Speaker 1: At least Bejeweled is not even as good as Tetris.
Speaker 0: Of course not.
Speaker 1: I mean Bejeweled isn't even at Sudoku levels.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, what are you trying to say?
Speaker 1: I mean Bejeweled happens to actually be in World of Warcraft, right?
Speaker 1: They actually did that?
Speaker 1: That wasn't like an April Fool's joke.
Speaker 1: That was real?
Speaker 0: That was real.
Speaker 0: Okay I think we're done.
Speaker 0: The moral of this, we suck ass at RTSs.
Speaker 0: We suck so much.
Speaker 0: And when Starcraft comes out for legit We're gonna play against you listeners and you will really really laugh at us.
Speaker 1: I've been playing, you know, a little bit.
Speaker 1: I beat all I beat the I played five times in the practice and I played the Get ranked five games and I ranked really low.
Speaker 1: But I did win some of them.
Speaker 1: because only because the one guy taught me I need to build a lot of SCVs.
Speaker 1: But I have no instructions.
Speaker 1: So if someone wants to send me instructions Like I don't know what I've been only playing Terran because I at least remember more of their stuff from Starcraft 1.
Speaker 1: But I don't know what half the units do like.
Speaker 1: I don't even build like the ghosts cuz I don't know how they work.
Speaker 1: and I Don't like.
Speaker 1: I built a unit once like a whole bunch of them and I was like, oh, yeah I'm gonna win.
Speaker 1: now the unit couldn't attack the ground it was only air to air and I was like, oh shit, and I just lost.
Speaker 1: and You know cuz there were no instructions.
Speaker 1: So whatever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's a beta.
Speaker 0: They're still.
Speaker 0: they're testing all sorts of other things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how about some instructions?
Speaker 1: So if I gave me instructions, I'd be able to help them test and say we're not testing.
Speaker 1: I'm not testing the game.
Speaker 1: I'm testing my stupidity.
Speaker 0: See I haven't looked for instructions.
Speaker 0: Yes I don't know if they're out there or not because I haven't.
Speaker 0: I just haven't bothered looking for him.
Speaker 0: I just kind of figured the game out.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Whatever we're done with this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think we're done.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.
Speaker 0: Oh Hey, it's Tuesday, May 18th, I'm rim.
Speaker 0: Good God.
Speaker 0: Hey, it's Tuesday, May 18th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I wasn't then.
Speaker 1: you honey You already finished.