Speaker 1: It's Thursday July 15th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight, Kineticon 2010.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So technically we were back from Kineticon Tuesday.
Speaker 1: We did that show that was one of the crab ist crab people We've done in a while.
Speaker 0: We were back from Kineticon on Monday.
Speaker 0: We just didn't do a.
Speaker 1: yeah I didn't have my voice back yet.
Speaker 0: I Didn't lose mine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I lose my voice much more readily than you do.
Speaker 1: This is a well-known bit of trivia and geek nights.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna build the skills.
Speaker 1: Yeah, mostly what killed me, you know, we didn't even do that?
Speaker 1: many panels.
Speaker 1: We did like between us.
Speaker 1: We did what like six or seven panels not counting the ones I guess we've kind of threw together at the con.
Speaker 1: I mean the old.
Speaker 0: well, I mean that's pretty much the max we've done not counting the Kineticon where we did a room.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, that was possibly not counting that one time.
Speaker 0: six or seven is like our max.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and even then I don't like to do six or seven.
Speaker 0: I like to do three or four.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because of course it's different at Kineticon because we're actually like the heads of panels Like we're both the co-directors of panels and workshops for Kineticon.
Speaker 0: So we give ourselves that our panels we want.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I actually think we didn't do our panels as well.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe we should talk about that in the other part of the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well all meta but Kineticon, you know wrecked me partly because we had to run around.
Speaker 1: you had the radio on.
Speaker 1: I'm responding to stuff like rim.
Speaker 1: this panel has disappeared.
Speaker 1: rim Microsoft wants a panel in this room But there's someone else already in here that you scheduled.
Speaker 1: We didn't tell you about that.
Speaker 1: so we you know dealing with all that stuff and On top of that doing a bunch of panels and not taking the Monday off Like I usually do after a con like that.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm that about wrecked me.
Speaker 1: So crab people on Tuesday, and I guess we're back.
Speaker 1: I think we're back in our full swing today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're good though.
Speaker 1: I do want to address.
Speaker 1: Several people asked what we meant by crab people at.
Speaker 0: we've explained that like ten times maybe a long time ago And I do.
Speaker 0: they not watch South Park.
Speaker 1: Maybe not or maybe they don't remember.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you what I'm not even gonna tell you again.
Speaker 0: You can either go and find an old episode of.
Speaker 0: you can answer we Explain it or you can go and get the appropriate South Park DVD and listen to the 30-second commentary And you'll figure it out man.
Speaker 1: That commentary really makes me want to get those DVDs just to watch it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even though it's free online.
Speaker 0: That's pretty much like normally.
Speaker 0: I don't watch commentary on anything except South Park firefly.
Speaker 1: I watched the commentary whatever and a doctor horrible because it was a. basically it was an alternate musical to the musical.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what it was just sung commentary.
Speaker 1: I know you don't like anything good like firefly and doctor anything bad.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the South Park commentary is great.
Speaker 1: They talk for like 30 seconds.
Speaker 0: Maybe maybe a minute Maybe but the thing is they don't do it for the whole episode.
Speaker 0: So it's like it's basically like when you read a webcomic and then you buy the book of the webcomic and there's like a little Note under each comic.
Speaker 0: like yeah, I wrote this and I was drunk.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, this is this game used to be awesome.
Speaker 0: Hey, whatever happened to that, you know And I like the penny arcade books exactly.
Speaker 0: So that's that's what South Park DVD commentary is like and it's totally worth it.
Speaker 0: They should put it on.
Speaker 0: if it I'd say they should put it on the website, but then why would anyone buy the DVD?
Speaker 1: So I feel like a long time ago We were trying to do a geek nights DVD and that that petered out mostly for the fact that it's infeasible Even just the technologically speaking even if we did per topic in low quality.
Speaker 1: We cannot fit them on DVDs.
Speaker 0: We'd had to use blu-rays, but then what's the point?
Speaker 1: or USB sticks, but then it's too expensive Yeah, and we were talking about well Maybe we'll just do like a selection and a value add.
Speaker 1: if we ever do commentary on geek night someday We'll just have to listen to an episode and do like the one minute.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that episode sucked.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean like a DVD is for gigs like even if we got cheap one gig USB sticks not gonna cut it We need 16 gig sticks or something like that.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be ridiculous.
Speaker 1: So you were you were talking up like you got something you can say some open event some way to roll the show in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, you know I've had some.
Speaker 0: You know, I am a healthy person.
Speaker 1: Oh god this again the fungus.
Speaker 0: But you know, I don't.
Speaker 0: I you know, I have some medical issues but they're never medical issues that actually are like.
Speaker 0: You know for serious like I need to go to an emergency room or I need to take a medicine or you know Anything like that.
Speaker 1: There was that one time you had the the injury from the Fight Club at RIT.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, right.
Speaker 0: But you know, that was a. that wasn't an illness.
Speaker 0: That was a physical.
Speaker 0: There's a wound.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyone can get wounded.
Speaker 0: I mean in fact only men get wounded.
Speaker 0: Getting wounded is manly.
Speaker 0: that's better than being just healthy.
Speaker 1: So well manly doesn't have anything to do with gender.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I'm obviously if you've listened to any of our shows about Randy ness, right?
Speaker 0: I'm obviously not someone who you know is like an old guy who doesn't want to go to the doctor when he's actually Never understand those people.
Speaker 0: if I want to go to the doctor.
Speaker 0: Trust me the only time I got a problem I gotta go there.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing one.
Speaker 1: I don't go to the dentist when I should I go.
Speaker 0: I didn't go to the in.
Speaker 0: the thing is I didn't go to the doctor or the dentist.
Speaker 1: No, it was a pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: not cuz I didn't want to cuz I didn't have time.
Speaker 0: I was moving.
Speaker 0: I was conventioning I had something going on every weekend.
Speaker 0: I was busy at work.
Speaker 0: I couldn't take a time off from work.
Speaker 1: Even now we've cut a lot of conventions out of our schedule and I look at it and it still wrecks me.
Speaker 1: I look back to when we would go to like 12 conventions over the course of a year.
Speaker 0: We should look and look at exactly each year and figure out which year was the busiest.
Speaker 1: I think we peaked like.
Speaker 1: remember that one year.
Speaker 1: We even went to freakin anime next.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the thing is that year we went to anime next.
Speaker 0: we didn't also do like anime boss now, but we did do course.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, we did anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I went to the dentist right a couple weeks ago And of course, right, you know, this is this is some advice for anyone out there.
Speaker 1: You're gonna say and I quote I quote a very important music video brush your teeth brush.
Speaker 0: Well, no, I brush my fucking teeth.
Speaker 0: What the fuck do you think this is?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: and no is that you know, even if it means like taking a day off from work when it's super busy or You know losing a weekend or something Don't not go to the dentist.
Speaker 0: cuz even me brushing and flossing I had filling so the one dentist Appointment turned into three because I had to go for the left side and then on Saturday and going for the right side You know, and so today I went to the doctor for the first time, you know to get some side of the stuff checked
Speaker 1: out.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I noticed your little.
Speaker 1: uh, they took blood.
Speaker 0: They stole my magical blood.
Speaker 0: I don't know what they're gonna do.
Speaker 1: They're gonna grow a race of supermen They were.
Speaker 0: they asked me do you want to test for STDs?
Speaker 0: and I'm like, I don't know if that'll be necessary.
Speaker 0: Is that gonna be?
Speaker 0: I was like, I mean if it doesn't cost anything extra and if it's no extra trouble for you I mean you can answer not you'd better test me for all of them.
Speaker 0: No, the doctor was like are you sexually active?
Speaker 0: I'm like not.
Speaker 0: right now, do you know anybody?
Speaker 0: But you know the thing is part.
Speaker 0: another reason that I didn't go to a doctor right is cuz when you're growing up you've got A doctor because your parents get a doctor for you, right and you stay with that doctor like all the way through high school.
Speaker 0: Probably yeah, right, but then you leave but you go to college.
Speaker 1: you go to college You get that nurse for like a couple years.
Speaker 0: Well, no you go to college and the school usually has doctors So you don't need to find one you just go to the school doctor Like you go to the school nurse when you're in high school, right?
Speaker 0: So when I was at RIT and I had the wounded leg I went to the RIT doctor and they were like are you in a fight club?
Speaker 1: and then campus safety came by later and they Were like will you sign that you're not in a fight club?
Speaker 0: I'm like, yeah.
Speaker 0: No, I should have told campus safety I'm in ten fight clubs.
Speaker 0: I'm the fight club champion.
Speaker 1: You should be like, where do you think I got this?
Speaker 0: Where do you think I had these trophies?
Speaker 1: You should have made a trophy
Speaker 0: a broken piece of a bicycle from them from the front foyer anyway, so Part of the reason I didn't go to a doctor since I you know left RIT, you know I think I went to a doctor once and I just picked the one that was closest to the house in Beacon Right is because I didn't know what doctor to go to.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's a lot of doctors and you go to the insurance company's website And how do you know which one is good?
Speaker 0: there could be you know?
Speaker 0: I've heard of real doctors telling you to get the acupuncture and the chiropractic and the homeopathy, right?
Speaker 0: So if I can't even trust a real doctor, who do I you know?
Speaker 0: I really don't want to waste my one doctor visit on a BS doc.
Speaker 1: Well, the BS doctor sucks.
Speaker 1: Just go to another doctor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then the insurance is like why did you go to two doctors?
Speaker 0: And I'm like the first doctor sucked Like we ain't covering that second doctor.
Speaker 0: and you know what.
Speaker 0: you know how much I paid to go to the doctor today $20, you know what the says on the bill like 400 something right?
Speaker 0: I could have gotten like two or three wheeze I could have gotten like nine video games for the price of the doctor if I didn't have any right.
Speaker 0: and that's the reduced insurance Rate because people don't know this right, but let's say you go to the doctor right and the doctor is $500.
Speaker 0: I'm picking a nice even number, right?
Speaker 0: If you go with insurance, not only does the insurance pay for most of it except the copay or whatever they're gonna do But the price is actually lower.
Speaker 0: So the insurance would only give them 300 and you give them 20 and the doctor actually makes less money When you're paying with insurance than if you're paying with cash, right and that's why insurance is a scam.
Speaker 0: It's BS.
Speaker 1: It's not so much that it's a scam That's like that.
Speaker 1: collusive business practices like that are problematic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's like if I went to the gas station and I had a Ford so the gas was a dollar a gallon But I have at a Chevy it'd be three dollars.
Speaker 1: I think we need gas neutrality.
Speaker 0: I think we definitely need you know doctor price neutrality.
Speaker 0: the price of a physical should be the price.
Speaker 0: there should be this bargain.
Speaker 0: Oh negotiating.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we can do it based on weight more person.
Speaker 0: Let's not turn that into the show.
Speaker 1: alright, so so you're.
Speaker 0: so because of busyness and because of Untrusting and wearing this of Randy doctors.
Speaker 0: I delayed going to the doctor but went to the doctor today and you know what the way.
Speaker 0: I picked the doctor as it went to the insurance company's website and I picked the one that was close to work that had the letter E because apparently e according to the insurance company website says that they adhere to evidence-based medicine practices like a Certain percentage of the time more than other doctors.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: I wish I had a metric like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was just a symbol that was like e or not e there wasn't any sort of number Etosiated with it and you know what the doctor I went to is probably the best doctor I ever went to.
Speaker 0: it was like They'd like the perfect doctor and I was kind of worried when I walked in.
Speaker 0: cuz it was like NYU and I'm like Oh shit that I accidentally go to the college doctor.
Speaker 0: I'm not a student, but I saw old people in there.
Speaker 0: So I Students now just old real old people and apparently as opposed to fake old people The only reason it's NYU is because it used to be st.
Speaker 0: Vincent's apparently but he's like.
Speaker 0: you probably heard that st Vincent's went under.
Speaker 0: if you've been in New York, I'm like, no, I only been here for like a little while.
Speaker 0: I didn't know anything about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but apparently it just means that the doctors are also faculty.
Speaker 0: That's all it means.
Speaker 0: So alright, it was totally.
Speaker 0: if anyone needs doctoring.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I guess there's laws about recommending doctors, isn't there?
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 0: But anyway, it was a cool doctor.
Speaker 0: but now I've got a referral to the dermatologist to check on my the fungus fungus in the hair and You know, I got another referral for another doctor.
Speaker 0: So I will see what's going on.
Speaker 0: I never had referrals before.
Speaker 1: so now now that's cuz we're old.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're old But otherwise, I was completely healthy like the doctor started asking me questions and I was like, you know It was like you're taking an oral exam not an oral exam.
Speaker 0: I'm like, you know He's looking in your mouth but an oral exam like a test in school where you say the answers.
Speaker 0: and he was like Do you drink alcohol?
Speaker 0: I'm like, nope.
Speaker 0: He's like you drink coffee.
Speaker 0: I'm like, no, I'm winning here.
Speaker 0: I got all these like the exercise easy.
Speaker 1: Like do you drink orange juice?
Speaker 1: Oh shit Man, it was like.
Speaker 0: he's like do you exercise?
Speaker 0: I'm like I didn't but now I'm biking to work.
Speaker 0: So mmm my win.
Speaker 0: I was like I beat you doctor you lose.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's like damn it.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's a fat guy coming in next got him.
Speaker 1: yep, that's right, so Otakon has done something that anime Expo should have done and Because of the nature of the culture pretty much every convention should be doing this.
Speaker 0: Every intelligent convention is already doing in advance because they have foresight and thinking in their brains.
Speaker 1: Yep The vuvuzela is not welcome at Otakon.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Well the thing is, all right, so they get All right.
Speaker 0: banning the vuvuzela is is well and good right but the thing is shouldn't they just ban all they already do not All noise-making devices other than you know, I mean he's got well.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing.
Speaker 1: most cons have bans already against disruptive behavior and against like all you know A generic kind of statement about noise makers and things.
Speaker 1: I think the purpose of this vuvuzela specific ban is that because of the culture right now people are like like I've seen if I was poking around because People are split weirdly about this ban.
Speaker 1: A lot of people are like damn Otakon taking away my fun.
Speaker 0: I think that the vuvuzela should only be banned if you you know, you should be allowed to bring one in and I don't think You should.
Speaker 0: here's why are you ready?
Speaker 1: If the crowd is big enough, you cannot deal with it quick enough.
Speaker 0: Here's why What if I the Otakon has this musical area right?
Speaker 0: what if I am bringing in my vuvuzela for legitimate music playing purposes?
Speaker 1: So, you know what?
Speaker 0: I mean I could bring in a trumpet right and I could say and they would totally let me in because I'm gonna go play Music in that band area right?
Speaker 0: They have the band area, don't they?
Speaker 0: So here's the way they would they wouldn't even question that.
Speaker 0: but if I play my trumpet in an annoying way in the otterbean lobby And pissed everyone the hell off then you may confiscate my trumpet or my badge.
Speaker 1: No, the only reason I disagree with that and I think this is a very pragmatic policy Is that you know what goes on at these cons, you know, what's going to happen?
Speaker 1: No one and also a vuvuzela can play a flat B flat.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I'm gonna make the argument that if you can only play one moat and one note you don't get in.
Speaker 0: Oh So any instrument is okay that can play more than one note.
Speaker 1: even a snare drums got two notes.
Speaker 0: Are you ready for this rim?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna beat your policy so fast.
Speaker 0: All right How do you think I'm gonna do this?
Speaker 0: Can you guess?
Speaker 1: I don't know because I'll just ban Whatever you say I'm banning.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna drill a hole in my vuvuzela.
Speaker 1: All right You know what if you now place two notes open hole closed hole and then we ban you for being disruptive and that's the end Of that.
Speaker 0: that's fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I still I you know, it's like okay.
Speaker 0: pragmatically you got to just ban anyone The yaoi paddle before and that saved us a lot of BS, you know I don't know what the harm is in the actual yaoi paddle hitting each other with them.
Speaker 1: It's just mechanism design It's the.
Speaker 0: if anyone hits anyone you should just kick them out and ban them forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I don't know it's it's a younger demographic.
Speaker 1: I was actually I was a little.
Speaker 1: we didn't ban them at Kinetic on.
Speaker 0: in fact The penalty should be you get hit but whoa, but I know it's consensual hitting.
Speaker 0: What's the problem?
Speaker 1: You know often I was radioing back.
Speaker 1: I'll be like there's a girl dressed like this blue vuvuzela unless you just blew it.
Speaker 1: if you see her blow it anywhere kick Her out.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they actually kicked anyone out, but we kept the vuvuzela under.
Speaker 0: There was like a couple of them early on but then they were gone.
Speaker 1: But of course we only had you know 7,000 to 8,000 people.
Speaker 0: Okay, so Otakon is like four of those.
Speaker 0: so it's for Kinetic on simultaneously, but also much denser.
Speaker 1: I mean even if someone in the middle of a crowd is like vuvuzela By the time you get to them, he's dropped it.
Speaker 1: He's passed it to someone else.
Speaker 1: You can't get it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just a matter of.
Speaker 0: there's a conflict between my idealistic You know, this is how it should be done.
Speaker 0: This is what's right and what's practical to be done.
Speaker 1: And I I will say this having been the head of panels for Kinetic on this year Practicality will win out every time with me for pretty much the rest of my life Mmm, most of the time in most cases.
Speaker 1: So what's scary is that a lot of people like it seems like it's split like 70/30 like 70% of the people out there are like, yes Thank you for banning these god-awful things or people are like I was at anime Expo.
Speaker 1: It was I don't want to even remember it, but there's people like a small minority who are really angry about this.
Speaker 0: alright, I Mean they got rid of the hug signs and they got rid of oh my god Kinetic on.
Speaker 0: well, I don't see.
Speaker 0: I can understand right the obvious Prostitution proximity kind of situation.
Speaker 0: but really what is a hugs unless someone is hugging people?
Speaker 0: Unsolicited hugging right?
Speaker 0: What is the harm?
Speaker 1: I've got in cons ban and because specifically of the legal liability.
Speaker 1: That's the only reason.
Speaker 0: that's fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have no problem with that.
Speaker 0: But the thing is when people were discussing the hug sign at Kinetic on they were not bringing up that particular reason.
Speaker 1: Same thing we're talking about like the meme show.
Speaker 0: they were to bring up that reason and say yes There is a legal liability with the hug sign.
Speaker 0: I would say fine get rid of it.
Speaker 1: But if they say we're banning the hug sign because but note at the Scott the discussion at Kinetic on We don't ban hugs.
Speaker 0: I know but there are people who's saying we should.
Speaker 1: yeah people in the audience.
Speaker 1: But they they can say what they want.
Speaker 1: It's a con feedback.
Speaker 0: All right, that's fine Yeah, and but if you say ban it cuz it creeps me out It's like well, should we ban the furry costume because it creeps you out too.
Speaker 1: I mean, come on You gotta be pragmatic about it.
Speaker 1: really look at the demographic of the convention.
Speaker 1: You look at past behavior like say the hug thing Like we see like demonstrably this hug thing is causing a problem.
Speaker 1: then the next year we can say look look what happened last year.
Speaker 1: There's no way out of this.
Speaker 1: but to ban it.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: That's right about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right, it's Thursday.
Speaker 1: You can talk about whatever you want.
Speaker 0: Oh, I do have a news, right?
Speaker 0: All right, so I'm sure everyone knows.
Speaker 0: I'm sure everyone knows about Rim your band from geek night.
Speaker 0: All right, so everyone knows about Old Spice Guy, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, and is it his epic geek nights like display of making like an internet video every four minutes?
Speaker 1: Oh my god, right.
Speaker 0: and you know, the thing is, you know, I applaud their skills, right?
Speaker 0: They obviously had people who were excellent writers of jokes.
Speaker 0: They had an excellent actor an excellent set excellent, you know production crew to put out these videos so quickly.
Speaker 0: they had Excellent internet people who knew what was up like.
Speaker 0: they knew what anonymous was and they knew you know They knew what was popular and they were covering Facebook and even nerdy things like reddit.
Speaker 0: right places normal people don't even know exist Looking for comments to respond to on YouTube, you know, they they had it down.
Speaker 0: They were all very smart people with the skill.
Speaker 1: I see where you're going with this Let's see.
Speaker 0: So I applaud their great talents and excellent productions and and providing everyone with awesome entertainment.
Speaker 1: I ask you a question.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna see if I'm on the right track.
Speaker 1: Do you wear Old Spice?
Speaker 0: exactly Is this gonna sell them any Old Spice, you know, I mean it seems like this is the new thing.
Speaker 0: It's gonna definitely has brand awareness if they want people to know what Old Spice is people didn't know if they wanted people to know That Old Spice has body wash.
Speaker 0: Guess what?
Speaker 0: I know that now I thought it was just deodorant.
Speaker 0: now I know they have body wash.
Speaker 0: Yeah, am I gonna buy Old Spice body wash?
Speaker 0: not a chance in hell.
Speaker 1: Well, the reason I don't is that it smells like old.
Speaker 0: They should make New Spice.
Speaker 0: I might at least try it once.
Speaker 0: At the very least I would go into the grow to the drugstore open it and take a whiff.
Speaker 1: you do a cross-brand, right?
Speaker 1: It's New Spice on the cover Dune Treachery.
Speaker 1: They have to have two flavors.
Speaker 1: I try new treachery body wash from the makers of spice.
Speaker 1: It comes in it comes in sandworm and No amount of advertising over changing me.
Speaker 1: I wear.
Speaker 1: I don't wear antiperspirant screw that and I just wear basically unscented antibacterial deodorant that Deodorant.
Speaker 0: but it has a scent and I switch between red green and blue.
Speaker 0: Mine has a slight scent but is basically the scent of the antibacterial thing is I don't know what the difference is between the red green And blue.
Speaker 0: they're all basically the same.
Speaker 1: Is it like diamond?
Speaker 0: one of them is like one of them is like Arctic something and the other one is Friday.
Speaker 1: even now I tended to go with the Arctic something because every brain is their Arctic equivalent.
Speaker 0: It's a blue one.
Speaker 1: I because that was the least like offensive.
Speaker 0: I think one of them is like active sport something which is Whatever.
Speaker 1: I use my adidas.
Speaker 0: But yeah I think that you know, I'm still waiting for the time when people figure out that Advertising as a whole is sort of a scam.
Speaker 0: right advertising sort of works when you put it on TV because you know It basically hypnotizes and brainwashes stupid people into buying something.
Speaker 0: But it's not gonna.
Speaker 0: it doesn't work on internet people.
Speaker 0: I want to see statistics.
Speaker 1: Do you know you're you're positing?
Speaker 1: I don't disagree with you necessarily, but we don't have data.
Speaker 0: I would be incredibly surprised.
Speaker 0: I want to see data.
Speaker 0: show me the sales of old spice.
Speaker 0: now Here's the thing it might be thrown off Right there might.
Speaker 0: here are some factors that might make it look like old spice sales increased when they did not ready.
Speaker 0: factor number one that might makes old spice look like it's selling more is There's a middleman the drugstore the Duane Reade and they might be convinced because of this campaign that old spice is going to sell More and they might order extra old spice body wash.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because I guess I don't know what I guess they do.
Speaker 1: it like the book industry.
Speaker 0: there is no evidence We need numbers from the drugstore of how old spice sells through to the customer.
Speaker 0: This is actually that happens to comics allies.
Speaker 0: If you look at comic sales figures, it tells you how many copies of the book are sold to the comic shop.
Speaker 0: It doesn't tell you how many are sold through.
Speaker 1: the same thing happened when you TSR back in the day.
Speaker 1: their D&D books like sold Well for a while and then every bookstore had like one full set of D&D books that never sold again.
Speaker 1: And eventually I got shipped back to TSR.
Speaker 0: That's what happened to the anime.
Speaker 0: That's happened to the manga.
Speaker 0: That's why media play couldn't pay its bills to all the anime companies because they bought put all this anime on the shelf that they didn't Sell through, you know comic books.
Speaker 0: They'll tell you all.
Speaker 0: we sold a zillion Batman's.
Speaker 0: But then you go to the convention and you see all the quarter bins the 50 cent bins The dollar bins are filled with those issues of Batman booster gold because the comic book store bought too many copies Right, and that is the thing there.
Speaker 0: So that's that's one thing that could throw off the sales.
Speaker 1: Our supposition is that this guy has basically sold himself, but not old spice.
Speaker 0: This guy is gonna have awesome acting.
Speaker 1: I want to get him at a con.
Speaker 1: Oh, absolutely like magfest or something weird.
Speaker 0: Oh, dude at magfest with the Duke Nukem guy, but balls of spice.
Speaker 0: Oh my god It would just be epic with the entertainment value.
Speaker 0: Oh my god It's like they've done a really good job of making a TV show.
Speaker 0: They've done a really bad job of selling old spice.
Speaker 0: In fact, did you see the reply from this great awesome dude who did?
Speaker 0: he was like duff men.
Speaker 0: You see that guy?
Speaker 1: Oh, no, I didn't.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, that guy's awesome.
Speaker 0: You got to check this guy.
Speaker 0: I'll check this out.
Speaker 0: He's on boy.
Speaker 0: I'll show you when the show is over.
Speaker 1: So right on two things of the day.
Speaker 1: I I feel stupid.
Speaker 1: I saw this picture the thing that is my thing of the day and I immediately realized that I am not A good problem solver because remember we lived in colony at RIT.
Speaker 1: We had that shitty electric oven.
Speaker 1: I think was like the worst oven ever and it was like super uneven.
Speaker 1: the my thing of the day is the instructions how to make a map of your broiler and Then you can or even a map of your oven and you can just use this To know where the hot spots and cold spots are in your oven, you know Just take a pan cover it in slices of bread Put it in turn it on wait until like somewhere turns black pull it out take a picture of it.
Speaker 0: broiler map Darker is hotter, you know, it would work better if you had one big bread.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's not it was in the crust wouldn't you know, I'm the kind of person who's made one big bread.
Speaker 1: I probably already have a good oven.
Speaker 0: the other thing this doesn't count for broiling but for baking at least.
Speaker 0: I have the baking sheet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, really helps out and it's a gas oven that helps out even more.
Speaker 0: Anyway, is that it?
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: It's cool I like this.
Speaker 1: All
Speaker 0: right, I have for you an open letter to the French Parliament originally published in 1845 1845 it is a petition for the manufacturers of candles tapers lanterns sticks street lamps snuffers and extinguishers frontiers and from the producers of tallow oil resin alcohol and generally of everything connected with lighting.
Speaker 0: and Basically, this is one of those things from the olden days where you say more shit changes more shit stays the same.
Speaker 1: Here's the exact.
Speaker 1: that was the year the rubber band was invented.
Speaker 1: What yeah, that was the year the Raven by Edgar Allan Poe was published for the first time.
Speaker 1: That was the year at least.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically this art this this letter to Parliament talks about, you know, man There's some guys.
Speaker 0: they're making candles in another country we under far superior conditions and they're flooding the domestic market with candles at an incredibly low price and it's hurting our business, right and Let's see the rival which is none other than the Sun is waging war on us So mercilessly that we suspect he is being stirred up against us by perfidious Albion Particularly because he has for that haughty island a respect that he does not show for us.
Speaker 0: And we ask you to be so good as to pass a law requiring the closing of all windows dormers skylights Inside and outside shutters curtains casements bull's-eyes Deadlights and blinds.
Speaker 0: in short all openings holes chinks and fissures Through which the light of the Sun is want to enter houses to the detriment of the fair industries With which we are proud to say we have endowed the country a country that cannot without betraying and gratitude Abandoned us today to so unequal a combat.
Speaker 0: Wow, and that's just part of this letter.
Speaker 0: I How relevant?
Speaker 0: is that today to say?
Speaker 0: I don't know drms Right and other such things.
Speaker 1: I think more to the point is that look at the level of discourse or Outsourcing things to India or China, right?
Speaker 0: This is so incredibly relevant to all these things.
Speaker 0: It's like look, this is the reality of the world.
Speaker 0: We shouldn't make laws that Basically illegal eyes the reality of nature and the world except for Vuzela for the benefit of business.
Speaker 0: Right, it's like yes, we must outlaw, you know computers have this magical ability, right?
Speaker 0: You know therefore and that is hurting business, which has relied on that ability not existing.
Speaker 0: Therefore.
Speaker 0: We need to outlaw that.
Speaker 0: It's like if Wizards invented the flying spell.
Speaker 0: So in order for the airlines to stay in business, we need to outlaw wizardry.
Speaker 0: That's what you know.
Speaker 0: Because copying has now become possible.
Speaker 0: We need to outlaw copying so we can continue to sell CDs and DVDs because really that's not working out for us.
Speaker 0: It's the same as this which is let's outlaw the Sun so we can sell more candles, right?
Speaker 0: This is obviously a satirical letter, but it applies so well today, you know, how can you ignore me fair?
Speaker 1: You don't know.
Speaker 1: you could go back to that day.
Speaker 1: That guy has got like cannons pointed like every day He's firing cannons at the Sun getting just that much closer to taking it out once and for all.
Speaker 1: uh-huh, so The meta moment that I almost forgot about all right coming up The Otacon is the 30th.
Speaker 1: It is this what we are next next weekend Not this weekend not next weekend But the following.
Speaker 0: we just say what date.
Speaker 1: it is July 30th 31st and 1st, but sadly we have announcement We will not be attending Otacon or performing any of our panels this year in any capacity whatsoever, really?
Speaker 1: Sadly, they don't have a panel schedule announced yet And we kind of passed all of our deadlines for setting up our own stuff.
Speaker 1: So there's really nothing we can do.
Speaker 1: We hope we'll be there at Otacon 2011.
Speaker 1: I apologize to all of the listeners who have emailed me or have responded to our Twitter about the fact that we won't be there
Speaker 0: or anyone who has gone to Otacon expecting us to be there and you know if we were a factor in your decision to Go,
Speaker 1: so I would recommend in the very least You should check out Darryl Sarad will be there doing some panels with the anime world order crew and I'm I'm assuming Mike tool Will be there doing his awesome stuff.
Speaker 1: So go and have fun.
Speaker 1: Tell us how it is, but It's basically.
Speaker 1: sadly no one in the front row crew is going to.
Speaker 1: Otacon Did independent of us our entire like circle of friends and our staff and everyone's been going every year since 2000.
Speaker 1: They all bailed on us like months ago.
Speaker 1: So Scott and I were gonna be the only ones going anyway.
Speaker 0: So they're pretty much three other.
Speaker 0: besides the lateness of the schedule which pretty much sealed us not going There are three other reasons we didn't know about.
Speaker 0: it wasn't until this morning that we had to give up But we would be remiss to not mention all of the four reasons of not going, you know.
Speaker 0: The first reason late schedule right.
Speaker 0: reason number two is that we're in New York City and we don't have cars anymore.
Speaker 0: So going to Otacon is much more difficult for us than it was in the past.
Speaker 0: I mean if we still had cars or relive closer We may still have gone.
Speaker 1: this is part of the part of the reason why we've really moved on to Anime Boston because we cut out, you know anime next and all that because we can just fly there really easily.
Speaker 0: Yeah, reason number three is the same reason that our all of our friends have bailed which is not mailing the badges.
Speaker 0: still I mean, right.
Speaker 1: There's nothing we can do about that.
Speaker 0: And then reason number four is Simply that Otacon isn't really that good to us.
Speaker 0: other conventions.
Speaker 0: anime Boston gives us hundreds of dollars to go right and they're actually the only ones who pass actual money.
Speaker 0: But you look at Kineticon, you know Kineticon, you know, they they love us.
Speaker 1: They made us the heads of panels.
Speaker 1: So right either we did something right or they're setting us up for some horrible fall.
Speaker 0: They're gonna murder us, you know packs, you know gives us what we need and it's you know I'm not saying oh you need to kiss our feet to get us to show up.
Speaker 0: You know, not every convention we go helps though when magfest emailed me.
Speaker 0: That was a really nice email guys Yeah, you know, I mean, you know, obviously it helps but it's not necessary.
Speaker 0: You know we go into Otacon because we want to entertain the fans of Otacon.
Speaker 0: We don't go for us.
Speaker 0: We go for the people there to bring them a better convention.
Speaker 0: But you know, we can't go if you really you need can't?
Speaker 0: you know, we're not asking for money.
Speaker 0: That's something anime Boston happens to give us.
Speaker 0: We would still go to anime Boston without it.
Speaker 0: We're not asking for hotels or comps or anything like that.
Speaker 0: You know a free badge, I guess might be necessary and Skipping the line is necessary.
Speaker 0: But that's right.
Speaker 0: If you give us that we're good, you know.
Speaker 0: But Otacon really they just make it hard for us to go.
Speaker 0: It's like they put up blocks in our way.
Speaker 1: It mostly just comes down to the scheduling from that and that front.
Speaker 1: like for my interactions.
Speaker 1: It's the only con where we actually submit panels and then wait for response and then, you know But they won't it, you know all that stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, they just have like a conference call a few months ahead of time.
Speaker 1: We sort it all out.
Speaker 0: They make it difficult for us.
Speaker 0: if they would make it easy like New York Anime Festival What do they give us?
Speaker 0: They're not giving us anything except for panels, right?
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: They don't give us anything and that golden badge But no, but I mean they give us basically the same thing Otacon gives us.
Speaker 0: They don't give us anything different from them except, you know Otacon makes it hard for us to go where New York Anime Festival makes it easy.
Speaker 1: one thing with the New York Anime Festival comic-con is that They make it very easy to attend partly due to the fact that the seven train goes almost all the way to the Javits.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean if I lived in in Baltimore or close to it, you know DC I'd probably go to Otacon and not New York Anime Festival because it's the same treatment.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe I would go.
Speaker 0: I would probably would have gone this year because the double Megacon Yeah, but I probably never would have gone in the past ever, you know, but that's just how it is.
Speaker 1: Yep So again, we apologize.
Speaker 1: I know a lot of you expect us to do panels.
Speaker 1: None of the front row crew are really gonna be there.
Speaker 1: So try to bother Dave and Joel and Daryl and Mike tool Pax prime is sold out sold out and is Labor Day weekend.
Speaker 1: We're gonna be there doing Seattle doing at least two panels.
Speaker 1: All we can announce right now is we're doing egregiously unrealized potential Which is I like to call it the act eraser panel All right, and we're doing a game mechanics and mechanism design, which is pretty much the hardest core Like all right.
Speaker 1: you assholes you want us to talk about the theory straight up.
Speaker 1: Let's go.
Speaker 0: So this is a this is a game of imperfect information.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're gonna.
Speaker 1: we're gonna.
Speaker 1: actually, you know, every time we do a panel we're like this is a zero-sum Perfect information.
Speaker 1: So game theory blah and then we just talk about games.
Speaker 1: This time we're gonna like game theory blah game theory game theory game theory game theory game.
Speaker 0: This is a prisoner's dilemma This is a Nash equilibrium This is a coffee grinder, oh wait Oh That looks like World of Warcraft to me.
Speaker 1: we have a couple other events.
Speaker 1: we're gonna be doing big New York.
Speaker 0: And if this festival New York Comic Con combo con Friday and Saturday at the New York and invisible comic-con.
Speaker 1: We're going to be doing Pretty much as many panels and things that we can't announce yet, dude I need at least like three hours to walk around both of those mega exhibit halls.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's all I need, you know.
Speaker 1: Well, luckily, hopefully if we do that the screening room thing that we're still sorting out That's easy.
Speaker 1: You walk in.
Speaker 1: Hey, this is blah blah blah blah five minutes.
Speaker 1: You're out of there.
Speaker 1: Now you got two hours to go wander around.
Speaker 0: Okay, the only other metas we have are that The the Studio Ghibli movie based on Earthsea which reportedly was okay ish is gonna be in theaters soon Of course, it's limited run, you know, New York City LA whatever.
Speaker 0: We'll probably go see it.
Speaker 0: I guess I don't know.
Speaker 0: I have some other local New York City events, but they're technology related.
Speaker 0: So I'll tell you about them on Monday.
Speaker 0: and The book club is the lies of Locke Lamora.
Speaker 0: Maybe the next Thursday episode of the one after that cuz rim actually read.
Speaker 0: you finish it.
Speaker 1: Yeah a while ago.
Speaker 0: Holy crap He actually read the book.
Speaker 0: It's a miracle.
Speaker 1: You know, I'd finished cosmos way early - no you didn't.
Speaker 0: you said you were still reading it.
Speaker 1: I was reading like over parts again to remember like what I liked what to talk about.
Speaker 0: Anyway, maybe we'll have book clubs a lot more often if we continue this trend.
Speaker 0: It'll be it'll be good.
Speaker 1: Yeah Have any of you read it yet?
Speaker 0: No, no, maybe not.
Speaker 0: I read.
Speaker 0: So we did news thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Okay, Connecticut As you know, we've said that we're we are the heads of panels for Connecticut.
Speaker 1: We're gonna try to not do talk about meta con stuff in any way until we've talked about the con from the fan perspective because it's very easy for us to talk about cons from this kind of professional staff guest Perspective and It's a stupid review like we went to the New York Anna festival that one year where they even like gave us guest billing and everything.
Speaker 1: What kind of review of the con is?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, they took us right in.
Speaker 1: they gave us free badges.
Speaker 1: They let us do whatever we wanted.
Speaker 1: That's not that's not useful to you.
Speaker 1: No, it's also kind of dickish.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so Connecticut is a. for anyone who doesn't know a lot of our listeners are actually Surprisingly really interested in Connecticut because this year we published the schedule after we'd finished it in our own forum and a lot of people who you know, don't live in the States don't live around here saw it and The response we got from these people was overwhelming it generally.
Speaker 1: I'll sum them all up into one sentence.
Speaker 1: Holy shit That con looks awesome.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I mean the thing is right, you know, this is basically that you know.
Speaker 0: If I have one thing to say about Connecticut, it's this right.
Speaker 0: pretty much most of what we saw was panels Because we were running and doing panels.
Speaker 0: That's 90% of my weekend was that I didn't get to play a single board game.
Speaker 0: I bought a board game in my one like 30-minute trip through the dealer's room.
Speaker 0: I did not get to play a single game.
Speaker 0: I was very sad I talked to.
Speaker 1: but like Lou all our friends that are like doing stuff at the con We all the only time we saw you going on at all.
Speaker 0: I high-fived you go once during that trip to the dealer's room.
Speaker 1: I also high-fived her during my saw a non during his panel.
Speaker 0: I think I helped him with some technology.
Speaker 1: I saw you.
Speaker 1: I saw the panel getting done and get to stay for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I we saw them at the bar which apparently is the only building that has that is unlocked after midnight In Hartford.
Speaker 0: that has food.
Speaker 0: that's within walking distance But appetizers only by the time we get there which is fine because I can make a me a lot of appetizers.
Speaker 0: Oh that tostada is pretty good tostada.
Speaker 0: I'm so hungry cuz I didn't eat this morning cuz they told me not to eat after midnight for the doctor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I was like fucking gremlins what the shit.
Speaker 1: but basically Connecticut feel like a lot of people think it's an anime con, but it's not.
Speaker 0: I didn't finish what I was saying.
Speaker 0: All right Is that the general thing I had to say about Connecticut?
Speaker 0: is this right?
Speaker 0: is that most cons you go to?
Speaker 0: You don't really get to see every panel right?
Speaker 0: it's pretty much impossible.
Speaker 0: You see like a very small sampling relative to the mount on the schedule because I was running panels.
Speaker 0: I saw almost every panel for at least a few minutes.
Speaker 0: some of them I ran and some of them I saw the whole thing when we went through the schedule and put smiley faces frowny faces or flat faces or late or you know Notes on every panel after you know reviewing them.
Speaker 0: basically I was amazed at the sheer number of like smiley faces which means like fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: We don't give a smiley face if it's just an okay panel.
Speaker 1: No, I mean the just smiley face is like.
Speaker 0: that panel was awesome and like exceeded everything.
Speaker 0: like I was like wow smiley face Smiley face again, holy shit I just kept putting smiley face after smiley face.
Speaker 0: It was like epic.
Speaker 1: and the con feedback was great because numerous people basically said it was the best like year of panels ever Which it means a lot to us, you know before we'll stop all this meta mostly for the fact that we actually took over the panels department halfway through the year and Totally had to like wing it and throw everything at their last minute.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't know what to think about the feedback panel though because they were like.
Speaker 0: most of the comments were about panels.
Speaker 0: They weren't really that many actually the rest of the staff.
Speaker 1: I sent my.
Speaker 1: I had my report of like the panels department and they basically said yeah I remember how last year you guys schedule the panels feedback separate from the con feedback.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got to do that again Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, because I mean there was almost no Feedback for anything else but panels.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I'm wondering is that because we failed so hard?
Speaker 0: All the complaints were about us because that could be true.
Speaker 0: It could also be true in a complaint.
Speaker 1: Well, they said some complaints but one guy didn't like one panel he went to and one girl.
Speaker 0: But I mean, it's like is every other part of the convention just so perfect that there's no complaints?
Speaker 0: or is it so Tame that there's nothing to say good or bad, you know Is it?
Speaker 0: is it good or bad that there most of the feedback was for us?
Speaker 1: I can say that I don't know.
Speaker 1: I want to get out of the meta.
Speaker 1: We keep pulling back to the mat.
Speaker 1: I had the radio on a lot longer than you did cuz I the earpiece So I listened to like the radio.
Speaker 0: I had the radio on even when it wasn't on my ear But I just had it.
Speaker 1: you only had it Saturday and parts of Friday and then Sunday I had it, you know all day Friday and It seems like the staff were good enough at any time.
Speaker 1: There was an issue like jumping on it and fixing it before most attendees noticed that.
Speaker 1: I think that goes a long way To the lack of negative feedback.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Also line mail anyway skipping all the meta stuff.
Speaker 1: Connecticut is a con about everything.
Speaker 1: our goal At least us for panels is one-third anime stuff.
Speaker 1: You know anime manga comics all that sort of that like genre slash medium of stuff.
Speaker 0: You got to get the webcomics.
Speaker 0: You got to get the sci-fi.
Speaker 0: You got to get the fantasy.
Speaker 0: you got to get the arts and crafts.
Speaker 0: You got to get the technology.
Speaker 0: You got to get the gaming.
Speaker 0: you got to get the tabletop and the video and the miniatures and the.
Speaker 0: you know other geeky things in there like the airsoft and the paintball and you know anything that is nerdy in any way.
Speaker 0: You know the parkour and the para para and the belly dancing and the hypnotism guy and pretty much cosplay.
Speaker 0: Anything that's geeky.
Speaker 0: that is falls in our realm.
Speaker 0: We're gonna try to get it in there somewhere.
Speaker 1: So imagine a con that a third of the attendees are like Otakon or anime.
Speaker 1: Boston attendees You know cosplayers running around yelling having a good time.
Speaker 1: a third are gamers the same people who go to packs and a third are Just like everybody else.
Speaker 1: old ladies mothers.
Speaker 1: We had a whole family.
Speaker 1: the mother the father and the son all did panels and all of them were like grade-a panels Mm-hmm the family the geeks together.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they geeked together a lot.
Speaker 0: They play saw them playing a spooky manner Spooky manner.
Speaker 0: they were quite good at that.
Speaker 0: But yeah, you know and the thing is no one Daryl Sarai You can't complain because you know it says right there on the cover of the con book kinetic on everything But the kitchen sink.
Speaker 0: it is an everything con.
Speaker 0: It does not advertise itself as any specific thing Right.
Speaker 0: Therefore it is okay for us to do everything and we will do everything.
Speaker 0: We want to get all the nerds, you know, cuz Connecticut isn't really the most populous state.
Speaker 0: It's spread out big houses lots of trees and most of it, right?
Speaker 0: So, you know, it's not.
Speaker 0: I mean There's a lot of geeks up there who are underserved and we want to serve all the geeks in that area because it's not like There's any you know in order to serve, you know, we want to get the convention be bigger.
Speaker 0: But if we just had just anime we wouldn't get as many people.
Speaker 0: if you're just gaming wouldn't get as many people.
Speaker 0: But we get them all together which we can do.
Speaker 0: we can get all those geeks together and because a lot of people have Crossover interest we are serving a greater population and a greater You know need.
Speaker 0: but the bigger con and that's that's the the way kinetic on should be.
Speaker 1: the other thing that helped out a lot And that we do is we have workshop rooms and we filled them with like just straight-up workshops.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's this plushy building workshop.
Speaker 1: That's just amazing.
Speaker 0: I think that was the same one.
Speaker 0: That was an anime Boston.
Speaker 1: I think it was if I'm correct and like a sculpting one a whole bunch of art panels ball Joanna dolls a bunch of jewelry making panels.
Speaker 1: We had a knitting workshop that the popularity of that surprised us immensely.
Speaker 0: almost every workshop I went to peek in on even like writing workshops basically almost all.
Speaker 0: if they were in the small room and there was actual arts and crafts involved full and The big room like almost all of them just filled the big room.
Speaker 0: The origami one was insane.
Speaker 0: It actually went over time.
Speaker 0: I had to be like, alright guys, look you gotta get out.
Speaker 0: It's you know, it's enough origami.
Speaker 0: Yep, we had to go downstairs in Russian like take the cons paper from the printer and you know Bring it up there so more people could do origami.
Speaker 1: But like for an example, like we had a panel on Japanese tea ceremony Oh beer works and Walt Disney the American tezukas How to not suck at GMing.
Speaker 1: that wasn't us.
Speaker 1: That's the Albany School of GMing.
Speaker 1: those guys kick fucking ass.
Speaker 1: Yep, we had a kendo workshop.
Speaker 1: We had a million like steampunk panels.
Speaker 1: They were awesome.
Speaker 1: We had one beyond Victoriana.
Speaker 0: This was that panel is so awesome.
Speaker 1: That's.
Speaker 1: we got to bring that back and put it in like a bigger room.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, basically that panel needs a different name.
Speaker 0: I didn't know what it was till I saw.
Speaker 1: so steampunk's really popular, right?
Speaker 1: It's good thing.
Speaker 1: It didn't have a different name.
Speaker 1: cuz that room we had a line out the door.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm It was about steampunk.
Speaker 1: That's anything but like Victorian Europe.
Speaker 0: Yeah notice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I never really thought about it.
Speaker 0: But all steampunk is basically Victorian plus gears and brass, right?
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: why not have like, you know Native American steampunk or some Russian.
Speaker 0: see, you know there's so many other nationalities and time periods and thing, you know You could even do Star Wars steampunk or you could take your steampunk with anything but Victorian England and it could be awesome You know, you could do it with 1700s US steampunk.
Speaker 0: It'd be a little different from the Victorian England, right?
Speaker 0: So She was like why not do something different?
Speaker 0: and it was totally totally sweet.
Speaker 0: That was like genius that panel.
Speaker 1: Yep, we had like a cell painting workshop an old-school inking one a Japanese woodblock workshop.
Speaker 0: That was frickin boss, man I wanted to go to that if I couldn't go to that.
Speaker 1: I know I went
Speaker 0: over to it thinking I'm gonna make a woodblock print, but then it was full already
Speaker 1: Next year, you know the one thing we you know We kind of rush this is that my philosophy for running conventions at this point forward is it's always dictate delegate or do-it-yourself.
Speaker 1: That's right, and I'm delegating a lot.
Speaker 0: We did not delegate nearly enough pretty much.
Speaker 0: whenever something came through I would most of the time just go and try to take care Of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I would oh I would you know I would only delegate like if I was pretty sure someone was not doing something already.
Speaker 1: We had a bunch of guy panels a bunch of you know Meet-and-greets for all these webcomic artists and all the guests we had.
Speaker 1: we had our first like a Japanese guest of mineral.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, he is a a producer of anime.
Speaker 1: He's an awesome guy.
Speaker 1: as a professor and Him and as I was since they came and did like this awesome panel on kawaii, you know, like cute culture Yeah, and you know, it's great.
Speaker 0: You know, it really surprised me though, right?
Speaker 0: I mean I guess it helped that we pimped the panel and tried to tell people to go to it right during our very popular panel that The anime you should see.
Speaker 1: that was very.
Speaker 0: that was very convincing.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know friggin Nobru Ishiguro like huge dudes at anime con like guys who made macross and crap.
Speaker 0: You know huge Japanese anime producers have trouble filling the room.
Speaker 0: Fred show has trouble filling the room at Otakon at Kinetic on little convention.
Speaker 0: That is not just an anime con.
Speaker 1: that includes many other things We had like seventy five hundred or so people.
Speaker 0: this guy is in basically the same size room that they have at Otakon for the small panel room right and He's from Japan.
Speaker 0: He's doing a panel on kawaii and anime culture friggin packed Like we had to close the door.
Speaker 0: No, no more permitting.
Speaker 0: That was that was amazing.
Speaker 1: I was so pleased with that.
Speaker 1: That was great and they had such a good time.
Speaker 1: They came to a bunch of our panels - that was cool.
Speaker 0: speaking of full rooms, right?
Speaker 0: Two points to the fire marshals, right?
Speaker 0: Do you remember my story of PAX East?
Speaker 0: the Boston fire marshal was the awesomest, dude.
Speaker 0: He was this short jolly fat dude with a big ol mustache and he was like so fucking awesome.
Speaker 0: I was like, oh my god, you were the best fire marshal, right?
Speaker 0: The the fire marshal who came to Kinetic on right?
Speaker 0: I was like he came down walking down the hall And I'm like, hey the fire marshal.
Speaker 0: He's like, no, it's a costume and he keeps going.
Speaker 0: He was that was like the best fire marshals.
Speaker 0: I think in order to be fire marshal like to get the job.
Speaker 0: It's like job requirement number one be an awesome, dude.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like.
Speaker 0: I don't even know if I could get that job because I'm not awesome enough.
Speaker 0: Maybe I should just quit and try to become a fire marshal.
Speaker 0: That's a full-time job, right?
Speaker 1: I think you got to be a fireman first But fireman is a volunteer job.
Speaker 1: You got to be able to do a push-up Scott.
Speaker 0: But the thing is being a fireman is a volunteer job, but not in New York City.
Speaker 0: It's a. it's an actual job job also in Detroit.
Speaker 1: My dad's a fireman.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I can't get that job I was a fireman.
Speaker 1: I don't I think it's too late for me to get that job But like so I'll get all these crazy panels like anime video games everything all over the place even like the cost.
Speaker 0: not every panel Was awesome.
Speaker 0: I mean there were some panels.
Speaker 0: I personally did not enjoy that were full.
Speaker 0: There were some panels that seemed like they were good in material, but were empty And then part of that was like well it was scheduled at 9 a.m So we're trying to normal.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we definitely normalize but you know there were.
Speaker 0: not every panel was perfect, but there was a Overwhelming number of smiley faces to the point at which I was amazed.
Speaker 1: and one thing we did that was new this year And we got some good feedback about it.
Speaker 1: So it was a test.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do it like crazy next year is Instead of just like some guests just like have their own panels like.
Speaker 1: I got this panel and they just do it and it's awesome.
Speaker 1: Some guests like they have a lot to say but they don't really know what to do at a con.
Speaker 1: So we set up all these round tables.
Speaker 1: We're get some guests and one of us and one of our staff come into the room and moderate a topic Like.
Speaker 1: I think the best example of this was on Sunday.
Speaker 1: We had one copyright remixing and moral rights.
Speaker 0: Did we actually make that happen?
Speaker 0: I know that we had like a webcomics TBA and I managed to get a webcomic in there.
Speaker 0: Did the secret webcomic panel actually happen?
Speaker 1: I got something in there.
Speaker 1: it happened.
Speaker 0: Okay, cuz it's like we had some TBA slots because you know, we didn't have the whole year.
Speaker 0: We needed to plan and we didn't get the guest panels until too late.
Speaker 1: We're forcing them to get those much earlier Yep, but now the copyright remixing thing went really really well.
Speaker 1: the crowd loved it and you know, what's weird No one in the room had ever heard of the Creative Commons.
Speaker 1: Why and There were some inspired people in that room.
Speaker 0: We got to do something about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah next year.
Speaker 0: I'm doing it.
Speaker 1: So panels aside, I mean the con went off as far as I can tell without a hitch The the reg line was actually really reasonable.
Speaker 1: I still I walking out of town to mail the badges.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't think you know, they're not at the point where they need to.
Speaker 0: yeah They don't need to mail the badges.
Speaker 0: It never hurts to mail the badges.
Speaker 0: you have one pre-reg.
Speaker 0: you should mail that motherfucker, right?
Speaker 0: But they have this system where you go up to the these netbooks.
Speaker 0: They got really cheap and you go and you type your information in and then you go to the desk and pay and get a Badge and it's you know, it works.
Speaker 0: The line is never really that long.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the line kind of breezes through but part of it What helps is that it's a con where a lot of people show up on Friday But a lot of people only show up on Saturday and a lot of people only show up on.
Speaker 0: I mean if you live in the area, I mean some people.
Speaker 0: they might not be interested in the whole kit everything But the kitchen sink.
Speaker 0: they might just want to play some board games.
Speaker 0: Why not just come Saturday play board games for eight hours and leave?
Speaker 0: there's nothing wrong with that here.
Speaker 1: Let's talk briefly about all the areas of kinetic on video games like any other gaming con like it.
Speaker 1: just it's fine.
Speaker 0: They have a partnership with Best Buy that brings over a bunch of stuff and I learned some interesting things about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't really want to talk.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm stopped - they have a DDR machine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've stuck in there for like one minute and play DDR.
Speaker 0: They have a dealer's room which is actually pretty good.
Speaker 1: It's pretty eclectic.
Speaker 0: It's pretty good.
Speaker 0: Um, they have an artist alley.
Speaker 0: It's actually artist colony.
Speaker 0: I think yeah.
Speaker 1: Well one thing I want to point out.
Speaker 1: they have a tabletop gaming area.
Speaker 1: the tabletop gaming content It's at a con is better than the majority of gaming only cons.
Speaker 0: I've ever been to it's you know what?
Speaker 0: It's better than the table.
Speaker 0: It's better than the board gaming impacts.
Speaker 0: It is.
Speaker 0: Yeah straight up straight up It is it is the best, you know, I've never been to a Gen Con or origins or anything But I have confidence in what I know about those conventions.
Speaker 0: Kineticon might be the best tabletop gaming at a convention.
Speaker 0: I know if now there is a board game geek con I do I. I don't.
Speaker 0: I want to leave that one out.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I can guess it might be better there but kineticon has the best tabletop board gaming of any con I have been to and the role-playing is nothing to sneeze at - we got Luke Crane and Jared Sorenson in and They rocked it.
Speaker 1: They did all their panels.
Speaker 1: Jared did action castle spooky Manor and jungle event Luke Crane.
Speaker 0: They were they had this character burning workshop.
Speaker 0: They showed up to it, right?
Speaker 0: I remember like why and Pete did it last.
Speaker 1: yeah I remember how crazy popular it was.
Speaker 0: and Luke shows up and he's like, how am I supposed to do this?
Speaker 0: What the hell did Pete do?
Speaker 0: He's like, how did they do this last year, but he just started doing it and it was really awesome.
Speaker 0: And we made this crazy dwarf who is an arbal Esther twice and then became a drunk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know people were like, whoa I have to get this game.
Speaker 0: and Luke like.
Speaker 0: he figured it out as he was going through and I was like, dude You don't need to do the skills.
Speaker 0: He's like I want to do the skills.
Speaker 0: So we did this, you know and I have the character on Google Docs or whatever.
Speaker 0: So yeah that you know, even that went well something he didn't even know what to do walking into it But then he did it.
Speaker 1: and one thing too that works for kineticon is they've due to location.
Speaker 1: We get the Hartford Convention Center every year Which used to be way bigger than we needed and we're growing into it to the point that we're gonna fill it up someday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're actually you know, we're using almost all of it right?
Speaker 0: what part are we not using?
Speaker 1: Well, we can't that the middle parts hard to use.
Speaker 1: at most we can put up stuff in there But there's no room that's big enough for panels that we would save.
Speaker 0: there did used to be that conference room.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it's still.
Speaker 0: it's still there.
Speaker 0: It didn't used to be there.
Speaker 1: I want to see if we can get some of those little conference room.
Speaker 0: Yeah, why can't we we need?
Speaker 0: why can't we get that conference room with the big table?
Speaker 0: Remember they used it like lat, you know a few years ago.
Speaker 1: What if we got all those office rooms in the esplanade level and made those the individual rooms for scheduled RPGs?
Speaker 0: And now the RPG rooms are fine.
Speaker 1: If we need more RPGs or then we could cut down one of the RPG rooms in the main area Get another workshop room because we're already out of room for workshops.
Speaker 0: That's all right.
Speaker 0: The workshops are cool.
Speaker 0: We're there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see we're good.
Speaker 1: Well, we got not talk about meta stuff, but I don't know.
Speaker 1: everyone seemed to have a great time.
Speaker 1: Vuvuzela's were a little bit of a problem, but we finish going through every area.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's the ballroom where the dance is that it all switches in the hotel, but it's not like anime.
Speaker 0: Next we have to walk from building to building.
Speaker 0: It's like right there.
Speaker 0: They're basically attached, right?
Speaker 0: there's also some showing rooms over there and an all-night gaming room.
Speaker 0: and What else is there?
Speaker 1: we put a bunch of stuff over there like the weapons check and the cosplay stuff.
Speaker 0: There's a there's concession stand.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that helps but it's necessary and the prices are reasonable.
Speaker 1: It's not like.
Speaker 0: it's not like it's a good price But it's more reasonable than other cons like a few bucks less and it's not amazing food But it's better like a food icon like Otakon, you know, forget the inside.
Speaker 1: Nobody.
Speaker 0: Nobody should buy the at-con food.
Speaker 1: No, it's a lot cheaper than it used to be but there's restaurants like all over the place.
Speaker 1: You don't have to worry about it Hartford There is nowhere to eat.
Speaker 0: do not eat the at-con food.
Speaker 0: at most pretty much any convention But a kinetic on you can eat the at-con food.
Speaker 0: It's a little bit.
Speaker 0: It's okay It's a buck less and it's like plus Tastes a buck better and it costs a buck less.
Speaker 1: in their infinite wisdom this convention center.
Speaker 1: There's an ice cream stand on the first floor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you get soft-serve for like what?
Speaker 0: two or three dollars?
Speaker 1: Oh my god I stopped there like ten times ten times.
Speaker 1: I was yelling.
Speaker 1: I was doing pan.
Speaker 0: I only went there one day.
Speaker 1: I was also running around just shot swapping microphones in rooms because we didn't get enough microphones.
Speaker 1: I'm bringing our microphones next year to supplement.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was definitely some technical, you know, basically they get the technology They have this company, you know most conventions like when you go to the Javits They pay the Javits because they have to to do it.
Speaker 0: and those guys they're awesome.
Speaker 0: They're actually good, you know, even though they're a union.
Speaker 0: Those are high quality guys still prefer.
Speaker 1: They're probably way We got probably the best guy got this one awesome, dude, and he just deals with he's kinetic on staff.
Speaker 0: Yeah and what they do is they rent all this equipment from this company for like You know the lowest bid or whatever and they just drop off the equipment on Thursday or early Friday.
Speaker 0: They set it up and that's it and it's up to kinetic on to use the equipment which gives us the freedom we need.
Speaker 0: But at the same time it's kind of a pain when we need some more equipment.
Speaker 0: Like we only had enough equipment to hook up like three laptops to put you know with audio to put we could hook up video No problem in every room, but the audio not so much.
Speaker 0: So if someone needed, you know audio with their PowerPoint or something like that We and enough people wanted it at the same time is problematic.
Speaker 0: And if they wanted it in a different room, that means we had to run around and move a bunch of wires.
Speaker 1: I guess we're back to meta.
Speaker 1: So yeah, Steve Jobs.
Speaker 1: Fuck you Did did the biggest I'd say the biggest problem.
Speaker 1: we dealt with this entire con since we were just talking about office staff at this Point.
Speaker 1: there's people who have Mac laptops and don't have the little adapter to plug into a proper projector.
Speaker 1: I mean, you're never gonna go to a con but a VGA is a DVR.
Speaker 0: PGA is so ugly We can't put that in our MacBook.
Speaker 1: fine.
Speaker 1: No, the thing is part of it is honestly the panels and the attendees.
Speaker 1: They should bring that little adapter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we should just basically be like, well you forgot the adapter.
Speaker 0: That's you know, whatever.
Speaker 1: But instead we managed.
Speaker 1: Well, I let my laptop to a couple of panelists.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Is there anything else about the con that we can discuss?
Speaker 0: Oh, they had this main events.
Speaker 1: We forgot to say that main events is actually like super well put together.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's crazy because they actually they pretty much have a main event in there at all hours almost right and I mean obviously not overnight.
Speaker 1: yeah, like here's an example last year we bought super art fight in for the first time and They could have filled probably all the panel room simultaneously.
Speaker 1: Mmm, so this year we put him in main events and they rocked it.
Speaker 0: They didn't fill the main events, but they had no main event.
Speaker 0: They had.
Speaker 0: people have filled made the masquerade fills.
Speaker 1: it actually didn't.
Speaker 1: there was room Really?
Speaker 1: It just barely like the whole line getting.
Speaker 1: but you know, why all the panel rooms during the masquerade?
Speaker 1: We're mostly filling up - yeah, that's right.
Speaker 0: There were quite a few panels during the masquerades.
Speaker 1: We put a lot of really good panels directly opposite the masquerade on purpose.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I actually even ran that Hudson Amico panel started as the masquerade theoretically ended even though the masquerade went late And I thought there's gonna be like five people there.
Speaker 0: I just wanted to practice this panel see if it worked and the people showed up.
Speaker 0: There was like 20 people in there out in a tiny panel room late at night and I was like damn look at this.
Speaker 0: Actually had to do it for reals.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got to bring that guy to.
Speaker 0: you know Some anime Boston and such.
Speaker 1: it says something that this con like going to Connecticut despite the fact that we basically worked for the entire Con was super fun Like it was crazy fun and all you know We've got a lot of for most
Speaker 0: of the time
Speaker 1: who had never come to Connecticut before but they normally would go to like Otacon anime Boston like all the kind of cons that they go to and The universal sentiment among them was Wow Connecticut is nothing like I expected it to be.
Speaker 1: It's awesome It's the.
Speaker 1: it's my favorite con.
Speaker 0: Yeah The location is kind of Blair but because the board gaming is the best Because we actually have staff stuff to do We're never bored right?
Speaker 0: and the panels there's just so many awesome ones.
Speaker 1: It's like why I still I want to fly Daryl Surratt out if I ever could I would love for him to do his panels.
Speaker 0: We got it.
Speaker 0: We got to get him there.
Speaker 0: Maybe well, you know bring we got to bring up because if we get him in there to replace all the frowny face panels He would just be so epic.
Speaker 1: Oh my god If there's all smiley face panels.
Speaker 1: all right legend of Krauser animes craziest I mean.
Speaker 0: imagine if you went to a convention and at any given moment There are two or three panels running simultaneously because we staggered the schedule.
Speaker 0: so there's breaks in every room right and Every single one of those panels is so sweet and you can't go to all of them.
Speaker 0: What do you do?
Speaker 0: It's like oh my gosh.
Speaker 0: Now the only thing I would like to change is we had a few people that did so many panels Which is part of the reason there were so many smiley faces right up like those steampunk dudes did so many.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, the family there's like.
Speaker 1: there's all this group stuff.
Speaker 1: So I'm not like the penny dreadfuls SS Icarus all those guys whisper.
Speaker 1: They the Albany School GM and guys Yeah, all we had all these like groups of people and their pant like they were so professional and so organized like us.
Speaker 1: had we Died before kinetic on and we're not there for staff.
Speaker 1: a lot of the like normal panels might add some trouble.
Speaker 1: These guys would have showed up gotten badges somehow done all their panels and left and they would have no trouble.
Speaker 0: They could have taken over the panel's department for us if they wanted to.
Speaker 0: in fact You know what happened.
Speaker 0: a lot like two or three times.
Speaker 0: Panelists didn't show up and someone just stood up and tried to do the panel and I was like Whenever that happened whenever that happened.
Speaker 0: I made sure to like tell the people that did that like.
Speaker 0: look email me.
Speaker 0: Hey seriously tell me that you took over this panel.
Speaker 0: like one example.
Speaker 0: you are on the good list with a few panels who would show up a Little bit late and I always felt bad when that happened because it's like.
Speaker 0: well I went up there and I was like look the panelist is late.
Speaker 0: We are not going to schedule a replacement panel.
Speaker 1: They may yet show up But I cannot guarantee they always showed up a few minutes later and had a good excuse like I was in the bathroom.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I would say look if they you know, I can't promise that you should stay here.
Speaker 0: You might be wasting your time I don't know.
Speaker 0: and then when I said when I made that Announcement most of the people would leave and then a few minutes later the person would show up and I'd be like ah I just I destroyed your audience.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry In checking every room Yeah after the second time that happened and I destroyed someone's audience I basically the third time I was like look the last time I made this announcement the panelists showed up five minutes later.
Speaker 0: So You know, I don't want to destroy the audience for this person if they show up.
Speaker 0: and you know I making that announcement everything worked out.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I you know, we're talking about people taking over panels Like we got to tell.
Speaker 1: you know, because we basically meted this whole thing.
Speaker 1: So I got some amusing anecdotes I guess from Connecticut not waking up on time on Saturday.
Speaker 1: So backstories many of you know, but we have a lot of new listeners.
Speaker 1: in 2002 there was no geek nights.
Speaker 1: yet me and Scott is two slubs.
Speaker 1: go to our first anime con ever.
Speaker 1: It's Ohio con in Ohio.
Speaker 0: that con was so bad looking like a worse con.
Speaker 1: Ohio con.
Speaker 1: everyone says it's gotten better since then, but I'm sure it's a real con now.
Speaker 1: But that Ohio con.
Speaker 1: the second one in 2002 was not a con.
Speaker 1: That was nothing that basically like.
Speaker 0: if you think back to it compare that to like the thing they do in Wildwood in the Convention Center with Wildwood I mean, but I mean compared to the baseball card thing.
Speaker 0: It's pretty equal to that, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, except to the DDR pad that works for a half hour the whole week, but that con, you know We'd never even heard of anime cons before.
Speaker 1: we'd know I didn't really get it like until we showed up.
Speaker 0: I was like, I mean RIT spring fest was better than Ohio con 2.0, but everyone's like Oh anime con.
Speaker 1: so we go and We go to our panel.
Speaker 1: We're like, oh, they've got panels.
Speaker 1: Let's go to our panel.
Speaker 1: The first panel we went to was like anime club summit.
Speaker 1: We're sitting there There's some people in the audience and like a bunch of our crews there and no one like shows up And eventually we all kind of look at each other and we're like we were in the RIT anime club.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're this our panel.
Speaker 1: Sorry and we started running it and we took over this panel and ran and it was awesome.
Speaker 1: And we kind of wormed our way and did a similar thing at Otakon the same year in 2002 to the same panel the anime club summit.
Speaker 1: and Then we did that panel every year at Otakon for a couple more years and then from there geek nights And now we've got like a hundred and fifty something.
Speaker 0: pan Yeah, cuz.
Speaker 0: basically all you would say when we wanted to do a panel is we would say look we did the anime club summit X-times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we're the host of geek nights.
Speaker 0: Give us a panel and as soon as someone gave us a non anime club summit panel that opened the gates We'll be like, hey we did this Let us do it again and let us do this new one and now let us do seven.
Speaker 0: now Let us run your whole panels.
Speaker 1: when Magfest emailed us They're like, hey, would you guys like to be guests?
Speaker 1: like?
Speaker 1: we'd love you to come and I really want to go to Magfest.
Speaker 0: I so I so want to go to Magfest like as everyone there has balls of steel Like.
Speaker 1: so do you have a list of like stuff you've done in the past?
Speaker 1: just for?
Speaker 1: and I sent them the list of panels We've actually done and we're like too much.
Speaker 1: the response back was just an exclamation point.
Speaker 1: So Saturday right Friday like we'd managed.
Speaker 1: everything was awesome Sunday.
Speaker 1: Everything was awesome.
Speaker 1: We have this ass early panel.
Speaker 1: Good morning Connecticut.
Speaker 1: But it's kind of like morning announcements and all this stuff.
Speaker 1: we have this whole strategy as to why it's there and it works.
Speaker 1: we basically hang out and I Well-rested really sunny out and then Scott's like, oh shit.
Speaker 1: It's like nine Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: We both fucked up our alarm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we didn't.
Speaker 0: the alarms did not go off.
Speaker 0: I looked at the clock when I woke up I pushed the button on my phone and said nine and I was supposed to be at the panel at 830.
Speaker 0: I was like fuck me one my breakfast.
Speaker 1: all of our staff like the front row crew like all our friends who were doing staff stuff For us.
Speaker 1: they didn't bother calling us.
Speaker 1: They assumed we had something going on and they just managed all the other panels just fine.
Speaker 0: No, no other panels had started yet There's nothing to do and they were.
Speaker 0: they like checked in all the panel ballroom guy though That's early in the morning.
Speaker 0: is the?
Speaker 0: is the the guy who does the exercising and stuff.
Speaker 0: He's a staff guy.
Speaker 0: He's totally.
Speaker 1: but Scott Johnson comes to me later and he's like, yeah these two guys were like doing good morning, Connecticut.
Speaker 1: I figured that was the plaque is gonna left him there.
Speaker 0: Johnson always wakes up early.
Speaker 1: So Scott runs down there and those two guys were just kind of running the panel.
Speaker 0: Those guys are awesome.
Speaker 0: I'm waiting for those guys to email us so we can make sure they get a panel next year.
Speaker 1: and along those lines we added A lot of panels, you know, they're in the addendum all that stuff because of scheduling.
Speaker 1: You know cons always have these troubles next year none.
Speaker 1: But fuck who dotnet want to do a panel called hentai worth watching.
Speaker 1: and we're like, alright, we need some content.
Speaker 0: We had us.
Speaker 0: we had a spattering of hentai content.
Speaker 0: We had like we had an 18 plus night court thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we had a vampires don't spark which is done by one of our like regular awesome panel.
Speaker 0: The vampires don't sparkle was not hentai right?
Speaker 1: No, but it was still 18 plus.
Speaker 0: So many bad words and it wasn't that the deal.
Speaker 0: yeah It's also some possible vampire who are worth watching.
Speaker 1: the long story short is these guys Told us straight up that they saw our anime.
Speaker 1: You should see panel and they were inspired and they're funny guys like.
Speaker 1: they have a similar dynamic that we do.
Speaker 1: so they're like we want to do the same thing with hentai and I got it, you know, I checked the IDs for that panel and I kept peeking my head in and watching it.
Speaker 1: It was hilarious.
Speaker 1: Those guys are awesome.
Speaker 0: Like happy house a hentai hilarious.
Speaker 1: It was actually funnier.
Speaker 0: I think whoa Sorry happy house ahead.
Speaker 0: I didn't see it.
Speaker 0: I can't corroborate this insult.
Speaker 1: It's hard to say house because the happy house of hentai was a long time ago, but I remember laughing so hard.
Speaker 1: I couldn't breathe.
Speaker 1: That was a sitcom Fucking amazing.
Speaker 0: All right, but yeah, there's actually the other hentai panel.
Speaker 0: was What?
Speaker 0: why hentai?
Speaker 0: and I was little.
Speaker 0: I didn't know what was going on with that panel But when I checked it out like I poked my head in at the end to make sure his ending on time and she was talking about like the conflict legal Defense fund and stuff and I was like, oh shit.
Speaker 0: This is a real panel.
Speaker 0: This isn't just like a bunch of porn.
Speaker 0: What's going on here?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it was totally sweet panel.
Speaker 0: So I mean to have not only to have all these smiley face panels, but the few hentai panels we do have.
Speaker 0: we're classy and not like, you know, just Tentacles, you know or the worst hentai panels.
Speaker 0: There was a tentacle panel, but it was all Lovecraft.
Speaker 1: There's three levels.
Speaker 1: the Lovecraft panel was done by Alex a friend of ours uncle yo, Carl Custer and Alex's father and CJ Henderson and one other guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah That was awesome.
Speaker 1: No Peter and out here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we ended up mostly talking about meta cuz we you know We have our weird perspective.
Speaker 0: Well, I mean what else.
Speaker 0: I mean, I you know It's like but the things I saw in the dealers room I bought.
Speaker 0: I finally found that Krauser revoltech that is damn that was made famous by astro toys Rob Rickins - I have.
Speaker 1: is he gonna be in a scout's box, maybe I have the Krauser.
Speaker 0: and then what else do I have?
Speaker 0: I had I bought Oh, I bought roll through the ages, which is basically Yahtzee plus Civilization, so I'm gonna play that tomorrow board game night and see how good it is.
Speaker 0: And you know, I played the solitaire version and it was pretty fun.
Speaker 0: I liked it Nah, even though it's half Yahtzee, which is bad.
Speaker 1: So I mean, I guess we can do a few shout outs.
Speaker 1: I can't like.
Speaker 1: shout out cuz it's weird.
Speaker 1: Normally expect after a thing like this like you guys are awesome.
Speaker 1: You can have like five or six names.
Speaker 0: shout out to every panelist cuz that who had a smiley face.
Speaker 0: You're all awesome.
Speaker 0: You know who you are.
Speaker 0: you guys like really even even the guy who didn't show up to his panel about.
Speaker 0: you know dog You know mushing, right?
Speaker 0: He was awesome because he did the other panels and he was staff and he apologized to us and he was totally sweet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I bet that pet that panel seemed pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: I kind of want to see it now to learn about.
Speaker 1: you know, like I did a rod and shit Yep, but we really got to thank as always sensei and auto sensei because they came.
Speaker 1: they seem to have a great time.
Speaker 1: Their panel went really well.
Speaker 1: It was auto sensei look like he was laughing when I was tough.
Speaker 0: We were talking about fist of the North Star and showing those, you know a politician in Japan cuz this stuff going on in the in The diet right now Basically one, you know Faction is really failing and the guy was like a my one more.
Speaker 0: He's like they're already dead.
Speaker 0: Who else?
Speaker 0: oh all the volunteers orange shirt people at Connecticut.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, so awesome.
Speaker 0: Like they were they were almost enforcer quality.
Speaker 0: I don't want to.
Speaker 0: you know, I don't wanna say they were in force of quality But they were almost in force of quality because the only thing I mean in there were individual in volunteers who were in force of quality But there were also enforcers who ran away.
Speaker 0: So the total across all of them was, you know lower But the ones that did work were so great.
Speaker 0: There was a girl who watched that panel room like the whole time and there were like the two people who would always sit in front of the dealers room and the two who Sat in front of the artists.
Speaker 0: Oh my god The worst job is the worst job, but they sat there doing that job and they did it.
Speaker 1: Well, and you know I grabbed.
Speaker 1: I rounded up two volunteers to handle the the line for the Connecticut musical and they they held that line like tighter against The wall that I could have imagined.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the volunteers were totally sweet and also our staff and pretty much all the staff of Connecticut kick-ass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was not any Connecticut staff who were failed.
Speaker 1: now I did not see one of everyone to uh, Laura You know one of our front row crew people for basically like managing the entire Hallway of panels a couple of times while we were running around and a Wyatt yeah And yeah Wyatt man in the walkie-talkie.
Speaker 1: So right Jess and Judith handling the workshop hallway ripe up nerdy doing the knitting panel Emily translating for the guest.
Speaker 1: but we had.
Speaker 1: there was this period where Scott and I had to kind of go off the radio and be Unavailable because we had to do.
Speaker 1: you know The enemy you should see which is like a big panel and then I had to do with eyes on o sensei's panel and all This stuff.
Speaker 1: so I basically handed why at this radio just as there's all these people all of us be like We need room from panels to come here.
Speaker 1: We need room from panels to come here.
Speaker 1: and I gave wife ready I'm like, you're me have fun and I booked.
Speaker 0: yeah I mean most of our problems really stemmed from the publications, right?
Speaker 0: Which was due to the fact that because we had the real schedule, but we couldn't get the real schedule out there Most people had the flawed schedule got the addendum and the addendum which was also flawed.
Speaker 1: It was only flawed in two ways.
Speaker 1: One panel did not actually say said panel and didn't say the number two of them and the workshops are all flipped in the addendum.
Speaker 1: That was it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well only on Friday.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, the addendum had some problems.
Speaker 0: We're working on that for next year, but next year if the publications are perfect Which I suspect they should be the schedule will be finalized early enough.
Speaker 0: So there shouldn't be really that many changes if any to that final printed schedule.
Speaker 0: and it'll be so amazing Because every no one will say where's the whatever or what time is the war?
Speaker 0: or you know?
Speaker 0: What's gonna be in this webcomic TBA slot?
Speaker 0: It'll just be perfect.
Speaker 0: and we found out we actually are allowed to put up, you know, the standees outside the rooms.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, I'll buy myself if I have to.
Speaker 0: yeah, we'll just do it.
Speaker 0: It's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: So, there you go It's gonna be perfect.
Speaker 1: Connecticut was freaking awesome.
Speaker 1: And basically it's a con where I don't think it's at the point.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't feel like if I lived in Seattle, I would not fly to Hartford.
Speaker 0: No, I anyone who travel, you know, it's not something you should travel far to.
Speaker 0: but if you're in New England Maybe not North Maine but if you're
Speaker 1: within like three or so three or four hours of Hartford, Connecticut if you're
Speaker 0: in New England or New York City or Even Northern Jersey or Southern New York State Southeastern New York State ish area, you know between the Hudson the Mid-Hudson Valley
Speaker 1: Con
Speaker 0: you got to go to gotta go to Connecticut, you know anywhere in Massachusetts, Rhode Island, Connecticut Maybe South New Hampshire Vermont even Connecticut is where it's at.
Speaker 1: Yep Oh, so we had you know, one of the panels we had to add.
Speaker 1: It was actually like a big deal like one of our guests.
Speaker 1: kind of panels aren't the hypnotist He does like a hypnosis show.
Speaker 1: He doesn't every year.
Speaker 1: It's always awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I'm I get this hypnotist guy he comes in and we're doing Good Morning Connecticut, right?
Speaker 0: And I'm sort of a little bit skeptical, you know me we're skeptical on this show.
Speaker 1: So he's he comes in and Scott's like this hypnosis really work.
Speaker 0: I'm like, is this for real?
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: 90% of this question 90% of his answers to my questions were not Randy.
Speaker 0: There was a little bit right?
Speaker 1: He was talking about it's weird cuz he'd edge toward Randy.
Speaker 1: But the last second he'd be like, but you know the reality of science blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's like.
Speaker 0: he was like.
Speaker 0: there are some studies into breast augmentation by hypnosis and I'm like, uh-huh Really?
Speaker 0: Boobs getting bigger waving a watch in front of your face, but then he's like, yeah Placebo effect and all these things like.
Speaker 0: he was definitely not a man who believed that it was magic.
Speaker 0: He definitely believed it was science.
Speaker 0: He definitely had studied the science and you know, neuro-linguistic whatever's counts for a lot Too is he was.
Speaker 1: he was for real.
Speaker 1: He's hilarious.
Speaker 0: He is also an excellent entertainer.
Speaker 0: So I highly recommend art the hypnotist for your and like if you have a kid's birthday party Why don't get the lame magician who pulls the bunny out of the head?
Speaker 0: get art the hypnotist seriously.
Speaker 1: But the best and what we learned is no Scott's grilling him, right and we had this audience for Good Morning Connecticut.
Speaker 1: We got to do a Q&A with this guy like as a panel because people why don't we get him on the geek nights?
Speaker 1: Oh, that's a good idea.
Speaker 0: Also, right.
Speaker 0: We had these two guys who also came to Good Morning Connecticut and they were doing the how to build a gaming computer.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, uh-huh So do you think as so I'm grilling them too because I just love grilling people, right?
Speaker 0: I'm like see you think SLI is a good idea.
Speaker 0: They're like.
Speaker 0: no you should get just one video card and I'm like Intel or ATI.
Speaker 0: they're like, okay, if you need you really need to save money.
Speaker 0: get the eight, you know the AMD but Really Intel is is the quality teller ATI.
Speaker 0: I freaking grilled them and they had the right answer to every question.
Speaker 0: These guys were the.
Speaker 0: they would give the same advice as me.
Speaker 0: So their panel was totally sweet and awesome.
Speaker 0: even had a computer there.
Speaker 0: so they could show you putting it together.
Speaker 0: Excellent panel.
Speaker 1: one building a computer guy actually, so we had the.
Speaker 1: you know parkour.
Speaker 1: Phil did a parkour panel.
Speaker 1: We had a workshops and everything.
Speaker 0: Excellent thing.
Speaker 1: We learned from this.
Speaker 1: There's a huge parkour community in Hartford.
Speaker 1: Yep, they all showed up there.
Speaker 0: They're all these like parkour experts like ah, man parkour Did they come to the con because of the parkour?
Speaker 1: supposedly some did oh snap.
Speaker 0: See look at that That's what you get for diversify.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Phil was like, oh my god.
Speaker 1: There's people here who were good.
Speaker 1: This is awesome.
Speaker 0: How about the the para?
Speaker 0: para totally packed and those guys?
Speaker 0: awesome.
Speaker 0: Who else is right?
Speaker 1: he's doing his show.
Speaker 0: I just need you actually saw.
Speaker 0: I didn't get to see any of the show.
Speaker 1: sadly I just sneak into the rooms.
Speaker 1: I took my head in.
Speaker 0: I'm watching and you got hypnotized.
Speaker 0: He trapped you there.
Speaker 1: Basically.
Speaker 1: I was watching it.
Speaker 1: I had to you know, why watch it a little bit?
Speaker 1: and I went to the front door.
Speaker 1: I tried to sneak in to get an audio cable out from the back.
Speaker 1: so he looks at me and I just kind of like stopped and stood there like I was mesmerized and Then the crowd the crowds were nuts and then he totally played with it and he went with it.
Speaker 1: So I went with it.
Speaker 1: It was hilarious.
Speaker 1: Let me go.
Speaker 0: But of course that was fake.
Speaker 0: You were not actually hypnotized No, but it was hilarious.
Speaker 0: You should have been like yes master I Don't know what else I can say.
Speaker 1: This was freakin awesome and not.
Speaker 1: and as a testament to you know How much we love kinetic?
Speaker 0: Well, I can.
Speaker 0: let me try to make some negatives of kinetic on right?
Speaker 0: Publications we failed slightly.
Speaker 0: Yep Well kind of bigly as medium failure.
Speaker 0: on publications The parking is still a lot of monies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but Harvard still sucks for food still better than Actually Citicon was the only other economy trouble with food at.
Speaker 0: yeah Let me try to think of what else sucks.
Speaker 0: You do have to wait in line for the badge Even though it's not an epic line and somebody will fix that.
Speaker 1: and next year No panelists left to wait in line.
Speaker 0: There is that down there is an awesome system of getting tickets for playing board games that get you awesome prizes Like you can get an actual board game.
Speaker 0: You can get oshi a great game.
Speaker 0: They had a huge stack of it for like seven tickets.
Speaker 0: That's how it's crazy.
Speaker 0: You can get like $40 board games for like 12 tickets.
Speaker 1: Well what they pointed out was and so I suggested they need to basically in have inflation a little bit in the tickets.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they need some.
Speaker 0: they need tickets to get.
Speaker 0: you need to be able to get more of them.
Speaker 0: They need them to be worth a little bit less and they need to make it more Publicized that the ticketing system exists and how it works because it's not very consistent.
Speaker 0: So like you actually like are just there for board games and you want to get a copy of a board game for reals For you know tickets.
Speaker 0: you have to play a lot of board games and really work this system.
Speaker 1: That is not so well explained though in the count feedback It was great because one person they made this really valid point about how the tickets need to be Devalued a little bit to make it work better and they're perfectly right.
Speaker 0: I think we should do it only value devalued a little bit because I think it's kind of awesome that a ticket is worth so Much.
Speaker 0: right if the ticket isn't worth a lot like you go to the arcade and it's like a thousand tickets you get the plastic Frog, it's like you don't feel like getting any tickets.
Speaker 0: Why should I bother?
Speaker 0: but if the tickets are so valuable?
Speaker 0: You'll be like I will fucking do anything to get a ticket, but they pointed out the fact that alright.
Speaker 1: So because of the way the tickets work if you play like ten games in the one period you only get tickets for one of Them and she's like you don't get anything.
Speaker 1: and the one staffer like the gaming guy was basically like well I'm assuming you had fun playing the game and she was like, oh, yeah Yeah, I was like, oh because you need to be paid to play for it.
Speaker 0: You know, you wouldn't have played the board game if you weren't basically being paid to do it, right?
Speaker 0: But no, but they should.
Speaker 0: I think the system should basically be what I thought the system was but I was apparently incorrect.
Speaker 0: If you play a board game right by taking it out checking it out You mark down the time you took it out and the time you brought it back, right?
Speaker 0: They should just give you one ticket per half hour Right, but it had you had to have actually played, you know, and yeah, so I check out oshi and I come back four hours Later.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I won the board gaming.
Speaker 0: people can tell right if you've played it or not.
Speaker 0: They can ask you how the game works.
Speaker 0: They can ask they ask who won the game.
Speaker 0: right give the extra ticket to the winner Right, so, you know, obviously people might try to work the system But you can monitor that right if someone comes up for the second time because giving someone one ticket You know for falseness is not is not a problem, right?
Speaker 0: But giving them two tickets for lying is kind of okay.
Speaker 0: Maybe we're gonna check you the second time.
Speaker 0: So if someone comes up a second time, just keep your eye on them.
Speaker 0: Look that they're actually playing a game over at one of the tables and if they are keep giving them tickets.
Speaker 0: And if not, then be like look I watched you.
Speaker 0: you just walked out with that and didn't come back.
Speaker 1: Of course, you know, that's another department.
Speaker 1: Basically.
Speaker 1: I'm so happy with ya.
Speaker 0: that has nothing to do with us.
Speaker 0: That's a game department.
Speaker 0: We got no control over that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, is that a con?
Speaker 0: is that the end?
Speaker 1: I think that's the end.
Speaker 0: But we're oh there.
Speaker 0: I have one more negative.
Speaker 0: come on more.
Speaker 0: Yes the dealers room, right?
Speaker 0: They have this bag check and on Friday.
Speaker 0: The bag check was for the video games and for the dealer room.
Speaker 0: now the thing is it's They.
Speaker 0: they decided to stop doing bag check for dealer room, which is good Cuz what other con does bag check for dealer room?
Speaker 0: not Oda come right?
Speaker 0: No almost none of them, right?
Speaker 0: So that made no sense.
Speaker 0: Also you go into the dealer room your dealer area.
Speaker 0: you get a. you know You buy something they give you a bag.
Speaker 0: So what's the point of the bag check?
Speaker 0: right that bag check on the way out make sense.
Speaker 0: doing the receipt thing?
Speaker 0: You know, even though I don't like that but doing it on the way in makes no sense.
Speaker 0: However, there is.
Speaker 0: there is no, you know lying about it.
Speaker 0: There is a shoplifting problem in the kinetic on dealing room.
Speaker 0: Of course any dealers were very upset.
Speaker 0: It happens at a lot of cons more and more yes But a kinetic on it is particularly a problem and I really don't know what to do.
Speaker 0: I mean, we might just have to hire like real security to actually stand in the dealers room looking around.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Is that even gonna stop it?
Speaker 1: I don't get standees of cops and put them just Outside where it looks like it's a real cop standing there like 20 of them lined up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, I really I really have no idea what to do about that.
Speaker 0: Oh speaking of cops I'll make this the final note.
Speaker 0: I remember my story about the racist guy at the barbershop.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I there were two cops just standing in the hotel at kinetic.
Speaker 1: Oh, those guys were also awesome.
Speaker 0: So real cops Hartford cops.
Speaker 0: So I was like, hey dudes I have this completely unrelated question for you.
Speaker 0: So they're like, hey, what's up?
Speaker 0: They were you know, they I almost thought they were firemen.
Speaker 0: They were so nice I mean and you.
Speaker 1: so what you're like, so I got this weed, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, no, I was like.
Speaker 0: I was like I was in this barbershop and this dude was so racist.
Speaker 0: I'm like, what would you do?
Speaker 0: They're like, oh man, it's like you can't do anything.
Speaker 0: It just sucks.
Speaker 0: But they were.
Speaker 0: they were totally cool.
Speaker 0: They they gave me some advice.
Speaker 0: So awesome to the cops in the hotel And kinetic on 2010 is out.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So we will see you guys at kinetic on 2011.
Speaker 0: I hope will be opening panel submissions sooner than you'll expect as soon as the website people get their stuff in order.
Speaker 1: Yep, and we're already like content like we're already putting together the list of people we want to invite back.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: You guys did awesome panels.
Speaker 1: Do you want to do another panel next year?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think though we're gonna.
Speaker 0: you know The people who did like ten panels.
Speaker 0: we should shrink them down to three or four.
Speaker 0: We kind of had a turning maybe put like a three or four maximum on.
Speaker 1: we had to turn away a lot of panel submissions And I think we're only gonna have to turn away more and more.
Speaker 1: We're really kinetic on is reaching a turning point to where we're gonna be able to be really picky and choose.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the best of the best but we can so we can do is we always want to let in some new stuff Each time so we can let reruns happen next year.
Speaker 0: But I don't think we should allow reruns more than anything to go more than two years in a row Even if it's really popular.
Speaker 0: and then you know If one group runs a lot of panels.
Speaker 0: we can shrink them to like a limit of three or four and have them cycle it Right if they want to stick around.
Speaker 0: if they can't cycle it then we can let someone new in.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's what we do at PAX.
Speaker 1: We don't run beyond D&D at every PAX despite the fact that they kept.
Speaker 0: I think beyond D&D is dead.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, my running of beyond D&D was perhaps the worst beyond D&D we've ever done.
Speaker 0: It was so there was fun.
Speaker 0: There was almost no one in there and I like you change the panel or the order of the slides.
Speaker 0: There's something now you just forgot.
Speaker 0: it was so messed up.
Speaker 0: Our other panels are really good though, so it makes up for it.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, I love running anime anime openers from around the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is like my favorite panel to run.
Speaker 0: bite-sized anime was alright.
Speaker 0: The Mika panel was pretty great and Anime CC was great, and we're good.
Speaker 1: We ran a bunch of like quickie panels.
Speaker 1: like.
Speaker 1: there was one panelist who showed up late.
Speaker 1: So I did a quick thing on.
Speaker 1: you know, I had a harmonica with me.
Speaker 1: So I was like, hey, I'll teach you guys how to play the harmonica and people seem to really like it.
Speaker 0: We're really done now for real.
Speaker 1: We're really done for real.
Speaker 1: done done done.
Speaker 1: Thank you, you're liking the show to end.
Speaker 0: I like it.
Speaker 0: I showed it.
Speaker 0: I like you to eat a dinner.
Speaker 1: You like it.
Speaker 1: the show to end.
Speaker 0: I like it a room to shut up.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand Okay for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.