Speaker 1: Hey, it's Wednesday March 17th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: It's Wolverine.
Speaker 1: Oh shit Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I bought a bike yesterday, and I bought a bike yeah And today was the very first day that my office building would allow bikes to be brought up the service elevator as is the law The new law.
Speaker 1: so I am assuming that you rode this bike to work and had a wonderful time.
Speaker 0: No in fact I didn't and the reason I didn't you know is because Number one.
Speaker 0: well, no actually I'm going to talk about the bike stuff later But the reason I didn't basically is because I didn't know how long it would take and I wanted to get to work on time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you got to try that.
Speaker 0: on like a week on the weekend I'm gonna ride to work and back and time it with the stopwatch and such and then next week I'll be able to ride to work.
Speaker 0: You know and leave at the appropriate time, but anyway I am glad I did not ride like to work today because I did not realize today was Everyone.
Speaker 0: get the fuck off the street before I kill you day.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I forgot to.
Speaker 1: you know I get to work.
Speaker 1: I'm sitting there, and I look on FARC and someone says blah blah blah st.
Speaker 1: Patrick's Day, and I'm like oh crap I Better not go anywhere for lunch today cuz I'm in Midtown like right by where the stupid parade is.
Speaker 0: I think the thing is I'm like oh, but the parade isn't today right.
Speaker 0: It's like Sunday, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh shit praise today fuck.
Speaker 1: so you know I got to lunch because of course three hours later I totally forget about this.
Speaker 1: so I go to lunch.
Speaker 1: It's like 1130 and There's just a crowd of people in green surrounding my building outside of grounds just Staggering around yelling at each other throwing shit.
Speaker 0: There aren't even any sports teams doing well.
Speaker 0: I mean if a sports team just won Then I can justify some whoo.
Speaker 1: the best part is that cops like last year were lined up on 42nd Street between Grand Central And the parade and they were just stopping Anyone who looked like they were either underage or had open containers of alcohol Giving them tickets right there, and then there was a booth.
Speaker 1: They could go pay the ticket, so I wouldn't get mailed home to their mom.
Speaker 1: very excellent It was like 25 bucks was one of the tickets because I saw a whole group of kids getting it at the same time.
Speaker 1: I'm very good, but you know I went to a Starbucks Figuring.
Speaker 1: you know there's a long line, but all those people are in line for the bathroom not for coffee.
Speaker 1: So I go get my coffee and as I'm walking out.
Speaker 1: I trip over something you don't.
Speaker 1: I tripped over Dude passed out in front of the door of the Starbucks and vomited all over himself.
Speaker 0: That's about right.
Speaker 1: I literally tripped over the guy, and I kind of surround like are you okay, and he's wearing green and vomit And he's like vomit.
Speaker 1: It's covered.
Speaker 1: It was kind of a pinkish vomit.
Speaker 0: could have been green vomit if he had drinking green beer or some green coffee Or ate a green muffin, but you know what he does.
Speaker 1: He gives me the classic thumbs up.
Speaker 1: I'm okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah He did not look okay, and I waved to a cop and he's like yeah, I saw him.
Speaker 1: I'll deal with it.
Speaker 0: Spray him with the hose.
Speaker 0: you need to wave at the fireman.
Speaker 1: I did see something cool though.
Speaker 1: go into the parade route because I went across it.
Speaker 0: Oh shit is it.
Speaker 1: pray didn't start yet, and I wanted to go to the pen.
Speaker 1: go to the end.
Speaker 1: I wasn't gonna screw up my lunch plans for this BS.
Speaker 1: Okay, and you know the cops have.
Speaker 1: now they have you know they're like command center vehicles where they can set it up.
Speaker 1: One of those vehicles now has this Gigantic tower on a lift that comes out of the top and there's a little glass enclosed pod up there And there's one cop sitting in there watching the crowd controlling all the cameras.
Speaker 1: It was pretty cool-looking.
Speaker 0: hmm anyway, so yeah, so I basically had a similar situation where I was in work.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize it was st.
Speaker 0: Patrick's Day.
Speaker 0: I Didn't need to eat lunch out You know because I ate my peanut butter and jelly sandwich, but it was.
Speaker 0: but it was so nice out.
Speaker 0: I looked out the window.
Speaker 0: I didn't look stupidly.
Speaker 0: I didn't look down.
Speaker 0: I only look straight out the window at the Barclays building formerly the Lehman Brothers building you know and When you would never know you didn't.
Speaker 0: it was never the Barclays building the way they the way they you know have it going.
Speaker 0: But I didn't look down, so I didn't realize.
Speaker 0: So I went down You know just to go for a walk during lunch and as soon as I walked out the door.
Speaker 1: I was like ah fuck There's really nothing you can do at that point though.
Speaker 0: You're already out Mm-hmm, but anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I get out.
Speaker 0: I just start walking around.
Speaker 0: you know I went to.
Speaker 0: I was look basically I was looking for a plate because We the office usually stocks disposable plates, but they ran out.
Speaker 0: So I wanted to get like a you know a reusable plate to eat lunch with and they didn't have one of the Duane Reade.
Speaker 0: so I just came back, but it was like I had.
Speaker 0: all these streets are closed off and the cops weren't letting you in and Unless you had like you know a ticket to Radio City because it was like right next to it
Speaker 1: Ah,
Speaker 0: and then so I had to like wait, and I had to tell the cop look I'm going to the Duane Reade, and he was like all right all
Speaker 1: right Yeah How I got around cuz I couldn't get back.
Speaker 0: the parade BS was getting in my way serious like and he's like you're probably going To the parade and I'm like.
Speaker 0: no really.
Speaker 0: I'm going to Duane Reade.
Speaker 0: Do you see an inch of green on my body?
Speaker 1: I accidentally wore green at this tiny little thing.
Speaker 1: smell alcohols on me You know, but I couldn't get back.
Speaker 1: so you know what I did.
Speaker 1: I went into the subway station at Bryant Park, and you cut under.
Speaker 1: yeah very good I had to pay, but you know unlimited metro car.
Speaker 0: Oh, yes, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah good call I'm using that tunnel a lot more now that it's basically free.
Speaker 0: so what was worse is I finally got back to the office through all the drunken black people fuckers right and I leave work and I before I left work I looked out the window at the street to make sure and I saw a few green here and there but it didn't look crazy from up above.
Speaker 0: I Walk out of the building and there is this like Red Bull truck thing parked directly in front of my building.
Speaker 0: That's bad news with like a sound system playing at the front.
Speaker 0: See I'm on the seventh floor so I didn't hear it and I was looking out the other window, so I didn't see it.
Speaker 0: Hey, and like there is a drunken mob in front of it dancing and drinking and partying it up I just draw that's right next to my building and so I basically Ducked into the subway real quick like huh?
Speaker 0: Oh, and then I came home.
Speaker 1: really what I wonder?
Speaker 1: remember beacon.
Speaker 1: every year We had the the opening bit of the pub crawl.
Speaker 1: But remember last year the last pub crawl we had to deal with they were gonna ban it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Did they ban it?
Speaker 1: I don't know what's happening.
Speaker 0: Yeah I have to ask Alex and Jess the one thing that sort of you know saved the day from being just a drunken mess hating Everybody was.
Speaker 0: I was on the subway over here just now and I'm standing on the subway like you do Waiting to get to Queensborough Plaza.
Speaker 0: I'm in the tunnel.
Speaker 0: I look behind.
Speaker 0: me is a dude.
Speaker 0: He's reading some Scott Pilgrim.
Speaker 0: What's up, dude, and you know seeing out social currency in action?
Speaker 0: Yeah, we talked a little bit.
Speaker 0: I told him the mocha was in a few weeks.
Speaker 0: He's like, oh he knew what it was.
Speaker 0: You know, he just kept missing it, but he because it's earlier this year he said he'd probably see me there and He likes that pilgrim.
Speaker 0: he likes walking dead.
Speaker 0: he just doesn't have a lot of monies Like most comic fans.
Speaker 0: He doesn't buy too many but you know.
Speaker 0: So I was like, hey, not everyone on this horrible day is horrible.
Speaker 0: and he was reading volume 4.
Speaker 0: So, you know, it wasn't like, you know, it was the real deal.
Speaker 1: So what someone who's reading volume 2?
Speaker 1: they don't cut it.
Speaker 0: Well, you know if they're reading volume 1 that means they might just be trying it out.
Speaker 0: But if they're reading volume 4 then they're definitely the fan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at least in my perception the people, you know that when you try to get someone who's not into geeky stuff Or you know, they're the kind of person who says oh, I wouldn't like Scott Pilgrim I don't read comic books.
Speaker 1: the same people who say things like I don't like robot shows.
Speaker 1: They wouldn't even try it.
Speaker 1: they were like they'd have the first volume they'd read two pages of and be like, this is crap It's just video game BS and they wouldn't even bother.
Speaker 1: if you're holding it for more than five minutes and it's open You probably already like it Mm-hmm Alrighty.
Speaker 0: Yeah So, oh, so for once right?
Speaker 0: This is a rare event, right?
Speaker 0: Very rare.
Speaker 0: I think we should make it less rare because I think the fact that it's sort of a one of those self-fulfilling Prophecies, you know because it is so rare that we do this.
Speaker 0: It is so rare.
Speaker 0: They mean, you know, it's it's that kind of thing Yeah, but basically I go into a geek bag.
Speaker 1: Oh shit, then what like a year and a half?
Speaker 0: Yeah, people forget this that you know, I think it's the podcast is the thing I philosophically I don't want geek nights.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of podcasts out there that become they respond to their users in the podcast.
Speaker 0: listeners.
Speaker 0: users Tell them a programmer, right?
Speaker 0: You know, they respond to the show listeners in the show.
Speaker 0: so much Right that it becomes a community show where it's about the community and it's not accessible to people who aren't in the community anymore Right, so I wanted to avoid that.
Speaker 0: but at the same time you I like getting feedback But you the way to encourage feedback is to include the feedback in the show, you know And that that brings you to closer to being a community podcast, which I don't want to be.
Speaker 1: so you To achieve the fine balance I would say there are two secondary weird complications.
Speaker 1: we have that a lot of times people will say something really interesting and I argue with them or I have a response and I either just email them back or it's in the forum and I just post exactly.
Speaker 0: but anyway the I have a geek back for reals that is not you know.
Speaker 0: inside Basically, if you remember there is a listener named Chase Gordon who has moved up the ranks and the listener ranking scale.
Speaker 1: Isn't he pretty much like number one listener who isn't already a member of our crew?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: He's.
Speaker 0: he has moved up the ranks significantly.
Speaker 0: Isn't he perhaps the top five listeners now?
Speaker 0: yeah, not bad and basically, he right.
Speaker 0: number one thing I think he's one of those guys that we always meet at the the The the concerts at PAX, you know, he's one of those guys, you know, which one.
Speaker 0: I think he might be the animating one that Emily talked to but I can't remember.
Speaker 0: I'm not a hundred percent sure.
Speaker 1: we kind of made friends with them by accident because we happen to stand near them.
Speaker 0: Number two, he is definitely the guy.
Speaker 0: I'm almost 100% positive.
Speaker 0: He is the dude who did Riven Scott's old Rochester whiskey in that comic.
Speaker 0: He is also definitely 100%.
Speaker 0: no, you know question at all.
Speaker 0: He is the guy who won the geek nights ad contests somewhat recently.
Speaker 0: So I sent him all six volumes of Akira which was the prize for said contest.
Speaker 1: I forget.
Speaker 1: Did you send the remastered new one?
Speaker 0: I said I said in the old one They're basically the exactly the same 100%.
Speaker 0: there you go.
Speaker 0: So there was no point and you know even deciding about it.
Speaker 0: So because I sent him this prize he sent back some other stuff, right?
Speaker 0: He sent me some emails and such.
Speaker 0: but then he sent me this book and this book is called the devil in the white city.
Speaker 0: Hold on.
Speaker 0: The full title is not displaying devil in the white city Murder magic and madness at the fair that changed America and It is a is that the World's Fair is the Chicago era 1893 World's Fair perhaps the best World's Fair.
Speaker 0: No the 1960s ish New York Queens World's Fair.
Speaker 1: Why is that one better?
Speaker 0: Because that's my World's Fair and had Belgian waffles.
Speaker 1: because you were there I wasn't there.
Speaker 0: But Belgian waffles can't lose, you know, I can make Belgian waffles.
Speaker 1: the diner has Belgian waffles.
Speaker 0: Do you not know about the World's Fair Belgian waffle?
Speaker 1: I know all about.
Speaker 1: we actually talked about this on the show.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure You will not make that building, you know, find someone who ate one and you will.
Speaker 0: you know You will not.
Speaker 0: I mean my mom who had that Belgian waffle.
Speaker 0: She was at the pan cut to the end and she ate that waffle and That's not a Belgian waffle though at Le Pen cote dien Is that the the World's Fair waffle was still better than that waffle and that's a pretty good waffle.
Speaker 1: so Tinted glasses.
Speaker 0: I don't know about that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the point is is you're not gonna duplicate that waffle.
Speaker 0: All right, secondly, so he sent me this book All right.
Speaker 0: It's like okay awesome listener sends me a book.
Speaker 0: cuz he wants me to read it.
Speaker 0: He's a big fan of it and it sounds I haven't read it yet, but it sounds like it's up my alley.
Speaker 0: I like World's Fairs a whole lot.
Speaker 0: if I was the mayor of any place my first thing would be to get the World's Fair to be in that place and The thing that makes him so high up in the rankings.
Speaker 0: cuz I mean, you know people have sent us stuff before.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sending me a book.
Speaker 0: It's like okay send a book.
Speaker 1: I'll remember the the cornucopia.
Speaker 0: Yeah, someone's in a boo cornucopia just as good as sending a book.
Speaker 0: I've got my pit boy inside the box with the book and he was smart.
Speaker 0: He used a $5 You know USPS flat rate box, right inside the book was a letter on paper, right?
Speaker 0: But it wasn't just a scrolling on paper It was a prepared paper perhaps the letter in itself a work of art that he created Right.
Speaker 0: It was all colored You know all brown to look all old and he typed on it with.
Speaker 0: it appears to look like he typed on it with an Actual typewriter if not some sort of really awesome looks like a typewriter font and somehow gets the printer ink to look like typewriting
Speaker 1: Trick
Speaker 0: right and the contents of his letter were incredibly Steampunk And to awesome and I wish I would have remembered to bring it over here.
Speaker 0: Perhaps I will put this letter on the internet's for people to read rather than waste time on the show reading this letter.
Speaker 0: But it is a high quality letter and the high quality ness of this letter is it makes Chase Gordon the high quality?
Speaker 0: Geek nights listener.
Speaker 1: wait, so your geek back is basically this one guy's awesome.
Speaker 1: all the rest of you step up the game.
Speaker 0: Not that you're not awesome.
Speaker 0: Is that you have not yet displayed?
Speaker 1: Your awesome is giving us stuff.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: We're giving you free stuff entertainment right now Therefore and we don't ask for money.
Speaker 0: We are so generous you people who decide and and you think we're awesome because you're listening to us.
Speaker 0: Therefore right.
Speaker 0: Why do you think we're awesome?
Speaker 0: cuz we're generous.
Speaker 0: So if you want to be awesome, you must also be generous.
Speaker 0: generous equals awesomeness.
Speaker 0: That's that is bad rationalization.
Speaker 0: How the internet works right.
Speaker 0: someone makes a funny video puts it on YouTube for free.
Speaker 0: They're great generosity and everyone says oh my god, you are so awesome.
Speaker 1: That is how the world works now Unless that YouTube video is of you, but not created by you.
Speaker 0: If it's of you that is also awesome in a way Yeah, you can achieve internet.
Speaker 1: you're by making a really sweet ramp trying to jump it and hurting yourself.
Speaker 0: There are many ways to display awesomeness.
Speaker 0: giving us stuff is one of them.
Speaker 1: I like the way peacocks do it with their feathers like check me out.
Speaker 0: That's what you got to do.
Speaker 0: I'm.
Speaker 0: what do you think?
Speaker 0: I'm peacocking right now.
Speaker 1: See we'll know we've gone too far.
Speaker 1: if we ever have a panel that is basically watch your strut and peacock We should.
Speaker 0: we should get some peacock costumes.
Speaker 0: I'm sure they make them.
Speaker 1: I'm sure we can find one.
Speaker 1: So has to exist in some actual newsy kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: Emily sent me this the traditional wisdom.
Speaker 1: Everyone knows if you're an anime fan that by and large Animators in Japan get played pretty much crap.
Speaker 0: It doesn't pretty much anyone in any sort of awesome job in Japan get paid crap.
Speaker 1: Not all of them I mean like sumo wrestlers get pretty good money.
Speaker 1: Well, that's a you know, once they get up in the ranks They don't get paid anything in the beginning.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know anyone who is low ranking gets paid.
Speaker 1: But it's not just I mean.
Speaker 1: look at America to like in America.
Speaker 1: You won't be a video game programmer.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna make any money.
Speaker 0: in most cases It depends what kind y'all testing?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's different from being a. you know Any time.
Speaker 1: we have an industry where a lot of people are dedicated to it.
Speaker 1: They want to be in the industry.
Speaker 1: They're willing to sacrifice other aspects of careers just in order to be working in the industry And there's a very small number of actual good positions in said industry.
Speaker 1: Mmm, you get a lot of low wages exploitation and generally crap.
Speaker 0: That is true.
Speaker 1: So Emily pointed out this article that kind of takes all of that.
Speaker 1: talk about how bad it is in Japan with both video game programming and Animating and give some also manga.
Speaker 0: don't forget the manga.
Speaker 1: Oh my god manga people.
Speaker 0: I guess they're not giving numbers for manga right now.
Speaker 1: Basically, they asked a bunch of people in 2chan.
Speaker 1: They got a whole bunch of responses that are all catalogued on this Japanese site that I can't read but I'm linking to an English site talking about it and People who do these jobs are saying yeah, here's how much I make and here's what it's like.
Speaker 1: Some of these animators about a quarter of them in Japan make maybe the equivalent of ten grand a year.
Speaker 0: So how isn't Japan really expensive to live in?
Speaker 1: well Tokyo is really expensive to live in.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay So we're hands also live in Tokyo or do they?
Speaker 1: yeah I mean where's the stereotype of the animator who can barely afford ramen and this all they can afford to eat is not a stereotype.
Speaker 1: No, it's pretty much true.
Speaker 1: In fact, they're lucky to get ramen sometimes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is why you know you look at things in Japan, right people live in really tiny apartments, you know, totally true People have a kotatsu because they're not gonna pay for heat.
Speaker 0: totally true.
Speaker 1: Except look at us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we want a kotatsu just because they're cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, isn't that so weird?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know people eating ramen because it's really cheap and they can't afford, you know, sushi or meats.
Speaker 0: It's because meats are wicked expensive.
Speaker 1: Of someone in the Midwest saying you know what I have this dishwasher, but I'd rather not have it.
Speaker 1: I want a sink that I have to manually wash dishes in because it's cool.
Speaker 1: I see people out in other places doing that.
Speaker 0: I think the thing with the kotatsu is that it's it's like.
Speaker 0: it's also a table.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's also really efficient heating.
Speaker 1: I remember a lot of Japanese homes don't have central heating or cooling.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which I still think is kind of a problem.
Speaker 1: But all that aside the numbers here are pretty Soul crushing.
Speaker 1: if you're one of those people who thinks like I'll make it over there.
Speaker 1: and in America It's kind of the same way.
Speaker 1: you think I'll make it in the video.
Speaker 0: Does this supply numbers about like what you know, the high-level anime people's make like what does Miyazaki make?
Speaker 0: You know, I'm sure me is like, yeah well it talk it's.
Speaker 1: it breaks it down into groups like 33 percent 10 percent something like that.
Speaker 1: and obviously the hot like Hideo is making a lot of money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, the thing is like he might.
Speaker 0: he's obviously much richer than we are.
Speaker 0: There's no question about that.
Speaker 0: You know, he's probably wealthy, but I question whether like, you know is Kojima really as rich as say like rock band dude in the US, you know or rock band dude in Japan?
Speaker 0: That's true too, but you know rock band isn't from Japan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a. it's harmonics Activision.
Speaker 1: Oh, I thought you meant like a guy in a rock band.
Speaker 1: Oh the guy just our rock band.
Speaker 1: hearing game developers to game developers here, you know I don't think that like here's where I think a big difference is in Japan And I think this is primarily cultural.
Speaker 1: more people are more willing to put up with more salaryman bullshit Mmm, I think a lot of people who anime do it out of passion and basically that is why the industry gets away with paying So little.
Speaker 1: but a lot of people, you know the argument they make in Japan and this is probably true Is that well if we paid the animators more we couldn't make nearly as much anime and almost all of it would be completely Outsourced overseas.
Speaker 1: no more animation in Japan.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: I mean probably true.
Speaker 0: think about someone like Satoshi khan, right?
Speaker 0: He makes amazing movies, you know from madhouse and such.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: or think about someone like Murayama who is the head of madhouse the studio which you know makes Stokes econ's movies, right?
Speaker 0: He's got money.
Speaker 0: We saw him.
Speaker 0: He came to the u.s.
Speaker 0: He wore had nice clothes.
Speaker 0: He had a high expensive, you know DSLR camera.
Speaker 0: He's probably making six figures and the first digit is probably not a one I would guess Right, but he's probably not making like millions Whereas I'm pretty sure right someone with a similar position if they were making like movies in the u.s Like someone at like DreamWorks making you know Animated movies.
Speaker 0: a director of those is maybe a millionaire, you know It's.
Speaker 0: I don't have any like numbers for this but it's sort of like.
Speaker 0: my feeling is that you know in America the same job Even in the higher levels is getting more money, you know, yeah Well, I mean it's not like.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: what I'm trying to say Is that the the director the higher level people in Japan aren't exploiting the lower ones?
Speaker 0: It's like they're also not making as much as they would.
Speaker 0: and you know the u.s Everyone is making more than doing the whole.
Speaker 1: I think a secondary part of it Is that a large number of people become fans of something specific like animation and basically want that to be their life No matter what, like I'm willing to do whatever it takes to be an animator.
Speaker 1: hmm and I think for a lot of things in America video games are one of the and video games and Sports are some of the only careers that are like that.
Speaker 1: I mean thing well that people who make it to professional sports and even you know The amateurs make a lot of money.
Speaker 0: The thing is the exploitation in American sports is in the college sports college football in college basketball.
Speaker 0: It doesn't happen in Baseball and hockey because those are primarily.
Speaker 0: they have minor leagues as opposed to college.
Speaker 0: Which is why I really think if I was in charge, I don't think there should be College basketball college football.
Speaker 0: I know there's like blasphemy.
Speaker 0: It should be minor leagues if you want to.
Speaker 0: if your career is going to be basketball or you're gonna try for it You shouldn't be going to college taking up someone's spot.
Speaker 1: Well, you should be going to college because only 1% of those people are gonna miss you.
Speaker 0: But it's like don't you know this college?
Speaker 0: the basketball helps schools in that it brings in money.
Speaker 0: But at the same time we could just you know simulate that by taking money from the minor league Basketball and giving it to the schools, you know by other means.
Speaker 0: but if you just go to minor league basketball You know get hired by a team and if you're not good enough then go to college.
Speaker 1: There's some really interesting quotes from this article to our one guy.
Speaker 1: He's a video game programmer said my only take-home pay is the smiles of our customers.
Speaker 1: Mmm, and I think this guy has the completely wrong idea about a business model because as River City ransom taught me smiles are free.
Speaker 0: That's right It's just.
Speaker 1: it's an interesting read and if you read Japanese you can look at the actual article that talks about this a lot more.
Speaker 1: but I Think there's a really bigger root issue.
Speaker 1: I don't want to talk about it a lot on this show But think about the argument they're making.
Speaker 1: in Japan at least if we paid these people a living wage Then we could not do the job here at all and it would just be overseas and there'd be almost no animation made in this country.
Speaker 0: and That is true despite like the collapse, you know There's a lot less fans a lot less people watching a lot less people buying.
Speaker 0: they are able to put out an incredibly large amount of Content.
Speaker 1: that is, you know, it's not the highest Though basically on the backs of the work.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: That's basically what it is because these people are paid almost nothing.
Speaker 0: They are able to make all this anime and it's at the quality level that it's at.
Speaker 1: But think about what's going on in the world right now.
Speaker 1: many industrialized nations, especially the US and Japan.
Speaker 1: Much of the money they make much of their economy is based on intellectual property Mmm, and that's why there's so all these fights about you know, protecting intellectual property as opposed to physical property.
Speaker 1: But and their worry is that you know the third world or countries that aren't number one that aren't the US and Japan are going to Steal their intellectual property and just copy it and not pay us back.
Speaker 1: That shouldn't be the thing they're worried about.
Speaker 1: what they should be worried about Is that if things continue eventually the third world countries are just going to manufacture intellectual property.
Speaker 1: That's just as good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is that Not happened, you know You know, there's this slow rise of like.
Speaker 1: the Korean animation is getting better and better and better as time goes on because that's where They were outsourcing a lot of the low-level animation stuff.
Speaker 0: The thing is they're able to animate things that look really great.
Speaker 0: They can't tell a story for crap.
Speaker 1: So yeah, I mean it's gonna happen though I mean all these.
Speaker 1: the more they fight Outsourcing like this the more it's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: Anyway in the long run We got to figure out more fundamental ways to deal with the economy of the fact that it's not viable to make the things that people expect in the industrialized world IP or not Internally.
Speaker 1: and if we do it externally we kind of set up.
Speaker 1: so we set ourselves up for a fall regardless.
Speaker 0: The thing is the US and Japan Pretty much more than any other country in all of history Have been the only ones that have really been able to majorly export culture their own culture worldwide.
Speaker 0: Movie that's made in the US is gonna play Avatar right plays around the world Whereas even like the hottest movie in France that might play around the world But that's just one whereas pretty much every blockbuster movie, you know in the US plays around the world.
Speaker 1: you know and look at just compare the population of Japan as a Percentage of the world population and then consider the mind share that Japanese pop culture has worldwide.
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 1: I want to use this as a thing of the day Just because we haven't talked about it in a while and it is a surprisingly solid webcomic.
Speaker 1: but anime news Nina has the 100th comic up and It's pretty great.
Speaker 1: And I realize now really why I like anime news Nina so much independently the fact that it's kind of Surprisingly biting and harsh on anime culture, which is not what you would expect for the kind of semi official webcomic for something Like the anime news network.
Speaker 0: Yeah, usually when you have say like, you know a movie magazine or you know Like it's all it's gonna be rah rah rah movies, right?
Speaker 0: Whereas anime news network is not always rah rah rah anime.
Speaker 0: Sometimes it's like hey anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and that's really, you know, that's kind of good.
Speaker 0: I think that helps out the anime industry a lot and I think it'd be better if you know some other industries had similar News outlets and anime news network anime news.
Speaker 1: Nina is definitely a part of that Yep, but I realized something else because the in the 100th comic She kind of breaks the wall by having a nerd call her out in a way that made me realize that We do the exact same freaking thing.
Speaker 1: Look at all the references in anime news.
Speaker 1: It's to anime that I care about and then Scott cared about stuff that was popular as we were getting into anime.
Speaker 1: I mean she does the whole thing about Shiki Yugi and all that.
Speaker 1: It's all like 90s anime and OAVs and I don't know she's cut from the same anime fan stripe that we are.
Speaker 0: No, she's probably our age.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just found that interesting.
Speaker 1: So if you guys aren't reading it and you're an anime fan, you probably should be yeah And if you feel offended by it at all, you're probably one of those people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh so what this is website I found today called code Oregon calm and you go to it and you get a picture of an organ and you think oh It's a PN organ.
Speaker 0: Let me play and you start clicking on the keys and nothing happens and you go Oh, what the hell is this organ that doesn't even play?
Speaker 0: The way it works is you type in a website like a URL like google.com or something like that And then you push the button.
Speaker 0: This is play this website and what will happen is it will take the code of that website?
Speaker 0: I guess it doesn't explain exactly how it works or at least I haven't read it yet.
Speaker 0: It takes you know, the HTML JavaScript whatever from that website and somehow converts that into.
Speaker 0: You know music that is in the key of whatever, you know It gives it a synth loop and a drum loop and whatever.
Speaker 0: and it see.
Speaker 1: now how did it?
Speaker 1: It almost sounded from the music sample you played at least that it just uses the HTML to seed some sort of set of existing Nice sounds that will all mesh together no matter what.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know how exactly how it works.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna figure it out.
Speaker 0: But regardless it's pretty cool and You know, you can go and type in different sites to see what they sound like and it's fun.
Speaker 1: hmm, see though what you should do is make sites that are literally just things like H1 h1 h1 to see what it does with it.
Speaker 0: That's a good idea.
Speaker 0: It's figured out.
Speaker 0: reverse engineer how it works.
Speaker 0: Yeah thing is I think it'd be easier to just go and look at the code of code organ to figure out how it works.
Speaker 1: Oh is the code available?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it might probably like JavaScript or something I could.
Speaker 1: probably JavaScript might just be calling stuff on a server.
Speaker 0: Let me see.
Speaker 0: It's using some jQuery stuff.
Speaker 0: I could probably figure out how this works.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll see.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's a cool concept, but people have done things like this a million times before.
Speaker 1: It's a flash thing, I guess what they usually do is basically set it up to where it'll sound good no matter what and the source input is kind of just a Like random seed as opposed to it actually kind of making the music of the website.
Speaker 1: It just makes a song that the idea of that song happens to be the entirety of the text of the website.
Speaker 0: Hmm We'll see.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so the meta Moment which we often forget to do but is important because very soon conventions penny arcade expo is Going to be the East penny arcade in Boston next weekend Not this weekend, but next as in Friday March 26 27 28.
Speaker 1: We are doing three panels there beyond dungeons and dragons losing should be fun and beyond Candyland.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: also Action Castle which is not our panel technically, but it'll be awesome.
Speaker 1: You should leave more awesome than our panels.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you should if you're gonna you know, I don't care what panels you go to.
Speaker 0: action castle is like the mandatory at at PAX East.
Speaker 0: okay number two on Friday April 2nd Saturday 3rd and Sunday 4th in the same bad time same bad in the same exact building in Boston the Heinz Convention Center is anime Boston.
Speaker 1: We will be there doing five panels five.
Speaker 1: Oh god Yeah, they're almost all on Friday.
Speaker 1: and then Saturday is dick around and go to the concert day and Sunday is go home day.
Speaker 0: Yeah After a week, we got a flight Sunday.
Speaker 0: So I don't know how much anime Boston will be doing on Sunday But regardless, yep Saturday though.
Speaker 1: I'm looking forward to very much So big con stuff coming up the book club still going.
Speaker 0: It's Carl Sagan's cosmos, which you should all read Oh and don't forget that April 10th and 11th is the Museum of comic and cartoon art arts festival in New York City.
Speaker 1: Always awesome always relevant to Wednesday.
Speaker 0: You'll be doing zero panels.
Speaker 0: We will be walking around as schmucks just like everyone else.
Speaker 1: Well, we will also be buying more comics than we should we'll be.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna have a new.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking about doing this Right, and here's what my policy is gonna be at mocha, right?
Speaker 0: Basically, it is the Scott's mocha challenge.
Speaker 0: the way this works is you go up to me, right?
Speaker 0: Or I come up to you and I say I will.
Speaker 0: you know I will buy X that you want me to buy.
Speaker 0: if you buy X that I want you to buy, huh?
Speaker 0: And that's how.
Speaker 0: and the thing is you can't you know, they gotta be relatively equal in price.
Speaker 0: I can't be like I'll buy that $1 mini comic if you buy that $50 slip case unless you agree to.
Speaker 0: you know I like this idea as long you know, the prices are pretty close.
Speaker 0: So that way, you know, basically it'll sell more shit and you'll be able to.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: It's like hey that guy says this is good.
Speaker 0: I will trust you but only if you also trust me.
Speaker 1: Well now that we live in the city one thing I'm gonna do differently is if anything is cool.
Speaker 1: I'm just buying it.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm not even gonna look before I would not buy things cuz I didn't want to carry him around.
Speaker 0: the rest I'm bringing a bag to carry stuff around in bringing a rolly bag.
Speaker 1: No big bag like, you know, I have a rolly bag That's basically dedicated to carrying board games to events.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 0: Do you want to bring that to carry comics home?
Speaker 1: I don't want to be that guy Of course.
Speaker 1: the thing is that guy has a rolly thing already full that he brings to the car.
Speaker 0: Exactly those guys who bring their rolly things full of comics usually bring a long box full of comics.
Speaker 0: They're trying to sell and or get graded and instead I'll bring autographs and or all three together They'll get them autographed and they'll get them graded.
Speaker 1: then they'll sell them at the same at the cut I'll bring an empty one and then I'll leave with it full.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 0: So anyway, so Wolverine oh shit.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: It's Wolverine.
Speaker 0: So Recently, right?
Speaker 0: I don't know if people know this Marvel.
Speaker 0: has you know some comics that are the ultimate comics right?
Speaker 0: ultimate spider-man ultimate x-men Whatever and the original idea this started like a decade ago or over a decade ago and the idea was like hey Reading spider-man is kind of hard because it's unlike issue bajillion and if you haven't been reading spider-man since the 60s It's hard to figure out.
Speaker 0: learn everything that's going on.
Speaker 0: If all you've ever done is watch some spider-man movies, right?
Speaker 0: so they made ultimate spider-man.
Speaker 0: it was number one and you could just start reading it from the beginning and You would know everything and you wouldn't need to you know Know all this stuff to understand spider-man.
Speaker 0: and they did this for a bunch of different comics.
Speaker 0: So you could just start reading all the ultimate comics and you'd be set.
Speaker 0: The problem is is 10 years ago.
Speaker 0: So if you want to start reading ultimate comics today You've got 10 years of comics you have to read.
Speaker 0: so it's like oh my god, right?
Speaker 0: They totally defeated the purpose.
Speaker 0: So it's like well if we want someone to start reading comics now, what do they do?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: So they came out with ultimate spider-man number one again, you know, they reset and I think it's still the same universe, but it's you know It's.
Speaker 0: it's reset to a point at which you don't need to know anything.
Speaker 0: and you know They made an entry point and everything is now number one again.
Speaker 0: So these are all super cheap and discounted.
Speaker 0: because you know I buy my comics on the pre-order internets and one of the comics I got was ultimate X number one and I knew That.
Speaker 0: okay, the letter X is the title.
Speaker 0: This is gonna have something to do with mutants perhaps x-men.
Speaker 0: But I didn't really know for sure what it was until I read it and I got it and I read it.
Speaker 0: I'm basically much to my surprise.
Speaker 0: It was son of Wolverine.
Speaker 0: I don't know why that is didn't title it son of Wolverine.
Speaker 0: I guess cuz I probably would never have bought it if it was not all the sons because I'm sure he has like a thousand kids.
Speaker 0: Hello no, it's it's just.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 0: basically this comic is son of Wolverine and I started reading it and after the first few pages I sort of realized oh, it's son of Wolverine.
Speaker 0: and I was like do I really care about son of Wolverine right?
Speaker 0: You know this I was sort of lukewarm, but by the time I got to the end I was like, wow I guess I do kind of care about son of Wolverine.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, he's just you know pulls up with fists.
Speaker 1: He's and she's like have you ever tried, you know.
Speaker 1: with the claws he goes And claws pop out.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 0: He's like, oh, huh Wow, and then it was weird.
Speaker 0: the adamantium came out.
Speaker 0: It was like whoa.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is I worry that the the answer to that is gonna be some bullshit comic book crap.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: We'll find out.
Speaker 1: They didn't really react to that strongly enough.
Speaker 1: They're like, huh?
Speaker 1: And he's like, yeah, they're not adamantium She's like, yeah Well, you know they put that on after the fact and then they turned adamantium and he's like, huh?
Speaker 1: And she's like.
Speaker 1: that's weird That's weird.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, I think what was interesting though is that at least the people in the comic they weren't Because normally in a comic the people just be retarded, you know, whereas in this the parents were like, okay come clean You know, it wasn't.
Speaker 0: there wasn't like this excessive Moronic drama.
Speaker 0: It was just sort of normal comic book shadow cat.
Speaker 1: just come she's like, yeah, you're Wolverine's kid.
Speaker 0: Here's a video Yep, and then well, it was not a video is more like a Princess Leia message.
Speaker 1: That's basically just a video from from.
Speaker 0: I guess Wolverine is dead in the ultimate universe.
Speaker 0: So it was a really be dead.
Speaker 0: No, he's probably alive.
Speaker 0: But yeah, you know, so yeah, you know The art also was like freakin crazy.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 0: Did you notice like during the opening of the comic with the drag race?
Speaker 0: I couldn't really tell what was up, you know, I knew that these were probably important characters, but that's all I knew.
Speaker 1: I expected it to be.
Speaker 1: you know punk is racing and then they run into the son of Wolverine or some crap like that.
Speaker 0: And you saw on the cover there was a guy with claws.
Speaker 0: So, you know which is?
Speaker 0: he is the son of Wolverine obviously, but I didn't you know know really what it was about.
Speaker 0: I just thought okay, it's high school x-men something.
Speaker 0: But then it is the part where you know kitty pride shows up at the house and there's that panel in the bottom Right where the lights coming over and he's on top of the roof and he has like the Wolverine hair.
Speaker 0: But he draws it in like such a way that it's like it's not obvious the Wolverine hair.
Speaker 0: But then in the one panel and then it makes sense when you look at the way he draws it in the other panels It's sort of like almost Wolverine hair.
Speaker 0: He's got.
Speaker 0: no one can pull off that Wolverine hair except Wolverine Mmm, and maybe son of Wolverine Yeah, but yeah, you know if you like Wolverine, you know, I would wait for the trade and get ultimate X trade number one.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna buy it and I'll see if trade number two or well if the rest of trade one is good Then I'll get trade too, but maybe at least issue number one was cool.
Speaker 1: Maybe think a lot about Wolverine as a character in general because the you know recently Wolverines been up in.
Speaker 1: you know My FRC culture again at Wildwood last year.
Speaker 1: We all watched everyone but Scott.
Speaker 1: He wasn't around.
Speaker 1: We watched the Wolverine and the x-men like the new x-men cartoon Which gets a million bonus points for the fact that it knows what made the original?
Speaker 1: X-men cartoon popular and does enough of that to you know.
Speaker 1: say hey look we know here we go Even in the opening song that the theme is the original theme just kind of redone.
Speaker 1: It's like it's there in the opening of this.
Speaker 0: I'll have to go check that opener.
Speaker 1: But it's weird because it's Wolverine in the x-men is kind of Wolverine ends up being the leader and everyone else is trying to run Away from the x-men.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know the thing is like most people don't like Cyclops, but like Cyclops is my guy But he's I don't.
Speaker 1: he's deterred.
Speaker 1: I mean depending on where you're reading.
Speaker 1: He's either just Saccharine or a wuss.
Speaker 0: that's the easy I think that's you know.
Speaker 0: the problem is how he's written in the way They made his character, but how.
Speaker 1: the problem with the characters how they made the character like.
Speaker 0: you know the like.
Speaker 0: You know if he's he should be the awesome leader guy.
Speaker 1: You know he was in the cartoon.
Speaker 1: Yeah the original cartoon He was just awesome all the time.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's the that's the Cyclops Wolverine.
Speaker 1: in the x-men though I like him cuz he's basically you know gene is gone And he's just kind of like he's unshaven drinking a bottle of Jack Daniels.
Speaker 1: He tries to kill Wolverine.
Speaker 1: He's living like this Kelsey apartment.
Speaker 0: No, but Wolverine is sorta.
Speaker 0: It's it's strange.
Speaker 0: It's like Wolverine You know originally was like this side character in like some Hulk comic And then he like when the x-men went to Canada they like bumped into him along the way, and he's like okay There's this freaky guy You know and he wasn't really.
Speaker 0: you know the Wolverine that we have today is like incredibly different mostly because of Frank Miller You know and that Frank Miller Wolverine just became so crazy popular That they sort of now Wolverine is like you know the most important thing and they just stick him all over the place.
Speaker 1: That's why he's on every team's like team a will be Cyclops storm and Wolverine team B. Will be the Hulk and Wolverine Team C. Just Wolverine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's got his own comic book.
Speaker 0: He's got.
Speaker 0: he's on the Avengers.
Speaker 0: He's on the x-men.
Speaker 0: He's on the Like everything.
Speaker 0: there is not a comic book you can buy from Marvel almost that doesn't have Wolverine or a mention of Wolverine in it And it's like are there like a hundred Wolverines or something?
Speaker 1: he also has the backstory of everything.
Speaker 1: He was everywhere involved in everything.
Speaker 0: It's also.
Speaker 0: You know he's sort of invincible to who at the.
Speaker 0: yeah The healing power used to just be.
Speaker 0: originally it was just healing power.
Speaker 0: now It's like yeah, you could like you know blow him up with a nuke Skin cell left and eventually he'll just you know eventually oh shit.
Speaker 1: It's Wolverine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was pissed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so but apparently he's dead.
Speaker 0: for reals in Wolverine he's dead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just like at that America.
Speaker 0: So what's everyone else?
Speaker 0: It's interesting how.
Speaker 1: think about it's everything that you would normally hate in a character.
Speaker 1: He's the invincible badass Who is basically he's all-powerful effectively and can't be killed and will always win.
Speaker 1: And he has a cool mysterious past and he's rugged and everything.
Speaker 1: and yet it kind of works.
Speaker 1: But he's kind of it's.
Speaker 1: maybe it's just because he's an amalgamation of every individual thing that in the 80s and 90s people thought would Be cool in a character, and he also did a lot of stuff that you know was done in manga that you didn't really see in American comics, but then again, that's just Frank Miller.
Speaker 0: Well, I think a lot of what the problem is with Wolverine is that you know Wolverine was just sort of superhero guy.
Speaker 0: You know he's just a fun guy with claws who was you know slightly more You know down-to-earth and rugged and angrier than the other.
Speaker 0: you know sort of Tight-swearing superheroes around him.
Speaker 0: you know he was a nice contrast.
Speaker 0: And then Frank Miller came and you know pulled him all the way down into the dark Wolverine.
Speaker 0: But then after you know after Frank Miller a lot of the people doing like the dark rugged angry Wolverine character What they actually ended up doing was more like a stereotype of Frank Miller's Wolverine.
Speaker 0: He would just be sort of like this angry guy who said bub a lot.
Speaker 0: You know he wasn't.
Speaker 0: actually It wasn't the real deal.
Speaker 0: It was like you know this Caricature of the real.
Speaker 1: it's the same as and I might get some flack for this the modern like the recent Batman movies where Batman Is basically just a guy who smoked too much.
Speaker 1: as I'm Batman like that's all the character is now mmm.
Speaker 1: But we know we were talking about the origin story before and how it like.
Speaker 1: it was a mystery like he's just the guy with no Origin.
Speaker 1: then they kind of explained the origin.
Speaker 1: But look at what they did.
Speaker 1: every time they explained his origin in any capacity.
Speaker 1: it always has this element of but what was he?
Speaker 1: doing before that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, where was he?
Speaker 0: never.
Speaker 0: where was he born?
Speaker 0: Who's his mom?
Speaker 0: Yeah, right?
Speaker 0: There is a comic Wolverine origins.
Speaker 0: I've never read it, but supposedly like that has his origin in it for real, so I don't know how far back it goes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I know there's like fighting.
Speaker 1: You know Louisiana stuff.
Speaker 1: There's Japan which is basically just lone wolf.
Speaker 1: that is true.
Speaker 0: It's like he's all over the world.
Speaker 0: You know he's got the Canada parts right because he's from Canada Where that's.
Speaker 0: we're all like the.
Speaker 0: you know the weapon x project was but he's also got all this stuff that goes on in Japan.
Speaker 0: He's got all this stuff that goes on now.
Speaker 1: the end stuff is weird.
Speaker 0: He's got all the stuff that goes on in the south.
Speaker 0: He's got all this stuff that goes on with like the Avengers and like the superhero world level stuff.
Speaker 0: It's like how can one guy have all these things in his life?
Speaker 1: by making him the consummate badass dark and brooding Especially in the Japanese stuff.
Speaker 1: you know ancient history that he's all through history.
Speaker 1: Wolverine is there.
Speaker 1: He's just an anri's vampire.
Speaker 0: You think so that?
Speaker 1: no at least character-wise.
Speaker 1: That's what his character functions as in a lot of those stories.
Speaker 1: Mmm, and I think that comes kind of to the root.
Speaker 1: weird Stuff of Wolverine is that American comic books tend to be very static and they tend to not like.
Speaker 1: They basically kept.
Speaker 1: every time they had a cool idea like what if we had a character who was like this?
Speaker 1: they basically just said Well, let's just make that part of Wolverines backstory when they should have made a new character.
Speaker 0: Well the thing is making new characters right is?
Speaker 0: they don't sell comics You know if you go to the store, and it says you know guy from Japan.
Speaker 0: right you know They have guys from Japan and they those guys Superheroes.
Speaker 0: if you put them on the front cover of the comic and name the comic after them it won't sell.
Speaker 0: But if you call it Wolverine like if I've gone to comic book stores And you go on Wednesday everyone whether you buy comics or not find your local comic store.
Speaker 0: go there on Wednesday right after work and watch what the people who are regulars just watch them.
Speaker 0: buy their comics right you will see these guys.
Speaker 0: They'll go to the shelf and they'll just buy every comic that has the word spider-man or a picture of spider-man on the cover.
Speaker 0: There are other guys.
Speaker 0: They'll go and they'll buy every comic that is a picture of Wolverine or Wolverine's name or X you know and they'll just buy every single one that goes together.
Speaker 0: and This is how certain people you know they're guys to go to buy every Superman every.
Speaker 0: that's all they do.
Speaker 0: They don't think they don't look at any other comics.
Speaker 0: They don't explore They don't do anything just by every Superman every flash every.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: they have a thing.
Speaker 0: That's their thing.
Speaker 0: they buy every one of them And that's all they do.
Speaker 0: so if you were to say come up with this great idea for a comic story And you include Wolverine in that story or make Wolverine the focus.
Speaker 0: your sales are gonna be ha ha ha even if your story is Poorly written or drawn whereas maybe your story would have been better if you used like some character No one ever heard of or a new character, but your sales are gonna be right Even if your comic is actually higher quality
Speaker 1: result at least
Speaker 0: in the superhero marketplace as opposed to the mocha marketplace.
Speaker 1: We have Wolverine who has possibly the most crowded back story of any character in American comics ever You know.
Speaker 0: that's why the cut that the cartoon you watched.
Speaker 0: Why is it called Wolverine and the x-men?
Speaker 0: because we're gonna make a comic that was just called X a cartoon That was just called x-men.
Speaker 0: would not you know get as much viewers right?
Speaker 0: I mean, there's a. there's a DC cartoon that a lot of superhero people like.
Speaker 0: that's on TV right now.
Speaker 0: I've never seen it.
Speaker 0: It's called Batman brave in the bold.
Speaker 0: right.
Speaker 0: the original comic book was just called brave in the bold.
Speaker 0: Why do they call it Batman brave in the bold?
Speaker 0: because if they just made a cartoon called brave in the bold?
Speaker 0: Maybe a fraction of the people would watch it or care about it as opposed to if you call it Batman brave in the bold And Batman's in every episode.
Speaker 0: a lot more people are gonna watch it.
Speaker 1: But there's still some sort of mystique about Wolverine specifically because look at you know when they made the new x-men movies, right?
Speaker 1: They were okay movies.
Speaker 1: the first one.
Speaker 1: I thought was good.
Speaker 0: I yeah the first one I was not a fan of.
Speaker 0: I didn't see these or three second.
Speaker 1: the second third one were just Terrible.
Speaker 1: the third one was was a joke.
Speaker 0: I didn't see it.
Speaker 1: second or third remember the third one was the one where you know Every.
Speaker 1: that was back when ah she's the juggernaut.
Speaker 1: When the juggernaut was popular they changed the movie and added a scene where the juggernaut said I'm the juggernaut bitch.
Speaker 1: Right yeah, yeah, and the movie was just a joke.
Speaker 1: but Wolverine was very popular as a character among normal people who went to see these x-men movies But otherwise never read the comics didn't care about him.
Speaker 1: Hmm the movies were really popular among normal people, and there's something about Wolverine's character to where everyone always likes Wolverine.
Speaker 1: But maybe that's just I want to call this Blue cat syndrome.
Speaker 1: Emily and I were talking about this a lot last night.
Speaker 1: Oh, I found an article of someone who clearly I gotta find the article.
Speaker 1: yet He clearly does not know about the internet and furries.
Speaker 1: all right I think he has no idea about this and probably doesn't know about anime and cat girls either.
Speaker 1: But he said something along the lines of ever since avatar came out I'm seeing more and more like cat people and things like that.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, and how there are people who would like a certain kind of thing like maybe there's someone who was born to be a going Guy fan.
Speaker 1: they just never encountered that in the wild in their entire life.
Speaker 1: But there are people who would be a furry or would like anthropomorphic art But they never encountered any furries.
Speaker 0: And that's why there are more furries because they're on the internet, and then they find out about furriness.
Speaker 0: so suddenly They would have been a furry, but because if there was no internet, or if they didn't have internet They never would have actually found out they were a fur.
Speaker 1: But suddenly you know they just go to see avatar with their mom, and they're like blue cat people.
Speaker 1: whoa whoa Hmm, and I think that's what happened with Wolverine in that he's the dark brooding awesome Antihero bad guy on the surface But actually a good guy at heart.
Speaker 1: conflict like he has every element that makes a good character that you often don't get in American movies and as a result the people who saw these movies just there they want to see a summer blockbuster.
Speaker 1: They really like Wolverine because if there were more movies with characters like that they'd love them.
Speaker 1: Hmm, so I think that Wolverine is kind of the the Jack of all trades.
Speaker 1: that is the character that almost anyone will like.
Speaker 1: But because they put every kind of character in him yeah, well the thing is it's like.
Speaker 0: It's not just they put every kind of character in him.
Speaker 0: It's that he's a different character each time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not like what it's not like.
Speaker 0: he's not like an everyman.
Speaker 0: It's depending on which book you read.
Speaker 0: He's a different man.
Speaker 0: You know in one comic.
Speaker 0: He's like.
Speaker 0: you know He's actually just sort of.
Speaker 0: he's mostly responsible.
Speaker 0: He's just sort of snarky and angry and doesn't like people, but he's a good guy And he does the good thing.
Speaker 0: and another comic.
Speaker 0: He'll actually do some wrong things.
Speaker 0: Just because he's that kind of guy He's like fuck you right.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna do the bad thing you know or in some other comic.
Speaker 0: You know it's different every time, but whatever I remember.
Speaker 1: I was a huge fan of Wolverine.
Speaker 1: I didn't even like comics that much, but I collected the Wolverine cards.
Speaker 1: Remember there was like x-men cards like series one series.
Speaker 0: That was something that I felt really right is when I was a kid You know I came into comics and such in the 90s right and Wolverine You know the first Wolverine I saw was was sort of had the brown Costume.
Speaker 0: there's orange and brown.
Speaker 0: and then I saw the blue and yellow.
Speaker 1: one see blue and yellow was my first Wolverine, right?
Speaker 0: But then so I thought oh they changed it.
Speaker 0: then they did change it from you know the brown to the blue and yellow But apparently the original was blue and yellow Which I didn't find out until more recently.
Speaker 0: Then they actually change it from blue and yellow to brown back to blue and yellow.
Speaker 0: And then of course the more recent x-men they have all those x-many movie like costumes that are all different.
Speaker 0: I don't even know anymore, but you know.
Speaker 0: Regardless it was just.
Speaker 0: you know when I was a kid Wolverine was like.
Speaker 0: I didn't read like those Frank Miller ones.
Speaker 0: So I only got you know the x-men Wolverine like I was.
Speaker 0: I was reading the comic where I get his metal ripped out Everything.
Speaker 1: I remember that.
Speaker 0: I remember that oh my god.
Speaker 0: He had bone claws.
Speaker 0: Oh shit I still have those comics in the closet.
Speaker 1: I got him some.
Speaker 0: I can go dig him out.
Speaker 1: That's the very brief era where I even got issues of comics.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right But actually I'm thinking you know maybe I should go back and find like the original Frank Miller Wolverines like those the ones that you know Transformed Wolverine from.
Speaker 0: you know the Canadian just you know Superhero guy into.
Speaker 0: you know the dark and angry Wolverine.
Speaker 1: here's something interesting.
Speaker 0: So I only knew the blue and yellow, but you know of course was heavily inspired by like lone wolf and cub and such and such.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's basically lone wolf, but there's no cub right, but I read you know the comic the 90s comics.
Speaker 1: It was just like kind of Wolverines there.
Speaker 1: But because I I saw you know in the store I'd see like x-men cards and then next to those Wolverine cards, and I was like why does Wolverine have cards just for himself?
Speaker 1: So I bought him and I started collecting him and each one had a little bit of backstory on it.
Speaker 0: And yeah, I learned a lot about.
Speaker 0: you know most of what I know about superheroes because I collected freaking Marvel superheroes cards.
Speaker 0: You know I didn't actually comics.
Speaker 0: I read were x-men and Spider-man 2099.
Speaker 1: I read a little bit of x-factor in x-force But only because that was the end of comics for me when I followed the executioner song Yeah, so I was like I gotta buy other comics.
Speaker 1: Oh, and I sorted it all out.
Speaker 1: I read the whole thing and I felt really accomplished And then I decided that was never worth the effort again And I stopped.
Speaker 1: so much yeah so much work to get all the different freaking issues Yeah and most of it I didn't care about like you'd be like.
Speaker 1: oh now you have to read x-factor whatever and I'd read it and it Didn't have anything to do with what I cared about.
Speaker 0: I could have just skipped it Yeah, but it said part three of five, and you were trying to read all five parts.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah, but I learned so much about Wolverine from these cards.
Speaker 1: I still have a bunch of the foils.
Speaker 1: I didn't get all of them though, but I remember thinking someday these will make me rich.
Speaker 0: nope Unless you know you find everyone else who has that exact same card and destroy it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess I could work on that.
Speaker 0: yeah thing is there's so much Wolverine shit now like I don't understand like it's The one thing that puzzles me right is that you would think when something's rare right like think about baseball cards, right?
Speaker 0: You know you can understand that.
Speaker 0: say for example a Babe Ruth baseball card be worth more right and probably because this you know Not only are there less of them right, but it's because that's the famous guy right.
Speaker 0: But you look at something like a Wolverine card or Wolverine comic.
Speaker 0: well there aren't less of them in fact There's more of them.
Speaker 0: He's the guy, but there's so many more of them wouldn't be?
Speaker 0: you know?
Speaker 0: non Wolverine comic be more that is you know in such a lower supply Be in much.
Speaker 0: You know greater demand and price and such you know.
Speaker 1: I don't know whatever so I just randomly pull up the Wikipedia and It's kind of poorly written, but I have to read this.
Speaker 0: it's got to be gigantic right it is.
Speaker 1: But I have to read this excerpt under skills and personality because this is just too funny And I think I know who Wolverine really is all right.
Speaker 1: During his time in Japan and other countries Wolverine becomes proficient or becomes an expert in Virtually all forms of martial arts and is familiar with and experienced in virtually every fighting style on earth.
Speaker 1: He's proficient with all weaponry including firearms.
Speaker 1: There is partial to bladed weapons Defeated Captain America and Shang Chi and single combat.
Speaker 1: He has a wide knowledge of the body and fresher points.
Speaker 1: He's the successor Hokuto no Ken.
Speaker 1: That's the only way to explain it, but he doesn't make anyone explode.
Speaker 1: He punched himself to give himself the healing factor.
Speaker 0: The thing is right.
Speaker 0: if you think about this like it doesn't really Make total sense that he would beat Captain America.
Speaker 0: right because Captain America is basically like the perfect human who is also the master of Human.
Speaker 1: Wolverine is the perfect mutant oh shit.
Speaker 0: I guess that's how that goes.
Speaker 1: yeah, I mean healing factor.
Speaker 1: He's basically God.
Speaker 0: yeah But it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like oh, he's basically God.
Speaker 0: Yeah, except in Marvel Comics.
Speaker 0: This guy's like you know Galactus or whatever Thor.
Speaker 1: Thor is a superhero.
Speaker 1: It's Thor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm pretty sure Thor could beat Captain America.
Speaker 1: Yeah, could Thor be Wolverine though?
Speaker 0: or here.
Speaker 0: Let's see here's Captain America powers and abilities.
Speaker 0: He has no superhuman powers.
Speaker 0: as a result of the super soldier serum and Vita Ray treatment He is transformed.
Speaker 0: from a frail young man.
Speaker 0: Is he the perfect specimen of human development conditioning so Wolverine could just kill him.
Speaker 0: his strength endurance agility speed reflex durability healer the highest Limits of human of natural human potential has been said.
Speaker 0: his body regularly replenishes the serum.
Speaker 0: It does not wear off.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh There's more to blah blah blah during his.
Speaker 1: due to his increased lifespan he Speaks almost all languages and understands almost all cultures English Japanese.
Speaker 1: really Wolverine really speaks all Japanese Russian Chinese cayenne Spanish Arabic and Lakota.
Speaker 1: He's also known for knowledge of French Thai Vietnamese German Italian Portuguese Korean and Hindi.
Speaker 1: When Forge monitors Wolverine's vitals during a danger room training session He calls Logan's physical and mental states quote Equivalent of an Olympic level gymnast performing a gold medal routine while same simultaneously beating for chess computers in his head.
Speaker 1: He's basically just a Mary Sue who kicks everybody's ass.
Speaker 0: I didn't really you know, they've really up to Wolverine's power.
Speaker 0: originally He was just strong dude with claws But he's a grown a healing power as in if you cut him, it'll grow back.
Speaker 1: He's a gruff loner often taking leave from the x-men to deal with personal issues.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, except in Wolverine in the x-men where everyone else does that yeah, and he also totally makes out with well Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically that that whole thing is just him desperately wanting to bone Jean Grey And then she desperately wanting to bone him and then she dies and then she doesn't comes back and then she dies and then she comes Back.
Speaker 1: actually, there's this cool thing that's currently dead.
Speaker 0: I think she's gonna come back soon though.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 1: She's gonna come back.
Speaker 1: And But in case anyone, you know Wolverine in the x-men the reason we keep saying oh shit, it's Wolverine We were stinking drunk everyone.
Speaker 1: but Scott watching Wolverine in the x-men and the MRD, you know The mutant risk whatever responds something.
Speaker 1: there people are as mutants.
Speaker 1: They have a little heads-up display and every time they look at a mute It's always like his power level is over.
Speaker 0: now No shit law.
Speaker 1: and they're all these scenes Where like they'll be looking at some other mutants and be about to like fight him or arrest him and suddenly Wolverine jumps down And I feel like based on Wolverine's power.
Speaker 1: It should be like mutant mutant mutant.
Speaker 1: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: It's Wolverine in red And that became kind of like the FRC catchphrase, all right, I Think we've done all about we can on the show.
Speaker 1: Wolverine is I don't know either really like the character or really hate it But I think I actually just really like.
Speaker 0: it depends on like which little Wolverine is there at the time.
Speaker 0: You know, it's like some Wolverines are great and some are not so great?
Speaker 0: because this is what happens when you have a character.
Speaker 0: You know, look at someone like Harry Potter, right?
Speaker 0: Harry Potter is pretty much in completely controlled by JK Rowling, you know.
Speaker 0: I mean there are fan fictions, but those don't you know count right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but Wolverine the real Wolverine He's in movies is in cartoons is in comic books.
Speaker 0: all different writers all different directors all different, right?
Speaker 0: It's always the same, you know, there's some things that are always the same, you know the hair, you know, he's a dude He's never a female, you know, he's strong.
Speaker 0: He's got some sort of healing power He's got claws, but everything else is different every single time.
Speaker 0: So, you know is Wolverine really a single character?
Speaker 0: same for Batman and super, you know.
Speaker 0: And so sometimes he's good and sometimes he's not so good.
Speaker 1: due to high-level Psionic shields implanted by Professor Xavier.
Speaker 1: Wolverine's mind is highly resistant to telepathic assault Mmm, he also possesses psychic scar tissue Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually you see that news article.
Speaker 1: I'm slashed out about the Wolverine factor.
Speaker 0: What is it?
Speaker 1: They basically found a gene that if you turn it off in mice They don't scar and they basically just regrow damaged tissue.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's like a starfish.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, turn that on in mammals.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the starfish is not like.
Speaker 0: I would be cool if I had that power But it's not Wolverine level power.
Speaker 0: if you stabbed me I would die.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't like grow a new heart and come back to life.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but like cut off a finger you could theoretically grow the finger back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like a starfish.
Speaker 0: Yeah, nothing wrong with that That's completely great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it would be great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, buddy, but at the same time I would still not want my finger to get cut off.
Speaker 1: No, but I would like to have the the regeneration as long as it doesn't just cause cancer.
Speaker 0: That's also true.
Speaker 0: You might you know grow you.
Speaker 0: they might remove a cancer and then like a starfish you would grow back the cancer.
Speaker 0: That would be bad.
Speaker 1: All right, I think we're done here.
Speaker 1: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand Ok for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.