Speaker 0: It's Wednesday September 8th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight Futurama.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: and now we're actually back from PAX.
Speaker 1: How are we now?
Speaker 0: No, we're not actually back.
Speaker 0: We recorded like four weeks worth of shows the night before we flew out.
Speaker 1: I actually know this is September 8th.
Speaker 0: No, it's August 31st.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're recording like.
Speaker 0: Sure, all right Scott if this is the future then tell me what happened at PAX.
Speaker 1: I'll tell you everything that happened at PAX in another episode.
Speaker 1: I don't really feel like it now But if I have to say one thing to prove that PAX happened I can say that the the final round of the Omega thon was the omega.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay Omega claw I win.
Speaker 0: So for any of you who are new listeners You're wondering what's going on geek nights is four different shows four nights a week.
Speaker 0: You know Mondays like science and neck beards and all that.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays is what you want.
Speaker 0: Tuesdays is your gaming, but you know, I ran into a lot of anime fans at PAX.
Speaker 0: We saw three anime world order hoodies at PAX.
Speaker 1: In fact during what I think one of them was the same guy twice But during one of our panels we were like hey who watches anime?
Speaker 1: and a whole bunch of people raise their hand But they clearly they weren't hardcore anime fans because we said who is seen or heard of summer wars?
Speaker 0: and almost nobody But a bunch of the enforcers really watched anime.
Speaker 0: the good one of the cool guys I was talking to you after the late show was all about fist of the North Star.
Speaker 1: No snap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so was Our recent interview Marcos Ove and is all about this the North Star.
Speaker 0: It's kind of cool that you go to Otacon and like the people there are really not anime fans.
Speaker 0: alert.
Speaker 0: when I say Otacon I guess I use that to mean like any anime con.
Speaker 0: a lot of people are not super into anime.
Speaker 0: They're kind of just there and into anime culture and they watch a little bit anime.
Speaker 0: But all the random people I kind of talked to at PAX where anime came up They were just kind of casual anime fans and they'd seen way more anime than the average anime con attendee.
Speaker 1: I think.
Speaker 1: is they just seen more better anime because they're only watching the good stuff Whereas the so-called anime fans at the anime cons are watching tons of crap like Naruto and bleach which are tons and tons of episodes that are really terrible, but is there really tons of anime?
Speaker 0: I mean, they're watching tons of individual episodes, but not tons of different shows.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: It's exactly right Whereas the more casual fans are watching only the really quality popular stuff or the stuff from their youth.
Speaker 1: But they're watching all this.
Speaker 1: good stuff such as you know goes in the shell movies and Miyazaki movies.
Speaker 0: It was funny though At least some of the enforcers I was talking to in a gaggle on Saturday We're talking about how yeah, they were really into like Naruto and bleach and really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's interesting.
Speaker 0: But then they also had seen cowboy bebop.
Speaker 0: it goes to the shell and all that All right, and remember we when I got into anime, I was watching Dragon Ball Z and Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: I did not of course when I really got into anime.
Speaker 0: I watched vampire hunter D and project echo, but I did All right, yeah, I did both.
Speaker 0: But the funny thing is of the anime world order hoodie people one of them And I didn't catch his name because we saw him like we were getting in the elevator Like Saturday night to go pass out and this guy's like walking by in the lobby like yo anime world order And he's like yo geek nights.
Speaker 0: What up?
Speaker 0: I used to listen to you, but I disagreed with you about some anime.
Speaker 0: So I stopped listening.
Speaker 1: He was like yeah, I disagreed with you about some of the stuff you said, but he was totally friendly.
Speaker 1: He wasn't like.
Speaker 1: I hate you guys.
Speaker 1: Thank you.
Speaker 1: It's just like what's up?
Speaker 0: I'm like oh all right, but I was like what you agree with.
Speaker 0: let's talk about it.
Speaker 0: He was like I don't want to talk about it.
Speaker 0: See you later.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm like all right.
Speaker 0: go So anime world order Daryl and Gerald and Clarissa.
Speaker 0: find out who that guy is and find out what he didn't like.
Speaker 1: I want to talk to him or Stop telling you're making your listeners hate us.
Speaker 0: We got a cut to this person.
Speaker 1: we don't make our listeners hate you.
Speaker 0: we used to.
Speaker 0: we should Purpose that'll be a war you want.
Speaker 0: ever war War.
Speaker 1: it'd be hard to get my top hat and monocle for war.
Speaker 0: It'd be very difficult to have a war with those guys.
Speaker 0: cuz what am I gonna say?
Speaker 0: I'm like yeah, Hokuto no Ken is awesome like fuck.
Speaker 0: Yeah We'll have to say it sucks, but could you really say that we used to say?
Speaker 1: I will have to say that it.
Speaker 0: I used to say it sucked a long time ago, but you know what I was wrong.
Speaker 0: I was stupid.
Speaker 0: I was young.
Speaker 0: I didn't know what was up.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: There's no point having a war with someone who is already dead.
Speaker 0: I Must be causing so much trouble for Emily.
Speaker 0: she every time anyone who speaks Japanese is around.
Speaker 0: you know cuz she speaks Japanese.
Speaker 0: She hangs out with people who speak Japanese.
Speaker 0: I pretty much cannot stop myself from saying oh my wah moh shindeiru or at least being like I Don't know.
Speaker 0: I'm weird.
Speaker 1: Why do you do that?
Speaker 1: I just do you think you need to eject the Stan Lee from your body.
Speaker 1: I'm not bolding when I say oh my It's equally corny in fact perhaps even more corn.
Speaker 1: is it really corny?
Speaker 1: or is it mean even Stan Lee?
Speaker 1: well He'll say things like Excelsior or you know stuff like that or you know.
Speaker 0: see I don't think it's corny.
Speaker 0: I will argue that what I do is just weird.
Speaker 1: It's corny.
Speaker 0: now corny is this whole different level.
Speaker 1: it makes it.
Speaker 1: it causes everyone near you to groan in pain.
Speaker 1: Therefore you should not do it Everyone.
Speaker 1: just oh god stop it.
Speaker 0: That's just.
Speaker 0: I was trying to buy some anime on the Amazon.
Speaker 1: Well, why were you buying anime on the Amazon?
Speaker 1: is it not at the anime you wanted not on Netflix?
Speaker 0: Netflix is dub only it's not on crunchyroll.
Speaker 0: Actually, no.
Speaker 0: It's not on crunchyroll.
Speaker 1: Is it anyone where it's a?
Speaker 1: what anime Did you want that you had to get on DVD?
Speaker 0: well Emily has never seen try gun what?
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is?
Speaker 0: that's probably the only gap in her anime watching experience.
Speaker 0: at this point I mean mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: she she's into anime as much as we are and that's the only show I can think of.
Speaker 1: try gun was one Of my favorite shows when I first saw is still one of my favorite shows.
Speaker 1: I never got the whole box.
Speaker 1: I think I only bought the final DVD for some because we had to watch the.
Speaker 1: But anyway the We never got the full box set because it was always like a zillion dollars And it never got cheap, and they never made a thin pass.
Speaker 0: so it got re-released.
Speaker 0: It's like $32.
Speaker 0: oh Three order.
Speaker 0: it comes out in like October, but whatever.
Speaker 0: so 32 bucks.
Speaker 0: No shipping basically no sales tax.
Speaker 0: This is why anime con dealers do not get my money anymore because I in the last like three years you walk in there you Look at the box set on the table like the $5 bin, and I'm like all right.
Speaker 0: Here's a box set for five bucks.
Speaker 0: I go to Amazon $3.99.
Speaker 0: use no shipping.
Speaker 0: all right great It'll be sent to my house at the carrot home Came to a sad revelation because I was like oh, yeah, and I pre-order try gun.
Speaker 1: like nobody's business I can just tap a few buttons on my phone And I have 32 bucks pre-ordered.
Speaker 0: good to go.
Speaker 0: and then it you know after I pre-order it recommends at the bottom like you might Also like these.
Speaker 0: and I saw gunkatsu.
Speaker 0: Oh a show that I really liked like if try gun is an a anime gunkatsu.
Speaker 0: Oh, it was like a b-plus.
Speaker 0: It only doesn't get the a because the ending was bullshit.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm I don't think.
Speaker 1: actually I think I saw most of the show But I don't think I saw the end.
Speaker 0: oh good basically watch up to that climax.
Speaker 0: You know the really awesome client with the robot fight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I saw that.
Speaker 0: and then the denim all like right after the robot fight.
Speaker 1: I think I saw one or two episodes after and after.
Speaker 0: you know Albert and everybody like everything kind of gets on and everybody's having their like badminton moment.
Speaker 0: Just don't watch anymore Cuz the end is really fucking.
Speaker 1: so just stop at the salad days.
Speaker 0: the end is yeah salad days.
Speaker 0: beyond that everything's really fucking stupid And nobody's up for tennis, okay?
Speaker 0: So in front oh That was a good show.
Speaker 0: maybe I should buy it.
Speaker 0: it was.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't mind showing that to someone else Maybe watch it again, and then I looked and it was like 13 bucks.
Speaker 0: That's a really good price for the whole show, but then I thought about it And I realized that 13 bucks is really not worth it.
Speaker 0: cuz at that point The space that those DVDs take up in my apartment is almost not worth owning the show because maybe I'll watch it again once ever.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll lend it to someone once or twice, but that's really it.
Speaker 0: I can't think of anyone.
Speaker 0: I know I'm gonna lend gonkotsuo to that.
Speaker 0: I don't already have to lend like bebop Ava, Eska, Trigon Eska flow.
Speaker 1: if it was if it was $13 right for like it's like 50 cents an episode for HD downloads that were free of DRM.
Speaker 1: I might have bought it.
Speaker 1: I would have bought that yeah, but for DVDs.
Speaker 1: It's like I don't want these DVDs taking up room in my house.
Speaker 1: Also, I heard from reliable source that there were extras on the original DVDs and that thin case Does not have the because I wanted to fit it on for DVDs, but who cares about the extras?
Speaker 1: What do you need extras for?
Speaker 0: the extras are supposed to be awesome like a new town where they had all that useless bullshit.
Speaker 1: The only extras in any DVD I've ever wanted were the South Park and also Futurama.
Speaker 0: I did enjoy some of the commentary and the interviews on the ghost in the shell But there was all like original Japanese extras.
Speaker 0: a lot of these DVDs have like American extras that just suck Or they have just the art gallery only.
Speaker 1: the only things I ever want to see are really short And really insightful commentaries by the actual creators of the thing not by some American voice actors or adapters.
Speaker 0: Hey to be fair the full commentary track to these had.
Speaker 0: a movie is worth it just to hear him being like.
Speaker 1: I Really like that sort of thing, but I also want to see Deleted scenes and that sort of stuff because even though I know deleted scenes are deleted for a reason because they suck It's still.
Speaker 1: they're still interesting Yeah, and the other oh, there's actually one other kind of extra that is good, and that is the omak a kind of thing for Example Minnie Pato or lotus island lotus island or What's on the the Hypno toad.
Speaker 0: oh Was that really extra?
Speaker 0: that was a full episode of course, that's.
Speaker 1: that's why that's what.
Speaker 1: that's what an omak a is.
Speaker 1: It's actually extra Actual real content that's on there not some addendum sort of half content like a commentary.
Speaker 1: It's an actual.
Speaker 1: hey look you buy this DVD you get an actual extra episode sort of like.
Speaker 1: you know They do that in comic sometimes like buy this comic and guess what there's actually another comic in it an Actual real comic not just like a page of something or an ad an actual extra comic free.
Speaker 1: So when you buy you know that's a real extra whatever All right.
Speaker 1: So yeah So that the reason that gun could sue it was so cheap is because apparently there's this funimation save Program sa ve and they're selling save anime or save money.
Speaker 0: I think it's save money because it's not save anime.
Speaker 0: cuz the thing I've seen in the anime community lately is oh my god Bye DVDs.
Speaker 0: We're all going out of business.
Speaker 1: Well, it definitely saves the customer money because they have all these anime series for like 15 bucks.
Speaker 0: I'm not paying 15 bucks.
Speaker 0: I don't need the anime.
Speaker 0: This is where they fail.
Speaker 1: Well the thing is I went down the list and I looked at every single one of the shows.
Speaker 1: I was like nope nope nope nope nope except for one and I bought it.
Speaker 0: What show was that?
Speaker 1: galaxy railway?
Speaker 0: But you know what I. you know what I found out.
Speaker 1: you find out there's actually galaxy railways too, and they don't have that.
Speaker 1: It's unlicensed.
Speaker 1: So this is galaxy railways one only which is which is a full series.
Speaker 0: I considered though buying Eden of the East.
Speaker 0: there's like 30 bucks.
Speaker 0: But I kind of just want to watch it, and I don't want I read it.
Speaker 1: I was really I watched it all already.
Speaker 0: is it worth buying?
Speaker 0: is it worth watching again ever?
Speaker 1: I would watch it again.
Speaker 1: Maybe in a few years.
Speaker 1: Maybe but I wouldn't buy it yeah.
Speaker 1: So I also bought that book Rules of play that Luke crane is always talking about.
Speaker 0: oh wait wait wait.
Speaker 0: so not anime stuff.
Speaker 0: We're talking about not anime stuff for buying.
Speaker 0: I wanted like a board gaming orgasm spree.
Speaker 1: What'd you buy?
Speaker 1: an Amazon?
Speaker 0: well cuz we were just at PAX.
Speaker 0: I bought modern art.
Speaker 0: It was like 20 bucks, and that was a fun game to whip out mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I bought Zula right oh cuz it was 20 bucks.
Speaker 0: It was a fun game.
Speaker 0: I bought Bonanza cuz that's a fucking awesome game And it was like 20 bucks mm-hmm, and I got the second Locke Lamora book cuz it was super cheap.
Speaker 1: Already had that book.
Speaker 0: yeah, I didn't have it.
Speaker 0: I got lost.
Speaker 0: cities cuz that game is pretty good.
Speaker 0: I hear yeah It was like 15, but it's a two people game, which is rare.
Speaker 0: I also finally got some headphones.
Speaker 1: Oh, which can?
Speaker 0: some Panasonic like retro looking pink ones pink ones It's.
Speaker 1: the pink ones were like $30 cheaper than the identical black ones Uh-huh, but to get some pics for the people who will love that.
Speaker 0: I think they're pretty cool.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna be a headphone Musume I also bought.
Speaker 1: I have a new strategy for the book club.
Speaker 1: I bought the next book club book But you're not gonna say I won't say it on the show until it's time.
Speaker 0: It's not time yet.
Speaker 1: No, I have a new strategy.
Speaker 1: I don't even.
Speaker 1: the thing is I don't even know if it'll be a good book.
Speaker 1: I actually might be a bad book, but I think it will get people to read.
Speaker 0: so huh That's tantalizing because get people to read only means one of two things at least from your perspective.
Speaker 0: one It's a children's book or two.
Speaker 0: it is controversial.
Speaker 1: Neither one really yeah, huh?
Speaker 1: Third I did buy something.
Speaker 0: I think you really are gonna want.
Speaker 0: but I got the ultra rare cocoa bean.
Speaker 1: So I guess we should do news, but there is no news or at least there's no news that I care about.
Speaker 0: I mean right stuff said that they're not gonna carry urban visions catalog anymore, but I can't think of what is urban vision have I don't.
Speaker 0: they can't think of anything they have since like gogo 13 or ninja scroll.
Speaker 0: I got like nothing.
Speaker 1: so I want to do a geek bite.
Speaker 1: Geek bite Bye ultra rare geek bite the.
Speaker 1: so I got Scott's box right before packs and I talked about this on there, but it was so awesome And I read the whole thing that now I have to talk about it.
Speaker 1: on geek nights I got this trade paperback called strange tales.
Speaker 1: It's a Marvel comic and There was a strange tale series back in the day right, but this is a new strange tale series right and Basically in this trade paperback you get the whole it's.
Speaker 1: there was three issues Originally, and you get all three issues in this one trade.
Speaker 1: It's totally awesome.
Speaker 1: Now what is strange tale?
Speaker 1: so basically what they did is Marvel believe it or not went out, and they got some of the best Non Marvel indie comic creators that are out there and they had each of them do really tiny Marvel comics like a few pages like a page or two maybe you know something like that and They put them all together in this one book.
Speaker 1: and let me tell you this book is so awesome like unbelievably awesome.
Speaker 1: Let me just give you some of the names of people that made stuff in this book.
Speaker 1: Are you ready?
Speaker 1: I'm ready alright.
Speaker 1: So Paul Pope the amazing, right?
Speaker 1: Peter bag - oh James kachaka the guy who did the hockey and the elf and all that stuff, right?
Speaker 1: You got Nick Gurwitch.
Speaker 1: You know that is Probably bowel fellowship Nick Gurwitch.
Speaker 0: He's an important man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what if that's updated?
Speaker 0: yeah?
Speaker 1: Yeah, Matt Kent super spy Matt Kent.
Speaker 0: I really like super spy.
Speaker 1: No Jason from Europe Doing doing spider-man and dr.
Speaker 1: Octopus by Jason.
Speaker 0: oh man wait Jason doing spider-man.
Speaker 0: I picture us a forlorn looking spider-man standing there.
Speaker 0: It's all cool It's.
Speaker 1: it's totally.
Speaker 1: this book is like so epic.
Speaker 1: you got fucking like Galactus like eating the planet getting a big fat gut for meeting too many planet donuts planets.
Speaker 1: You got a really crazy.
Speaker 1: You know freaked out Hulk you got all it's.
Speaker 1: it's totally off the hook.
Speaker 0: I'm all about this.
Speaker 0: his book is totally sweet enough to borrow it and perhaps read it.
Speaker 1: Everybody should go out to Amazon and buy Strange tales the trade paperback from Marvel Comics, you know what they're now they're doing strange tales max Which is gonna be all more hardcore, and you know dark and for serious than regular strange tales.
Speaker 1: So it's gonna be totally sweet.
Speaker 0: so things of the day.
Speaker 0: What do you got for me?
Speaker 1: So we were at packs packs West 2010. right and many things happen there But we can't talk about them because then what we talk about when we do the pack show and this show will become full of packs talk and we come the pack show.
Speaker 1: So but that does not mean I cannot steal a thing of the day from packs.
Speaker 1: And you know I'm probably gonna steal a bunch of things of the day from packs because I need some things of the day.
Speaker 1: So here is a thing that happened at packs.
Speaker 1: that was I guess indirectly our fault that it happened But I was not present at the time, but luckily it is on the youtubes.
Speaker 1: in This video you see the man John st.
Speaker 1: John balls of steel in the magfest sponsored JAM space and He is singing the song that is known as free bird In its entirety.
Speaker 0: so you got to admit it was pretty great at the omega-thon finale.
Speaker 0: when they're like Can you guess the game?
Speaker 0: and that one guy yelled above everybody else free bird.
Speaker 1: that was a great guy?
Speaker 1: But yeah, here's this video for your entertainment.
Speaker 0: Alright, so I for once do not have a video.
Speaker 0: I was gonna do that synchronized walking on College Humor from Japan because typical Wednesday thing of the day fodder.
Speaker 0: But instead I have an article that I don't have any commentary about so I figure I'll link to it.
Speaker 0: This is my thing of the day, but then I don't have to talk about it.
Speaker 0: It's by W to Arudo who seems to write somewhat inflammatory articles for the Japanese or the Japan Times.
Speaker 1: So it says a Japanese troll not troll.
Speaker 0: They're inflammatory, but they're very observational and correct like this is most recent one before.
Speaker 0: this talks about how in Japan There's super racism against non-japanese people in hostels.
Speaker 0: And if you're not Japanese, they pretty much won't let you stay in hostels.
Speaker 1: That's true?
Speaker 0: Yes, so this sounds true?
Speaker 0: I don't know talks about the jet program and The fact that the Japanese people by and large speak English worse than any other people in the world.
Speaker 1: You know, they do.
Speaker 0: they pronounce things pretty poorly But they you know they have perfect grammar and he talks about that in extensive detail.
Speaker 0: as to why he thinks that is and the He gets really into this stuff about the culture of the classroom and what programs like jet really do and what happens when you get Fluent English speaker in a classroom after the kind of tutelage that they get in Japan about English.
Speaker 0: up to that point He basically says they teach English the way they teach Latin in America Mmm, and he makes really interesting points and it's a really good read.
Speaker 0: But I didn't really feel like commenting on it on the show other than getting you to read it All righty, and if you want to read about Japan and stuff that is kind of fucked up.
Speaker 0: W tell Ardo is the way to go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just you know, I worry because it sounds like almost this is like a Fox News person of Japan almost, you know.
Speaker 0: So I wonder and without further ado, I guess it's time for the meta Moment, let's keep the meta moment kind of short.
Speaker 0: here almost everything we care about is done.
Speaker 0: We got the New York Anime Festival New York comic-con coming up.
Speaker 0: We're doing like two panels at it.
Speaker 0: We'll be there same.
Speaker 0: October 8th, 9th and 10th is 10 10 10 the burning con which is actually the 8th 9th and 10th and The.
Speaker 1: I think.
Speaker 1: let me check my calendar here.
Speaker 0: I thought you wanted to keep it quick and then you're like delay.
Speaker 1: October 8th is also a board game night as is this nerd NYC board game night.
Speaker 1: this Friday September 10th is also a nerd NYC board game 9 10 and 10 10.
Speaker 1: Yep, and This Saturday September 11th is recess Downtown a full day of nerd NYC gaming.
Speaker 0: Yep, you want to play some role-playing games with the likes of us or some board games or hang out.
Speaker 1: We'll be there.
Speaker 1: There are only three other things you have to know.
Speaker 1: Monday September 13th on a Monday.
Speaker 1: No, okay.
Speaker 1: Goddamn it says Sunday, September 19th is International talk like a matey day.
Speaker 0: You mean like a pirate?
Speaker 1: I maybe.
Speaker 0: And Do we did many years ago?
Speaker 0: We did the entire first half of the show talking like pirates.
Speaker 1: now September 25th and 26th is the New York City World Maker Faire Surprisingly shame general location as the new World Fair without the word maker in the middle.
Speaker 1: I Forgot all about that.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I think that cover club book is golden apples of the Sun Ray Bradbury.
Speaker 0: We're gonna review it really soon.
Speaker 0: So read it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's short.
Speaker 0: It's like twenty two to four page short stories.
Speaker 0: It's not that hard.
Speaker 1: Is there any other meta stuff we have to cover?
Speaker 1: if there is we'll cover it later.
Speaker 1: That's the end of that moment.
Speaker 0: That was not prepared at all and kind of crappy what?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and this day.
Speaker 0: Let me look up the date.
Speaker 0: We're doing something cuz I was looking at the wrong thing No one cares about unless they live in New York.
Speaker 1: We got it.
Speaker 1: We need to get like the non New York convention schedule, you know.
Speaker 1: So we can tell like the next, you know relatively major anime gaming comic conventions that are.
Speaker 0: Anybody cares about that stuff?
Speaker 0: probably already knows.
Speaker 1: you'd be surprised how many people like that.
Speaker 1: You know they they'll post even in our forums which means they're paying attention to the world.
Speaker 1: a Convention happens near them and they don't find out until after true or even like I remember it nerd NYC.
Speaker 0: You know super hardcore gamers and a bunch of them.
Speaker 0: They never heard of packs Penny arcade and yet they're like super video game super board game.
Speaker 0: Yep It happens and it's not like they don't like penny arcades like they'd never even heard of it.
Speaker 1: Yep, so we should get like a list of you know cons that are relatively big.
Speaker 1: I don't want to talk about like the Holiday Inn guy shows up selling some comics in a box.
Speaker 0: Oh, you mean like that comic con in Wildwood that we go to but it's not a con.
Speaker 1: It's just a.
Speaker 0: it's a con.
Speaker 1: It's not a con.
Speaker 1: It's a sales.
Speaker 0: It's a convention.
Speaker 1: It's not.
Speaker 0: it is a convention.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: Yes, it is Definition of convention needs to have events to be a convention.
Speaker 0: No, it doesn't.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: Just a dealer's room counts.
Speaker 1: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: So then the malls a convention.
Speaker 1: No, okay, that's permanent So any temporary.
Speaker 1: so flee it's a flea market is yeah, basically flea market convention.
Speaker 0: Basically the same thing.
Speaker 1: No, a flea market is not a convention.
Speaker 0: I would argue that they are in fact the same thing.
Speaker 1: a flea market would have to have a scheduled events to be a convention.
Speaker 0: However, I would argue that many conventions do have fleas.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 0: so when you know, we're talking about a Hypno toad as an extra and We actually watch and when I say we I mean me and Scott the entire front row crew.
Speaker 0: for any new listeners who missed this Old episode we watched the entire episode of Hypno toad that was on that one future.
Speaker 0: I'm.
Speaker 1: a thing is I don't remember if anything happened stuff at the end or not.
Speaker 0: quite a bit happened.
Speaker 1: In fact, I don't remember.
Speaker 0: we watch as a group the entire thing.
Speaker 0: No one got bored known when did anything.
Speaker 1: In fact, we were bored.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone looked away from the screen.
Speaker 1: I looked away.
Speaker 0: serotonin problem from the Hobbit joke.
Speaker 0: But future Amma animation one of the more important beloved well-known well-loved beloved Cartoons to ever be shown on American television very popular worldwide even and it's Wednesday and we've never talked about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean we're like every I've been.
Speaker 1: I watched a whole bunch of animes But rim really hasn't and I read a whole bunch of comics.
Speaker 1: but rim I'm watching fist of the North Star and I'm watching already finish that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I already finished that more almost finished with that one.
Speaker 1: So I'm just way out of you.
Speaker 1: So yeah, that's a problem.
Speaker 0: I've been reading books.
Speaker 1: I also been reading books.
Speaker 1: You have also not been shit-talking.
Speaker 1: Do you just way behind on everything?
Speaker 0: I've been actually working on shit.
Speaker 0: Talk to you quite a bit.
Speaker 1: All right Well, we'll see when I will see when I see some shit.
Speaker 0: cuz Pax was our last big thing.
Speaker 1: The next important thing we have to do is Pax When I see some when I see some poop, I'll believe that you're not shit talking.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So yeah, so I said hey Let's see Futurama's animation and we've never done a show about that.
Speaker 1: And you know what people probably really like a show on that.
Speaker 1: So let's do a show on that.
Speaker 0: Wait, this opens the door.
Speaker 0: We could do a show on the Simpsons.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we could do a show on South Park.
Speaker 0: Why Futurama?
Speaker 0: Why is Futurama different from the Simpsons?
Speaker 0: They're both still going They're both wildly popular.
Speaker 0: They're both good.
Speaker 1: Well, I think the thing with Futurama is that it has so much more nerd cred and it's much more appropriate for geek nights.
Speaker 1: Cuz you know, first of all, it is all sci-fi II right and has a future spacey theme large numbers of surprisingly subtle physics Jokes, yeah, and you know, the Simpsons has jokes all over the place too like that, you know.
Speaker 1: And it has plenty of geek cred as well.
Speaker 1: You know, you're not gonna go in a comic store without seeing some Simpsons stuff.
Speaker 1: You got Simpsons comics You got comic book guy.
Speaker 1: There's plenty of nerd jokes, you know, Alan Moore was on the Simpsons and in a guest appearance, right?
Speaker 1: There's plenty of nerd cred going on there.
Speaker 1: But I think you know, the Futurama is just a little bit more nerdy And I think it's really nerds that are propping it up.
Speaker 1: right because it came.
Speaker 1: it didn't really get the TV ratings.
Speaker 1: It went away, but then the nerds sort of kept it alive.
Speaker 0: It's one of the only times the nerds who wanted something to come back actually got what they wanted.
Speaker 0: I mean, how much did people lose their shit about Firefly?
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: We got a fight to bring Firefly back.
Speaker 0: It's gonna cut.
Speaker 0: it's never coming back.
Speaker 1: I Have a. There are a few loud fans.
Speaker 1: The number of fans isn't actually that large just seems larger than it is because there's a few loud ones and not only are they Loud but they're extra dedicated.
Speaker 1: It's even an event.
Speaker 1: They all show up and pack the house.
Speaker 1: We have a service and you have a Simpsons event.
Speaker 1: There's got to be a hundred times more Simpsons fans than Firefly fans, but if you have an event those people who are Simpsons fans They just watch it every Sunday.
Speaker 1: They don't.
Speaker 1: it's not their lives.
Speaker 1: You know, they don't live and breathe Simpsons.
Speaker 1: There's only so many people who do that.
Speaker 1: So they're not gonna show up in droves and scream on the internet if there's a Simpsons event or a Simpsons thing or whatever.
Speaker 1: You know, there's only some people who will do that.
Speaker 0: So really I think wide future Alma's relevant is that you know The Simpsons is still going but I watched a whole bunch of episodes of it in the last few weeks.
Speaker 0: It's really not that funny anymore at all.
Speaker 0: It's really kind of mainstream and kind of Mainstream and lame do not necessarily mean the same thing.
Speaker 0: But the Simpsons is really just kind of these like obvious Ham-fisted pop-culture jokes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that's the main thing is that when you do the pop-culture jokes, you know You're really sort of like.
Speaker 1: it's not enjoyable to anyone who doesn't isn't a person who was in pop.
Speaker 0: I'll get old Simpsons like Willie, you know the shinning.
Speaker 0: that was mostly kind of timeless jokes.
Speaker 0: You can watch the episode today.
Speaker 0: It's just as funny.
Speaker 1: Well, that's because it was.
Speaker 1: it was still a pop-culture reference to the shinning.
Speaker 0: It was a pop-culture reference to what was itself a timeless thing exactly what I was about to say, you know.
Speaker 1: So if you make if you look at like old Looney Tunes Episodes right the ones that hold up are the ones that just have generic jokes like, you know, rabbit season duck season, right?
Speaker 1: But the ones that are like where they're impersonating famous people of the time like, you know, Jack Benny.
Speaker 0: I would argue that those still work.
Speaker 1: for example they work But they don't work on people who don't know who those famous people were.
Speaker 0: But the Groucho Marx ones definitely work because I think a lot of people think that that kind of character is Bugs Bunny and don't Realize that there was a Groucho Marx.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that that worries me.
Speaker 0: or Rodney Dangerfield?
Speaker 0: I think people think that is a character, but don't know Rodney Dangerfield is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know the point is What's his name are?
Speaker 1: Yes Peter Laurie.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Peter Laurie or how about?
Speaker 0: I don't know who that is.
Speaker 0: You don't know that guy is.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: He's the the hotel manager in the hotel broken arms.
Speaker 0: Fame is famous actor and voice actor.
Speaker 0: All right I can't do it.
Speaker 0: Okay voice is still kind of shot from packs, but future Amma is Mostly with the exception of that iPhone episode.
Speaker 0: They just did pretty timeless.
Speaker 0: I think yeah.
Speaker 1: And the other thing is that the characters are just so much, you know, like the the variety in there.
Speaker 1: you got so much, you know, each one is more exaggerated and Has more shtick going on right?
Speaker 1: Whereas the simp - whereas the Simpsons.
Speaker 1: It's like, you know, they have just this huge cast right where each one does a little bit first notice how.
Speaker 0: that's a recent phenomenon.
Speaker 0: the Simpsons had.
Speaker 0: you know the core and they're all the urban.
Speaker 0: look at the early eras of the Simpsons you basically define them by.
Speaker 0: was it about Bart or was it about Homer?
Speaker 0: and then you defined it by.
Speaker 0: was it when Homer was stupid when he was evil when he was cunning?
Speaker 0: all these eras of the Simpsons and Every now and then they give like Moe would have an episode and then they kind of ran out of stuff to do.
Speaker 0: and I Feel like now like half the episodes are about Moe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't even know anymore it's always Moe.
Speaker 1: but in future in Futurama they have core characters.
Speaker 1: They've brought a few in.
Speaker 1: you know, like zap Brannigan became more important and I guess I love that brand the green.
Speaker 1: What's the green guy?
Speaker 1: The alien kiff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he became more important, right?
Speaker 1: But and you know, but other than that, you know, most of the characters who were side characters like, you know Nixon and scruffy and hedonism, but they maintain like the right level.
Speaker 1: They maintain their sideness.
Speaker 1: There isn't a hedonism bought episode But they're still strong.
Speaker 0: a hedonism bought episode would I think harken the end of future?
Speaker 1: I would be a shark jumpage even though he doesn't bust up.
Speaker 1: I love he doesn't buy but it would be a shark jump, but it's the same thing.
Speaker 0: every Oh most his lack was my favorite character in the Simpsons just because of two knives.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Oh, yeah, but then now like there's a Moe episode and I just don't care.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is in Futurama.
Speaker 1: every episode what focus is usually on one of the core characters is oidberg or Amy right or fry or something like that.
Speaker 1: and then the other characters all the main ones are all in there Constantly, you know.
Speaker 1: and the side characters they all.
Speaker 1: they remain side.
Speaker 1: They'll show up for like one second in the episode and be gone.
Speaker 0: I've I've noticed something to the kind of talking about like and they can keep.
Speaker 1: they can keep cranking the episodes and they still work Even though they're keeping the focus on the main crew.
Speaker 0: think about nerd culture.
Speaker 0: when you were in high school You know back when the Simpsons was still, you know The old kind of Simpsons and even early college People would collect Simpsons.
Speaker 0: quoting was kind of like the nerd thing to do Like.
Speaker 0: you'd always make the Simpsons reference in concert conversation.
Speaker 0: It would just come up.
Speaker 0: You mostly hear the Futurama references around nerds.
Speaker 0: You don't hear that many Simpsons references and if you do it's always old Simpsons.
Speaker 0: Mmm, that's true.
Speaker 0: I feel like Futurama is the mantle of like.
Speaker 0: that is the nerd cartoon And I guess the only other cartoon as he referenced a lot are like Venture Brothers or Archer South Park.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: plus name the good popular Cartoons that are on TV or were recently on TV in America that weren't animes.
Speaker 0: there were an anime.
Speaker 0: There's an animation cartoons Futurama South Park.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I would argue Archer you didn't watch Archer.
Speaker 0: but Archer is fucking hilarious Whatever.
Speaker 0: and I think a lot of people are quoting Archer and you just don't notice because you don't you didn't watch it.
Speaker 1: It is very likely that many people quote things and I have no idea that they're quoting something because I did not watch the thing That they're quoting much like someone watching a non timeless Simpsons episode with pop culture references.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Simpsons kind of went the Shrek route.
Speaker 0: I mean Shrek was.
Speaker 0: it's all just pop culture.
Speaker 0: That won't make any sense ten years from now.
Speaker 0: Yep Of course, I worry that there's going to be a day when no one knows what the Shannon was.
Speaker 1: There are people already who don't know what the shitting is.
Speaker 0: I know I mean the fact that we'll go to an anime con and we're like how many people haven't seen cowboy bebop like half the crowd Raised their hands and then we're like how many people haven't seen Star Wars.
Speaker 0: about half the crowd raised their hands.
Speaker 1: There were people who raised their hand.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and they were.
Speaker 0: there are many gasps But there'll be a day when the gasps is.
Speaker 0: you've seen Star Wars Which I mean look at this.
Speaker 0: every Pax we have been to has the focal point of the keynote not been Star Wars changed everything.
Speaker 1: every single Pax keynote speaker always Mentions and makes a big deal out of how Star Wars changed everything in their lives.
Speaker 0: anime to every anime director We ever see in person is like yeah Star Wars fucking changed everything for me.
Speaker 1: But meanwhile, right?
Speaker 1: It's so disappointing at George Lucas is a piece of shit right now.
Speaker 0: No, he's not.
Speaker 0: you know, what happened there Means a sad story.
Speaker 0: He was a great director and then his neck killed him and continued making movies.
Speaker 1: The thing is he didn't even direct Empire Strikes Back Jedi.
Speaker 1: He gets all this credit mean, you know.
Speaker 0: Well, it's kind of like M Night Shyamalan who unfortunately died before he can make the Avatar movie.
Speaker 0: I was looking forward to.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying, you know, it's like The like who you know every other awesome Thing that is huge.
Speaker 0: Well, look at the difference.
Speaker 1: The person is also awesome.
Speaker 0: Here's a big contrast.
Speaker 0: So we've got Lucas, right?
Speaker 0: There was a happy accident that all the people around him were amazingly competent and this awesome work came out and he's kind of a mediocre You know director.
Speaker 0: all things considered meanwhile, I look at Soshi Khan who wrote and directed like everything.
Speaker 1: Yep Yeah Anyway, why couldn't they take Lucas's thing?
Speaker 0: Anymore so Futurama is just kind of poor nerds.
Speaker 0: This is our show.
Speaker 0: This is what we've got.
Speaker 0: and also look at Family Guy.
Speaker 0: Family Guy was super popular Died and the nerds got what they wanted.
Speaker 0: it came back.
Speaker 0: Remember that first episode when it came back when they brought back Ollie Williams with the Blackie weather forecast And we knew that they knew what made the show funny.
Speaker 0: and then they never did that again.
Speaker 0: And the show is just self-referential crap and pop culture.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: It's very rare that a show comes back and maintains goodness.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is very rare.
Speaker 1: I mean the thing is I will not lie.
Speaker 1: Personally think that the Futurama comeback was a you know It was a decline in quality But it was not so much of a decline as to no longer be good.
Speaker 1: it like went from like 10 To like eight and a half, you know.
Speaker 0: I would argue that most of the decline was in the interim movies because they were good but because they were long.
Speaker 0: That was yeah, that was so tried to plot way too much.
Speaker 0: and Futurama is not about plot.
Speaker 0: It is about Azusa.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that was sort of the slope downwards, right?
Speaker 1: It's like the movies were all okay But like the Beast of the Billion Backs that was way too long.
Speaker 1: I really like the the one with the the fantasy one the best although vendors game was okay But it had.
Speaker 0: it had some really kind of crap moments near the end.
Speaker 0: It was kind of dumb, but it did individual jokes in that one made me laugh so hard that I almost peed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's why I like it the best cuz it's all about the actual jokes, you know I mean that was the episode.
Speaker 0: that was the one we watched.
Speaker 0: Maybe might have just been because it was late But it was the whole front row crew like laying all on top of each other's big pile on that old-ass TV late at night after like a burning wheel game And he made that Hobbit joke and we laughed for like 20 minutes and couldn't stop and I couldn't breathe.
Speaker 0: Yep That was the same night.
Speaker 0: We watched Hypno Toad.
Speaker 1: Yep But yeah, it's like, you know the movies.
Speaker 1: they were alright and some of them were better than others But it's sort of like now.
Speaker 1: they started this.
Speaker 1: these.
Speaker 1: I guess it's technically the 60s season because they're calling the movies the fifth season right and All the episodes in the current season.
Speaker 1: I've watched most of them.
Speaker 1: there might be one or two new ones I haven't watched but I've watched all the ones up, you know quite a few and the quality is pretty steady.
Speaker 1: All the episodes are equal.
Speaker 1: They're all funny, but none of them are oh my god funny.
Speaker 1: They're not like memorable for all time funny.
Speaker 1: They're just really good and worth watching.
Speaker 1: kind of funny, you know.
Speaker 1: Whereas I feel that the episodes from before right some of the older ones are all time funny, you know.
Speaker 1: But that's how it goes.
Speaker 1: it's better to have you know Some good stuff than to have no stuff.
Speaker 1: Of course and especially in the absence of South Park where it also kind of treads this line between.
Speaker 0: it is mostly comedy But there is kind of a plot and you do care about the characters like.
Speaker 0: there is good writing a good story and you really like you are sympathetic and this is a show that makes a lot of people cry and it's very emotional sometimes.
Speaker 0: the Dog episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean that is one thing that Futurama has family Right that South Park Simpsons Family Guy none of the other shows have and I think this is why nerds dig a little bit more.
Speaker 1: Is that it actually has this mild continuity?
Speaker 1: It's like any episode is episodic You can just watch it but sort of like cowboy bebop, right?
Speaker 1: Some episodes are continuity episodes, you know and They they go with each other and the characters actually sort of kind of change a little bit over time.
Speaker 1: Personalities don't change their sticks don't change, you know bender still steals and is a jerk and you know You know, I noticed a claptrap in Borderlands is bender who's not a jerk.
Speaker 0: I've decided that's right Cuz that's all he is he's bender.
Speaker 0: bender was just not a complete asshole.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah, I gotta finish that game But the yeah.
Speaker 1: but you have these characters that continue over time with a mild continuity to it and there's actually some development and Because of that they can actually Make a thing where you care about the characters based on their history Whereas like the Simpsons can't really do that.
Speaker 1: They might be able to make an episode where the story of that single episode is Sad or you know has some sort of you know emotional message as opposed to just pure comedy.
Speaker 1: But the characters can't change but they can't do it based on the main characters or anything like that.
Speaker 1: It has to be like oh my god You know Lisa Simpson met a really sad person and we learn about the sad person I get this in a recent episode.
Speaker 0: They gave Bart a girlfriend.
Speaker 0: Oh, man, and that didn't continue.
Speaker 0: in the next episode The character just gone as far as I can tell.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right, but it ended with like they're totally dating.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah And how'd you know that?
Speaker 0: cuz I watched it whoa And I was reminded of her.
Speaker 0: remember we had the private West Coast front row crew after party at PAX.
Speaker 0: Yep, that episode was on the screen in the background where we were hanging out.
Speaker 1: No, I barely looked at it.
Speaker 1: I just I just sort of glanced and I was like, oh Simpsons and I didn't really watch the episode.
Speaker 1: I didn't watch it either Subtitle so it wouldn't have mattered.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's that episode plus.
Speaker 0: we were too busy hanging out with.
Speaker 0: uh, Aaron Clark packs, Aaron Clark Not Otakon.
Speaker 1: Aaron Clark good Aaron Clark not as evil twin from the east.
Speaker 1: You got to make that clear, but I don't know if he's a twin not even close.
Speaker 1: The Divergence of the level of awesomeness is so great It's like hard to imagine that both the people have the same name.
Speaker 0: Wow, that was the side.
Speaker 1: They have nothing else in common.
Speaker 0: You realize that was simultaneously a shout-out and what I can only call a reverse shout-out.
Speaker 0: Oh shit Luckily, I don't think the bad Aaron Clark actually listens to our show.
Speaker 1: If he did it would make him less crappy.
Speaker 0: there everyone whose name is Aaron Clark email us.
Speaker 0: Let us know you listen.
Speaker 1: Let's get the phone book.
Speaker 1: There's plenty of Aaron Clark's in the phone.
Speaker 1: There's no shortage.
Speaker 1: I At least ten in any phone book Any US phone book.
Speaker 0: I just can't help but think back to.
Speaker 0: we were having some argument at the shore about like information being free and your argument was basically the phone book never killed anyone and I think my Rebuttal and proof that you were wrong was Sarah Connor.
Speaker 0: Anyway Sarah Connor lived the other like seven.
Speaker 0: Sarah Connors didn't.
Speaker 1: that's their problem.
Speaker 0: so Futurama It's awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's hard to review things that we like.
Speaker 1: What's what's some of your favorite?
Speaker 0: Episode that's such a crap.
Speaker 0: cop-out.
Speaker 1: What about that makes them your favorite episodes again?
Speaker 0: So my favorite episode straight up is the gargoyle one because it has the old jokes.
Speaker 0: I'm stealing my favorite episode as the old jokes and the gargoyle and then just and now a little one is that is how pop?
Speaker 0: Freedom.
Speaker 1: that is how papa gets freedom.
Speaker 0: now born we born we tell you are born to me.
Speaker 0: That was hmm.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: There's something about that episode.
Speaker 1: Well, it's because it's like they all fall in like the time goop and they're like There are so many like concise quotable memes in it.
Speaker 1: My what my Get a job got a job.
Speaker 1: I forgot Was in the same episode.
Speaker 0: I don't think so.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: that was also an excellent episode.
Speaker 1: Time traveling boxes and they get a job.
Speaker 1: That's a good one.
Speaker 0: That wasn't time traveling boxes.
Speaker 0: That was universes in boxes.
Speaker 1: All right universe is in the boxes.
Speaker 0: kind of inception.
Speaker 1: They're all.
Speaker 1: they all feel the same way.
Speaker 1: like a time travel episode a universe switching episode a space travel planet switching episode.
Speaker 1: They don't feel they don't feel like the same thing.
Speaker 0: They didn't actually travel through time.
Speaker 0: They just started going.
Speaker 0: they started merlin.
Speaker 1: yeah, the time travel episode was the Fry.
Speaker 1: does the grant?
Speaker 1: does the grandma episode?
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yeah But that would the time travel time shifting of bodies and world boxes for three different episodes you realize yeah It's also I think that sometimes there are self-referential jokes in Futurama Like though like they'll insult fry for getting with his grandma or something like that.
Speaker 1: But all right, so I remember they trying to them doing that.
Speaker 1: But it's not.
Speaker 1: it's not like.
Speaker 1: it's different to reference your own continuity to make a joke that it is to Sort of just retell the same joke over and over again like just Ali Williams is there.
Speaker 0: I think it's only a matter of artistry because you can do both.
Speaker 0: venture brothers and Archer did the self-referential thing I think the right way.
Speaker 0: Futurama does it in like a plotty way.
Speaker 0: That's also good.
Speaker 0: and say family guy at first They made the self-referential.
Speaker 0: that was kind of the meta like.
Speaker 0: haha We know that you like to this character and his one joke.
Speaker 0: But then they just kind of keep using like these meta jokes like that chick.
Speaker 0: it was fucking come out of nowhere and attack Peters.
Speaker 0: Like all right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like think about this Ollie Williams from Family Guy, right?
Speaker 1: Why is he funny?
Speaker 1: He's funny because it came out of no, it's funny because it came out of nowhere and because he says it in a funny way It's gonna rain.
Speaker 1: It's gonna rain, right?
Speaker 1: It's a Physicality of it.
Speaker 1: the sound of it is funny.
Speaker 1: It's just a funny sound It's no.
Speaker 1: it's funny for the same reason that getting hit with a pie in the face is funny because it looks funny, right?
Speaker 1: It's.
Speaker 1: it's just hilarious to look at and out of the ordinary.
Speaker 0: So if you're just gonna reference it straight you do it again.
Speaker 1: It's not it's only funny It's not actually funny to just for him.
Speaker 1: Just just keep saying it's gonna rain.
Speaker 0: Look doing the same the exact same joke or the same style of joke one more time Later is also funny cuz that you know, a lot of comedians do that, but it's funny because hey Hey, I'm reminded of the funny joke from a second ago.
Speaker 1: That's not an old joke.
Speaker 0: yet You can't do it the third time unless you do the comedian thing.
Speaker 0: where you do it once do it twice Don't do it for a long time and then bring it all back to that at the end.
Speaker 1: But you can't do that across multiple episodes Oh and again within a single episode.
Speaker 1: right if you do it across multiple episodes That doesn't work.
Speaker 0: but like look at Archer and Venture Brothers.
Speaker 0: This is where you can do the sort of self-referential Comedy in the right way because then it's more of a character development thing.
Speaker 0: Like you're getting to know the character That's what future.
Speaker 1: I'm ahead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the other ones like an archer they have this thing.
Speaker 0: We're like in one of the early episodes like someone's like that's how you get ants and the other characters like hey yep, and they said like a yep kind of a like front row crew.
Speaker 0: we have stuff like that.
Speaker 0: we say things in certain ways and That yep.
Speaker 0: Nope kind of Characters do that to each other the way friends do throughout the entire show and then it becomes kind of this meta joke later.
Speaker 0: Mmm, that's the right way to do it.
Speaker 0: Not just having the chicken suit come out.
Speaker 0: Yell It's going to rain while a deaf guy runs by all greased up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, family guy's not funny anymore.
Speaker 1: Here's it is another example, right?
Speaker 1: So Bender has his bite my shiny metal ass, right?
Speaker 0: Remember when he didn't have his shiny metal ass?
Speaker 1: that is that is very similar.
Speaker 0: bite my majestic golden ass to benders.
Speaker 1: To Bart's.
Speaker 1: eat my shorts, right?
Speaker 1: But bender I mean Bart.
Speaker 1: he stopped at the heat my shorts and the I Caramba and such and don't have a cow man.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: he only really said those things once and they were only Memorable slogans because people put them on t-shirts and shit, right?
Speaker 0: Think of this back then.
Speaker 0: this is just kind of unrelated food for thought.
Speaker 0: back then in the eat my shorts.
Speaker 0: I Caramba era of the Simpsons.
Speaker 0: I Cedar Point had to turn my I Caramba shirt inside out.
Speaker 0: They wouldn't let me into the park because it was bad.
Speaker 1: and what's bad about I Caramba?
Speaker 0: back then Parents would not let kids watch the fucking Simpsons.
Speaker 0: the Simpsons was the controversial show.
Speaker 1: But by my shining metal ass is better than I could look how far societies come.
Speaker 1: we've come a long way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we have but anyway the yeah, so That those jokes, you know, they really only told them once in the Simpsons.
Speaker 1: They couldn't really do.
Speaker 1: use them again You know to great effect.
Speaker 1: They were basically just.
Speaker 1: they just fell flat recently.
Speaker 0: They did a few eat my shorts jokes, but the thing is a bender.
Speaker 0: They were a hundred percent meta, but you can do bite my shine in my last.
Speaker 1: but he doesn't just say it, right?
Speaker 1: They remix it each time they have learned from the internet.
Speaker 1: So instead of it.
Speaker 1: He will buy my Golden, and he only said like bite my shiny metal ass like a few times, you know.
Speaker 1: And every other time he said it It was always a remix like he was wooden once and he would be like bite my splinter.
Speaker 1: He wouldn't ass.
Speaker 1: or one time like his ass fell off or something and he was like, oh no bite No, he sold it to the devil.
Speaker 0: No, right.
Speaker 1: He sold sold his ass to the devil.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know, so they mix it up if they want to reuse it, you know.
Speaker 1: I mean if Bart actually did stuff with his shorts, you know or found interest they could have kept that going But they were not as clever and because they didn't have the continuity Right.
Speaker 1: Hey, that was really a flop if they would have tried to do that at all And there was no way they could have kept it going for that many years.
Speaker 1: cuz you know Simpsons did it Except Simpsons did.
Speaker 0: it is almost a South Park at this point.
Speaker 1: It is indeed a South Park.
Speaker 1: It is indeed All right, is there anything else to say here?
Speaker 0: Uh, the only thing I really want to say is that Futurama started in In 1999.
Speaker 1: I know how fucked up is that right?
Speaker 0: She's like 12 years ago.
Speaker 1: It went for four years.
Speaker 1: so in oh three it ended years ago ended in oh three and the movies came out when uh, 2003?
Speaker 1: well, no, that's when the TV show ended.
Speaker 1: So when did the first movie come out?
Speaker 1: 2008. so there are five years of no Futurama.
Speaker 1: That's a fucking long time.
Speaker 0: So, uh, Team Fortress 2 was what like nine years ten years in the making.
Speaker 0: and then holy shit It came out.
Speaker 0: Duke Nukem forever even fucking came out.
Speaker 1: It did it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not in the stores yet.
Speaker 0: I played it.
Speaker 0: you played it.
Speaker 1: you played a demo.
Speaker 1: there were demos before.
Speaker 0: I fucking played Duke Nukem forever John St.
Speaker 0: John.
Speaker 0: the voice of Duke Nukem took me into the back room.
Speaker 1: I fucking played a fuck you with his balls of steel and then a booth babe gave me a tank top Tank top to cover up after.
Speaker 1: The thing is that just because you could have played it just a demo there was.
Speaker 1: that was not the full game.
Speaker 1: It is not in the store.
Speaker 1: We do not know.
Speaker 0: So I think the real notable thing about Futurama is that Nerds always demand shit and sometimes like in the situation of tribes - you've got to ignore those nerds and not fuck up your game Mmm, and sometimes the situation of Family Guy, you've got to understand what made your show great in the first place.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know We did a whole panel of packs where we talked about like Actraiser this video game and it had the overworld map thing That was cool and had this shitty side-scroller kind of tacked on and the game was super popular.
Speaker 0: So the people who made it were like, you know what?
Speaker 0: Let's make a sequel.
Speaker 0: Nobody cared about that cool overworld part.
Speaker 0: clearly What made this game awesome was that shitty side-scroller.
Speaker 0: make a sequel just shitty side-scroller.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel like Family Guy when it came back did that they they're like what made the show popular.
Speaker 0: stupid self-referential humor.
Speaker 0: Let's just go with that.
Speaker 1: They were lazy and it worked, you know, I mean, that's the one thing.
Speaker 1: look at South Park, right?
Speaker 1: They started off with poop jokes.
Speaker 1: It seems like all the shows start with food.
Speaker 0: scarily enough watching some South Park again.
Speaker 0: The poop joke era lasted like a few episodes in the first season.
Speaker 0: They got into social commentary like actual social commentary and jokes that weren't just.
Speaker 0: oh my god Those kids are swearing pretty fucking quick.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's it's like a difficulty curve in a video game You start with low difficulty you get with the low brow and then you raise the brow with a nice difficult You know challenge curve, you know, you got.
Speaker 1: the show gets progressively more difficult.
Speaker 0: I mean South Park today is I think some of the better popular social commentary television out there.
Speaker 1: Maybe the best.
Speaker 1: But you know the some of these other shows like Family Guy.
Speaker 1: they lowered the brow.
Speaker 1: They didn't raise the brow.
Speaker 0: Family Guy is not saying anything about society.
Speaker 1: Not really.
Speaker 1: No, you know, the Simpsons does sometimes and Futurama does every.
Speaker 0: it says such a milquetoast things nowadays.
Speaker 1: Futurama does sometimes Kinda, but that's about it.
Speaker 1: It's all good All right.
Speaker 0: I think Futurama social commentary is more taking Everything that it like every trend in our current world and just driving them out to the extreme Exaggeration of what if this course continues that long?
Speaker 0: Mmm, and in that way, it's weird I'll.
Speaker 0: Futurama is incredibly like over-the-top and inaccurate and yet in many ways very like Spiritually accurate to what our society is like if you take it to the extreme in every direction at once.
Speaker 1: I guess that really applies to its theme of future Futurama, right?
Speaker 1: You know you take something that we have currently and you extract it through the future And you you know, I mean you look at have all like the famous people of current time with their heads are in a jar And stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll look at like the like the popular style architecture or they'll be like, it'll be like no robo sex.
Speaker 1: You know, there's a social commentary in a Futurama.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's so.
Speaker 1: it takes like.
Speaker 1: it takes a current social issue and extracts it out to the future robo.
Speaker 0: Yep, but they rarely make focus of the episode.
Speaker 0: The real focus of the episode is the character driven joke humor.
Speaker 0: joke If I got a word is joke humor.
Speaker 1: That's what South Park, right?
Speaker 1: Will make the focus of the episode that social commentary and have the sort of plot on the side Whereas Futurama is the same thing only flips slightly.
Speaker 0: So right part of my feeling about South Park is colored by the fact that I've watched so many of those one episode commentaries.
Speaker 1: We watch the Futurama Extras and things but the commentaries weren't as good.
Speaker 0: They didn't talk as much about like the jokes and they were long and I want to watch them all the way through.
Speaker 0: It wasn't like South Park where they'll tell you the secret that yeah this whole episode I really really wanted to see Cartman in his little boat t-shirt.
Speaker 0: I feel like that really like that's funny to me.
Speaker 0: He's really funny or we didn't know what the fuck we were doing.
Speaker 0: So crab people.
Speaker 0: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.