Speaker 0: It's Thursday October 28th 2010 and this is geek nights Tonight with our special guest international juggler entertainer extraordinaire and geek nights forum.
Speaker 0: I'd Luke Burrage.
Speaker 0: We discussed the nature of spiritual experiences.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So before we begin to preface this slightly we recorded about two and a half almost three hours worth of conversation while Luke was actually in New York and We decided to cut that up into a number of episodes that we'll be bringing out every now and then as we have time.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know what else I can say.
Speaker 0: Enjoy and look forward to the next episode.
Speaker 0: I think the end of this one will give you a pretty good idea of where we're going as the topics progress.
Speaker 0: So how do we define spirituality?
Speaker 0: What does that word actually mean?
Speaker 1: I'm not.
Speaker 1: when I when I wanted to talk about this I wasn't talking about spirituality as such.
Speaker 1: I'm talking more about the Experiences that you can have in a spiritual environment that you interpret as a spiritual experience like but from an atheist point of view We all know that those experiences are actually.
Speaker 1: well, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: people atheists say that Spirituality is incorrect.
Speaker 1: It's wrong and therefore they skip over all of the other things about it call it Incorrect and then suddenly say it's invalid.
Speaker 2: Well what I mean?
Speaker 2: what makes an experience spiritual as opposed to non-spiritual, right?
Speaker 2: If I go on a roller coaster and it feels really good and it makes my body emit chemicals and makes me feel certain Emotions and feelings and then I do something else and I get similar feelings You know what?
Speaker 2: Why in one case would I apply the word spiritual and another case not apply that word?
Speaker 2: It's really a meaningless a meaningless label.
Speaker 1: This is purely to do with context.
Speaker 1: I would say it's purely to do with context because like let me just tell you a bit about my story I was brought up in a Christian family and we were going to church like all the time.
Speaker 1: I went to church like three times a week four times a week and another head church three times exactly.
Speaker 0: I had church every day in Catholic school.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: So it's that kind of thing.
Speaker 1: So if you interpret an experience that you have and people are saying oh when you feel this That's God touching you.
Speaker 1: when you think this this is God giving you an idea.
Speaker 1: when when you're like this it when it when there's Lots of music on and yeah, and you're singing and you feel a lot of you know, good stuff.
Speaker 1: You feel all these good vibes.
Speaker 1: That's God speaking to you.
Speaker 1: That's God touching you.
Speaker 1: you interpret that as yes that is spiritual even though it isn't even though you can get exactly the same experience from a rollercoaster.
Speaker 1: and You don't.
Speaker 1: you don't experience you don't interpret that.
Speaker 1: however If you woke up one morning and saw a fantastic like sunrise and it was the most beautiful thing you've ever seen if you're from a if you're like your life is from a Christian point of view or some kind of spiritual point of view if that's what you You know the lens that you're
Speaker 2: looking for.
Speaker 2: Is that where the sun rises and like sun sets and almost every Christian like book you see in the story?
Speaker 1: Exactly people then associate that as a gift from God as some kind of message from God or something like that.
Speaker 1: So what I'm saying is that for most people or most Christian organizations almost spiritual organizations They restrict your access to all of these other things which would otherwise cause you to have and peak Experiences or some kind of spiritual experience.
Speaker 0: I never thought of it that way.
Speaker 0: a lot of my experiences involve things that Christians Not Christians, but Catholics at least would not want me to have been doing.
Speaker 1: there's this whole thing.
Speaker 1: It's like so what are you gonna do this weekend?
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm gonna go out and I'm gonna get so drunk I can't stand up anymore.
Speaker 1: And then I'm gonna fall over bash my head.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna see stars.
Speaker 1: I mean that could be.
Speaker 1: I mean not for me.
Speaker 1: There's a reason why people do that.
Speaker 0: an example I think every man has gone through the moment you realize what masturbation is and that you're in fact capable of it.
Speaker 2: Well for him is the moment you realize the masturbation is maybe there.
Speaker 2: everyone else is the moment you you know get with You know, whatever your preference I would assume that you masturbate first at least once exactly.
Speaker 1: But I mean, that's the thing when you when you have that first awesome orgasm You're like that was amazing and then you spend your entire life trying to recreate that because it wouldn't be a first one anymore.
Speaker 1: But and it's the same thing.
Speaker 1: It's like with sex It's drugs is going to a rock concert and being standing at the front of having like a thousand.
Speaker 2: But the Christians have rock concerts with.
Speaker 1: However, they're Christian rock conference rock concert conferences concerts.
Speaker 1: So when you're there, it's sort of like we're gonna invite God into our lives and this is the thing.
Speaker 1: I led worship I played guitar at the front of in the front of churches and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: you know leading worship playing music and I would leave to people in to these and Spiritual experiences, you know.
Speaker 1: so that we would talk about, you know, not talk about.
Speaker 1: we would sort of say, okay We're gonna do this We're gonna sing a song play a fast song get everyone sort of like jumping and clapping.
Speaker 1: Let's play another song.
Speaker 1: people would like dance and stuff like that and then you take it down and I played keyboards as well.
Speaker 1: So then I'd put on there like the synth sounds and it's all.
Speaker 1: Sing some slow songs everyone to close their eyes.
Speaker 1: the heartbeats would slow down again the pipe organ going.
Speaker 1: Well, not so much pipe organ.
Speaker 1: That's sort of like the big sort of like church.
Speaker 0: Interesting study came out It was a long time ago, but there's been a lot of writing about it since but that you can use certain kinds of low-frequency sounds to instill Unnerving senses of awe wonder and fear in people and they won't realize where it's coming from.
Speaker 2: Oh, they can't even hear the sounds because they're below human hearing.
Speaker 2: the same way The dog whistle is a high frequency that a human can't hear You know, you can get a lower sound than a human can resonate literally in your bowels.
Speaker 1: I know there's no noise.
Speaker 1: It's like 14 her That's it.
Speaker 1: I think it's around about 14 or something hurts.
Speaker 1: and if you and also if they're you're in a room which has got a resonant Frequency to like that.
Speaker 1: You can't help but shit yourself.
Speaker 1: I think that's one of those those things.
Speaker 2: It depends also on the amplitude though, right it might be not powerful enough.
Speaker 1: It's one of those things that yeah, you really I mean, I'm not sure exactly how real this is But when you're.
Speaker 1: well, so I did.
Speaker 0: I did that was the plot of a South Park episode.
Speaker 1: Oh, really?
Speaker 2: Yes What I don't see that episode.
Speaker 2: What was it played?
Speaker 0: the brown note around the entire world.
Speaker 2: I don't remember that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so well the reason I'm dubious in particular just to say because Mythbusters has not had an episode about it Season.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe I'm just making that up.
Speaker 1: It would be next season.
Speaker 1: No There was a science.
Speaker 1: there was a science show or like science experiment II kind of show in In the UK that did something like that, but I don't think that the one where they like blow up bathtubs It was.
Speaker 1: it was one of the.
Speaker 1: I Can't remember what it was called, but it was.
Speaker 1: it's got Richard Hammond presented it.
Speaker 2: They always use the word boffins - they never say scientist.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know why.
Speaker 1: anyway to bring it back.
Speaker 0: I didn't know what that word meant for like three years.
Speaker 1: It means scientists.
Speaker 1: It's rainy people with glasses and bald heads.
Speaker 1: So bring it back to the.
Speaker 1: the church thing is that you know when you go through this like Christian rock concert.
Speaker 1: It's all about channeling God.
Speaker 1: It's all about channeling the Holy Spirit.
Speaker 1: It's all about this and that which is you know, which is a cool way to You know to approach it.
Speaker 1: However, I went to this Conference.
Speaker 1: I was gonna say atheist conference is the the amazing meeting in London last year and there was this.
Speaker 1: it was a really weird kind of sneering kind of view that they had of people who are Christians or anything like.
Speaker 1: that is like anyone who's a Christian is deluded.
Speaker 1: I agree that they are deluded at being an ex Christian myself, but also that they're stupid or Dumb in some way and that's not true.
Speaker 1: The reason why lots of Christians stay Christians is because they have Spiritual experiences which are real to them.
Speaker 1: They're not real as in God doesn't really exist and therefore the spiritual experience actually means something in a spiritual way Like God is telling them something but the experience that they go through the the heightened you know heart rate and all of these are the things that you have when you have a Like a spiritual level spiritual type, you know peak experience that actually is fulfilling and is actually something which means something to people and It's and and they get it regularly from church.
Speaker 1: I you know, I worked for God TV and my job was to go around Christian conferences and you know Mix music that was being you know recorded for the TV and do sound technician stuff and I did that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: so in one year, I went from conference to conference to conference and Saw lots of people, you know doing all kinds of stuff being slain in the spirit and talking in tongues and you know Raising their hands and all the weird kind of stuff that you see on like the Jesus camp, you know DVD No the movie whatever it was called Jesus can't be heard about that.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 2: I've said we saw a trailer for okay.
Speaker 1: So anyway, I started watching that.
Speaker 1: I couldn't watch it all the way through because that used to be my life.
Speaker 2: I didn't watch the trailer.
Speaker 1: I used to be that kid.
Speaker 1: I went to a Jesus camp in that way.
Speaker 1: and the thing is those experiences are real.
Speaker 1: they actually mean something to people.
Speaker 1: and this is a thing that they see that all of these new atheists and all these people that Were at this conference that I went to the town London last year and all these different things that are going on They missed the fact that these experiences are Valuable to people.
Speaker 1: they're wrong.
Speaker 1: I mean the people who are experiencing them.
Speaker 1: are you know, they're?
Speaker 1: what am I trying to say?
Speaker 1: They're not.
Speaker 0: Well, they're definitely.
Speaker 2: I don't think anyone.
Speaker 2: you mean.
Speaker 0: I would say that if they are intelligent There are people who they're smart atheists and stupid atheists and they're smart Christians and stupid Christians.
Speaker 0: We can't say all X's are why but at the same time I believe someone who is intelligent Even if they're having these experiences must over the course of their lives either ignore things They see or build up this kind of debt of cognitive dissonance that eventually something has to give.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cognitive dissonance is pretty much the way Christians live their lives.
Speaker 2: I don't see, you know, I don't know.
Speaker 2: maybe the people at the time London were different But I mean most of the atheist writings I see even grumpy old Richard Dawkins Right, all the all his stuff and mostly Carl Sagan stuff is all about having spiritual.
Speaker 2: You know those levels of like looking at the sky and thinking I know look at that.
Speaker 2: There's so many stars out there There's more stars and they're like grain of sand grains of sand on the beach.
Speaker 2: Holy shit It's like oh my god.
Speaker 2: And if you do if you go out there and you know that and you look at the sky You can have that, you know a very similar experience.
Speaker 0: That's why Carl Sagan or like Alan Watts resonated so much because they did take the I guess it's kind of the Framing these experiences saying look you can have these experiences or anything because those experiences are life.
Speaker 2: Yes I mean nobody's.
Speaker 2: I don't think anyone's saying that experiences like that aren't worthwhile.
Speaker 2: I think what they're saying is look here's someone who goes to church.
Speaker 2: They're getting these experiences regularly from church right and they like them.
Speaker 2: who wouldn't right?
Speaker 2: That's that's you know part of life, right?
Speaker 2: But yet if they're smart, they would know that those experiences could be had without church.
Speaker 2: So why would they continue to go to church?
Speaker 2: and would it?
Speaker 1: maybe this is the thing?
Speaker 2: Why would they continue to pay money to the church or whatever it is when they could just go and get it without?
Speaker 1: this is The church is actually providing a service.
Speaker 1: You are going along there.
Speaker 1: You're following the rules.
Speaker 1: It's like it's like role-playing.
Speaker 1: It's like in it.
Speaker 1: It's like a game that they're playing.
Speaker 1: they're going along and there is sort of like certain games.
Speaker 1: Well, it's not games.
Speaker 1: You know if you go out to the front at the church and you're getting prayed for and the pastor is standing there and holding On to you and you know and praying for you.
Speaker 1: It's like you have to respond to it in some way Otherwise because the pastor or the minister will keep praying for you until he gets a response.
Speaker 1: So it's one of those things that it's sort of like.
Speaker 1: it's like a game that they play but they you know consciously or unconsciously They know.
Speaker 1: if they keep going to it.
Speaker 1: They're gonna get attention.
Speaker 1: They're gonna get like a whole Group of like.
Speaker 1: you've seen these televangelists and stuff Thousands of people all putting out their hands and praying for one person for that one person to be the center of attention.
Speaker 1: That's the only time that they've ever had a thousand people looking in their way all wishing them You know a fantastic experience all blessing them.
Speaker 2: go get some friends.
Speaker 2: It's free.
Speaker 0: Maybe they don't realize they can't.
Speaker 1: maybe Is that this kind of thing is never addressed by any of these new atheists.
Speaker 1: they do address Hey life is excellent.
Speaker 1: and Carl say, you know when I listen to that Symphony of Science song What was it called?
Speaker 1: You know the Yeah, the glorious dawn one You know and that is that sort of made me tear up the first time I heard that.
Speaker 1: and there was another.
Speaker 1: one of his songs that it may you know was also a. You know, we are all connected or whatever.
Speaker 1: That one was called.
Speaker 1: that was good.
Speaker 1: The rest of them sound all the same and they annoy me now.
Speaker 1: But you know when the first time you hear that.
Speaker 1: that affects me because I know what they're talking about.
Speaker 1: I know about astronomy and I know about science and I know about.
Speaker 1: you know that we are all star stuff and all that kind of stuff.
Speaker 1: and Richard Dawkins opens his God delusion with the things like.
Speaker 1: I lay on my back and I looked up at the stars and I thought It was wonderful.
Speaker 1: and he has this kind of rapturous experience thinking about Thinking about what we're trying to say You know evolution and all like all the science stuff that he does.
Speaker 1: he looks at it and finds it wondrous and gets that kind Of spiritual fulfillment out of it.
Speaker 1: However, it takes a lot to get to that point.
Speaker 1: It's very difficult to get to the point.
Speaker 1: It happens sometimes with me like for the first time I ever managed to.
Speaker 1: well I say it takes a lot.
Speaker 1: the first time I ever managed to juggle three balls for like 30 catches and then stop when I Wanted to rather than dropping them.
Speaker 1: That's still one of these peak experiences in my life and the next time I had that same level of experience from juggling That same like a comparable experience was when I managed to do 11 balls for the first time, you know and there was a lot of a gap in between that and that the 11 ball experiences.
Speaker 1: when I just got into a car crash flipped My van over going down the steepest road and he jumped out of the car and took all the balls out.
Speaker 1: I was waiting there and I was so frustrated.
Speaker 1: I was so hyped up.
Speaker 1: I was like, right I'm gonna do this and it was the first time I ever managed to do 11 balls Not the ambulance.
Speaker 1: I was waiting Anyway, I was waiting for the tow truck to come and take away my utterly smashed up vehicle and then waiting for someone to come And pick me up, you know, it was one of those bad things but it was.
Speaker 1: it was this weird combination of a car accident smashing my car up and Then and Then doing this juggling feat and at the time maybe like six or seven other people in the world had ever done 11 balls And I was then one of them.
Speaker 1: so it's like a high-level thing and it affected my life in in a way Like like I didn't go back to university the next year.
Speaker 1: I mean it was one of those things.
Speaker 1: It's like I could have died then and yet I've had this experience and I need to move on with my life.
Speaker 1: It was a life-changing experience.
Speaker 1: It's difficult to have those kind of experiences and this is probably the main reason why I'm Why I turned away from being a Christian because you know the whole cognitive dissonance and the whole self-delusion stuff that helped me all Over all of like the scientific questions and and God and stuff for a long time.
Speaker 1: But it got to the point where I was like, okay, I believe Jesus exists or but might not have been God.
Speaker 1: It was good and you know, I'm not.
Speaker 1: I believe in evolution I believe the world is old, you know There's all these different questions that you sort out.
Speaker 1: But there was this whole thing in my head or not just in my head but in my body is like all these spiritual experience that I've had.
Speaker 1: they must be true at some level.
Speaker 1: otherwise because what I Experienced was real and it was only when I had many other peak experiences outside of a religious context outside of a church context outside of a like classically spiritual context when I actually lost my faith completely and I could identify myself as an atheist or maybe a agnostic or but you know it took me a while to actually work out what it was, but I realized I didn't need the church anymore for the like the Spiritual peak experiences because I'd taken up surfing and that was good.
Speaker 1: I'd been juggling.
Speaker 1: I was performing for the first time to juggling.
Speaker 1: when you get like 200 people like giving you a standing ovation for a show that you're doing.
Speaker 1: that's a great feeling, you know.
Speaker 1: When you when you like, okay, like do a really high-level juggling trick for the first time It is like a rapturous experience to rival anything that I'd felt in church.
Speaker 1: However, I'd had a lot of experiences in church, you know, so it was difficult to sort of like go Ah, it isn't actually the church environment and isn't the Holy Spirit.
Speaker 1: But the thing is you need these kind of experiences elsewhere To have people who go to church regularly to not go to church anymore.
Speaker 1: That needs that need has to be fulfilled and it's not going to be fulfilled by looking at the stars And it's not going to be fulfilled by thinking about evolution and it's not going to be fulfilled In lots of other ways, you know.
Speaker 0: So do we take a bunch of Christians and have drug-fueled raves that are mandatory attendance?
Speaker 1: I'm not.
Speaker 1: I think I'm not into the drugs as a spiritual experience.
Speaker 1: I have had a spiritual experience is taking drugs.
Speaker 1: I
Speaker 0: guess it's more because this raises a lot of interesting kind of Contrast between my own experiences and yours because I've you know Catholic school and I can safely say that there were never peak Experiences were involved with Catholic mass and the way the school and the church and everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah Was this terribly boring thing and I'd go to it and from even as a very young child I remember thinking this is all kind of silly and I just never quite got it.
Speaker 2: That's pretty much the same as me with Judaism.
Speaker 0: I had peak experiences outside of school.
Speaker 0: So I think a lot of it is just the context of when you have these first few experiences.
Speaker 0: I'll bet a lot of it is developmental and I think this speaks very very well as to why the modern church Movements are doing so well while Catholicism at least in the Western world is collapsing left and right.
Speaker 1: exactly This is what the whole mega church phenomenon is about.
Speaker 1: It's give people peak experiences and they will keep coming back week after week.
Speaker 1: They run these things like rock shows.
Speaker 1: they have you know all the lights going on and thumping music and they'll have a pastor who's really You know enthusiastic and charismatic and is leading people into like a frenzy.
Speaker 1: It's awesome.
Speaker 1: It really is.
Speaker 1: if you ever go to one of these things, it's a big show And and people get something out of it.
Speaker 1: and what what do the atheists have in return?
Speaker 1: I went to this.
Speaker 1: I say I went to this Tam London and I might be going again this year.
Speaker 1: It's in.
Speaker 1: it's in a few weeks time in October and I've just got a gig at the moment Which means I could probably end up in London the day beforehand.
Speaker 1: So I probably gonna go again this year.
Speaker 1: however, it was you know, lots of people sitting round and listening to conferences and it was.
Speaker 1: there was only one point in it where I thought this is even slightly comparable to the excitement of a quite average Church service.
Speaker 0: now here here is where I can make a point.
Speaker 0: Finally.
Speaker 0: I was thinking about this.
Speaker 0: so I get experiences like this.
Speaker 0: a lot of people get these very strong peak experiences from things like the penny arcade expo and the way they Rile up the crowd in this huge thousands of people.
Speaker 0: and I don't think it's fair to say that atheists don't have the same thing because I would argue that anything that Is not a religious event is by definition a neutral event Which therefore is an atheist event.
Speaker 0: So every single rock concert in the world I'd say it's a secular event rather than an atheist event because I I feel secularism and atheism are The same I would argue except that someone who's specifically a secularist is entertaining cognitive dissonance.
Speaker 2: hmm, maybe anyway, whatever your Semantic point was right.
Speaker 0: The thing is boy was that we get these peak like.
Speaker 1: yeah, that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 1: However, what?
Speaker 1: What can an atheist movement offer To Christian people to bring them away from Christians, which has got something to do with atheism.
Speaker 1: But you know, this is we think.
Speaker 1: maybe I saw what the thing that really impressed me was.
Speaker 1: it was a musician called Tim Minchin.
Speaker 1: He's from Australia, but I think he lives in the UK most of the year now, and he is just awesome.
Speaker 1: He was funnier than anybody else who appeared on that stage.
Speaker 1: He was a better musician than all of the other musicians.
Speaker 1: He actually set had a message which was more poignant and In a way more interesting than any other people and he was just an all-around better entertainer.
Speaker 1: It's a good job that I'm a better juggler than him.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, I think I'd feel inadequate in every single way because he also juggles.
Speaker 1: No, he doesn't juggle I'm saying now at all because I'm a better juggler than him.
Speaker 1: I can I still have My own worth because he is so because he and because he is so awesome in so many ways that I just feel Insignificant next to him.
Speaker 2: if that makes sense, maybe Because you said that you're a better juggler that implied that he had some amount of drug.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: No, it's because.
Speaker 1: well Maybe watch your secret skills.
Speaker 0: You don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean he could just bust out with like a seven 27 balls at home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the point is that that when I actually watched him I came in when he was doing a year when he was doing a like his sound Set up and he sang this song.
Speaker 1: and then he's like I'm gonna do it again But I'm gonna do it with the piano and he went did the same song again word for word But this time played along to the backing track on the piano and I must admit I had one of those fan moments that I Have only very very rarely But it was amazing.
Speaker 1: But then again, I go to a juggling convention, which isn't an atheist event But then there's.
Speaker 1: it's a very secular event Let me put it that way like there's nothing to do with spirituality there.
Speaker 1: and there was a few times when I saw people on stage In their theater shows and with their juggling which made me have that same kind of experience And I had a really good massage and I almost had a spiritual experience in there.
Speaker 1: But you understand that.
Speaker 1: but the thing is it's like what are you gonna do with the skeptics in the pub?
Speaker 1: It's you're getting together and there is fellowship there, which is a big thing And I think that's something that the like the new atheist movement is getting
Speaker 0: Part of it's that the new the so-called new atheist movement or the very kind of vocal act of atheist the people who get to The point where I'm going to run and have an atheist convention are not the majority and they're not the real atheist movement.
Speaker 0: I would argue that the primary real atheist movement is Kids growing up now who are entertained by the internet and entertained by other things who just don't even care at all about religion.
Speaker 2: It's because they're getting peak experiences basically constantly from the the infinite piles of entertainment media and Information, you know It's like just like you you watch.
Speaker 2: you can get like big experiences watching even little videos of TED Talks or YouTube's or whatever.
Speaker 2: Yeah, just because you know and the thing is is you were complaining that some of these like people at the amazing meeting were you?
Speaker 2: Calling like Christian stupid.
Speaker 2: Well, the thing is there are some ways to get experiences that would be sort of inaccessible to people who are stupid like if I watch a TED Talk I might be like Oh my god, that was amazing.
Speaker 2: But if somebody isn't as educated right or intelligent or whatever, you know, they might Watch it and just be like what you know some hick from the woods watching it.
Speaker 2: It's like what that word mean?
Speaker 2: He doesn't you know, he's not gonna get experience from it.
Speaker 2: So that's why you might get this or you know somebody.
Speaker 2: well You might not have had that much excitement at the amazing meeting and most of the things I enjoyed.
Speaker 2: No, no, I mean you might not have had such great, you know, like amazing, you know experiences at every ed Like just sitting there watching people talk, you know, someone else might have found what they were saying.
Speaker 0: Just so Fascinating, you know, but at the same time I think his point stands that for the kinds of people who go to like these Megachurches there are very few things that can offer that same sort of experience.
Speaker 0: football.
Speaker 1: Yeah football.
Speaker 1: Is it sports?
Speaker 0: I would say They can't offer the same sort of experience framed in this kind of bigger that like watching football you can get really into it.
Speaker 0: But you can't feel it as some sort of universe changing event.
Speaker 2: unless you're crazy This is pretty universe changing.
Speaker 1: The thing is you have to be seriously into your football team for it to become like a life-changing experience.
Speaker 2: You know, I'm a fan, but I'm not like seriously into it, right?
Speaker 2: You don't see stuff hanging up my house, but you know, I'm a Giants fan, right?
Speaker 2: You know.
Speaker 2: But if you if I watch that video from Super Bowl 42, I can watch that a thousand times and it is good Every time.
Speaker 2: you know, it does not get old.
Speaker 0: Well consider this one of the piquest experiences of my life and it's funny.
Speaker 0: But this this very much like this moment is burned into my mind is when Scott and I had a bunch of reference went to RIT hockey game and it was like the important hockey game.
Speaker 0: Oh, that was the best and they were down by two and it was standing room only.
Speaker 0: We're like crunched in.
Speaker 0: We're not even in seats.
Speaker 0: We're kind of there semi illegally like just standing there.
Speaker 2: We're not illegal.
Speaker 0: We weren't actually sitting in seats.
Speaker 0: We should have been off in the standing area.
Speaker 2: That's fun.
Speaker 0: And all our friends leave.
Speaker 0: They're like, yeah, it's over They've lost and we stuck out to the end and they won in this like crazy Goal with a few minutes left.
Speaker 2: So they were down by one.
Speaker 2: then with like two seconds left They scored to tie it up and then they scored in overtime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and won it.
Speaker 0: It was such a peak experience.
Speaker 0: But Scott, what if you?
Speaker 0: what if someone takes that same level of experience or that same exact experience?
Speaker 0: but for whatever Trickery or belief or something are able to frame it in such a way to where that wasn't just a hockey game That's the world.
Speaker 0: That's your soul, right?
Speaker 2: They're basically, you know, as soon as the thing is it's okay to just have a hockey game, right?
Speaker 2: But for someone to try to come in with that extra bit Right is there?
Speaker 2: that person is actively trying to deceive you usually with the intent to give you For them to you know for to get you to give them money or to give them loyalty.
Speaker 0: Forget about their intent.
Speaker 0: The thing is they're offering more at face value.
Speaker 0: if I offer you a hundred bucks This other guy offers you a hundred bucks and a check for three thousand dollars.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying that whatever all these things is is true And I do think this is what the church has got something going for it because it is a repeatable experience.
Speaker 1: You go along to a to a hockey game.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna get that every time, you know, it's it's one of those standout.
Speaker 2: Yeah, we haven't had it ever again exactly Things.
Speaker 1: but you go to one of these Jesus camps you go to one of these ministry meetings you go to a prayer meeting And and and you go forward to pray.
Speaker 1: you're gonna have an experience or maybe not every single time But it's a good chance.
Speaker 1: But then you don't want to do it too often because it's like self Regulating in a way that you don't want it to be.
Speaker 1: too often you can get burnt out and that kind of thing.
Speaker 1: but the My entire reason that I wanted to bring this up and why I want to talk to people about this is because this whole Dimension is missing from the whole kind of new atheist or atheistic movement or whatever you want to call it.
Speaker 1: It's the discussion of the spirit the very real spiritual experiences that people get from from churches is missing.
Speaker 1: It's like people don't know it and I think that people who haven't been Christian or haven't had these Christian experiences Don't know the power of them and why people why it makes people believe.
Speaker 1: because for me It wasn't just a thing that I was going for and it wasn't that I didn't Not believe in science or all these other things except it's just that these experiences to me were very very real experiences and it was only until I had enough of them outside of church that I realized that they Only came from that and I don't think I'm that unintelligent.
Speaker 1: I don't think I wasn't very clever back then.
Speaker 1: It's just that the experiences were so real and and that's what it came to.
Speaker 1: I remember then sitting it with a with a friend of mine a juggler and we were you know Good friends were hanging out in his home and and I was talking about You know about and I said, well, I still believe in some in something spiritual because you know I have had these experiences and this was even like after.
Speaker 1: I must have been maybe 22 or 23 at the time and I was just holding on to the fact that there must be a Spiritual element out there because all of these other things I'd always associate them so much with spirituality and all these experiences.
Speaker 1: So there was something there.
Speaker 1: I didn't know what I was feeling and he just said to me Luke It's just people make shit up they just make something up and then they and then they tell it to somebody else and the other person believes it and then they Tell somebody else and that's how everything begins He says it's like the same with you know, all these different stupid.
Speaker 1: You know spiritual things and ley lines and I can't remember these other things.
Speaker 1: But he came up with this whole list of things and this is a guy who you know Has been to the Glastonbury Festival all the time, you know, all these different things.
Speaker 1: He's sat in the stone circles He's experienced all these things, you know firsthand, but he's just like no, it's all bullshit.
Speaker 1: It's because he just it's all bullshit.
Speaker 1: Someone just made up attached some meaning to it and then other people believe them and he says that's how everything starts.
Speaker 1: Somebody just make something up tell somebody else and that's where it all begins.
Speaker 1: and it was that moment, which I thought I'm an atheist You know because it really was that time when someone just really told me it's all made up the experiences are real.
Speaker 1: I mean he didn't actually say this but this is what I was saying my brain.
Speaker 1: So all the explanations for all these experiences are just made up.
Speaker 1: It's not about standing in the right spot and in the ley lines and then the Sun rises and you having a spiritual experience.
Speaker 1: You're gonna have that spiritual experiences, but these rules around you it's like the lay like somebody actually had a spiritual experience here and then there and then in another place and then they drew lines between Them and said there must be something meaningful at this spot.
Speaker 1: and then they go there, you know, there's some.
Speaker 1: What's that?
Speaker 0: There's a gas leak.
Speaker 1: Well, no, they just I'm just saying they go there and of course, they're gonna have a. It's a preconditioned spiritual experience just waiting for them because of their exponent Expectation.
Speaker 1: but the expectation is based on made-up shit that other people have just made up and you believe it Yep, and I'll agree with you that it's very even intelligent.
Speaker 0: people are very prone to this.
Speaker 0: It's human nature because you find the pattern.
Speaker 0: when I was in middle school when I was in high school I mean, I'm an atheist now and I've never been a Christian.
Speaker 0: but when I was young I got to the point where I was convinced that I could tell the future with tarot cards because it always worked and I would tell people people's fortunes.
Speaker 0: and I actually People were afraid of me in high school and I would tell their fortunes.
Speaker 0: and I wasn't until just before I got to went to college at RIT and I was Watching a documentary on cold reading and I'm sitting there and literally like I think the moment I saw that.
Speaker 2: Oh shit the thing Oh shit,
Speaker 0: and I sat down and I went through like the motions and you're
Speaker 1: like, this is what I did And this is what I did.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I sat down with one of my friends.
Speaker 0: I was like, I'm gonna tell your fortune as I was doing it.
Speaker 0: I realized I'm just telling him everything He told me last week.
Speaker 2: Oh my god This is why I saw that documentary and cold reading much earlier in life than you did.
Speaker 2: Yeah, you know and I think you know Luke your whole point is, you know The atheists aren't paying attention to the fact that these you know experiences exist or that they're important.
Speaker 2: I think part of it is because you know You are actually sort of in the minority like most of the atheist or non religious people that I know Are people who were never in the.
Speaker 2: you know, the kind of religion that has you know The rock concerts in the mega churches and all these sorts of things.
Speaker 2: most of the the non religious people I know Were Jews or or they or their their family was non religious or they did something, you know They're.
Speaker 2: any religious life if there was you know, or if they had a pre atheist life was boring and was not, you know They weren't getting any experiences from any religious source.
Speaker 2: They were getting if they had any, you know, awesome experiences.
Speaker 2: They were always from something else, you know, I mean Judaism for me, you know for me and most of the other Jews I know is it's a cultural thing.
Speaker 2: It's a cultural thing.
Speaker 2: It's like being Irish, you know, it's like if you're Irish, that doesn't mean there's no religion implied.
Speaker 2: You know, there's Irish Catholics and Protestant Catholic.
Speaker 2: I mean, you know, I mean there's Irish Protestants and Irish Catholics and always fighting.
Speaker 2: but Being Irish means that you wear green on st.
Speaker 2: Patrick's Day and you get drunk and it has not there's.
Speaker 2: no they don't associate any.
Speaker 2: You know, it's called st.
Speaker 2: Patrick's Day, but it doesn't have any meaning.
Speaker 2: Yeah And Judaism was always the same kind of thing, you know you eat.
Speaker 2: on this day We eat apples and honey.
Speaker 2: on this day we eat You know this kind of food and everyone gets together on these certain days of the year to have a party and you know It doesn't mean anything.
Speaker 2: They never tried to give us, you know in any of the the religious places we ever went to no one ever tried to give You know any kind of experience?
Speaker 1: No, but the thing is with the Jewish faith.
Speaker 1: Is it's like like you get these charismatic churches, you know Like these mega churches.
Speaker 1: they're going for that like the spiritual experience and they're going for the whole fellowship thing as well.
Speaker 1: They're going for the for the community thing.
Speaker 1: get together go on, you know and go out and have pizza.
Speaker 1: this night Doesn't like pancakes exactly and that's what I think.
Speaker 1: that's what the Jewish Religion or the Jewish culture is is so good at and that's why so many people really value their Jewish identities and their culture is because it's such a family thing It's such a community thing and they want to keep that part of it.
Speaker 2: The mistake the Jews made at least in the US right is they emphasize education a great deal, right?
Speaker 2: You know Judaism itself is about education, you know, they talk about studying the Torah, you know, you're supposed to study, right?
Speaker 2: And if you don't become a rabbi they you know You're.
Speaker 2: they're gonna want you to study to be a doctor or study to be a lawyer or you know It's all about studying and education is very very highly valued Among, you know the generation of Jews before me and also my generation, you know.
Speaker 2: So by emphasizing someone to become educated they become They learn science and then they no longer again.
Speaker 1: This is another thing that all the religious people, you know.
Speaker 1: They're down on science and they're down all this kind of stuff there's.
Speaker 1: a reason is because when you are educated in that you do lose faith in things.
Speaker 1: and Like I say I when I was younger, I was really into dinosaurs and this is talk about coming into dinosaurs.
Speaker 2: Exactly.
Speaker 0: and for me, we're not worship dinosaurs if they came back and could talk.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying for me dinosaurs were very impressive.
Speaker 1: I knew the names of lots of them.
Speaker 1: I don't know the many now because they all change and things but I know right the point is In my head.
Speaker 1: I knew dinosaurs died out 65 million years ago.
Speaker 1: 64 65 million years ago.
Speaker 1: you ever take whatever millions.
Speaker 1: but also in my head There was this fact that the earth was very young like between 10 and 6,000 years old or something like that.
Speaker 1: And I I was the kid in geography class who would get a hundred percent on all my exams with geography You know because I was actually quite clever and I knew about this because I lived in out outdoor kind of life and I knew how caves are made and things like that and I knew caves took millions of years to form as well or thousands, you know hundreds of thousands of years to form and yet still I Thought the world was only 10,000 years old, but I looking back now There's absolutely no way I can work out how I thought those two facts fitted together in my head and yet somehow They did.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know I can't explain it except for this massive massive like watching a segmentation in my brain where like reasoning and scientific stuff went in one direction and religious stuff went in the other and There was this very clear dividing line.
Speaker 1: and when in what situation I was in where Science would be in one side and Religion would be in the other side.
Speaker 2: My brain had sort of a similar but slightly different problem.
Speaker 2: Right is I would go to school and they would teach me history and then I would go to Hebrew school like Tuesday Thursday and Sunday And they would teach you like, you know Moses or whatever, right?
Speaker 2: Yeah, and I always try to think okay So when was Moses?
Speaker 2: and when was Alexander the Great?
Speaker 2: And the thing was is you know?
Speaker 2: This is also part of the reason people keep getting on me about my memory is that my school system actually did one thing That you know throughout my entire public schooling, you know I was in one town and they did.
Speaker 2: they actually did one good thing in my opinion Which is they always stayed away from rote memorization, right every single class I was ever in they were like listen Well, this is not about, you know rote memorizing things You know,
Speaker 1: you never learn how to remember
Speaker 2: anything would never ask they would never ask you like what year did X happen?
Speaker 0: Scott legitimately asked me in college at one point.
Speaker 0: This is at RIT.
Speaker 0: He thought that the Romans got the idea for swords and that sort of fighting from the Middle East like the Knights.
Speaker 2: You didn't know.
Speaker 2: It's like I didn't know.
Speaker 0: If there was a physics test they would give you the equation Over that fact.
Speaker 2: right never have to memorize equations.
Speaker 2: It was all about the ability to solve problems to work things out for you.
Speaker 1: So why?
Speaker 2: I'm kind of good at computers and solving problems and those sorts of things, but I'm not good at Memorizing like X and numbers because they said they tried they tried to de-emphasize it.
Speaker 2: I think it is too heavily emphasized in most education systems But I think that there was also this problem of not having it at all.
Speaker 2: He which I have no Memorizing.
Speaker 2: which came first?
Speaker 0: Sparta and the whole 300 thing or Alexander the Great.
Speaker 1: Oh Greek.
Speaker 0: well, no, no, no was Macedonian.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it's Sparta was The Dorian.
Speaker 2: I'm gonna say the Sparta came first.
Speaker 2: All right Yeah, see that that's a hard one.
Speaker 1: I think most people wouldn't be able to know that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually this comes up with another topic that we might do.
Speaker 2: We could do on a different show Trojan horse and all that kind of shit.
Speaker 2: That's about that's The same time as Sparta.
Speaker 0: No, that's pre the archaic age of Greece.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's guys legendary times.
Speaker 2: So wait, so she was that real or was it not real?
Speaker 0: We're not sure.
Speaker 0: we know that there was a city somewhere called Troy.
Speaker 0: basically there were Greeks and they stuff happened and they're all mostly gone and Theoretically the Dorian's were kind of Greeks as we know.
Speaker 0: them moved into their area like the Sparta We know was founded on the site of.
Speaker 2: I gotta get A book because this is getting too important.
Speaker 1: Okay, we could.
Speaker 1: I've got this great thing about Another atheist topic, but I think we've gone on quite a long time here.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 2: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 2: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 2: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 2: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 2: It's actually recorded at night.