Speaker 1: Hey, it's Tuesday, May 4th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We talk about the dorfs or Dwarves in the vernacular.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be a board game week on Friday.
Speaker 1: We got the nerd NYC game night as always and on Wednesday There's a muse games game night.
Speaker 0: Oh snap.
Speaker 0: It's too many board games.
Speaker 1: I'm going to both though.
Speaker 0: Are you this time?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think I can go on Wednesday.
Speaker 0: Just because it would require you know with bicycling.
Speaker 1: It's like You could take the subway and that cost money.
Speaker 0: Down there is that this is like the dilemma here.
Speaker 0: right if I get the unlimited subway card it costs like 80 bucks.
Speaker 0: Yep, but Basically, I'm free to just take the subway whatever.
Speaker 0: I don't have to think about it right like.
Speaker 0: but now I'm riding the bike.
Speaker 0: so the bike means that I can take the subway Less times per month.
Speaker 0: I guess 32 times per month would make the $80 Infinite card worth it.
Speaker 0: if you go less than 32 trips Less than 32 swipes actually then the $80 unlimited card is not worth it.
Speaker 0: Do you really care about the odd two or three dollars randomly, but the thing is it's a lot of two or three dollars.
Speaker 0: But no think about it, right So I'm still saving money.
Speaker 0: But because I didn't ride my bike today because there's a 30% chance of rain it cost me like wait wait wait wait.
Speaker 1: 30% chance is not that likely.
Speaker 0: the clouds are all bleh in the morning.
Speaker 0: It was beautiful all day, but not when I was going to work.
Speaker 0: So it cost me seven dollars, so it's like fuck.
Speaker 0: so now you know.
Speaker 0: on the one hand.
Speaker 0: I am saving money.
Speaker 0: I am spending less than $80 per month on MetroCard, but at the same time I'm like conscious of X every trip.
Speaker 0: I take like Another trip.
Speaker 1: See I get the unlimited.
Speaker 0: I could just not take that trip and save some money.
Speaker 1: I rollerblade one way every day.
Speaker 1: So I'm already using half as many swipes as I would but I get the unlimited anyway because it's just.
Speaker 1: I don't have to worry About it.
Speaker 1: I'm just always subway.
Speaker 1: I use the subway egregiously Outrageously.
Speaker 1: I use it when I shouldn't even use it.
Speaker 1: like one day I was running and I was like a subway time and I took the subway home.
Speaker 0: huh I Would if I had limited fact.
Speaker 1: the other day it rained.
Speaker 1: I was in Bryant Park getting lunch So I just went into that subway station and took the subway the seven from Bryant Park to Grand Central to get back to work.
Speaker 0: Hey, why not, but you know the thing is it's like I'm trying to save some monies here, so If I start if I get the unlimited, I'm not saving Jack.
Speaker 1: I Can't feel like the difference is that much money between unlimited or not.
Speaker 0: well if I bike right eight out of the 12 months of the year yeah eight times 40 bucks is $320.
Speaker 1: but then you have to subtract every time it rains and every time you do anything in the city no It's it's cuz I'm.
Speaker 0: that's taking into account basically.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying 80 times You know eight months.
Speaker 0: I'm saying 40 times eight months.
Speaker 0: see I'm basically assuming I'm still gonna pay 40 bucks a month on MetroCard, so I'm saving like $320.
Speaker 1: well as fascinating as that is I did finally beat my magic clash of heroes.
Speaker 0: Oh you actually beat it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, after I got to that boss that I couldn't beat I stopped playing.
Speaker 1: Every boss was pretty much trivial except the last one because the last one I had to fucking level up for.
Speaker 0: yeah No, but there was the necromancy one.
Speaker 0: were you supposed to use a certain item?
Speaker 0: I didn't use.
Speaker 1: you don't have to use an item.
Speaker 1: She was piece of there.
Speaker 1: There was basically nothing to that battle.
Speaker 1: just kill her I didn't.
Speaker 1: or if you're a wuss use the spider cloak.
Speaker 0: And yeah, that's what I didn't know.
Speaker 0: to use the spider cloak.
Speaker 1: it seemed kind of obvious though.
Speaker 1: It's a crazily overpowered.
Speaker 1: It's like if you're playing Mario right and in world 8 right before Bowser.
Speaker 1: you have the option of like.
Speaker 1: it says you could have Normal fire flower or you can have a fucking hammer suit that we brought in from the future.
Speaker 1: Pick one.
Speaker 1: they're both equal in cost.
Speaker 0: I think the reason I didn't pick it was cuz what it gives you like twice double damage.
Speaker 1: But it gives you plus 90% or plus a hundred percent or some crazy amount to all your guys.
Speaker 1: But it also makes your health starting health like way low right and then one vampire brings that all the way back up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't you?
Speaker 0: that's the thing.
Speaker 0: is I messed up without that.
Speaker 1: think of it.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: I don't use the vampires.
Speaker 0: I use the skeletons and the zombies one.
Speaker 1: You're stupid.
Speaker 1: You should be using the vampire To the vampire.
Speaker 1: Scott is with the ghost.
Speaker 1: It's a special guy not a normal guy.
Speaker 0: Oh is it?
Speaker 0: yeah I don't think I was using him at all.
Speaker 0: I was using like this mobbie in the and the zombies a normal guy the Draco Litch.
Speaker 1: But that's one of the double wide guys.
Speaker 1: What about your single wide guy?
Speaker 1: the only other option was the ghost and the ghost sucks.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't think you put much thought into that game.
Speaker 0: I play it was a long time ago.
Speaker 1: You didn't get to the awesome demon level which is pretty much the best level.
Speaker 1: that the most fun is to be had there I don't know.
Speaker 0: I like the Connecticut level.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that one was okay.
Speaker 1: It wasn't that much going on though, and I didn't really like using the Knights.
Speaker 0: The thing is is way too many goddamn video games right now.
Speaker 0: It is not cool that to give me so many video games.
Speaker 0: Right, it's like pie cross.
Speaker 0: 3d came out for the DS.
Speaker 0: It's like I'll fuck you.
Speaker 1: So you're just playing a variant of Sudoku Sudoku effectively.
Speaker 0: now pie cross is far.
Speaker 0: Is it a game?
Speaker 1: Pie cross is it a competitive game?
Speaker 0: It's a puzzle just a puzzle.
Speaker 0: if you have a timer on it, then it becomes a game.
Speaker 1: So why not just play Sudoku?
Speaker 1: Because there's an algorithm in fact Scott.
Speaker 1: I have an algorithm that solves pie cross.
Speaker 1: It's called Photoshop.
Speaker 1: Yeah Maybe Google image search I type in fire flower and bam But there's also.
Speaker 0: I didn't buy that by the way, but I probably will eventually.
Speaker 0: Also, right, I still have freaking the Edgeworth game that I haven't played at all.
Speaker 0: All right, it's just sitting there.
Speaker 1: I didn't even buy it.
Speaker 0: Yeah I still haven't played New Mario Brothers, which I haven't bought either from how long ago.
Speaker 0: It's probably still 50 bucks, isn't it?
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is one that games only worth playing if we have four crew people here to play.
Speaker 1: That's right, and we've got three right now.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So then you know the Street Fighter which I actually am playing and the thing the reason I am playing that is because you got Nice crew going on.
Speaker 0: It's like if I go home tonight and turn it on like you.
Speaker 0: there's like a whole bunch of Xbox friends are gonna be on.
Speaker 0: We're getting a little endless game going on.
Speaker 1: I got to say to that you assholes I I was just gonna wait for it to come out on the fucking PC and have my little media PC with steam and whatever and just play it there with my windows.
Speaker 1: and Now, I think I gotta buy a stupid Xbox.
Speaker 1: I was just gonna wait like three or four years and get the next Xbox There.
Speaker 0: isn't that there?
Speaker 0: I think people you have to realize that you know The reason.
Speaker 0: part of the reason I bought an Xbox is that we realize It's not gonna be like before.
Speaker 0: there's not gonna be new consoles for quite a few years.
Speaker 0: These are gonna live a lot.
Speaker 1: But the thing is what bothers me is that there's no reason.
Speaker 1: my PC is more powerful than an Xbox and it's running Windows.
Speaker 1: There is no reason but the fact that they didn't do it that Xbox Live isn't just the same on Windows and I can't just play Every Xbox game on my Windows PC.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it bothers me that I basically have to buy and if I buy a stupid Xbox I still got to make a freaking PC for the living room.
Speaker 0: Yep, I have both.
Speaker 0: and then you got to pay 50 bucks to get Xbox Live Gold at 50 bucks a year.
Speaker 0: if you want to play online Yep, I might do it anyway though because I gotta say then if you want a joystick you gotta pay a hundred bucks.
Speaker 1: I mean, I love fighting.
Speaker 0: or you can get the non good joystick I was never that or you can get the gamepad with six buttons.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna get the mad cat.
Speaker 1: If I'm going I'm going all out But I don't foresee a Bushido blade coming on the horizon.
Speaker 1: No, so I can't wait for that.
Speaker 1: I can't wait for my glory day to return.
Speaker 0: Yes, you've got a problem as people have been practicing this game already for weeks, you know came out last week.
Speaker 0: You're behind Yeah But how long is it gonna take you to get all that stuff set up?
Speaker 0: our
Speaker 1: group community is gonna be much more fun to Play than say the Smash Brothers community because one online play
Speaker 0: The best thing is they have this endless mode and the way endless mode works is you get I think eight maybe ten people and they all join and Basically, everyone starts off You know lined up in the order in which you joined the top the two first people in the list fight Well, everyone else watches and then the loser goes to the bottom and the next person fights and loser goes.
Speaker 0: So it's like standing in the arcade.
Speaker 0: It's so awesome.
Speaker 0: And so basically you sit around and you just use your Xbox headsets and you just chat it up with everyone You know discussing what's going on like oh shit.
Speaker 0: He's a super Oh snap.
Speaker 0: Oh you cheap using that whatever, you know Everyone's chatting it up.
Speaker 0: You got like 10 people talking, you know voice chat and like a little conference while you watch people play Street Fighter and then every once in a while you play Street Fighter and if you win you just Keep playing Street Fighter as long as you keep winning just like the arcade.
Speaker 0: It's still awesome.
Speaker 1: I work today.
Speaker 1: I was I was reading that thread and I was thinking you know what god damn it and I almost just bought an Xbox right there.
Speaker 0: You better.
Speaker 0: I see.
Speaker 0: thing is if you want to get in quick you're better off going to the store and getting one.
Speaker 0: It's the same price.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, actually Amazon price is a big discount, don't they?
Speaker 1: It's hard to say because I gotta.
Speaker 1: I gotta compare because Best Buy.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, and I pre-ordered Starcraft 2.
Speaker 0: So I get.
Speaker 0: I'm supposed to get a beta key sometime this week.
Speaker 1: You're already fucked everyone.
Speaker 1: I know workers who like Starcraft.
Speaker 1: They've been playing some pirated ass leaked copy for the last month.
Speaker 0: I'm already fuck cuz I just suck ass.
Speaker 0: but you know, whatever you got to practice the turn-based - and it's - is gonna come out eventually, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah So what it?
Speaker 0: what's the fuck?
Speaker 1: see my pro at least NS2 is definitely a ways out.
Speaker 1: I mean you play that alpha.
Speaker 1: I played that not even an alpha.
Speaker 1: That was a pre alpha Yeah, and one and then I slept his death sitting there.
Speaker 0: that you know, I'm tweaking.
Speaker 1: Yeah well I was poking at that because I sadly my plan was to use it for a secret project at Paxi or Pax West Pax Prime.
Speaker 1: we can't divulge that yet, but For various reasons I have pushed that back.
Speaker 1: So I have a whole year now to do.
Speaker 1: the thing I was going to do with sleep is death You know for the next Pax East.
Speaker 1: so that's basically at the bottom of the hopper right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but looking at so many goddamn games.
Speaker 1: Yeah project Dorf Civ 5 is coming.
Speaker 1: We're fucked.
Speaker 0: Fuck me, right that one.
Speaker 1: The worst part is all the games that we're gonna play.
Speaker 1: It's not like they're all out right now.
Speaker 1: It's that not only are enough.
Speaker 0: coming out faster than I can play them is the problem.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know Street Fighter can I could just play only that and ignore all other games for quite some time?
Speaker 0: Cuz there's a lot to do.
Speaker 1: Luckily Team Fortress 2 is just beyond hope.
Speaker 1: It's not have no son situation now.
Speaker 1: So don't have to worry about that.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 0: why is this news now?
Speaker 0: We discussed that I think years ago.
Speaker 1: I didn't say it was news, but here's something.
Speaker 0: imagine if I even bring it up.
Speaker 1: imagine if you would quit World of Warcraft because you realize it was just a grind.
Speaker 1: and then like two years went by and One day you saw your account.
Speaker 1: You're like Let's go see what's going on in that grindy coffee bean game and you logged in and they had literally and you saw like an update flash.
Speaker 1: it was like there there's been an update since you last played and Here's the new interface and it was literally just a physical wheel you had to buy and spin to grind out levels.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is the equivalent of going back to play Team Fortress 2. now that game is dead.
Speaker 1: I have no son.
Speaker 1: The worst part is it is so crazy.
Speaker 1: There are more people playing that than playing Counter-Strike.
Speaker 1: Yep What does this world come to?
Speaker 0: People who don't play no skill games except right.
Speaker 0: we thought all people don't like games of skill.
Speaker 0: Well, there's three fighters three fighters.
Speaker 0: So that's way more a game of skill than like even Counter-Strike.
Speaker 1: I think here's one reason why Fighting games are a game that still exists in what few arcades they are.
Speaker 1: We're in that Mott Street Chinatown arcade.
Speaker 1: What was it?
Speaker 1: a hundred fighting games and Azen standing there playing them for there was a line of people waiting Outside that arcade for the fucking open so they could go in and play Street Fighter all day.
Speaker 1: Yep There's no such thing as that for FPS is.
Speaker 1: so you already lose that avenue of getting into it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and to the consoles on the console.
Speaker 1: You can still have a hardcore fighting game like Street Fighter.
Speaker 1: You can't have a hardcore FPS.
Speaker 1: It is absolutely.
Speaker 1: If we could somehow make a hardcore console FPS, which is impossible Or I think what would do it is if every game that was available on the Xbox was also available on any like Windows 7 PC or maybe Windows 7 Gaming Edition, you know some bullshit.
Speaker 0: be like Team Fortress 2 where you have a mouse, but it's really just.
Speaker 0: you know an analog stick.
Speaker 1: but if The Xbox stuff were on the PC it would be possible to make a game aimed at those PC people.
Speaker 1: That was the straight-up hardcore and people would see.
Speaker 0: but any FPS game the aim situation it totally You know, they won't make a game with precise quake aim because then you'll be unplayable on a console.
Speaker 1: So I think the moral here is we need Capcom to find like John Romero's corpse and reanimate it.
Speaker 1: I don't think he's actually dead Far from it, but imagine if Capcom just made a new hardcore FPS.
Speaker 0: Capcom doesn't know how to make an FPS for shit I know but they know they know.
Speaker 1: it said the people who know what to do.
Speaker 1: Well, you should get the people who can do it.
Speaker 0: What you do is you get the Capcom art team to work with valve on an FPS.
Speaker 0: Oh, no way, but valve made Team Fortress 2 but valve also made good.
Speaker 1: FPS is the worst part is valve?
Speaker 1: No, they know how to make a good FPS, but they also know how to make an FPS that makes money.
Speaker 1: And if you know how to do both It's like if I know magic missile and fireball and I can cast them an equal number of times What am I gonna cast?
Speaker 0: Anyway, I guess unless I'm fighting a ghost too many goddamn games coming out I got another one in my news to discuss.
Speaker 1: So speaking of games and speaking of Street Fighter, but this may be news to some of you.
Speaker 1: I would hope that you all know about this, but I'd heard about it.
Speaker 1: I didn't know what it was until I finally Like.
Speaker 1: it was everywhere and I just looked at this stupid article and watch the trailers.
Speaker 1: Street Fighter legacy is not a game.
Speaker 1: It's a movie based on Street Fighter.
Speaker 0: oh, we don't have enough of those being made by Joey Ansa who is a for real Hollywood guy and We don't have any of those.
Speaker 0: we've never seen this before.
Speaker 1: so before you doubters doubt and before you haters hate You need to check out these trailers because I've never seen a trailer for a video game movie in any capacity.
Speaker 0: I've never seen a trailer that looks as good as the one for kassan.
Speaker 1: God I remember that.
Speaker 0: All right, I win that argument.
Speaker 1: All right, so I think this guy knows what's up.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of crazy like surprising.
Speaker 1: Hollywood talent is behind this.
Speaker 1: It's a short film.
Speaker 1: It is coming out Thursday as in two days from now in real movie theaters.
Speaker 1: No on the internet for free
Speaker 0: Okay
Speaker 1: And I'm going to quote for you exactly what the guy who made this had to say because this gives me hope Just like when the guy who made bionic commando Rearmed said his little thing about what he liked about bionic commando and we all knew what was up and we knew that he knew What was up?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm quote as an actor filmmaker and a fan.
Speaker 1: I've been repeatedly disappointed by the many diluted unfaithful and outright butchered movie adaptations of fighting video games.
Speaker 1: It was clear to me that given the way the movie industry worked We would never see a super faithful darker toned more adult themed or just plain good incarnation of Street Fighter unless a diehard fan director or filmmaking team with a game can and knowledge Filmmaking know-how and the connection stepped up to the plate and made it happen Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So basically it's kind of a robert-coups situation.
Speaker 1: You've got someone who's brilliant in one realm like already professional already knows what's up But is also a fan of like a real fan of some other thing that does not have talent like that in the realm.
Speaker 1: And when you combine those two magic happens, so I'm about I withhold judgment until Thursday.
Speaker 1: I'm almost willing to call this guy the Robert coup of making Street Fighter movies happen And he got the director of top gear to help him do this.
Speaker 1: Owen Trevor, okay, yeah Seriously watching these trailers.
Speaker 1: I'm I'm legitimately excited.
Speaker 0: Okay, so you're ready for another game to eat up your time?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah But there's like a Tecmo Bowl on.
Speaker 0: don't eat on the 360 like it's Tecmo Bowl retro or something remake.
Speaker 0: and there's also.
Speaker 1: You listeners might not realize it but I actually really really like football games.
Speaker 0: football games are the best not recent football.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not Madden anything, you know.
Speaker 1: remember Madden on the we quarterback club.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anything like that is good.
Speaker 0: Here's another game to eat up your time here.
Speaker 0: So apparently they're coming out with a game called Castlevania harmony of despair, which is HD, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah That's right.
Speaker 0: Might and Magic Clash of Heroes is gonna be on the 360 also.
Speaker 0: There's another game.
Speaker 0: Every turn Dave Riley was like what game should I play?
Speaker 1: and I was like might magic clash of heroes.
Speaker 1: He was like, yeah, I'll just wait for it to come out on the Xbox.
Speaker 0: Castlevania HD harmony of despair.
Speaker 0: I always love how they do that like DS.
Speaker 0: They did Donna sorrow, right?
Speaker 1: Well portrait of ruin didn't really do much PR yeah, but what did what that stand for?
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: It's just the funny joke.
Speaker 1: They do you know what it stood for not as good.
Speaker 0: So there's a rumor that went out and it's looking.
Speaker 0: there was like a leaked document that was then Unleaked or whatever, but basically the rumor is and it's pretty good.
Speaker 0: rumor Is that this is gonna be a Castlevania just like the DS ones and the GBA ones?
Speaker 0: But it's going to be a six players simultaneous co-op multiplayer Metroidvania game and apparently there are screenshots indicating that the Aria of sorrow character a la card The portrait of ruin character the order of ecclesia character the port another portrait of ruin character will all be Playable, so like six different characters from the you know, GBA and DS series,
Speaker 1: but all I want is Simon and Trevor
Speaker 0: Altogether some.
Speaker 0: well, you know, they didn't say they're not in there But yeah, but I can't trust that it's gonna be an Xbox live arcade game.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess all these Castlevania.
Speaker 0: basically It's like, you know symphony tonight where everyone's playing at once and that is like the best thing ever.
Speaker 0: So, you know if there's that's Konami, that's not even Capcom.
Speaker 0: So quite surprising Box tonight just tonight.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'll just go and get one.
Speaker 1: Damn it.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I just bought a friggin gaming PC - yeah, I Just bought a new laptop, but I'm not using that to play games only to mail.
Speaker 0: I might but you know, oh, yeah By the way, like Linux team we want to talk about that.
Speaker 0: Oh Mac and Linux team.
Speaker 0: I mean we talked about Mac's team, but now there's screenshots of Linux team.
Speaker 1: Well here predictions about that.
Speaker 1: the fact I mean we they.
Speaker 1: it's been talked about that.
Speaker 1: this was happening for a long time But the news is kind of just that it's actually happening.
Speaker 1: Yeah any more than we expected.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's something that I should have predicted because it was sort of obvious that you know people don't realize this.
Speaker 0: But the old steam client right which is pretty much the one that was around a couple weeks ago Until they just switched it just now Use was heavily integrated with Internet Explorer.
Speaker 0: Like if you open up steam the store that you were looking at was actually just steam powered.
Speaker 0: calm and it was used.
Speaker 0: You know Internet Explorer was built into it.
Speaker 0: So they what they did is they recently Upgraded the steam client.
Speaker 0: So it's now based on the webkit browser, which is what's in Safari and Chrome not Firefox.
Speaker 0: and So now, you know, so it's like, huh?
Speaker 0: Okay, they finally made it better and you think the reason they would do that is just cuz IE sucks, but it's like.
Speaker 0: no Obviously the reason to do that is that you can get the steam client to run on something besides Windows But if you use IE you can't you you know, that wouldn't be enough.
Speaker 1: what I expected perfectly Honestly, even when this was all like announced for real and not just a rumor.
Speaker 1: I Expected them to make it available and only a handful of games would get ported.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like they would sell Linux games or they would sell Mac games in the Mac one.
Speaker 0: But you know and me the thing is it looks like they're actually to port the valve games and not only that.
Speaker 0: But it's like if you legitimately own them, then you legitimately get them, you know, I bought half-life 2.
Speaker 0: So they port half-life 2 to Linux and I install steam on Linux.
Speaker 0: I download it again just like you know, I always don't to pay for it.
Speaker 1: now What's interesting is think about this.
Speaker 1: Imagine, you know four years from now, let's say if steam just works on all three major OS's.
Speaker 1: well, maybe all two major OS's and you can choose which one.
Speaker 1: I'm leaving out based on your personal preference, but That really kind of side swipes if Microsoft in the long run is trying to make but when the Xbox Windows gaming platform their thing because steam would kind of work on everything and gamers trust steam a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think it just really encourages Like people especially people making small indie games or whatever, you know Like, you know if steam runs on Mac and Linux and encourages you if you're making a game to sell on the steam to also make sure your Game works on Mac and Linux.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that you can get you know more sales.
Speaker 0: And of course, you know, they're gonna have all the statistics about how many installs are out there with.
Speaker 0: you know OS X and Linux, but I think it's gonna be a slight chicken and egg situation where you know, okay People are still only using the windows team So no one's gonna make games for the you know Mac and Linux team unless it's gonna be enough extra sales to be worth it.
Speaker 1: But valve is obviously going to push this by porting all their game.
Speaker 0: Yes, so that might right.
Speaker 0: if this you know, there's some people out there It's it's like a slight crack in the eggshell of the chicken eggs problem, right?
Speaker 0: You know some people who are currently using windows just for gaming, you know might go Aha, I finally have steam on a win Apple or I finally have steam on Linux and they'll switch and that slight switch Will upset the numbers a little bit and then it will slowly move and slowly move and maybe eventually Right X years down the line, you know, there'll be some sort of you know miracle where there's just enough games That run on not windows that you know all the gamers won't have any reason to use them.
Speaker 0: and if the performance gets better on OS X and Linux than it is on Windows then you're gonna see some crazy shit happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll see about that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that made the big problem.
Speaker 0: that was direct direct X rather than steam.
Speaker 1: I don't foresee anyone making a cross-platform equivalent of DirectX anytime soon.
Speaker 0: No, it's not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: It's called OpenGL.
Speaker 0: It's not really the equivalent things of the day.
Speaker 1: It's been all over the place, but it's surprisingly high quality.
Speaker 1: There's the Super Mario crossover.
Speaker 1: basically, you can play Mario 1 as far as I can tell much of if not all of the way through it as Samus Characters every level - yeah.
Speaker 1: but the best part about this is people have done this a million times over.
Speaker 1: it wouldn't be notable if someone had.
Speaker 1: you can Play the first level of Mario 1 as spider-man from the Atari 2600.
Speaker 1: Every character pretty much controls exactly like the character like exactly like they did in the game.
Speaker 0: They're from well except for some changes like little things like double jump in Simon Belmont and link can jump.
Speaker 0: Yeah, granny it's weird that they did Zelda 1 link because Zelda 2 link actually would have worked really really well Yeah, but I think if you know It's interesting to use all the one link because it's like Zelda 2 link is so similar to like Belmont or yep.
Speaker 1: It's so surprisingly well executed that It's well worth checking out.
Speaker 1: do not pass this up All right.
Speaker 0: Well, you know Street Fighter isn't pretty much the focus lately in terms of video games.
Speaker 0: So I have for you a simple YouTube video not anything very exciting.
Speaker 0: It is the world record Street Fighter 4 combo.
Speaker 1: Oh, man, Scott showed this to me.
Speaker 1: It's pretty crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah I've seen some crazy combos.
Speaker 0: This is the craziest combo and it is a world record.
Speaker 0: So there you go.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I could deal with that combo if it was put before me.
Speaker 0: I definitely could not deal with it.
Speaker 1: I mean, I mean the last time I had a combo like that was God I was like high school.
Speaker 0: I've never had a combo like that.
Speaker 1: So Dwarves Which have vaguely Scottish accents most of the time but not always.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, we we've talked about dwarf fortress on the show quite a bit and at PAX I mean as you recall the losing should be fun panel basically starts and ends with dwarf fortress.
Speaker 0: Yep So, you know we were.
Speaker 0: you know after our last burning wheel campaign ended we tried to start up some new stuff.
Speaker 0: You know, some people are trying to do some burning dark Sun.
Speaker 0: Some other people are trying some other action.
Speaker 0: But you know, I was looking for an idea of something that would actually Sail right from the forum.
Speaker 1: No is Water is poison.
Speaker 0: Who always he has all the ideas.
Speaker 0: So anyway You know, he's like, hey, I got an idea burning wheel dwarf fortress and I'm like, oh shit people would actually play that.
Speaker 1: Well, didn't he present it more like here?
Speaker 1: cuz the way you presented it to me was.
Speaker 1: so check out this idea for a burning wheel scenario.
Speaker 1: Seven dwarves go out to form a fortress strike the earth.
Speaker 0: Yeah And it was perfect.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's too perfect.
Speaker 0: It's supposed to be six doors.
Speaker 0: But and it was weird cuz like I thought it was six and then we ended up with four and I'm like Oh, it's not six like I wanted but you know what four is gonna be very manageable.
Speaker 1: and then Phil and she came Like seven people and I'm like fuck and Steve it was perfect though.
Speaker 0: Yeah Absolutely, it's still a few two more people that I can handle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll get better.
Speaker 1: You haven't DM too much in recent history.
Speaker 1: I mean your last foray into that was the kobolds.
Speaker 1: ate my baby games.
Speaker 0: that count I Would count it.
Speaker 0: I don't think that.
Speaker 0: the thing is I blame partially the players in that game who are not The players who tried to do cool stuff and everything they did.
Speaker 1: you said now that wouldn't work.
Speaker 0: That's not how this game would play.
Speaker 0: kobolds ate my baby works.
Speaker 1: So how does kobolds eat my baby work?
Speaker 0: It's a retarded game.
Speaker 0: You're just supposed to go around and try to get the.
Speaker 0: it's like playing zombies Basically, you're not really supposed to try to roleplay it up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: so You got nothing to say captain game master.
Speaker 1: We played burning dwarf fortress, which is the inevitable conclusion of any game of dwarf fortress.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know.
Speaker 0: I was wondering, you know, you think on paper that it would work really well and then We played it and for the most part it actually did work really well just like we thought it would.
Speaker 0: You know, the thing is I had to try to find a balance between the burning wheelness and the dwarf fortress ness.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: should I make them like?
Speaker 0: count all the resources they have?
Speaker 1: no to a degree we should though I mean, yeah, it's like like I've cut some really nice limestone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you got to remember that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: But you know, it's like okay Am I gonna have?
Speaker 0: you know, should we count like how many you know?
Speaker 0: Barrels of nog or should it should it just be you had?
Speaker 0: all right, the nog is good this year.
Speaker 1: actually what I was thinking is the way to go about that is to have a Resources stat for each major thing or maybe just a resources stat.
Speaker 1: overall That is the end.
Speaker 1: the character that has this stat is the fortress.
Speaker 1: hmm, so like you do things to basically level up the stats for food and wealth and
Speaker 0: Dwarves, I think it's best to just basically keep it as a you know In the in the rules, right if you have zero resources someone supposed to give you a loan of a temporary res point.
Speaker 0: So I think that having like a good is sort of like having a temporary res point, right?
Speaker 0: So if you make something that's you know, a perishable or disposable good is something you're gonna trade away.
Speaker 1: They just made the big this big pile of temporary resource points that could be used Because half the fun of burning we about burning wheel of dwarf fortress is the minutia and the other half is watching everyone eventually Dive some horrible situation.
Speaker 0: that part worked really well.
Speaker 1: god How could we fail such a low obstacle after having rolled so many dice?
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean it was nice.
Speaker 0: It was kind of hard for me because I was like trying to gauge the obstacles.
Speaker 0: and the thing is, you know You're not five life paths.
Speaker 0: You're four.
Speaker 0: So you're not that powerful, but you're pretty powerful.
Speaker 1: well, and you're between four and five is the difference between like Artificer and master of art.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean if I didn't give you four you wouldn't be able to do anything, right?
Speaker 0: so I had to give you four and You know, you've got all kinds of forks and Arthas and things.
Speaker 0: You're just getting shit done that you wanted to get done.
Speaker 1: Nobody took my favorite trait though remarkable flatulence.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I couldn't really justify higher obstacles and a lot of these mundane tasks, you know.
Speaker 0: But I needed you to fail for awesomeness to happen.
Speaker 1: Well, no I think the point is no matter what you do if you keep introducing things success We'll just raise the bar for failure.
Speaker 1: Like the more you succeed the more catastrophic failure will be in the long run.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I need to get you to do stuff that's you know harder such that you know There actually will be a failure.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, we failed immediately.
Speaker 0: Yeah Person failed.
Speaker 0: I felt like everyone else is just succeeding way too much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and at the same time It's like I got engaged what the correct obstacles should be.
Speaker 0: better.
Speaker 0: It's actually like the hardest part of GMing burning wheel is figuring out like what the obstacle should be.
Speaker 0: It's tough and having it be correct.
Speaker 1: It is tough with the front row crew because people tend to.
Speaker 1: our burning wheel games are very specific in that a certain certain Sets of the crew like myself or Scott Johnson.
Speaker 1: We're in that both in the same camp.
Speaker 1: We'll play very straightforward Earnest characters who strive for what they want in a very direct way and tend to not be just backstabbing assholes and then people like Pete.
Speaker 1: and Pete Always play the character who's good on the surface But then does like some crazy like as soon as getting Scott's like alright on the game.
Speaker 1: master You've accomplished your great task.
Speaker 1: What do you do now?
Speaker 1: And Pete's the kind of person will say something like I just try to stab the king right here.
Speaker 1: Let's see what happens.
Speaker 1: I just go for it.
Speaker 1: I got that belief.
Speaker 0: That's good.
Speaker 0: I need more of that.
Speaker 0: I wish you would do that.
Speaker 1: He's brought a little bit I don't know.
Speaker 1: I think it's gonna work really well for this game because we don't want just our fortress We want some of the burning wheel shtick.
Speaker 1: But he's basically bringing in the outside world by trying to affect the outside world from the fortress which will work though because it's gonna bring Consequences from the outside world back in something that real dwarf fortress really doesn't do.
Speaker 0: it Does it a little bit but not very much.
Speaker 1: most it does is that if one of your dwarfs wanders way out and leads something?
Speaker 1: Back it'll cause chaos, but you're not gonna have like a caravan of traders or like dwarf refugees coming in.
Speaker 0: Do you have dwarf refugees and caravans and traders coming in all the time?
Speaker 1: You didn't let me finish who themselves because they went out from the fortress or came in in a certain route lead monsters to the Fortress.
Speaker 0: Yes, that happens all the time.
Speaker 0: When does that happen all the time?
Speaker 0: Uh-huh that happens in door fortress.
Speaker 0: So You don't know anything about door fortress cuz I've never played it.
Speaker 1: I can't.
Speaker 0: it's impossible.
Speaker 0: So why are you saying things about you don't know.
Speaker 1: have you ever had that happen?
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you had a monster follow a refugee in who wouldn't have otherwise come.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like if there's a monster just like out in the you know in the distance, you know And the monster is basically when they see something they want to eat.
Speaker 0: They'll follow it, right?
Speaker 1: So if like but so it's just like a monster following but not more strange far-reaching consequences Like a far-off civilization finds out about the fortress because you gave something to a caravan.
Speaker 0: No, but you know caravans show up and then they might be followed by something if it's out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's weird because the real door fortress as Complexity as it is at the same time seems to almost belie itself by An extremely restricting simplicity of action.
Speaker 0: No, that's you know It's it's a lot of.
Speaker 0: it's a lot of just separate systems that all interact with each other in interesting ways.
Speaker 0: And because there's so many systems and each system, you know while ranging in Complexity is actually fairly detailed or perhaps overly detailed in some instances, you know Very interesting things just sort of happen like that, you know Like there's a monster system monsters will follow things that they can eat, you know And try to eat more things if it's a big monster.
Speaker 0: and at the same time There's another system every X months every X seasons traders will appear and look go head towards your trade depot.
Speaker 0: So if these two systems working together, right?
Speaker 0: Monster traders chasing to the trade depot monster in the trade depot monster in your fortress?
Speaker 1: Oh, no, of course It is still interesting about how by Abstracting all of that and adding just a tiny bit of human intelligence not even that much You basically accomplish the same stories by just using burning wheel to do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean part of the things though.
Speaker 0: Is that like a lot of this stuff in?
Speaker 0: Dwarf or just that makes no sense.
Speaker 0: you start to realize how little sense it makes when you start playing her burning wheel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like the rate at which they excavate and the ease in which they excavate, you know, it's like.
Speaker 0: no not really That's not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna dig like gigantic tunnels that are really complex so quickly it that just doesn't go.
Speaker 1: Yeah of course what we haven't done in the burning wheel game that I think you really need to do more is really because Burning wheel has very specific rules about how long it takes for things to get done.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's hard to figure that out Yeah, but you just kind of wing it and give people turns or something because excavating a cave is like a week-long endeavor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yep It's you know, it's like how do I know how long excavating a cave takes?
Speaker 1: Well, just wing it, you know, it takes say it takes a week.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, maybe it takes a day cuz you're awesome dwarves.
Speaker 1: Well, do you want it to take a day instead?
Speaker 0: I don't know how long I want it today.
Speaker 1: Well, you should decide that before you DM a game of dwarf archers.
Speaker 0: It's not easy.
Speaker 0: What I think because the thing is the right answer right you think in D&D right.
Speaker 0: the right answer to that question would be Well, how long does it take to excavate?
Speaker 0: but the right answer in burning wheel is not how long it actually takes to excavate.
Speaker 0: The answer is what length of time would provide the best story, you know, that is the correct answer.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know what the you know, which length of time?
Speaker 1: of course That's in standard burning wheel.
Speaker 1: with a game like to our fortress word We're bridging the gap between just a role-playing game where we want interesting immersion story to happen and a simulator.
Speaker 1: I mean, we're still we're.
Speaker 1: also there's certain elements of us who want to play Sim dwarf and we want mechanical effects of the mechanical actions that we take.
Speaker 0: But then we got to start like doing all sorts of Excel spreadsheets and shit, but you don't have to do a lot.
Speaker 1: That's why I think a really elegant way to do that is to have stats for the fortress that can be called upon like dice Pools, I hate making up rules, but they're so easy.
Speaker 1: I already made them up.
Speaker 1: They're done.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I hate like just throwing in rules that like haven't been tested yet.
Speaker 1: Just wait, I mean we've learned with games like power grid that half the time it just works out anyway.
Speaker 0: You know cuz you knows what kind of weird things gonna happen that I won't be able to like undo and then someone's gonna make Trouble.
Speaker 0: who cares?
Speaker 1: that'll be awesome.
Speaker 1: I mean, what are we gonna do?
Speaker 1: what I?
Speaker 1: Accidentally get a bunch of mithril and then because of a bug in Scott's brain.
Speaker 1: I forge an awesome sword.
Speaker 0: That's no good Can't let that have.
Speaker 1: you have the power to patch those bugs quickly and easily.
Speaker 1: a dragon eats my sword a dragon eats me.
Speaker 0: No, then we're going back to D&D land.
Speaker 0: I got to stay in burning wheel and But Then you need to use the rules.
Speaker 1: you can't just use what you're bringing to the table.
Speaker 1: you gotta have rules to do it all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the other problem.
Speaker 0: Is that you know people are so Like arguing like if I come in and I'll be like look the OBS is five people like oh fuck you the OBS should be Three.
Speaker 1: it's not that people people people that was one person who will go on who go unnamed You know.
Speaker 1: and it's like 90% of the arguments came from 10% of the dwarves.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying you know it's hard to You know if people are gonna be fighting with me.
Speaker 0: It's like look.
Speaker 0: I don't really want to you know be doing that.
Speaker 0: the other thing there is your D&D G.
Speaker 1: you're forgetting a very important aspect of burning wheel game mastering even any game mastering is that you've got to Even if you just make up an obstacle off the top your head based on nothing if you say For then immediately everyone in the room and the meta level knows you just fucking made that up And you didn't have any basis for it, and they feel a little bit cheated Because they feel like all right.
Speaker 1: He made up an obstacle so it didn't really matter what my skill was because he probably made it up by looking at my skill And then deciding what percent chance he wanted me of succeeding or something like that.
Speaker 1: so they feel subconsciously like advancement won't matter Or that you're just arbitrarily setting them up to succeed or fail or something like that.
Speaker 1: You've got to always sound like you had it written down like you knew.
Speaker 1: someone's like What's the obstacle for me to dig a 10 foot by 10 foot square into the side of this basalt?
Speaker 1: Like wall and you got to look at them and say five.
Speaker 0: I think the other problem.
Speaker 1: you say four plus one abs because of and just say some gibberish.
Speaker 0: I think the other problem right is it a lot of times.
Speaker 0: It'll be like it won't just be a boolean situation, right?
Speaker 0: It'll be a. how well do you want to do with situations?
Speaker 0: He knows, but it's not an open-ended test right.
Speaker 0: so it's like okay.
Speaker 0: You know you want to do what you know?
Speaker 0: You want to climb the tree, okay?
Speaker 0: Well do you want to climb the tree?
Speaker 0: Like you know without hurting yourself at all and get all the way to the top quickly or do you want to get the top of the jar you making a mistake though burning wheel handles that already with the you Know working quickly.
Speaker 1: options if you and so if someone wants to do something they say I want to dig a cave this long I want to climb a tree or whatever.
Speaker 1: I think what you should do is just say OBS whatever and By the degree of their failure decide how dire the consequences are if they fail
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's like and
Speaker 1: otherwise pretty much give them whatever they wanted if they succeed yeah
Speaker 0: But it's like I'm sort of you know.
Speaker 0: it's like if I give someone options like you know you want to do it better Don't get my desire.
Speaker 0: And if you want to do it less good Then the OBS is lower than what they do.
Speaker 0: is they just pick the OBS that they want to succeed at and not really you Know.
Speaker 1: now vote that the way around.
Speaker 1: that is very simple Arthur and beliefs.
Speaker 1: if The way I do it is anytime I give someone an obstacle at least when I run like the sword Which is the only burning wheel I've run in recent memory at all or ever.
Speaker 1: If they write they I give them an obstacle.
Speaker 1: if they balk at it at all I say well And I give them a lower obstacle that is in direct conflict with one of their beliefs or instincts And there is never a third option if they want a third option.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess that's part of it.
Speaker 0: It's like you know these sort of like degrees of success on a lot of things.
Speaker 0: It's like they didn't really care as long as they got.
Speaker 0: you know something.
Speaker 1: let's remember burning wheel gives you the option to of They'll succeed in the basic way no matter what.
Speaker 1: if they want to succeed and excel They have to beat the obstacle or they have to give themselves obstacle penalties.
Speaker 1: You know depending on the skill like with my masoning and all that if I want to make a crazy awesome wall There's rules for that saying ad-ops too, and then the wall is this much better.
Speaker 0: Yep The other thing is that because everyone's dwarves is like all these like extra exception rules that we often forget.
Speaker 1: Scott forgets.
Speaker 0: Many people forgot many rules quite oft.
Speaker 0: You know that many.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much.
Speaker 1: There's a speed cap on dwarves and dwarves are bearded mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: There's a lot more rules than that.
Speaker 0: There's like dwarven tools.
Speaker 0: Give you plus one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I booked Yeah.
Speaker 0: But also like if you want to make something that is dwarven Quality then the OBS is like plus two and if you want to make something where the OBS to make it is higher than
Speaker 1: Three then
Speaker 0: you need a workshop, and then to make a workshop you need and it's like this whole.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of like all these little things to remember that are sort of outside The default rules and you're not you know.
Speaker 0: it's hard to remember everything.
Speaker 1: if I were you I would have made it.
Speaker 1: I would have made a burning dwarf DGM sheet before I started with all I did.
Speaker 0: I studied it But I didn't remember every see.
Speaker 0: I would have printed it out and some of the things are hiding in the book in places I didn't notice.
Speaker 1: there's something visceral about having a DM sheet.
Speaker 1: I've always I have trouble doing any sort of game mastering without some sort of screen in front of me.
Speaker 1: in D&D that screen was just so I could lie about die rolls, but Yeah, I don't need to lie about any die rolls.
Speaker 0: I just roll right out on the table.
Speaker 0: as you can see it.
Speaker 1: It's interesting.
Speaker 1: how?
Speaker 1: The the flow of our game basically went straight along to.
Speaker 1: we arrived and everyone bickers just burning wheel.
Speaker 1: And what do you do?
Speaker 1: have a duel of wits immediately no matter what.
Speaker 1: and then?
Speaker 1: Adversary adversity forced us to oh shit We got to get our act together or we're all gonna die and then we succeeded at something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the other thing is it.
Speaker 0: now that I've got like everyone's you know I sort of figured out all the characters I can totally just like.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna come in and just gonna bring like multiple simultaneous horrible conflicts right like boom.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna come out with it like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah What are just gonna be like off fuck?
Speaker 1: one option to whenever you give someone a role where they might fail is to let them Succeed straight up, but not in time Mmm.
Speaker 1: You know you succeed in excavating the hole, but so-and-so already starved to death.
Speaker 0: Planning product.
Speaker 0: you have someone died.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you get my drift.
Speaker 1: Yeah But what I want from you out there the listeners is that we're trying this grand experiment of striking the earth with burning dwarves in a wheel of fortresses.
Speaker 1: We're gonna.
Speaker 1: Did you post our game report in the secret forum or the public forum?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: we should post it.
Speaker 1: I think we'll make a thread about it in the public forum.
Speaker 1: I want all of you to form burning wheel dwarf fortress games.
Speaker 1: just use the straight-up rules.
Speaker 0: it just works and I yeah all you have to do is you know you just take the burning wheel rules.
Speaker 0: you make every character You know dwarfs, and then you just say all right everyone you go out into the middle of nowhere and to start a fortress Go and you just use the burning wheel.
Speaker 0: rules straight up.
Speaker 0: You don't even really think about dwarf fortress that much.
Speaker 1: you see all those crazy stories like bronze murder people talk about like the epic Fortress game.
Speaker 1: if you are unable or unwilling to play dwarf fortress You can basically have the exact same thing by using burning wheel and your friends brains.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know I want to hear your stories.
Speaker 0: I'm sure people will tell you their stories now.
Speaker 1: on a completely unrelated dwarf tack.
Speaker 1: We we were talking about dwarf fortress and some Scott was complaining about how his dwarf fortress game that he was playing Was really really really laggy like Unduly laggy even with the the admittedly bad code of dwarf fortress.
Speaker 1: like it was just way too laggy.
Speaker 1: and Someone made some comment like oh, there's probably a city of undead stuff living under you that tends to slow the game down.
Speaker 1: Nope, no no city of undead, but even if it were I think I said something like well That's just really bad coding.
Speaker 1: nothing should slow down the dwarves like nothing.
Speaker 1: meta should slow down your dwarves The dwarves making decisions or like making your hallways too narrow or something like that shouldn't slow down the game.
Speaker 0: The game is just really poorly coded.
Speaker 0: We've discussed this even when we had the creator of the dwarf fortress on the show.
Speaker 0: We asked him like why don't you open source this so people can fix it up?
Speaker 0: You know and he just won't.
Speaker 1: and yep, but the conversation went in a direction.
Speaker 1: and finally we're like.
Speaker 1: you know what we always say things like this and our motto is usually put up or shut up or Put up and get and then trick someone else to continue putting up and then shut up.
Speaker 1: But someone suggested it and the discussion happened, and we now have a geek nights coding Club.
Speaker 1: We'll see how long this goes.
Speaker 1: but a bunch of listeners you and you know Scott kind of laid the groundwork are trying to Make a dwarf fortress like game completely open source MIT license.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing is it's like.
Speaker 0: This is one of those situations.
Speaker 0: I think that's like dude, bro, right.
Speaker 0: It's where flame war begets work.
Speaker 0: You know it.
Speaker 0: I think this is really sort of like the rule and perhaps the solution on the internet right is if you see some flame War or you know typical internet in this.
Speaker 0: Basically your choices should be right.
Speaker 0: if you care about whatever this flame war is Then you have to do right.
Speaker 0: you have to do some creativity or some work and that wins the flame war like you know Making dude, bro that wins right.
Speaker 0: or you know if you're arguing with someone in an open source project somewhere, and they say The colonel should use this scheduler.
Speaker 0: Oh the colonel should use this scheduler.
Speaker 0: Whoever writes the code, and it works is probably gonna win right?
Speaker 0: so this is yet another instance of.
Speaker 0: we were saying look dwarf fortress is coded like shit and Someone in the forum was trying to say it wasn't and I don't know why they thought it wasn't because it is.
Speaker 0: It's pretty obvious to bring anyone who knows anything about software that the code of dwarf fortress is probably like the worst in the universe And it was coded properly.
Speaker 0: it probably runs so fast you couldn't even see the dwarves moving around Like you know really sim C to 2000 on cheetah mode on a modern PC.
Speaker 0: And it's like and it's like a thousand years fast by in like a second because it's so fast.
Speaker 0: That's probably how fast again dwarf fortress would run if it was coded properly.
Speaker 0: so we just started Kind of making it kind of sorta.
Speaker 1: yep the working title is still project door if we haven't decided what dwarf stands for yet.
Speaker 0: No, no it doesn't have to stand for anything.
Speaker 0: But you know it's not like we're trying to compete with dwarf fortress right?
Speaker 0: we're primarily you know we're sort of.
Speaker 0: you know We're trying to learn different algorithms because you know dwarf fortress actually is a pretty good.
Speaker 0: It has so many different systems the water flowing system.
Speaker 0: You know the the dwarves moving around system the dwarven AI system.
Speaker 0: You know animals moving around caves caving in.
Speaker 0: you know all sorts of.
Speaker 0: you know making things out of different materials terrain Generation also weather.
Speaker 0: it's got so much stuff going on right.
Speaker 0: all these different systems are actually You know make for really interesting algorithms that need to be written.
Speaker 0: You know pathfinding and rendering and all sorts of stuff, so if you want to learn different computer science stuff You know making a dwarf fortress like game is a good opportunity to learn all these sort of different fundamental and not so fundamental Algorithms and computer science techniques.
Speaker 1: so even if this project doesn't go anywhere a lot of the listeners gonna learn a lot about coding And like so even right now I mean a lot of them have learned about git at least a little bit.
Speaker 0: That's the thing is I made a how-to to set up the Python environment.
Speaker 0: I made some screencasts there on YouTube, but I got to make some git how-tos because people don't know how to use it.
Speaker 1: really I'm not even I mean even at work.
Speaker 1: We still I use subversion for everything.
Speaker 0: No, so bad you can use git to talk to subversion, then you don't need subversion.
Speaker 0: Yep If you know if the other person refuses to make a git repository you can just use the git client and then with subversion anyway.
Speaker 1: but I mean for now.
Speaker 1: at best I see this being a a Long-term project of becoming eventually a generic fantasy world emulator I don't know if it'll even be a fantasy world, but you know or just a world out an object emulator.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I'm thinking like maybe we should just make an engine and then you could make the game.
Speaker 0: it like you know.
Speaker 0: Take the NS2 path.
Speaker 0: if you make an engine into the game is written in Lua or something.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: the game is separate.
Speaker 0: so then people can make all sorts of dwarf fortress style ish games You know of their choosing.
Speaker 0: maybe elf castle yeah, maybe have like you know some plugins You know.
Speaker 0: so people can make a plugins for it.
Speaker 0: You know like.
Speaker 0: oh, you know here's a weather plug-in.
Speaker 0: Here's a I don't know a. cars driving around on roads plug-in.
Speaker 0: Here's a. here's a train plug-in.
Speaker 0: I'm mostly
Speaker 1: interested in the procedural content generation side of it like the idea that you have Area like areas of a world you know maybe theoretically an infinite world or a large world that are Unexplored and does not computed or computed like abstracted from the point beyond which you've ever experienced them.
Speaker 1: But then once you as a once a human sees or interacts with directly any part that was unexplored it is procedurally generated and then from that point forward is persistent and Part of the world.
Speaker 1: so the world only grows as a human has seen it.
Speaker 1: because until a human sees something there is no reason To actually simulate anything beyond that boundary.
Speaker 1: you might as well Just abstract it and remember everything you've abstracted so that can be made consistent with whatever is quote unquote discovered behind it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right so get on that.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm saying like that because the whole point of my losing should be fun.
Speaker 1: the first time I ran into Pax was the whole idea That procedural content generation is the holy grail right now.
Speaker 1: That'll change everything like it'll.
Speaker 0: just it'll That love FPS game that was procedural and that totally did not work out, so yeah Well because it wasn't.
Speaker 1: it didn't do everything well enough and in the right directions Mmm.
Speaker 0: You even play it did you know?
Speaker 0: so what do you know about it?
Speaker 1: Clearly it didn't.
Speaker 1: you didn't like.
Speaker 0: you seem to like to make a lot of claims about things you'd have been played And don't have you played it?
Speaker 0: I played the outfit.
Speaker 1: it procedurally generate an entire world procedure.
Speaker 0: you generated the game the entire game map.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and was it any fun to play on?
Speaker 1: is anyone talking about it?
Speaker 0: still it wasn't fun for many reasons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and now it's probably gone.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 1: It's around well gone as in no one plays it, but the hardcore elite I don't think anyone plays it then it's not around.
Speaker 1: That's like a tree falling in the woods by itself.
Speaker 1: if an xbox is alone in the woods turned on With one guy playing by himself is he really even there?
Speaker 0: maybe It depends.
Speaker 0: is he online I mean.
Speaker 1: so we've basically stricken the earth in two completely opposite directions And they both involve dwarves in some capacity.
Speaker 0: yeah I just want people to remember that we know when there is internet arguing you should either counter with making something or Just don't and then the internet will be fixed.
Speaker 0: so we can fix the whole internet.
Speaker 1: people and if you want to Help us out with this project dwarf thing.
Speaker 1: We'll send a link.
Speaker 1: Just you know join in.
Speaker 1: it's totally free.
Speaker 1: It's open as MIT.
Speaker 1: if you think as long as your code doesn't suck And you know what if you're if you realize the world dumbasses you can just fork it and go nuts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, do whatever.
Speaker 1: God forking a project this early.
Speaker 1: It's kind of That's like forking hello world.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website At front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.