Speaker 0: It's Monday, June 21st.
Speaker 0: I'm Ram.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: I can't believe we never talked about net neutrality.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: You know, it's.
Speaker 0: I didn't realize this but this is gonna be one of those moments like hey Beatles is spelled like beat in music.
Speaker 1: No, no, it's not even close to that now.
Speaker 1: No, so I didn't realize that summer begins like so late.
Speaker 1: I always thought that I thought it was summer already, but it's not.
Speaker 1: it's Summer now and like last night the Sun was out at like 830.
Speaker 1: It was crazy.
Speaker 0: You know, it's even crazier.
Speaker 0: We live right now right on the far eastern side of this time zone Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: when I was a kid, we lived on the other end of the time zone.
Speaker 0: It's the same time in Detroit that it is here Mmm, so the Sun would be up until about 9.
Speaker 0: Summer days were crazy long and it was awesome.
Speaker 1: Well, it was very dark when you went to school though, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I'd get up for school.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, there's.
Speaker 1: no there's no school on today.
Speaker 1: I hope not.
Speaker 1: that would suck.
Speaker 0: You know, I got this impression.
Speaker 0: You know what though?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know because the Sun was out so much You know what that meant?
Speaker 0: What did that mean?
Speaker 0: It's warm today warm yesterday Warmer today even warmer today.
Speaker 1: No, no, no trouble way Like ten times ten thousand times over nine thousand times.
Speaker 0: I got two of the three aces on right now.
Speaker 1: It was so warm today Rose mom You need like you would need like ten geodudes to cool it down.
Speaker 1: You can't live ten geodude so it's gonna stay warm.
Speaker 0: you got any more any more things to throw in there.
Speaker 1: We used every inside joke or not.
Speaker 0: There's one you're missing.
Speaker 0: what deep in other people.
Speaker 1: No, it's yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Whatever yeah, let's let's get on with it.
Speaker 0: That's what you had.
Speaker 0: You were like, oh don't worry I got an opening but I wanted I wanted to bring back to say at the front of the show Rim, I got it.
Speaker 0: You don't have anything.
Speaker 0: It is all right.
Speaker 0: Well, I gotta bring back blushing over the weekend It was awesome.
Speaker 0: And I went to where the ruins of the world's fair big deal.
Speaker 1: It doesn't compare to warm today, which has to be brought back.
Speaker 0: See I remember at one point we started doing the opposite in the winter.
Speaker 0: I would say, you know warm today and then summer.
Speaker 0: I would say woman.
Speaker 1: No, I don't know.
Speaker 1: this is on record.
Speaker 1: Someone go find out.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: I'm gonna bring it back woman.
Speaker 1: It's warm today So you need to find some other weather related inside.
Speaker 0: You know, it's not gonna do today.
Speaker 0: snow rain Actually, it could rain at any moment in the summer doesn't really fit in the meta moment cuz it's not a geek nights thing It's just a rim thing.
Speaker 0: But I'm gonna be at the sifma conference in New York City on Wednesday, it's going like.
Speaker 1: I don't think I think there will be zero listeners.
Speaker 0: at the same time last year at sifma I tweeted out and a few people responded and I met some people.
Speaker 0: really who is this?
Speaker 0: just some people.
Speaker 0: they're like Yeah, I listen on the forum, you know the answer we always get and they were at sifma.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyone who's a tech or a business person in the financial world is gonna be at sifma.
Speaker 0: All right, at least if you live in New York, not that many companies I think are flying Their people out as many as they used to what with the economy and all ching-ching.
Speaker 0: But actually I'm gonna be there like all day Wednesday except at noon.
Speaker 0: I'm going to a lecture on What caused the flash crash and they're supposedly the the.
Speaker 0: the people who are doing this are gonna go through the tick data like the ticks Like something sold at this price now if they know.
Speaker 1: if they know this Why don't they say now and my see a little blog post why they got to say it then why they holding on to this?
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure like I haven't been following up on the investigations after the flash crash But I'm pretty sure everything I'm about to see is already available and just someone smarter than me is gonna explain to me what?
Speaker 0: It means.
Speaker 0: But they're supposedly gonna go through the data and do some data mining stuff and be like, so here's what happened.
Speaker 0: Like check this out the order of events could have been predicted all this cool math stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and at night I'm going to a lecture and a cocktail thing and the bunch of CEOs are gonna talk about I don't even know what but free drinks.
Speaker 1: Here's what you do right you bring.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna give you some disposable like plus who's a loss?
Speaker 1: no plastic Chinese.
Speaker 1: I should bring my boo boo Zilla The SIFMA.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna bring some plastic Chinese takeout Containers and you're gonna go in and fill them up with catered food and then bring them out and then go back in.
Speaker 1: Come on Why not?
Speaker 0: but I'll be at SIFMA.
Speaker 0: So if any of you are SIFMA types, you know, you're learning about financial sector technology and business and stuff like that I count apparently as a c-level employee.
Speaker 1: What does that mean?
Speaker 0: Basically, they have the demographics of SIFMA and they're like look like two-thirds the people who come are managing directors and one-third are like vice-presidents and you all these corporate titles.
Speaker 0: and then all the rest of the people who go to SIFMA are Class C employees which means any employee who has a stake in the company, but is not Corporate titled.
Speaker 0: No, okay.
Speaker 0: So basically until I become a VP.
Speaker 0: I'm a class C according to SIFMA.
Speaker 1: So there's no A or B. It's just.
Speaker 1: C means not Crap.
Speaker 0: C means rim.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like everyone else is C. There's no D or F below you.
Speaker 1: You're already the C is the lowest.
Speaker 0: I don't know if companies send people at the lower tiers.
Speaker 0: I don't even know there are lower tiers.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess they even let you.
Speaker 1: I mean, that's pretty.
Speaker 1: I mean, why don't they just say boss?
Speaker 0: lower boss not a boss Like a boss, all right.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's it.
Speaker 0: Just it'll be interesting.
Speaker 0: I'll be there.
Speaker 1: Is that your news or is that just such just something?
Speaker 1: Okay, got any news wouldn't shouldn't that be met a moment?
Speaker 0: No, I'd already said why it shouldn't be a met a moment.
Speaker 0: Okay, this is not geek nights.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is not lecturing or doing a panel at SIFMA.
Speaker 1: So it's still opening bit actually.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 1: It's just rim is going to say let's let's do some news here.
Speaker 1: All right, so Barnes & Noble they make the Nook which is the sort of Android ish e-reader thing right it was $200.
Speaker 1: now it's Damn it.
Speaker 1: I mean they dropped that price like a fucking rock.
Speaker 1: The thing.
Speaker 1: Amazon dropped the price of the Kindle to like something else pretty low like 180 something.
Speaker 0: See, here's the problem.
Speaker 0: The only reason I didn't buy one already is that I'm morally convicted about keeping for sale rights.
Speaker 0: yeah, that's the only reason I haven't bought one of these devices.
Speaker 1: and For a hundred bucks you buy something on Steam.
Speaker 1: You don't for sale rice.
Speaker 1: of that I know but I'd say we're a big hypocrite.
Speaker 0: So here's the thing With steam.
Speaker 0: I have no other way to play some of these games.
Speaker 0: I can still buy a book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know what these books a lot of them are a lot cheaper than the same book.
Speaker 1: actually.
Speaker 0: so far They've not been as in every time I've bought a mass-market paperback.
Speaker 0: The Kindle version has been like a dollar cheaper.
Speaker 1: Well, here let me let me use our latest book club as an example.
Speaker 0: When I looked I found the mass-market paperback for $7 $6.99.
Speaker 0: free shipping.
Speaker 1: All right, I found the Kindle one at $7.99 on Amazon, but actually you can get a used one for $0.75.
Speaker 0: Never doing that again.
Speaker 0: the last time I bought a book used on Amazon it came it was readable It was in good condition.
Speaker 0: It smelled like lox.
Speaker 1: It's currently unavailable on the Kindle.
Speaker 1: Oh, so there you go There we go.
Speaker 0: So but anyway the hundred bucks on this thing in the.
Speaker 1: I bought used stuff on Amazon and it's always been pretty good.
Speaker 1: I got a high quality monstrous manual.
Speaker 0: Maybe I just got unlucky.
Speaker 0: I the fact that it smelled like a lox like not like rotten fish book like it smelled like lox.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually, I got a bagel ox and cream cheese on an amazing bagel for five dollars And that came.
Speaker 1: that technically came with a free soda or coffee, but I turned that down.
Speaker 0: really You should take it anyway and give it to the homeless person.
Speaker 1: There was no homeless.
Speaker 0: people around should take it it and then throw it away right there and just laughed at how wonderful capitalism is.
Speaker 1: But there was a cute girl making the bagels.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, you should have taken the free coffee But she she looked like she had plenty of coffee.
Speaker 1: She worked in the bagel place.
Speaker 1: She could have had infinite coffee.
Speaker 0: Are you sure she wasn't learning?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm pretty sure wasn't?
Speaker 0: wasn't a promotion?
Speaker 0: She's like, hey free coffee.
Speaker 1: No, there was.
Speaker 1: it was a big sign.
Speaker 1: outside was five hours big.
Speaker 0: So is that it?
Speaker 0: they're just lowering the prices.
Speaker 1: yeah, but I mean that's kind of a big deal.
Speaker 1: That's a really freakin low price for what you get right?
Speaker 1: I mean the only thing it's lacking real I mean, it doesn't have a very powerful processor or anything But it's powerful enough, you know, the only thing is that these things don't have like, you know, high quality screens.
Speaker 0: They have a reader screen Which actually I would argue are higher quality for certain kinds of reading but much lower quality for other kinds of reading, right?
Speaker 1: But I mean for 150 bucks you can swap out the screen bubble.
Speaker 1: You need to get a video chip in there I don't know, but a hundred bucks what you're not swapping out that screen?
Speaker 1: No but the point is that the price is low enough to where it's sort of worth it to like.
Speaker 1: just buy it and hack the device and do something else with it.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's Android, right?
Speaker 1: So you can go to town at least on the nook which is the cheaper of the two.
Speaker 1: The Kindle is not as cheap.
Speaker 0: See if I bought it for a hundred bucks, you know It's 150.
Speaker 0: I'm saying but if it got to a hundred bucks, which it will I'd use it to read books.
Speaker 0: That's what I want.
Speaker 0: I mean think about it.
Speaker 0: the people who want more than that are gonna buy an iPad and they'll think it's an iPad I can also read.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what's the iPad cost?
Speaker 1: Let's go.
Speaker 0: Yeah People who buy the e-book readers just want them to read books.
Speaker 1: iPad starts at five hundred.
Speaker 1: so for the price of an iPad you can get like three nooks.
Speaker 1: that is pretty bad for the iPad.
Speaker 0: Remember the people who buy the iPad are not buying it for the e-reading.
Speaker 0: They use the e-reading the fact that it can do it to justify the purchase of the iPad because they say yeah It was expensive and it does, you know only these limited things, but it's also an e-reader.
Speaker 0: I didn't have to buy a Kindle.
Speaker 0: So it's like it's a hundred and fifty dollars cheaper.
Speaker 0: So it's $350.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, it's weird though, right?
Speaker 1: is iPad five hundred bucks, right?
Speaker 1: But the iPhone if you get it unlocked is like six seven.
Speaker 1: It's ridiculous price.
Speaker 0: look something Americans always forget about is that miniaturization is very expensive and Even the cheap cell phones are really expensive to manufacture in a lot of cases and they use a lot of very high-end technology.
Speaker 1: But as of today, you can actually get the iBooks on your iPhone or your iPod touch.
Speaker 1: You don't need an iPad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know if I can read something on that small screen for that long.
Speaker 1: Well, but the thing is that the you know It has the higher.
Speaker 1: if you get the iPhone 4 it's got the high-res screen with the 4x pixels.
Speaker 1: true I bet you could read on that motherfucker.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I hope so.
Speaker 1: I bought one.
Speaker 0: good I feel like I'd like the bigger screen anyway for reading a book.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I wouldn't want to pay $500 for because I've always liked the books that have fairly large pages But that are extremely word-dense.
Speaker 1: My problem is you know, you the thing is like I'm not one of those zealots is like I gotta read it on paper.
Speaker 1: Right, you know what the in terms of just the experience forgetting about the DRM or the price or any of that sort of.
Speaker 1: You know meta stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in terms of just the experience of reading the number one thing that the digital readers are missing You know what?
Speaker 0: It is writing notes.
Speaker 1: No They have writing notes.
Speaker 0: They don't work that well.
Speaker 1: It works.
Speaker 1: Yeah bookmarks - they better bookmarks, you know.
Speaker 1: Better book, you know what they're missing.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm doesn't smell good.
Speaker 1: I'm a book smeller Scott.
Speaker 0: So what you should do right?
Speaker 0: buy a pack like a bunch of boosters of like foreign magic cards real cheap and just tape it To my nose every time you go out.
Speaker 0: tape a new freshly open magic card to the back of your nook.
Speaker 1: You know for the that amount of money.
Speaker 1: I might as well just play some fucking CCG.
Speaker 0: I got a bit playing magic.
Speaker 0: that day was pretty fun except that you know The decks were kind of broken and you don't make any decisions after you start playing.
Speaker 1: She just played with some old cards with one of those Methods that what they were talking about were like you have one big deck and everyone shares it and you could you know What are those kind of things?
Speaker 1: There are a lot of.
Speaker 0: you know, very play magic the conquering.
Speaker 0: No one fucking remembers that.
Speaker 0: it came in I think scribe magazine.
Speaker 1: How does that work?
Speaker 0: So it came with this big hex map With land like land like planes and mountains all over it and then the middle was this monolith and I forget the exact rules.
Speaker 0: But you you had your wizard walked around Like he was on a hex.
Speaker 0: you summon a creature they're on a hex they move around on the hexes and You basically have to like conquer land to use it to tap to do shit.
Speaker 1: Why don't we do?
Speaker 1: why don't we make play magic with Dominion rules, right?
Speaker 1: You start you start with it.
Speaker 1: We you start with a deck right and we'll use I don't know like Artifacts as victory points, right?
Speaker 1: So an artifact is worth the number of victory points equal Playing that way.
Speaker 0: Why don't you just play cards use them to be me like rules to kill the other player.
Speaker 1: so everyone gets 20 health and your deck starts with 10 lands and you draw five
Speaker 0: or 10
Speaker 1: lands and like three one one creature if you seven seven lands and three one one creature This
Speaker 0: gets overpowered really quickly because you have enough money to buy a creature like a Siobhan dragon.
Speaker 0: You can just keep whipping that Siobhan dragon out over and over and over again.
Speaker 0: You don't care if it dies.
Speaker 1: So you start the game with.
Speaker 1: yeah The math doesn't work.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I got a couple of quick news is I just want to mention partly because we're trying to kill time before the second half of the show But also because I think they're worth talking about.
Speaker 0: So there was a internet shitstorm and a little bit of a kind of real-world shitstorm about the fact that the Utah Attorney General tweeted the orders to execute someone which While some people said was in bad taste.
Speaker 0: I say why is one medium any different than any other medium?
Speaker 1: Oh, you put it in the newspaper.
Speaker 1: That's tasteful.
Speaker 1: He did it on TV.
Speaker 1: That's not.
Speaker 0: I mean go back to the year 15.
Speaker 0: Whatever is like how dare they record?
Speaker 1: I don't know how dare they announce it on the radio?
Speaker 0: So one I said 1500 and two, I don't know why there was no radio in 1500.
Speaker 0: Why either one of us did that accent.
Speaker 0: that has nothing to do with 1500 cuz that's how they talked in the radio.
Speaker 0: Everyone from any year before 1930 talked.
Speaker 1: how dare they?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean, you know 1500.
Speaker 1: I don't think they spoke English.
Speaker 0: I'm sure he thought no they definitely did because he fit it into the hundred fifty characters.
Speaker 0: I just gave the go-ahead to Corrections director to proceed with gardeners execution.
Speaker 0: May God grant him the mercy.
Speaker 0: denied his victims Mm-hmm, and it was retweeted.
Speaker 0: There's all sorts of chaos about it, but I It's weird.
Speaker 0: I want to bring this up just to say that it's not newsworthy.
Speaker 0: that it was newsworthy like this is just.
Speaker 0: you know This is national extension.
Speaker 0: Twitter like things are a means of communication and the only reason they're not respected now.
Speaker 1: He texted it.
Speaker 0: Oh, no is because We broke up over.
Speaker 0: I am.
Speaker 0: what did will right say over and over again people don't Respect any new form of media until all the people who were around before it existed die.
Speaker 0: And then once it's just commonplace people don't think of it any differently from any other media.
Speaker 0: Yep, so video games people some people still don't respect them.
Speaker 0: Twitter's the same way that newfangled radio there.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's not older than me.
Speaker 1: Therefore.
Speaker 0: I don't respect it which comes into the same because there's another article I want to mention briefly that's related to this.
Speaker 0: There's this whole thing on.
Speaker 0: it was linked to on slash job about how according to a recent study Engineers the vast majority of them don't use Twitter and personally dislike Twitter and a lot of people hate on Twitter.
Speaker 0: I mean everyone out in the air.
Speaker 0: There's blogs like oh Twitter.
Speaker 0: I don't care about what kind of sandwich you ate today.
Speaker 0: and so far.
Speaker 0: This is a statistic that is completely accurate that I made up right now of the people who complain about Twitter.
Speaker 0: Don't understand what Twitter is and her complaint.
Speaker 0: It'd be like me complaining.
Speaker 0: I'm trying to think of a good example.
Speaker 1: It'd be like playing counters when rim said he didn't need tabs in his web browser.
Speaker 0: No It's more like if I started playing Said he didn't need a camera in his phone if I started.
Speaker 0: that it's not in any way related.
Speaker 0: It's not about needing.
Speaker 0: Say they don't need it.
Speaker 0: They're saying they don't like it.
Speaker 1: primarily You said you didn't like having a camera in the phone.
Speaker 0: Actually, I didn't because I wasn't allowed to have a camera at work.
Speaker 1: So you also didn't like it.
Speaker 0: in addition to that now because I couldn't bring my camera every day when I got to work I'd take my fucking cell phone and give it to the security guard and I had to get it back when I left because cameras Were banned from my facility.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it sucked.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that was in addition to you also Expressing dislike with the camera.
Speaker 0: No, not really.
Speaker 0: I mean the camera my phone was shady.
Speaker 0: I never used it.
Speaker 1: back then You didn't use it when you didn't have it.
Speaker 0: No, I had it.
Speaker 0: that I didn't use it because it took shitty pictures.
Speaker 0: It wasn't easy to get the pictures off.
Speaker 1: That's enough of this anyway.
Speaker 0: most of the complaints about Twitter are people who are basically saying There is spam on Twitter and I go actively seek it out and read it in order to complain about it.
Speaker 0: Like don't these people realize?
Speaker 0: you only see the tweets of people you subscribe to?
Speaker 1: it's the same shit with the people who are like You know, oh my god, they publish my email address.
Speaker 1: It's a privacy violation.
Speaker 1: It's like so the phone book wasn't.
Speaker 0: I mean I'm not gonna go that way.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's the same situation here.
Speaker 0: It's just very specifically the issue that there is a medium whereby you subscribe.
Speaker 0: You say I want X in front.
Speaker 1: if someone says that it's because they don't understand how email works.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, the whole world got me email address.
Speaker 1: So you just make a fucking filter and you report a spam and you have a spam filter and no one who ever you know No one will be able to email you and they won't be able to do anything else.
Speaker 1: to you having your email address means nothing.
Speaker 1: They can't do anything to you at all period.
Speaker 1: All right Same with Twitter.
Speaker 1: if you don't follow the spammers They can't do anything to you period.
Speaker 1: your lack of understanding of technology is what opens you up to getting abused by the technology.
Speaker 0: I just want to leave the email example off because this is so much more direct.
Speaker 0: It's not like you know.
Speaker 0: with email at least someone can send you, you know, whatever filters you have There's a tiny possibility someone could send you an email that is bullshit that you didn't want and it got to you somehow.
Speaker 1: Actually this lately.
Speaker 1: They're actually the Gmail spam filters been getting a little weak.
Speaker 0: I've gotten about one spam every few days for the pad like just recently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just very very recently I think someone figured out a trick that will soon be unfigured out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but at least you know There's the tiny chance that like one spam will get through every now and then because there is still the capability for push Mm-hmm, but with Twitter, it's just pull.
Speaker 0: if you ever see a tweet that you didn't care about it is your dumbass fault.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 1: Sometimes I used to have a policy if you follow me, I'll follow you.
Speaker 0: I stopped that a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Stop that policy.
Speaker 0: I heard a lot of people's feelings when I unfollowed them all at once.
Speaker 1: I don't even how do people even know if you get unfollowed?
Speaker 1: It doesn't tell you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it does.
Speaker 0: You can tell it.
Speaker 1: to tell you I've never gotten it.
Speaker 1: It never tells me.
Speaker 1: anyway I unfollowed a whole bunch of people recently, but if I get a spam, right like someone adds me a spam Oh, I just block him without even thinking.
Speaker 1: Oh, there's a button in tweet deck that says block and report as spam.
Speaker 0: Oh, I don't have a report as spam button.
Speaker 1: I click that mofo right away.
Speaker 1: I had no prejudice.
Speaker 1: one guy He was.
Speaker 1: he was he was a real person.
Speaker 1: He was trying to like.
Speaker 1: he was like a job recruiter.
Speaker 1: He was like, hey you want to give me your phone number?
Speaker 1: We could talk.
Speaker 0: and I was like, eh So, how do you how do you get you?
Speaker 0: did he at you?
Speaker 1: I think you just look for technology people on Twitter.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: See here's the other thing.
Speaker 0: I don't read ads except when I'm at a convention or something.
Speaker 0: I never read ads.
Speaker 1: I have all these columns and stuff.
Speaker 1: What I do is I columns are actually pretty good because I have a geek nights column and I got a column.
Speaker 1: That's so I can see whatever your tell.
Speaker 1: whoever like.
Speaker 1: I can follow you and I have a column so I can see Anything you say and anything anyone says to you.
Speaker 0: Only read Twitter.
Speaker 0: really for the few people I follow and to self organize when I'm out in public at conventions and stuff.
Speaker 0: So I use all those like.
Speaker 0: I set up all the columns and timelines and everything like before packs.
Speaker 0: I think I rid of them all or turn them all off after packs because normally I only read the tweets from people.
Speaker 0: I Actually actively follow.
Speaker 0: Yeah But it just it.
Speaker 0: it amazes me that to this day so many people who complain about Twitter are basically All they're really saying is I'm a dumbass who doesn't understand this and I'm going to complain about it.
Speaker 1: It's a new fangled thing.
Speaker 0: I don't like it And the examples in this article are just hilarious.
Speaker 0: So what like the slash shot article actually links to like, you know Most tweets are useless crap like this and they link to this guy's Twitter and he tweeted and I quote Go That's a great tweet when he's talking about his team price scored.
Speaker 0: bang our hashtag.
Speaker 0: por, you know Portugal.
Speaker 0: I love my country.
Speaker 0: I love my team heart.
Speaker 0: OMG comma OMG OMG Portugal.
Speaker 1: Dude about some Portugal.
Speaker 1: that might be mad my tweet.
Speaker 0: I might start following this guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I followed Vibhu Zilla for a while.
Speaker 1: It's also I followed that go go 13.
Speaker 0: Oh go go 13 is one of my all he ever says is that that that?
Speaker 0: yeah Occasionally, he'll add it someone and he'll just still say dot that that do Togo that that that.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, but I have a real news.
Speaker 1: That wasn't the real news.
Speaker 0: That was all just fluff.
Speaker 0: We're trying to kill time.
Speaker 1: It's taking a long time here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well you wanted me to.
Speaker 0: do you want me to not use the real news?
Speaker 0: Yeah so we don't have to talk about this too long because I don't care about the details because I have funny things to say.
Speaker 0: so the article is VLC 1.1 Has to stop allowing Shoutcast support.
Speaker 1: why?
Speaker 0: because AOL won't let them anymore.
Speaker 0: now that I'm Question the first what the fuck shoutcast?
Speaker 0: and question the second what the fuck is AOL?
Speaker 1: Well shoutcast is.
Speaker 0: I know what shoutcast is 100 years old.
Speaker 1: who cares about shoutcast and who cares about AOL I think a lot of people.
Speaker 0: actually this article was like out of the early 2000s.
Speaker 0: It talks about shoutcast about nullsoft video land AOL It this is crazy, but apparently here's the deal.
Speaker 0: so Shoutcast you can like.
Speaker 0: there's a license where you can use it, right?
Speaker 1: I didn't.
Speaker 1: I thought it was open.
Speaker 0: I guess it's not completely open but the license is there.
Speaker 0: VLC was using it.
Speaker 0: Apparently the terms of the license don't allow you to use it in a project that itself has a viral license to make things more open Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So basically in other words, it's non GPL compatible.
Speaker 0: Yes, but the the language of it.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna bother quoting and everything, but it's almost as though and I wonder if we're gonna start seeing more of this.
Speaker 0: They have made shoutcast very specifically free as in beer and not just not free as in speech But against free as in speech.
Speaker 0: that basically imagine if you have a reverse GPL.
Speaker 0: a license says you can use this for free But you can never use it with or in relation to any open source thing Or anything that requires something to be open source or anything viral.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter because you can just see.
Speaker 1: the problem is only the GPL is viral.
Speaker 1: None of the open source licenses have the viral nature of them.
Speaker 1: So you could just use the MIT license of the BSD license.
Speaker 1: But the thing is it's a lot of difficulty for VLC to switch.
Speaker 1: if they would have started out that way They'd be all good.
Speaker 1: But now to switch is a huge legal pain in the ass.
Speaker 0: Yeah basically The license clause prohibits the prohibits the redistribution of shoutcast with any product whose own license requires that it be quote Disclosed or distributed in source code form license for the purposes of making derivative works or redistributable at no charge.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe AOL will fix it or now not out.
Speaker 0: That's all you know part of this.
Speaker 0: That's just.
Speaker 0: it's an interesting idea that people might start making kind of like you can.
Speaker 0: you can make viral Licenses to do all sorts of crazy stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like you can only use the software if you include a picture of your own penis and remember postcard wear.
Speaker 1: It's like if you use this send me a postcard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I like that sort of concept though But at the same time it comes down to the whole thing of our eulas and things like that binding or not?
Speaker 0: Because if they are you've got to send the postcard.
Speaker 0: you're breaking the law and if they're not it's it's open season on everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well this is you know lately I've been sorry.
Speaker 1: It's it's weird.
Speaker 1: It's like You know, you look at the GPL and it's like well if we don't if everyone used MIT and BSD license stuff Right, then, you know, for example of Linux We're not GPL right.
Speaker 1: a lot of the contributions to Linux come from say Nvidia and Red Hat and these IBM and real companies.
Speaker 1: right, so if Linux kernel were MIT licensed would and videos still help, you know Submit their patches back to Linux kernel or would they just maintain their own branch?
Speaker 1: Would they?
Speaker 1: you know, you don't know.
Speaker 1: so the GPL sort of makes sure that they have to do the first which is good.
Speaker 1: But on the other hand, it's like, okay nothing I'm gonna do is gonna have a GPL license.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna use MIT license.
Speaker 1: go nuts, you know, if you want to use my code, you know for whatever you want to do It's it's just free party to think.
Speaker 0: it's the idea that you know, we want things to be open and free.
Speaker 0: But something you know, there's the two alternate philosophies.
Speaker 0: one hand It's make everything free and just let's have fun and the other idea is Make everything free But not completely free because we're gonna use the fact that we can control the freedom to force other people to make things more Free, so I'm a little less free, but I force other people to be a little more free and it's 50/50.
Speaker 0: I'm completely ambivalent.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we wouldn't be like without the GPL.
Speaker 1: We wouldn't be hacking any routers or anything, you know.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, it's just interesting.
Speaker 0: but there's a second part of this apparently that license for the furthest video land, you know stuff.
Speaker 0: video land would be forced to bundle some nullsoft adware if They continued to use shoutcast.
Speaker 1: Why?
Speaker 1: Do that which?
Speaker 0: it scares me nullsoft adware?
Speaker 0: remember when nullsoft was the good guys and then AOL bought them like the worst possible outcome.
Speaker 0: Yep, nullsoft are the same people mean they made winamp.
Speaker 1: They've revolutionized a lot of the internet and pretty much when in the windows days Right in like, you know the late 90s Like about a decade ago you had a Windows computer and you had pretty much a nullsoft suite and that was that was your computer.
Speaker 1: You had every nullsoft thing.
Speaker 1: you had a new teller you had a winamp you had a whole thing going on And that was that was your computer.
Speaker 1: But anyway things of the day All right, so I just read this article here.
Speaker 1: It's actually a PDF which is annoying.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry, right, but basically this guy says pi is wrong.
Speaker 1: So immediately you're like No Not wrong it right.
Speaker 1: But then he goes on and he's like really I'm not saying that pi is not irrational I'm not saying pi is not transcended and I'm not saying the numerical calculation of pi is incorrect.
Speaker 1: What he's saying is that instead, you know pi Should mean two pi it should be three is six point two, whatever whatever and not three point one, whatever whatever right and I can.
Speaker 1: at first I was like, ah, that sounds good to me.
Speaker 1: but then on second thought I was like that doesn't sound good to me because All right You know if you take pi and multiply it by I you get a crazy fucked up number.
Speaker 1: And then if you take e a crazy fucked up number to that power you get negative one, which is awesome Which is amazing.
Speaker 1: the I Two pi, you know what that is, huh?
Speaker 1: One.
Speaker 1: No, so that turned me back around.
Speaker 1: I was like, oh it should be two.
Speaker 0: What about radians?
Speaker 0: What about the radius based math?
Speaker 1: Well, that's just the thing right?
Speaker 0: It's like I are squared That's true.
Speaker 1: But if you think about it, right you have a circle, right?
Speaker 1: So a circle is two pi right and half the circle is one pi.
Speaker 1: So if we had the whole circle if we switch if we replaced pi with two pi So right then a quarter of the circle would be 1/4 pi and a half a circle would be 1/2 pi and a 3/4 of a circle would be 3/4 pi.
Speaker 1: and that would actually be like Yeah, kind of makes more sense and it would be easier to teach kids.
Speaker 0: Would it be really easier to teach kids though?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm pretty sure it would be.
Speaker 0: I Don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't think I'm sorry.
Speaker 1: I think I'm sort of liking the 2 pi but I'm also not completely liking the 2 pi.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like no.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: No, you know, this is one of those rare situations where I think a forum poll Is the best way to go.
Speaker 1: that should we replace pi with two pi so that you know pi better is high.
Speaker 1: No longer means three point one four one five nine, but it now means six point two eight three Sign three point one four one five nine pi I times three.
Speaker 0: Let's go.
Speaker 0: We totally stole this from MIT.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: so This is just beautiful because we talk a lot or at least.
Speaker 0: we used to talk a lot about fonts and how people don't put Enough thought into typography.
Speaker 1: I try to put thought into photography, but I don't Typography, but I don't know shit about it.
Speaker 1: So I fuck it up.
Speaker 0: But in general like good fonts can make an already good thing look so much better.
Speaker 0: Like it's one of the reasons why Apple stuff just looks.
Speaker 1: they're the only ones who actually care about fonts for reals.
Speaker 0: So if a lot of people didn't believe us or they railed on us or they argued with us.
Speaker 0: Behold this picture.
Speaker 0: if there is ever a real a rationale for thinking about what font to use this picture epitomizes it in one glorious but related word Would it be Uranus?
Speaker 0: it's some kind of fantasy?
Speaker 1: I love me a Uranus joke.
Speaker 0: So the meta moment, I guess we should get into that.
Speaker 0: Oh notice I'm not gonna talk about sifma here because geek night doesn't get on.
Speaker 1: kinetic on is July 9th and such all right.
Speaker 1: so go to Hartford Connecticut And we will be there in charge of panels, and we're doing panels, and it's gonna be crazy.
Speaker 1: good nut go nuts.
Speaker 1: awesome.
Speaker 1: There's awesome gaming awesome everything.
Speaker 1: yep The current book club book selection is the lies of Locke Lamora by Scott Lynch.
Speaker 1: It is a fun part of time fantasy ish novel.
Speaker 0: I haven't read it yet Scott did.
Speaker 0: I'm ordering on Amazon tonight.
Speaker 1: You don't want me to just lend it to you.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you want to lend it to me I guess I'm not.
Speaker 1: I already read it.
Speaker 0: so all right give it to me.
Speaker 1: save you some money.
Speaker 0: It's like it to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right I don't.
Speaker 0: we have much other matter.
Speaker 1: No do we have any other matter now?
Speaker 1: We got sex is Labor Day weekend.
Speaker 1: Holy shit back Seattle.
Speaker 0: I got the hotel.
Speaker 0: we get our plane tickets.
Speaker 1: actually my dad said he would.
Speaker 1: he has a zillion miles.
Speaker 1: We can't.
Speaker 1: he doesn't have any jet blue miles, but we might be able to go for free on a non jet blue, so I mean I would prefer jet blue, but if it's free.
Speaker 1: I would go on a shit airline if it's zero dollars.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yep, so I'll see.
Speaker 1: if he can.
Speaker 0: you know cuz my experiences with continental are always super nice.
Speaker 0: It's just I'm gonna see.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna see if there's like a Virgin America Option cuz they have the Wi-Fi and shit, but you can't fly your Lufthansa or anything.
Speaker 1: well I don't think Lufthansa goes to Seattle now.
Speaker 1: probably be like us air American air Delta.
Speaker 0: We're not flying us air.
Speaker 0: the odds are those.
Speaker 0: leave us behind.
Speaker 0: They've had some trouble lately.
Speaker 0: I don't trust him.
Speaker 0: I'll see what I would rather pay than fly us air free.
Speaker 1: Well, you know it's a lot of monies to save so I don't care.
Speaker 0: I've been fucked by us air three times in my life.
Speaker 1: I've been fucked by everyone.
Speaker 0: I've never flown us air and not been fucked by them in some manner.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'll call him and I'll see what the deal is.
Speaker 0: so we'll get some us air or your dad my dad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can call us air.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 0: cuz we I want to get the plane tickets early.
Speaker 0: We waited a little too long for the packs.
Speaker 0: plane tickets last.
Speaker 1: yeah, all right.
Speaker 1: I'll call them.
Speaker 0: You guys should go to packs.
Speaker 0: We're doing at least a couple of panels and something else secret and awesome.
Speaker 0: That's still in the works that we can't announce yet that we're still working on secret mode.
Speaker 0: I was just I was as vague as possible there.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I don't know Any other metas?
Speaker 0: I think that's it.
Speaker 0: you stream comes and goes when we feel like it go to front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm It's our website.
Speaker 0: Yeah, join the forum forums awesome.
Speaker 0: So net neutrality okay, I can't believe.
Speaker 0: we we I think we talked.
Speaker 1: we've talked about it on the show enough.
Speaker 1: I think this is sort of a rerun we have own.
Speaker 0: We've never done a show about network neutrality and in fact We have only done three shows in the history of geek nights where the word neutrality appears in Any part of the text associated with the episode.
Speaker 1: I feel like we've talked about it so much.
Speaker 0: Well if we have we either didn't type it in or your search is broken if it's a rerun.
Speaker 1: We've done how many hundreds of episodes without reruns?
Speaker 0: so on Monday to December 15th 2008 we had a news about net neutrality.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: No one understands what it means okay?
Speaker 1: What was the main bit in that episode?
Speaker 0: Uh let's see Kindles and things.
Speaker 1: well so in this show We did a news about Kindles and things.
Speaker 0: well now.
Speaker 0: We're gonna.
Speaker 1: It's the reverse shows.
Speaker 1: come folks.
Speaker 0: It's the reverse show.
Speaker 1: reverse show plus.
Speaker 0: that was in December.
Speaker 0: so now.
Speaker 0: We're in June Six months apart.
Speaker 1: all right for us.
Speaker 1: the reverse show inverse geek nights.
Speaker 0: Anyway on July 5th 2006 we talked about Google talking about network neutrality as a news and on July 3rd 2006 we made fun of Ted Stevens Because he didn't know what tubes were.
Speaker 0: yes now He knew what tubes were.
Speaker 0: he didn't know what an internet was.
Speaker 1: well apparently didn't know.
Speaker 1: maybe he was right about what an internet Was and wrong about what tubes were.
Speaker 1: you don't know.
Speaker 0: maybe maybe he was wrong about both.
Speaker 1: So so a cat is a series of uvulas.
Speaker 1: You obviously don't know what a uvula is.
Speaker 1: Anyway the so net neutralities.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna straight up.
Speaker 0: This is an issue that see it seems like only technology professionals and even then only a small subset of technology professionals Understand and care about the issue.
Speaker 0: now That's key because there are techs who understand it and don't give a shit, and there are people who give a shit But don't understand it.
Speaker 0: hmm But I feel like only telecommunications people and then a small subset of other people in the tech world understand it and everyone else Seems to always fall back on arguments about well Where does it say that they have to be neutral?
Speaker 0: and our point is that it doesn't and it should?
Speaker 1: well I mean, that's just something that's in general on the internet right.
Speaker 1: is that people especially if they're lawyers or lawyer types Right or like D&D types.
Speaker 1: You know like law and books with rules in them.
Speaker 1: They have a hard time Separating a discussion about what's right and wrong and what's legal and illegal.
Speaker 1: you'd be like I think X is wrong, and they'll be like well.
Speaker 1: Where does it say that X is is illegal?
Speaker 1: I'd be like I didn't say that X is legal or illegal.
Speaker 1: I'm only discussing whether I think it's right or wrong.
Speaker 1: What does the law have to do with it?
Speaker 1: nothing?
Speaker 1: I mean are we gonna go back to 1920?
Speaker 1: you know and I'm gonna say I?
Speaker 1: Think that you should allow the colored people to sit at Walgreens.
Speaker 0: You'd be like Where does it say that the Constitution?
Speaker 1: kind of kind of right people were but you understand.
Speaker 1: my point is that they right.
Speaker 1: so You study.
Speaker 1: there's nothing to do with law right and that's part of.
Speaker 1: actually the issue is that there is no law whatsoever.
Speaker 1: the internet Is completely unregulated almost completely unregulated and part of this problem is well?
Speaker 1: It's unregulated which is good for us right?
Speaker 1: so Wild West we can do the stuff We want to do on the internet freedom.
Speaker 1: At the same time the evil businesses can do what they want to do on the internet Which is anti freedom.
Speaker 1: so should we make some laws to keep those businesses in line and regulation?
Speaker 1: But no that regulation will also take away our freedom, so it's like god There's evil businesses doing things to take away freedom.
Speaker 1: How can we stop them?
Speaker 1: the only way to stop them for sure is to have the government take away freedom.
Speaker 1: It's like no.
Speaker 0: And even then you know we say the evil companies.
Speaker 0: But I still think that much of the internet if not most of the internet at least you know what people define as the internet Should be pretty much completely unregulated.
Speaker 1: Wild West yeah Because I mean it's only the only companies that are really evil.
Speaker 1: right in terms of internets are Companies.
Speaker 1: that for example Cisco right, but it's Cisco evil not to us.
Speaker 1: But they're evil that they help China do censorship right.
Speaker 1: and then you also have evil like Time Warner.
Speaker 1: They will blow our Comcast.
Speaker 1: They will block your torrents and throttle you and that is evil.
Speaker 1: But no one else is really even.
Speaker 1: what about what everyone else on the internet is not evil?
Speaker 0: well Not necessarily evil It's just.
Speaker 0: it's evil I'm willing to put up with because the internet has shown me over the years that it Flourishes best when no one has any way to tell anyone else what to do except by force.
Speaker 1: yeah But they're not.
Speaker 1: eat their own bones.
Speaker 1: No one else is evil in a routing way.
Speaker 0: well in general Technological solutions solve problems on the internet much more readily than legal solutions Do.
Speaker 0: oh yeah because the but the end of then.
Speaker 0: again it shouldn't be this way.
Speaker 0: It's only this way because the law can't keep up and the people who make the laws Often have a vested interest or a secondary vested interest by way or no knowledge in maintaining.
Speaker 0: and But the part when we say net neutrality.
Speaker 0: when I say net neutrality, I mean we're technology professionals.
Speaker 0: I'm a senior engineer in the financial sector in telecommunications Fancy.
Speaker 0: yeah, like you know it's like I don't make too much of it, but we're professionals like.
Speaker 0: this is our professional opinion.
Speaker 0: This isn't like when we talk about any other topic when we're just two guys like.
Speaker 0: we talk about anime.
Speaker 0: We like anime.
Speaker 0: we talk about anime a lot.
Speaker 0: We don't make it.
Speaker 0: We do anime panels.
Speaker 0: We but we're not like Industry professionals.
Speaker 0: really when it comes to anime we talk out of our asses a lot And again we talk more out of our asses the further from our realms of professionalism that we get.
Speaker 0: we talk about Astrophysics.
Speaker 0: you all have seen the results.
Speaker 0: Oh you use your appeal to authority over not quite okay, but in my Technology professionalistic opinion, I guess I meant to say technologically professional opinion.
Speaker 0: We need network neutrality.
Speaker 0: You know not network neutrality.
Speaker 0: We're not talking about the internet.
Speaker 0: We don't need like neutrality on the internet and this ephemeral thing because the internet is just a series of interconnected internet works.
Speaker 0: We need neutrality on the base plane the actual like low-level network the stuff that connects stuff all the glue of the internet Should be neutral should be dumb At least dumb in terms of the content.
Speaker 0: It should be a hundred percent agnostic to the content going over it and it should just be a kind of vast plane or us Wild west people ride across and shoot Buffalo.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm and anything less than that is a recipe for disaster.
Speaker 1: I mean the whole issue started right where.
Speaker 1: basically, you know We pay your ISP, right?
Speaker 1: You pay your ISP to get a connection to the internet and you give lay a flat rate for unlimited or in some countries Bet.
Speaker 1: you pay for a certain amount of bandwidth depending on where you are.
Speaker 1: Maybe you pay for more speed or who knows what and you're connected and when you're connected you can go to any website.
Speaker 1: You know, you can do anything.
Speaker 1: you can go to any RSC server You can.
Speaker 1: you can route your pat You can send any packet to any IP address and any packet they send back to you will get to you unless you're in China.
Speaker 0: Now they can choose not to listen to you.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: and those Pat and all the routers in between you and them will make a you know a best effort to get those packets to You as quickly as possible.
Speaker 0: and they have to.
Speaker 0: yes, the middle should have to deliver messages Now.
Speaker 0: it does get tricky really because there are situations where temporarily for the greater good of a network Someone would want to.
Speaker 1: that's not that you know, it's not a best.
Speaker 1: It's a best effort right if it's broken?
Speaker 1: Well, I made my best effort.
Speaker 1: It's broken.
Speaker 1: I couldn't do it So it didn't happen.
Speaker 1: but the issue started where some of the ISP said hey look at this.
Speaker 1: right on this side We got customers connecting and paying us to go to send their packets on our networks.
Speaker 1: But on the other side Google is sending packets over our networks and they're not paying us anything.
Speaker 1: So anyone who sends a packet over our network, they got to pay and that was what they said in the first.
Speaker 1: That was their original Instigation of this issue.
Speaker 0: now there already is a lot of paying.
Speaker 0: I mean the internet.
Speaker 0: we people like to think of it as a big web, you know the internet routes around trouble but really Most of the traffic flows in the United States and flows through a very small number of very important nodes and data centers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like there's a big old sprint link.
Speaker 1: That's like this gigantic, you know, five The internet.
Speaker 0: there's a difference between an internet lowercase I and the internet uppercase I. The internet is composed of a bunch of networks that all connect to each other and internet works.
Speaker 0: So someone owns like a big network and some you know packets have to get from Google to me.
Speaker 0: They might go through Joe's network or Bob's network and the internet only works because Joe and Bob Agree to let anything that comes in from networks They're connected to through.
Speaker 0: but it was a turn.
Speaker 0: they can send anything they want to send through everyone else's network.
Speaker 1: There's a great talk I think it might have been a TED talk where this guy goes up and he's like who is hitchhiked in their lives.
Speaker 1: and they Were old people.
Speaker 1: so they raised their hands like who's hitchhiked recently and Nova almost nobody.
Speaker 1: and he's like who would hitch who would hitchhike?
Speaker 1: And almost nobody.
Speaker 1: so he's like, alright So the thing is on the internet.
Speaker 1: you hitchhike every day.
Speaker 1: You basically hand off your packets to someone and then you trust someone else with your packets and you trust that they're gonna get them.
Speaker 1: That's like just taking your mail out to the street.
Speaker 1: some cars are driving by.
Speaker 1: you say hey, man You want to take this to Texas for me and they say I'm not going to Texas But I'll hand it to some other car.
Speaker 1: I want to get close close to Texas as I'm gonna get You know and eventually your letter gets to Texas.
Speaker 1: and you know in the real world, would your letter get to Texas?
Speaker 1: Probably not.
Speaker 1: Would you do that?
Speaker 1: in the internet It's the only internet.
Speaker 1: everything you do is exactly like that and it works.
Speaker 0: But the only reason things get there is because by and large everyone in between is not a jerk and not a dumbass.
Speaker 1: Yep Now people if we lose sometimes in someone's a dumbass you get trouble like when Pakistan screwed YouTube But or when your packets come back to you Right, and sometimes someone's a jerk like when China blocks everything.
Speaker 0: Now we can't talk about the rest of the world.
Speaker 0: We can really.
Speaker 0: you know net neutrality right now is an issue only in the United States.
Speaker 0: We live in the United States the rest of the world.
Speaker 0: You have to have your own debates as to what your society wants its internet to be.
Speaker 0: But we have the biggest internet.
Speaker 1: we have all the Internet's most of it.
Speaker 1: Most of the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, so it's this is that we invented the internet.
Speaker 0: We're really only talking about like internal to the US but I really like Cellphone providers are the worst example of this because they already violate all sorts of these principles and I feel like really data Communication infrastructure is as important as electrical infrastructure and water infrastructure in the modern industrialized world.
Speaker 0: Yeah Pretty much stream of data coming into my house right now has more impact on my life than the water and the electricity.
Speaker 0: Well, I need the electricity to get the data, but I could use my laptop for quite some time and still get internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, but the thing is need electricity for your router to work.
Speaker 0: I could plug it into my UPS.
Speaker 0: I like eight hours.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, I use the internet in beacon a couple times when the power was out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I know the files equipment beyond the router is all UPS.
Speaker 0: There's a giant battery in my closet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it has to be because there's a law that says because it's 9-1-1 because files is also telephone Yep, so they battery that shit up.
Speaker 0: But the cell phone providers like for example, all right It's just data and I've ever all the data we're sending around is just data.
Speaker 0: But then they said you know what we're gonna treat some data differently from other data.
Speaker 0: We're gonna let it be free.
Speaker 0: if you send voice data to people on our network We're gonna make you pay minutes if you send voice data to people outside of our network.
Speaker 0: Mmm, and we don't stand for that bullshit on the internet.
Speaker 0: So why do we accept?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you think you know, I go to a website.
Speaker 1: Well, this is a Time Warner website.
Speaker 1: So it's free.
Speaker 1: Oh you visited a website that was on.
Speaker 1: you know, someone was on Comcast with that Website, so we're gonna charge you money.
Speaker 1: They don't do that shit there.
Speaker 1: I would never get away with that in a million years.
Speaker 1: All right, but how did they get away with it on cell phone?
Speaker 0: Well, I think part of it is that because the internet is much more open and there's so much room to move around That a lot of interesting things were happening.
Speaker 1: So rapidly devolved so rapidly and it's like the you know, you think oh What's the difference with the cell phone carriers?
Speaker 1: Well, they have the last mile thing.
Speaker 1: They own all these towers.
Speaker 1: Uh, the cable guys have just as much of a Napoli on the last mile as the cell phone guys do In fact, a lot of the times of the same exact guys.
Speaker 1: Verizon, right?
Speaker 0: The thing is we're luck where the only reason things work now is that we're lucky that the last mile providers have not decided to Be jerks yet.
Speaker 0: Yep, but some of them have and some of them want to yep.
Speaker 0: And I just I feel very strongly that we need a completely open completely dumb at least in terms of the idea of what is being transported over the networks like baseline infrastructure and ISPs that are last mile like, you know, I get my internet from Verizon.
Speaker 0: They should be subject to very strenuous Regulation to prevent them.
Speaker 1: the thing is if we if we open up the doors to allow them to be regulated Then you open up the doors to bad regulation of you know The government is gonna decide some regulation and then we're not going to be able to.
Speaker 1: there'll be some technological solution But we can't do it because the government regulation conflicts with it.
Speaker 1: and then how it's gonna be Terrible.
Speaker 1: see me the worst thing ever.
Speaker 0: well part of this is a situation of a lot of the people who are afraid of a collapse of net neutrality are all afraid of Different things even though not all those things are equally likely.
Speaker 0: and the industry people who might not want net neutrality or might want it Also all have very different motivations.
Speaker 0: some people don't want regulation so that they can be evil because they're not regulated and some people don't Want regulation because they're being evil and regulation would stop them.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I generally don't trust the FCC that much to be perfectly honest.
Speaker 1: We just we need some way to like Guaranteed freedom without opening up the door to any badness and it's interesting You know guaranteeing freedom because look at a whole a wholly separate debate.
Speaker 0: That is still very important and a lot of people conflate piracy with this even though it's not really true.
Speaker 0: but in the Napster days and when you know people started sharing media on a Massive scale the fight wasn't really.
Speaker 0: don't let them pirate or I'll be our business will disappear.
Speaker 0: The fight was don't let them have the ability to share information easily with each other Because eventually they'll start making content on their own and giving it to each other for free and destroy us.
Speaker 0: The piracy wasn't what the industry is really really afraid of and a lot of like real networks.
Speaker 0: back in the day They were pretty much pushing for lockdown computers not to stop piracy like that was the the stated goal.
Speaker 0: But really it was more the idea that lockdown computers make it more difficult for you to be a publisher on your own.
Speaker 1: Apple Apple gives you some tools of production.
Speaker 0: We're seeing this now in a lot of industry.
Speaker 0: like the anime.
Speaker 0: industry is being crushed not by piracy anymore.
Speaker 0: If all the piracy disappeared, no one's gonna buy DVDs.
Speaker 0: They're crushed by the fact that there's so much totally legal free stuff out there that no one's willing to pay There's.
Speaker 1: so you never see us using like a real movie is the thing of the day.
Speaker 1: It's always some YouTube movie and that's what we entertain ourselves.
Speaker 1: You know, it's never a TV show, right?
Speaker 1: It's always something some guy made on the internet just like it tonight something some guy made on the internet Which you are listening to as opposed to listening to you know Howard Stern or some other radio thing you could be listening to.
Speaker 0: I personally don't pirate any media because I have enough free media to Keep me happy for most of the rest of my life already and what little I can't get free I buy.
Speaker 0: but other than that everything else that I don't buy it's not like I would have bought it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right nothing Nothing, no force in the world could make me buy it except I guess if YouTube disappeared I might have to start buying media again for a little while.
Speaker 1: I mean like.
Speaker 1: I pirate like almost nothing but anything that I download Legally or illegally for without paying money.
Speaker 1: if there wasn't a way to get it for free I just wouldn't get it and that would be that there I would not pay for any more than what I already pay for.
Speaker 1: I'm already buying the.
Speaker 1: I'm already spending the maximum amount of money that I would spend on entertainment media.
Speaker 0: Now the interesting thing is that a lot of people who are afraid of that nurture of anti I like their for net neutrality are afraid of like bandwidth caps and things like that and I think bandwidth caps are shit.
Speaker 0: but at the same time this whole unlimited data idea is basically Pointless and stupid and it's collapsing now that more and more people are savvy and actually using that data.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I think this it's sort of a weird issue.
Speaker 1: right because think about this, right?
Speaker 1: Okay, so if you we should have some sort of metering.
Speaker 1: right, you know If you use more bandwidth, you should pay more.
Speaker 1: right that's pretty obvious.
Speaker 1: But the problem is is that there is sort of infinite bandwidth.
Speaker 1: It's not a matter of how much bandwidth total use like oh I used a gigabyte.
Speaker 1: It's bandwidth that is available at any given nanosecond.
Speaker 0: How much electricity is available right now, what's the peak load?
Speaker 0: that's why you know They like you can have peak rates for electricity.
Speaker 0: you pay more for electricity on the hot fucking day at 4 o'clock Than you do at the cold part of the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the thing is we just need electricity has reasonable rates.
Speaker 1: Right, my electric bills like about 50 bucks, you know, it's not and that's what they're conditioning going on.
Speaker 1: It's 40 bucks when there's no air conditioning.
Speaker 1: So it's it.
Speaker 1: that's a reasonable rate, you know.
Speaker 1: So if my bandwidth right the problem is is everyone who's every suggested tier or metering plan is Always an incredibly unreasonable rate.
Speaker 1: It's like oh, yeah, we could charge you like a fucking dollar a gigabyte.
Speaker 1: It's like I know that's a way too much money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if it was a reasonable rate then who would complain?
Speaker 1: Oh, it's gonna be ten cents a gigabyte.
Speaker 0: Oh and it's actually perfectly Okay, these current unlimited like this whole unlimited idea just brings out the fact.
Speaker 0: that's true in every realm of the world where people overestimate their own contributions.
Speaker 0: more importantly They underestimate what things really cost and they pay their 70 bucks a month or 50 bucks a month and get unlimited.
Speaker 0: But it's unlimited with a tiny asterisk that basically says it's not unlimited will cut you off at any time for any reason.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I would much rather, you know, the only problem I have with the unlimited is that it's false advertising, you know I would be much happier with a fair rate because you know What I could do is I could you know, I could manage my internetting to save monies, you know Which is which is a good thing.
Speaker 0: But here's why at least I think a lot of the people who are against net neutrality like the people who are lobbying Against it straight up don't want it.
Speaker 0: It's because they.
Speaker 0: the world where everyone has high bandwidth is one the world where people pirate things on grander and grander Scales, but whatever.
Speaker 1: Well, they want to do stuff like the world where YouTube exists.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's the world word.
Speaker 0: I can just watch video on the internet and it's a world where ESPN could get to the point where they could say You know what?
Speaker 0: Cable companies pay us a million dollars that we just won't give you our cable anymore because we don't care.
Speaker 0: We're just gonna publish it on ESPN comm and charge people five bucks a month to just watch it.
Speaker 0: Imagine if someday, you know in the far future Imagine when ESPN gets to that point where they're just you know What it's a website.
Speaker 0: you pay a subscription fee and you have unlimited access to all the ESPN sports on your computer.
Speaker 1: Well, first of all, the problem is is they couldn't.
Speaker 1: you know all the sports that they show they have contracts with the people all Those you know, the the leagues inside the leagues got the leagues have to go for it and the whole or so.
Speaker 0: Oh, so far farther future major league baseball decides, you know what?
Speaker 0: Let's just cut out every middleman They already have.
Speaker 1: you can pay to get that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's starting already But they still like a charge way too much money for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but that's cuz.
Speaker 0: they don't get it.
Speaker 0: and because it's still too soon for the average person to have their internet TV It's too complicated for the average person to plug a computer into their TV.
Speaker 0: But think about how afraid of all this the industry is.
Speaker 0: remember when they prevented Hulu from being able to be watched on boxy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe you know right now everyone wants like a la carte cable, right like cable company.
Speaker 1: I tell you I want these three channels and I should only pay three dollars because each channel is one dollar.
Speaker 0: What is that?
Speaker 0: What would happen?
Speaker 1: What if the channel just said screw you cable company instead?
Speaker 1: We're gonna just go on the Internet's and our channel will only be on the Internet's and it'll be a dollar a month and then It'll basically be all a cart.
Speaker 1: But the cable company doesn't get any part of that dollar.
Speaker 1: think about only the channel against that dollar.
Speaker 0: this market This is.
Speaker 1: but you guys thought to pay the cable company for internet access because they're the ISP.
Speaker 0: But that's when the cable company says things like oh Well, alright, we'll launch our own competing service for blah and we won't let you have access to the other blah.
Speaker 0: You can't go to mlv.com directly Because you're stealing our bandwidth.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or what if mlb.com makes a deal with?
Speaker 0: Comcast is only Comcast.
Speaker 0: people can get mlb.
Speaker 1: Well, that's what ESPN has right now, right?
Speaker 0: It's bullshit.
Speaker 0: I have it free with Fios.
Speaker 0: But I'm got.
Speaker 0: I'm morally opposed to the principle that because my IP is X I'm allowed to watch this service, but no one else is.
Speaker 1: well because you know, right.
Speaker 1: so Verizon gave right.
Speaker 1: good luck, right?
Speaker 1: So let's say Verizon wants to have Comedy Central on Fios right cable TV.
Speaker 1: They give Comedy Central money and then Comedy Central appears on right whatever.
Speaker 1: and you know The HBO and stuff works the same way.
Speaker 1: only it costs so much money.
Speaker 1: They make you pay right, you know to get HBO on there.
Speaker 1: So imagine if right you got a website and now, you know some ISPs decide to pay that website.
Speaker 1: So you only get Google if AT&T decides to give Google money.
Speaker 1: other what you know.
Speaker 1: good, you know.
Speaker 1: The net neutrality people were originally worried about was Comcast saying haha, we're gonna block Google unless Google gives us money.
Speaker 1: Well think about this.
Speaker 1: Google says, haha We're gonna block Comcast unless Comcast gives us money.
Speaker 1: No Comcast people can search on Google.
Speaker 1: So unless Comcast gives us money, that's a nuclear war.
Speaker 1: Yeah, nobody's you know worried about that issue yet.
Speaker 1: But that could happen and that you know.
Speaker 1: It might not be part of the net neutrality as people have been discussing it because the cable companies were the first dicks.
Speaker 1: And the I think in the websites aren't.
Speaker 1: have not the dicks that came have not been the dicks yet.
Speaker 1: But ESPN 3 is the first website.
Speaker 1: dick, right?
Speaker 0: So it's well, I would argue that the first website dick came about about a day after.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying is that they're you know, alright, it's the same issue.
Speaker 1: Well think of it.
Speaker 1: you make a website you have to let everyone in the world visit that website.
Speaker 1: That's what that's what's right.
Speaker 0: Well, you know all those scenarios are basically the like the worst case like oh shit crazy disasters scenarios.
Speaker 0: But the real problem comes down to the idea of a conflict of interests and that if you give the people who control the last mile infrastructure Also the ability to negotiate content deals So they have a hand in the content cookie jar and a hand in the last mile infrastructure cookie jar.
Speaker 0: Even if they are they they decide to be good guys and they are good guys.
Speaker 0: The conflict of interest is Insurmountable and it is unconscionable that we should allow such a just a gross conflict of interest to exist.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we don't let the company's Trying to leave a good example.
Speaker 0: that would make sense to all of you.
Speaker 0: All my examples are other technology things?
Speaker 1: Yeah, no I mean, I think the you know I think the best solution that we put your in your newspaper carriers the people who don't.
Speaker 0: Here's the analogy for the people born before 1940.
Speaker 0: If you let the companies that deliver the newspapers to the people's houses Also own a share of the newspapers thus having editorial control over the newspaper that the people receive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the newspaper delivery boy doesn't like this article on the front page.
Speaker 1: So he gets a scissor and he cuts it out and he delivers it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if you want to get that article, well, you got to pay some money.
Speaker 1: Maybe you won't cut your newspaper.
Speaker 0: Yeah Never mind the fact that a lot of local ISPs have straight-up monopolies.
Speaker 1: or maybe like this.
Speaker 1: or maybe the New York Times says You know what?
Speaker 1: We don't like Queens.
Speaker 1: We're gonna deliver this nice awesome full paper with a hundred pages to Manhattan and we're gonna deliver half as much Pages to Queens.
Speaker 1: Queens you for the same price.
Speaker 1: you get half as many pages because we don't like the delivery company over there.
Speaker 1: They're jerks they you know, and if they give us money or if you give us more money Then we'll send you this the Manhattan paper.
Speaker 0: So really in the end Data transport at the last mile level and at the high level ISP level I think should by law be data agnostic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean really that's the long short of it and the last mile providers should not.
Speaker 0: this is just my straight-up opinion.
Speaker 0: They should not be able by law to have content production.
Speaker 0: I guess they shouldn't be able to have a hand in the content production cookie jar and simultaneously be an ISP.
Speaker 0: They should have to be two separate companies.
Speaker 1: I think you just need to make an I as you know ISPs into a utility like electricity.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know just the just the consumer ISPs, you know You don't need to regulate so much the middle parts, right?
Speaker 1: Because those you know with the peering agreements and all that stuff is really self-regulating at least for now.
Speaker 0: No to a degree.
Speaker 0: every now and then they have a.
Speaker 1: every now and then there's two jerks.
Speaker 1: But you know what those you know, the two jerks everything just routed around the jerks And it's not actually no for large portions of the world like Google stops working and things.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean this you know, it's stuff like Australia right where they only have one in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Like there was a situation a few months ago where half our customers, you know, but where I work They just like lost half their internet access because of one of these peering slap fights.
Speaker 0: really this happens more often than you'd think.
Speaker 0: It's not super obvious But you go to YouTube and it's down.
Speaker 0: you think I YouTube's down.
Speaker 0: That might have been a slap fight that you didn't know about.
Speaker 1: Oh, we gotta stop those slap fights.
Speaker 0: Yes alright, but like Part of the reason why there's so much fun.
Speaker 0: I was gonna say this before we got sidetracked.
Speaker 0: You're talking about the alicard cable, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so think about all the hands in this cookie jar.
Speaker 0: So, why do we have the current like structure?
Speaker 0: the way we do?
Speaker 0: you pay like 50 bucks a month to get you know?
Speaker 0: The whatever cable package and you can't get basic cable because it has a million channels But it doesn't have like Comedy Central the one channel you wanted or sippy.
Speaker 0: so alright you got to get the advanced package for 20 bucks more a month.
Speaker 0: that gives you like the three channels you wanted and There's like a thousand other channels.
Speaker 0: You don't give a shit about like the like BET or lifetime and you're paying for them.
Speaker 1: Right, it's like right now.
Speaker 1: Let's see your files cut.
Speaker 0: Well, are you really paying for them?
Speaker 1: Yeah indirect, you know the cable companies giving money to those channels.
Speaker 0: It's probably more complex than that.
Speaker 0: a lot of times those channels are paying the cable.
Speaker 1: Well, that's that's like if it's a QVC situation not even just QVC.
Speaker 0: a lot of those channels Only are watched or only exist in packages because they can sell based on number of subscribers to Advertisers and weird stuff like that and those channels.
Speaker 0: if you have to choose alicard I'd argue that 80% of the cable channels that exist would have less than a hundred subscribers.
Speaker 1: Well also think about this right?
Speaker 1: there's the.
Speaker 1: there's a bunch of TV production companies.
Speaker 1: They produce TV shows like crappy like traveling shows and shit like that right that almost nobody watches.
Speaker 1: But they sell those shows to these channels, right?
Speaker 1: I remember when like my parents first got the HD TV, right?
Speaker 1: There was a channel.
Speaker 1: that was the HD channel and all it was is like HD video of nature And that's all.
Speaker 1: it was like someone had just taken an HD camera out into the woods just to make content to have a channel to show off HD TVs and No one watched that.
Speaker 1: no one would pay even a penny for that channel, right?
Speaker 1: Maybe someone would pay it when HD TV first came out to like be a demo guy if it was the only HD channel.
Speaker 1: But no one else no one would you know continue to pay for it month after month unless they were just stupid rich and they weren't Paying attention to who knows what.
Speaker 1: but it would make almost no money.
Speaker 1: But whoever produced that video sold that video to that channel, right?
Speaker 1: It wasn't the same.
Speaker 1: for you know The company the production company and the channel are not the same.
Speaker 1: and then they don't.
Speaker 1: they don't have they don't worry They don't care about the production company that made the show doesn't give a shit if no one watches it.
Speaker 1: They got their money.
Speaker 1: So there's tons of TV production studios out there that make shows sell them and if the show does well They're happy because they can sell the show another season and that's good for them.
Speaker 1: But if the show doesn't do well They just make another show and they'll try to sell that.
Speaker 1: and they'll make another show and try to sell that until they get A hit.
Speaker 1: and as long as they keep selling that first season or you know, the first show they're still doing all right.
Speaker 1: They're not doing great, but they're doing.
Speaker 1: they're in business because they're selling a show.
Speaker 1: They only fail if they make a show and no channels buy it.
Speaker 1: So if these channels go away No one's gonna buy these shows and those production companies are gonna go away.
Speaker 1: and is you be huge huge You know.
Speaker 1: disaster in the TV arena and we know that like the TV arena there was a writers strike recently, right?
Speaker 1: So all these unions and shit.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's gonna be.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be devastating and the channels to all those little small channels that no one watches would either disappear.
Speaker 0: they they have a vested interest in keeping non a la carte cable and preventing that neutrality so that they can then make deals to where you know, basically you pay for Comcast Internet and Lifetime is included.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know those production companies Their only option is gonna be either go out of business and get a go to get a real job.
Speaker 1: No our job somewhere else.
Speaker 1: then, you know, that's a real job making TV shows.
Speaker 1: but it is if they or make TV shows and put them on YouTube and hope the fuck that people watch them and they're actually Good.
Speaker 1: Yeah right, which Most of those shows no one's gonna watch.
Speaker 0: and then don't forget the advertisers who are in this.
Speaker 0: It's this whole like gigantic circle of people and they all have such vested interest in actually think it.
Speaker 1: I think it actually might help out in the advertising department because the supply of advertising would go way down and all the people the ad buyers would have a lot less ads to buy and Thus if you actually had something that people were watching then you could actually get a lot more monies for it.
Speaker 1: You know right now right now internet stuff can't get a lot of monies just because they're morons and they getting it way more.
Speaker 1: Better eyeballs on the internet than they get on TV, but they keep buying that.
Speaker 1: He's paying more for TV and radio than they pay for internet.
Speaker 1: but if the TV disappeared then the things on the internet that actually get visits would suddenly get way valuable.
Speaker 1: and all that crap on the You know the same.
Speaker 1: You know stupid piece-of-shit show that moved from TV to the internet when the crap TV channel disappeared Wouldn't sell any ads because no one watches it and everyone would see that.
Speaker 1: No one watches it.
Speaker 1: and infomercials I don't even know they would be gone which would be a great awesomeness to the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course think about the thing is right.
Speaker 1: Look there's still ways to make it within infomercials.
Speaker 1: Look at the blend guy, right?
Speaker 1: Will it blend?
Speaker 1: That's an infomercial.
Speaker 1: He made it on the internet.
Speaker 0: That's guys, you know but look that's that that's part of the.
Speaker 0: I think a lot of the people who are against net neutrality are Actually just straight up against the idea that people who create content can provide it to the consumers directly Over their precious tubes,
Speaker 1: you know it comes down to the fact that they
Speaker 0: want to cut of their electricity.
Speaker 0: be like if the electric company wanted a cut of the Fact that I use their electricity to make money by doing a podcast.
Speaker 1: It just goes back to what I always been saying the internet destroys all middlemen.
Speaker 1: if you're a middleman the internet destroys you because Now the consumer can get directly to the producer and no one needs to be in between.
Speaker 1: and right now in the time period we're In there are middlemen who are surviving for example Apple Amazon, right?
Speaker 1: These are middlemen who are surviving but the reason they are surviving is not because they're middlemen.
Speaker 1: It is because they are providing Technology services to both the consumer and the producer because the consumer and the producer are not technologically competent.
Speaker 0: This is what they do the job themselves.
Speaker 0: This is also what middlemen used to do a long time ago when there weren't things like the internet where all right you want to Distribute a book or a movie.
Speaker 1: I can handle the printing and the shipping parts that you could not do on your own because you Don't know about them, but nowadays we can do a lot of those things without those people.
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: so as soon as once producers are Technologically competent enough to not need an Apple to not need an Amazon and consumers are Technologically competent enough to not need an Apple or an Amazon or whoever Then all middlemen will be gone except for the utility providers like electricity water you know Transportation, you know and in convenience
Speaker 0: providers, but only if they can be more convenient than the direct which is possible in some.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean a convenience provider is a producer, right?
Speaker 1: I mean if I order a comfy chair, that's a convenience provider Producer of products, you know, that's what like shipping aggregators or things like I mean UPS.
Speaker 1: Is that you know shipping?
Speaker 1: isn't that a utility in my eyes?
Speaker 1: I mean, right?
Speaker 1: It's possible.
Speaker 1: I can say that a utility.
Speaker 1: shipping and transportation.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.