Speaker 1: It's Monday December 19th, 2011.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 1: Tonight, software development methodologies.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: While you were home being a bum, I was out shushin'.
Speaker 0: Shushin'.
Speaker 1: Shushin'.
Speaker 0: That's nice.
Speaker 1: There was actually some pretty good shushin', even though it was kind of disturbing that, you know.
Speaker 0: How many people other than you were shushin'?
Speaker 1: Not that many people.
Speaker 0: I didn't think that many people would be.
Speaker 0: There were maybe... But it was cold.
Speaker 1: Maybe thousand people other than me at the mountain.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's a lot.
Speaker 1: Not really.
Speaker 0: How many people is it usually?
Speaker 1: A lot more than that.
Speaker 1: There's usually lines where you have to wait like 20 minutes just to get on the lift.
Speaker 0: Oh, but there's no line to shush.
Speaker 0: There's just a line to get up to the top.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why would there be a line to shush?
Speaker 1: You just shush.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: But, you know, people could be lined up, you know, if it's like a narrow entryway.
Speaker 1: That's not how it works, by and large.
Speaker 0: Is there like a line at the top, like start here?
Speaker 1: No, there's just a mountain, and you can go in any direction.
Speaker 1: There's like 20 different ways down.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Though the funny thing...
Speaker 0: So you can even go down, like, in between one of the spots where you're not supposed to go.
Speaker 0: You can.
Speaker 1: You shouldn't.
Speaker 1: Obviously you should.
Speaker 1: But there are people who do.
Speaker 1: I've done it a couple of times.
Speaker 1: I've gone places that weren't actually trails.
Speaker 1: What happens?
Speaker 1: Or gone down closed trails.
Speaker 1: You just ski and hope you don't get hurt, because if you do, they're not going to find you.
Speaker 0: Alrighty.
Speaker 0: Even if you scream or something?
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Just if you're not in screaming condition.
Speaker 1: Usually you go, you do that with a buddy.
Speaker 0: A buddy system.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So one person will do the screaming.
Speaker 1: But it was interesting that I'm there, right?
Speaker 1: And there hasn't been really any snow this year.
Speaker 1: So everything around was green and brown, except the mountain, because Hunter actually makes snow, and they made a ton of snow.
Speaker 0: But it was cold, so the snow probably didn't melt.
Speaker 1: No, it didn't.
Speaker 1: They were making snow constantly the whole time I was there, too.
Speaker 1: So feet and feet of it were just being dumped.
Speaker 0: So there's a snowmaking machine.
Speaker 1: Many of them.
Speaker 0: And they spray snow.
Speaker 1: They spray water into the air that basically turns it into snow and falls back down.
Speaker 0: Okay, so is it just like it's snowing everywhere?
Speaker 0: I have a video of it, in fact.
Speaker 0: Or are there people shoveling the snow to get it on all the parts?
Speaker 1: Oh, it's basically snowing everywhere.
Speaker 0: So basically they spray it off the top of the mountain.
Speaker 1: Well, no, they spray it.
Speaker 1: Scott, Scott, they spray it at intervals all over the mountain.
Speaker 1: If you want to get into the details of how they make snow, it's not what you're envisioning.
Speaker 0: It's not about how they make the snow.
Speaker 0: It's about how they get the snow, which is also how they make it.
Speaker 1: They spray it at every individual point along the way.
Speaker 1: There are thousands of spray nozzles all over the mountain.
Speaker 0: I thought it was a machine that just sort of sprays it in one big spot.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, no.
Speaker 0: They make the snow and they pump it around.
Speaker 1: Now they have some point places that'll make the snow for like one particular area at a time.
Speaker 0: So the snow gets delivered at like a sprinkler system almost out of separate thingies.
Speaker 1: Sort of, yeah.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: But there hadn't been any snow.
Speaker 1: So the whole area around the mountain was basically brown.
Speaker 1: And then the mountain itself had these crazy ungroomed moguls because they were basically pouring snow down and it tends to form into moguls.
Speaker 1: It was awesome.
Speaker 1: It was absolutely awesome.
Speaker 0: Why aren't they like raked or something?
Speaker 1: They do groom things, but not while they're making it because it'll just get ungroomed.
Speaker 1: And frankly, I prefer skiing ungroomed crazy terrain.
Speaker 0: Wouldn't you want like, what do they do for like Olympic snow?
Speaker 1: Uh, same thing.
Speaker 1: and or using natural snow.
Speaker 1: And then they groom it depending on what kind of race it is.
Speaker 1: They make like the field for the racing or the slalom or whatever.
Speaker 1: There's some racing courses at Hunter.
Speaker 0: It's just like you see Olympic snow and it's like oh yeah, they groom that.
Speaker 0: It's like that's the, you know, where can you get that kind of action.
Speaker 1: They groom that shit.
Speaker 1: But anyway, the funny thing was there's one run.
Speaker 1: They don't at the same time.
Speaker 1: So they made like a set of runs you could do.
Speaker 1: And one of them Minya Konka, which is one of my favorites anyway, or Minya Konka I guess.
Speaker 1: I've never actually looked at how it's spelled and I'm trying to think back as to how it's spelled because it's going to make fun of you.
Speaker 1: You're going to get, you're going to get reamed of the trails.
Speaker 1: But uh, there it was, it looked like it was closed.
Speaker 1: But if you skied all the way over there and look down, the sign didn't say closed.
Speaker 1: It said warning ungroomed experts only.
Speaker 1: So I went over there and there was maybe one other dude going down that same trail.
Speaker 1: So I just had this whole trail to myself like all day.
Speaker 1: It was kind of hard though.
Speaker 0: No kidding.
Speaker 1: In fact it was way hard, but I took a lesson.
Speaker 0: I feel kind of confident now because you paid money for a lesson for a professional person because I was, you know, why did the professional person tell you?
Speaker 1: Well, basically he told me what I expected.
Speaker 1: He looked at how I skied and said, you're great.
Speaker 1: You're on your way to be an expert.
Speaker 1: Just keep skiing all the time.
Speaker 1: And he showed me a couple exercises to do that I'd never thought of.
Speaker 1: And it was actually surprising how much that helped.
Speaker 1: He told me this thing called pizza, pizza, french fries.
Speaker 1: He was like, yeah, right.
Speaker 1: Actually there's a big argument that you shouldn't even teach kids that you should start them on parallel skiing right away.
Speaker 1: And I kind of agree with that because the snowplow formation is basically dangerous and slow and stupid.
Speaker 1: And if you go too fast, it can't stop you.
Speaker 1: And you're more likely to have a spiral fracture.
Speaker 1: And if you don't know what that is, imagine a fracture of bones that is spiral.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you don't want that shit.
Speaker 1: But you taught me this weird exercise to do.
Speaker 1: And usually I'm like, eh, exercises, I'll just practice by skiing or whatever.
Speaker 1: But basically I had to stand sideways.
Speaker 1: So like if the mountain's down, I'm standing to where I'm kind of facing perpendicularly to the fall line.
Speaker 1: And then he's like, and then change your edges.
Speaker 1: You start sliding sideways on your skis down the mountain.
Speaker 0: So you're looking left, but you're going down and your skis are pointing down.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And then he's like, all right, then change your edging so that the front is falling faster than the back and then repeat.
Speaker 1: So you kind of go like a falling leaf, like woo woo woo all the way down the mountain.
Speaker 1: He was like, do that twice down the entire mountain and you'll be a better skier afterward.
Speaker 1: And I did it and it hurts like a hundred percent and I can't even figure out exactly what I'm better at, but I'm better.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So do that thing if you want to get better at skiing.
Speaker 0: You should maybe just do that thing every time you go to the mountain, like, like start off by just doing that two times and then, you know, until you can do it until you can do it without even thinking about it.
Speaker 1: I realized that it's like DDR, like aside from exercises and things, you know, this guy, he's an expert skier and he's trying to explain like concepts of skiing.
Speaker 1: And it's a lot like, you know, when you try to explain like a skill that you know intuitively that you learn from practice, how usually the advice you give doesn't really mean much to someone who isn't on the heads.
Speaker 0: It's like, yeah, thanks.
Speaker 0: I knew that.
Speaker 0: Yep, exactly.
Speaker 1: It just kind of reinforces this idea that for physical skills, skills of dexterity, of balance, of physicality, very little help is gained in the end from someone telling you or showing you, you really just have to do it.
Speaker 0: Well, I think, well, obviously you have to do it, but showing definitely helps because you can watch.
Speaker 0: To a degree, but it can only get you so far.
Speaker 0: You have to watch and duplicate, but once you're able to duplicate and the person is watching you, it confirms you are doing it properly, then, you know, that's only step one.
Speaker 0: Step two is repeat it now a thousand times.
Speaker 0: That's, you know, so it just, but it does help to watch and have a person confirm that you are duplicating properly.
Speaker 1: That was the main reason I got a lesson because, you know, I've been skiing for a few years and I'm doing like pretty expert stuff, but I, I always feel really not so confident sometimes on these hills.
Speaker 1: So I wanted an expert to look at me and tell me if I was an idiot or not.
Speaker 1: And apparently I'm not that much of an idiot.
Speaker 0: All right, so, so news, news, technologies, lots of technology.
Speaker 0: news too much.
Speaker 0: Uh, so check this out.
Speaker 0: in India, in India, India, people don't have a lot of money, relatively speaking, not a lot of money, but they got a lot of cell phones, cell phones, too many cell phones, almost too many cell phones and too many people.
Speaker 0: Uh, so they want to save money on the cell phone bill.
Speaker 0: Thankfully it doesn't cost as much as it does here.
Speaker 0: Well, how can you do this?
Speaker 0: real easy?
Speaker 0: First, get one of those plans where you pay as you go and by the minute, as opposed to buying minutes upfront, like you have to do here, which is annoying too.
Speaker 0: Let's say you want to call someone, but you don't want to pay for minutes or anything.
Speaker 0: Call them and hang up after the first ring, they'll see your number on the caller ID and they'll call your ass back on the landline or whatever.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, a lot of people do this.
Speaker 0: Apparently about half of people in India have done this, uh, with their cell phones to save money.
Speaker 1: You know, I used to do something like that when I had to get, before I had a car.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'd take classes at the local college and to call my mom to pick me up after school, I would basically do a collect call to the house and it would be like collect call from pick me up.
Speaker 0: It totally works.
Speaker 0: So, but here's something even crazier.
Speaker 0: A lot of people out there are specifically creating automatic phone services that use missed calls.
Speaker 0: So for example, in the US, you know, you might call Google four one one.
Speaker 0: Does that still exist?
Speaker 0: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Uh, or you might call, you know, uh, for example, I called the jury duty to find out if I had jury duty.
Speaker 0: I don't, I'm probably not gonna, but I still have to call for the rest of the week.
Speaker 0: Uh, and I call and I wait and I push the numbers and then eventually they, you know, I'm on hold and eventually they tell me, you know, whether it's yes or no.
Speaker 0: Imagine if I called the jury duty and hung up and then they called my ass back on the, with the automatic system, called me back and told me based on my number.
Speaker 1: Now, maybe though that might cost them something.
Speaker 1: So what if instead you had a service where you call them and hang up and then they call you back and let it ring a number of times and hang up and then you have a system that knows one ring means show up to means don't.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But no, this is basically like there's people are setting up systems where you'll call a phone number, hang up after one ring and it'll call you back and tell you the weather.
Speaker 0: I'll call you back and tell you the bus schedule or you know, do all kinds of other stuff so that you don't need to use your minutes and you can still get service.
Speaker 0: And the person who has to pay is, you know, the person on the other end who has maybe a landline, it isn't paying so much.
Speaker 0: And apparently, you know, they make an average of three dollars per customer in profits of revenue of three dollars per customer on phone service in India.
Speaker 0: Nine hundred million accounts times three dollars is still two point seven billion dollars, but they're only making three bucks per customer.
Speaker 0: That's not a lot.
Speaker 0: And they would make a lot more, they said.
Speaker 0: But half of people, you know, use this this kind of trickery.
Speaker 0: So maybe they'll make five dollars per user instead.
Speaker 0: Five times nine million is four and a half billion.
Speaker 1: See, the only way instead of two point seven billion, you really want to make money off of from something like that.
Speaker 1: You either have to use that as a kind of bundled service with a bunch of other things or no.
Speaker 1: Eventually they'll be open source.
Speaker 1: Everyone individually is empowered to use their own services like that.
Speaker 0: I think it's there also because they're just.
Speaker 0: they're not milking it and locking people in like they are here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's an interesting.
Speaker 1: I don't want to even call it a problem because one, I think there's nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 1: If you are afforded charge people for calling, then if you don't want him to do this, if you were afforded something by technology and it appear, you know, it's an accepted part of the protocol.
Speaker 1: Like, for example, I have a laptop and I say, hey, Wi-Fi, can I connect to you?
Speaker 1: Well, I'll just go into further.
Speaker 1: Wi-Fi says, hey, you, you want to connect to me?
Speaker 1: And I say, yes, I want to connect to you.
Speaker 1: And they give me Internet.
Speaker 1: It's you know, that's not my problem if I use it.
Speaker 1: If the other person didn't want me to use it, they shouldn't have afforded me that thing, that ability.
Speaker 1: This is just an affordance of the way the phone system works.
Speaker 1: And because you can exchange any information over the sideband, that could be your entire stream if you use a good encoding.
Speaker 0: Don't offer caller ID if you didn't want this to happen.
Speaker 1: It's very yet caller ID.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: If you charge, charge people for the caller ID.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Which they used to.
Speaker 0: You could spoof the caller ID.
Speaker 0: I could call some service.
Speaker 0: That's like, you know, it's like call us and hang up after two rings to get a hoe to show up and I'll dial the fake number.
Speaker 0: And then the hoe looks.
Speaker 1: Or I call someone and I shows up at some office.
Speaker 1: I spoofed the caller ID.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: And the caller ID is spoofed.
Speaker 1: So I've sent a bunch of digits.
Speaker 1: I can then have an encoding scheme to put data in those digits.
Speaker 0: Oh, here we go.
Speaker 0: You ready?
Speaker 0: You spoofed caller ID to 911.
Speaker 0: So you call the weather service and then they call 911 and tell it the weather.
Speaker 1: That is just.
Speaker 1: these are all just riffs on the old Chinese restaurant double take.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: I read some crazy story today that I think it was probably a FARC story.
Speaker 0: The two guys robbed the place and then one guy ass dialed 911.
Speaker 1: That happens kind of often.
Speaker 0: I don't I actually sort of while that's hilarious and it could be true, I sort of don't believe it.
Speaker 0: And I think that one guy actually wanted to turn him in.
Speaker 0: One of the two guys wanted to, you know, like wanted to, you know, go to jail or at least, you know.
Speaker 1: But it's hard to say.
Speaker 0: But, you know, he didn't want to just rat out his friends straight up.
Speaker 0: And he also couldn't convince the friend to turn himself in.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So this way, at least the friend thinks he's dumb as opposed to the friend thinking he's a rat.
Speaker 1: Thing is, a lot of phones have emergency dialing mode, which will bypass the lock screen and simultaneously will have like 911 already pre-coded in there.
Speaker 0: I know it is possible, but really.
Speaker 0: But dialing 911 and then on while the 911 is dialed, talking about the crime you committed and talking about, hey, we're going to go sell the stuff at this place and then going to the place and the cops are already there.
Speaker 0: It's a little a little too far fetched.
Speaker 0: It's possible, though.
Speaker 1: Of course, what is funny is that this is actually very.
Speaker 1: this India thing is very reminiscent of the old black boxes.
Speaker 1: You know how black boxes worked?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Do you?
Speaker 0: Well, most of those boxes were just, you know, put some sound.
Speaker 1: No, no, no, no, no.
Speaker 1: You're thinking of red boxes and blue boxes or the I think the beige box.
Speaker 1: The black box was different.
Speaker 1: It would basically make the phone circuit appear as though the phone was on the hook at both ends because the billing system would not charge you for a time where one or both parties has the phone on the hook because you can't be talking.
Speaker 1: So you'd mess with the line level, the voltage with this black box on both ends so that look like the phone was actually on the hook.
Speaker 1: It was hung up.
Speaker 1: And then you just keep talking through the open circuit.
Speaker 1: It's similar to that, only actually a little bit more legit.
Speaker 0: It's a lot more legit.
Speaker 1: I have no problem with anyone using a side.
Speaker 0: I don't have a problem either.
Speaker 0: I just think it's really interesting.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: But I know there are people out there going to try to argue it's a bad thing.
Speaker 0: Whatever.
Speaker 0: Shut up.
Speaker 1: So it turns out that Facebook is suing Mark Zuckerberg.
Speaker 1: For something kind of funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's some other guy who changed his name to Mark Zuckerberg.
Speaker 0: So it's not their own CEO.
Speaker 1: Some other guy.
Speaker 1: I want to talk about this because everyone has the headlines.
Speaker 1: People haven't actually been reading the article, I don't think so.
Speaker 0: Some guy.
Speaker 0: I was too lazy.
Speaker 1: Made a store company.
Speaker 1: I think it's based in Israel.
Speaker 1: What it does is called the like store.
Speaker 1: You want to buy likes for your business's website.
Speaker 1: Three thousand five thousand ten thousand.
Speaker 1: You pay them and they provide them nice.
Speaker 1: They have armies of people and robots and accounts that will just like the shit out of your website.
Speaker 1: And you pay per like.
Speaker 0: Nice.
Speaker 1: You have bulk discounts.
Speaker 0: How much is it per like?
Speaker 1: I have no idea, Penny.
Speaker 1: This is against Facebook's terms of service.
Speaker 0: No kidding.
Speaker 1: So they sued the guy saying, hey, I don't know, can you sue a guy for violating the terms of service?
Speaker 0: I mean, because he was you can you can get rid of his account, but can you sue him?
Speaker 0: I guess they're doing it.
Speaker 1: Well, they want.
Speaker 1: they basically want his business shut down.
Speaker 1: And there's all sorts of shenanigans.
Speaker 0: I'm skipping the Israeli law.
Speaker 1: But the funny thing is, this guy, in response to being sued, legally changed his name to Mark Zuckerberg just for publicity.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: It worked.
Speaker 1: It appears to have worked really well.
Speaker 1: Everyone knows about the like star.
Speaker 1: So I went to this like star to see what the deal was.
Speaker 0: How much of the likes?
Speaker 1: You can buy Google plus one's YouTube views.
Speaker 1: You can just buy YouTube views.
Speaker 0: How much?
Speaker 0: How much is a YouTube view?
Speaker 1: Let's find out right now.
Speaker 1: Let's see.
Speaker 1: I want a real YouTube view.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: I can get twenty five thousand for two hundred and thirty dollars.
Speaker 0: That's not worth it.
Speaker 0: That's not even close to.
Speaker 1: I can get a thousand for twelve dollars.
Speaker 0: No, see, that's that's an insignificant number of likes.
Speaker 0: I've already got like one hundred thousand likes.
Speaker 0: just rainbow dash.
Speaker 0: Oh, my gosh.
Speaker 0: You need you want a significant number of likes.
Speaker 0: I need like twenty five million likes.
Speaker 0: That's a real number of likes.
Speaker 0: How much is twenty five million likes?
Speaker 1: Well, twenty five million likes is much harder to get than twenty five million views.
Speaker 0: But that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: And it's like that's a. you know, it's a real number.
Speaker 1: More importantly, this goes back into something we used to talk about more often than we do now.
Speaker 1: But SEO scum, this is the same as SEO scum.
Speaker 1: If you're a business and you think that this will help you, you're an idiot.
Speaker 0: No kidding.
Speaker 1: And it amazes me that people fall for this snake oil.
Speaker 0: Well, it could help you a little bit, right?
Speaker 0: If it works, if and you don't get caught and shut down your video, take it down.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Then you might actually get, for example, your video on the YouTube homepage, which will then get you actual views.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: It's not that likely, though, because I cannot believe that you'll actually make it to the homepage with fake views and especially because I would not put it past Facebook and Google and anyone to perfectly let this happen.
Speaker 1: Don't even make it against your terms of service.
Speaker 1: And this have an algorithm that identifies these accounts doing these likes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just ban them.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Or don't count their likes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And not show that video on the home page.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It totally won't work.
Speaker 1: But it amazes me that people still fall for this stuff and that they think they need it.
Speaker 1: And to it amazes me that people who look at sites, because I used to think that stuff like this didn't affect individual users, but people seem to be drawn to things that have a lot of Facebook likes, even though most of those things appear to have gained those likes by scams like this.
Speaker 1: This is not the only place that sells these things.
Speaker 0: Same people who are like obsessed with like post counts and forums.
Speaker 0: It's like just whenever there's any number of people like crazy about making it get bigger, they have some sort of psychological hang up they can't get over.
Speaker 0: And, you know, Farmville and everyone else takes advantage of it.
Speaker 0: That's just all there is to it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Now, I don't think there's anything wrong with selling likes and I don't think there's anything wrong with a company like Facebook figuring out whose likes are fake and not counting them.
Speaker 1: And I think that's the end of that.
Speaker 1: I think the lawsuit is kind of silly.
Speaker 1: And I think the guy is actually a genius for changing his name to Mark Zuckerberg.
Speaker 0: That was definitely a move of genius right there.
Speaker 1: And I wish everyone in this story the worst of luck, because frankly, they're all scum.
Speaker 0: Scum versus scum, the best guy.
Speaker 1: I do want to talk briefly about one more news item, because this has been making the rounds.
Speaker 1: People have been in uproar lately.
Speaker 1: There's been a lot of articles, op-eds, people complaining about how Google, partly with the advent of Google Plus and their verifications and everything, has been shutting down Gmail accounts of children.
Speaker 1: Or people...
Speaker 0: There's a law that says they have to.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So most of the articles about this basically blame Google.
Speaker 1: It's not Google's fault.
Speaker 1: You ever wonder why Steam and like every website in the world often will ask you, hey, when were you born?
Speaker 0: Well, some of it's ESRB compliance for video games.
Speaker 1: And it's also COPPA, the Childhood Online Privacy Protection Act.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: Which, one, it's an unconstitutional load of shit that I've hated from day one.
Speaker 1: I don't think it should be a law.
Speaker 1: It's ludicrous that we have a law like this, because what kid doesn't just say they were born on January 1st, 1900?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Why even make the websites go through the motion?
Speaker 1: I also don't think it should be constitutional to have restrictions like that anyway.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: But I digress.
Speaker 1: It's not Google's fault.
Speaker 1: Google is dealing with the bullshit laws that we let get passed.
Speaker 0: If you don't like it, get the law changed.
Speaker 1: I disagree with that argument because our government is incapable of fixing anything at this point.
Speaker 0: Violent revolution.
Speaker 1: That might be the only option.
Speaker 0: I think so.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I think, you know, a lot of people say that, you know, the last the last...
Speaker 1: I mean, we could get in trouble.
Speaker 1: We don't verify age.
Speaker 1: So if if someone under the age of 13 is using our forum, we could actually get a lot of trouble.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, a lot of people say the last kind of discrimination we have to fight against is like, you know, anti-gay, anti, you know, lesbian and transgender and all that.
Speaker 0: And that's not true to, you know, even if we, you know, somehow get it to the point where there's no more, you know, homophobes and whatnot, people are still going to be against atheists.
Speaker 0: And that's the group that comes next.
Speaker 0: And then even then...
Speaker 1: Actually, that's the most distrusted group in America.
Speaker 0: But even then, even if we somehow get it to the point where atheists are accepted, right, by, you know, the whole of society, there's still going to be age discrimination.
Speaker 0: Age discrimination is the very last form of discrimination.
Speaker 1: No, you're forgetting, Scott.
Speaker 1: Furry freedom.
Speaker 1: What about pond hopper?
Speaker 0: That's not discrimination.
Speaker 0: That's justified.
Speaker 1: I wear the tanooki suit to fly.
Speaker 0: Age discrimination is the very last form of discrimination.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's the very last one.
Speaker 1: What about A.I.s and robots?
Speaker 1: They're going to get discriminated against like all fuck.
Speaker 0: No, because they won't let you.
Speaker 0: They'll just fucking kill you.
Speaker 1: See, everyone says that.
Speaker 1: No, because in what world do we make an A.I.
Speaker 1: and then immediately give it control of nukes?
Speaker 0: You wouldn't?
Speaker 0: Why wouldn't you?
Speaker 0: I trust the robot with the nukes more than just people.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 1: But oh, by the way, you know what?
Speaker 1: You're not allowed to use our forum if you're under the age of 13.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 1: I'm sure that'll stop all of you who are under the age of 13 from using our forum.
Speaker 0: Great.
Speaker 0: But yeah, age discrimination will probably won't even see a dent in age discrimination in our lifetimes or perhaps in the next century.
Speaker 1: But Scott, what constitutes age discrimination specifically?
Speaker 0: I mean, when you discriminate against someone simply based on the length of time that they have been alive as opposed to based on the merit of their character.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: You got people who are completely dumb and incapable of thinking or driving, who are very old, perhaps 40s, 50s, yet there are like 12 year olds who are extremely capable of many, many things far more capable than people who have been on the earth far longer than them.
Speaker 0: So discriminate against, you know, to give one person more or less rights or privileges simply based on the number of seconds since they're, you know, conception.
Speaker 1: So I have one question for you, Scott.
Speaker 1: Yes, I'm just going to ask you this question.
Speaker 1: It's a loaded question.
Speaker 0: I know heavily load.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure I know the question already.
Speaker 1: You run a company.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: You need to hire a developer.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: There are two developers who are exactly equally qualified in all regards.
Speaker 0: Hire both.
Speaker 0: Can never do without, you know, can't have enough.
Speaker 1: You only have budget to hire one person.
Speaker 1: You don't need to.
Speaker 1: One of them is 20 and one of them is 111.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Now, which one are you going to hire?
Speaker 1: Assuming that we have not discovered immortality and the average human lifespan is well under 111.
Speaker 0: Well, the dude is sickly.
Speaker 0: He was 111.
Speaker 0: Or is he healthy?
Speaker 0: He looks like he's going to keep going.
Speaker 1: He looks like he's going to keep going.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, he's not going to live past 120 because no one does.
Speaker 0: Well, see, I'm not discriminating based on his age, discriminating based on his health.
Speaker 0: That's completely different.
Speaker 1: But his health is solely due to his age.
Speaker 0: Not necessarily.
Speaker 1: In this case, yes.
Speaker 1: He's 100 percent healthy, except for the fact that he is aging.
Speaker 0: Well, aging is the disease.
Speaker 1: That if you're hiring someone, he will not be around 20 years from now, while the 20 year old, if you keep paying him, will probably still be around.
Speaker 0: I'm not discriminating based on age, I'm discriminating based on another factor.
Speaker 1: What other factor?
Speaker 0: That happens to be correlated, happens to be correlated with age.
Speaker 1: Happens to be correlated 100 percent directly, one to one.
Speaker 0: For example, if a three year old was really good at driving, but he couldn't reach the pedals, I wouldn't let him drive.
Speaker 0: It's, is it age discrimination?
Speaker 0: Well, the length of his legs correlates with his age.
Speaker 0: But it's not age discrimination because he can't reach the pedals.
Speaker 0: So the requirement is you must be healthy and you will live a long time.
Speaker 0: Scott, the requirement is you have to be able to reach the pedal.
Speaker 1: All right, Scott.
Speaker 1: So why would I ever hire someone who's 50 when I could hire someone who's similarly qualified, who's 20?
Speaker 0: Because nobody is going to work for you for that many years.
Speaker 0: The 50 year old dude isn't going to die in nine years.
Speaker 0: Nine years is, you know, people work at companies for more than nine years.
Speaker 0: You know, if you expect, you know, the 20 year old guy might work for you for 20 years.
Speaker 0: Well, the 50 year old guy could work for you for 20 years.
Speaker 0: Also, you know, there there's no worry of the guy's going to die tomorrow.
Speaker 0: It may be if a 20 year old comes who's like, you know, may you know, he's fully capable of doing the job, but he's got cancer and he's going to die tomorrow.
Speaker 0: So you're going to get a cancer guy if he's got a week to live?
Speaker 1: Yes, but that's discriminatory.
Speaker 0: He's got a week to live.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to hire someone who is not even going to make it through training.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's a guy who is more qualified than the 20 year old.
Speaker 0: He's one hundred and nineteen.
Speaker 1: OK, he is statistically pretty much guaranteed to die in the next six months.
Speaker 1: OK, you know, hire him or the 18 year old might think about hiring that old guy.
Speaker 1: You don't get that much work out of him in six months.
Speaker 0: Well, he's probably a genius, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, seriously, he could probably do like 10 years of work in six months.
Speaker 0: If he's if he's better than the 20 year old.
Speaker 1: But anyway, things of the day for the life of me, I'm almost 30 years old and this is going to sound like an old man thing, but I got fitted sheets and I basically just wad them up in a vaguely like rectangular shape.
Speaker 1: Well, for anyone who doesn't know, shove them into the back of my linen closet to then pretend they're not there.
Speaker 0: Fitted sheets are the ones that, you know, you put on a bed that have the the elastic strap around the bottom.
Speaker 0: They're fitted.
Speaker 0: They tie, you know, they stay tight on the mattress in case you're dumb and you don't know what those are.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So, yeah.
Speaker 1: How the fuck do you fold those?
Speaker 1: Well, now I know.
Speaker 1: now I know how to fold them.
Speaker 0: Could you actually pull it off?
Speaker 0: I got I got it halfway through.
Speaker 0: I've watched that shirt folding video about a thousand times.
Speaker 0: You know, I can't fucking do it.
Speaker 1: I folded one fitted sheet pretty close to this.
Speaker 1: The key is if you get that trick of holding the corners, it's all about the pointy corner.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm getting better at this.
Speaker 1: This was actually life changing.
Speaker 1: And I think you should all watch it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So, you know, the game, the kids for the NES.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that game was OK.
Speaker 0: It's actually called MC Kids.
Speaker 0: And yeah.
Speaker 0: And apparently this dude named Greg is Tavares and also someone else named Dan Chang.
Speaker 0: They made that game.
Speaker 0: They program that shit.
Speaker 0: And in 1992, they wrote an article in the Journal of Computer Game Design talking about how they program that shit.
Speaker 0: And here is that article on the Internet.
Speaker 0: And you know what?
Speaker 0: It's pretty fascinating how they program this fucking game on NES.
Speaker 0: So, you know, if you're actually a computer person or a game coder or anything like that.
Speaker 0: Read this, because it's pretty fascinating.
Speaker 0: And then on top of that, maybe you should make some NES roms or something like that.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Maybe mod some NES roms.
Speaker 0: So very briefly, make Zelda D. No, please don't.
Speaker 0: I can't even beat Zelda C. Don't make Zelda D.
Speaker 1: Zelda D would just be you start, no sword, surrounded by blue dark nuts.
Speaker 0: Come and stay.
Speaker 0: Final destination.
Speaker 1: No idea.
Speaker 0: AIs reprogrammed, so they come right at you.
Speaker 0: Oh, and there's a whole lake.
Speaker 0: You're in a middle of an island and all the water around you has Zora's shooting fireballs.
Speaker 1: You just spawn on a dark nut.
Speaker 0: Maybe I should just make that as like a piece of art.
Speaker 1: I prefer your...
Speaker 0: It's like you push start and it's like, doo, doo, doo, doo, doo, doo, doo, doo, doo.
Speaker 1: No, we should make a whole installation.
Speaker 1: Like there'd be a nice art gallery where there's a bunch of NES games that are each of them not only impossible, but impossible to a ludicrous and surprising degree.
Speaker 0: A Tetris that only gives pieces.
Speaker 0: you can never finish a line.
Speaker 1: Someone programmed bastard Tetris that is designed to give you the worst possible piece every move.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but isn't it possible to give someone pieces that it's impossible to make a line?
Speaker 0: If we got all S pieces?
Speaker 0: No, because you could put them all right next to each other.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then there'd be all the bottom.
Speaker 0: There would be.
Speaker 1: Tetris is no bottom.
Speaker 0: Just make up new pieces that are asshole pieces so you can't pos-.
Speaker 0: So if anyone has a possibility of completing a line, make a piece that can't-.
Speaker 1: There was that Japanese joke one that the pieces were all irregularly shaped.
Speaker 0: Right, that's what I'm saying.
Speaker 0: Just make up new pieces as it goes along so that any piece it gives you will not possibly make a line.
Speaker 1: I'm talking like a Mario one that just starts you and there's just nothing but goombas and turtles everywhere and there's a pit you can't jump over right past it.
Speaker 0: Yup.
Speaker 1: So in the meta moment, the book club books are...
Speaker 0: Little Prince by Antoine de Saint-Euverie and Wind, Sand, and Stars by the same person.
Speaker 0: I'm about halfway through Wind and Sand and Stars.
Speaker 1: I am also about halfway through Wind, Sand, and Stars.
Speaker 0: So this book club book is probably gonna happen before the next year.
Speaker 1: It is a fantastic book.
Speaker 0: The best.
Speaker 1: I'm very much enjoying it.
Speaker 1: I really want to fly a super dangerous dodgy old plane across the desert now.
Speaker 0: You know, these planes weren't so dodgy and old.
Speaker 0: He wrote this thing in like the 30s.
Speaker 1: Yeah, planes in the 30s, Scott, were dodgy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it wasn't like the fucking Red Baron, alright?
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't- It was real airplanes made of metal with engines.
Speaker 1: Yes, it wasn't that much better than the Red Baron.
Speaker 0: Two or four propellers on the wings.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they were not that great, these planes.
Speaker 0: It was a lot better than the Red Baron.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they were still dodgy.
Speaker 0: Dodgier than the 747, sure.
Speaker 1: And I know how much he talks about, "Hey, it's much better here than it was in the old days when you- In addition to worrying about the engine failing, you also have to worry about the wings falling off.
Speaker 1: Luckily, I don't have to worry about
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 1: Except in that typhoon, he's like, "That was the one time I was worried about my wings falling
Speaker 1: off.".
Speaker 0: I just read the typhoon chat.
Speaker 1: That was great.
Speaker 0: He's just like, "Yeah, there's really no drama here.
Speaker 0: I'm just gonna tell you what happened.
Speaker 0: I was in a
Speaker 0: typhoon.".
Speaker 1: He meant not to, just to kind of, not spoil the book on the book.
Speaker 0: Let's not ruin the book club book.
Speaker 0: Let's continue with the better moment.
Speaker 1: To try to trick you into reading this book, he makes a very salient point about how horror never exists in the moment.
Speaker 1: You're never horrified in the moment of some gigantic looming catastrophe.
Speaker 1: You're only horrified in retrospect.
Speaker 0: Or going in.
Speaker 1: And the people who feel horror during the event are the ones who cannot deal with the event and thus don't survive.
Speaker 0: Courage.
Speaker 0: Anyway.
Speaker 0: Uh, other meta moment.
Speaker 0: You know what's happening one week after New Year's?
Speaker 1: I believe it is...
Speaker 0: MAGFEST!
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: Oh my god, I'm so excited.
Speaker 0: If you don't go to MAGFEST, stop listening to the show because you suck and you're not allowed to listen.
Speaker 1: Dude, a good portion of the front row crew is gonna be there.
Speaker 0: Let me change that.
Speaker 0: If you are going to MAGFEST, do not listen to the show because you're already awesome and we can't help you.
Speaker 0: If you are not going to MAGFEST, you are now hereby required to listen to every episode of Geek Nights Ever twice so that maybe you could maybe build up some awesomeness and be awesome enough for MAGFEST.
Speaker 1: We are going to be on three panels, not simultaneously at MAGFEST.
Speaker 1: We're doing our own lecture, a new one, actually an old one, Beyond Advanced Dungeons and Dragons 2nd Edition Revised.
Speaker 1: It's beyond D&D but it's totally different panels.
Speaker 0: My shit is fucked up so I got it.
Speaker 0: Shoot/slice you.
Speaker 1: We are also going to be on two discussion panels with the MAG and I guess, I don't know how many it is in the MAG anymore.
Speaker 1: Gaming Intellectuals will be on the Moneymaking Game, which funnily has a nearly similar title to a lecture we're planning to do at PAX East, if Kahil will let us.
Speaker 1: And we are going to be on Gamer Motivations, which is basically the discussion of the carrot in games.
Speaker 0: What other meta is there?
Speaker 0: You should go to the internets where we live and visit us in the places where we live on the Plus, Google and the Facebooking and the Twats.
Speaker 1: Much more importantly, you should go to the Geek Nights Rim YouTube channel and like all that shit because not only is there good shit there...
Speaker 0: Because you need more likes, because you don't want to pay for likes from Mark Zuckerberg.
Speaker 1: Exactly, I want you to like it up.
Speaker 0: We need legitimate likes guys, serious.
Speaker 1: Of course, if you think our videos suck, you should dislike them and post about it.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's enough.
Speaker 0: That's enough.
Speaker 1: So, someone on the forum posted recently, and I forget what we were talking about, and they said something like, "What do you guys think of paired
Speaker 1: programming?".
Speaker 1: And Scott and I looked at each other over the internet and we were like, "Simultaneously, I got shit to say about
Speaker 1: that.".
Speaker 0: So here's the deal, right?
Speaker 0: When you work, in the olden days, in Henry Ford's factory, right?
Speaker 0: Your work is pretty much do this thing over and over again, right?
Speaker 0: And it's just, you know, do a manual labor, just like at Foxconn, you know, hit this nail, screw this screw.
Speaker 0: So it's easily quantifiable and it's easily manageable because it's just how many can a guy do in an hour?
Speaker 0: He gets tired.
Speaker 0: He needs this many breaks.
Speaker 0: We need this many people.
Speaker 0: You know, it's an easily quantifiable and easily manageable thing.
Speaker 0: And over decades, we have become pretty much experts at managing that sort of labor.
Speaker 0: But when it comes to art, right, you know, you don't really manage artists.
Speaker 0: You just sort of like, you know, authors.
Speaker 0: It's like, how do you manage an author?
Speaker 0: I guess someone out there is probably going to tell me I'm dumb that you do manage authors somehow, you know, but you don't manage Picasso, right?
Speaker 0: You're not going to tell me that he needs a manager, right?
Speaker 0: He just sort of does his arts and he makes the arts.
Speaker 1: He was only able to do that because of reputation and having the income to be able to do it.
Speaker 0: I'm not saying I'm not thinking about the economics of it.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying he doesn't need some sort of structure to like, you know, his day or some procedure to follow.
Speaker 0: He's, you know, his muse comes to him and he he makes the paintings.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But programming is always been, you know, for the past decade or two, this sort of weird in-between place where you're sort of doing a work, you know, but you're also doing an arts.
Speaker 0: And, you know, ever since, you know, even before, you know, the Mythical Man month, people have been trying to figure out how to manage and sort of, you know, structure the work of programmers to quantify it and sort of, you know, manage it and structure it in some way.
Speaker 0: And there are lots and lots and lots of different ideas.
Speaker 0: And we haven't really had a lot of time to test out many of them scientifically.
Speaker 0: Some have, some have not, you know, so we only have so much data to go on to, you know, objectively say what works and what doesn't.
Speaker 0: So now it's not just there's a lot of people who are trying to do a lot of things that are new and there isn't a whole lot of data to say what's a good idea, what's a bad idea.
Speaker 1: The thing is, I want to expand it a little bit.
Speaker 1: It's not just programming because, you know, I know it's mostly software.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but computer stuff in general, there's, you know, management in that field is also kind of a new and strange thing, especially with the advent of, you know, ticketing systems and technology.
Speaker 1: To actually track workflow and actually do metrics on things.
Speaker 1: And there's a lot of certifications and a lot of methodologies like Sigma and the Sigma 7, Sigma 6, whatever, or IDLE compliance, ITIL and all this stuff.
Speaker 0: And
Speaker 1: it's actually a very related discussion because I found in general, just to get into my opinion on all this, is that the majority of people who look to any of these to improve their process and follow them per the rules of their own systems, like I'm going to implement Scrum and they follow the rules of Scrum 100 percent, tend not to do that well.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the thing is we don't really have any data to know who does well, right?
Speaker 0: It's just people sort of, you know, some people do things and some people like what they came up with.
Speaker 0: And so they continue to do it and some people don't like it and they try something else and they just do what they like, but they don't necessarily do what's best or no one really even knows what's best.
Speaker 0: In most of the cases.
Speaker 0: But what it comes down to is even an IT guy, right?
Speaker 0: A software guy is even harder because in software you're doing something that has never been done before, because if it's been done before, you don't have to do it.
Speaker 1: You can just get it unless you work for a large enterprise company.
Speaker 0: So most of the time you're doing something new and someone's asking you even the simplest question, estimate how long this will take.
Speaker 0: And you can sometimes estimate based on a lot of things, but they're basically saying you're about to do something that's never been done before.
Speaker 0: How long is it going to take?
Speaker 0: You know, and it's like I can only get so close and there's a chance that it's going to take way longer or maybe even way less than I estimated, even though I made a really good guess based on a lot of information and experience.
Speaker 1: Now, there are a ton of, you know, scientific and I'm making quote marks, methodologies for figuring out how long stuff will take, you know, scoping and sizing of projects in software and in everything.
Speaker 1: And they usually actually involve a good degree of math and weightings and things.
Speaker 1: And I found that they're about as accurate as a relatively experienced person just making a gut guess.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And, you know, sometimes you're going to be pretty close, you know, but most of the time you're going to be like maybe a month off or something like that, depending on the size of the project.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: And, you know, over the course of a career or at least a job you have at a company for many years, at least once you're going to be way the fuck off by a long time.
Speaker 0: You know, there's going to be something that you thought, you know, or estimated would take a few months and takes like a year or half a year or something ridiculous like that.
Speaker 0: It will happen at least once.
Speaker 0: you see it happen all the time.
Speaker 0: And worst case, you know, Duke Nukem forever.
Speaker 0: Best case, I've never seen a best case.
Speaker 0: Have you ever seen anyone like turn something out overnight?
Speaker 0: They thought would take a year.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen that.
Speaker 1: Not a year, but I have had programmers surprise me.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, but even in IT, right, in IT, you know, you're not necessarily creating something new.
Speaker 0: You're just sort of setting up a software or installing a thing or configuring a thing.
Speaker 1: You are creating something new, but in a different regard.
Speaker 1: But what you're creating that's new is all the glue between a bunch of other things.
Speaker 1: And while those solutions are well known, the actual details of your environment make it such that what you're doing is effectively an entirely new thing.
Speaker 1: Because nobody's actually taking like a ticketing system and a software development system and repositories and servers and software and installing them with default configurations and integrating them via UIs or defined APIs.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: There's a bunch of cruft in between because you got something that's customized.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: it's a little bit a little bit easier to estimate and work things out with IT, but not much.
Speaker 0: You know, you're always going to have like, well, how long does it take to set up exchange?
Speaker 0: Well, about a couple of hours.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Well, you got to migrate our exchange server.
Speaker 0: OK, there are specific things in our old exchange server.
Speaker 0: They're going to cause you a lot of fucking trouble.
Speaker 0: Well, now I have no fucking clue.
Speaker 0: Here's a big example.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll look up that thing on Google and I'll have it in one hour extra.
Speaker 0: Maybe it'll actually be a nightmare that requires an overnight thingy.
Speaker 0: Maybe it requires even more work.
Speaker 1: IT project I ever had for a real company was when I was working for ITS at RIT.
Speaker 0: Oh, not IBM?
Speaker 0: OK.
Speaker 1: No, this is my first real project.
Speaker 1: I had worked before IBM.
Speaker 1: And actually, no, I worked there after I worked at IBM the first time anyway.
Speaker 1: So what we had to do was migrate all the computers on RIT's faculty and administration network to Active Directory.
Speaker 1: They weren't on the domain.
Speaker 1: There were a bunch of like other domains around and it was kind of this hodgepodge.
Speaker 1: Simultaneous to that, we had to migrate all of them to exchange.
Speaker 1: Most of them had Outlook connecting to God only knows what.
Speaker 0: Grace or Vex.
Speaker 1: And every one of those people could not lose their like 10 years of accumulated emails.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can import into Exchange, export it to a file.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, you say that.
Speaker 1: OK, that is what to do.
Speaker 1: This is why IT sizing is so difficult.
Speaker 1: There is a pretty straightforward path to doing this.
Speaker 1: Try doing it for more than a thousand people, each of whom have a slightly different environment.
Speaker 1: And some of whom, in fact, almost all of whom have one thing that throws a monkey wrench into that.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And that project took the better part of six months.
Speaker 0: And it was a lot of people working on it.
Speaker 0: There were just one guy, an army of guys.
Speaker 1: I would go to an office and I'd have like 10 people with me and I'd fan them out across all these computers.
Speaker 1: And nine of them would come back and say, oh, there's a problem.
Speaker 1: And I'd have to do it myself.
Speaker 1: And the number of things you would run into, like we set everyone up with these admin accounts.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 1: Every one of them would add nine or 10 computers to the domain and then couldn't add them anymore because the accounts that were created happened to have a restriction where you could only add an account to the domain before your account was barred from adding further ones without special approval.
Speaker 1: Nobody in the entire organization was prepared for that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So let's talk about a few specific methodology thingies.
Speaker 0: I guess the most popular one is, you know, is one that's pretty, pretty talked about frequently.
Speaker 0: Internet is this pair programing, which is an aspect of something that was popularized by some books and some other guys who came up with it, which is extreme programing.
Speaker 0: And, you know, basically I haven't looked too much into it because whatever.
Speaker 1: But I have an opinion on it.
Speaker 0: But yeah, but pretty much what it comes down to, at least the basic idea of pair programing.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Which is an aspect of extreme programing, which is extreme is that instead of sitting there and coding by yourself, you actually get two people.
Speaker 0: One person is at the keyboard and one person is just sitting there.
Speaker 0: And basically the person who's just sitting there says what to code and the other person types it in.
Speaker 0: And you can sort of think together and discuss and all this stuff.
Speaker 0: And the idea is that, you know, most of the time you spend coding is time you spend thinking.
Speaker 0: It's not the typing isn't the bottleneck.
Speaker 0: So even if you should actually put the slower typing person at the keyboard, you know, that way you have more time to sit and think and look.
Speaker 0: And it's not really slowing you down with the slow typing, the thinking and figuring out what to type is where all your time is.
Speaker 0: So if two of you work together, not only will you come up with the correct thing to type faster.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You'll both keep each other on task instead of browsing the Internet's all the time.
Speaker 0: But on top of that, you'll have fewer bugs because you have two sets of eyes to recognize them like, aha, you missed a thing there.
Speaker 0: Oh, I missed a thing.
Speaker 1: Now, there's a. there's a great picture of this.
Speaker 1: I went to the Wikipedia article on pair programing because there is one and the picture is clearly a fake one.
Speaker 1: One of the programmers is pointing at the screen and the other one is looking.
Speaker 1: No one ever does that in the real world.
Speaker 0: That picture you see is a stock photo.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Two.
Speaker 0: We got that b-roll.
Speaker 1: Two in the background.
Speaker 0: Guy pointing at a computer, one of the guy looks on, we got that b-roll.
Speaker 1: There's actually like a proper looking scrum like clipboard, you know, the kind of like scrum tracking thing people would use.
Speaker 1: I've never seen someone actually use it like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And three is on a Mac and he's using the mouse.
Speaker 0: So this is one of those things where it's like, OK, some.
Speaker 0: I do know that some people definitely do this.
Speaker 0: I've met people who do this and they say they do it at work.
Speaker 0: I met these people in person, never met anyone who's done it.
Speaker 0: I've met people who say they have done it.
Speaker 0: I've never seen a workplace in person that is doing it, but I have met people who say they do it at work every day.
Speaker 0: That's all they do.
Speaker 0: And, you know, they personally like it.
Speaker 0: Do they have any evidence, actual studies and, you know, observed cases to, you know, compare it with controls against something to show that it is actually more efficient and produces less bugs?
Speaker 0: Not really.
Speaker 0: I mean, there's some stuff out there, but not a substantial body of, you know, work to show that this is a good way of doing things.
Speaker 1: I have a guess, though, and I also have an environment where I think it is a very useful thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but, you know,
Speaker 1: I guess is that it only works well if the two people involved are reasonably socialized at a similar seniority and at a similar ability level, because otherwise the guy who knows more is just going to code the whole thing and the other guy is just going to kind of type it all in.
Speaker 0: But maybe that guy will learn something.
Speaker 1: Maybe he will, but it's probably going to slow the more senior guy down.
Speaker 1: And I thought the whole goal of this was to make better code, not to train.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe once in a while that guy who's not as good will notice a bug in the thing the other guy wrote.
Speaker 0: Maybe.
Speaker 1: But I feel like just from experience, when a more junior software engineer or IT guy is working with a senior person, they'll pretty much defer to the senior person even when the senior person is wrong for various social reasons.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: You know, basically, you know, no, we don't.
Speaker 0: I've never done pair program in any place, but every place I've ever worked is basically you're sitting there doing your work.
Speaker 0: And if you have a real problem, yes, another guy, because you never were completely alone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean, my one and suddenly you can have two or maybe even three or four guys all looking at the same thing, trying to figure it out.
Speaker 0: And, you know, usually just in the course of explaining what it is to everyone, you'll figure out what's wrong with it.
Speaker 1: I mean, one of my senior developers will just get up and go to the other coders, be like, I'm having trouble with this and I'll just kind of huddle for five minutes and they'll go back to work.
Speaker 0: So just because huddling is sometimes effective to solve a problem doesn't mean you should stay in the huddle the whole time.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You're playing football, you huddle up, you break and you go, you know, you do the play.
Speaker 1: No, we should remake football to be more efficient.
Speaker 1: It's all huddles.
Speaker 0: Actually.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's all huddles.
Speaker 0: Actually, they're thinking about if they add technology to football, they might be able to eliminate the huddle if everyone has a headset.
Speaker 1: That'd be awesome.
Speaker 0: It would be the awesome.
Speaker 1: I would love to listen to that headset during the game to.
Speaker 0: they have headsets now, but they're all encrypted and you can't listen because that means the other team will be able to listen, which ruins the whole thing.
Speaker 0: But it does remove an aspect of the game, which is the, you know, they keep changing the number of, you know, who's in the huddles.
Speaker 0: You don't know who's going to be on the play to sort of get the other guy to mess up his substitutions.
Speaker 0: You bring you know, you got a slow guy in the huddle, so they let their fast guy take a rest and then you switch, which is why you're not allowed to have more than a certain number of guys.
Speaker 1: Imagine if we had a technology, complete aside, where at the line where the ball is, there was an opaque screen.
Speaker 1: You could walk through it, but there's no big screen would just appear every time the whistle blew and neither team could see what was going on on the other side.
Speaker 1: And that screen disappeared the moment the hike happened.
Speaker 0: That'd be the awesomeness.
Speaker 1: I would I would kill.
Speaker 0: Well, it couldn't.
Speaker 0: No, it couldn't be at the point of the snap because then it'd be like you line up and you don't even get to see the defense.
Speaker 0: No, no.
Speaker 0: Part of part of part of football is seeing how the other guys line up and trying to fake the other guys out, you know, that kind of thing.
Speaker 0: But it would be cool if it didn't go away until like the center put his hand on the ball.
Speaker 0: And then, you know, you got to see what the other how the other team was looking.
Speaker 0: That would be that would be a little bit more interesting.
Speaker 1: But anyway, one place where I could see this working really well is extremely security sensitive environments like a government place where you're writing software for important spy things, because then then you're getting benefits that you don't even need science to prove that are actually better.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: For example, in order to put a backdoor in the code, you need an accomplice to simultaneously decide to do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Then dependent of passing code review, you have a special case.
Speaker 0: You're getting a guaranteed benefit.
Speaker 0: You don't need science to prove it's a benefit.
Speaker 0: And it's worth even if there are other harms, it's worth it because security is so extremely important.
Speaker 1: A special case that I don't believe and I have no evidence of this, that there are places where there will have two teams or two people code the same thing simultaneously with no communication.
Speaker 1: And then a third person will review both of their code and then write the solution based on those two.
Speaker 1: Again, high security, military, possibly never actually done in practice.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I mean, that's not a bad idea either, right?
Speaker 0: Because then if one guy writes a backdoor, he doesn't know if his back door is actually in the product or not.
Speaker 0: And, you know, so it's like, well, you're not even going to try to write a backdoor because someone else looks at your code before it gets in.
Speaker 0: And, you know, you don't even know who that guy is.
Speaker 0: So you can't be your accomplice and you don't even know if it's actually going to make it in there because someone else is doing it also.
Speaker 0: So there's not even a point to do and it's just do your work.
Speaker 1: So very popular.
Speaker 1: I want to talk about is Agile, particularly Scrum.
Speaker 0: Well, Agile, it's weird because a lot of these things.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: A lot of the reason I think a lot of them are such snake oil is because they're so ill-defined.
Speaker 0: And like, there's always going to be some guy who says, that's not Agile.
Speaker 0: This is Agile.
Speaker 0: I'm not Agile expert, blah, blah, blah.
Speaker 0: And maybe, maybe that guy is.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: I've read stuff that's like by the guy who came up with certain things and he says, I came up with it.
Speaker 0: I'm the inventor of this thing.
Speaker 0: And he is.
Speaker 0: And he says, this is what the thing is.
Speaker 0: But there'll be some other guy who's the expert on the thing, even though he didn't come up with it, who says, no, no, no, it's something different.
Speaker 1: That's why you can't evaluate something so ephemeral or because these words, people instead you have to define like people make very specific systems based on these like Scrum.
Speaker 1: There's some pretty particular rules about how to do Scrum.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: It's like people came up with like these sets of rules and instructions and procedures and everyone is actually doing something different.
Speaker 0: And a lot of people are calling it the same thing, like, oh, we're an Agile workplace.
Speaker 0: We're an Agile workplace.
Speaker 1: But at the same time, you go to the two workplaces and they look completely different.
Speaker 1: And there are things like IDIL, I-T-I-L, which are extremely, excruciatingly defined in detail.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But it's sort of a no true Scotsman.
Speaker 0: It's like we're Agile.
Speaker 0: No, you're not really Agile.
Speaker 1: But Scott, what about things like IDIL where there's kind of a board that decides and that is it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, that's a different thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's what I was saying.
Speaker 1: There are things like that, too.
Speaker 1: My problem with all of these is that they all have these big graphics that remind me of what I studied at RIT in classes, unlike project management.
Speaker 1: And they're all completely useless.
Speaker 1: They either tell you something obvious like work on stuff, then QA it, then work on stuff.
Speaker 1: Like, do you need a graph to explain that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, no.
Speaker 1: Do you need to have the thing that says plan your project before you write it?
Speaker 1: Does someone actually need someone to tell them that?
Speaker 1: The thing is, I kind of worry that that, in fact, is necessary.
Speaker 0: Sometimes.
Speaker 0: But and the thing is, a lot of people have these things on paper, but don't actually do them.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like we put such emphasis on like maintenance, documentation or testing or no one's test driven.
Speaker 1: Development is never on the road.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: It's like people have all these things on paper.
Speaker 0: These procedures and stuff, they don't follow them for shit.
Speaker 0: I have never been in a place.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: A lot of the test driven development.
Speaker 0: That's one that drives me crazy.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Because, you know, there's some cases where it's a good idea in some cases where it's a bad idea or whatever.
Speaker 0: But it's like how many people actually have tests?
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Like, you know, it's one of those things where you go online and you read articles written by people.
Speaker 0: Here's a great example.
Speaker 0: It's not actually of a, you know, a software development technique, but it's like, you know, a deployment.
Speaker 0: This is a particular web software deployment technology.
Speaker 0: And everyone, if you read articles, is like, oh, you got to be using these tools for deployment.
Speaker 0: They're amazing.
Speaker 0: They're amazing tools.
Speaker 0: You got to use them.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: So my coworker goes to a conference and everyone is like, you got to use these tools.
Speaker 0: And I had seen a zillion articles about using these tools.
Speaker 0: So one guy gets up in front of the thing and says, these tools are the greatest.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: You know, everyone's got to use them.
Speaker 0: Who here is using them right now?
Speaker 0: Nobody.
Speaker 0: Who here is planning to use them soon?
Speaker 0: A whole bunch of people.
Speaker 0: OK, so that same guy giving that talk, saying how those tools were great later on gives another thing like how we do it at my company.
Speaker 1: They don't use any of those tools, do they?
Speaker 0: He's not actually using them yet.
Speaker 0: So, yeah, you're right.
Speaker 1: That's the thing.
Speaker 0: He's like, yeah, we just had of all these hacks built on the old tools.
Speaker 1: I've dealt with a lot of this stuff.
Speaker 1: I mean, part of my job now is managing a bunch of developers for this stuff.
Speaker 0: A lot of people, I bet, who are emphasizing the agile's and the scrums and the test driven developments.
Speaker 1: They're not using it.
Speaker 1: They all think that they will be using it someday.
Speaker 1: Every one of those people has a plan to use them, plans to do the documentation and a plan to do that.
Speaker 1: When you said yet, that's the key, because with all these software development methodologies, everyone I have ever met who spouses them will say we are working toward implementing them.
Speaker 1: And I've never met anyone who actually implemented them fully.
Speaker 0: Yep, never.
Speaker 1: Some people have gotten close, though.
Speaker 1: And I think for some professional advice, the real key is to learn about these things and look for stuff that you think will work in your environment and pick and choose and come up with a methodology that works for your own internal environment.
Speaker 1: And by trial and error, make it better over time.
Speaker 1: If you try if you try to implement scrum and religiously follow it to the point that you let the rules actually drive your process and get in the way, then you're probably worse off.
Speaker 0: That's the thing that bothers me about them the most over everything else is not necessarily, you know, they're not actually helping you.
Speaker 0: They are actually helping you.
Speaker 0: You don't have evidence to show they're helping you.
Speaker 0: That doesn't really bother me as much as the fact that when you do these people concentrate so much on the procedure of work, that actually they end up doing more meta work than work.
Speaker 0: They'll spend more time like modifying their tickets and arranging their Kanban board and, you know, having the little meetings and getting with the team and organizing the thingies and distributing the workflows and all that time.
Speaker 0: They spend doing all that nonsense, which is supposedly going to increase the efficiency of their work.
Speaker 0: They're just not working.
Speaker 0: They're doing this meta work instead of doing work work.
Speaker 0: That's like if we sat around half the day discussing how we're going to do the thing and then only spent half the day doing the thing.
Speaker 0: If we wouldn't have had any organization or maybe only had five minutes of organization, even if without any official procedure, and then just spent all day doing the work, even if we were working less efficiently, we would probably still get more work done.
Speaker 1: I disagree for one reason that usually it's because it takes a lot of work to set up one of these systems or to set something up in general, set up the internal infrastructure to manage products in a sort of verifiable or controlled way.
Speaker 1: But once it's set up, if it's maintained and works, then it probably pays out dividends in the end.
Speaker 1: It doesn't.
Speaker 1: It's not like you have to rebuild the process for every new project.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of it depends on the size of your project, you know, because when you get more people, you need more meta work.
Speaker 0: There's just no way to get all the people to work in concert without the meta work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the thing is, you have to be smart about it and you pick and choose what parts work.
Speaker 1: Like in idle, there's this idea of if you're categorizing the severity of a problem, like a bug comes in and you're tracking it and whatever ticketing system you use, instead of just having a priority like A, B, C, D, E or high, medium, low or whatever, it has the idea that priority is always the two dimensional matrix with two elements.
Speaker 1: The severity or the urgency, depending on how you want to call it.
Speaker 1: I believe the technical term is urgency, but whatever.
Speaker 1: And the impact, like what it impacts.
Speaker 1: So, for example, the difference between something that impacts revenue and is low priority versus something that doesn't impact revenue, but is high urgency.
Speaker 1: The idea of separating impact from urgency.
Speaker 0: Like, oh, my God, it crashes, but we're not actually losing any monies.
Speaker 0: or hey, this isn't really a crash.
Speaker 0: It's just like a weird number error.
Speaker 0: And it's only in this tiny thing that's hardly ever used, but it is losing us a tiny amount of monies.
Speaker 1: But the idea of separating impact from urgency and then prioritizing based on a combination of the two is a fantastic idea and everyone should do it.
Speaker 0: It's a good idea.
Speaker 0: Going the rest of the way, you don't necessarily need to follow all the idle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, implementing all of idle.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't believe that anyone in the world has.
Speaker 0: There's probably some place they got certified and is doing it just because they wanted some bureaucracy nonsense.
Speaker 1: And I've studied it a lot because I've implemented aspects of it in ticketing systems.
Speaker 1: But spending a lot of time to define workflows and things is very important.
Speaker 1: The problem is people who aren't naturally good at organizing tend to fall back on these systems and tend to put a lot of effort into implementing the systems, probably more so than they should be compared to the time they should be spending on just actually getting the project going.
Speaker 0: Well, also, people who tend to be bad at organizing tend to really just.
Speaker 0: they can't stick to the system like they really want to in their minds.
Speaker 0: Like they have this idea, like I'm going to get an organizer and they get an organizer and they start using it and they get a to do list and they use it for about a day.
Speaker 0: And then they forget about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, that's the analogy.
Speaker 1: I know a lot of people who do this.
Speaker 1: I used to do it.
Speaker 1: You'll need to work on some stuff.
Speaker 1: You're sitting at home at Saturday like, shit, I got to get some stuff done.
Speaker 1: So you sit down, you say, I'm going to make a list of all the things I have to do.
Speaker 1: And the Twilight Sparkle style, you sit there for an hour and make this exhaustive list and prioritize it.
Speaker 1: And then you feel like you got a bunch of work done.
Speaker 0: So you take a break and then you at the end of the day, you didn't get any of those things.
Speaker 0: Go back to the list and you spent an hour making a list.
Speaker 0: Congratulations.
Speaker 0: You made a list.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Good job.
Speaker 1: Now, if you want to break yourself of that habit, if you make a list like that, you're not allowed to throw it away.
Speaker 1: You've got to leave it on your desk and look at that fucker every day and feel bad about it.
Speaker 1: That's the only way to break that cycle.
Speaker 1: The moment you say it and you make a new list, you're done.
Speaker 1: It's over.
Speaker 1: You've lost.
Speaker 0: But yeah, that's how these things go.
Speaker 0: So, you know, when someone tries to sell you on like a test driven development or an agile this or whatever, that that just sort of tells me that, you know, not necessarily that they're a bad person or that they're no good, but that they sort of, you know, easily seduced by these these ideas.
Speaker 0: They sort of had this naive attitude that these that these magical systems are kind of awesome.
Speaker 1: They're seduced by the idea that if they find some instructions on how to do X, like project management or software development, and they follow them, that it'll just work.
Speaker 1: Kind of like how if I follow the instructions on an Ikea thing, an Ikea thing comes out at the end.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like they have this imaginary sort of world where all their projects are managed in this beautiful structure.
Speaker 0: And, you know, you always test driven development.
Speaker 0: We're going to write before we write any code, we're going to write a test and write the code every time.
Speaker 0: And they believe in this like fantasy universe that they will and everything's perfectly documented.
Speaker 0: documentation always gets updated in the wiki.
Speaker 0: And they believe that that universe exists.
Speaker 0: They can imagine it in their minds and how great it would be.
Speaker 0: And they actually believe that they're going to go there and that they are going there instead of recognizing that that is a fantasy land that can never exist.
Speaker 1: Yup.
Speaker 1: You know, to quote something that gets said often, actually releasing something is a feature.
Speaker 1: And here's a story from my past.
Speaker 1: When I was a senior production engineer, my old job, I would often be approached by developers or people who would say something to the effect of we need to get this patch, whatever it is, into this production environment.
Speaker 1: We can't wait for a full regression test.
Speaker 1: It's a small patch.
Speaker 1: It's not that big a deal.
Speaker 1: And of course, I would say no, because, you know, and then I'd get overruled and I'd always be mad about that.
Speaker 0: Did you get it in writing?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but I'd always get overruled.
Speaker 0: You just got to say you just got to get it in writing that they overruled you so that then you can have the I told you so stack.
Speaker 1: Let's do a Monday show on the proper means of covering one's ass in the real technical world.
Speaker 0: Get it in writing.
Speaker 0: End of story.
Speaker 0: Yeah, someone rang the doorbell.
Speaker 1: Anyway, but I used to always say things to myself like if I was in charge, you know, I wouldn't I wouldn't be the one who overrules those things.
Speaker 1: I would follow the process.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't follow the process, but I also, you know, wouldn't do certain things like letting untested grab code.
Speaker 1: Well, no, it's not a matter of untested.
Speaker 1: Imagine something that was tested by developers and was tested by QA, but the full system was not re-regression tested, even though there was a low chance of a regression anywhere else in the system.
Speaker 0: Well, since I know how the thing works, because I'm actually a technology person and I'm not one of those bosses who's just a boss and doesn't actually know how the shit works, I would look at the specific thing.
Speaker 0: And decide or I would just trust whoever was under me close most closely and not even it was also a discussion.
Speaker 1: But like, for example, a procedure was put in place where when code is ready to go to production, their release notes, they have to be signed by all the approvers and pretty much without fail, there'd be someone who wasn't around to sign.
Speaker 1: You have to roll something out anyway, and someone would overrule them, at which point, why even have the process if you're obviously going to, you know, violate it every time you have to.
Speaker 1: Now that I'm a manager and I deal with this stuff and I'm the boss who has to sign the overruling procedures and everything, I'm pretty much doing everything that I always used to complain about.
Speaker 0: Don't be doing that.
Speaker 1: Now, because I know better and I know that, you know, decisions I'm making are actually pretty safe.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Has anything fucked up yet?
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: But when the bosses you had before made those decisions, did shit get fucked up?
Speaker 1: Occasionally.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So has you fucked up anything ever?
Speaker 1: I once choned an entire production system to be owned by Apache.
Speaker 0: I meant as the boss, have you, when you overruled, have you fucked it up?
Speaker 1: I have not yet, but I have not worked at this new company that long.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: But you know about the technologies?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: The people that were your boss before, did they know about the technologies?
Speaker 0: They did.
Speaker 0: Did they?
Speaker 0: As much as you?
Speaker 1: Depends on what realms.
Speaker 0: See, here's the thing, right?
Speaker 0: I noticed this, this is sort of getting off topic, but I've noticed when I look at companies these days, I can sort of tell the good and the bad company.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: Look at the company like HP.
Speaker 0: Who's in charge of HP?
Speaker 0: Just business people.
Speaker 0: They don't know shit about computers, technology or anything like that.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But look at Marriott Hotel.
Speaker 0: The guy just died recently, which is kind of sad because he's actually a pretty cool guy.
Speaker 0: The Marriott Hotel guy was like the master of hotels.
Speaker 0: Like dude would figure out how to fold the sheets faster and shit like that.
Speaker 0: You know, like he knew about hotels.
Speaker 0: And when you have bosses that actually know about the work that's being done, that's when the good shit happens.
Speaker 0: You know, Steve Jobs actually knew about computers and things.
Speaker 0: That's why they were successful.
Speaker 0: It's when the companies are run by business people who only know about monies and managing.
Speaker 1: But at the same time.
Speaker 0: When you get shit fucked up.
Speaker 1: You have that layer of middle management or management or executives that are pure technologists, but who don't have other skills.
Speaker 1: Well, obviously, well, obviously.
Speaker 0: But I do believe that anyone who just has normal social skills and intelligence and also, you know, the skills of whatever the job is can become the boss and they can learn to be the boss.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Couldn't if you were already a boss and that was all you could do.
Speaker 0: You could shit on Deborah's desk, but you couldn't know about it.
Speaker 1: What is one of the most common complaints about people who become senior technologists or developers?
Speaker 1: They get pushed toward being the boss and they don't want to be the boss.
Speaker 0: Well, then don't make that guy the boss.
Speaker 1: I'm sure there's a guy who wouldn't mind being the boss, but also I think there is a huge shortage of people who want to be the boss and are technologically skilled.
Speaker 0: Perhaps there's a but there's a shortage of people where technology is skilled, period.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: But so I'm saying that it doesn't have to be technology in a shoe factory.
Speaker 0: The boss should know something about shoes.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And I'm saying that in general, there's a shortage of people who know about underlying whatevers, not even just technology, who also want to be a boss and have the basic skills to be a boss.
Speaker 0: But that doesn't mean, you know, but maybe have, you know, just keeping the current boss, whoever it may be, is better than putting in a bad boss who's only a boss and doesn't know about the thing.
Speaker 0: Or at the very least, right, if you're going to bring in someone who's just a boss or someone who went to business school as a manager, make them learn the thing.
Speaker 0: A lot of times you put that person in without even at least try.
Speaker 0: I mean, they're not going to become a programmer or a shoemaker or a cobbler, whatever it is that the company does.
Speaker 0: Maybe make towels.
Speaker 0: They're not going to become a weaver.
Speaker 0: Right.
Speaker 0: But at least make them learn about weaving as much as they can before making them the boss of the textile mill.
Speaker 0: You know, at least try.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, a lot of times you put these people in there who don't know about the thing.
Speaker 1: They went to like they got a communications degree and an MBA and now they're middle.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: They're just a professional boss.
Speaker 0: They don't know about the thing you do and they don't care and they're not even going to try to learn it.
Speaker 0: They just say, get it done.
Speaker 1: So I guess the final moral professional advice I have, having been in all the different levels of this personally, is that you use you come up with a process that works to get whatever it is you're trying to do done.
Speaker 1: And the moment you start to say things like, let's implement, you know, X methodology, you know, if you can explain to another human being specifically what you think will be better after you implement it and why.
Speaker 1: Go for it.
Speaker 1: If your explanation is it'll make our process better, you're committing logical fallacies and you're not going anywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And you know what about your process is going to get better and why and how it's going to make it better.
Speaker 0: You know, you've got to actually also get the people do it, but like aspects of scrum work really well.
Speaker 1: The idea of having periodic short meetings that are time constrained, where you get out.
Speaker 1: What did I do?
Speaker 1: What am I doing next?
Speaker 1: What is in my way?
Speaker 1: That concept is fantastic.
Speaker 0: It's an OK concept.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But maybe that, you know, you don't need to make sure everyone knows that everyone else is working on all the time.
Speaker 0: You're all on the same page, but it doesn't take up too much time out of the day.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's a common sense kind of thing, you know.
Speaker 0: But it's like, you know, have we done a huge study as to, you know, as opposed to what?
Speaker 1: Maybe you can come up with a better idea when you start worrying about who the pigs are and like actually using the jargon fully.
Speaker 1: Unless you can articulate how that helps you, then you shouldn't be doing it.
Speaker 1: Now, you might be able to articulate it.
Speaker 1: And, you know, those things do work in certain situations.
Speaker 1: But it's kind of like to talk back about skiing.
Speaker 1: I was looking at skis a long time ago.
Speaker 1: I wanted to buy some skis.
Speaker 1: I went to the guy and I said, what's the difference between these two skis?
Speaker 1: One was like double the price.
Speaker 1: And he was like, that one's blue.
Speaker 1: And I was like, no, really, what's the difference?
Speaker 1: And he was like, see this thing here?
Speaker 1: I'm like, yeah.
Speaker 1: He's like, it'll reduce shutter.
Speaker 1: And I'm like, what does that mean?
Speaker 1: And he said, if you can explain to me what it means, then you should buy that ski.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, you should buy the cheaper one.
Speaker 1: And you know what?
Speaker 1: That was the best advice I ever got for pretty much anything I've ever done.
Speaker 0: That guy's a bad salesman.
Speaker 0: He should have said the more expensive one is clearly superior.
Speaker 1: This has been Geek Nights with Rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Cat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion, news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember, Geek Nights is not one, but four different shows.
Speaker 1: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek Nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.