Speaker 0: It's Thursday, April 19th, 2011.
Speaker 0: I'm Rem.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, we talk about asses and Mars and reactors Quaid.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: I Swear this has nothing to do with all this sudden news about Arnold having a kid.
Speaker 1: It's a nice coincidence.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we just happen to.
Speaker 0: you know many people in our crew had never seen Total Recall and Why are you skipping in the second half of the show right away?
Speaker 0: It's one of those movies that everyone's seen so we made sure everyone saw it.
Speaker 0: But the reason I bring it up early is that I didn't care at all about this whole.
Speaker 0: You know Arnold had a kid and he was paying child support.
Speaker 0: I don't care either.
Speaker 0: So I Happened to see a picture of the kid.
Speaker 0: All right, and you know, what's great.
Speaker 1: Is he gigantic?
Speaker 0: The kid looks Exactly like Arnold like not even like a little like Arnold but like it's Arnold Baby Arnold like there is no doubt to the paternity of this child.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so in much more happy news it was sunny today.
Speaker 0: Rainbow Dash finally did her job.
Speaker 0: not really I was sunny most of the day.
Speaker 1: Have you looked out the window like right this second?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: I had a nice lunch at Bryan Park Sun was out.
Speaker 0: the white stones of the library were gleaming so hard I can hardly look at him.
Speaker 0: the library I got a go-to in about a day and because it was raining in the morning hardly anyone was in the park.
Speaker 0: So it was just fantastic.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: And there were signs all over the park.
Speaker 0: You know what those signs said?
Speaker 1: don't go on the grass smell the flowers not the smoke.
Speaker 0: all smoking banned May 23rd.
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah We still guys not yet May 23rd yet though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got a few more days.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna happen.
Speaker 1: That's post apocalypse.
Speaker 1: We're never gonna see.
Speaker 1: Oh, right the non-smoking bark I Mean and no one will smoke tobacco in the park instead.
Speaker 1: There'll be brimstone smell.
Speaker 1: I Actually like the smell of brimstone.
Speaker 0: So you'd better listen to geek nights pretty soon because this is pretty much it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you if you wanted to listen to some old episodes Maybe we should.
Speaker 1: maybe we should you know, stop being nice after the apocalypse.
Speaker 1: It's gotta end sometime, right?
Speaker 1: We can't do it when we're 90 years old.
Speaker 1: We I think we could especially since when I'm 90 you'll be dead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm going to win the game of who lives the longest.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure I'm gonna win that game.
Speaker 1: I'm winning that game.
Speaker 0: I'll bet you all my money.
Speaker 1: That is the game that we've been playing since we were born and will not end for hopefully a long time, you know Tomorrow?
Speaker 0: supposedly Thomas Jefferson and John Adams played the same game.
Speaker 1: They did.
Speaker 1: who won?
Speaker 0: it was close.
Speaker 0: suppose It was real close.
Speaker 0: Jefferson died first, but Adam died saying Jefferson still lives.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the story that I've heard as well.
Speaker 1: True it is.
Speaker 1: we'd have to ask this story, but you know what?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: That would be awesome If the same exact thing happened, huh?
Speaker 1: Well, I'm dying and I'm like that bastard rim still is.
Speaker 1: meanwhile rim is dead.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm pretty sure that Thomas Jefferson and John Adams were exactly as they were portrayed in 1776.
Speaker 1: I think they disagreed more than we do though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we agree on a lot of fundamental Fundamentally disagree on a lot of things but they'd fundamentally disagreed on everything.
Speaker 1: They were like opposite opinion on ever write down the the whole not are both pretty keen on democracy.
Speaker 1: They were pretty keen on alcohol.
Speaker 0: Yeah and ladies And wait none so much as Benjamin Franklin.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, he was the man.
Speaker 0: I mean, why else would you go to New Brunswick?
Speaker 0: They were professionals.
Speaker 1: Ben Franklin was the master.
Speaker 0: So you got any news.
Speaker 0: it's Thursday, it's the lounge.
Speaker 1: it's whatever your lounge This is.
Speaker 1: this isn't really.
Speaker 1: it's normally would be a thing of the day But I'll make it news.
Speaker 1: Anyway, because it's not really anything in the day format So you remember the original got milk commercial?
Speaker 1: Remember where the guy Right where the guys in the the restaurant or whatever?
Speaker 0: It's probably the only reason that anyone in America today knows who Alexander Hamilton or Aaron Burr.
Speaker 1: I knew who they were before the career.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think anyone else did maybe but anyway My co-worker actually never saw the commercial.
Speaker 1: really one interesting piece of information.
Speaker 1: side note this Commercial was directed by Michael Bay The explosion guy.
Speaker 1: Wow, I know that I didn't either.
Speaker 1: So here's the story.
Speaker 1: some guy.
Speaker 1: His name is left ventricle two years ago.
Speaker 0: Okay Uploaded.
Speaker 1: his YouTube name is left ventricle.
Speaker 1: Okay, he uploaded.
Speaker 0: I was wondering is I mean is ventricle the surname like Ventricle years ago.
Speaker 1: He uploaded I think in oh eight That video of that commercial to YouTube.
Speaker 1: it got many views many many views.
Speaker 1: However, this guy left ventricle is his YouTube name.
Speaker 1: Apparently has OCD and you know YouTube comments.
Speaker 0: Did he take it down and put it back up?
Speaker 0: No, does he respond to every comment?
Speaker 1: No, he moderates all the comment.
Speaker 0: Whoa has been doing so for years Whoa, so when I made my youtube account to put up the you know The way is geek nights rim if you want geek night stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I pretty much Looked at all the stuff I could do with comments and decided that would never be worth my time, right?
Speaker 1: So what he does is like any comment.
Speaker 1: that's just like misspelled or whatever.
Speaker 1: He actually deletes this guy's any and he got pissed off because there were like certain trends in commenting Like.
Speaker 1: there are a whole bunch of people who would comment like spit out the sandwich dumbass and he would delete all those.
Speaker 1: Or the be people who would point out facts like wait wait who?
Speaker 0: Commenting to spit out the sandwich is like the old guy who yells at the screen in the movie theater.
Speaker 1: Right, but basically there are people who are posting like facts like, you know the actor, you know People would make a comment like oh the actor's name is Sean Whalen The DJ on the phone's name is Rob Paulson and director is Michael Bay.
Speaker 1: and anyone who posts that information He deletes that too because he already has it in the description I'd like.
Speaker 1: basically he's moderates this thing every day.
Speaker 0: and what do you think?
Speaker 0: We'd have to pay him to moderate our forum.
Speaker 0: He's a completely obsessive nut and yeah, I really want him to moderate our right, but I would consider paying him.
Speaker 1: But the point is is that it's like he's been doing this on this YouTube video.
Speaker 1: where he could He could just turn off comments.
Speaker 0: I want to invite him into the ivory tower.
Speaker 1: but the point just gotta read the story of this guy because it's like an epic story of a guy who does not understand the Internet and has fallen victim to it and his own.
Speaker 0: this is pretty disordered.
Speaker 0: I mean this guy is basically It's the equivalent of correcting all the graffiti that you see.
Speaker 0: not not removing the graffiti but correcting.
Speaker 1: So the top two comments are number one with 78 thumbs ups.
Speaker 1: Judging by the uploader comments in description.
Speaker 1: the person who uploaded this is a massive control freak asshole.
Speaker 1: Comment number two not 56 upvotes Michael Bay.
Speaker 1: question mark then.
Speaker 1: where the hell were all the explosions?
Speaker 1: It seems unlikely that left ventricle will ever find peace.
Speaker 0: So Very briefly.
Speaker 0: I probably will regret this but I do want to talk a little bit about President Barack Obama's recent speech about the Middle East because Many US presidents have given speeches and tried to do them.
Speaker 0: Not every single one.
Speaker 1: the top few decades.
Speaker 0: Thomas Jefferson did not give any speeches about how we need to reconcile Israel and Palestine.
Speaker 1: He cared about Tripoli just close.
Speaker 0: Yeah So, you know Carter Wanted to have peace in the Middle East and pretty much every American president is wanted to have peace in the Middle East.
Speaker 0: and we do Because you got it.
Speaker 1: You can't just do nothing because stuff is happening and you're the president's.
Speaker 0: not just that It's because the United States plays a very vital role in Israel's foreign policy of
Speaker 1: course and you know You got to do something and I bet every single one of those presidents is thinking if I'm the guy who makes the big move And actually something good comes of it then I will be remembered forever as so great.
Speaker 1: So they all try to do something.
Speaker 0: pretty much every time this has come up.
Speaker 0: the US is usually really heavily sided with Israel and for many reasons, but President Barack Obama might have grown another testicle because he Basically said that Israel needs to pull back to the 1967 borders and give up the West Bank and East Jerusalem anti-semite.
Speaker 0: And I am so proud of him for going for this.
Speaker 0: and now it's funny because you know We're doing some more hardcore panels at PAX this year.
Speaker 0: So I bought three books on game theory All right, and they're through their three levels of difficulty and so far having read one and a half of them We got this shit not difficult enough.
Speaker 0: yet We know this shit.
Speaker 0: the math is the hard part.
Speaker 0: so I flipped through the third book and the first two pages.
Speaker 0: They're like, all right.
Speaker 0: All right, the rest of the book is almost nothing but math.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 0: we'll see I've been writing utility functions and they seem to work.
Speaker 0: anyway, there's a Concept that we already know and we've already talked about this a lot on the show and in our lectures at Conventions like tax but it comes up very directly in this situation and it came up in the book I was just reading so it was fresh in my mind.
Speaker 0: It's the idea that you can play an equilibrium strategy in a strategic game like foreign policy Which guarantees you a minimum return but also limits your maximum return, you know, assuming everyone's rational.
Speaker 0: This is like your default strategy.
Speaker 0: It's the equivalent of playing conservatively in hearts.
Speaker 0: Yep, if I play conservatively and the three people I'm playing with their dumbasses I'm pretty much guaranteed to win.
Speaker 0: and if I play conservatively and everyone else is smart.
Speaker 1: Someone's gonna shoot the moon eventually because they're either gonna play conservatively or shoot the moon.
Speaker 0: but on average playing conservatively guarantees that you will not lose a game of hearts because odds are at least one person's a dumbass or Someone will make a mistake or the game will come down to use a complete randomness.
Speaker 0: But the only way to break out of a perfect equilibrium where both sides are rational is to get into the poison cup Second-guessing game where you decide that you think the other person is going to be perfectly rational.
Speaker 0: Therefore you act very irrationally and have a smaller chance of a bigger payout.
Speaker 0: That's how to you know Because it's more interesting to play a game like hearts when you go over the fucking moon because otherwise you're guaranteeing yourself second place.
Speaker 0: Who wants second place?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you might risk falling way low But you get a chance of shooting the moon and going directly to first.
Speaker 1: do not pass go now.
Speaker 0: the book gave an interesting Example because I used to always give an example of this Situation in terms of paper rock scissors the idea that if you're playing paper rock scissors against a little kid You can pretty much assume they're gonna throw scissors Because kids try it sometime.
Speaker 0: little kids feel like scissors is powerful.
Speaker 0: They tend to throw scissors first almost always.
Speaker 1: It's I remember doing that when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and no kid, you know why you're kid?
Speaker 0: You're not even like sentient yet cuz it made of metal.
Speaker 1: It's like yeah cutting is cool.
Speaker 0: It's the same way.
Speaker 0: in your little kid you got a coloring book and yours like yeah blue all over the fuck place.
Speaker 1: It's like paper whatever papers boring rocks.
Speaker 1: I have rocks in the backyard, but scissors.
Speaker 1: I'm not even allowed to play with dangerous scissors as a dangerous weapon.
Speaker 1: as a kid.
Speaker 0: I read I recognize this and I thought all right if the if the kid I'm gonna play paper rock scissors with is a dumbass I know he's gonna throw Scissors so I'm gonna throw rock.
Speaker 1: how about that?
Speaker 1: Pete and Pete.
Speaker 0: and then I would think about Someone who's one like degree removed from dumbass attitude like he's one level less of a dumbass.
Speaker 0: I assume that he knows the same thing.
Speaker 0: I know that the kids are gonna throw scissors So he assumes that I think he's gonna throw scissors.
Speaker 0: So he throws rock to get rid of my scissors.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So basically you can iterate through this repetitive mod 3 math Depending on what degree of intelligence you think the other person has relative to a five-year-old, right?
Speaker 1: But the thing is if they have once they're at the fourth level of intelligence, you know, they're gonna pick randomly.
Speaker 0: Ah, no, I don't think they will.
Speaker 0: I think that you know, I'll pick randomly.
Speaker 0: There's a modulus 3 that goes to infinity degrees of intelligence Unless they're smart enough to realize that playing randomly is the only way to get out of that.
Speaker 0: But if you know, they're going to play randomly, you know that your best strategy is to also play randomly However, and you can't affect the outcome so it doesn't really matter.
Speaker 0: But if you know if you think the other person is going to play randomly and they don't then everything moves around again.
Speaker 1: Hey, let's do one right now.
Speaker 1: Just one.
Speaker 1: All right, one, two, three.
Speaker 1: Are you scissors?
Speaker 0: Are you scissors?
Speaker 0: So The point of all this is that Barack who aren't any smart at all.
Speaker 1: That's what that means, right?
Speaker 0: or we're modulus 3.
Speaker 0: So Barack Obama I think is bucking the trend of previous presidents who basically said yeah is real blah blah blah blah and he's basically taking The the more he's trying to shoot.
Speaker 0: he's trying to shoot the moon instead of not losing because Israel is gonna be like no Fuck you but you know what Palestine's chill with this and Much of the rest of the world is chill with this and it really shifts the onus of who's the bad guy.
Speaker 0: even though They're both both good and bad guys a little bit more toward Israel I still don't have confidence that they will ever.
Speaker 0: I do I think I will predict right now that in our lifetime you and me before we both die We will see a Palestinian state.
Speaker 1: that doesn't mean that there will be peace and they'll stop fighting I don't know.
Speaker 1: but there could be a state but there's still gonna be war and it's never gonna end.
Speaker 1: I think it'll actually reduce quite a bit because having a pal and I'm saying it won't reduce or wax and wane with the times But it will never end.
Speaker 0: that's that's stupid.
Speaker 0: That's pointless.
Speaker 0: That's like saying yeah, there will always be entropy.
Speaker 1: Well, no, but always Scott there always be war in that particular spot.
Speaker 0: There will always be dumbasses.
Speaker 0: You can't eliminate the dumbass.
Speaker 1: I think there will never be peace between Israel and Palestine.
Speaker 0: I think there will be relative peace.
Speaker 0: I think a Palestinian state two or three generations from the point where that happens just by pulling the rug out from under the semi-legitimacy of the groups that actually try to get people to be suicide bombers that rile the people up.
Speaker 0: if There's if that like core legitimacy of yes, we need our own state is gone.
Speaker 0: They can really only tap the craziest people and a few generations out.
Speaker 0: I think the rate of violence will go the same route that the rate of violence in North Ireland did.
Speaker 1: It's incredibly optimistic.
Speaker 0: Look I know but again 50 years a lot can happen and I praise Barack Obama For shooting the motherfucking moon.
Speaker 1: He didn't shoot the moon yet.
Speaker 1: He's trying to shoot the moon, which is cool I think by saying this is his policy.
Speaker 0: He shot the moon.
Speaker 1: You don't know you actually have to shoot the moon.
Speaker 1: I could try to shoot the moon all I want but as soon as you take the Queen that's it.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is there's nothing the US can do other than you know.
Speaker 0: I guess if you cut all our aid to Israel we could force them to pull back to those I know I'm not saying it's a bad move.
Speaker 1: It's actually.
Speaker 0: that's not shooting the moon.
Speaker 0: That's that's going all in.
Speaker 0: and Euchre.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying it's a bad move.
Speaker 1: I'm just.
Speaker 1: I have very little optimism.
Speaker 0: That's going alone in Euchre.
Speaker 0: He's not going alone He's just shooting the moon.
Speaker 1: I don't think he's actually gonna.
Speaker 1: he's gonna take a heart.
Speaker 1: Ah You're gonna he's gonna.
Speaker 0: ah, you know what I'm gonna make a crazy prediction.
Speaker 0: All right, I think there will be a pseudo-palestinian state with some form of legitimized self-rule Within Barack Obama's second term.
Speaker 1: if he has a second term, I guarantee you're also predicting a second term I'll bet you 500 bucks.
Speaker 0: He gets a second time.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure there'll be a second term also But you're not gonna bet against me.
Speaker 0: I'm 99% You're wrong.
Speaker 0: he's not gonna have a second term.
Speaker 0: Oh really because the Raptors this fucking weekend.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so I've one other thing I want to talk about because this actually kind of annoyed me.
Speaker 0: It's just a news that I randomly stumbled upon.
Speaker 0: United Airlines Apologized to a fat person to everybody everybody because they happen to have two flights flight 175 and flight 93 recently.
Speaker 0: Okay, those happen to be the flight numbers of the flights that went down in the 9/11 attacks.
Speaker 0: Okay, so so apparently enough people recognize that and were pissed off about it and had thought that the airline had retired the numbers because apparently Terrorist attacks are the same as hockey where you retire the jersey.
Speaker 0: So they apologized and they have now retired.
Speaker 0: those two numbers, okay, and I just find that incredibly stupid.
Speaker 1: Agree that it is incredibly stupid.
Speaker 1: I mean fucking.
Speaker 0: I didn't forget that the September 11th attacks happened on September 11th But I had already forgotten the flight numbers.
Speaker 1: and who cares.
Speaker 1: It's just a fucking number.
Speaker 0: The thing is I don't even know who cares.
Speaker 0: It didn't state any particular person was angry.
Speaker 1: The news article just said we apologize It was probably the press saw it and the press wanted to make a story.
Speaker 1: a lot of these things are like that.
Speaker 1: where?
Speaker 0: Manufacture?
Speaker 0: some outrage like yeah, they may not store.
Speaker 0: recently There was a story about a woman who injected Botox in a little daughter's face.
Speaker 1: Was that true?
Speaker 0: No Well, but it basically it generated so much traffic.
Speaker 0: There's a great industry in manufacturing outrage.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I feel like we can export it To where we gonna export it to.
Speaker 1: everybody's already has outrage.
Speaker 0: Scandinavia doesn't have plenty of outrage.
Speaker 0: I don't think they have a go.
Speaker 0: So how many fat?
Speaker 0: Indignant slow people are there in Scandinavia?
Speaker 1: They've got other kinds of out.
Speaker 0: They do but it's it's cold.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's enough That's not outrage that's all right, that's something.
Speaker 1: it's just you're so cold.
Speaker 1: You don't look outraged you're just shivering.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you're not gonna make on the inside.
Speaker 1: The outrage is like 10x And the beer is also 10x.
Speaker 0: So things of the day This is just a kid's toy.
Speaker 0: it all they can say is numbers But in the fashion of everyone awesome.
Speaker 0: someone discovered that you can fairly trivially make it say motherfucker fuck and fuck you.
Speaker 1: I wonder if it was designed into the toy or just an accident.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure 50/50.
Speaker 0: It's just an accident But I enjoy any time something like this happens like the guy who realized that Cookie Monster can also sing romp.
Speaker 1: Well, the best is when you get like an eight-year-old.
Speaker 1: you sort of knows the bad words and then he discovers it and like nursery School or something in the in the playroom and that is where the awesomeness happens Take away the toy.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's just an innocent toy.
Speaker 0: You didn't know when I was a little kid.
Speaker 0: I was like six and my brother was like three and a half.
Speaker 0: Maybe he was four and he was in the kitchen.
Speaker 0: You know kids just like do stuff.
Speaker 0: He was just in the kitchen like on a stool in the kitchen sink Just like doing stuff in the kitchen sink Like he filled it with water and he was doing something whatever kids do And he dropped something.
Speaker 0: and just from the other room.
Speaker 0: We hear this four-year-old boy.
Speaker 0: Just yell son of a bitch And it was one of the funniest things I'd ever experienced.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's good.
Speaker 1: I like that.
Speaker 0: So motherfucker.
Speaker 0: What do you got?
Speaker 1: So, you know an f1 the steering wheels are totally insane, yeah, they got a billion knobblies on him, right?
Speaker 1: Well in this video Nico Rosberg who is sort of like I don't think he's actually won anything any championships At least not that I remember.
Speaker 1: maybe I'm wrong But I remember that when he was brand new to f1 They were like they were all talking about like oh how great he was and like, you know They're like the testing and such.
Speaker 1: like he had he had passed the test like better than any other rookie ever or something like that.
Speaker 1: but anyway He in this video he describes what everything on his steering wheel does except there might be something hidden on the back cuz he doesn't Show you the back of the steering wheel.
Speaker 1: So there might be something secret back there.
Speaker 1: But at least on the front he tells you what every one of those knobs does and it's so clearly now pretty interesting if I Want to.
Speaker 0: I am fully aware of what I need to do to drive an f1 car.
Speaker 1: Well, you don't know how to work the pedals Gas and brake clutch.
Speaker 1: the clutch is first of all The clutch is on the steering wheel All right.
Speaker 1: Second of all this gas brake and then there's a bunch of other levers to adjust other things that you that were in the car.
Speaker 0: so according to Wikipedia the wheels cost about 25,000 pounds and are made of carbon fiber.
Speaker 0: Yep, and it doesn't say anything about the back or a secret.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I guess you know, they told him not to show anyone the back.
Speaker 0: So I wonder something back there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you think it's the like the wiring heart.
Speaker 1: I think it is because and you can see the whole back of the steering wheel on television Whenever they're showing the front view of the driver's helmet.
Speaker 1: But what you can't see is the part of the steering wheel that actually connects to the steering column.
Speaker 1: That must be where the secret magic is.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's that.
Speaker 1: I think either he's got another button Or he could have another button and they're hiding they're cheating.
Speaker 0: or I think there's some sort of maybe the design of the paddle Or something like on the back.
Speaker 0: There's some design and the way he's got the grips that they think is great and they don't want anyone to see it.
Speaker 0: Possible?
Speaker 0: or Maybe he's just fucking with us.
Speaker 1: No, cuz I'm pretty.
Speaker 1: he seemed like he wanted to show it to you, but he was told not to.
Speaker 0: yeah Maybe he was told not to just because they're like, hey, let's pretend there's something on the back.
Speaker 1: No, you know, they're always so secret in the f1.
Speaker 1: Yeah I guess the only reason they even showed the front is because it's probably public knowledge anyway And he gets some attention and you can see the whole front no matter where you look.
Speaker 1: I just really can't hide the front of things.
Speaker 0: You can hide the back to the day when we finally get f0 I know.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, if there's ever f0.
Speaker 1: I'm signing up.
Speaker 0: You're signing up.
Speaker 0: Yep You think you'll be able to hack it?
Speaker 1: Have you seen the drivers in f0?
Speaker 0: Have you seen big bad guy?
Speaker 0: Actually, we need to watch red line.
Speaker 1: Do we need to watch it real bad?
Speaker 0: I'll get it.
Speaker 1: get it.
Speaker 0: and briefly in the meta moment.
Speaker 0: this weekend is bar camp.
Speaker 1: Yep It's Saturday and Sunday.
Speaker 1: I think the Saturday tickets are sort of sold out.
Speaker 1: ish.
Speaker 1: They're free.
Speaker 1: You can go sign up again on the waiting list.
Speaker 1: Maybe you'll get in I don't know but Sunday you can register for Sunday.
Speaker 1: Sunday bar camp NYC six.
Speaker 1: It's free.
Speaker 1: It's at the Microsoft Office.
Speaker 1: You can go to the website and find all about it.
Speaker 1: What else Connecticut is in some months coming?
Speaker 0: Yeah We'll be there.
Speaker 0: We may be at Otacon.
Speaker 0: It really depends on whether or not they accept our panels But if they accept them we'll be there.
Speaker 0: if we're not there It means they didn't want us to do panels despite us doing almost a decade worth of panels.
Speaker 1: Nerd NYC recess is June 18th.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Pax and Pax dev will be at both of those.
Speaker 0: most likely Yep, and the book club book is still Isaac Asimov's Foundation.
Speaker 1: Also, you should actually go to front row crew calm.
Speaker 1: a lot of people they just subscribe to us in iTunes Or maybe they go directly to the forum and they don't go to front row crew calm which is where you can find every episode of the show among other things.
Speaker 1: and I'm gonna be adding more things there After this weekend when my time becomes more for your Many things become finished.
Speaker 1: this week There's a feed for like.
Speaker 0: the thing is there's a day if you want to.
Speaker 0: you know You just want to get the feed of the things of the day the links to all this stuff.
Speaker 0: There's all kinds of stuff and it's not integrated with the site yet.
Speaker 0: But like I said earlier my youtube account geek nights rim has three of our.
Speaker 0: well one of our panels that included three panels from paxies and Of my little pony video that I made.
Speaker 0: that's very popular.
Speaker 1: There's also a geek night's YouTube account and my youtube account which is a PR ECHE.
Speaker 0: Yeah And there will be something special appearing in my geek nights rim YouTube account in the next week or so.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be making a video pretty soon of what happens when you put a helicopter in the elevator.
Speaker 0: Ah, I will be having a video about my year with the dragon But that is not the secret video.
Speaker 0: a few listeners know what that is, but something special is coming And I hope you'll like it, okay, you're really gonna like it.
Speaker 0: yeah Get your ass to Mars to Mars Get eats quaid.
Speaker 1: so like we said We discovered recently that some of the people in our crew had not seen the movie total recall a very important science fiction action film from the 90s.
Speaker 1: so we got it on DVD real cheap at the book off and We finally got around to watching it with those people and now they have seen it But they are not here to comment on it.
Speaker 1: instead We are here to comment on it people who have seen it in our youth.
Speaker 1: yep, and then again.
Speaker 0: I had not I'd seen total recall Probably in 1990.
Speaker 1: I I saw it in the late mid to mid ish 90s And I saw it again in the late night probably on television theater.
Speaker 0: I think we rented.
Speaker 1: I don't think I saw it on the theater.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure we rented it from a video store.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure I saw it on a VHS and also on TV with commercials, and then I'm pretty sure I also saw it perhaps Sometime at RIT or maybe during a summer.
Speaker 1: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: I just it was weird.
Speaker 0: It was one of those movies that when I was a kid like I just assumed Everyone had seen it kind of like I don't know Terminator 2.
Speaker 1: well there words I knew there were some kids who didn't see it because you know it is pretty gory and also has boobies in it.
Speaker 1: So there were some kids who were not permitted to see it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Or I was going to our at the time it came out when I was a little kid.
Speaker 0: I mean, I saw a Robocop like right away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway, but I didn't actually like.
Speaker 0: I remembered the plot.
Speaker 1: I remember the plot.
Speaker 1: I remembered some scenes.
Speaker 0: I remembered all the important scenes because the important scenes in total recall are pretty much when he rips that Johnny cab apart Yeah, when he pulls the thing out of his nose.
Speaker 1: I actually forgot about the Johnny cab until I saw it that I remember the job.
Speaker 1: When he pulls the thing out of I remember pulling the thing out of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, three breasted hooker three breast.
Speaker 1: he can't forget that one.
Speaker 0: I forgot the midget hooker.
Speaker 1: I remember the ending.
Speaker 1: I remembered all the parts where you know he went into the memory machine And I remembered some of the action scenes.
Speaker 0: got y'all house to Mars.
Speaker 1: I actually forgot about the guy in the stomach until I until I saw him.
Speaker 1: then I was all right forgotten kawatu.
Speaker 1: I Dennis actually saw kawatu.
Speaker 1: I was like all right kawatu right.
Speaker 0: and I also remembered I remember that the guy was a traitor that none of it actually happened, and it was just a dream and planted into his brain.
Speaker 1: Well, it's sort of like Inception.
Speaker 1: right.
Speaker 0: you could go either way Good, but the evidence is overwhelming by the way spoilers.
Speaker 0: if you haven't seen total recall what you want fuck.
Speaker 1: so When this is not for people who haven't seen total recall by though.
Speaker 0: here's my primary evidence And I don't think I need any other evidence, and I can dismiss the few points of evidence against me By saying that the movie was somewhat poorly constructed.
Speaker 1: all right I'll play a game all right.
Speaker 0: one of the only evidence you need is that when he goes in to get his You know his memory he's gonna buy that trip to Mars and put his ass there.
Speaker 0: as The tech is taking the little CD looking thing to load up the program He holds the case and he looks at it and it very quietly in the background says huh blue skies on Mars That's a new one.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 0: I think that's clinches it all right, so I got.
Speaker 1: I got two points All right.
Speaker 1: number one right.
Speaker 1: if the whole movie was from the time when he first goes into the machine at recall Yeah, very end of the movie is if that is the memory that is implanted that whole thing right?
Speaker 1: then Why would they implant a memory in which he does not end up where he started?
Speaker 1: otherwise it would be inconsistent with ah?
Speaker 0: Movie.
Speaker 0: he they just didn't show you the end.
Speaker 0: I mean it's it's basically Brazil without that little clip at the end where they're like oh yeah by the way in case you didn't get I mean if they're Selling you vacations the vacations would have to end with you coming back home.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they didn't show that in the movie.
Speaker 1: so somehow you're saying after that the memory continues and somehow He ends up back home with the wife that he killed.
Speaker 0: Yeah He remembers all this.
Speaker 1: he said he remembers killing his wife as part of his vacation.
Speaker 1: What kind of a who sells a vacation like that?
Speaker 0: uh clearly this company has some has some Cave Johnson in it.
Speaker 0: I mean who is selling that memory was pretty cave job.
Speaker 1: is possible that they sold him a memory that would totally fuck up his Life?
Speaker 0: it's also possible that they sell the memory But maybe the way it works is they play it out in his head like a dream with stimuli to imprint it But his conscious brain is reacting.
Speaker 0: Maybe but anyway um because he acted like himself just with superpowers.
Speaker 1: It's true.
Speaker 1: So here's a second is another isn't?
Speaker 0: so he must just really hate his wife, maybe?
Speaker 1: So there's the scene where the wife and the psychologist show up, and they tell him that he's you know in inside of recall.
Speaker 0: That's just a really clever scene that they put in the scenario.
Speaker 1: or was it true?
Speaker 1: and actually The reason that the dream doesn't the reason that the vacation doesn't match up and bring him back home at the end is Because he really was being lobotomized.
Speaker 1: and there that's the real ending is.
Speaker 1: so it was all recalls You're right, but it wasn't that wasn't the dream.
Speaker 1: They intended.
Speaker 1: You know what I actually got lobotomized.
Speaker 1: I'm going to place like they said and that was real.
Speaker 0: I accept your point as an alternate answer because it still proves to me right.
Speaker 0: my core point was not that The whole thing was a dream.
Speaker 0: My main argument against is that they show you a couple of scenes where Quaid's not there to see anything But there are many scenes where Quaid is not but at the same time they don't show Quaid knowing about that information and Maybe he just remembers it.
Speaker 0: Maybe that's just.
Speaker 0: you know Verhoeven not being the best director in the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like the goldfish Quaid is never in that office.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right as far as I can remember.
Speaker 0: So yeah that the other thing is.
Speaker 1: it went to perfectly of course, I mean he's basically an invincible superhero Yeah, but I mean in terms of you know was the movie good.
Speaker 1: I think it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: It's not Terminator 2, but it's like one step under.
Speaker 0: well It's a sci-fi part of Terminator 2 I think hold up pretty well one these the action scenes because this is a 90s movie But it's the beginning.
Speaker 0: It's 1990. the action scenes reek of 80s.
Speaker 1: Well, they do.
Speaker 1: the action scenes do reek of 80s, but they're clearly aid.
Speaker 0: it's Arnold with a machine gun going Million bullets, they're really not so bad.
Speaker 1: It's not like they're painful to watch.
Speaker 1: Yeah, right, but the problem is that since then we've had such advances in action scene choreography, you know now I know the matrix didn't cause those advances and it was simply stealing from you know, Asian cinema.
Speaker 0: But
Speaker 1: the matrix did introduce those advanced fight choreography Techniques to the Western audience and because of that we have you know Western audiences in general have now gotten used to much much higher Expectations of what kind of things you're gonna see in action scenes and that you know causes total recall to be dated in that respect.
Speaker 1: But really it's not.
Speaker 1: it's not like I'm watching the action scenes going.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's so bad.
Speaker 1: Like when you look at the CG and Tron now, right?
Speaker 1: It's not like that It's just you know And also some of the action scenes with like the drill are pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah It is clearly also more 80s than 90s in that the technology of the future apparently is just 80s technology But more of it, I mean, well, that's something that's something that gets right.
Speaker 1: So in the beginning of the movie when he's in the apartment with the with the wife They got this incredible flat-screen TV.
Speaker 1: It's like part of the wall and it can actually be three panel.
Speaker 0: How do you know?
Speaker 0: it's not just a giant CRT but then the rest of the movie is all CRT's.
Speaker 0: But this is their vision of the future.
Speaker 0: It's like 80s culture extended into the future.
Speaker 0: TVs fucking everywhere and They suck.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and no one has any way to communicate except payphones, but the payphones have TVs in them I know right and it's just.
Speaker 0: everything really looks like the 80s Like it's not like Ferris Bueller, which is set in the 80s.
Speaker 0: It's set in the future, but it looks like the 80s.
Speaker 1: This is the problem.
Speaker 1: if you make anything that's set in the past You can't become dated.
Speaker 1: It's guaranteed to be timeless.
Speaker 1: But if you make anything ever that's set in the future, right?
Speaker 1: It could unless it's like Star Wars.
Speaker 1: right Star Wars pulls the ultimate trick Long time ago galaxy far far away.
Speaker 1: A lot of people don't actually think and we oh shit long time ago Star Wars is in the past And that's how right.
Speaker 1: and by making it a totally different time and a totally different place They can do whatever the hell they want.
Speaker 1: But because total recall is earth This earth in the future.
Speaker 1: Pretty much you're going to be dated at some point no matter what year you said it at.
Speaker 1: I mean how many animes are set in 20x DX and shit?
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: It's actually now it's 20x DX.
Speaker 0: We fucked well, I mean October in.
Speaker 0: That was the end day.
Speaker 1: No, not the Saturday.
Speaker 0: I was at a football game But this Saturday isn't the end day.
Speaker 0: That was a better end day.
Speaker 0: It was all you can't.
Speaker 1: you can't make any work of art You can't tell any story about the future of Earth without being dated unless it's near future.
Speaker 1: It's not possible because you can't get it exactly right, but at the same time you can do it.
Speaker 1: Well, you can look at Minority Report, which actually people, you know is the movie that people are always like, oh, yeah It gets.
Speaker 1: you know, it's like Minority Report, right?
Speaker 0: Well, here's one way to look at it.
Speaker 0: Look at a movie like Ferris Bueller where it's set in the 80s and it works.
Speaker 0: Look at a movie like Terminator 2 where while it's got a lot of futuristic stuff It uses like good techniques from its era so that it doesn't like it doesn't use crappy 90s soundtrack.
Speaker 1: Well, I think what Terminator 2's advantage right?
Speaker 1: Is that the future of Terminator 2 is the post-apocalyptic Fantasy future.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even though it's sci-fi because it's robots and machines.
Speaker 0: Compare all the movies from the era of Terminator 2. a lot of them have Crappy, you know late 80s early 90s synth soundtracks.
Speaker 0: That's true pop songs that really stand out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's the worst thing to do that but Terminator 2 orchestral sound has one of the better soundtracks in the history of movies.
Speaker 1: That's true.
Speaker 0: I mean how many people?
Speaker 1: just Yeah, that's why I'm a big fan of pretty much everything Either using you know, I really don't like it when people use, you know, like actual songs like from radio.
Speaker 0: No, here's my third thing.
Speaker 0: Remember I watched the the Lost Boys recently because Emily never seen it.
Speaker 0: It's a great vampire movie from the 80s.
Speaker 0: Yeah 90s Corey Haim Corey Feldman all those guys.
Speaker 0: Yep, and it is set in that time and it plays all songs from that time like Saxophone.
Speaker 1: I Was about to say if you're making a Vietnam movie, right?
Speaker 1: You always got to use those same songs.
Speaker 1: I like give me shelter by the stones and all the same songs You got to do if you're doing a Vietnam movie.
Speaker 0: I don't do that.
Speaker 0: If you just make if it happens to be that year and you're making a movie that's set at some generic time Yeah You can't.
Speaker 1: I'm talking about when somebody makes a movie and because the movie happened to be made in 2006 they use in the movie.
Speaker 1: the soundtrack is the hit songs of 2006. that is.
Speaker 1: the problem is when you just use the hit songs of the day.
Speaker 1: The movie was released as promotional things as opposed to picking songs that fit the movie.
Speaker 1: and I still prefer original score orchestral if possible right or musical like ponies or broadish or show tunes to Using hit songs.
Speaker 1: because then you're the reason I prefer that is because a most of the great movies do that.
Speaker 1: It's just like a. you know, there's a there's a correlation there and two.
Speaker 1: It makes more music.
Speaker 1: You're making new music.
Speaker 1: You're creating more art as opposed to you know, you're actually making less art.
Speaker 0: What about a movie?
Speaker 0: That's like a mat cross kind of thing where it makes a new hit song that happens to also be a hit song.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Matt cross You did both orchestral sort of rock and show tunes for itself that were originally new.
Speaker 1: They created new music for the new show.
Speaker 1: as opposed to you know It's like you're there's more art created in the world.
Speaker 1: if you decide to spend money to record new music It is if you just use existing music, you're actually making less stuff.
Speaker 1: That's the main thing.
Speaker 0: So here's something weird.
Speaker 0: I noticed that I never noticed before.
Speaker 0: Benny the cab driver the assholes also a mutant.
Speaker 0: Yep They foreshadow the fact that he was gonna die by a drill and pilot a drill Like crazily Every time you like you see him like he's driving or something.
Speaker 0: There are three scenes in the movie well before he drives the drill and tries to kill them and then gets drilled Where you see him and then you immediately see one of those drills.
Speaker 0: Yep They do that three times like they're being like hey, he's gonna get drilled.
Speaker 0: and apparently the movie was originally rated X. Yep, they had to cut several Ultraviolet sections of existing scenes to get the movie to our.
Speaker 1: one of them was thing is if that movie.
Speaker 1: Here's the thing if they had the original cut of the movie the one that was originally rated X Yeah that came out today.
Speaker 1: It would not be rated X. Nope and the same thing with Hellraiser, right?
Speaker 1: These were not porn.
Speaker 1: nowadays you have to be a hardcore porn to be rated X or I guess maybe something like each of the killer might be if they Bothered to rate it, but I mean, you know, the original cut of Total Recall would no way be rated X.
Speaker 0: today Really X doesn't do.
Speaker 0: it have to be MD.
Speaker 0: MD They Show you what happened to Benny instead of just kind of implying what happened to Benny.
Speaker 0: Yeah and they also the scene where he I Love.
Speaker 0: when Arnold is in a movie and in the end the thing that saves him is the fact that he's just Arnold.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean in the end Things often stabs the one scientist in the neck.
Speaker 1: that's yeah, that's what you see in an Arnold movie.
Speaker 0: Apparently they cut out a lot of him stabbing other scientists in that scene.
Speaker 1: It's actually, you know surprising though.
Speaker 1: You go to look at Arnold's movies Terminator 2 Total Recall Predator and Running Man and you know these kinds of movies and it's like it's kind of surprising how a lot of the other Action movie stars, you know
Speaker 0: Stallone
Speaker 1: Yeah, a lot of them pretty
Speaker 0: much Tom Selleck
Speaker 1: just did boring action.
Speaker 1: But you know Arnold did a lot.
Speaker 1: you mean Arnold did his share of boring action.
Speaker 1: I mean a race, you know, he's got bad movies eraser crap, right?
Speaker 1: But I like last action hero, though It's okay, but okay The point is is that he did a lot of movies that actually had a plot.
Speaker 1: That was a pretty good sci-fi plot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean Total Recall is based somewhat loosely on a Philip K dick dick story and it's a pretty good sci-fi.
Speaker 0: Just they threw in a lot of Arnold.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course, you know It's a it's a two-for-one deal.
Speaker 0: Also because I haven't seen an Arnold movie in a while Motherfucker makes some great faces sometimes.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, it's not like he's not playing a character he's playing Arnold playing a character, right?
Speaker 1: But it's you know, it's.
Speaker 1: everyone had.
Speaker 1: it gets a start for a reason, right?
Speaker 1: Even people.
Speaker 1: you might you know, you look at famous people, right and it's like how did you know?
Speaker 1: This person isn't talented or they suck.
Speaker 1: I hate them.
Speaker 1: But the fact is they got to start somewhere, right?
Speaker 1: They didn't start out famous.
Speaker 1: They had some sort of talent or something that got them off on the right foot somewhere.
Speaker 1: It might have just been something shallow like good looks or an Arnold's case.
Speaker 1: He was like, you know ultra muscly because he was a bodybuilder or whatever.
Speaker 1: But he had to have some acting skills what you know in order to get into movies they just wouldn't have.
Speaker 1: you know, if he didn't sell tickets and Wasn't able to act directors wouldn't want him.
Speaker 0: You know, he had something going on Whoa, so supposedly in the early like when they were trying to get this movie made Philip K dick was still alive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and They went through.
Speaker 0: they thought about getting Richard Dreyfuss or Patrick Swayze to play Quaid.
Speaker 1: Okay, that would have been a very different movie totally different movie Not even close to the same movie.
Speaker 0: You know what though?
Speaker 0: I think Stallone could have maybe pulled it off Tom Selleck would have pulled it off just fine.
Speaker 1: I think Bruce Willis Bruce Willis might have made this one of the best movies that he's the breeze pretty much the other guy who does action movies that Are also have some intelligent sci-fi thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and he also nearly sci-fi A lot of his action movies.
Speaker 0: He's Bruce Willis.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: And I love Bruce Willis and I love Arnold.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not Arnold but Arnold.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you know in in related news I also wanted to watch this movie because there's actually a total recall comic book coming out.
Speaker 1: Oh I ordered the first issue just because curious.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's gonna be good.
Speaker 1: I actually doubt it will be good, but I actually saw the cover To the second issue because I they sent me the evil catalog I hate for free and the second issue has aliens on the cover.
Speaker 1: So I guess We're gonna find out right.
Speaker 1: I guess if you're if you're right or not.
Speaker 1: It goes this comic is canon and it picks up where the movie left off.
Speaker 0: Well, well, apparently there's a script for total recall - that was never made.
Speaker 1: There's a script for every.
Speaker 0: no, so, you know what is based on minority report And it picks up right after where Quaid is still Quaid.
Speaker 1: Well, there you go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how about that?
Speaker 1: Yeah But I mean that's another thing.
Speaker 1: right is if you go with my theory that he was really lobotomized And that means he's probably a vegetable but he's probably Dreaming this vacation until the day his vegetable body dies.
Speaker 1: so it could just be that you know that continue any continuation you come up with is all in his brain and It's part of his infinite vacation until he his body runs out.
Speaker 1: You know though I would say and since he's got a pretty muscly body It's gonna be a while if you've never seen total recall.
Speaker 1: Why did you listen this far?
Speaker 0: I highly recommend seeing it because it is a very enjoyable movie.
Speaker 0: It's definitely iconic of 90s action movies like basically Until the matrix all good action movies were kind of like this.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm a matrix like above Terminator 2 just because and I put total recall one step lower than that.
Speaker 0: Well because Terminator 2 all did the same thing.
Speaker 0: the matrix did like movies were action.
Speaker 0: movies were a certain way.
Speaker 0: Terminator 1 was just another action movie.
Speaker 0: Terminator 2 happened and the entire world went whoa.
Speaker 0: And then movies changed forever.
Speaker 1: We need a new we need a neck.
Speaker 0: Terminator 2 did that.
Speaker 0: the matrix did that.
Speaker 0: Star Wars did that.
Speaker 1: we need one.
Speaker 1: we need something to break us out.
Speaker 1: Did you know that there are more movie sequels this summer than ever ever in history randomly?
Speaker 1: There's 20. there are 27 sequels coming out this year.
Speaker 1: I had to clean up living need something like Star Wars Terminator 2 or the matrix to break something a blockbuster.
Speaker 1: I mean we can make all the great art films we want.
Speaker 1: there are plenty of them, but they're not gonna change Hollywood.
Speaker 1: We need something big like matrix Star Wars Terminator 2 - I have Hollywood has gold member Buster a few days ago while I was gold member the Austin Powers one yeah, not as funny as the first.
Speaker 0: You know what not even funny at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was a terrible movie.
Speaker 1: I I still like the first one I like the first one is the second one.
Speaker 1: the girl is way hot like the hottest But the third one has the hottest girl, but the I think the second one.
Speaker 1: the second one has the hottest girl Foxy 70s.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah And the first they've got.
Speaker 1: not that the girl in the first movie isn't incredibly hot either It's just the second movie.
Speaker 1: one is tiny bit hotter.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: There's no anapuma.
Speaker 1: No there's.
Speaker 1: We're getting off topic.
Speaker 0: yeah, I think we're running out of steam here, I mean I Think that total recall is a fine movie and the sci-fi angle is good, but if you want an Arnold action movie I think running man is a better Arnold movie.
Speaker 1: I would put my if I had to rank are not a better movie.
Speaker 0: It's a better Arnold movie.
Speaker 1: I think predator is better.
Speaker 0: Oh predator is better as well.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen predator up ready since I was a little kid.
Speaker 0: really I haven't seen.
Speaker 1: I mean when I had this um In high school I took a sci-fi class But it ended up being filled with like a bunch of these sort of funny Frat drunk you guys and all they wanted to do is watch predators every day in class.
Speaker 1: They'd be like the predator and then on the last day of class the teacher was cool, and we watch predator.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our Website at front row.
Speaker 1: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows.
Speaker 0: sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays Is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night that to the choppa get your ass to the choppa.