Speaker 0: It's Monday November 21st 2011.
Speaker 0: I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott, and this is geek night tonight.
Speaker 0: how to get around the SOPA.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: This past weekend.
Speaker 0: We played a game.
Speaker 0: We have not played in many moons.
Speaker 0: Played the game called Shogun.
Speaker 1: Hey used to be called Shogun.
Speaker 0: It's like samurai sword.
Speaker 1: It's like three other games called Shogun.
Speaker 1: I know this is the Milton Bradley game master series samurai sword slash Shogun one of the finer Games in the genre better than axis and allies or risk or any of the oh.
Speaker 1: But there I did sort of finally fully realize the one fatal flaw in this game Which is it sort of has the same problem, and it is a minor problem.
Speaker 0: the second to last loser chooses the winner.
Speaker 1: well It's sort of the same problem is counter-strike.
Speaker 1: right I go up to a guy and I go.
Speaker 1: But a bit of but a bit of.
Speaker 1: but I came down to 99 health and then some guy gets a headshot on me Yo.
Speaker 1: And then some other dude just sort of go is shooting like a crazy guy Right all over the place in a stray bullet hits this dude in the foot.
Speaker 1: that guy gets a kill And I get bupkis even though I did 99 damage and that guy did one damage.
Speaker 0: granted in this case Scott You were doing okay, but I was pretty much the undisputed master of Japan.
Speaker 0: I'm just saying I'm pretty fucking early on.
Speaker 1: the thing that samurai swords does that's sort of cool is that if you kill someone's last daimyo you get their whole empire as now part of yours and That is usually.
Speaker 1: if you do that That's enough to win you the game because now you basically just double the size of your thing and you win immediately.
Speaker 1: So if so for example right Pete had three daimyo's.
Speaker 1: everyone has three daimyo's rim.
Speaker 0: killed one Yeah, because he left it hanging out.
Speaker 1: then the general degree his other.
Speaker 0: I betrayed him.
Speaker 1: his other two were incredibly vulnerable.
Speaker 1: So I had to make a move on one of them because he just killed one of mine.
Speaker 1: So I destroyed one of his just boom it was totally wasted.
Speaker 0: Both have two daimyo's each, and I'm you also had two daimyo's.
Speaker 0: Well the thing is I only lost one because I was a dumbass.
Speaker 1: You killed Pete's final daimyo which allowed you to win.
Speaker 1: if I had killed Pete's final daimyo Which I was fully capable of doing I would have won.
Speaker 1: But Pete chose to move his final daimyo to your side of the board.
Speaker 0: He made a very good gambit.
Speaker 0: you Pussy'd out.
Speaker 0: you had all your two daimyo's hidden in the corner in your basey area In forts.
Speaker 0: Yeah Meanwhile Scott's or Pete's daimyo went out and he went near me.
Speaker 0: because what you should have done is chased him sooner because if you've been More aggressive he would have been there and my daimyo and your daimyo would have been there And then it would have been.
Speaker 0: I probably would have ninja'd and or preemptively attacked your daimyo.
Speaker 1: Also, I do want to point out there was an extreme luck factor Twice and it got revenged twice.
Speaker 1: the odds of a successful revenge ninja are 1/3 Times 1/3 one out of nine one.
Speaker 1: so two times in a row the one out of nine chance Occurred one.
Speaker 0: I never used the ninja because ninja socks - there was a one out of it.
Speaker 1: It was an eight out of nine chance.
Speaker 1: that would not have happened.
Speaker 1: and it happened two times God.
Speaker 0: both times you ninja'd me when I wasn't even going after but if I had Succeeded I would have gotten you.
Speaker 1: you would have been toast.
Speaker 1: I would have won either one of those roles succeeded.
Speaker 1: I would have won the game.
Speaker 0: I highly doubt.
Speaker 0: I guarantee it.
Speaker 0: God you let me consolidate in those islands that basically fucked you from the.
Speaker 1: I couldn't because I was I all of my Starting cards on the other side of the board.
Speaker 0: so the real reason I won is because Pete Let me consolidate on those islands in return for me giving him some bullshit that I then took back from him anyway.
Speaker 1: Anyway, anyway, that's how that game goes.
Speaker 0: So what do you got?
Speaker 0: It's Monday.
Speaker 0: It's news day.
Speaker 1: I just got one sort of crazy news crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's sort of weird.
Speaker 1: So people might not know this right but some companies Apple being the chief among them Right do not allow their products to be discounted under any circumstance.
Speaker 1: This is why even on the blackest of Black Friday's in the heart of blackest America Right, you will not see an iPod for even one dollar below manufacturers.
Speaker 0: This is bullshit and you'll see it a lot on Newegg and Amazon where they'll say like you'll see a product and it says Price can't be displayed because the.
Speaker 0: basically the agreement is that they can't display the price and continue to sell products from that company.
Speaker 0: but They get around it by you click on it and it quote unquote Adds it to your cart and shows you the price and then gives you the option to immediately remove it from your cart But it prevents competition and that you can't search for those prices, right?
Speaker 1: Even even without the C pricing cart.
Speaker 1: BS right Apple has been known to where like if you were to sell.
Speaker 1: if you were to buy iPods from Apple because you're a Digital electronic store you buy a bunch of iPods from Apple and then you sell them for 10 bucks off.
Speaker 1: Apple would never sell you an iPod or any Apple product ever again.
Speaker 1: They blacklist you and you would never be able to stock their things ever not even little converti cables Because they would just cut you off because they never want anything of theirs to be sold at even a 1 cent discount.
Speaker 1: Best buy right now has MacBook Airs with C price in cart for $200 off for the 13-inch.
Speaker 1: Whoa It's crazy.
Speaker 1: Is this because Steve Jobs is dead?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: They've also got.
Speaker 1: they've also got the 11-inch for $60 off.
Speaker 1: Here's what I was about to say pricing card.
Speaker 0: had I been a big distributor as in one that Apple couldn't just ignore I would have bought in bulk and then just discounted anyway and said alright.
Speaker 1: I think though I think Apple would have no problem being just like Best Buy.
Speaker 1: you're done never no more for you.
Speaker 1: Fuck it.
Speaker 0: It's hard to say.
Speaker 1: I don't.
Speaker 1: they would be like we don't need you have our own stores, right?
Speaker 1: We don't give a shit about you.
Speaker 0: But I'm saying is that if I were someone like Best Buy I would risk it.
Speaker 0: I would risk it if I had.
Speaker 1: that's a good short term.
Speaker 1: But if you I mean if you did but you know get a big stock Short term would be really good.
Speaker 1: long term if you did if they actually pulled out on you would be zero.
Speaker 1: Thing is you could also Buy but in a bad economy in a holiday season not a bad time to blow your short-term load.
Speaker 0: You could also arrange for distribution of Apple products from gray markets and such to continue selling.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Apple might to go take it to court.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's tough.
Speaker 0: That's real tough.
Speaker 1: They would do it.
Speaker 1: They got the money.
Speaker 0: I don't think they'd be able to pull it off though.
Speaker 0: Maybe the other thing you could do is If Best Buy does it everyone else realizes?
Speaker 0: Hey, I can do that once to small little stores.
Speaker 1: suddenly suddenly you go on an Amazon and it says see pricing cart MacBook half-off Right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I have a store, you know, I'm Best Buy now.
Speaker 0: I have a store in Amazon Messed by and I'm selling Apple stuff and then crest by and I'm selling Apple stuff.
Speaker 1: Okay Anyway, another tiny news.
Speaker 1: right Amazon has a beta site where they I wish Amazon would do this more have specialized Amazon sites for specialized product categories.
Speaker 1: You can go to wireless.amazon.com and it's Amazon wireless beta which is an Amazon store only for buying phones and not for buying anything else.
Speaker 1: and They've actually got a whole bunch of Android phones for a penny.
Speaker 1: Just one penny.
Speaker 1: Come on You like the guys in the street?
Speaker 1: But yeah, you can actually get like phone X's Nexus Nexus Nexus I mean like Rolex.
Speaker 1: next for example the Droid razor, right if you get that with the contract from Verizon The phone is gonna make 300.
Speaker 1: I think right, you know with the subsidy and everything like.
Speaker 1: yeah They're not giving any discounts on the plans cuz that's just Verizon's plans, but the phone one penny.
Speaker 1: So you're saving $2.99 if you go to Amazon wireless.
Speaker 1: that amazon.com is.
Speaker 0: I'm in the middle of my cycle right now.
Speaker 0: I'm just probably gonna get iPhone and I got a great phone until 4g stops working.
Speaker 1: Thanks I'll be getting iPhone 5 in 2012.
Speaker 0: most likely thing is Since I'm losing my 4g I have to upgrade at the end of my upgrade cycle.
Speaker 0: Mmm, I'm either gonna go iPhone or we'll see what droid has.
Speaker 1: Yeah The main thing is like even though some of these friends still has unlimited data Even though some of these Android phones are starting to look better and more usable and I'm very googly.
Speaker 1: So they would probably work out for me software wise and I could probably deal with the hackiness and such.
Speaker 1: There's not you know.
Speaker 1: main problem with them that I'm having is that they're too big.
Speaker 1: They're like a whole diagonal inch bigger than I got.
Speaker 0: you know, what the majority of Android phones are monsters bricks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got the Nexus s.
Speaker 1: that's why I'm probably gonna end up sticking with iPhone Unless someone comes out with a high quality like.
Speaker 1: it's got to be access.
Speaker 1: It's got to be like high but Nexus s is already obsolete.
Speaker 1: So what I'm being a high-end best Android phone, but also has to be three and a half inches not four and a half.
Speaker 0: So here's what I'll do When it's time to upgrade.
Speaker 0: if there is an Android phone that has the same form factor as the Nexus s that is top of The line I'll stay Android.
Speaker 0: Otherwise iPhone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's looking anyway.
Speaker 0: I don't know why they're making the droid phone so big.
Speaker 0: who needs that much power?
Speaker 1: I think it says that I think what it is.
Speaker 1: They can't make the hardware part any smaller So they just cover it with a screen Whereas Apple basically fights and fights and fights.
Speaker 0: No Online a lot of people say like they like the bigger phone and people I talked to like I'd see people that's post purchase Liking, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I see people who are like they see someone else's big droid and they're like, oh man I wish I had a screen that big really.
Speaker 0: Yeah people you You have particular tastes in things.
Speaker 0: There's those people want other things.
Speaker 1: Is it seem you'll find SUVs.
Speaker 1: They're just stupid.
Speaker 1: It's not even a matter of taste.
Speaker 1: It's just stupid.
Speaker 1: Okay, let's move on to the real news the most important news of the month.
Speaker 0: We have not talked about this much But there's a bill in Congress, this doesn't matter if you're not in the u.s.
Speaker 1: H well it will well, but HR 3261 and also known as SOPA or the stop online piracy act the Senate bill is protect IP Act Which is slightly older and still awful, but only like 90% as awful as 10% less awful But now awful.
Speaker 1: we can't have either one of these.
Speaker 0: I don't want to get too much into you know, exactly what's wrong with it because the entire internet is talking about it.
Speaker 0: But I'll put it this way if you haven't been paying attention The DMCA by comparison seems like a perfectly reasonable and rational compromise on copyright enforcement.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and when the DMCA came out we're like, this is the worst thing in the universe mostly the biggest thing.
Speaker 1: That's bad about the DMCA.
Speaker 0: Well, Google now gave us some evidence for this argument, too, right?
Speaker 1: but the number one thing that's wrong with the DMCA that you could say that's bad law right is That it outlawed like devices that were primarily user infringement, right?
Speaker 1: So it was like, you know, it basically outlawed breaking DRM Even if you were going to legitimately do something legal the other You couldn't break the DRM on your DVD Even if you're going to use the video on the DVD in a fair use.
Speaker 0: There's a secondary problem that I think is just as important that According to Google the majority of takedown notices that they receive for YouTube are blatantly false.
Speaker 1: Yes The Google representative said this during the SOPA hearing before Congress under penalty of perjury because if you testify before Congress perjury.
Speaker 1: So, yeah crazy.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so but the DMCA looks reasonable next to sofa now.
Speaker 0: granted SOPA is in May is not actually as bad as the CBD tPA if you remember that.
Speaker 1: well, they're they're all equally awful.
Speaker 0: Well, the CBD tPA was gonna require basically hardware DRM and all digital devices.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: So SOPA in a nutshell Basically says that the government through courts Someone who has intellectual property who believes or claims that they are being infringed upon can get a court order to have the DNS of the site shut down Basically permanently and all service providers the entire DNS system has to accommodate this blacklist.
Speaker 1: Well these ones in the US Yeah.
Speaker 1: so the problems with this are a few number ones.
Speaker 0: blocking someone's DNS doesn't actually block them because you can just type their IP and So the law goes on to say that they also have to block access But doesn't say how?
Speaker 1: Right because they want to leave it up to ISPs.
Speaker 1: That's what they'll tell you.
Speaker 1: is they want to leave it up to ISPs and service providers?
Speaker 1: exactly the implementation deep Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: I'll tell you kids.
Speaker 0: There's two Implementations implementation.
Speaker 0: the first also block IP addresses, which we'll talk about.
Speaker 0: how to get around that to implementation to Deep packet inspection as in looking at the content of all the packets and figuring out what is going to the previously infringing site.
Speaker 0: That is something that for the majority of smaller ISPs is a ludicrous requirement and for the large ones I mean, don't we hate China's firewall?
Speaker 1: It's so weird, right?
Speaker 1: I mean gee people are like surprised.
Speaker 1: It's like it's weird to see like people are so surprised at things The government is doing like oh my god Look at this and it's totally a Daily Show thing.
Speaker 1: Right you go and you watch a video of like Joe Biden talking about how like censorship is bad.
Speaker 1: Okay, you know, you shouldn't be doing a firewall China and then Right turns around and he's like, oh man this stuff is so awesome.
Speaker 1: It's like what you're the contradiction in the government.
Speaker 1: it exists and I'm like, yeah, that's par for the course.
Speaker 1: But it's weird to see these other people go like, oh my god.
Speaker 1: Look at this contradicting government.
Speaker 1: I'm like the Daily Show's been on TV for like over a decade showing you the same stuff.
Speaker 1: Why are you surprised every time?
Speaker 0: because you've got to get mad?
Speaker 1: Not gonna take it anymore.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna.
Speaker 0: I'm mad as hell and I'm not gonna take it anymore.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what?
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, we'll get to that but Other issues with this bill.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's not like you can say that this is the Republicans the Democrats.
Speaker 0: This is everybody a bipartisan initiative.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much the only ones who are against it are like the few cool people in Congress and or the Somewhat cool people and all the other ones are totally for Ron Paul's against it Ron.
Speaker 1: Obviously the number one guy we got in our side is a guy from Oregon, which is like the most open source of all states Ron Wyden.
Speaker 1: I think his name is.
Speaker 1: he's gonna go for a filibuster on the protect IP half and You can send in and fill out a form and he'll read your name because he needs something to read.
Speaker 0: so I believe he's gonna be up there saying such things as penis McMytear and Michael Hunt.
Speaker 1: nice, you know That's fights just gotta read something.
Speaker 1: I think what he should do is actually go and find like, you know websites that have just huge comment threads talking about sofa or You know all sorts of papers pretty much anything or just like letters that let's go one step further.
Speaker 0: What I would do is I would find a work a written work.
Speaker 0: That is a fan work some sort of like technically violating copyright, but yet is a good novel and so Fan fiction.
Speaker 0: basically find good fat and fiction and read it or you know, what just read.
Speaker 0: horrible like furry fanfic furry clappy, whatever fanfiction clappy.
Speaker 1: I love that.
Speaker 0: That's a there is.
Speaker 1: there is no end to material because the internet exists and but it won't if this bill becomes a law.
Speaker 0: so We've been through this before with many laws.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's no point in reiterating the same things.
Speaker 1: we have reiterated this one for over a decade.
Speaker 0: it has a pretty decent shot of passing and Whereas the cohes and the CBD TPAs we were able to defeat and the DMCA was watered down to where as much as it sucks There are people.
Speaker 1: it's Tolerable, right?
Speaker 1: It's hardly because Google I'd like to see it go.
Speaker 1: I would not mind.
Speaker 0: but Google via YouTube does a really good job of basically helping people go through the paperwork to you know.
Speaker 0: Fight bullshit take down notices.
Speaker 1: Yeah, kinda.
Speaker 0: Yeah kinda they do better than I could have expected.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but this bill unlike all the other ones that we've seen Would be a disaster for the structure of the Internet.
Speaker 0: I'm a technology professional.
Speaker 0: I'm a vice president of product management.
Speaker 0: I was a senior engineer on Wall Street for four years.
Speaker 0: You know, I have a degree.
Speaker 0: Scott has the degree.
Speaker 0: We're both scientists of commute of computers.
Speaker 0: This law will destroy the internet.
Speaker 1: It will.
Speaker 1: if this law passes and is implemented the internet will be broken in a really bad way.
Speaker 1: The number one way it will be broken is the destruction of DNS sec, right?
Speaker 0: So the way to be fair isn't really like implemented fully.
Speaker 1: it's they've already signed all the root thingies.
Speaker 1: They're ready to go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's if we can get it to work.
Speaker 1: You're fully.
Speaker 1: then it'll be so awesome and they put already so much work into doing it that it would basically throw.
Speaker 0: I'm sorry.
Speaker 0: I was reading a talking point from a bunch of the people who are for this bill saying that DNS sec is Unimplemented and we don't need to worry about it.
Speaker 0: Sure.
Speaker 0: Those people are smart.
Speaker 0: They'll figure out a way around.
Speaker 0: the you know, no apply with the law.
Speaker 1: Here's the way.
Speaker 1: is the thing with DNS sec Right?
Speaker 1: is you?
Speaker 1: you know?
Speaker 1: Everyone knows if you listen our DNS episode DNS is the system that turns names into numbers.
Speaker 1: you type in google.com.
Speaker 1: It turns it into an IP address so that you know where to actually go.
Speaker 1: But what if you were to say type in bank.com and instead of getting the numbers for your bank?
Speaker 1: You got some wrong numbers so you end up going to my server instead of the bank server even though your web browser or whatever using says bank.com.
Speaker 1: and Then what do you know?
Speaker 1: you just typed in your bank info into Scott Scott's website and now I have your bank info.
Speaker 1: Good job.
Speaker 1: This is why DNS is important.
Speaker 1: We need to make sure guarantee Cryptographically Mathematically that the the numbers you get for that name are the right ones because DNS relies on Trust and the trust goes up to basically the root DNS servers.
Speaker 0: we listen to the episode from our details, but Basically, you've got a trust DNS all the way back up to that route And even if people in the middle are you're wrong.
Speaker 0: the route can basically be the safe place.
Speaker 0: It can be the place that fixes everything.
Speaker 0: if you know a whole swath of the internet turned evil.
Speaker 0: The root DNS servers always know the way home.
Speaker 1: So for example, I set up a DNS server and I got all the numbers in there And they're all the right numbers.
Speaker 1: bank.com goes to the right number google.com goes to the right number.
Speaker 1: Right, then I if you do the math if your computer does the math to check the DNS sec, it'll thumbs up.
Speaker 1: Hey, this DNS server is totally chill and all these numbers are right You don't have to worry that you're actually going to the wrong server.
Speaker 1: that's gonna steal your stuff.
Speaker 1: But what if the government says yeah Scott?
Speaker 1: Hey on your DNS server there.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: What's up government?
Speaker 1: Yeah that server you got there.
Speaker 1: I need you to change pirate bay.org to point at this other number because pirate bay.org is no good.
Speaker 1: So now my server's got the wrong numbers so it no longer checks out.
Speaker 1: So What it?
Speaker 1: but other people in other parts of the world.
Speaker 1: they have the right numbers, but you can't use their server.
Speaker 1: But now you basically you got rid of security instead of now.
Speaker 1: It's not gonna match up.
Speaker 1: So what can you do?
Speaker 1: Well, you can keep using my wrong server and tell your computer Yeah computer ignore it when the stuff is wrong and just do it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that way I can.
Speaker 1: you know, my computer will keep working But then I'll just send you to Scott comm instead of bank comm and I'll fuck you over.
Speaker 1: Right, so you'd be trading.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Look, it's harder for normal people to get to pirate bay, but normal people also now just lost all their banking.
Speaker 0: now more importantly Technological issues aside.
Speaker 0: I mean, why is this bad?
Speaker 0: because In the end, you know piracy and intellectual property.
Speaker 0: There are many arguments you made on both sides.
Speaker 0: We've been having this argument since the first mini file was uploaded to the internet will not reiterate the argument.
Speaker 1: We'll simply reiterate that we are not going to reiterate it.
Speaker 0: But the salient point here is that when it comes to that sort of thing?
Speaker 0: Regardless of whether or not you think we need stronger copyright protection weaker copyright protection need to make more piracy stop piracy.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter where you sit.
Speaker 0: One of the most important aspects of America that we have left is freedom of speech That we have that you can speak freely that the government basically can't stop you from speaking.
Speaker 0: they can arrest you for very very very specific kinds of dangerous speech and the the Barrier to actually doing so is surprisingly immense.
Speaker 0: the courts almost always rule in favor of free speech but One of the problems of free speech is that you have to deal with people doing really horrible things.
Speaker 0: with free speech I mean hate speech all that sort of stuff.
Speaker 0: cyberbullying and all that stuff is kind of collateral damage of having free speech.
Speaker 0: We agree that free speech is so important to us that we're going to put up with all the bullshit that comes with it Except child porn except child porn.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: but in this case by Making a system where the government can basically shut down a website based on some copyright infringement we're destroying a ton of culture and a ton of DMCA where there's no reason not to believe that this is gonna be abused just as much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even more.
Speaker 0: the collateral damage to free speech of a bill like this is far worse than any piracy could ever be.
Speaker 1: Yes, it is not.
Speaker 1: even if this bill right somehow actually did do good for the world at what cost?
Speaker 1: destroying the internet?
Speaker 1: Sorry, there is nothing worth that cost.
Speaker 0: But anyway things of the day.
Speaker 0: if you know me, you know I'm a fan of the particular kind of prank where the people who are pranked never really know that it's a prank like the weird stuff like going to a restaurant that has a little display outside with like bronze fruit or something at a border like around their menu and replacing a pair with a banana.
Speaker 0: You know stuff that will make will weird someone out, but they'll never quite get the answer like they'll just wonder about it forever.
Speaker 0: Or it'll be this weird anecdote.
Speaker 0: They tell their friends like yeah, this weirdo whatever but This guy is doing the exact kind of thing.
Speaker 0: I like the rude roll-up prank.
Speaker 0: He's pretty clever and he has a lot of video of himself doing this.
Speaker 0: He'll drive up in a car and stop.
Speaker 0: some pedestrians rolled out his window and ask for help.
Speaker 0: ask for directions.
Speaker 1: common thing They'll give him directions because they're friendly.
Speaker 0: while they're giving him directions He just kind of rolls up his car window and looks away from just sits there Just to see what they'll do and beyond that.
Speaker 0: This is priceless.
Speaker 0: This is a beautiful beautiful pranking Alright, so check this out.
Speaker 1: This is a tumblr.
Speaker 1: Gabe.
Speaker 1: Gabe's face sexual.
Speaker 1: tumblr.com.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, it is a blog Consisting of fan art of Gabe from penny arcade.
Speaker 1: So yeah, there is some actual penny arcade art But most of its fan art of other people drawing Gabe from penny arcade usually in sexual ways.
Speaker 1: and You know Mike Krahulik himself tweeted So much of this art is so good that I cannot help but love it.
Speaker 1: Gabe's face sexual calm.
Speaker 1: tumblr.com.
Speaker 1: NSFW.
Speaker 1: So it is approved by Mike himself.
Speaker 1: check this blog out.
Speaker 1: It is the goods.
Speaker 1: and yeah, there's some NSFW right on the first page.
Speaker 1: But it's strange because he's having sex with a woman and Gabe's supposed to be totally gay gay gay for spider-man.
Speaker 1: So that's weird.
Speaker 1: It's clearly not canon.
Speaker 0: So very briefly in the meta moment mag fast is coming up.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be there.
Speaker 0: we're gonna be doing beyond Dungeons & Dragons - oh shit We're gonna be doing.
Speaker 0: we're gonna be on two panels.
Speaker 1: No, it should be beyond.
Speaker 1: on the dragon second edition.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be on two of the mag nine or whatever they're called advanced beyond gaming intellectuals panels, I don't know if I can say what the titles are yet, but Dr.
Speaker 0: Hazard is gonna be on at least one of the panels with us.
Speaker 0: So watch out.
Speaker 1: He's you.
Speaker 1: he's harder than us Don't worry.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you ever thought that we were full of ourselves and like maybe like you wanted to disagree with us But you weren't sure how dr.
Speaker 0: Hazard fucks us up when we argue about games It'll be a good time.
Speaker 0: It's like it's gonna be like punch out to glass.
Speaker 1: Joe's and Mike I was gonna play so many games.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, you know so much game I like packs.
Speaker 0: more packs is my favorite con, but I play way more games at mag fest.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: I Also, don't yell at packs nearly as much as I do at mag fest.
Speaker 1: other meta moments You should check us out on the Internet's Facebook's Twitter's Google+.
Speaker 0: is Shit son also on December 8th a Thursday.
Speaker 0: It's coming up in New York City.
Speaker 0: There's a thing called nerd night.
Speaker 0: Are we confirmed for that?
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, we're pretty much confirmed.
Speaker 0: We're going to present.
Speaker 0: we're going to be doing a 20-minute version of our old lecture.
Speaker 0: losing should be fun.
Speaker 1: This is 100% confirmed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if it's not whatever Okay, I'll issue a retraction.
Speaker 1: It costs money to go to this thing.
Speaker 1: I personally probably wouldn't pay to go.
Speaker 0: just being honest I don't pay to go to anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know, maybe I don't pay to go to anything because I can usually get a free press pass into anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I still wouldn't pay for a nerd get-together in the city because there's so many free ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we'll see.
Speaker 0: We've heard good things about this month.
Speaker 0: Many of our friends have been to these and/or presented at them and we were invited and it looks fun.
Speaker 0: So we'll be there and I'll see if we can video the thing.
Speaker 0: if they don't video it and get it up on the inner Tubes.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Otherwise the book club book is two books double book club.
Speaker 1: A lot of people having trouble realizing this.
Speaker 1: you must read two books.
Speaker 1: The first book you must read is Little Prince by Antoine de Saint-Ejupéry.
Speaker 1: It is very short.
Speaker 1: You should be able to read it in a night.
Speaker 1: I can read it in like two hours or even less, right?
Speaker 1: It's so short.
Speaker 1: Then you have to read a real book also by Antoine de Saint-Ejupéry.
Speaker 1: that will take you a little bit longer to read But not that much longer.
Speaker 1: It's still short.
Speaker 1: It's just not one sitting short and that is Wind, Sand and Stars.
Speaker 1: at least that's the English title.
Speaker 0: And while you should buy these books, I'll just point out that PDFs are available everywhere.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we don't care about you buying books.
Speaker 1: We care about your reading books.
Speaker 1: It's about reading books.
Speaker 1: It's the important part reading not audiobooking like some of you do reading.
Speaker 1: There are scientific studies that reading uses a different part of the brain.
Speaker 1: That is the part of the brain.
Speaker 1: We want you to exercise your exercise.
Speaker 1: you still get in the story But you're exercising a different brain part with the audiobook and that is not the goal.
Speaker 0: and last but not least Pax East is coming up.
Speaker 0: If you didn't get your hotel room already good If you're awesome, you're already going.
Speaker 0: Pax East is the same weekend as Anime Boston So double fucked if you don't have your hotel.
Speaker 0: Oh shit Registration is open.
Speaker 0: So if you're even thinking for a second that you might possibly go buy a goddamn badge now because they're gonna sell out Yep, but like today not tomorrow not all remember to pause this show.
Speaker 1: Get thee to a computer unless you're in a car in which case pull over to the side of the road and use your phone And buy the stupid ticket.
Speaker 1: Yes because you do not buy a ticket from a third party at all under any circumstance because it will be a Forged badge and they're gonna come down on you so hard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I'll tell you what guys.
Speaker 0: Shortly ahead of Pax we're probably gonna put out a nice informative video on how to stop counterfeits because you know what.
Speaker 0: it is Way easy to spot the counterfeits and the more of you are out of a guy is selling them on the street for ridiculously low price.
Speaker 1: They're probably counterfeits.
Speaker 0: Well, it's a way to find out.
Speaker 0: just rip it in half.
Speaker 1: Yeah 9% chance.
Speaker 1: it's a counterfeit.
Speaker 1: The only chance it's not is if some moron Sold their real one to that guy and he's probably gonna sell his counterfeit ones before he sells his real one.
Speaker 0: So yeah, and so SOPA.
Speaker 0: We already talked about this So we're not gonna talk any more about SOPA itself about the law about the activism any of that crap.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm because we're nerds we're geeks and We personally in case this passes have contingency plans to not have to deal with the BS.
Speaker 0: It's gonna happen because while the pirate Bay dot org won't resolve anymore from us DNS Pirate Bay org is gonna keep resolving on my personal PC.
Speaker 1: It sure is.
Speaker 0: and if my ISP starts blocking me Well, there's some VPNs and some SSL that's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: Yep, but you know what?
Speaker 1: There's a much easier way to solve all these problems.
Speaker 1: Move to the Netherlands Joe's over or Canada.
Speaker 1: Well, the Netherlands has like awesome fiber for everyone.
Speaker 1: That's why I chose that place.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I wouldn't mind moving to the Netherlands.
Speaker 1: I wish it were warmer than yeah, but you know just fucking move somewhere that's fucking fiber.
Speaker 1: and Story don't live in the US.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do worry that SOPA might pass.
Speaker 1: I guess I'll plan to move.
Speaker 0: So, how do we get around this?
Speaker 1: Well one if you decide that you can't leave the US for whatever reason What do you do?
Speaker 0: So the one thing is that China's really good at cracking down.
Speaker 0: I Do not think the US is gonna be that good at cracking down.
Speaker 1: No, because it's not gonna be in China is a government censorship organization, right and the US it's gonna be companies Filing court thingies and sending notices and all sorts of bureaucracy of that nature.
Speaker 1: So there isn't going to be this central crackdown, you know thing that's like at the edge of the internet run by the government.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be ISPs and search engines obeying orders and doing and obeying those orders in whatever way they deem necessary.
Speaker 1: So it's you know, it's gonna be like, huh?
Speaker 1: How are we gonna do that?
Speaker 1: So all kinds of different things.
Speaker 1: so like something that might work like some easy way out that might work on Time Warner might not Work even on Time Warner in a different state or it might not work on files, but it works on cable vision.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be all crazy.
Speaker 0: So what do we do?
Speaker 0: first the way DNS works?
Speaker 0: You can google around for the details on how to do this But basically you should be running a DNS server in your house.
Speaker 0: If you're a nerd at all It's trivial to do and you'll learn a lot actually along the way.
Speaker 0: Now if you're using DNS server in your house What I recommend you do is set it up such that old records unless they're refreshed like hash records never expire.
Speaker 0: Yep, so if DNS for something gets blocked you know already know the IP address because you've been to that site before.
Speaker 1: So for example pirate Bay.
Speaker 1: today, I can go to my computer and I can type in a mactomatic computer, right?
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna do.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna do this right now for the good of everyone.
Speaker 1: dig pirate Bay org.
Speaker 1: Dig.
Speaker 0: You can use nslookup if you're on Windows.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's true.
Speaker 1: I actually have dig installed on the windows at work, which is why I would thought I could.
Speaker 1: Okay, the IP address of the pirate Bay is 194 dot 71 dot 107 dot 15. as of 708 p.m.
Speaker 1: On November 21st 2011 Eastern Time us Right, so if they decide that they're gonna block pirate Bay, which is pretty much gonna go down immediately if this law passes Well one.
Speaker 0: you've already committed a crime if that law were passed because you provided the service of providing the name resolution of the you know To the infringing site.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, right and you type in nslookup pirate Bay org.
Speaker 1: You're actually gonna get different numbers.
Speaker 1: You're gonna get the numbers for some government server that has a takedown notice web server running or something like that.
Speaker 1: So what all you have to do is you just have to either put it in your host file.
Speaker 1: Or if you did like rim said and have your own DNS server that never forgets like an elephant and an elephant DNS Your elephant DNS server will still give you the old pirate Bay number and Only people using their isp's normal DNS servers will get the new number of the.
Speaker 1: that does that's wrong.
Speaker 1: So Yeah, and most people, you know have it will never change their DNS, but it is trivial to do So.
Speaker 1: even complete doofuses can do this thing.
Speaker 1: It's really easy on all three operating systems to change your DNS.
Speaker 1: In fact as an aside I found you can even change it on your router and then every computer in your house will automatically have It changed even phones and other things.
Speaker 1: Yeah via the DHCP server that is running on your router Yep, so you don't even need to like tell teach people to do anything.
Speaker 1: It's just like they'll come over to your house and like how come pirate Bay works at your house because I typed some numbers into My router.
Speaker 0: so phase two or maybe phase zero.
Speaker 0: Maybe it comes before so that may work.
Speaker 0: If anyone's gonna fight this it's gonna be Google.
Speaker 0: So you might want to just preemptively switch to Google's DNS.
Speaker 0: Oh because there's a good chance that They'll hold on to records longer and or fight for whatever they need to fight for.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you might not want to use Google DNS if you're not living in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Oh, but there's no danger of this bullshit.
Speaker 1: So cares?
Speaker 0: yeah, actually Europe has good coverage for Google DNS, that's true.
Speaker 0: But anyway, some European countries do have some censorships though I recommend doing that anyway, because lately I've actually been having a ton of problems with Verizon FiOS Periodically crapping out and I did some investigation.
Speaker 1: It's really fast when it works.
Speaker 0: It turned out it was Verizon's DNS servers Mysteriously stop responding when I queried YouTube and pirate Bay and stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then they start responding in later.
Speaker 0: So I switched to Google and that problem stopped happening.
Speaker 0: Awesome, huh?
Speaker 0: Funny that?
Speaker 1: yeah All right.
Speaker 1: So what if they don't just do this DNS blocking?
Speaker 1: What if they also do like IP blocking deep packet inspection?
Speaker 0: Well, those are two things.
Speaker 0: if they do IP blocking specifically then People who really want to provide their pirated stuff to the u.s Will start using dynamic IPS or you'll start going through proxies stuff like that.
Speaker 1: It'll basically be the same thing that Chinese people do to get to the real internet.
Speaker 0: It'll slow us down, but it won't stop us exactly and it'll be annoying.
Speaker 0: but Blocking IPS that'll stop like going to a website and downloading the content directly.
Speaker 1: Yes, for example, so like they turn off mega upload That's just.
Speaker 1: that's gonna be the end of that.
Speaker 0: but say they shut down pirate Bay and they block all the IPS.
Speaker 0: They keep it like every time part Bay has a new IP address They find it and block it and there's no way around that.
Speaker 0: All right, you can use a proxy to get to pirate Bay.
Speaker 0: Just fine.
Speaker 1: because what if they start blocking all the proxies?
Speaker 1: they have to do it really fast because it's how fast can we switch?
Speaker 1: It becomes a pain in the ass basically because it's got that whack.
Speaker 0: a little game is never-ending and impossible.
Speaker 0: But - it's it.
Speaker 1: but it's basically two people playing whack-a-mole against each other forever.
Speaker 1: So you have to basically keep changing the number in your proxy software thingy and they have to keep changing.
Speaker 0: No, because you keep your old IP - oh For the rest of the world DNS stops working.
Speaker 0: DNS still points at you except where the u.s Is minding that they break it not sure which is an interesting problem because you know, we talked about this before But
Speaker 1: the people running the proxies if the proxies get their IPs blocked the proxies have to keep moving and you have to keep Updating the proxy on your computer.
Speaker 0: These are really hard to find and block especially because most proxies are gonna use SSL.
Speaker 1: Everything you send to the proxy will be encrypted.
Speaker 1: So how's anyone gonna even know to send a takedown notice for the proxy?
Speaker 1: because they can be like take down this IP address.
Speaker 1: What's at the IP address?
Speaker 0: There isn't even a website there or anything and the majority and piracy will just move even further into the pirate Where it's peer-to-peer.
Speaker 1: Anyway, once you get that torrent file from Pirate Bay, that's it, right?
Speaker 1: They can't be blocking like Everyone's individual personal computers.
Speaker 1: This is mostly gonna be used for taking down sites Not my compute my IP address in my house.
Speaker 1: So once you get the torrent file and your torrents running that's all peer-to-peer and they're gonna have a really hard time doing anything About that.
Speaker 1: pretty much impossible.
Speaker 1: do anything about that.
Speaker 0: So say you want to go the next step and have your DNS keep working.
Speaker 0: Well, if this passes, I'm pretty much assuming that DNS is fucked.
Speaker 1: Anyway, there are people have already set up elephant DNS servers.
Speaker 1: That's the name.
Speaker 1: I'm calling it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I just made up that name Like that name.
Speaker 1: I just coined it.
Speaker 0: So what you do and this goes back to a kind of deeper discussion we're kind of planning on doing a Thursday show about the general concept, but Trust networks are very important If you ever intend to do things where you need to coordinate among a number of people and not get caught.
Speaker 0: That is the most diplomatic way I can put that.
Speaker 0: Mmm So if you have are conspiring to do something, whatever it may be In the future, it's too late.
Speaker 0: If you need to do it now, you haven't already planned this it's too late.
Speaker 0: But if you have to do something down the road like this you plan now.
Speaker 0: You've got a network of trust network of friends.
Speaker 0: you exchange keys, you know one-time pads asymmetric keys Whatever kind of encryption you want to use.
Speaker 0: you exchange keywords you exchange IP addresses.
Speaker 0: You exchange all this information that is ready to be used to build a communications network on the fly Immediately in the vent of trouble, right?
Speaker 1: so there's one software that could be used to do this.
Speaker 1: that might be hard to set up but basically the Architecturally, it's exactly what you want and we could rebuild something like it quite easily.
Speaker 1: It was called waste.
Speaker 0: It was written by the guy who made nullsoft waste was ahead of its time and is a very important piece of software, right?
Speaker 1: But it was incredibly hard to use.
Speaker 1: So the way waste works is this I run waste on my computer.
Speaker 1: I create cryptographic public-private keys Which we have talked about in the show before goes to an old episode for how they work.
Speaker 1: You send your public keys to your friend.
Speaker 1: You tell your friend your IP address.
Speaker 1: He gives you his public key.
Speaker 1: now you connect.
Speaker 1: your two wastes are connected.
Speaker 1: You've shared public keys.
Speaker 1: You know each other's IP address.
Speaker 1: You can now chat and send files with your friend in an unbreakable Encrypted manner.
Speaker 1: It's so awesome.
Speaker 0: It's deniable.
Speaker 0: You can set it to Constantly send data at a rate and then if you send real data the rate doesn't change.
Speaker 0: So you're gonna slow yourself down significantly because you're picking the small rate.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna be blowing you a megabit up and down constantly, right?
Speaker 0: But there is no Trivial mathematical way to figure out if what is going over that connection is garbage or content.
Speaker 1: Yep, so then you get more friends in on this and more friends into this and everyone you create this, you know It's hard to do.
Speaker 1: you have to do footwork.
Speaker 1: You have to give people key files and exchange IP addresses.
Speaker 1: But it all if everyone just connects to someone in this web you build this mesh of encrypted deniable perfect trust and information sharing with the chatting and the file sharing.
Speaker 0: now a lot of people unbreakable a lot of people try to Kind of they.
Speaker 0: they have these visions where they want to take something like this and make it gigantic Or they want to make like a peer-to-peer DNS.
Speaker 0: That is gigantic.
Speaker 1: It breaks down because it's not fast enough.
Speaker 0: No, not because it's not fast enough.
Speaker 0: it breaks down because now it's no longer a circle of trust.
Speaker 0: It's an open system that can be trivially exploited by people who you know, basically betray.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like you go to a website and there's a list of IPs of people in the waste network and a list all the public Keys, it's okay to share the public keys, but it's still like.
Speaker 1: here's a list of all the IPs to connect to derp derp derp.
Speaker 1: Oh great.
Speaker 1: Thanks guys.
Speaker 0: Yeah, your network of trust is fucked the moment you trust anyone who themselves are untrustworthy.
Speaker 0: So This is more a more delicate thing.
Speaker 0: This is a balkanization of the internet in the short term.
Speaker 0: basically you and all the people you actually trust You know really really trust.
Speaker 0: you have a list of people, you know, and it lists people you're friends with you.
Speaker 0: No, you have a list of people you trust.
Speaker 0: These are the people you give an account on your personal PC to.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 0: So you and only those people form your own network of trust.
Speaker 0: and if every circle of nerds does that?
Speaker 0: Will basically route around this because every circle of nerds has at least one person outside of the u.s Who can provide real DNS for them and or all the other proxies they need, right?
Speaker 1: So for example, you could exchange, you know, the current IP address of the Pirate Bay on your waste network, right stuff like that.
Speaker 0: now in general you should do this.
Speaker 0: anyway, if you're nerds who ever plan to you know, Do big things because doing the footwork on this now sets you up for the future because once you know The FBI comes crashing down on you or once the government comes crashing down on you or you're in China and the government comes Crashing down on you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's already too late, but pretty much the tools available to you are Encryption which is the most important right peer-to-peer, which is the most important.
Speaker 1: if they're taking down centralized repositories of things, right?
Speaker 1: Backup DNS.
Speaker 1: So you have the IP addresses proxies so that you can route around things that need to be routed around and And that's pretty much it.
Speaker 0: in a way This law passing would not be good.
Speaker 0: It would ruin the internet for the short term but at the same time it would basically force all the circles of nerds who have the capabilities to do things like this to do it and Not to quote Star Wars or anything.
Speaker 0: But that is literally striking them down.
Speaker 0: so they become more powerful than we could possibly imagine.
Speaker 0: Yeah, pretty much because once the nerds all descend into the darknet with hamachi's and wastes and things like that There's basically no way to get them back out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, hamachi's VPNs and virtual lands and all this, right?
Speaker 0: Nothing is actually driven nerds in the u.s.
Speaker 0: To need this technology.
Speaker 1: people are based nerds Basically, you know, it's like nerds like convenience, you know So what they do and they want to stay hidden.
Speaker 1: those they use something like IRC Which is something normal people would never figure out how to use or news groups, right?
Speaker 1: So it's hidden.
Speaker 1: It's hard for normal people to see but it's still out in the open and if a government agent wants to look at it Well, they're fucking is.
Speaker 1: they're just had to know that it's there.
Speaker 1: if we actually hide further if they push us farther down We'll actually start using tools that are a huge pain in the ass So even less people will be able to use them.
Speaker 1: but those that do use them will be unassailable.
Speaker 1: Will be is basically like we're in the fortress or on the ramparts and we're like, yep Pretty safe up here, right and then some guys start climbing up and we're like shit.
Speaker 1: Let me actually go in the fortress and close the port colors.
Speaker 1: You ain't getting in.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're down.
Speaker 0: We're down an issue.
Speaker 0: all you know where the fuck that is.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much game over once you close the port colors, so Learn how to close your port colors As you might need to go in there soon.
Speaker 1: stock up with the water and the food and the swords if you have to now.
Speaker 0: my recommendation again is to Make these plans with your friends now because one this might pass and you've got it You know.
Speaker 0: be ready before it's too late and a good example of that if any of you saw the old classic movie hackers Which is basically the same movie as the craft They're both my cool thing.
Speaker 0: I wish it was actually that way even though it isn't for Wicca and hacking.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the matrix kind of fulfilled that same purpose that same niche market for hacking.
Speaker 0: But anyway, there's the matrix is good I think it was.
Speaker 0: cereal gets arrested and he says something to his friend as he's being arrested to the effect of Because remember he's being arrested.
Speaker 0: Everyone knows what he's saying.
Speaker 0: Hey, remember that place.
Speaker 0: I hid that thing that one time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that doesn't there's no way for that to mean anything.
Speaker 1: so they know Yeah, they know that the FBI now knows that he hid a thing and when they go to court They'll say he hid a thing somewhere.
Speaker 0: He said remember that place.
Speaker 0: I hid that thing that one time.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's a key word where you know.
Speaker 0: Like if I tell Scott, you know, so now I'm not gonna use any of my stuff.
Speaker 0: but if there are references I can make to things that Literally Scott is the only person in the world who would know what I was referencing and he would know exactly what to do.
Speaker 0: Yep, so if you've got all that stuff set up ahead of time when you get arrested like cereal and you gotta hack the planet You're good.
Speaker 0: You know, that's all your friends get arrested at the same time.
Speaker 0: Then it's time for a radio free America, yep, this has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew dot-com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 1: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.