Speaker 1: It's Tuesday September 20th 2011.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: the hive a game buzzing with Possibilities.
Speaker 1: that's what it says on the box.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: That is what it says on the box hive a game buzzing with possibilities.
Speaker 1: and the website is hive mania.com.
Speaker 0: Okay, so So rim?
Speaker 0: yeah, you know there's a lot of old games that we'd like to play But we cannot play at least not easily or reasonably like tie fighter.
Speaker 0: Oh my god You actually came up with the game.
Speaker 0: I was going to discuss because without any sort of Pre-telling wait that's ready to get.
Speaker 0: that's really what you're gonna Talk about because usually I was expecting you to like be like tribes to and name all the other games except for the one that I was trying to discuss.
Speaker 1: No, but you see if I go back of all the if you talk about like my desire to play a game That does exist or did exist in some form where I don't even need it to be.
Speaker 0: I know that that was the right answer But I was just.
Speaker 0: I was assuming that as soon as I needed you to say it you wouldn't say it But the fact that you said it is like oh my god That was kind of amazing because usually tribes too is the answer and I swear there was no pre talking whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Rim had no idea what I was going for.
Speaker 1: so all right.
Speaker 1: so tie fighter.
Speaker 0: I. literally there's a major flaw in tie fighter of an extreme flaw.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: Here's one flaw.
Speaker 0: It's so old.
Speaker 0: That's not the flaw and so slow.
Speaker 1: You're totally way off, and I'm so good at not even close that I Can basically single-handedly with a tie interceptor take out like a star destroyer.
Speaker 0: So here's the flaw of tie fight single player that I realize is a major problem.
Speaker 0: alright That makes it basically.
Speaker 0: I can't I can't play that game.
Speaker 0: You don't have a joystick.
Speaker 0: No not even close.
Speaker 1: You don't have the instruction manual anymore.
Speaker 0: No when you're playing tie fighter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what do you see I?
Speaker 1: See a tornado withering?
Speaker 0: no What do you actually see on the screen?
Speaker 1: I see out the front of my ship.
Speaker 0: yeah Have you ever seen a tie fighter pilot?
Speaker 1: Yeah, the kind of funny look.
Speaker 0: do you remember what they look like?
Speaker 0: they look something like this?
Speaker 0: What do you think he fucking sees out of that fucking helmet?
Speaker 0: he probably he sees like two black slits.
Speaker 1: He probably has displays inside of that helmet.
Speaker 0: then how come he you when when you're playing tie fighter you actually see the physical Inside of the ship as opposed to just heads-up display.
Speaker 1: You're so badass.
Speaker 1: You took the helmet off.
Speaker 0: I know you didn't.
Speaker 0: you die in the cold horrible of space plus.
Speaker 1: How do you know?
Speaker 1: maybe there's cameras?
Speaker 1: No eyes, maybe there's lenses.
Speaker 0: No, it's it's total bullshit.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's that bad.
Speaker 1: You don't know what it looks like.
Speaker 0: a helmet off.
Speaker 0: That's what this hose is coming out of it So he can fucking breathe.
Speaker 1: I want to point out.
Speaker 1: There's a much bigger flaw.
Speaker 1: What did what was Darth Vader doing?
Speaker 1: I take it Scott that you when he kept turning way way way little knobs I was gonna say what.
Speaker 1: what like interface does Darth Vader have to his ship?
Speaker 1: and apparently it is an Atari 2600 paddle controller and nothing else.
Speaker 0: I Basically I can tell you exactly what he was doing.
Speaker 0: and no this isn't.
Speaker 0: this is based on my Scott Reuben, it's not based on any Star Wars things.
Speaker 0: I'm sure there are plenty of Star Wars nerds who came up with an answer for this.
Speaker 0: All right, but according to me what he was doing is basically he controls the ship with the force.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So what was that knobbly?
Speaker 0: The only thing he can't control with the force is the fuel injection.
Speaker 0: So Fuel.
Speaker 1: what fuel does the tie fighter use base fuel do?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna google right now What is Darth Vader doing with?
Speaker 0: they definitely have fuel because they had the the Millennium Falcon Refueles on the cloud city and also tattooing.
Speaker 1: All right, I searched for what was Darth Vader doing with that knob and I didn't find anything really.
Speaker 0: I'm sure this.
Speaker 0: the nerds are gonna come out and tell us.
Speaker 1: I'm sure I could google more specifically for like tie fighter knob interface.
Speaker 0: But basically my excuse is that every part of the the rest of the time Look at what was controlled with the force except for the knob.
Speaker 1: So look at what Porkins and everybody was doing.
Speaker 0: No, you know what?
Speaker 0: I got here's the real answer.
Speaker 0: That was wizard.
Speaker 0: No that no, he was actually controlling the entire ship with the force and that was his flask.
Speaker 0: He was unscrewing the cat.
Speaker 0: That's why he spun off into space cuz he was wasted.
Speaker 0: he could.
Speaker 1: I think they can see just fine out of those stupid helmets.
Speaker 0: They can't see fine out of the stupid helmet.
Speaker 1: That helmet actually doesn't look that bad Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 1: Also Scott.
Speaker 0: We call it the 501st.
Speaker 0: You'll put one on.
Speaker 0: we'll see what you can see.
Speaker 1: I'm sure I will be able to see many things including a dread specter of stillborn children on the horizon.
Speaker 1: Sure I love how the prince of nothing has corrupted me.
Speaker 1: to where if any if someone so much as says the words see See and anything in any way related to a question do see you see?
Speaker 1: yep Any of those?
Speaker 1: any combination or what?
Speaker 0: do you something else beside?
Speaker 0: What do you hear?
Speaker 1: It's a very simple regular expression That generates this meme coming out of me, right?
Speaker 0: So let's let's move on
Speaker 1: Alright, so I got a little bit of a geek bite because as you may know Natural selection is one of our favorite games ever made favorite one of our favorite FPS
Speaker 0: and we're not talking about the Darwin book even
Speaker 1: One of our favorite games of any genre.
Speaker 1: It's a fantastic game.
Speaker 1: In fact, we talked about it glowingly in many different panels over many years at many conventions and many episodes of you.
Speaker 1: So I don't need to talk about how great it is.
Speaker 0: Except you just did so a while ago.
Speaker 0: Uh, we bought natural selection to a long time ago pre-ordered that shit 50 bucks.
Speaker 1: Yep We paid for the super ultimate platinum gold black edition.
Speaker 0: We gave them a pile of money and Before seeing any product that could have been a bbocs situation.
Speaker 1: I point out many times in my life.
Speaker 1: I have been burned.
Speaker 1: Burned is such an understatement roasted.
Speaker 1: I remember there was a website where you typed in a person's name and it would go through the decade that that person waited between team fortress and team fortress 2 Mmm and yeah team fortress 2 Was.
Speaker 1: it was kind of a disappointment.
Speaker 1: Yeah To me personally, so go on and tribes, you know, it's just never gonna come back.
Speaker 1: But tell natural selection 2 is playable in an alpha beta state.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's technically an alpha or a beta anymore.
Speaker 1: I don't remember if it was a telecaster or a stratocaster.
Speaker 1: So That's another thing that comes out.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so I tried to play a natural selection - again Over the weekend as I attempt to do about once a month.
Speaker 0: and you know what on your very fast computer on your files.
Speaker 1: Yes, I have files.
Speaker 1: I have a computer that while I built it quite some time ago.
Speaker 1: I seven with 7 money could buy one enough to play.
Speaker 1: ns2 is the point?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: ns2 is unplayable any server I join.
Speaker 1: There's one skulk Running around biting a bunch of t-pose Marines stuck in their base.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile if you would read the ns2 Twitter feed It's like they're talking about adjusting the game balance and upgrading weapon models.
Speaker 0: It's like are you even playing the same fucking game?
Speaker 1: So your team doesn't work.
Speaker 0: About balance and models and graphics.
Speaker 0: your game does not work.
Speaker 1: I have two questions because one Reading forums and what other people are saying about the game It appears that there is a small percentage of people who actually claim to be playing.
Speaker 0: either they're lying Or maybe they're only playing land mode or something.
Speaker 1: Maybe I gave my money to a different group of people and got scammed by accident and they're all playing the real game.
Speaker 0: I don't fucking know.
Speaker 0: Maybe I think my guess is that is land mode right because in the office they're testing against each other on a land They're not doing because I realized that most of the anecdotes I've heard about ns2 play come from the development team themselves and not any other person.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they need to all work from home with fucking cable modems until that shit fucking works.
Speaker 1: However, it's not the net code in and of itself.
Speaker 1: There are more fundamental problems.
Speaker 1: I've mostly lost faith in the project, but I lost faith a long time ago.
Speaker 1: I already gave him my money.
Speaker 1: However, unlike Team fortress or weapons factory or tie fighter or tribes 2 or tribes?
Speaker 1: I can still play ns and you know what and as one ns natural selection is still to this day one of the best games ever and you know what.
Speaker 1: I was playing over the weekend and It was exactly the same as it's always been though.
Speaker 1: The community is a tiny bit smaller Tiny bit.
Speaker 0: I haven't noticed that only a tiny bit.
Speaker 1: There's like four or five active full-on real games without any bullshit mods.
Speaker 0: I only ever go to bad clan.
Speaker 0: That's bad clan.
Speaker 1: There's one other server.
Speaker 1: I go to.
Speaker 1: okay But the community is a little more pissy.
Speaker 1: I haven't noticed it except for marine commander who yeah sounds Older and a little more subdued.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's going around.
Speaker 0: He's like, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah get him gorge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, fuck we lost.
Speaker 1: Let's just like he gives up way more easily.
Speaker 0: They never have drugs this weekend.
Speaker 1: But yeah, I joined the server and I hadn't played this game in like a year and I start to play on the random server.
Speaker 1: I just join and immediately I'm on the aliens and some guys like You've got to get a gorge.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I was like, oh man, it's him.
Speaker 1: That guy must do nothing but play this game.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 0: So check this out.
Speaker 0: I should probably talk about this on Monday, but I don't care.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right, so the Maker Faire was this weekend.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I did not go.
Speaker 1: I biked past it.
Speaker 1: Oh exciting Yeah, I was on my ways to flushing The Maker Faire cut through the park and then the park was full of maker.
Speaker 0: I thought you wanted like hurry up the show.
Speaker 0: But meanwhile here you are like The show.
Speaker 1: you said that right before we started was that wasn't set on the show so it wasn't canon sure fine.
Speaker 0: Then I'm gonna that I'm not gonna hurry up the showing a delay.
Speaker 0: So fine.
Speaker 0: I was I was gonna go.
Speaker 0: I went last year.
Speaker 0: It was cool.
Speaker 0: But it's I was thinking well this year.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be 90% the same stuff, right?
Speaker 0: So why?
Speaker 0: you know, maybe I'll go next year.
Speaker 1: It's your news the thing that you wanted to see.
Speaker 1: that now that you know, it was there.
Speaker 1: You should have gone.
Speaker 0: No, not at all.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: So one of the things that's all that was always there like the maker bots You know the the 3d printers, you know print out plastic shit, right?
Speaker 0: So this is really interesting article that brings up this question that I had not thought of right apparently, right.
Speaker 0: The question here is what if somebody prints out guns?
Speaker 0: Real gun.
Speaker 1: Oh, we already have laws about that.
Speaker 0: No, so check this out ready.
Speaker 0: So here's the first question right is as many layers to this right the people who host like the model files It's like should they host the model files for the different parts of the guns?
Speaker 1: Well, are we are so.
Speaker 1: are we gonna talk morally or legally?
Speaker 1: Legally?
Speaker 1: as far as I can tell I am NOT a lawyer of any stretch nor is Scott.
Speaker 0: according to this article It is not illegal really.
Speaker 1: Well, it depends because what I was gonna say is that there's regulation about certain kind of least.
Speaker 0: here's a quote from Brie Pettis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we've already been through a few flame wars around what a weapon is.
Speaker 0: our take is that we'd rather you not upload weapons But we're not going to regulate it unless it's illegal, which it isn't.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, the thing is is it illegal to forge your own sword?
Speaker 1: It depends on where you live.
Speaker 1: Maybe there's a law against having a blade that long.
Speaker 1: Maybe not.
Speaker 1: Maybe you can't carry it.
Speaker 1: There are some places where you can own a sword, but you can't carry it in public.
Speaker 1: I'm sure if I walked around Manhattan with a fully sharpened six foot long sword I would get stopped.
Speaker 0: Yeah, probably so but there's even here's an even deeper question, right?
Speaker 0: apparently two people have uploaded two parts to the to.
Speaker 1: Oh, I saw an article about this on FARC, right?
Speaker 0: One of the parts they uploaded was just for a magazine complete with spring.
Speaker 0: Alright, the second part was the ar-15 lower receiver.
Speaker 0: Apparently the entire of the entire ar-15 Only the lower receiver is the part that you actually need like the.
Speaker 0: apparently the gun laws.
Speaker 0: like they thought about this.
Speaker 0: If only they would think this hard about the tech laws.
Speaker 0: It you know.
Speaker 0: It's like they have gun experts through these gun laws.
Speaker 1: The gun laws get to the point to where there's.
Speaker 1: they list like six Aspects and if you have any N of them you are classified as an assault rifle, right?
Speaker 0: But it's like how come they have experts who in guns writing these gun laws?
Speaker 0: But meanwhile, they have like retarded homeless bums writing the computer laws.
Speaker 1: What the fuck.
Speaker 1: but anyway, so then it's got most gun people As I have heard them rant many times say that the gun laws are only impressive to people who don't understand guns Probably ludicrous to gun, but at least they put some thought into it.
Speaker 0: It's like here the lower receiver is the frame that holds together all the pieces of the firearm in the States.
Speaker 0: All the other pieces can be purchased without a permit over-the-counter or through the post.
Speaker 0: The lower receiver is the only part which requires a background check or any other kind of paperwork before purchase.
Speaker 0: Typically, it's made of aluminum.
Speaker 0: a rifle with a lower receiver made of plastic can be perfectly functional and you can just download the Schematic of this part and print your print one out for yourself.
Speaker 0: You know what awesome it is kind of awesome, but here where's your Story about the diamond age where they you know guns lots of guns and some you know awesome nerds or evil crazy guys or militia Prints out like an armory's worth of assault, right?
Speaker 1: This is the maker blood that people like us and by us I mean anyone with an IQ above 70 who was ever for more than a fraction of a second considered the future of technology.
Speaker 1: Well, you know those ads like you wouldn't download a car and the common meme response is fuck you.
Speaker 1: I would if I could.
Speaker 0: that's right.
Speaker 1: So it's from the first dawn of man People have assumed that someday we will mass produce weapons in our homes without any difficulty whatsoever.
Speaker 1: I am play God I don't think anyone in a position of power Anywhere in the world?
Speaker 1: Understands the ramifications of that.
Speaker 0: They're not even thinking about it.
Speaker 1: The thing is we already can you know, I can make a bomb really easily It's true.
Speaker 1: So and I could make the gun myself, but here's it is a different thing.
Speaker 1: So here's the thing.
Speaker 1: making the bomb requires lab skills and and the components and knowing what you're making.
Speaker 1: Making the gun requires machining skills of some kind or extruding skills or manufacturing skills and the equipment and the instructions.
Speaker 1: This just requires the maker bot and the file.
Speaker 0: You need the bullets.
Speaker 1: You can just buy bullets bullets or actually you can just go buy them.
Speaker 0: Yeah See, I think what we need to do is you need to just get rid of all the gun laws.
Speaker 1: We'll be able to print bullets and only where you need gunpowder.
Speaker 0: You can't print gun.
Speaker 1: You can make gunpowder pretty fucking easily.
Speaker 0: I know but you can't print.
Speaker 0: it is the point.
Speaker 1: Not yet.
Speaker 1: You need a chemistry set.
Speaker 1: Scott, you're telling me we won't have chemical printers in the next hundred years.
Speaker 0: So I'll just go and I'll take some atoms on my screen and I'll arrange them and I'll like take two I'll take two hydrogens and an oxygen.
Speaker 0: you'll buy push print and water comes out.
Speaker 1: I guarantee you within a hundred years we'll at least have maker bots where you give them a set of core components and they can make certain kinds of chemical reactions to Make certain materials.
Speaker 0: so I could go online and like get the the molecule of some medicine and like just print it out.
Speaker 0: I think it's like THC print it bitch.
Speaker 1: I think that's going to happen.
Speaker 1: want to get high give it a couple centuries That's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: The only thing that might stop it is energy depletion Because that'll probably be pretty energy intensive.
Speaker 0: I should just type in like, you know, just take like 900 protons.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just like go Nobel Prize.
Speaker 1: So What do we do about this?
Speaker 1: should we make a Thursday show about this?
Speaker 0: I just wanted to talk about it.
Speaker 0: cuz awesome.
Speaker 1: It is awesome.
Speaker 1: Uh, I Have very conflicted opinions on it But I feel like here's the reality.
Speaker 1: much like I'm gonna take my the same stance I take with things like privacy.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna take on this.
Speaker 1: Whatever regulation you make is pointless because it cannot stop it.
Speaker 0: Plastic is now no one's allowed to have plastic.
Speaker 1: All right, so they're gonna ban the plans.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they banned mp3 download.
Speaker 0: They're on torrent.
Speaker 0: Yeah use net you as a sneaker net.
Speaker 1: Yeah sneaker net somebody I mean think about it in Cuba.
Speaker 0: one guy has the plans.
Speaker 0: now The whole world has the plans.
Speaker 0: you delete them from the one spot.
Speaker 0: He just hosted them.
Speaker 0: from what I've read the whole world still has the plan.
Speaker 0: and North Korea?
Speaker 1: There's a thriving trade in USB sticks filled with data.
Speaker 0: No kidding.
Speaker 0: So yes, Lee TV shows and music.
Speaker 1: I love how the primary contraband in North Korea is South Korean movies.
Speaker 1: It's South Korean pop drama TV shows TV shows and news about the world.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but primarily South Korean pop dramas.
Speaker 1: Huh.
Speaker 1: So you're gonna download these plans and make an air 15 lower receiver.
Speaker 0: I don't have any of the other parts nor do it.
Speaker 0: Even if I had them I do not know how to put them together.
Speaker 1: I'm surprised.
Speaker 0: nor would I even know what kind of bullet to go hit that put in it.
Speaker 1: if I even got that far You can figure that out with Google.
Speaker 0: I'm sure I could wait Scott.
Speaker 1: I thought counter-strike trained you to be a fucking killing machine.
Speaker 1: I thought that if you played counter-strike for more than five minutes, you were militarily trained.
Speaker 0: Do you got anyway got a gun?
Speaker 0: I can operate leaning back in a chair without any recoil Then Everybody is in big trouble if they are if they are evil.
Speaker 1: So I want to talk a little bit briefly about the whole Sony PSN TOS.
Speaker 0: All right, go for it.
Speaker 1: Now there's a lot of news about this and then it's interesting because the news everyone's focusing on is that they basically Prohibit you from suing them and it's a kind of well That was the change.
Speaker 0: all the other stuff in the TOS is it was there before.
Speaker 1: so while that is the change And I think there were some other changes too because they kind of rewrote it and they're also making you agree to it Or you can't use the service anymore.
Speaker 1: One as some journalists are the same as every other service as one journalist very pointedly and poignantly pointed out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I learned about this because my ten-year-old son said that a window popped up and he clicked Okay to make it go away before the PlayStation would start this morning.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So yeah click through whatever.
Speaker 1: but Because of all this there's a point in this TOS that I want to read to you verbatim Because I know how Microsoft handles this BS and we know how Nintendo handles this.
Speaker 1: it's Sony.
Speaker 1: It's like they tried to find the worst possible middle ground between these two ways of doing things.
Speaker 1: It's like they went out of their way to make the stupidest most unenforceable and arbitrary policy in the world.
Speaker 1: Okay You may not provide anyone with your name or any other personally identifying information other than your online ID nor the name password or personally identifying information of any other person or business through any means.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh So you cannot.
Speaker 1: basically if you have a handle your online ID in PSN It is against the terms of service and a kickable bannable offense to so much as reveal anything about yourself Where you live what your name is?
Speaker 1: Another handle you have an email address the name of any business whether or not it's related to you theoretically.
Speaker 1: According to this if you say the word Microsoft you should be banned.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, if you say the word Sony you should be banned.
Speaker 0: All right It's ludicrous.
Speaker 1: I mean Nintendo just doesn't actually let you communicate with people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and Microsoft is just a sea of dicks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the internet is just somehow I don't know if it's actually more or less dicks Because I found that Xbox Live tends to have more assholes than on Normal online play but I play in walled gardens.
Speaker 1: I play in like password-protected CS servers, and I don't know.
Speaker 1: I just find this Sentence ideas.
Speaker 0: I mean all.
Speaker 0: every TOS you're ever gonna read Apple Nintendo my anybody is Full of evil and crazy stupid bullshit like this.
Speaker 0: Adobe sure right, but the Sony ones, right?
Speaker 0: It's like Sony has more so than any of these other companies cuz all companies have had huge fuck-ups in the TOS Department of like.
Speaker 0: oh my god.
Speaker 0: They're so evil.
Speaker 1: Sony goes above and beyond Sony Fuck up department.
Speaker 1: My job is to fuck up.
Speaker 0: Remember Apple was like.
Speaker 0: you can't make Software for the iPhone using it right and no.
Speaker 0: and Nintendo everyone had.
Speaker 0: so everyone has had their evil But Sony has had is the only one that has can had consistent streak of Evil over and over and over.
Speaker 1: It's not just evil without taking a break.
Speaker 1: It is evil followed up by incompetence.
Speaker 0: Yes, but you know, you can't.
Speaker 0: we can't tell which one it is Right.
Speaker 0: we the old saying goes but regardless which whenever whether it's evil or incompetence Sony is the only company that has had a never-ending streak in that department going on What like ten plus years since I was in like high school.
Speaker 0: so Seeing that I don't know why people still give money to Sony for anything Well, they want to use their stuff.
Speaker 0: What stuff does Sony have that you need to use?
Speaker 1: maybe games that other people might like that are exclusive that you personally might not?
Speaker 0: Like for how many of those games are there?
Speaker 0: three depends?
Speaker 0: Yeah almost none.
Speaker 0: It's not worth it I just fight.
Speaker 1: I feel like in general the terms of service stuff when it comes to online stuff is So broken like we just talked about how broken gun laws are.
Speaker 1: I feel like all this stuff is just a giant catastrophe waiting to happen.
Speaker 1: I mean part of the terms of service says that I affirm that I'm at least 18 and Emancipated minor or possess legal parental or guardian consent, but if I'm not I can't have agreed to the contract anyway.
Speaker 1: so TOS seemed to only exist to cover people's asses from liability.
Speaker 1: I don't feel like that liability should even exist.
Speaker 1: I don't feel like any online service should actually have any responsibility to do any checking or follow-up on the age or Locality or anything of its users.
Speaker 0: Well, the problem is that there's actually laws about.
Speaker 0: I know
Speaker 1: I don't think there should be
Speaker 0: The
Speaker 1: fact that to go to a website that talks about beer if it's hosted in the US They tent like for like a beer distributor you have to say what your age is
Speaker 0: But you can watch a football game with a beer commercial
Speaker 1: or
Speaker 0: go to a football stadium with or
Speaker 1: Scott everywhere.
Speaker 1: I point out that every 13 year old in the world was born in January 1st 1901.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Think there's a much more elegant terms of service that we should use for just about everything with maybe minor improvements.
Speaker 0: use at your Own risk.
Speaker 1: don't cheat don't steal don't punch or kick people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't harass anyone.
Speaker 1: Don't spray paint on stuff.
Speaker 1: I guess in counter-strike.
Speaker 1: We need to be able to spray paint on stay.
Speaker 0: Hey, that's important.
Speaker 1: Don't mess with things that aren't your.
Speaker 1: again I guess in counter-strike.
Speaker 1: I need to be able to mess with things that are mine.
Speaker 0: Well, there are yours.
Speaker 0: if you if I kill you I don't know all your stuff belongs to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's not how it works.
Speaker 0: But Scott.
Speaker 0: so I planted this bomb.
Speaker 1: you came over and started fucking with it.
Speaker 0: You put it on the ground still mine.
Speaker 0: I'm standing right next to it.
Speaker 0: No That's like move your feet lose.
Speaker 0: you see You're not touching.
Speaker 0: it is not yours Scott.
Speaker 1: That was my bullet.
Speaker 1: Give it back I'm touching.
Speaker 0: it is mine now.
Speaker 1: So things of the day It's metapony and that is related to ponies.
Speaker 1: It's not a pony much pony.
Speaker 1: It's a good thing though.
Speaker 1: So when Emily pointed this out, I had no idea.
Speaker 1: even though I'm a fan of Barbra Streisand I just actually never heard this song.
Speaker 0: really the mega Streisand?
Speaker 1: I'm also you know what Scott?
Speaker 1: I am also a fan of meatloaf Bonnie Tyler and Cher.
Speaker 1: In fact, I actually really like Cher style concerts, okay, they're kind of like modern pop costume roof.
Speaker 1: anyway Any of you, you know what punk kids in the forum your whiny?
Speaker 1: Yima, whatever music it is.
Speaker 1: I guess dubstep is what you're all into now.
Speaker 1: Cher is better than dubstep.
Speaker 1: Okay, so The art of the dress a song about which many of you may be familiar Many of you are probably humming it right now or going on YouTube to listen to it So it gets stuck in your head is in fact based on a Barbra Streisand song.
Speaker 0: It's not every pony song is based on some other song exactly.
Speaker 1: so if you were into music It would be interesting for you to look at these two songs and then go check out all the other.
Speaker 1: like relations I did a week-long thing the day years ago where I took the song born to be alive and Followed it through the internet to its source through all the remixes and covers and mashups and everything.
Speaker 1: I did the same thing with another Russian song at one point and I don't remember even what it was called.
Speaker 1: Oh, those were the days.
Speaker 1: So it's a fun hobby of mine.
Speaker 1: So I'm giving you the pony version and the Barbra Streisand version and I encourage you to use these as seeds to do this To some other song or maybe this song.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so this isn't really, you know a typical thing of the day with like a funny video and all that stuff, right This is just a long.
Speaker 0: Well Meg, I guess New York Times magazine article, I guess it's one of those big long six pagers, but it's really fast words exactly words.
Speaker 0: But basically the deal here.
Speaker 0: the summary is there's a guy and he was a foreign correspondent, right?
Speaker 1: And so he had oh, is this the high school football thing?
Speaker 0: no, okay, nevermind.
Speaker 0: so his job was to work in Russia Right.
Speaker 0: So he had to take his family to Russia and he was like, oh, do I really want to do this?
Speaker 0: Should we just send them to an international school where everyone speaks English?
Speaker 0: or she sent him to the Russian school, right?
Speaker 0: so at first They were you know, they had a hard time.
Speaker 0: They were like, alright, let's be badasses Let's send them to the you know to the Russian public school, right?
Speaker 0: That was bad didn't work out so well, huh?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But then they were gonna send them to the international school.
Speaker 0: They were gonna give up right like Oz isn't working.
Speaker 0: but instead they sent him to this totally cool school.
Speaker 0: and the thing with this totally cool school is It was one of those situations.
Speaker 0: It was like one guy who was sort of like it was his school sort of I guess a John Taylor Gato of Russia maybe Bill Gates.
Speaker 0: no and Basically his idea, you know, he has ideas about how kids should learn and all that shit, you know.
Speaker 0: And it tells the story about the kids struggled but eventually unstruggled and the whole stuff.
Speaker 0: But was the thing that was most fascinating about this right which they didn't talk about too much.
Speaker 0: No was Some of the classes they had there.
Speaker 0: They basically had classes on.
Speaker 0: I can't see.
Speaker 0: I forgot I can't find in the article because it's six pages the Russian name they used for this class.
Speaker 0: But it was basically the avoid bullshit class like how to detect coercion and Propaganda and not have it influence you because it's a Russian school.
Speaker 0: So the totally makes sense that this totally yeah, we need that here that this totally cool guy running the school is like yeah We're gonna have a class about not falling for bullshit.
Speaker 0: Yeah another cool thing in this.
Speaker 0: Yeah Another cool thing is they talk about how you know When the kids are having a hard time.
Speaker 0: one of the teachers for one of the kids Taught the whole class in English one day and was like, yeah, that's how it is for you know The American kid all you Russian kids Apparently and they says like one of the Russian kids was crying cuz he didn't know what's going on You know.
Speaker 0: and he was like, yeah, so that kids feeling every day cuz he doesn't know what the hell's going on So leave him alone.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it was really fascinating and It's cool.
Speaker 1: So very briefly in the meta moment the book club book which we'll be doing as soon as I finished reading it Which won't be that long is the ear the IVR my Nancy farmer.
Speaker 1: It's a future cyberpunk II sci-fi detective stories set in Africa.
Speaker 0: Someone is gonna make a fanfiction.
Speaker 0: It could be like, you know Mm-hmm what like the boob the butt the dick something like that.
Speaker 1: That that was.
Speaker 0: I thought you're gonna that okay, I was gonna say like if there are three-year-olds, you know Poop That's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: Gaming cons that are coming up in the near future.
Speaker 1: Well, not the near future.
Speaker 1: the nearest future Magfest is gonna be fucking awesome here because it's in the new venue.
Speaker 0: no cons for the rest of the year.
Speaker 1: Yep, mag fast though.
Speaker 1: It's coming.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: I'm charging my laser Already charging.
Speaker 1: It's the only thing that moves the blob.
Speaker 0: My laser is already full.
Speaker 0: I got a second laser coming.
Speaker 1: So long time ago at a I think it was PAX.
Speaker 1: I think we picked this game up at a PAX or connect.
Speaker 0: This was like a PAX multi years ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was called the hive or hi.
Speaker 0: Well, I was going recently.
Speaker 0: Let's find a two-player game.
Speaker 0: We can play really quick.
Speaker 0: I think it was must have been packs.
Speaker 1: Oh wait or oh nine corollary that find a weird game.
Speaker 0: Yeah find a weird game We never seen before.
Speaker 0: so we're in the PAX library and I see a bat a game in our bag and I'm like That's a winner.
Speaker 0: So I grabbed the game in the bag and we play it really quick and it was okay.
Speaker 0: Didn't really fully grasp it.
Speaker 0: We were sucked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we played it once like alright, whatever.
Speaker 1: Then we put it away and went to a concert or something.
Speaker 0: I don't know what we did.
Speaker 1: Oh, I remembered the game because every time went to a PAX I'd see it in the library like oh, yeah that game It's one of those games that you see around but you never play right?
Speaker 0: It's like when you go to a store, especially like a gaming store.
Speaker 0: There's the section or a comic store, especially.
Speaker 0: There's the section with the new stuff and it's always changing.
Speaker 0: So you're always looking there really closely to see the new stuff.
Speaker 0: But there's always that shelf where the stuff never gets bought and it's just sitting there with the same stuff on it.
Speaker 1: It's all the old war games and memoir 44.
Speaker 0: And you just sort of like you don't actually look closely at the shelf.
Speaker 0: Your brain doesn't process each item It's just your brain remembers the shelf as a whole unit and you can use recognize it and you know You can immediately tell nothing has changed on it just by glancing because it matches your memory exactly.
Speaker 0: But if someone asked you name one thing on that shelf without looking at it you'd be like, uh Right.
Speaker 0: So the hive is one of those things like.
Speaker 0: you see it everywhere.
Speaker 0: There's a picture of it in your brain if you go to the game store But you never actually Look closely at it or even recognize it exists.
Speaker 0: and if someone like were to take it off the shelf and show it to you It would like disrupt your brain like what?
Speaker 0: Well, I like you couldn't even imagine that the shelf would move.
Speaker 0: I wonder if there's a name for this like a neurological or psychological thing, whatever chunking.
Speaker 1: I've heard people use to describe that but I don't know if that's a technical term or just What my AP bio brain stuff?
Speaker 1: My AP bio teacher called it chunking that your brain will Take a set and if it can chunk it down into like one discrete unit.
Speaker 1: That's much more efficient and then you'll remember the unit but maybe not any details of the unit Though a detail may trigger memory of the unit even though you don't know won't know why it triggered it.
Speaker 0: So anyway, the hive is one of those things where you'll see it But you won't actually look at it closely until we tell you to right now.
Speaker 1: So the hive is just a bag full of a bunch of tiles.
Speaker 1: they're all hexes And they're equal.
Speaker 1: It's a perfect complete information game.
Speaker 1: It's completely symmetrical and The goal is to place your little Grasshoppers and aunties and beat least and then spiders and that's all the things.
Speaker 1: and it.
Speaker 1: well There's expansions like the mosquito and the ladybug.
Speaker 0: We got to get that shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people don't seem to like him that much whatever but your goal is to surround the other person's Queen bees around be to stay alive Without having your own bee be surrounded and it can be surrounded by tiles of either color.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter if the Queen bee is completely surrounded the Queen bee dies Yep.
Speaker 1: So beyond that every bug has a power and the game actually has a pretty unique starting like metrics or starting conditions.
Speaker 1: So you place any bug that you want.
Speaker 1: the first player?
Speaker 1: Second player places a bug has to be touching the first bug.
Speaker 1: They're all hexes.
Speaker 1: from this point forward You can only play a tile if it is placed such that it does not touch any tile of another color Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So the other person's tiles.
Speaker 1: Yep You cannot move any bee any bugs until you place your Queen bee.
Speaker 1: once you have placed your Queen bee you can either place a guy or Move a guy.
Speaker 0: so now you play the bee first.
Speaker 0: You can just start playing and moving and all that you want like crazy.
Speaker 0: But if you play something else, you've got to play some.
Speaker 0: you know You got to either play the bee or play something else until the fourth turn Where if you haven't played the bee yet, you'll be forced to play it now.
Speaker 1: So that's the rub.
Speaker 1: you must place the bee in one of your first four turn But you cannot matter which one.
Speaker 0: but also you can't you on your turn.
Speaker 0: Normally, you can move or place but I said that right.
Speaker 0: if you have not placed the bee you cannot move yet.
Speaker 1: And then it's just a game of maneuvering and every bug has a power.
Speaker 1: the ant can just move around the whole outside But not the inside.
Speaker 1: the beetle can walk on top of shit.
Speaker 1: the the bee moves like a chess king.
Speaker 1: He kind of bee kind of sucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, the bee is the defendant.
Speaker 1: Yeah Grasshopper can only jump over any number of do in a straight line.
Speaker 1: Spider moves three like spaces around the outside of other tiles that we already ran into a spider problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we can't.
Speaker 1: we came across an unresolvable spider situation.
Speaker 1: I have to go through the errata to figure out what to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah And So far it's a good game because I'm always a fan of the simple fairly abstract direct Competition to player complete perfect information games like oshi or the stick game, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, is you have a game that's basically fundamentally the same as chess or go right?
Speaker 0: It's it's.
Speaker 0: you can see everything that's on the board, you know, every move the other person can make.
Speaker 0: there's nothing hidden You know and it's just moving pieces and placing pieces and you're trying to win and it's.
Speaker 0: everyone has it.
Speaker 0: Everyone has the same thing and the only difference is who goes first, right?
Speaker 0: The difference here is that you know chess and go have like a you know, such a huge play space.
Speaker 1: You know a solution space Coupled with the fact that good players are way above you.
Speaker 1: playing against someone who's good at chess is The same as playing against someone who's good at Street Fighter.
Speaker 0: But the games also while having such as big space of decision-making Also have a lot of pieces like there's a lot of.
Speaker 0: even a chess board has a lot of pieces on it.
Speaker 1: now chess Is more fun if you play it with someone who is at your skill level.
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: But it does run into the problem of it'll take years to fully explore that play space a game like the hive or oshi If you're smart and you keep playing against one person or a few people over and over and over again You're gonna rapidly go through like phases of gameplay.
Speaker 0: We're already seeing that.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So we have the thing is a game like oshi or hive, right?
Speaker 0: Gives you quite a large decision space but a lot less pieces.
Speaker 0: It's like it's somehow it's like compressed You know because you have a less pieces on a smaller board But there's more complex rules perhaps or just the way the rules are.
Speaker 0: You know, I mean that the fact that they're hexes and there's different tricks you can do.
Speaker 0: It's like you've managed to be able to get.
Speaker 0: you know, a very complex game.
Speaker 0: Maybe not necessarily as complex as go But you can.
Speaker 0: it's easier to keep the whole game in your brain Even if you haven't studied it for years and years and years and it's also by being perfect and complete.
Speaker 1: It's a game where you can fully analyze everything that is happening and everything that has happened.
Speaker 1: And they're great games to teach you pattern recognition and you know gaming analytics game theory analyze You know analyzing data and patterns in game theory sense, even if you don't understand the math.
Speaker 0: And of course, they're two-player games which are rare and it's rare you get a good one and Very quick to learn and quick to play, you know people talk about easy to learn difficult to master.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sure, whatever quick to play is very important because otherwise you're sitting there for hours.
Speaker 1: You know the first time I heard that term.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It's watching mask.
Speaker 1: Okay, m.8 at s.k And I think it was Matt tracker got into my miles what's his name's?
Speaker 1: little motorbike II thing?
Speaker 1: and then he's like trying to shoot somebody with it.
Speaker 1: and then the bad guy radios him and He's like, ah, you can see that is very easy to pilot.
Speaker 1: a minute to learn But a lifetime to master they like blows him up or something.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So in our playing of the hive I'm gonna say and I say this about every game like this This game is straight up the stick game in that its primary Pattern is between stable and unstable states.
Speaker 1: unstable meaning one place.
Speaker 0: You put a link in the show to your stick game because I should people don't know I should make like a web Game, I should make the stick game online HTML 5 stick game.
Speaker 0: Yeah get put up against a random opponent.
Speaker 1: That'd be pretty easy to do.
Speaker 1: actually I'm not gonna do it, but be easy to do Okay, but anyway, so the game is stable and unstable.
Speaker 1: it becomes unstable Once one player has a direct path to victory as in they can just start attacking the other B in such a way that the First player cannot fill in or defend fast enough, right?
Speaker 0: It's like if you're beat.
Speaker 0: you remember you had to surround the B and it's a hex.
Speaker 0: You need six pieces around the B. So if your B has four around it and mine has three you're ahead by one it depending on whose turn it is.
Speaker 0: You know, even if I go first, okay, so now we're even but then you're ahead.
Speaker 1: It's still stable if a player doesn't have a clear Immediate path to finishing the surrounding due to you know attack.
Speaker 1: Yeah You have to count.
Speaker 0: basically what you end up doing is you look at how many things are already around your B. Then you see if you can maybe move your B. If you can move the B if it's not trapped yet, then that means you can probably Really?
Speaker 0: Fuck the other guy over thing is big.
Speaker 1: It's trapped like right away in the base game with it and there's not much you can do to avoid grasshopper, right?
Speaker 0: but What you do is once the B's trapped you count how many actions it will take For the other guy to the complete surround the B and how many actions it'll you to take to completely surround his B If you did full offense and then you like I what are the alternatives that can occur here to maybe change those numbers?
Speaker 1: now It's funny that whenever Scott and I play games like this.
Speaker 1: They always go through the same pattern the first bunch of games I'll win them because it's a new game We haven't played before and Scott always tries to play a real strategy and I literally just look at the game and say how can I do the most aggressive?
Speaker 1: Just make the game as unstable and unpredictable and crazy as possible and then just hope that that'll make me win.
Speaker 1: And in a game like this that'll work until we both know the game and then I'll lose an Equal number of games.
Speaker 1: following as Scott uses real strategy and my only one strategy no longer applies.
Speaker 0: And then you know since you know, we're both trying to figure of solve the game.
Speaker 0: It's like I'll just try crazy stuff and sometimes it works like my be ant ant ant.
Speaker 1: That was a great move But then I came up with the counter.
Speaker 1: I can't win against it, but I can force a draw reliably Yeah, and then we also learned that like going first sucks Yeah We game.
Speaker 1: we got into this pattern where you know I want a whole bunch of games and then Scott won a whole bunch and then we Alternated and then we realized we were only alternating because whoever went first always lost.
Speaker 1: So we started going first and trying different like patterns of play from going first to figure out if there's a way to escape.
Speaker 1: there's actually a very specific and direct way to win if you go second and The only way I can come up with to get out of it is to be able to force a draw.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I've been.
Speaker 1: I found myself going for the draw if I went first because I knew I couldn't win.
Speaker 1: I won one game Going first but that was the game where Scott tried some crazy bullshit.
Speaker 1: That was ill-advised.
Speaker 0: I was just trying it out.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, you can't get like.
Speaker 0: I tried my all spiders in the beginning strategy Something I noticed that happens in a lot of games right is like, okay, you've gotten to sort of a rut, right?
Speaker 0: You're using the same strategies over and over because you know, they've worked for you in the past or whatever teeny.
Speaker 1: I'm a huge victim of that.
Speaker 1: I will almost always play.
Speaker 0: you'll do what's familiar and safe and you can't risk Experimenting with the unfamiliar because you might lose.
Speaker 1: I always start in the middle with my red-black leaders I make the checkerboard.
Speaker 0: So what you have to do is you just be like, alright, uh, you know This game is short enough.
Speaker 0: in a long game It's like.
Speaker 0: you don't want to risk losing because it's for serious, but in a short game You can play it a bunch of times.
Speaker 0: So you just just try crazy shit even like one round.
Speaker 0: just play randomly for like a few turns like, you know Just be like bug bug bug and then if you haven't gotten the B by the fourth turn bring it out and then You know just go for it.
Speaker 0: See see what you know, try to win with whatever you happen to play.
Speaker 1: Well, more importantly once you get once you get to an equilibrium where you know the people you're playing with victory seems to follow play order or victory seems to be pretty even.
Speaker 1: or If you get to a stability point where one player is always winning
Speaker 0: Then
Speaker 1: keep playing the game over and over again and iterate through starting strategies because the starting like two moves of this game Determine a good deal of what comes after and
Speaker 0: you'd be surprised You have to start reacting to what your opponent did immediately like.
Speaker 0: if you go second and The first thing he puts out is B. Well that you got to take that into account.
Speaker 1: that on your on your move yep, so choosing your second piece for example is I'd say probably 60 to 70 percent of the victory condition of the actual underlying game.
Speaker 0: Yeah The other thing in this game right is that there's sort of these two aspects, right?
Speaker 0: There's the aspect of since you don't remove any bugs from the board But they do get trapped where they can't move.
Speaker 1: yeah Because you can't move a bug if it will disconnect the hive and make it two separate hives.
Speaker 0: It has to be one big hive and also You can't.
Speaker 0: a bug can be trapped like if it can't physically get out without bumping any other bugs out of the way Then it can't move.
Speaker 0: so this that creates this aspect of geometry We're like regardless of which bugs are out there You have to make the board a certain shape to make a disadvantage of your opponent If too many of his bugs are trapped or you know holding the hive together on like a big long string then That those are bugs that can't attack your B And now you've got the advantage.
Speaker 0: another aspect of the game is the bug select.
Speaker 0: Is the is the bug selection?
Speaker 0: there was a round where I was actually winning.
Speaker 0: I was gonna win, but but I had chosen grasshopper grasshopper grasshopper earlier Which means I didn't have any left and the only bug that I could have won with was grasshopper And I could have.
Speaker 0: I didn't have to use the grasshoppers earlier.
Speaker 0: I just chose to stupidly When I should have.
Speaker 0: if I had used a beetle earlier Which I very well could have I would have won yep the geometry of the board will definitely matter when you get into more advanced Play.
Speaker 1: if you play the game a whole bunch like try
Speaker 0: to move a bug next to my own B Just to allow my B to move yep Which you know works if no one's looking you
Speaker 1: want to move your B out as much as you can but a smart player is Gonna block you with an A and that's
Speaker 0: true.
Speaker 0: But I mean if you think about the shape of it though right if there's you know it's a hex.
Speaker 0: So if you know you if you surround it on four sides out of five out of six it can move out of That center piece and go to the edge and now it's only surrounded on one side.
Speaker 0: It's like the ultimate killer move because now the guys fuck because he's he has Four or more bugs.
Speaker 0: you know committed to this line is this half circle of bugs.
Speaker 0: they can't be split up because they're holding the hive together with your B at the very end and if you manage to pull that off you win, so In some if you're a board gamer at all just buy it.
Speaker 1: It's cheap, and it's one of those games you can just bring with you to like any event whip it out at a restaurant With just play it whenever it's great for like being in line at a con Or as a warm-up game while you're waiting for other people to show up to play a real game.
Speaker 0: This is the thing with the warm.
Speaker 0: There's been a lot of warm-up games lately and not enough hardcore games lately.
Speaker 1: Well, we're fixing that tomorrow.
Speaker 1: our private board game night is Puerto Rico.
Speaker 0: great.
Speaker 0: the thing with the The warm-up games that there's so many of them and sort of like.
Speaker 0: I'm tired of them.
Speaker 0: I want to play more real games.
Speaker 1: That's why you have so many so that you always have one you haven't played in a while That's true and also you got to have a variety of them like spot.
Speaker 0: It is good with a lot of people But the hive is good with two people and the hive is better is more brainy And the.
Speaker 0: you know you get all kinds of different ones.
Speaker 1: Oh, she's good, but it does take too long.
Speaker 1: It's kind of a flawed game even though.
Speaker 1: I like it.
Speaker 1: zero Was really boring to me until we played that tournament at PAX where the publisher was like Here's the tournament rules, and he made him up kind of on the fly Yeah, and they actually made for a really good tournament.
Speaker 0: It was all right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like.
Speaker 1: I still love the fact that against these people we just randomly played against.
Speaker 1: it was a perfect tie between you And me for first place, and we had to come down to like a sudden-death tiebreaker.
Speaker 1: I was one fucking tile away from walling you off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I couldn't keep it up.
Speaker 0: no Yeah, so the hive is pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: buzz buzz buzz buzz buzz.
Speaker 0: I don't know about the expansions though I want to try them out.
Speaker 0: mosquito the ladybug are the rules for them online.
Speaker 1: Ah yeah, it looks like it.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening.
Speaker 1: music can't leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.