Speaker 0: Hey, it's Thursday September October 20th.
Speaker 1: Fuck you I'm rim.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We're doing a short show about.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: we haven't done this in a while, but there was a time long ago, you know geek nights has been running since 2005 and We used to go four nights a week.
Speaker 0: In fact for many years we did four shows a week.
Speaker 0: Sometimes we would not have an idea for a show.
Speaker 0: luckily that never happens very often.
Speaker 0: But anyway, we uh, what we would do is we would do a special like alright instead of a full-on episode of geek nights We're gonna do like a five-minute episode or a ten-minute episode and skip all the formality.
Speaker 1: Yes, it's better than no episode right?
Speaker 0: But what we'd always do is preface it by saying something like hey This isn't a real episode of geek now.
Speaker 1: It doesn't fucking matter.
Speaker 0: We used to care We used to be like.
Speaker 1: so if you hear this people are new to podcast with new.
Speaker 1: podcasting was relatively new.
Speaker 1: people still didn't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean now it's dead doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I do have a little bit of news.
Speaker 0: I don't want a news.
Speaker 0: I want to talk about news.
Speaker 1: they can strip.
Speaker 0: we can stretch out for some time because there have been a couple of Articles like this recently and this one is not the most egregious.
Speaker 0: It's just the most recent.
Speaker 0: But the TSA as you know is is basically an organization designed to make air travel Uncomfortable and annoying.
Speaker 0: They have been expanding their purview into Amtrak.
Speaker 0: They've been randomly like setting up at Amtrak stations and they're allowed to do that.
Speaker 0: There's been fights about that, but they always seem to win.
Speaker 0: In fact, I don't know if it was them, but it looked like them There was some security.
Speaker 0: when when I took Amtrak up to go Apple buck in the other weekend Did they say that say TSA?
Speaker 0: on their uniform two of the people had TSA badges and the rest of them were like normal employees?
Speaker 0: But they were standing at like one stairwell going down to the train.
Speaker 0: We just walked you know It was Penn Station to one of the other like ten stairwells that goes down to the trains and skipped it.
Speaker 0: I wasn't gonna go through that and I remember when we went to Philly some of the trains they were doing like TSA crap More than once in Queensborough Plaza station.
Speaker 0: I've run into TSA agents with the police Randomly searching people trying to enter the subway.
Speaker 1: I've seen you know the cops standing there with a plastic folding table near subway engines But never once have I actually seen them ever search anybody.
Speaker 1: It's like they're just standing there because I've never seen a TSA agent with them.
Speaker 0: I've seen them search at least 40 people this year.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I've never been asked to be searched recently ever.
Speaker 0: But if I am well the thing is if I was I'd probably just walk to the next subway station and get on but I digress.
Speaker 0: Yep I still kind of like my plan of carrying a ratty briefcase and anytime if I do get stopped and they want to search it I'll be like no never mind and then throw the briefcase away in the garbage and just walk away.
Speaker 1: It's a good plan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's no crime committed there.
Speaker 0: I have no intent.
Speaker 0: It's a ready old briefcase I was taken to throw away full of I don't know rocks.
Speaker 0: Yeah and alarm clocks and bowling ball.
Speaker 0: But anyway, they Tennessee has decided to allow them to start searching Bus stations and waystations on the interstate.
Speaker 0: They are randomly checking trucks with drug and bomb sniffing dogs and all this BS.
Speaker 1: go to Tennessee.
Speaker 0: Uh, yeah, that's already good advice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even though the Smoky Mountains are beautiful actually, Tennessee I was sure you
Speaker 1: can see the Smoky Mountains from out for if you're not in
Speaker 0: I would regret not being able to go to Tennessee though Gatlinburg I hear has become even Increasingly touristy and I don't know if I ever need to go back.
Speaker 1: No desire to ever go to Tennessee really this I mean, you know, this Memphis is there I guess but you know what.
Speaker 0: Here's this good walking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know what?
Speaker 1: There's 10 billion other places on earth.
Speaker 1: I can go to see better better.
Speaker 0: So Tennessee was not that bad when I was there.
Speaker 1: I'm saying it's like if you made a list of places to go.
Speaker 1: It's not like there's no reason to ever go.
Speaker 0: Tennessee is a great But if you made a list or horse back near the bottom you want to go like horseback riding through mountain trails.
Speaker 1: Are there better places?
Speaker 1: yes lots of them.
Speaker 0: name one.
Speaker 0: I mean, where are the Smoky Mountains?
Speaker 0: Scott your choice of states is pretty limited.
Speaker 0: I think Tennessee is not writing for riding horses in mountains.
Speaker 1: I but I'd rather do desert horse riding.
Speaker 1: Really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you want to go to Arizona or Nevada which one's worse?
Speaker 0: Egypt Egypt.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Okay No turmoil there.
Speaker 0: Everything's just fine.
Speaker 1: I didn't say there wasn't a vibe for desert horse riding.
Speaker 0: ah, but the the political problems of Egypt are Analogous to the political problems of Tennessee and that your reason to avoid Tennessee seems to be due to the TSA is bullshit Not the quality of the activities they're in.
Speaker 0: Regardless anyway, I I Wonder at what point?
Speaker 0: People won't put up with the shit anymore and I worry that there is no point at which someone will say, you know What I'm not flying.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the problem is is that there are people there.
Speaker 0: So Scott Or any before you say problem is I'm gonna ask you a very simple question.
Speaker 0: Yeah if when we were about to fly to pecs prime next year over Labor Day and They stop you and say they want to do their extended TSA bullshit.
Speaker 0: I'll say I'll take the groping Alright, so you're gonna let him grope you to go to pecs rather than not flying.
Speaker 0: Regroping it's not a negative Alright, so you're cool with the TSA.
Speaker 0: No, I'm cool with getting groped But you're annoyed at the TSA, right you're annoyed at having to stand in these crazy security lines and take off your shoes.
Speaker 1: Yes, the waiting in line sucks Scott.
Speaker 0: Do you take off your shoes to get on a plane?
Speaker 0: Do you let?
Speaker 0: do you comply with that order?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so that means you're okay with it, right?
Speaker 1: I would rather not.
Speaker 0: so what are you doing to not have to do it?
Speaker 0: Don't we?
Speaker 0: I mean I would wager that's less.
Speaker 1: I probably would have flown to like anime Boston and all sorts in mag fest, but we took.
Speaker 0: oh, yes instead I fly less, but I don't fly zero because it's it's so incredibly inconvenient.
Speaker 0: Yes So we're still putting convenience above our civil liberties, but there is a point at which.
Speaker 1: what is that boy?
Speaker 1: I have to Seattle there.
Speaker 0: Is there really what would they have to do for you to say?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I'm driving to Seattle.
Speaker 0: I'm taking a week and a half off work for packs.
Speaker 1: if there was no Grop option if it was just go through the machine I would take I would not fly Do or what I would do is I would go through the expense of getting like the private jet or chartered flight.
Speaker 1: So you don't have to do that.
Speaker 0: Ah, you know what that actually brings up an important point.
Speaker 0: The rich probably have more control over the political process than the poor and the richer you are the more you can avoid that sort Of BS.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we just take the chartered flight no matter what it costs.
Speaker 0: Yeah But it's kind of disingenuous for us to $1,000 each way chartered flight say that the problem is that people put up with it when we actually have the monetary means to not Have to put up with it if it gets bad.
Speaker 0: Well, most people don't then I Don't know.
Speaker 0: I I feel like I'm getting.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying TSA is great I'm saying that there's a problem is when you go to airports, you know, I listen to people talk I talk to people.
Speaker 1: it seems like there is a percentage of people who knows what percentage it is without a study or a few studies that actually believes that the security is.
Speaker 1: You know help and actually increase the security Makes them feel safe and they like it and don't want it to go away.
Speaker 1: I don't think there is a large proportion because and I don't know what the proportion is But there are definitely such people Scott.
Speaker 0: there are people.
Speaker 1: there was a basically cowards who are better be safe than sorry the same Cowards who want the playgrounds to not have met.
Speaker 0: There was a story on today About a man who caused a gigantic fire in his apartment building because he took his poop and put it in his Ron his radiator Thinking that alchemy would turn that poop into gold.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: There are people who believe anything.
Speaker 0: Yes So you can't say I don't think there are enough people who actually fly who are okay with the TSA To where if we had a public referendum vote the TSA would not immediately be disbanded.
Speaker 1: But there's also people who don't fly also vote and could be affected by planes landing on them.
Speaker 1: But at the same time I would argue that lock They don't care about inconveniencing you non you fliers if it makes them right like imagine if there was some way.
Speaker 1: You know, like, you know almost all security causes inconvenience.
Speaker 1: There's no way to get security for free.
Speaker 1: It always costs something right cause money.
Speaker 1: or even locking your door to your house costs inconvenience.
Speaker 1: You're gonna lock yourself out at least once in your life.
Speaker 1: You got to remember the key.
Speaker 1: You got to spend that one second of time to lock it right, you know Security costs inconvenience.
Speaker 1: But imagine if you could somehow get security for yourself, but a hundred percent of the inconvenience is for somebody else.
Speaker 1: Well, it's got knocks on you at all.
Speaker 0: What if we pass the law?
Speaker 1: Why would you ever say no to that?
Speaker 0: cars can't drive more than two miles an hour in New York?
Speaker 0: That'd be great for us bikers.
Speaker 1: It would be awesome wouldn't hurt me at all.
Speaker 1: I'd be totally in favor of that shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, thus the problem.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I don't know what to do about it, but I'm getting to the point to where because I have the wealth to avoid the problems I will no longer put up with the TSA if I have to deal with their bullshit Except flying because I don't know if I want to spend the money to charter a flight to Seattle every
Speaker 1: year.
Speaker 1: But what if we could?
Speaker 1: the thing is what if we can get a whole plane to be PAX people?
Speaker 0: It would still be kind of expensive.
Speaker 1: I think it could actually be a good deal if we can like charter a PAX flight from New York to Seattle.
Speaker 1: There's enough people.
Speaker 0: It's not that there's enough PAX attendees.
Speaker 0: there's enough Industry people here who are going every year, right?
Speaker 1: But I'm saying is we can definitely get a plane full of people to get something that has jet engines and not propellers.
Speaker 0: Anyway, that's all I got.
Speaker 0: I'm so I'm angry about the TSA as always.
Speaker 1: that's not news.
Speaker 0: the only other thing I can say in history, isn't it funny how The Republican Party in America which claims partly that it doesn't want federal government overreaching Doesn't seem to be too broken up about the TSA because that's defense and or security and or police.
Speaker 0: But at the same time they want to spend a billion dollars in defense.
Speaker 0: But at the same time they they are actually really weak on defense lately and they were really mad about all the money We spent on Libya.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz they're mad about spending money.
Speaker 0: But yeah, they were.
Speaker 0: they would have been fine with that money had it been a Republican president because it doesn't matter what the actual Policy is.
Speaker 1: Oh, it's just about creating a story in the media that day whatever story they want to make.
Speaker 0: This is not news either.
Speaker 0: Nope We don't do news.
Speaker 1: But the thing is I love up, you know.
Speaker 1: It's like you see people.
Speaker 1: you complain about the same things over and over again acting like someone.
Speaker 1: it's a new discovery.
Speaker 0: Acting like somebody who hasn't discovered it already is Being lightened when the rest of us in the crew talk about politics.
Speaker 0: We actually have a discussion.
Speaker 1: It's just impossible with you because you immediately because you're not discussing anything What have you discussed that is new in any way shape or form that we do not.
Speaker 1: people do not already know That and you know, no one's ever gonna change your mind or be enlightened or discovery.
Speaker 1: There's nothing to discover It's it's already known.
Speaker 1: there is no secrets.
Speaker 1: There is no valuable political discussion to be had.
Speaker 1: if there is a valuable.
Speaker 1: I don't even believe that political science professors can have a valuable political discussion because it's pretty much a solved thing.
Speaker 1: Everyone knows everything and Scott.
Speaker 1: This is why nothing more to know.
Speaker 0: I talked to the other Scott about politics, right?
Speaker 1: But anyway speaking of your politics, right?
Speaker 1: There is a near miracle has happened.
Speaker 1: this is actually something new right not something old a Couple senators one of which is ours.
Speaker 0: He's actually crappy, but whatever Name a non crappy one who's still in power.
Speaker 1: I don't think Bernie Sanders is a senator isn't is?
Speaker 1: he's a house guy named two senators two senators period.
Speaker 0: yeah That are currently senators sure, you know, whatever Oh ever.
Speaker 1: Oh, well in Connecticut the senators when I was young were Chris Dodd who I don't think is a senator anymore.
Speaker 0: Okay, nevermind I made my point go on anyway.
Speaker 1: so our senator Schumer who sucks right and some of that bad.
Speaker 1: It's pretty bad.
Speaker 1: and the guy as some guy named Mike Lee from Utah Right came up with an original idea or at least an idea.
Speaker 1: I had not heard before which is Amazing.
Speaker 1: The idea is this if you want to move to the US and you buy a house Will give you a visa.
Speaker 1: So it's like hey, this kind of solves the immigration thing.
Speaker 1: It's like people can move here and totally cool if they have money if they buy a house You know.
Speaker 1: and it's like well, that's actually.
Speaker 1: and it also solves the problem of not enough demand for houses.
Speaker 1: So the idea I was thinking hey, it's a great idea.
Speaker 1: These Mexicans can come and just buy cheapo houses in Arizona or wherever people might think that's not terribly feasible.
Speaker 0: But there are a surprising number of abandoned brand-new houses in Arizona.
Speaker 1: You can move to Detroit buy a house for five bucks get a visa.
Speaker 0: So get houses for free in Detroit if you're willing to assume the negligible property taxes, so this is a great idea.
Speaker 1: Here's the problem with their idea.
Speaker 1: at least there's nothing wrong.
Speaker 0: It's got problem one the.
Speaker 0: you know To use it all the devil's in the details that the actual implementation of such a thing would be far from trivial.
Speaker 1: Well, no, here's the problem.
Speaker 1: They're not actually just proposing, you know won't be a good idea Which is buy a house get a visa.
Speaker 1: They're proposing spend half a million dollars on real estate in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Get a visa.
Speaker 1: Basically, it's like hey rich people can move here.
Speaker 1: It's like what.
Speaker 1: are you kidding me?
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: why did you even have it?
Speaker 1: What's the point of having a money limit at all?
Speaker 1: make it fucking zero.
Speaker 1: if anyone buys any real estate in the u.s They and they're not from the u.s.
Speaker 1: They she gives it a. get a visa.
Speaker 0: You know what I would do immediately.
Speaker 0: I owned some property.
Speaker 0: I could get some more and I would parcel it out into square centimeters Okay, and then sell it for 500 bucks.
Speaker 0: cool to give everyone visas sweet.
Speaker 0: So you do you think Scott honestly that if we effectively had an open border?
Speaker 0: Anyone in the world can just move here wherever they want.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: that that would not cause any political turmoil economic upheaval problems.
Speaker 1: I don't see the problem.
Speaker 0: So you think that would?
Speaker 1: I think I think anyone should be able to live wherever the fuck they want.
Speaker 1: if I want to Move to Finland they shouldn't be able to say no.
Speaker 0: I should be like I'm moving here I'm so Scott Do you think that universal health care in nations like Finland could still be feasible in a world like that?
Speaker 1: If it's not feasible in a world like that, it's not feasible Scott.
Speaker 0: by that logic I would argue that the majority of human accomplishments are not feasible.
Speaker 0: No kidding, but yet we have.
Speaker 1: it's not it's.
Speaker 1: but that's the thing.
Speaker 1: is it just shows you that all these things that people know No, I think it's your only have a surprisingly black and white and naive Worldview because people want all these things like oh we want universal health care.
Speaker 1: Well, that's great.
Speaker 1: Can you provide it for the entire world?
Speaker 1: It is not Paul.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna provide.
Speaker 1: you know been broken down to.
Speaker 0: if you didn't bring enough cupcakes for everybody Then you can't bring cupcakes for anybody right?
Speaker 1: because it's so hypocritical.
Speaker 1: you complain.
Speaker 1: You know these people out there are complaining about the rich 1% and they're like we should have health care for everyone.
Speaker 1: So it's like okay.
Speaker 1: Well now you've got the problem.
Speaker 1: So everyone in the US should have health care and anyone in rich European countries should have it.
Speaker 1: But fuck all those other people in the world.
Speaker 1: It's like well now you're the same as those 1% You were just decrying.
Speaker 1: you've just made it a slight.
Speaker 1: now It's the biggest 5% of the world is jerks you want instead of 1% of the Americans are jerks.
Speaker 0: You're once again as with pretty much every non computer anime or they don't believe in countries I don't ever see.
Speaker 0: people Have an amazing ability to not understand the concepts of scale for one.
Speaker 1: Anyway, no, but I mean what.
Speaker 1: why is it right to do?
Speaker 1: You know, I don't believe in countries.
Speaker 1: So why is it right to do it for the?
Speaker 1: you know these people but not for all the people.
Speaker 0: Maybe Scott?
Speaker 0: because there's no such thing as right or wrong.
Speaker 0: There's your own constructs exactly Yeah, so why should I listen to yours?
Speaker 0: because no one agrees with you?
Speaker 1: No, but I'm just saying I just point out there It's hypocrisy.
Speaker 1: everywhere Everyone is hypocritical.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because there's no such thing as taking into consideration, you know scale or real world.
Speaker 1: Okay, so we can afford to give it to this many people.
Speaker 1: How do you decide who?
Speaker 1: Oh the Americans only.
Speaker 1: well, that's okay.
Speaker 0: Great Scott.
Speaker 0: It's more that art inside of America.
Speaker 0: For example We've got an economy that we built.
Speaker 0: we have our own laws.
Speaker 0: I mean our laws don't apply to people outside of our country and some countries out there have laws that we would consider bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so why do we let them have those bad laws?
Speaker 1: I don't think that there should be countries.
Speaker 1: I don't think so should apply to all people everywhere.
Speaker 0: All right, Scott.
Speaker 0: So what is the idea?
Speaker 0: What if half the people in the world think murder should be illegal and half the people think it should not be illegal who?
Speaker 1: Gets to say I'm not saying I believed in democracy.
Speaker 0: So, how do you determine what law gets applied to all people?
Speaker 1: The right law?
Speaker 0: what's the right law?
Speaker 0: Whatever I say, okay This is why again I talked to the other Scott.
Speaker 0: when it comes to politics What is the point?
Speaker 1: is your position is laughable and all this this idea is dumb.
Speaker 1: half a million dollars I mean at least.
Speaker 1: even even if you're gonna make it some number at least make it a reasonable number.
Speaker 0: Is not that far from what I was gonna pay for a house in Beacon, yeah you an incredibly wealthy person Well, you think there's some immigrant from Mexico.
Speaker 1: how what kind of house?
Speaker 0: I'm just saying while I'm incredibly wealthy Relative to the majority of humans.
Speaker 1: I'm not incredibly wealthy compared to even the top 10% Right, and the thing is they're like, oh if you don't have half a million, that's fine.
Speaker 1: Buy two hundred fifty thousand dollar house and then buy another two hundred fifty thousand dollar house to rent out and that'll that'll give you Over-the-limit and you'll be okay.
Speaker 0: This law is prob.
Speaker 0: I haven't actually read this law because I don't think it'll pass.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, it's just.
Speaker 1: it's an idea.
Speaker 1: It's not only gives even a bill yet Yeah, but my guess is preparing to introduce the idea as a part of a larger package of immigration measures.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure it was thrown in as pork probably to kick the money back to some real estate Companies or the real having trouble selling the expensive houses as they have no no problem selling the cheap houses.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I don't know what to do about it I don't trust pretty much any legislation that comes because it's gonna have so much crap added onto it by the end that it Doesn't even it's even recognizable.
Speaker 0: No one in the Senate or the house even reads the legislation.
Speaker 1: I got a new law.
Speaker 1: no new laws for ten years.
Speaker 1: That's my new law.
Speaker 1: No country can make any new law for ten years.
Speaker 0: All right, so that also means we can't Lighten up laws.
Speaker 0: We can't make them less bad.
Speaker 1: Oh Any law that was made less than ten years ago is void.
Speaker 1: only older laws are okay.
Speaker 0: Alright hope so.
Speaker 0: ten years.
Speaker 0: That's your line.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're right before the GMCA.
Speaker 1: That's the line that gets rid of the Patriot Act - which came later Anyway, because this is turned into a long episode.
Speaker 0: Anyway things of the day you got for me is a funny video.
Speaker 1: It's not college humor.
Speaker 1: It's just a college humor spin-off site.
Speaker 1: Oh shit loophole people.
Speaker 0: I don't understand.
Speaker 0: I understand why they split off dorkly.
Speaker 0: I do not understand why they split off jest unless they're trying to market the exact same humor to people who?
Speaker 0: Look at the name college humor and think it's for punk kids.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure why people do these spin-off sites.
Speaker 1: Period it's like.
Speaker 0: why would you the reason they did it?
Speaker 0: My guess is that college humor?
Speaker 0: We don't look at that name and read anything into it.
Speaker 0: We haven't been in college for a long time And it's not really aimed at college students.
Speaker 0: to me this is what TV should be.
Speaker 0: So they're probably rebranding it to people who aren't in college who maybe will start watching internet crap like this Yet wouldn't watch college humor, but would enjoy everything that's on college humor.
Speaker 1: I don't know whatever the point is.
Speaker 1: they made a funny video.
Speaker 1: It's a an MBA lockout fundraiser.
Speaker 1: People in New York will understand this one a lot better than other people.
Speaker 1: Basically they get people pretending to be NBA players going in the subway.
Speaker 1: hey selling M&Ms.
Speaker 1: Just like you know kids often will do this for their high school basketball teams or at least say they're doing it for the high School basketball teams, but it's funny.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I don't I like this video So right along those lines doing something not a college humor because I don't need to rely on.
Speaker 0: Not dorkly sure not just right the bike thief.
Speaker 0: this is a video because my bike was stolen a while ago, and I miss old movie much better bike now, but New York City is with my last check the most bike steel in his place in America and You know my bike was stolen.
Speaker 0: bikes are stolen all the time.
Speaker 0: when I talked to the cops They said there's professional bike thievery rings because it's so lucrative and it's so trivial to steal them.
Speaker 1: so this guy How lucrative it is.
Speaker 1: someone has to be buying stolen bikes.
Speaker 1: yeah, who's buying stolen bike?
Speaker 0: Craigslist used bike shops.
Speaker 1: Which bike shop is selling the stolen bikes?
Speaker 0: who knows all of them?
Speaker 0: Do you know how many crappy bike shops there are everywhere?
Speaker 1: I only really see nice ones.
Speaker 1: Where's the crappy ones?
Speaker 0: I look at like the one right under my building.
Speaker 1: It's not you think that one selling stolen bikes?
Speaker 1: You never know.
Speaker 1: I don't think so.
Speaker 0: someone's buying him because there's a huge demand to steal him.
Speaker 1: I Don't know who's bought sues selling them, so I can buy the stolen bikes for less money.
Speaker 0: But anyway to prove how trivial it is to steal bikes these guys went around and basically just stole their own fucking bike.
Speaker 0: Isn't this really old?
Speaker 0: it is, but I don't think we've ever talked about it.
Speaker 1: I think I feel like we have whatever.
Speaker 0: maybe it got to the point to where he started bringing an angle grinder and Plugging it in.
Speaker 0: no one even batted an eye even when he tried to act as suspicious as possible.
Speaker 1: What are you gonna?
Speaker 1: Do if you see a suspicious guy like that?
Speaker 0: I would immediately go up and say hey is that your fucking bike?
Speaker 1: Go see if there's a police standing around.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: I just feel like what you doing.
Speaker 0: What you doing.
Speaker 0: take pictures of him like what's up?
Speaker 0: Hey there?
Speaker 0: Bike thief bike thief yo everyone because it's not like you're alone.
Speaker 0: It's not like this one dudes there, and he's gonna stab you.
Speaker 0: There's like a thousand people within sight of these bike thieves.
Speaker 0: So if I'm in you know New York.
Speaker 0: if you make a ruckus a crowd forms immediately.
Speaker 0: if it's a real ruckus Maybe purse thief.
Speaker 0: ten people already tackled the fucker.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: It's a purse thief.
Speaker 1: That's different than a bike thief Yeah, but no one's doing someone's hurting a person as opposed to hurting a thing.
Speaker 0: But at the same time if no one cares if you spray-paint the wall But you try to spray-paint a person, but if I call out the bike thief And then I'd be like oh shit like he's gonna attack me.
Speaker 0: He's gonna get tackled by the same people.
Speaker 0: Especially found a little old lady, but anyway funny story.
Speaker 0: Emily Did that to a guy Not that long ago.
Speaker 0: She was walking and a guy was just kind of walking up to a bike pulled out some bolt cutters and cut the chain And I was like hey is that your bike?
Speaker 0: What you doing?
Speaker 0: and the guy opens his jacket, and he has a Park Department Services shirt and badge.
Speaker 0: he's like yeah, this bikes been here for like a month.
Speaker 0: We're taking it to the impound whatever.
Speaker 1: is he full of shit?
Speaker 0: If he was full of shit He is a professional full-time bike thief And I guess he deserves it because he had the shirt and the badge.
Speaker 1: I guess so.
Speaker 0: And it think about it.
Speaker 0: if you have the shirt and badge you went out that day saying I'm gonna steal fucking bikes Mmm.
Speaker 0: You're prepared yeah.
Speaker 0: But also funny story.
Speaker 0: remember when I stole my bike back from that guy I had sawed the chain off in front of multiple trains of people because it took a while to heck.
Speaker 0: saw that chain off.
Speaker 0: Even the copper drove by looked right at me and didn't even slow down.
Speaker 0: No, so yeah no meta moment because it's Thursday episode.
Speaker 0: doing real quick Scott Emily, and I made Sushi.
Speaker 0: yeah for the first time ever.
Speaker 1: it's hard, but not as hard as I expected.
Speaker 1: I mean we didn't have to cut the fish.
Speaker 1: I'm sure cutting the fish is also a hard part.
Speaker 1: We did not do.
Speaker 0: yeah my skilled hands do not exist right.
Speaker 1: so the cutting of the fish is like supposed to be the hard Part and the skill requiring part.
Speaker 1: you know where you have a fish And you have to cut the piece of the fish off in just the right shape.
Speaker 0: We did not do that at all yeah, so if you guys want to make sushi really the trick is to get all the stuff.
Speaker 0: That's not dangerous.
Speaker 0: buy some crab stick some of that egg some of that like a B's a B Uh shrimp.
Speaker 0: get some avocado some honey-roasted peanuts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can get.
Speaker 1: you can get already ready to sushi eels yep You know from the Japanese market or whatever.
Speaker 1: and then you only have to do the rolling part.
Speaker 1: You don't have to do the cutting part you do have to do the making sushi rice, right?
Speaker 1: So that's actually some.
Speaker 1: you know the significantly hard part that people don't realize the making of the sushi rice.
Speaker 1: So you buy sushi rice you put it in the rice cooker?
Speaker 1: But then you gotta like add vinegar and some other and sugar and stuff to it.
Speaker 1: And then you got to whip it up.
Speaker 1: and and if you go on yeah If you go on YouTube right you'll actually see videos of like how to do this.
Speaker 1: you need to get like a big wooden bowl And a paddle and a fan.
Speaker 1: you'd like cool the rice down because it comes out of the rice cooker hot And you got a. you know you got to whip it up so that it sticks But then you'll know the rice is perfect when it sticks to itself.
Speaker 1: But eating it will cause it to just fall apart, and we did not do the rice a hundred percent exactly right.
Speaker 1: It was pretty good though.
Speaker 1: It was good, but it was still kind of warm, and it was too sticky.
Speaker 0: We had the fan.
Speaker 0: we had to fan it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we didn't fan it enough.
Speaker 1: It was too sticky, and it was too sort of heavy and dense.
Speaker 1: it needed to be a little bit lighter.
Speaker 0: It was it tasted it works.
Speaker 0: The sushi we made was one step above Mediocre deli sushi yeah, but it was definitely not restaurant sushi.
Speaker 1: No, but there are hints of restaurant sushi in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, those uh I think the the Philly roll was probably the best roll We made.
Speaker 1: the thing was it like I felt like I had a little too much cream cheese at least the one that I ate.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mine was fine.
Speaker 0: I think the cream cheese distribution was not uniform.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see that's another thing right It's all about.
Speaker 1: so you take the seaweed and you put the rice on the seaweed.
Speaker 1: now that actually is Significantly more difficult than you would think.
Speaker 1: you had to get it out perfectly evenly But leave a little space at the end for the seaweed like you know to glue to itself.
Speaker 0: I think the biggest mistake you made was the first roll you made.
Speaker 0: you made one of those inside-out like wraparound rolls.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you cannot.
Speaker 1: It's easier to do seaweed on the outside than seaweed on the inside.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's funny.
Speaker 0: You look at our rolls.
Speaker 0: We have some video.
Speaker 0: I'll put it up when I get a chance, but basically the first roll we made looked pretty awful But was actually really good.
Speaker 0: just had too much rice in it.
Speaker 0: Every roll got better and better and better and then like the last roll the second to last roll We made was awesome, and then we were running low on rice and the last roll.
Speaker 0: We made was as bad as the first roll.
Speaker 1: yeah Another thing is.
Speaker 1: you got to really work.
Speaker 1: You know I'm sure with much practice you could figure out the exact proportion of things to put in the roll, right?
Speaker 1: It's like and also the length of the seaweed.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: you know you the seaweed is this long which means it's gonna roll up You know to be nice at this diameter, which means you got to fill it with this much stuff.
Speaker 1: Otherwise you get one that's like too fat too thin not enough stuff in it too much stuff in it.
Speaker 1: You can't close it.
Speaker 1: You know it's.
Speaker 1: it's.
Speaker 1: it's tricky And I think you know you got to get a lot of practice in fig.
Speaker 1: You know you'll get a feel for exactly how how deep you know how thick the rice should be.
Speaker 1: you know how.
Speaker 1: you know?
Speaker 1: What size the seaweed should be how much stuff to put in it?
Speaker 1: all that you know takes a while practice learning?
Speaker 1: But yeah You know making sushi actually isn't that hard.
Speaker 1: you get a little wooden mat that rolls up.
Speaker 1: You put seaweed you put rice in the seaweed you put stuff on the rice you roll it up And then you chop it.
Speaker 1: the chopping is actually pretty easy.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: We needed a sharper knife.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 0: yeah, we had better luck with that serrated one than with the chopping.
Speaker 1: yeah We didn't have an appropriate knife for the chopping.
Speaker 1: I mean I had one in my house, but Yeah, you want to make sure the knife is pretty sharp.
Speaker 1: otherwise You're gonna smush the roll when you try to cut it into little smaller rolls.
Speaker 0: I feel like we do this again.
Speaker 0: It'll be pretty fucking awesome.
Speaker 1: though I also feel like we should make you know the cone Style where you just have a cone of seaweed and you jam a bunch of crap in there because then you don't have to.
Speaker 0: I think that might actually be a lot harder you think.
Speaker 0: so Yeah, those those rolls are a little more complex looking in terms of construction.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I mean otherwise if you just make a cone and dump crap in there.
Speaker 0: how you gonna eat that?
Speaker 1: The same way you eat it when you order it at the restaurant.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it's actually kind of arranged when you order at the restaurant.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's not just thrown into a cone.
Speaker 1: the other thing is you know we tried to make the kind You know the sashimi kind where you just have the ball of rice Put something on top of it, and that's it.
Speaker 0: that was actually way harder than making the roll.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like you thought that would be easy.
Speaker 1: But actually because the rice wasn't so perfect you it wasn't easy to make that little ball of rice exactly the right shape and size And consistency to lay the little piece of.
Speaker 1: you know whatever it is on top of it.
Speaker 1: But if you could get the ball of rice to be exactly right Then you could just take a little strip of seaweed and wrap it around like a little belt.
Speaker 1: that was actually pretty easy to do.
Speaker 1: But then the rice fell apart because it wasn't exactly right.
Speaker 1: so pretty much everything hinges on that rice.
Speaker 1: You don't realize it when you eat the sushi because when you're buying when you're buying sushis You know you don't think about the rice.
Speaker 1: you think about the other parts.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: do I want to buy this roll or that roll?
Speaker 1: or?
Speaker 1: and they all have rice in them.
Speaker 1: But the rice is actually the most important thing.
Speaker 1: get the rice right and then everything else will be ten times better.
Speaker 1: So I think next time when we do it I'm gonna you know we're gonna try to do the rice just like in the video.
Speaker 1: do not you know?
Speaker 1: try to cut any corners On it gonna spin, but a lot more time and effort into the rice making much more important.
Speaker 0: I'm making buterol first not last yeah, and then you know putting a lot.
Speaker 1: You know less well, I guess you know not less effort But you know I'm gonna basically.
Speaker 1: but most of the attention on to the rice.
Speaker 0: I'll have to do a. maybe we'll do a sushi party with the crew have some more people over not just us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they'll have to get a lot more.
Speaker 1: Let's get like two rice cookers going.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think one rice cooker We'll be fine.
Speaker 1: run it twice.
Speaker 0: Just fill it.
Speaker 0: We didn't fill it.
Speaker 0: It wasn't that much rice.
Speaker 1: Oh, we didn't fill it.
Speaker 0: no We filled it.
Speaker 0: it would practically fill this apartment.
Speaker 0: you know much rice comes out of a full rice cooker.
Speaker 1: a lot Yeah, zillion.
Speaker 1: I mean I make half a cup of rice, and that's a lot for one.
Speaker 0: Maybe we need that big square kind of bucket the guy on YouTube was using.
Speaker 1: well He had like a big wooden thing with a wooden paddle that he was using.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: But yeah go on YouTube and make.
Speaker 1: if you want to do this you know make sure you get the right techniques from YouTube, but Even though the rice you know didn't consist properly and was hard to make sushi with it tasted fine.
Speaker 1: You know everything actually tasted just like it would taste just because the shape isn't beautiful.
Speaker 1: and everything It's.
Speaker 1: you still get the same mixture of ingredients in the same proportions.
Speaker 1: It's still gonna have the same flavor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know it's like you.
Speaker 1: if you if you don't want to try to roll up the sushi Take a piece of seaweed plop a ball of rice on it Put a crab stick on top of it put it on a spoon and eat it.
Speaker 1: Put a drop of soy sauce on it, but it's you know.
Speaker 1: eat it It'll taste like sushi.
Speaker 0: also reminded me how much I really like crab sticks.
Speaker 1: crab sticks are pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah crab stick.
Speaker 0: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website At front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 0: remember geek nights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.