Speaker 0: It's Tuesday, March 8th.
Speaker 0: I'm Scott.
Speaker 1: I'm Rem.
Speaker 0: And this is Geek Nights.
Speaker 0: Tonight, the board game, Tales of the Arabian Nights.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So we've already talked on this show about the game of the year 2010 Pac-Man Championship Edition DX.
Speaker 0: We have.
Speaker 0: However, I must inform everybody that I am ranked number 214 in the world.
Speaker 1: Out of 240.
Speaker 0: No, out of like over a hundred thousand a lot.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's a hundred thousand It's a fuck ton of players thousands and thousands of players.
Speaker 0: I'm number 214.
Speaker 1: That is pretty damn impressive.
Speaker 0: It's actually less than that because there are like a few very few players at the very very top that are all cheaters.
Speaker 0: because if you go and look at the leaderboards You'll see that like there's like five or six guys like less than ten But their scores are pretty much at the limit of the score field and it's like yeah, they they definitely cheated.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's no way they didn't.
Speaker 0: There's no way that that was a legitimate score.
Speaker 0: Like some of them have you know?
Speaker 0: It's usually the thing is it's only on certain like scored Courses that they actually have these cheating times and whatever.
Speaker 0: on the time trials It seems like all the times are actually legitimate.
Speaker 0: The thing is basically what happened is I just kept playing and playing and my skill improved, right?
Speaker 0: And what happened is just there's so many courses and so many different, you know things you have to score on.
Speaker 0: I just kept playing all of them, you know, I kept cycling through them and every time I cycled through, you know It's like my score would it just?
Speaker 0: it just took time for it to jump up because it's like.
Speaker 0: well I haven't done the junction in a while.
Speaker 1: That's what I was finding.
Speaker 1: so
Speaker 0: I do the junction again and I
Speaker 1: was playing
Speaker 0: all my old junctions by a whole bunch
Speaker 1: when I was playing the game regularly just In the course of actually doing the time trial on what I hadn't done before my rank would jump like hundreds and hundreds and hundreds.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: But now I've pretty much sort of hit this limit where I've sort of done everything and I'm it's very very difficult for me to Beat any of my own stuff now.
Speaker 1: It's very frustrating to play a time trial of something You've already pretty much mastered.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the thing is I look at the leaderboard for that time trial and I'm only like this one time trial on highway Which is one of my best courses But for some reason my time.
Speaker 0: trial on highway is shit and I can't figure out like any way to make it go faster.
Speaker 1: See if you're off by a little bit Then it could just be a matter of perfect execution like getting sparks in every corner.
Speaker 0: No I'm off by a lot.
Speaker 0: I can't figure out but I can't like I've.
Speaker 1: it means there's an alternate path that you should be.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I can't find the alternate path.
Speaker 0: Maybe you know, you want to help me out.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I mean I actually I feel like I should start playing again cuz I played the game a whole bunch now but like Scott I were Neck-and-neck for a while and I just stopped playing and Scott.
Speaker 1: Scott kept playing.
Speaker 1: And now I think Scott is way better than me and I gotta catch up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's gonna be a Tournament for it at PAX But it's pretty I don't like really.
Speaker 0: the format of the tournament is kind of lame and also it's at a bad time.
Speaker 0: I already have a scheduled thing.
Speaker 1: if I were doing the tournament at PAX the way I would do it is alright.
Speaker 1: So you've got a hundred entries.
Speaker 1: Make sure you've got a hundred.
Speaker 1: Xbox is ready to go or maybe 50 bright.
Speaker 1: break it down into big groups and have everybody go.
Speaker 0: They only have like I think it's max like 30 something entries.
Speaker 0: It's not many.
Speaker 1: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course The game isn't that popular actually.
Speaker 0: Well, the way they're doing it is pretty much.
Speaker 0: you get to play Championship 2 So the default course and the 5-minute time a score mode the fault course.
Speaker 1: I kick the shit out of that right.
Speaker 0: So you have to basically what you do is you go and you sit next to someone and you get one try Right.
Speaker 0: or you know and one try means either the full five minutes or you die.
Speaker 1: Right that actually is important because one thing I've noticed I never die.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I never die.
Speaker 1: The dying is crazy, but playing the game Because we were both going for the high scores any time I made a mistake at all.
Speaker 1: I just reflexively restart.
Speaker 0: Yep, even if you reflexively restart at the tournament, you're just done.
Speaker 0: They'll mark your score or whatever.
Speaker 0: It was when you restarted.
Speaker 1: even if I'm three minutes into a five-minute run if I make a mistake I just start over because I know now that my run is used.
Speaker 0: Here's my strategy if I if I am in the tournament, which is not looking likely, but if it does happen Anytime that I would have restarted.
Speaker 0: pause Because you pause when you.
Speaker 0: basically you would restart when you're about to die, right?
Speaker 0: So instead pause.
Speaker 1: Take a look around you and try to figure out when I'm allowed to die if I'm about to die at bomb.
Speaker 1: if I if I Restart is because like I missed a turn Yeah, or something like that.
Speaker 0: What I would do is I would just because I because I'm not allowed to restart in the tournament It would basically just fuck me over.
Speaker 0: I would pause and say okay Where am I now that I fucked up and figure out the optimal escape?
Speaker 0: You know be a bomb or whatever and then you know go for will they?
Speaker 1: let you pause?
Speaker 1: many tournaments don't?
Speaker 0: there's no way they Can't not let you pause.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't let people pause.
Speaker 0: You got to be able to pause.
Speaker 1: I would argue.
Speaker 1: if I were running a tournament One of the rules would be you cannot pause the game.
Speaker 0: if you do you immediately lose.
Speaker 0: I would say pausing is allowed.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I wouldn't let pausing happen.
Speaker 1: I would ask about pausing But anyway, you should have tweeted Robert cool about pausing Anyway.
Speaker 0: So the thing is if I was in the tournament, right?
Speaker 0: It's like it was you go to championship - and yeah I had a five-minute score attack.
Speaker 0: you get one try Against one other person and whichever one of you gets the better score on that playthrough, right?
Speaker 0: Moves forward in the back now.
Speaker 1: The reason I bring up that whole restarting thing is that even if you don't restart People who play the game for the high score get into a mode where they're always going for the perfect run.
Speaker 1: They very rarely play the degenerated game.
Speaker 1: the I messed up have to keep going mode Which is actually important in a tournament where you're only playing once.
Speaker 1: because now it's not just what is your optimal play?
Speaker 1: It is also what is your average play?
Speaker 1: Like if you fuck up you have to deal with that now like you have to do this one shot.
Speaker 1: It's how consistent you.
Speaker 0: however in the final round when there's only two people left you get two shots and they take your better score Of the two tries, but you still have to make the most of each try.
Speaker 0: You can't bail on either one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because you know you like oh, it's the first try.
Speaker 0: I screwed up.
Speaker 0: I'll just throw this try out and do the next one perfectly.
Speaker 0: Well, what if you fuck up the next one - it's like you got to use the maximum Score that you're gonna get on either.
Speaker 1: try Races are like that like you when you have a ski team and you do races a lot of times.
Speaker 1: the way it's formatted is you have like say five team members.
Speaker 1: they all get to do the course and If you fall like you you basically don't qualify.
Speaker 1: like you don't?
Speaker 1: it doesn't count.
Speaker 1: like you don't get any score You basically you get an X like nothing Whoa, but you would need say three scores for the like how your team was ranked at the end.
Speaker 1: So if you have five guys - the scores won't count So you'll have your really good guys go first and you'll have them push it.
Speaker 1: Because if they fuck up you have the lame guys.
Speaker 1: who can you know?
Speaker 1: Just do this the course Okay, and get at least a score as opposed to usually like in a relay race you would do the opposite, right?
Speaker 0: You have the crappy guys go first and you have the best guy at the end who can make up for.
Speaker 0: you know How much time was lost, you know as opposed to having your best guy go first and then you know If someone else is ahead of you at the end.
Speaker 1: Well, you got no chance or what you do is put the best guys last but their dictum is alright.
Speaker 1: If the the not as good guys got like they passed they didn't fail.
Speaker 1: They made it to the end.
Speaker 1: They got okay times and all of them made it.
Speaker 1: Then you can really push it because if you fuck up and don't get a score at least everyone else got a score.
Speaker 1: But if say you're the last guy You're the best guy and three of your teammates fucked up and got no score You now know that you have to play the conservative route and just get a score no matter what it is.
Speaker 0: But yeah The tournament is pretty much all championship to five minute which is kind of like because I've pretty much.
Speaker 0: the reason my rank is So high I think is because if you actually look it seems like a lot of people don't play all the courses And I've actually gone through and played every mode on every course to the maximum of my ability and because of that That's
Speaker 1: hard to say.
Speaker 0: that is what has pushed my rank.
Speaker 1: So but thus it's hard to say how good you actually are at that course or overall because people are no good.
Speaker 0: There's also individual course rank.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I'm in the top.
Speaker 1: I'm in the top like hundreds of every course, but I think people who are really good at the game Some of them might actually they should be ranked higher, but they're not because they just never played one of the courses.
Speaker 0: That's quite possible that there are people who are perhaps like excellent at one course Like maybe there's a guy who mastered championship - this doesn't play any other courses at all You know, but so the thing is I have individual course ranks and you can you can see those as well.
Speaker 1: So I guess you have to decide are you going to enter the tournament or not?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think so.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the timing is looking bad, but it's not Prove anything because my rank is public on the leaderboards.
Speaker 1: So whatever I have mixed feelings about tournaments at conventions in general even packs.
Speaker 0: I feel like at least packs gives you sweet medals if you they do.
Speaker 1: but every con I've ever been to except Magfest the Tournaments they have in video gaming tend to be kind of not very glamorous kind of poorly run or if they're well run They're just not that fun and there's no spectator component by it by and large
Speaker 0: except the Omega thon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Omega thon separate though.
Speaker 1: That's a special event.
Speaker 0: My major problem with them is that they just take a lot of time.
Speaker 1: But that's because they're designed to do that.
Speaker 1: you could design them differently to where they wouldn't take up as much time.
Speaker 0: it is a serious time investment to go and be in the tournament and you know, the Cost-benefit ratio doesn't work out.
Speaker 1: I did enjoy the way Magfest did their hardcore challenge area where that wasn't.
Speaker 0: they could do the pac-man That way.
Speaker 0: they keep like, you know, here's a pac-man DX machine.
Speaker 0: Yep, anyone who you know, we're resetting the high scores on it, right anyone come over and play it at any time during the con.
Speaker 0: As soon as you as soon as you take a try We're gonna write down your badge number and I think I saw pictures of badges with numbers on them.
Speaker 0: We'll write down your badge number and that's if you try to you know Score out again when we will.
Speaker 0: we'll see that you've already scored on the spreadsheet or whatever.
Speaker 0: So you can't score again and everyone can try once at most and the highest score at the end of the con will mail you a prize Or something like that.
Speaker 0: or well, you know They'll have.
Speaker 0: no maybe they have an award ceremony while we're all waiting for the final omega thon to start instead of sitting there.
Speaker 0: Yep, you know during their delay They do.
Speaker 0: they could do a simple award ceremony.
Speaker 1: You do it like we did at RIT anime with like the trash talk Mario tennis tournaments.
Speaker 1: You have tournaments where all the qualifiers happen kind of on the down low and then the semi finals and finals Or maybe it was just the fine.
Speaker 0: I think about that.
Speaker 0: you're waiting for the final omega thon and they have the final round of Street Fighter of.
Speaker 0: You know these other like five other big tournaments like monkey ball Street Fighter.
Speaker 0: Halo, you know pac-man and something else.
Speaker 0: Right, you know they could have those while you're waiting for that final omega thon and it would be all like the highest skilled dudes It packs they also.
Speaker 1: they do need to have more odd tournaments because some of my favorite tournaments were like when we do the Blindfolded monkey ball.
Speaker 0: I think they just don't have the time and the resources for them, right?
Speaker 0: It's like Yeah, you they've already dedicated so many TVs machines and Adjudicators to the man.
Speaker 1: if they had more manpower they could do things like that, but it's not just manpower It's manpower that's willing to deal with that kind of BS.
Speaker 1: Anyway, I mean we've run that stuff.
Speaker 1: It takes a lot of patience.
Speaker 0: Do you think it's a big time investment for the people in the tournaments?
Speaker 0: Yeah bigger investment I think.
Speaker 0: I run in the tournament.
Speaker 1: So I know a lot of you been playing magicka.
Speaker 0: I actually really haven't played it much yet But I played a whole bunch of levels, but then I stopped and I need somebody to finish it with.
Speaker 1: yeah So there is an expansion that was announced to magicka and I thought it was actually a sequel is an expansion.
Speaker 1: It's called an expansion.
Speaker 1: Okay magicka Vietnam this is not a joke.
Speaker 0: I'm not even it's a joke, but it's real.
Speaker 1: What is this?
Speaker 1: I don't even.
Speaker 1: this is Excellent and more people who are making real games need to do stuff like this.
Speaker 1: It takes the piss out of the entire genre of realistic military sims.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I love the idea of stuff like this partly because you know our friend Scout Johnson.
Speaker 1: What does he want more than anything in the world?
Speaker 1: a movie or fighter jets and dragons fight?
Speaker 0: Well, this is wizards for soldiers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's basically the same kind of thing.
Speaker 1: Why do fantasy games have to be just fantasy and sci-fi have to be just sci-fi.
Speaker 1: Why do the games have to make sense?
Speaker 1: Just just make stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even that shit doesn't make sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I mean magic of Vietnam sounds crazy.
Speaker 1: and yet people who have played Previews of it said it's awesome.
Speaker 0: at first I was almost sort of slightly maybe offended by it.
Speaker 0: like because You know, it's like a lot of some people out there they get offended from like real war games, right?
Speaker 0: They're like, oh you can't turn war into a game.
Speaker 0: You know wars for serious and you can sort of understand why.
Speaker 1: especially all right, but then what about a game like counter-strike?
Speaker 1: That's bait not based on a particular con.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I'm not person, you know I'm personally not offended by that.
Speaker 0: But this it was like.
Speaker 0: I was almost offended because it was like.
Speaker 0: it's making light of war.
Speaker 0: it's like lol war.
Speaker 0: and I'm like.
Speaker 0: But I knowed another game that is equally because I sort of I sort of figured out that it's basically You know that this is really.
Speaker 0: it's not being lol war.
Speaker 0: It's saying lol realistic war games, which is sort of it's like.
Speaker 0: I can go with that.
Speaker 1: But also, I mean look at the original advanced wars games before they rebooted it dark and serious.
Speaker 1: with the new DS one They're not really going lol war.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were going.
Speaker 0: they're just going war.
Speaker 0: Yay.
Speaker 0: Yay war It's like punch-out.
Speaker 0: is the boxing right?
Speaker 0: It's like real.
Speaker 0: boxing is bloody and brutal and punch-outs like boxing.
Speaker 1: But at the same time look at the message of the old advanced wars.
Speaker 0: All right fortress 2 is also war.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've got two generals and they're friends, but they're having a battle because what the fuck let's have a battle and they're like Yay, send my infantry in.
Speaker 1: Yay I'll defend with my tanks and then if you zoom in you've got tanks mowing down human beings fighting in in.
Speaker 0: they just disappear They're not being.
Speaker 0: I mean the difference is right is that you know when it's specifically Vietnam War And you've got magicians going around setting people on fire and shit It's like, you know, you're it's a.
Speaker 1: it's a little bit different but at the same time I mean how if we go far back enough, I mean if someone made Magica Sparta Battle of Thermopylae Battle of Marathon.
Speaker 0: Nobody would care.
Speaker 1: Nobody would care.
Speaker 1: Is it just a matter of?
Speaker 1: well, those are people who fought and died and had these horrible experiences thousand years ago.
Speaker 1: So that's okay.
Speaker 0: I think I think pretty much too soon syndrome.
Speaker 0: No, I think what it is it's not the fact that it's too soon is that is a?
Speaker 0: it is a you know a graphic and brutal massacre and that you are trading basically an almost identical scenario.
Speaker 0: a wizard goes in and Massacres all the people with fire right in a horrible way and but he's a cartoonish wizard, you know, it'd be like It's like what if I just if I took full metal jacket, right But I replaced all the characters with like the Watchmen to make it I know.
Speaker 1: And One other brief thing I do want to mention is that there's a game for the Super Nintendo that I Perennially will forget the name of want to refer to not know the name of it and then we'll have to say it's like Flashback on the Super Nintendo, but it came out way before.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you're a guy it's called another world Yeah, and it's in the news because apparently it's being ported to the iPhone and the iPad.
Speaker 0: Well, I get you know, that's a game where the graphics weren't astounding But they had this unique look that has never been replicated.
Speaker 0: another game except flashback.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also for the day when that game came out.
Speaker 1: It was fucking amazing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean on the Super Nintendo It was a digitized.
Speaker 1: I'm making quote marks game as in.
Speaker 1: they modeled people and they made this kind of graphical Masterpiece.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the game itself is actually not that fun.
Speaker 0: No it's just you know, it has this really unique artistic style to it that makes it stand out and actually it also keeps it modern even Though it's old.
Speaker 1: Well, it had that.
Speaker 1: the game was fun in itself.
Speaker 1: It had this interesting concept of dying gave you various cinematics of your gruesome death Yeah, and I think that was half the fun of the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah problem, you know about all those slugs.
Speaker 1: Let's see what happens.
Speaker 0: a lot of the game was basically an adventure game, right?
Speaker 0: Cuz you had to solve puzzle game, but it had a real-time component.
Speaker 0: you had to solve puzzles in the adventure game sort of Monkey Island way, but you did it with a Real-time thing not like Dragon's Lair, but like a platforming more like Prince of Persia.
Speaker 1: It was a Original Prince of Persia.
Speaker 1: It's a cross between Prince of Persia and Dragon's Lair.
Speaker 0: It has some Dragon's Larry bullshit It does but the thing is it had Prince of Persia controls.
Speaker 0: Yeah, perhaps even or Dragon's Lair and he has controls.
Speaker 1: I never got past Where you get when you first get the laser gun and you get out of the jail and you're crawling through the steam vents.
Speaker 1: Past that point never never once in my whole life.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So is that the end of your newses?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right, so there's this game coming out called dark spore.
Speaker 0: I didn't even know about it until today.
Speaker 0: this heart this morning Amazon emailed me and said here's a beta key for dark spore.
Speaker 0: and cuz we like you and I'm like, all right Sure.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: So I download that shit.
Speaker 0: It's free.
Speaker 0: I got a beta key.
Speaker 0: Dark spore is on the spore engine.
Speaker 0: Remember the game that failed?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: So what dark spore is?
Speaker 0: it's basically Diablo spore.
Speaker 0: You got a guy.
Speaker 0: you click.
Speaker 0: It's a three-quarter isometric view.
Speaker 0: you click he walks there you click on bad guys you hit them and they die.
Speaker 0: It's got a little bit though of the more complex controls and in a dota sort of way, right?
Speaker 0: So first of all, you've got a team of three guys up to three maybe even four guys.
Speaker 0: I never got a four switch between him like a. do you can switch between them in real time?
Speaker 0: You can't do it quickly.
Speaker 0: It's like you switch and you to wait like a few seconds before you're allowed to switch, huh?
Speaker 0: Right, so you can.
Speaker 0: you can carry a healer and a fire and a tank and another guy the same right and you switch between Them.
Speaker 0: I think there's also a co-op or and PvP.
Speaker 0: if you go online maybe and It's pretty much Diablo you click on the bad guys and they die and you also.
Speaker 0: You can have special attacks which are number which are the number keys You press like number one to do your weak attack and number two.
Speaker 0: Did you your second your strongest special attack and you're just your regular old click is a regular old attack, you know The only thing that was spore like about it Is that when you get equipment and you and you can equip the equipment as in an RPG?
Speaker 0: You actually position the equipment on your guy and you know rotate it and all that stuff using the spore Character kind of thing.
Speaker 0: You don't actually get to make your character You just you just get them but you can equip them in a spore customizing kind of way.
Speaker 0: This game is really bad.
Speaker 0: I don't see how it was boring as hell.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much they somehow made Diablo even more boring.
Speaker 0: You literally do nothing but click on bad guys and that's that's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: Wow.
Speaker 0: It's just click on bad guys duly noted And in completely boring environments and they tried to do some interesting things with the bad guys Like there's a bad guy who shoots a teleporter at you.
Speaker 0: So every time it hits you you teleport and there's some bad guys you shoot bullets at you that are slow So you can actually skillfully sort of dodge them.
Speaker 0: and they tried to do some stuff with the bad guys to make it interesting.
Speaker 0: But really it just clicking on guys and it's I would you know of Diablo torchlight and darkspore.
Speaker 0: I'll take torchlight which is playable playable enough that I was actually beat it and was cheap five bucks.
Speaker 1: So things of the day, um college humor, you know We use a lot of college humor stuff for things of the day And I actually gonna do it again because they've made a show that is pretty damn solid and if it continues in the vein That is continuing I would continue to watch it.
Speaker 1: I would recommend that all of you do the same.
Speaker 0: It's similar in Structure to an ESPN show pardon the interruption, which is you know, I tried to make geek nights sort of like that.
Speaker 1: But yeah, we thought it doesn't resemble it in any way in the early conceptual days of geek nights.
Speaker 1: Yeah but nerd alert is Basically a nerd talk show.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like geek nights but a little slower and with an extra person.
Speaker 0: Well, it's much shorter.
Speaker 0: and video.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, is that I gotta say?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's all I gotta say.
Speaker 1: It's good.
Speaker 1: Watch it.
Speaker 1: They interview the guy who when he was a kid was in that Mortal Kombat ad where Kane was come or Kano was coming out Of the box and getting the guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, so if you ever have you ever wanted to play an MMO that looked like Final Fantasy 1 Kinda I could do that.
Speaker 0: Maybe there is one is it's a hundred percent free-to-play.
Speaker 0: It's called nostalgia and That's pretty much what it is an MMO that looks like Final Fantasy and plays like Final Fantasy 1.
Speaker 1: So I walk around and level up to 99 over the course of the next five years.
Speaker 0: Yeah I basically I played it for a minute and I was just as soon as I got to that.
Speaker 0: I walked into the town and then I was just like Stop playing.
Speaker 1: Can you talk to people like can you do all the MMO stuff?
Speaker 0: I played it for about 10 seconds before I realized.
Speaker 0: Oh, right It's like.
Speaker 0: the concept on the one hand makes you want to play it But then as soon as you play it, you're like, I don't want to play this.
Speaker 0: It's thinking today worthy.
Speaker 1: anyway, I'd say so I will check it out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I will not check out the beta key that I got from Amazon though.
Speaker 0: Apparently they have it.
Speaker 0: They do have an optional yearly subscription that enables some non-essential features such as you can leveling monsters.
Speaker 1: There's.
Speaker 0: there's extra classes that you can't get like.
Speaker 0: you can only be some base classes.
Speaker 1: If you don't pay you can't be a fighter or a wizard.
Speaker 0: You can be I think wizards the most fancy thing you can be but you can't be anything fancier than that.
Speaker 1: What's fancier than wizard there was.
Speaker 0: there were eight choices.
Speaker 0: I think you only get four for free and then you can also customize your guys appearance.
Speaker 0: You know that way people can tell that you paid money.
Speaker 1: Great.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So this weekend we're recording all our shows ahead of time because we're gonna be at pecs.
Speaker 0: pecs bitch.
Speaker 0: He's pecs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's right X East.
Speaker 0: No snap.
Speaker 1: We're doing five panels and three panel rooms.
Speaker 1: So Friday night our first panel the triple threat one of our new ones.
Speaker 1: I'm actually looking forward to it.
Speaker 1: I think we got a solid panel there Yeah, and then on a Saturday, we're gonna be playing games pretty much the entire time.
Speaker 1: So if you want to say hi, you want to hang out find us in tabletop on Saturday?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Don't try to grab us after our panels.
Speaker 1: that for our panels.
Speaker 1: We usually disappear.
Speaker 1: Yep Someday we're doing two panels and then we're going to the omega-thon finale.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: We're doing our game mechanics and mechanism design a favorite from the real packs and we're doing our winning at games.
Speaker 1: how to win at Games?
Speaker 1: because you play to win the game.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 1: Yeah also next weekend.
Speaker 1: I'll just know it again We're gonna be a zenk icon doing a whole bunch of panels and and the Boston will be a bunch of other cons.
Speaker 1: Join the forum blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: Yep, a little pony.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: So so a few weekends ago, we were up in Albany You know having a big old front row crew party as we are often likening to do and we played a game.
Speaker 1: Well, this game was sold to us by a friend of a friend who hung out at the party and he sold it to a friend of ours the whale shark in the forum and the whale shark described it to me as It's an Arabian Nights themed Role-board playing game
Speaker 0: and I was like, all right, you know This is do not confuse this with Arabian Nights the role-playing game.
Speaker 0: There is a tabletop role-playing game called Arabian Nights.
Speaker 1: Well, it's called a thousand and one nights that game.
Speaker 0: Okay?
Speaker 0: Yeah, but there are a lot of games that are have a rate.
Speaker 0: They're called Arabian Nights or a thousand and one.
Speaker 0: Arabian Nights or a thousand and one nights or Arabian Right.
Speaker 0: do not confuse this with the other ones.
Speaker 0: This is tales of Arabian Nights.
Speaker 1: Yes 1985 though apparently it has been changed many times since then.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: It is a board game that is currently published by who?
Speaker 1: It's published by West End Games currently, okay.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so just don't get it confused with the other ones, right?
Speaker 0: We'll have a board game geek link in the show willing to it.
Speaker 0: now, you know Which one we're talking about?
Speaker 1: the interesting thing about this game is that it was sold to us as a role-playing game Like.
Speaker 0: it's also a board game.
Speaker 1: It's a storytelling game.
Speaker 1: You play the game to win you move guys around you're trying to become the hero of Baghdad go on missions complete quest come back But you can win right?
Speaker 0: So it's I was originally I was thinking it was gonna be something, you know They said a role-playing board game.
Speaker 0: So I thought it would be more like.
Speaker 0: You know the hero quest kind of thing.
Speaker 0: right because that's most of what people say when they mean role-playing.
Speaker 1: but no we were told but it was more like a choose your Own adventure that there is a sort of storytelling mechanic.
Speaker 0: So I thought it would be hero quest with more story.
Speaker 1: I expected something more because they said choose your own adventure.
Speaker 1: sure enough This game comes with a big fucking.
Speaker 1: choose your own adventure book.
Speaker 0: that is fairly elegantly put together See, but actually even then I was still thinking because do you remember I forget the name of the game?
Speaker 0: It was the Dungeons and Dragons game.
Speaker 0: It was.
Speaker 0: it was around the second edition times and it came in a big box.
Speaker 0: You opened up this man dragon strike was.
Speaker 0: it did had a big box full of cards and the cards told you were the GM.
Speaker 0: You remember that?
Speaker 0: now it was.
Speaker 0: there was a D&D game because I a friend of mine had it and you.
Speaker 0: basically it was D&D.
Speaker 0: Walk around hit monsters, but you there was no GM.
Speaker 0: There was a big box of cards that acted as the GM.
Speaker 0: so this is Sort of like that where the book is the GM, but it's instead of doing a hit things.
Speaker 0: RPG.
Speaker 0: It's a storytelling RPG where a book is the GM.
Speaker 1: now I we've played this game once and I have my judgment on it But before I have only played it once.
Speaker 0: but I do think we played it for many hours And I do think it was sufficient and we didn't finish well here but it was sufficient enough to pass these.
Speaker 1: the playing time that that game says is 120 minutes bullshit.
Speaker 1: We played this game for over four hours and we're nowhere near anything even resembling the Midway Point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they are full of shit.
Speaker 1: That is that is 120 minutes is?
Speaker 1: they might as well just shoot you in the face.
Speaker 1: that is such.
Speaker 1: that is a lie, but Not to not to say whether or not I like the game or not.
Speaker 1: The way the game works is you have a guy and then all these different characters.
Speaker 0: Sinbad I wanted to be Alibaba but rim took I was Alibaba.
Speaker 1: Hell's yeah And your character has a gender male or female and you pick skills and the skills are things like luck Weapon use quick thinking and there's a whole bunch of them sailing And you have a wealth level and your wealth level goes up and down based on things and basically on your turn You decide based on you know Your wealth level which is how far you can move where you want to move on this map of Europe Africa the Middle East and Russia
Speaker 0: yep,
Speaker 1: and what looks like parts of Australia maybe and Britain and everything.
Speaker 1: and then you draw a card and based on the card you look up all these numbers and tables and charts and the person you're right and the person you left both Have a different reference and between all of them.
Speaker 1: They will come to a conflict.
Speaker 1: They read the conflict you.
Speaker 1: it's
Speaker 0: kind of magical right because it's like first There's a number on the spot you land on and then you roll a die and then you add some numbers together and then they Look up a number on a card and then you draw a card and they look at the number on the card and then they Look up a number on a chart and then you actually get to choose a reaction to something.
Speaker 0: so it'll be like alright.
Speaker 0: You know at this point that you're encountering a wizard.
Speaker 0: What do you want to do?
Speaker 0: Do you want to beg borrow steal bite?
Speaker 0: You know, what do you want to do to this wizard?
Speaker 0: and it's like a list of possible reactions?
Speaker 0: No, this is the cool.
Speaker 0: This is sort of the role-playing part.
Speaker 0: It's like do you want to steal from the wizard?
Speaker 0: Do you want to attack the wizard?
Speaker 0: Do you want to beg the wizard?
Speaker 0: Do you want to help the wizard right?
Speaker 1: But here's the good.
Speaker 1: This is why this is cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're presented with a Character you're going to meet like a lonely wizard or an angry with.
Speaker 0: it might not be a wizard It might be a monster.
Speaker 1: It might be an event like, you know, you're in a marketplace Yeah, but but it's always it tends to be like an adjective and something like you're in a spooky palace Yeah, or you encounter a crying dervish.
Speaker 1: Yep, and you're not told what the situation is.
Speaker 1: You're only told what it is that you're encountering and then based on the encounters and the references you have a list of Approaches to whatever it is You're going to encounter like.
Speaker 1: basically it'll come down to things like be pious be honest attack it He'll.
Speaker 0: you know all these verbs do something Yep, and after you pick a verb they look at a bunch of charts and they use another die to add a slight amount of Randomization to it.
Speaker 0: So it was not exactly the same.
Speaker 1: every time plus one or minus one The story could go in some slightly different ways.
Speaker 1: make it to make a team make a time make it though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not just you know set in stone or I believe I believe.
Speaker 1: make a team make a time make a toe make a - yep anyway.
Speaker 0: Then they finally look in the book and they read something to you and it's sort of magical that you did all these crazy numbers.
Speaker 0: And then someone eventually is like you.
Speaker 0: they read directly from the book and this big book They come out and they'd be like you encounter a crying dervish.
Speaker 1: He is crying over the fact that he has lost the knife that was given to him by his father and his father's father.
Speaker 1: And then it's like alright because you took steel You try to steal it from him and he catches you and punishes you.
Speaker 1: and you now have the cursed statistic or the cursed trait added to your character.
Speaker 1: or you
Speaker 0: get points
Speaker 1: or your gender has changed and you get some points and you win by getting a combination of fate points and story points and it's pretty fucking arbitrary as to which ones you get and when you get them and Depending if you have a skill like it might say like it'll read the story.
Speaker 1: They're like art.
Speaker 1: you encounter the angry wizard.
Speaker 1: He is a wizard and he is angry up.
Speaker 1: Scott does your character have the lucky or the pious skill?
Speaker 0: I have the lucky skill.
Speaker 1: Do you want to use it?
Speaker 0: Uh, Yes.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: Here's the problem with the game.
Speaker 1: Using a skill seems to be about 50/50 good or bad for you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like you might say yes I'll use my lucky skill.
Speaker 0: Well, you might have actually been better off not using the lucky skill.
Speaker 1: if you're trying to win Yep, or it'll be like do you have the wounded traits?
Speaker 1: Oh Well, then and then the story changes.
Speaker 0: Yep But basically it it's weird cuz like it's a role-playing game and like this book is full of this story and it's sort of crazy How the story actually works and matches what's going on, but at the same time you really have pretty much no control.
Speaker 0: At least no, you know, you know intelligent control over winning or losing.
Speaker 0: It might as well just be random and then on top of that the rules start to get shaky.
Speaker 0: the game.
Speaker 1: Here's my judgment.
Speaker 1: it is I'm sorry a shit game.
Speaker 1: It is not worth playing It is not.
Speaker 0: we're definitely not for the time investment.
Speaker 0: It's really cool to see it.
Speaker 0: You know just experience like a few turns to see the magic of how they set up this book and how much work that must Have been and it's like as a work of craftsmanship like.
Speaker 0: I can respect it like damn, but it is.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna pull this off Unplayable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not gonna spend hours investing into it.
Speaker 0: That is not worth it.
Speaker 1: find someone who owns it get them to run it for you And have someone else ready to call you with a fake emergency a couple hours later to get you out of the situation.
Speaker 0: Yeah, good idea.
Speaker 1: this game Just doesn't work.
Speaker 1: like your actions you move around this whole board of the world.
Speaker 1: You're given these destination tokens and these origin tokens and like I come from here and I go from there and my wife is Living there and I'm a criminal in this city.
Speaker 0: That stuff is so incomprehensible and meaningless and the Part of it is that a lot of this stuff just conflicts.
Speaker 0: the rules just conflict blatantly.
Speaker 0: It'll be like, alright I'm wounded.
Speaker 0: So that means this but I'm married.
Speaker 0: that means this and what happens on both.
Speaker 1: It's like The rules of the game have changed many times throughout its lifespan to like.
Speaker 1: apparently in the past You can only have one trait at a time, but then now you can have multiple traits But the traits are sometimes mutually exclusive.
Speaker 1: It just doesn't work.
Speaker 1: Every turn we ran into multiple Unresolvable rules questions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they thought through the book of story really well but they didn't really think through the rules of the traits and that sort of the winning and the losing very well at all.
Speaker 1: and on top of that the stories are not created equal.
Speaker 1: some of the stories are like Ten sets of crazy questions and do this and this and this and crazy stuff happens like and it's like yeah I got an awesome story.
Speaker 0: sweet my turn is so fun and then my turn will come up.
Speaker 1: and it's like you meet a crying beggar and I pick like Steal or kidnap or something and the story just doesn't go anywhere.
Speaker 1: Nothing happens like great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, you know, someone's sitting there writing this huge book of stories.
Speaker 0: They're not gonna write all of them to be awesome.
Speaker 0: You know, the worst part right is that it's on the board.
Speaker 0: They tantalize you with these places of power and it's like oh man.
Speaker 0: I want to go to the places of power I want to go able to legitimately get to any.
Speaker 1: we couldn't get to the brass city.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I want to go to the brass City, I wanted to go to the cave of wonders.
Speaker 0: I wanted to go to all these places that had super awesome magic in them.
Speaker 0: Right, you could you can't actually go there unless something else lets you go there.
Speaker 1: Even at the board game geek forums people point out that yeah You're pretty much never gonna get to those places.
Speaker 1: The
Speaker 0: other thing is the game has three phases of day like evening and then
Speaker 1: or hours didn't even get us through day
Speaker 0: Right, so it's like there's a whole bunch of this game that is pretty much inaccessible because apparently the game usually ends during the day And you're never actually gonna get to the night time.
Speaker 0: this game doesn't end.
Speaker 1: Now I guess my real problem is that what the way the game I mean all the coolness aside I'm not gonna get into all the cool mechanics it has because they're all pretty cool individually.
Speaker 1: Actually playing them.
Speaker 1: the way the game works is on your turn.
Speaker 1: you you decide where you want to move which doesn't mean shit.
Speaker 0: You go you go to your nearest quest dot.
Speaker 0: that happens to be your color.
Speaker 1: Yeah move around land somewhere look up a whole bunch of numbers and then the people the right and left you do all the work and Then you're presented with a trivial nothing.
Speaker 1: you pick an arbitrary option and then a short sometimes trivial Story that you have no control over is relayed to you And then the other player takes their turn and basically you have no input the game doesn't do anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like this illusion of input, right?
Speaker 0: It's like they give you these choices that feel like role-playing game choices.
Speaker 0: Like do you beg bar?
Speaker 0: You know, what?
Speaker 0: How are you going to react to this situation?
Speaker 1: I love this role-playing idea of you're presented with a situation and a course of action But no specifics.
Speaker 1: like you're presented with such an abstracted like.
Speaker 1: alright, what would my character do?
Speaker 1: Would he beg?
Speaker 1: What do you flee?
Speaker 1: Would he use a weapon and then based on that that tells the story.
Speaker 1: but the reality is the stories are all kind of pointless.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like the game would be great if it was just a storytelling system.
Speaker 1: Why bother with this whole Overly complex pointless game?
Speaker 1: that's kind of like hacked on the top of it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think what they should do is they should take the book story part, right?
Speaker 0: What they should do is they should make a game where everyone has sort of a character sheet with an inventory and these sorts Of things.
Speaker 0: right and it's choose your own adventure, but it's co-op.
Speaker 0: choose your own adventure.
Speaker 0: So it's like you're in a party and you just turn to page one and you read it and then it says alright You know to do this go to page two to do this go to page three and it's like.
Speaker 0: and then it.
Speaker 0: people can even have their own private books for their characters.
Speaker 0: or it's like You know, this is the stuff that they learn that no one else learns.
Speaker 0: So it might be like are you turn to page three?
Speaker 0: You know Scott should go or Alibaba should turn to page five in his personal book and you know read that and then it's like Alibaba can do his own thing just sitting there reading, you know, and also the party is doing something, you know And then Alibaba maybe suddenly has a treasure.
Speaker 0: No one knows how we got it.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, so, you know something like that and then that could be get all the good parts of this game Which is you know a pre-written choose your own adventure with limited replay value without Taking forever or having bullshit complicated rules of statuses that conflict with each other and quests and Trying to fit winning and losing and role-playing.
Speaker 1: Losing has no bearing on anything like winning.
Speaker 1: this game is completely random.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like some.
Speaker 0: it's basically the winning can basically be considered A timer.
Speaker 0: it's like when somebody any of the players has had enough story that is good Then they win.
Speaker 0: and then what?
Speaker 1: like an example of fiddliness There's two kinds of victory points and before the game starts and before you know anything you decide how many of each you need to Win.
Speaker 1: but there's no real way to say you're gonna get one point or the other point in the course of stories And sometimes the bad endings give you more points than the good endings and it just doesn't make any sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the game just.
Speaker 1: it's so tedious and the stories by and large would be cool If the game were a storytelling game, but it's not.
Speaker 1: it's like this trivial text where you read out Well, this is what happened.
Speaker 1: Maybe if the players were telling the stories somehow it'd be more fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know the fact that the stories are pre-told is I you know?
Speaker 0: It's like as opposed to us coming up with the store.
Speaker 1: They're pre-told pretty weekly to actually the.
Speaker 1: the stories themselves are.
Speaker 1: they're mostly consistent But they're just kind of written weirdly and they used weird phrasing.
Speaker 1: I get the impression that multiple people were writing the stories.
Speaker 0: There was no way one person did this.
Speaker 1: Not a lot of meshing between the thematic like style of all of these different people?
Speaker 0: no not at all.
Speaker 1: I mean, I don't know what else I can say.
Speaker 1: The game is not worth playing.
Speaker 1: It's kind of terrible, but there's such a good idea here.
Speaker 1: Someone should give someone.
Speaker 1: if you want you should buy this game and Deconstructed and make a simpler better game.
Speaker 1: that does some of the things this does.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I mean, you know, it was painful.
Speaker 0: It took a long time.
Speaker 0: It had a lot of bullshit rules and you know, if you can avoid caring about those rules maybe you could have fun with it, but at the same time the book as Poorly written as it was and as simple as some of the stories were like when you went through that book there was some sort of magic there and that you would draw a wizard card and roll some dice and add a whole bunch of Crazy numbers and then somehow you ended up hearing a story about a wizard and your reaction to it Actually sort of made sense with the story that was told and it came from a book.
Speaker 0: It was sort of like whoa, so, you know that Magical component there.
Speaker 0: I think there is something that you know is good but and that's what made the rest of the game so much more disappointing.
Speaker 0: cuz like I have to suffer through all this BS with Confusing rules in 10 hours just to have fun with this book like the way I would play the game I came up with one way that this game is worthwhile.
Speaker 1: if you forget the winning and losing and You kind of ignore any mechanics about getting victory points and you just have four artists sit down and play the game and the rule.
Speaker 1: After your story you have to draw a little comic like a three or four panel comic that tells the story your character just had happened to them and Then as you go around everyone's drawing this comic this continuity of their character at the end You'll get four mini comic books.
Speaker 1: This is the kind of thing artists could sit down on a Saturday and have a cool thing come out of.
Speaker 0: yeah It would take all day though.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, it takes all day to play the fucking game anyway.
Speaker 0: It would take even longer if you just stop and draw comic every time you had a turn.
Speaker 1: What's amazing is the game is ranked very highly on board game geek 7.2 out of 10.
Speaker 0: That's not that high but it is.
Speaker 0: it is higher than I would give it.
Speaker 0: I would give it five and the forum on it is interesting.
Speaker 1: It is 99 billion rules questions with no Canonical answers a million fiddly bits and half the questions are people saying well They're people saying things like.
Speaker 1: this is the best game ever I love is my favorite game.
Speaker 1: and the other half the people saying this game is unplayable.
Speaker 1: What the fuck is wrong with you?
Speaker 0: That's why I give it five stars.
Speaker 0: right because on the one hand it's not it's not the worst right.
Speaker 0: It's not like Hellas or anything.
Speaker 1: Hellas at least did not take Infinity time to play that's true.
Speaker 0: But you know, it has.
Speaker 0: it has something going on.
Speaker 1: No the game.
Speaker 0: This is why the game is why I put it right in the middle.
Speaker 1: This is why the game is worse than a five because while you're playing you feel like you're on the cusp of like figuring out Like oh and having a lot of fun, but that never happens because there's nothing to figure.
Speaker 0: That's why it's five.
Speaker 0: you're torn.
Speaker 1: You're torn between greatness and awfulness Thinking oh the game is almost there.
Speaker 1: I must be doing something wrong when really no you're doing everything, right?
Speaker 1: You'll be in a situation where you'll all every player will say really that's what happened.
Speaker 1: That doesn't seem right.
Speaker 1: There's no way they'd make the game like that.
Speaker 1: We must have done something wrong.
Speaker 1: But the reality is you did everything right.
Speaker 1: the game is just wrong.
Speaker 0: a good example of something that's fucked up in the game Is that you know everyone.
Speaker 0: you can have your sex change by accident?
Speaker 0: But the thing is it's nearly impossible to have it change back and you cannot win the game if it is changed.
Speaker 0: So basically having your sex changed means you can't possibly win.
Speaker 1: might as well just walk away from the table And you want to win.
Speaker 0: and it's completely random if it happens.
Speaker 0: It's like not much you can do to control it.
Speaker 0: It's just like oops.
Speaker 0: You met the sex change wizard.
Speaker 0: You just happen to draw the sex change wizard card.
Speaker 0: Good job.
Speaker 1: So, I mean that's pretty much it.
Speaker 1: We're gonna cut this a little short because of course we will be at PAX.
Speaker 1: So hopefully we'll see you there and we'll see how quickly we resume our normal geek night schedule after PAX because we have Zenka Connor right after.
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Speaker 0: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.