Speaker 1: It's Monday August 1st 2011.
Speaker 1: I'm rim.
Speaker 1: I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: get Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Started my new job today.
Speaker 1: It's pretty great.
Speaker 1: I got to say I was you know any any new job is great.
Speaker 0: in the first day I could start working at McDonald's.
Speaker 0: it'd be great.
Speaker 1: on the first, you know You know when I started at that hospital the first day a lot of warning signs.
Speaker 1: that really not so great.
Speaker 0: I've never seen warning signs.
Speaker 1: warning sign the first when I started that hospital a lot God like six years ago One.
Speaker 1: they gave me an alphanumeric pager.
Speaker 1: Oh Boy, and I was like, what's this?
Speaker 1: and they were like, it's your pager.
Speaker 1: and I was like, yeah, it's never getting turned on.
Speaker 1: Warning sign.
Speaker 1: the second Firefox not installed on the desktop and I didn't even know how to get it installed.
Speaker 1: Warning the third couldn't get to slashdot blocked.
Speaker 0: You know before I work somewhere I ask if they filter internet or anything like that.
Speaker 1: I normally do but I didn't back then.
Speaker 1: that was a long time ago.
Speaker 0: I've done that even before I graduated college.
Speaker 0: I was like, do you filter internet?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not working there.
Speaker 1: Sorry Anyway, yeah, but no, it's pretty great to be I don't know.
Speaker 1: This is a big step up.
Speaker 1: I can.
Speaker 1: basically I'm the vice president of product management.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you're only the vice president of like ten people.
Speaker 0: Well, it's more that I there's only ten people there.
Speaker 1: people actually listen to what I'd say.
Speaker 1: So it's not like like think about it.
Speaker 0: That is a key different about Connecticut.
Speaker 1: when we're like Here's the obvious smart thing to do.
Speaker 1: and then we had like fight for stuff.
Speaker 1: I can be like this is the smart thing to do and people are like, alright, are you describing some sort of non-existent utopia?
Speaker 0: People you say something and people listen like hey, yeah be really good idea if we switched from exchange to Google You know, it's even better if I'm wrong or mighty is bad.
Speaker 1: smart people intelligently disagree.
Speaker 1: Oh my god It's kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: Are you sure?
Speaker 0: is the real workplace watch?
Speaker 1: I never get a paycheck.
Speaker 1: I show up one day and there's like cardboard cutouts of everyone.
Speaker 0: That's the thing is like some recruiter just called me and I was like giving him the shit, you know.
Speaker 0: So I'm like whatever recruiters you happen to call me while I'm not I'm waiting for him to show up and I have nothing better To do.
Speaker 0: I'll talk to you because you had the balls to call me on the phone instead of just emailing the last recruiter I talked to.
Speaker 1: he emailed me and he was like, yeah, what do you want?
Speaker 1: I got this like Linux system administration job and I was like I need 300k Before I even gonna look at this.
Speaker 0: I'm just.
Speaker 0: I'm just like treating the guy like crap like yeah What do you make if I get hired?
Speaker 0: He's like 25%.
Speaker 0: I'm like, oh you told me that's not bad No, but the thing was is like, you know, there's always the.
Speaker 0: I always get these things from startup places, you know.
Speaker 1: Oh, they're like.
Speaker 1: I can gladly pay you Tuesday and stock options.
Speaker 0: Exactly, right.
Speaker 0: It's like startups.
Speaker 0: They really want to get you in because it's basically it's impossible to hire tech people But they're paying you nothing like rare rare skills like you.
Speaker 1: I think you said it best.
Speaker 1: I'm going to give you this pile of lottery tickets coupled with a pittance of a salary, but you get to work in a party But also 80-hour week also 80-hour weeks in the party zone and we'll give you lottery to go other Utopias.
Speaker 1: right, you know my work hours are.
Speaker 1: Get the work done nice.
Speaker 1: Yeah Like the big ups ride their bikes to work it's got like all the.
Speaker 0: how old are the big ups, uh Standard big up age what kind of.
Speaker 1: but all the people around like at my level and under are our age or younger like they're Actually, and they're all smart.
Speaker 1: He's like, yeah interns.
Speaker 1: Yeah co-ops Here's how.
Speaker 0: here's how we really know the three important questions to tell if these are big ups are good or not.
Speaker 0: You're ready.
Speaker 0: question number one.
Speaker 0: What phones do the big ups have?
Speaker 1: I actually don't know.
Speaker 1: but but they asked me what phone I had because they were gonna give me a company phone and it felt Like the Nexus and everyone's like, oh you don't need our phone.
Speaker 0: Okay, dude What computers do they have on their desk?
Speaker 1: Everyone has a different computer.
Speaker 1: One guy has a super fast Mac bunch of the tower, uh Or a MacBook Pro.
Speaker 1: one has a MacBook Pro one is a tower.
Speaker 0: Well, someone is the Mac Pro tower.
Speaker 1: Okay, also people like.
Speaker 1: the first computer they gave me before I got the Windows box was just Ubuntu.
Speaker 0: Okay, they took There's already an Ubuntu in the house.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's a good sign.
Speaker 0: Okay question number three is the most important.
Speaker 0: Uh-oh, what kind of bikes are they riding?
Speaker 1: Ah, actually he's got one of those commuter bikes.
Speaker 0: Oh the the foldy day on thing.
Speaker 0: Okay, okay That's a very CEO.
Speaker 1: the thing is they know real bikes and they're all super athletic which counts for a lot actually.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the question, you know if it was?
Speaker 1: I'm tired of working with Eunuch Santas much.
Speaker 1: I love Eunuch Santas.
Speaker 1: I like people I can play paintball with.
Speaker 0: the thing is in the ideal company All right has to have both.
Speaker 0: you have to have the Eunuch Santa.
Speaker 0: Ah, you don't think you can learn if there's nothing if there's no Eunuch in your job If there's no Eunuch, then you got another problem.
Speaker 1: Here's the weirdest thing.
Speaker 1: this is the first time in my life I have had a job where my job does not in any way involve straight-up support.
Speaker 0: But I mean your company uses Eunuch's machines.
Speaker 0: They're all your servers.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, there's stuff but I don't have to manage that.
Speaker 1: I'm actually kind of divorced from that.
Speaker 1: let like operational tech, right?
Speaker 0: but the point is You got to have Eunuch Santas and Steve Jobs is combined right because while lately I'm been a lot of you know a lot of my rants and Technical opinions have been very anti jobs.
Speaker 0: You got to remember that the jobs is also necessary.
Speaker 1: Well, let's put it this way the jobs made for whatever you feel about Apple some of the best goddamn user interfaces The world has ever seen.
Speaker 0: Yes, um, not.
Speaker 0: But look, you know.
Speaker 0: take for example my favorite example I always bring up in this discussion is the Apple to GS the most beautiful computer ever created.
Speaker 1: That's Eunuch Santa.
Speaker 0: Why was the Apple to GS created?
Speaker 0: is because it was a combination of Steve Wozniak and Steve Jobs.
Speaker 0: God, we just had the Wozniak.
Speaker 0: without the jobs The Apple to GS would have been like all sorts of wicked ugly.
Speaker 0: if you just had the jobs You wouldn't have been able to open it.
Speaker 0: It would have been welded shut right.
Speaker 0: but because you had both you had this perfect computer that opened up just once and it was Completely flat and all the slots were in a row.
Speaker 0: It was the ultimate combination.
Speaker 1: I feel like there's a third way.
Speaker 1: There's a third way.
Speaker 1: There's actually a triangle Eunuch Santa Steve Jobs and the other direction is Tim Berners-Lee.
Speaker 1: idealized software solutions Functional Requirements with no interface or thought for practicality Right.
Speaker 0: So speaking of Steve Jobs, right you you got a new HDVC.
Speaker 1: I did.
Speaker 1: I have not that exciting.
Speaker 1: I've not plugged it into my TV yet just cuz I've been busy.
Speaker 1: But yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: it works though, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know what my whole life.
Speaker 1: ever since I switched away from AMD I got to say I've never had a failure to post on the first boot.
Speaker 1: In fact, I Closed the case and put all the screws in before I turned it on for the first time.
Speaker 1: That is how fucking confident I was and it were.
Speaker 0: you were right, dude, my old AMD boxes.
Speaker 1: I would like plug power into the motherboard with CPU and RAM sitting on the floor and turn it on to make sure it worked.
Speaker 0: Can't go wrong with Nvidia Intel.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the so you didn't need the Mac Mini anymore now.
Speaker 0: So I said hey Mac Mini you have been you.
Speaker 0: you have served your many years.
Speaker 0: It's actually many years old.
Speaker 1: It was like it was a core solo.
Speaker 1: is the you?
Speaker 0: do you remember that you originally bought it to replace my normal PC?
Speaker 0: He uses your normal PC and it was in the earliest days of gig night.
Speaker 1: You may remember an episode that was me bitching for an hour because I unplugged my old computer Which was my old RIT computer.
Speaker 1: It was like a Thunderbird giga.
Speaker 0: So this was probably in 2005 six.
Speaker 0: I remember.
Speaker 1: there's a picture of me sitting there like holding it up like amazed at how tiny it is and I install it.
Speaker 1: I think was actually six seven, but I set it up and I'm like It still had that old 19 inch CRT.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it was so shiny and so nice.
Speaker 1: and then I opened up Garage band and I was like, let's podcast.
Speaker 1: and then four hours later I had plugged my old PC back in it wouldn't boot because it was broken.
Speaker 1: That's the reason I replaced it and I redid an entire episode from scratch.
Speaker 1: There was me bitching about how much I hate the Mac, right?
Speaker 0: So this Mac mini?
Speaker 0: I said well you have lived out your years.
Speaker 0: if we threw you out or just gate sold you or gave You away, that would not be bad.
Speaker 0: But you still work and you're a Mac.
Speaker 0: You're the only Mac I have.
Speaker 0: that's not a work computer that I can't use for personal things.
Speaker 1: I have some trouble with the optical drive.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I brought it home - I said why not?
Speaker 0: I'll try some Development of iPhone app.
Speaker 0: I'll make the simplest iPhone app.
Speaker 0: That's like just a fucking button or something.
Speaker 0: do the thing just to make an iPhone.
Speaker 1: You notice how that the Apple logo at the top like that's plastic is slightly yellowed.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah so anyway I brought a home and I really wanted to reinstall the snow leopard to get it back for it to nothing and I couldn't because the optical drive was busted which I remembered.
Speaker 1: It's okay the watch out.
Speaker 0: We switched it to region - you'll have to it doesn't matter because I'm not even gonna use the optical drive.
Speaker 0: I went and I used my work Mac to create a snow leopard bootable USB stick which race which worked.
Speaker 0: Amazingly if you search on Google for directions, it'll tell you how it worked perfectly.
Speaker 0: So I reinstall the snow leopard from the USB stick.
Speaker 0: beautiful.
Speaker 0: Then I said, well, let me get the X code.
Speaker 0: So there's a free X code in the App Store.
Speaker 0: X code 4.1 is the newest one.
Speaker 0: you need lion.
Speaker 0: Alrighty, what's only 30 bucks?
Speaker 0: Who gives a shit?
Speaker 0: I'll buy your stupid lion.
Speaker 0: You cannot install lion.
Speaker 0: You have a core solo, ha That's so sad which is not 64 bits.
Speaker 1: that's so sad.
Speaker 0: Well, then let me go get X code.
Speaker 0: cuz you remember there was X code 3 point something which is on the snow leopard disc.
Speaker 0: So I could have just installed that easily.
Speaker 0: but before they came up with X code 4.1 There was X code 4.0 Which is the one that they were charging like $10 for in the App Store.
Speaker 0: Remember that when everyone was like, oh they're charging for X code 10 bucks now, it's free again.
Speaker 0: Well, I said well, let me go get that one that they were charging 10 bucks for.
Speaker 0: right, but it wasn't in the App Store.
Speaker 0: So I went to the Apple developer site and it wasn't there.
Speaker 0: The only ones they had were 4.1 which which is the one you need lion for and three point something Which is the one I already had on the USB stick.
Speaker 0: So I'm like what happened to 4.0 point whatever.
Speaker 0: you need to pay $100 to be in the iOS developer program to get that.
Speaker 0: oh my god, and The Iowa you can't even if you you can make.
Speaker 0: if you had lion you could make all the iPhone apps you wanted.
Speaker 0: You can't load them onto your iPhone unless you pay the hundred dollars.
Speaker 0: Submit them to the App Store unless you pay $100.
Speaker 1: That sounds about right.
Speaker 0: you can only run them in a little emulator.
Speaker 0: And by the way that hundred dollars is a hundred dollars a year not a hundred dollars.
Speaker 0: once It's a hundred dollars a year to be an iOS develop still gonna be an iOS developer.
Speaker 0: Fuck.
Speaker 0: No Given that Mac mini to the parents to use as an HTTP C and to sync their iPods because right now I watch out It won't full-screen 1080p.
Speaker 0: it doesn't matter that my parents they can't even watch Netflix on their TV right now.
Speaker 1: Do you think they're gonna be okay with control zooming in to YouTube videos like we were?
Speaker 0: they're not gonna watch YouTube videos.
Speaker 0: They're just gonna use like boxy and watch.
Speaker 0: we're lucky if they watch.
Speaker 0: use boxy to watch a Netflix.
Speaker 0: All right, that'll be a huge improvement over what they're doing now.
Speaker 1: boxy didn't even work so well on that thing.
Speaker 0: It's better than what they have now at the very least, right?
Speaker 0: They don't even have like a. they only have like a Ubuntu on a Dell laptop that they use for everything and all they really do Is use Firefox which is just fine for them, but they have iPods that they can't sync.
Speaker 0: So the very least they can just use it for iTunes and nothing else, which it can definitely do.
Speaker 0: Yeah On snow leopard.
Speaker 1: I think in the long run It should probably replace the like.
Speaker 1: I don't put it somewhere in their house is like a little PC somewhere I don't know.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I'll just give it to them because now it's useless for me.
Speaker 0: But the thing is I have to go and buy them the little Mac keyboard that goes with it?
Speaker 1: No, yeah, cuz I kept that one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I like the boxy remote, but since I need a mouse anyway When I'm not in boxy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've been using boxy more though.
Speaker 0: I've got hooked up to pretty much all the video files.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I don't want to watch any.
Speaker 0: the only time I don't use boxy is pretty much to go to College Humor.
Speaker 0: Yep, I got a massacre.
Speaker 1: I got to see what it would take to set up like a boxy app thing that would just do College Humor you want to.
Speaker 0: There is a College Humor boxy app, but it only watches College Humor originals.
Speaker 0: It doesn't do all the videos in college humor.
Speaker 1: What the fuck?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can write a boxy app in Python if you want.
Speaker 1: really that's what I was about to ask.
Speaker 1: What does it take?
Speaker 1: is it easy to do that?
Speaker 0: Because yeah, there's just there's instructions on the boxy website.
Speaker 0: You can just write boxy apps.
Speaker 0: It's actually not that hard duly noted You know, you could definitely do it.
Speaker 1: your code might be ugly, but you could definitely write a boxy app Because I need a Python project and while I like a web stuff and like I was playing with Django and I really like flask.
Speaker 1: I was playing with that.
Speaker 1: That's really fun.
Speaker 0: Actually flask is a lot simpler.
Speaker 0: It's well, it's really fun because if I want but the thing is what's gonna happen is you I've used flask a bunch also.
Speaker 0: Yeah You start using it like we and then you want to do something like logging in and it's like you can write a login authentication thing or Django has authentication.
Speaker 1: So What I would use flask for in my professional life in the like operations is something like making a little status page of stuff.
Speaker 0: Absolutely Perfect use of flask.
Speaker 1: Yep, like see what's running on the PC.
Speaker 1: You see anything like that, but it's just fun too.
Speaker 0: Cuz you know you just got to make sure you put the Apache in the WSGI in front of it properly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll do that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can show you how to do that.
Speaker 1: I learned how to do that.
Speaker 0: Okay, cuz I had a lot of free time Because that way you can get things like the Apache offs and but as much no, you know.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's something I gotta tell you.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna go into this very long.
Speaker 0: You know the Apache configs is always like allow deny allow from all all that business.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mastered that really Yep, it's not that hard.
Speaker 0: I've completely mastered all that.
Speaker 0: I finally know what it all means and can do it perfectly.
Speaker 1: Can you here's here's the love this is.
Speaker 1: this is if you're like a four out of ten in terms of guru mastery of Apache Do you know how to pretty much drop in make Apache authenticate against an active directory like a Windows one?
Speaker 0: I already saw the instructions.
Speaker 1: Yeah, have you ever done it?
Speaker 0: I'm just curious.
Speaker 0: No, but I could.
Speaker 0: if I had to do it I could do it in a day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz I did it but it didn't work with Twiki.
Speaker 0: and then I gave up what I did Actually at work as I made it so that if you visit a page a site On a virtual host actually it gives you basic off which is you know username password against an HD pass.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if you're coming from a certain IP No basic off you just get right in.
Speaker 0: so if you're in the office you can just visit the page But if you're outside the office, you got to log in to get.
Speaker 1: I did the same thing.
Speaker 1: I had a thing that would control some fixed sessions on this like fixed gateway.
Speaker 1: I wrote right and it had a little like web page in it that would like.
Speaker 1: you could like turn Sessions on and off and whatever and I didn't want to put off into it because I didn't care, right?
Speaker 0: So anyway, the long day end of this opening bit is fuck you Steve Jobs.
Speaker 0: You want people to make iOS apps?
Speaker 0: You should let people develop them on Windows or whatever.
Speaker 0: I might try this phone gap thing which came out with 1.0 today, which lets you make an app in HTML CSS and JavaScript that will then work on Android iPhone Windows phone and fucking everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I'm gonna try that out.
Speaker 1: I thought oh we should make a nice app and I was like what the fuck would it do?
Speaker 0: Nothing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you want a geek nights app What you can do is you can use your Twitter and soon your Facebook app on whatever device you have and just go to Us in Twitter or Facebook.
Speaker 0: That's basically the equivalent of the app.
Speaker 0: is you'll get all the notifications about all our new shit Yep, and our I'll save for the meta.
Speaker 0: I got some Com in your mobile browsing.
Speaker 1: Let's talk about some tech because there was a. I had some other news I wanted to talk about but I noticed this article today.
Speaker 1: It's funny having a job where it's really knowledge based and not operational at all.
Speaker 1: And also, you know learning a lot.
Speaker 1: I didn't look at the internet like once the whole time I was at work.
Speaker 0: Well, you never look at the internet on your first day.
Speaker 1: You know what warning sign that hospital.
Speaker 1: two hours looking at FARC because no one would like meet with me to tell me what to do.
Speaker 0: So even you didn't even have a full day of HR papers to fill out.
Speaker 1: now actually today Five minutes of HR because it's an LLC.
Speaker 1: No, so it's like BAM nice plus, you know, I'm older now.
Speaker 1: I'm smarter I know what to expect.
Speaker 1: so I came in with my passport.
Speaker 1: I canceled check, you know all the stuff.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm I didn't do that.
Speaker 1: You know the last time I took a job.
Speaker 0: I always forget the cancel check.
Speaker 0: That's the one I forget.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I remember it cuz I changed jobs.
Speaker 1: This is you know, you change jobs a while ago.
Speaker 1: I hadn't changed jobs like four years.
Speaker 1: I was waiting for this day.
Speaker 0: You remembered it better because it was longer ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I thought back.
Speaker 1: I was like what went wrong the last time I got a job.
Speaker 1: the problems I had were I didn't know anyone's phone numbers for like the beneficiary stuff.
Speaker 1: I didn't even know my mom's address.
Speaker 1: I'd go like look it up.
Speaker 0: I always need my mom the beneficiary Social Security numbers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I didn't need that yet because well Anyway, anyway, yeah, but so there's this article from today about some CMU researchers Carnegie Mellon, by the way Which is yeah, we know what that is.
Speaker 0: I'm some people might not almost went there.
Speaker 1: I run into people.
Speaker 1: I'm like RIT.
Speaker 1: They're like, yeah RPI like no RIT RPI sucks but CMU is a good school and they uh, they came up with a pretty.
Speaker 1: this is one of those things like hey let's see if we can do it.
Speaker 1: and The fact that what they did as quickly and kind of half acidly hackishly as they did worked as well as it did is Kinda it's not
Speaker 0: scary to me
Speaker 1: cuz I knew but it might be scary to your mom with crappy off-the-shelf webcams and Fairly simple data mining of like Facebook.
Speaker 1: Okay, they were able to make a system where if you point a webcam at a crowd and it sees people's faces It'll find their Social Security numbers.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that could work because you get the face you match the face up with Facebook You get profile information get the name address whatever and then you look you basically get as much information as you can Start a really good or starting with flicker or Picasa.
Speaker 0: They just did Facebook apparently to start and then you just you start with just Facebook here.
Speaker 1: No, here's the thing.
Speaker 0: Here's the kicker and you just cross reference and if enough things match you can.
Speaker 0: just on different sites You go to you can just keep filling out the profile until eventually You hit a site that has social security number and you've now you've got the whole profile granted.
Speaker 1: That site is breaking the law.
Speaker 1: Well, duh, but here's the kicker that the thing that made this probably a lot easier.
Speaker 1: I didn't go into the depth of how they did it like on the low level but to this day Four digits of my social security number are in all my old RIT shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah you lot of times you could you could eat if you.
Speaker 0: I Imagine that like if they could get 80% of the real full numbers They could definitely get 99% of the last four digits.
Speaker 1: and here's the funniest part 60% of the students that they caught Didn't have Social Security numbers.
Speaker 1: So the it was crazy successful despite the fact that the majority of the people they were testing did not even have them.
Speaker 1: So it got some crazy percentage of the people who did.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So what this illustrates is Something we talked about earlier.
Speaker 1: We have talked about a lot.
Speaker 1: I think we've talked about it recently that there's a lot of publicly available but difficult to get information.
Speaker 1: Like if you really want to stalk one person, this is what P eyes used to do.
Speaker 1: a private investigator Just gets publicly available information.
Speaker 1: It's not a crime to stand on the sidewalk and look at someone's house.
Speaker 1: Not a crime.
Speaker 1: just follow someone unobtrusively.
Speaker 1: not a crime to take a picture of stuff in public places.
Speaker 1: Go to public records freedom information act stuff.
Speaker 1: Technology allows you to do that to everyone all the time at zero cost.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Oh really almost zero cost effective negligible cost.
Speaker 1: Yes couple this with the fact that there's well negligible cost per person.
Speaker 0: to actually do it to everyone at once You do need to buy a bunch of computers.
Speaker 0: your house per person will be zero But the cost of a rack will be like a thousand couple thousand a month.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it is Google.
Speaker 1: this is you know A lot of people are afraid of Google Maps and Google Street View and that's the least of your worries.
Speaker 1: I don't think Google should even be blurring out faces or anything.
Speaker 0: I don't understand the license plate thing.
Speaker 0: That's always really confuses me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that aside All Google did was economy of scale.
Speaker 1: it had people basically do the equivalent of walk around and take a picture of everything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they're actually.
Speaker 0: I wish they would do that.
Speaker 0: I heard that a while ago like months and months ago that they were gonna go into stores and take pictures in the stores If the stores let them.
Speaker 1: that would be so awesome, right?
Speaker 0: But I haven't actually seen that on any street views yet So I'm still been waiting for.
Speaker 0: the like announced that they've added that like if I could go and look in the bodega to see If they have.
Speaker 1: you know, dude, I'd go one step further.
Speaker 1: Here's a way for Google to actually make some money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like a product what they could sell is a service where if you have an event like a convention You can pay them to send someone Probably just someone they hire like a contractor who uses their technology who goes into the event.
Speaker 1: for you know Repeatedly walking around gathering like these gigantic panoramas of your entire event like Otacon Imagine a navigable street view map of the interior of Otacon at like noon.
Speaker 1: Okay, that would be awesome.
Speaker 1: But anyway,
Speaker 0: or like if they could temporarily update something on Google Maps like embed a map of your convention that weekend and then when the conventions over remove it or like Temporarily if you're having a concert at a football stadium, which means the seating chart is gonna change temporarily Embed the seating chart into Google Maps on the stadium for that weekend during the concert and then when the concerts over Switch the seat map back to the original football playing seat.
Speaker 1: couple that even further.
Speaker 1: you couldn't use GPS for this obviously but you could use either a creatively named access points that were set up ahead of time by Google or Some other like similar technology to make a local only Location system doesn't even have to be that precise.
Speaker 1: That gives you a map of the convention and a you are hair in the convention Even though it's in some ungodly bunker like the Javits.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway, so so I got a news.
Speaker 1: I got to finish my point here.
Speaker 1: I often Explain to people who don't understand technology that they cannot have privacy because even if we make laws to protect them Hackers can trivially aggregate extent information that cannot by law be easily hidden.
Speaker 0: and If you did hide all the information you'd basically wouldn't be.
Speaker 0: you might as well not use computers.
Speaker 1: Yep, you'd have too much like there'd be no more freedom of speech.
Speaker 1: Imagine if you couldn't tell another person that you saw a certain person on the street wearing a red cap.
Speaker 1: That's all Google does.
Speaker 1: Joe was wearing a red cap and he was standing in front of scandals.
Speaker 1: I Always try to tell people you can't get it.
Speaker 1: You can't get it.
Speaker 1: give up.
Speaker 1: You know, we've got to manage privacy before it's too late, but we can't keep privacy as we currently know it.
Speaker 1: No one believes me.
Speaker 1: if you ever run into an old person who doesn't believe that you can just aggregate information like this show them This article and scare the crap out of them.
Speaker 0: They'll just get more scared and do more reactionary stupidity Maybe.
Speaker 0: Anyway, so Adobe did something today.
Speaker 0: that so be slightly impressed me if that that's possible, you know, I Render don't you get a complaint about your premiere codec?
Speaker 1: I'm gonna one more me from like one complaint.
Speaker 1: You know, I recently put up an hour-long panel game mechanics and mechanism today.
Speaker 0: It wasn't that bad, but I have.
Speaker 0: I keep saying right all the yeah.
Speaker 1: Whenever I'm talking I'm like scooting back and forth like scoot to the light But we're good forward to back a worse problem than scooting.
Speaker 0: is me going right, right, right, right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I gotta I gotta work on the right.
Speaker 1: Well, what I do is when you're talking I keep touching my nose.
Speaker 0: That's why I keep zooming in on your nose that you're touching.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I just keep like poking at it pushing my glasses around.
Speaker 0: Oh, you got glasses.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, it's a situation and I think it's cuz.
Speaker 1: I used to always fiddle with my mustache, but there's no mustache there.
Speaker 0: So I got a fiddle with someone's got to invent something about something for glasses.
Speaker 0: That's different.
Speaker 0: in the nose area.
Speaker 0: I don't know what.
Speaker 0: lazy.
Speaker 0: I guess they already have pads of gelatin, right lazy.
Speaker 0: I mean, how could you do?
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway, so Adobe they came out with a beta of this product called edge.
Speaker 0: It's totally free and Actually, it's pretty fascinating.
Speaker 0: I opened it up didn't know how to use it and just started using it.
Speaker 0: alright, and What?
Speaker 0: it is an animation tool and you know It does sort of like that in-betweening that flash does.
Speaker 0: so you go to time you go to the timeline.
Speaker 0: You said it's zero seconds.
Speaker 0: You put something in the top left corner You go to five seconds You move it to the bottom right corner and then you press play and it'll show you it's Sliding from the top left corner to the bottom right corner over the course of the five seconds, right?
Speaker 0: Beautiful easy to use animation tool totally awesome.
Speaker 1: That'll actually really useful for making content for panels.
Speaker 0: Well, actually It can only at the present time.
Speaker 0: It can only do rectangles rounded rectangles and text.
Speaker 1: Ah, okay, which is like wait a minute.
Speaker 1: You know what this reminds me of.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna take you way back.
Speaker 0: It's a free beta that only works for hundred.
Speaker 1: No what I'm saying, you know, there's flash and shockwave and all this stuff.
Speaker 1: Way back when I bought a ball time meat while my parents bought a multi media PC It came with a product called Macro media remember macro media and action.
Speaker 1: Okay, you know that was this.
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't.
Speaker 1: it could do things like this.
Speaker 0: No, you're not you're not finishing cuz flash can do all this animation stuff.
Speaker 0: But what this does specifically is not so much about the animation stuff that it does which flash already does.
Speaker 0: It is about its export.
Speaker 0: It only exports to HTML 5.
Speaker 0: Oh That's all it does.
Speaker 0: So you go you can save it as HTML 5.
Speaker 0: It gives you CSS JS and a div and you put that div in a web page with those CSS and JS Included and there's your animation.
Speaker 0: Oh, they added support for audio.
Speaker 0: you could.
Speaker 0: and vector arts.
Speaker 0: You could make a homestar runner and you'd be all set, but I don't think it does.
Speaker 0: vector arts I don't think they plan to do that.
Speaker 0: So I think what it's gonna end up being is just text and boxes and images.
Speaker 0: So you basically would make Webpages.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling it'll go a little bit beyond that they're gonna.
Speaker 0: it's gonna be web pages with animations in them That are all smooth and fancy as of right now, but pretty chill.
Speaker 0: It's it's actually.
Speaker 0: the user interface was really good.
Speaker 0: It didn't crash.
Speaker 0: It was actually pretty fast for Mac and PC.
Speaker 0: It's free for 150 days.
Speaker 0: Some of the stuff is one of these.
Speaker 0: I looked at all the CSS and JS files It makes.
Speaker 0: so the files that it makes that are part of your project have no license.
Speaker 0: So I assume you own them.
Speaker 0: It does have two jQuery files those are open source and two JS files of one of which is BSD licensed and one of which you were free to distribute but not to modify.
Speaker 0: so so one of the JS files is BSD and one of them was there.
Speaker 0: but it's like It's produced.
Speaker 0: It's a Adobe product that outputs something Almost entirely open source as opposed to some locked up SW.
Speaker 0: What the hell?
Speaker 1: They must have gotten like a really good intern or something the fuck.
Speaker 0: They're smoking and it works and it does animate.
Speaker 0: so this is it's free for 150 days.
Speaker 0: get it now and Maybe make something awesome with it before it becomes $500.
Speaker 1: so Adobe when you get a support video formats in premiere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, when these Let's move on.
Speaker 1: so things of the day.
Speaker 1: What do you got for me Scott?
Speaker 0: It's a really good video.
Speaker 0: You know the those old videos like let's go out to the whatever.
Speaker 0: And it was you know, they're like dancing popcorn and the dancing.
Speaker 1: I saw one of those that was not ironic at the drive-in when I was a kid.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we had drive-ins You know, it's just that little.
Speaker 0: you know Those little cartoon videos that are sort of you know famous the watch in the movie theater and they're telling you to go out to the concessions to get Popcorn right and to make you thirsty for Pepsi or some shit.
Speaker 1: This is just one of those you should watch.
Speaker 0: Well, this isn't really one of those sort of a take on one of those right.
Speaker 0: that is pretty interesting and very Professionally well made by MK 12.
Speaker 0: It's called follow the Sun.
Speaker 0: Make sure you watch the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Don't stop You might get bored.
Speaker 0: It's like three or four minutes long.
Speaker 0: I know you have short internet attention spans, but this is one of those ones where it builds.
Speaker 0: trust me.
Speaker 0: It builds and it's got sort of a catchy tune like Right, so just keep watching it all the way to the end.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it's entirely safe for her work.
Speaker 0: It is not safe for work, but just watch the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Trust me.
Speaker 0: This is great.
Speaker 0: And it's not really made.
Speaker 1: It's no Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles, but it has a similar.
Speaker 1: you'll see.
Speaker 1: it's subtle and then unsubtle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, watch it It's great.
Speaker 1: I saw this a while ago and I forgot about it.
Speaker 0: Oh and mix it with ponies.
Speaker 0: cuz ponies go well with everything.
Speaker 1: That'd be a pretty good mix actually Kind of like that to our ring you mix.
Speaker 1: so I got something really simple.
Speaker 1: This is just the Batman equation.
Speaker 1: for any math nerd who's ever seen the Batman equation, which is holy holy plus something equals Goddamn, but no, that would be a Robin equation kid minus two ex parents plus Joker.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so this is just a fairly large equation that you can grab.
Speaker 1: It's a fairly like.
Speaker 1: it's relatively simple to understand though I defy anyone who is not insane to look at it and figure out what it graphs.
Speaker 1: Just from looking at it without a lot of well now that they know it's the Batman equation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's the Batman equation.
Speaker 1: It turns into Batman and it's kind of new.
Speaker 0: So basically you type it into your graphing calculator and the bat logo appears.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is the kind of thing that you should have on hand to impress the girls at high school calculus class.
Speaker 0: Ah Yeah.
Speaker 0: So metamoment.
Speaker 0: well, I mean it's not gonna impress any girls but on the On the off chance that it impresses a girl.
Speaker 0: That's the one.
Speaker 0: don't let her go.
Speaker 1: I want kids.
Speaker 1: the Rainbow Dash equation It's not gonna happen might happen.
Speaker 1: So the metamoment metamoment metamucil book club book is is all right the the ear the eye and the arm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yes Rim still hasn't uploaded the book club book episode, but it's already recorded.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: It'll be up as soon as I have time been busy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you might actually hear this before hearing the foundation episode, but we recorded it.
Speaker 0: Yes, it was done.
Speaker 1: Other metas we have a fax is coming soon.
Speaker 0: You can't get tickets.
Speaker 0: Yep, New York Comic Con is coming after that.
Speaker 0: mag fest is sometime next year after that.
Speaker 0: Yep We'll be at mag fest will be all three of those guaranteed.
Speaker 1: We are doing on Saturday at noon in I forget which theater I think is the big one.
Speaker 1: We're doing Discover the Forgotten Masters brand new panel.
Speaker 0: don't even know what it's gonna be cuz I've written it But it involves an Atari 2600.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: We have a fancy new Facebook page.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you should like us on Facebook.
Speaker 0: Right now I'm manually cross posting things to Facebook But I've already coded the site to automatically cross post things to Facebook and as soon as I launch the new updated site of front Recruit comm it will automatically post everything into Facebook.
Speaker 0: So you won't have to come to forever.
Speaker 0: I've given up on trying to get people to come to the site at this point.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much the site is basically for at this point one.
Speaker 1: I will occasionally post like a link to all the slides from panel.
Speaker 0: It's like at this point.
Speaker 0: It's like listen come and find our shit.
Speaker 0: whatever way is most convenient for you.
Speaker 0: If you're a Facebook person follow the Facebook page.
Speaker 0: if you're a Twitter person follow the Twitter account.
Speaker 0: do whatever makes you happy.
Speaker 0: I give up what amazing if you like our website come to that too is to.
Speaker 1: but I tell people like yeah geek nights And they're like, where's your website?
Speaker 1: I'm like just Google geek nights.
Speaker 1: It's the first thing.
Speaker 0: Let me make sure it is.
Speaker 1: it is the first thing.
Speaker 0: it sure is.
Speaker 1: We've been doing this since 2005.
Speaker 0: let me see if it is.
Speaker 0: if you use geek nights as two words and make a mistake Yep, still number one all right of course But we have.
Speaker 1: you know we put up our for one of our PAX lectures from PAX East last year on YouTube in the geek nights rim YouTube channel.
Speaker 1: I have now uploaded the second of our three panels a Second running of game mechanics and mechanism design.
Speaker 1: I thought
Speaker 0: it wasn't as good as the first time We did it, but I watched the video today, and it was alright except for me saying right Yeah, we
Speaker 1: ran it way better the first time we ran it, but I was kind of tired when we ran it at PAX.
Speaker 1: Yeah, East 2011, but the third panel how to win at games will be up as soon as I have time to edit it together.
Speaker 0: Oh, I forgot we even had a third panel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and keep your eye out because I am rapidly going to add a lot of video content for geek nights also.
Speaker 1: You pig fuckers You know what what.
Speaker 1: the first question we got on game mechanics and mechanism design to YouTube was guys Where's radio free equestria?
Speaker 1: I mean we made these pilots.
Speaker 0: It's not a regular show.
Speaker 0: We made three pilots.
Speaker 0: coming Jesus you kids your regular show is for later.
Speaker 1: I love my little pony, but Jesus really Jesus.
Speaker 0: Maybe when a new season come yeah Come when it comes right.
Speaker 0: videos hard.
Speaker 0: Any other meta merch anything?
Speaker 0: Oh hold off on merch if there's other meta that we forgot.
Speaker 0: worst Worst webcomic.
Speaker 1: yes, we have the worst webcomic contest.
Speaker 0: when you if you're gonna go to our site Go to the news section find the post about the worst webcomic contest And there's gonna be a link to a form to fill out.
Speaker 0: don't just post in the forum thread.
Speaker 0: forum Right your suggestion you actually have to go.
Speaker 0: There's a Google Docs form to fill out your submission for the worst webcomic contest.
Speaker 0: That is the only place to officially submit where you can win a prize and be considered along those lines.
Speaker 1: Stop submitting control alt elite.
Speaker 1: we already said that yeah, but I Okay, and I got it.
Speaker 1: preface this one last little thing.
Speaker 1: you if you submit an entry to this you might think This is a little bit of a mean-spirited contest.
Speaker 1: Yep, yep, so you if you don't actually create something are worse than whatever it is that you are submitting whoever created.
Speaker 1: That is better than you as a human.
Speaker 0: so feel bad and shitties.
Speaker 0: better than making a really poorly drawn furry porn Fanfic where you're the otter with in Star Trek.
Speaker 0: that guy's better than it's better than someone who makes Nothing unless I mean if Mike and Jerry you know penny arcade.
Speaker 1: if they submit a comic yeah Yeah, they get.
Speaker 1: they can call something shitty.
Speaker 0: They get away with it.
Speaker 0: They can diss whatever they want.
Speaker 0: alright, so We already did a show on version control systems.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: We have not done one on change management But that's more of.
Speaker 1: it's almost a more like release management.
Speaker 0: Those the same thing yeah anyway, but you know get is one of the few hot new Technologies that I am extremely familiar with.
Speaker 1: Scott.
Speaker 1: I would argue knows more about it than most people at this point.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the thing was is just because at my last job You know I was working with a guy who was pretty Linux II and he started using git like slightly before it was cool.
Speaker 0: So I started using it slightly before it was cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah Like hey, and I was like what do you mean?
Speaker 1: I use RCS.
Speaker 0: I was in the nub stage of git when other people didn't know it existed Except for really hardcore Linux people.
Speaker 0: and then when it became popular I had already sort of mastered the user parts and by now I've mastered the underneath parts which most people don't even know about.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean, I'm.
Speaker 1: I'm currently a nub at git.
Speaker 1: I mean I may.
Speaker 1: I have a GitHub account that I haven't logged into in a while and yeah.
Speaker 0: So the thing with git is that it is a version control system.
Speaker 0: Just like subversion or whatever Except it is architecturally different and that it is distributed right.
Speaker 0: there is no canonical.
Speaker 0: This repository is the repository.
Speaker 0: Instead every repository is the full repository.
Speaker 0: So you have a. you have it on your computer.
Speaker 0: you clone You don't check out you clone.
Speaker 0: You have the whole thing the whole history of the project on your computer.
Speaker 0: You edit that history and then you share commits with other people in a distributed mesh Fashion and that you know, that way anyone can do as they please.
Speaker 0: Alright, and this has many benefits and you know drawbacks, but mostly benefits.
Speaker 0: Once you understand it and use it properly You'll see that subversion and other centralized version control systems are just awful.
Speaker 0: There is a come some competitors.
Speaker 0: the chief among them is mercurial which is written entirely in Python.
Speaker 0: You know There's all sorts of arguments to be made.
Speaker 0: is one better?
Speaker 0: is one worse?
Speaker 0: the general consensus mercurial is a little easier to use.
Speaker 0: Git has slightly better performance.
Speaker 0: They have a lot of feature parity.
Speaker 0: It doesn't really matter that much but it seems to get his one, you know GitHub is destroyed bitbucket.
Speaker 0: So I Mean bitbucket still exists, but github is definitely winning.
Speaker 0: GitHub is sort of the way of the future.
Speaker 0: if you're not using git now You should learn it because if you're doing anything with software, that's where it's at And such alright, so I mean, what's that?
Speaker 1: Like what are the primary benefits for getting the architecture?
Speaker 1: that I doubt many of our listeners will know much about?
Speaker 0: well The primary benefits are distributed.
Speaker 1: if you can tell I don't know a lot about git.
Speaker 0: Well, do I mean I could start from like the bottom up if you want but I might be a little boring now Maybe maybe later.
Speaker 1: Let's know what you know what the listeners always want.
Speaker 1: They're always like well the listener always wants us to go in depth at our own level and to not like Pull back from our level of technological prowess.
Speaker 0: Okay, so here's here's I'll get.
Speaker 1: let's talk about this the way we talk about this stuff.
Speaker 0: Okay, so here's how git works.
Speaker 0: ready.
Speaker 0: You have a file.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: You hash the file with sha very strong hash.
Speaker 0: You're very unique Right, yeah, so what you do is you take a file you hash it you create a what's called a blob in git terminology.
Speaker 0: Right, so that blob contains the contents of the file compressed and whatever right and the name of that blob will be the hash The sha1 hash.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: You update the hat you update the file you update the blob.
Speaker 0: It's that simple, right?
Speaker 0: So you create a new repository in that file.
Speaker 0: in that repository you have some files.
Speaker 0: You add them all to what's known as the staging area the index, right?
Speaker 0: So basically this is advantage number one of git is the index.
Speaker 0: most You know things like subversion.
Speaker 0: you edit files and you commit and it commits all your changes no matter what files.
Speaker 0: they are Right.
Speaker 0: So if you what say want to have two files that are edited and you want to commit one file and not the other.
Speaker 0: You have to actually roll one of the files back commit and then roll the file forward, right?
Speaker 0: It's sort of annoying.
Speaker 0: in git you actually add your changes to the staging area The index and then when you commit the index is what is committed.
Speaker 0: Right, so you can actually if you do an interactive add you can actually add part of a file.
Speaker 0: So if I edit a file and I change two functions I can actually add one of those changes to the one of the functions to be committed and let the other one just stay as A dirty chain.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's pretty crazy.
Speaker 0: So you stage and then you commit, right?
Speaker 0: So that's that's the first advantage of git just from the user perspective, right?
Speaker 0: So anyway under the hood, right?
Speaker 0: It's making blobs.
Speaker 0: so everything is uniquely hashed which means that whatever you put into git is what you're gonna get out.
Speaker 0: a lot of other version control Systems don't actually guarantee that what you put in is what you get out With git.
Speaker 0: whatever you put in guaranteed to get out because if the hash don't match ain't gonna fly.
Speaker 0: So a commit in git is what's known as a tree.
Speaker 0: It's a tree and that tree is a list and the list is a list of trees and blobs.
Speaker 0: That's all it is.
Speaker 0: It's trees and blobs.
Speaker 0: So a tree would might you know would be the top level of your repository which would be your commit Yeah.
Speaker 0: and then underneath that would be trees which would be the sub directories and in those sub directories would be blobs and When you commit it just creates a new tree with the new blobs and the new trees in it.
Speaker 1: So when I've pulled out like I've brought down the repository or whatever I basically got the entire like everything in the project just local.
Speaker 0: you have the entire history of Every commit that has ever been.
Speaker 1: so I could step back through to like the hello world of the project.
Speaker 0: You absolutely could all right, you wouldn't even have to step.
Speaker 0: you just reset to it.
Speaker 1: Does this I mean?
Speaker 1: Does this cause disk space issues ever for people?
Speaker 0: I mean it is highly compressed and incredibly efficient I guess.
Speaker 1: does anyone use git for the management of things that aren't code like large images or video or anything?
Speaker 0: Oh, it's actually incredibly efficient at doing those things.
Speaker 0: You are you are going to obviously have to use a lot of disk space Yeah, but if I'm doing like video I have to use like anyway.
Speaker 0: It is better at that than the other version control systems.
Speaker 0: Well, I found it will not crash under the weight It was originally.
Speaker 0: git was originally gonna be a file system.
Speaker 0: So, you know if you have?
Speaker 0: I did not know that if you have 10 1 gig video files sure It's gonna be a 10 gig download.
Speaker 0: But yeah, but that's expected.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be 10 gigs if I use the version.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but switching between versions is like basically instantaneous once you've downloaded it.
Speaker 0: You're all set.
Speaker 1: The performance of git is is off the chart considering that local disk space is Effectively infinite in the modern world.
Speaker 0: I mean, yeah Git is actually really useful for things other than code just because it's so good.
Speaker 0: like if you go to github all the wiki's on github are actually powered by git and I've actually I've actually figured out a way to do wiki show notes on our site powered by git.
Speaker 1: Ooh, we kind of need that.
Speaker 0: It's pretty crazy when you once you see how it works.
Speaker 0: It's it's intense All right, so where was I?
Speaker 0: You're oh, yeah can get be used for.
Speaker 0: yeah You can use git for anything you want.
Speaker 0: a version.
Speaker 0: writing a book gets a great idea.
Speaker 0: Anything that you need to basically have another level of undoing and versions on git is a great way to go.
Speaker 0: So you make these commits and every commit is a tree and every commit has a hash of its own, right?
Speaker 0: So that's an easy way to identify.
Speaker 0: a commit is by its hash and a commit also has one other thing Which is a pointer to the previous commit in the history.
Speaker 0: So commit number one points at nothing but commit number two points at commit number one and every commit is a full tree full of trees and blobs.
Speaker 0: So the main thing here that this allows you to do that other version control systems don't allow you to do is easy branching.
Speaker 0: Right in subversion making a branch is a big deal.
Speaker 0: You've got one shared repository if you make a branch.
Speaker 0: That's a branch for everyone not just you right and it's a big deal to make a branch and then to merge your branch.
Speaker 0: Forget it kill yourself.
Speaker 1: I've never done it.
Speaker 0: I've given up People who have mastered it and can get it done with a minimum of pain.
Speaker 0: But if you do get properly you can always avoid the pain, right?
Speaker 0: So you can just branch like a nut job, right?
Speaker 0: You just be like, oh, yeah I'll make a branch over here to branch over there and what I tend to do which is a good best practice.
Speaker 0: That's that's another thing people can get confused about.
Speaker 0: git.
Speaker 0: is that other version control systems because they're so limited?
Speaker 0: There's only one workflow you can follow if you want to use them but git lets you do anything Which means it's like what workflow do I have?
Speaker 0: You have to make up a workflow and you have to enforce that workflow with just people and talking to each other.
Speaker 1: I imagine that's very difficult for many people.
Speaker 0: There's no technological enforcement of the workflow But there are certain practices that will sort of grease the wheels.
Speaker 0: So it's like you have to simultaneously know the path to follow to grease the wheels to make to have less conflicts and merge problems While simultaneously getting people to behave in a certain way so that you know, everything runs smoothly.
Speaker 0: it
Speaker 1: is however, I think in the long run a more fruitful path than say like ticketing systems are an example of this where you need to enforce certain workflows and The only way people ever do it is to make rules like a ticket cannot be set to a resolved state unless X Y and Z Have already happened to the ticket Unless it actually hasn't assignee because you can and the thing is once you go down that path.
Speaker 1: You can't trust people for shit because if there is any way to do the thing You don't want them to do they will do it and in their mind, it's okay because they'll let them do it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm It's like the difference between a ride with a car where you're on a rails no matter how what way you turn the car goes That the straight way anyway versus an f1 car.
Speaker 1: if you turn off the track you just die.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the.
Speaker 0: that's the thing because git is distributed right subversion.
Speaker 0: a commit in subversion Actually pushes your code to the central repository if there's a bunch of people working on the project together Which means one person can just commit and fuck the whole thing up in git.
Speaker 0: Everyone's working locally with their own copy of the repository and they're only sharing when they explicitly share.
Speaker 0: So committing making checkpoints It's free, you know.
Speaker 0: to Reset and roll forward and back for your code is completely independent of sharing code.
Speaker 0: So you can make checkpoints to make your life easier locally without sharing those checkpoints with anyone.
Speaker 0: So that would greatly reduces any chance of fucking things up right right up the get-go.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean I can't imagine but like the subversion I used to use at another company like pulling the repository down to my laptop Working on stuff for a week like on a trip or something coming back to work and kind of put that back in.
Speaker 0: Well, that's another thing.
Speaker 0: right subversion.
Speaker 0: You only get the most current version of the code when you check out Which you can't work if you're not online if you're not connected.
Speaker 0: get you have the whole thing.
Speaker 0: You can work completely offline, you know, it doesn't matter where you are open.
Speaker 1: as a version I could pull down what I'm working on and lock it for everyone else.
Speaker 0: You could do that.
Speaker 0: There's no locking and get right.
Speaker 0: So so when you do want to share something, right?
Speaker 0: There's a whole bunch of different ways to do it.
Speaker 0: You could share by email if you freaking want to.
Speaker 0: you could give someone a gz file on a stick if you want to.
Speaker 0: Right, you can do whatever.
Speaker 0: But generally people tend to do things in two ways.
Speaker 0: You could set up a Just a communally agreed upon central repository and push to it Right.
Speaker 0: So push should be a separate command and you would just send your commits to that.
Speaker 0: you know repository on whatever branch you wanted to send them on to and then other people would pull them and You would all be disciplined and no one would mess it up.
Speaker 0: That's what we do at work, but it breaks down when you have too many people, right?
Speaker 0: So when you have too many people like you do say on Linux What you do is you do a pull request Which is you email someone or call them on the phone or say hi and you talk to them and you say that's
Speaker 1: quite a difficult Protocol for many developers.
Speaker 0: I know and you say look my repository is over in this place And I have some commits on it that I would like to submit for your consideration.
Speaker 0: Please pull from my repository.
Speaker 0: All right, and this is how github works.
Speaker 0: is github has pull requests.
Speaker 0: So if you go on github you clone someone's project you do some work on it you finish it You push your code back to github from your local, right?
Speaker 0: So you push it from your local to your github.
Speaker 0: Then you do a pull request telling the other guy to pull your github into his github.
Speaker 0: You see how it's like.
Speaker 0: everyone has all these different copies of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so he gets a pull request notification on github.
Speaker 0: He takes your code from your github to his local machine.
Speaker 0: Hopefully check, you know puts it on a separate branch where it won't mess anything up.
Speaker 0: Checks your code out sees how good it is.
Speaker 0: sees if it's working merges it in with his code.
Speaker 0: See is how that works.
Speaker 0: If he likes your code, then he'll merge it in and push it to his repository There by accepting your pull request.
Speaker 0: if he doesn't like your code He'll just throw that branch away and give you the finger and ignore you.
Speaker 0: All right And but the thing is your code isn't lost.
Speaker 0: you still have it Right, if you don't like?
Speaker 0: if you like your thing a different way than he likes it then you maintain your own branch.
Speaker 0: Good for you.
Speaker 0: You forked it.
Speaker 0: Congratulations.
Speaker 1: so how well like.
Speaker 1: how does it handle merging like if two people have edit like you're trying to merge two branches where the Fundamental difference is like one section of code is just like two people implemented it way different.
Speaker 0: Okay, so get merges are pretty complex here, but they're also the most powerful and the best right?
Speaker 0: So here's how it works.
Speaker 0: Remember I told you a commit is just a tree that has trees and blobs under it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right.
Speaker 0: So I want to merge two branches together, right?
Speaker 0: So I take these two branches and all it looks at really is The top commits because a branch is just a pointer to a commit.
Speaker 0: That's all it is.
Speaker 0: and it just so happens that if you are on a branch and you commit it Automatically moves the branch pointer ahead to the new commit.
Speaker 0: That's all it does.
Speaker 0: So a branch is just a pointer an easy way to specify a commit.
Speaker 0: So I might say master.
Speaker 0: Well master is currently pointing at this commit.
Speaker 0: So master is just an easy way of saying that commit.
Speaker 0: All right Head is just an easy way of saying the commit I'm currently looking at.
Speaker 0: So head is just a pointer that looks at the commit you're currently looking at.
Speaker 0: and if you make a new commit head and the Rancher on get both get moved forward to point at the nuke, right?
Speaker 0: They're all.
Speaker 0: just point me all these names are just pointers to commits.
Speaker 0: So if I merge let's say I have a production branch and I go to the production branch and I say get merge master Right, which would take the commit of the master branch and merge it with the production branch, right in right?
Speaker 0: What happens is it takes the top it takes production which remember is just a commit.
Speaker 0: yeah, it takes a master which again is just a commit and Then it looks at their histories and it rolls back to find the common ancestor and it doesn't care about any of the commits in between.
Speaker 0: all it cares about is the two commits you're merging and the common ancestor.
Speaker 0: So then it looks at each blob in both commits.
Speaker 0: So let's say that all that's in there is a readme text and some other Five readme text.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it looks at the first readme text and it says alright this readme text I'm production branch.
Speaker 0: Was there any difference between this this readme text between production and the common ancestor?
Speaker 0: No, okay.
Speaker 0: Well, is there any difference between this readme text on between master and the common ancestor?
Speaker 0: Well, yes Yes, there was a change.
Speaker 0: So in the master branch this file changed.
Speaker 0: Yep, but in the production branch did not change.
Speaker 0: Nope, we're we're just gonna take that master change aren't we that easy merge?
Speaker 0: just do take the master done.
Speaker 0: Um easy.
Speaker 1: So what if the two readmes diverged?
Speaker 0: ah So both in the case where both readme files have changed there were edits on production and there were edits on master.
Speaker 0: Well, were they the same edits?
Speaker 0: exactly the same?
Speaker 0: because then that case we're just right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm assuming no bro, because that's the more interesting case.
Speaker 0: So no, they're not the same.
Speaker 0: There were some edits on the production branch and there's some edits on the master branch that were different.
Speaker 0: Well, are these edits like on the same line?
Speaker 0: You know, it has actually a bunch of different merge algorithms.
Speaker 0: It uses that.
Speaker 0: it tried All right.
Speaker 0: So let's say one one of the things added a commit at the top of the file and one of the things added a comment At the bottom of the file, it'll just merge them together.
Speaker 0: No problem Uh-huh, right.
Speaker 0: But let's say two people edited the same function.
Speaker 0: the same line of code is two different lines.
Speaker 0: Right since the common ancestor, it'll say Dude conflict yo and you.
Speaker 0: what you'll have to do is you have to open up the file and you look through the file And you see a bunch of chevrons and it'll basically say hey, dude Look this line on the production branch looks like this and on the master branch looks like this Manually edit me.
Speaker 0: So you manually edit that one area of the file.
Speaker 0: remove all the chevrons and all the extra crap it threw in there.
Speaker 0: Right get the file just the way you want it to look post merge Add it to the staging to the index the staging index and commit and then it'll be merged nice And of course it keeps the versions of everything along the way because it's good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course Alright, so, you know There's no way you could possibly lose anything unless you intentionally try to lose something.
Speaker 0: and even if you do lose something Like you accidentally like remove something You could actually check the git ref log and bring it back because unless the garbage cleaner has come along It won't actually be gone.
Speaker 0: Which is really the git ref log has saved my ass quite a few times.
Speaker 0: Let me tell you So yeah merge is pretty fancy like that.
Speaker 0: But the other thing about git that's incredibly powerful is the rebase.
Speaker 0: a lot of people if you look online They'll be like don't use rebase.
Speaker 0: That's a naughty thing to do.
Speaker 0: They're totally wrong.
Speaker 0: They don't know what they're talking about.
Speaker 0: There's a reason the tools in there They wouldn't have made it if you weren't supposed to use it.
Speaker 0: Linus Torvalds wouldn't have made rebase if you weren't supposed to use rebase.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So what rebase does is it basically rewrites history it rebases.
Speaker 0: So say for example, I start working on a new feature.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna add to the website the ability to post on Facebook.
Speaker 0: So I make a branch called the Facebook branch and I start working on it.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile you add the ability to post to Twitter right and you finish and now you put it on the master branch.
Speaker 0: So I forked the master branch and to add my Facebook feature, but your Twitter feature is now on the master branch But it's not in my Facebook branch.
Speaker 0: But it needs to be alright because I need to build my stuff taking your stuff into consideration because you finish your work first.
Speaker 0: Therefore I have to get my work to work on top of your work Right, and I don't want to just try to merge the two together when I'm all done.
Speaker 0: that could be painful.
Speaker 0: It might work, but it could be painful.
Speaker 0: So what I do is I rebase my branch onto the master branch.
Speaker 0: What that does is it takes all my commits on My Facebook branch and sort of puts them in a bin on the side.
Speaker 0: Okay, so now my right and then it takes your commits and it puts them right there, right?
Speaker 0: Where my Facebook commits just were.
Speaker 0: so now my branch and master look the same.
Speaker 0: Then it takes my Facebook commits and it puts them right on top of your Twitter commits on my Facebook branch.
Speaker 0: So now I've rebased.
Speaker 0: you see how I picked my stuff up.
Speaker 0: I made a new base for my stuff, right?
Speaker 0: Do you understand you get what I'm saying?
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right now this also has other Fancy powers and this is where the magic comes in.
Speaker 0: the magics the magics.
Speaker 0: I'm working on an open-source project say I'm making a Linux kernel driver.
Speaker 0: It's hard work.
Speaker 0: So I make a lot of commits locally a lot of checkpoint commits, you know.
Speaker 0: And a lot of these commits are just like fix the typo out of the line testing this out.
Speaker 0: Oh that didn't work.
Speaker 0: revert it, you know.
Speaker 0: And I just keep making tons and tons of commits all locally and eventually after ten days and a hundred commits I finished the driver, right now the Linux kernel doesn't want to see a hundred commits.
Speaker 0: Right, I can't be like hey Linus pull request hundred little commits with typos and all this nonsense for this one driver.
Speaker 0: He'll be like screw you.
Speaker 0: I don't want your hundred commits cluttering up the history of Linux kernel.
Speaker 0: It's you're.
Speaker 0: you're basically, you know, as far as you're personally concerned those hundred commits have meaning.
Speaker 0: but as far as it's basically one version like 1.0 as far as line, you know Linux the kernel is concerned It's one commit.
Speaker 0: that commit should have a message like added new driver for lousy webcam That only Scott has right?
Speaker 0: That's all he wants one commit with that whole change in it.
Speaker 0: So what you do is you rebase?
Speaker 0: Against yourself you rebase the branch against itself and you do an interactive rebase Which is allows you to manually control the rebase.
Speaker 0: and what you would do is you would actually squash the commits with this rebase Into just one commit that you would then share So that you it allows you to rewrite the whole history of what you just did on that branch Uh-huh, and then merge just that one really pretty commit back in.
Speaker 0: so you can make a whole bunch of messy commits all on your Own that make it really easy to do your work.
Speaker 0: because you have all these checkpoints You can roll them back and forward take them in and out You can try to a function other people.
Speaker 0: you can decide you don't like it take it out or place it with something else You know and you can have this whole.
Speaker 0: your whole workflow history is there You know to make it really easy to get the job done and try all sorts of stuff out Branches and all sorts of merging and nonsense, but when you're finally said and done You can rebase everything into one cozy commit that can then be shared With other people.
Speaker 0: that is clean and beautiful and no one will see all that mess you made when you were working locally.
Speaker 0: But you do and you still have that history.
Speaker 0: It doesn't go anywhere.
Speaker 0: It's hidden inside so you can always go back to it if you need to.
Speaker 0: you know, oh adding that one line was a mistake.
Speaker 0: I'll just go and find that.
Speaker 0: you know commit that got rebased in revert it and Read, you know make a new man.
Speaker 1: that makes a lot of sense in light of like.
Speaker 1: go back to my video example.
Speaker 1: say I Wanted to use that for like video collaboration.
Speaker 1: Well, I have a thousand one gigabyte commits of this video and The project manager doesn't want a thousand gigabytes of crap.
Speaker 1: They want the final one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not sure how exact.
Speaker 0: I haven't done a lot with binary files so much and get at least not big.
Speaker 0: I don't know either.
Speaker 0: So I'm not sure if it only stores the diffs of the binary files or if it actually stores the whole files.
Speaker 1: that diffs of Binary files are often.
Speaker 0: but the thing is even though even though it will be expect exceptionally good At performance of saving space and being very fast at executing commands.
Speaker 0: Don't fool yourself.
Speaker 0: You know with subversion when you check something out you are only checking out the newest version.
Speaker 0: So it's a pretty quick download.
Speaker 0: if you try to clone the Linux kernel and get the complete history from git It takes a long time to download because even though it's mostly just code.
Speaker 0: In fact, it's almost all code There's a lot of it and the history is long.
Speaker 0: It takes a long time to download that it's a big package.
Speaker 0: Don't fool yourself.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So if you if you consider download time to be incredibly important, you know that that is a negative.
Speaker 0: it's there.
Speaker 0: There.
Speaker 0: there are tons and tons of fancy things.
Speaker 0: I can go on for like hours talking like git bisect and which like you would Git bisect.
Speaker 0: I won't tell you how it works But what it does is you tell it lets you have a bug and you don't know when the bug appeared.
Speaker 0: You tell it the last known good commit and it will roll forward one commit at a time asking you is this commit good?
Speaker 0: Yes, no.
Speaker 1: So I could run that through a regression tester.
Speaker 1: that regression tests every commit until it hits the one that fails the test.
Speaker 0: And I know you know that that's you know, which commit introduced the problem.
Speaker 0: And yeah, you can run it through an automatic testing system that will automatically mark the commits as good or bad.
Speaker 0: So it'll automatically just play good.
Speaker 0: This is the bad commit.
Speaker 0: This is where the problem came from.
Speaker 0: It can do all sorts of crazy shit.
Speaker 0: There's like hooks.
Speaker 0: so you'd be like here's a here's a shell script.
Speaker 0: whenever anyone commits automatically execute the shell script.
Speaker 0: Whenever anyone pushes execute the shell script.
Speaker 0: so you can have like your git repository email everyone when there's a new commit or stuff like that.
Speaker 0: You can do tagging of releases.
Speaker 0: You can do bringing tons and tons of ridiculous shit.
Speaker 0: that most you can do get blame is really good It.
Speaker 0: no it knows who edited every single line and every single file.
Speaker 0: So you do a git blame.
Speaker 0: when you see a bug and see who exactly introduced that bug cuz their name is right there on The line, you know who did it?
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I know it's just.
Speaker 0: it's crazy shit.
Speaker 0: but if you are You know if you've never used version control or even if you have been using it or if you're coding anything Even the simplest little project personal thing just for yourself.
Speaker 0: That might be one file.
Speaker 0: It's worth the distort and git even if you're not coding if you're doing anything where versioning might be a good idea, right?
Speaker 0: I mean, I know that like doesn't Microsoft Word do versioning in itself?
Speaker 1: now Yeah, and a lot of people use like web dev and stuff to do that sort of good God.
Speaker 0: Yeah you want to use if you're doing any work that needs to be versioned where you want to be able to roll back to old Versions rolled in new versions if you're working collaboratively on something with anyone that is in that is files especially text files.
Speaker 0: You want to use git and you want to learn it?
Speaker 0: Even if you start out using it just really simply don't bother with the fancy stuff like rebase and whatever.
Speaker 0: just do commits on one Branch push and pull between two people what you know, just use github in the simplest way possible.
Speaker 0: That's okay.
Speaker 0: You're doing something and even though you don't know the advanced features You might need them and when you do come to need them You can look them up how to use them to save your ass Or you can get someone to help you save your ass.
Speaker 0: if you're using something else Saving your ass might not be a possibility and you know, that's the thing with git is like, you know It's the whole hog of Neil Stevenson, right?
Speaker 0: It's this incredibly powerful drill that you could just fucking kill yourself.
Speaker 0: It's so powerful, but it can always get the job done.
Speaker 0: So you could.
Speaker 0: it can shoot yourself in the foot, but it can also unshoot yourself in the foot.
Speaker 1: And of course with the whole hog, you can't undrill a hole.
Speaker 0: That's true But get you it's very hard to get to ruin it completely.
Speaker 0: It might be also really hard to get it back to goodness, but it's possible almost always possible to fix Anything and it's all.
Speaker 0: it's definitely possible that no matter what problem you're in you can escape.
Speaker 1: so kids Just remember it's trees and blobs all the way down.
Speaker 0: It is trees and blobs all the way down.
Speaker 1: pretty much This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Speaker 1: Remember geek nights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.